All right. Uh, I'm here
with Kevin Folta, Kevin,
your a scientist,
a GMO foods expert and if there is one
subject that gets beaten to death online
and in conversation
and butchered. I, I've,
I've heard many conversations that I had
to just walk away from at parties where
people started talking about what GMO
foods do and what's going to happen and
all the horrible things.
Gmo Foods are probably one of the most
confusing and also one of the most hated
things in,
in the world today,
but also one of the most common
and most misunderstood, right?
I mean almost everything,
there's a,
Neil degrasse Tyson did a video about
this where he was kind of explaining like
the term GMO foods,
like virtually everything you see,
including things that are quote unquote
organic at a supermarket have been
modified in some way in order to prolong
the shelf life in order for them to
taste better,
including corn and tomatoes
and oranges and you name it.
Yeah, I think that's the big problem
is that when you frame this very well,
the problem is that we
confuse this idea of GMO,
which is kind of a pejorative term that
we've derived to a kind of misrepresent
this kind of technology, which is really
just plant genetic improvement. Um,
like you say, we've been improving
plants for 10,000 years as a species.
We find the ones that work best and we
continue to select those particular lines
that have benefits for us.
And we'd been doing this for a long time,
so everything is different
than it was in the wild.
If you look at the natural forms,
there are nothing like what
you see today in the store.
So this GMO thing is just the most recent
way that we've been able to modify the
way a plant behaves and
what plant products are.
And it just is a much more precise
extension of conventional breeding.
But there is a company that looms like
the death star out there in the world of
GMO foods. And that company, I
don't even have to say the name,
it's spoken in hushed terms around
Hippie campfires. Monsanto. Yeah, right.
And well, Monsanto was also
responsible for a lot of good things.
I'm sure they, they have done some
creepy shit and they have, uh,
gotten, especially in
India, I mean they're,
they're directly connected to the suicides
of countless farmers who can't afford
to use their seed. They have to
replace every year. I mean there's,
there's good and bad when it comes
to the ability to modify things.
And I think what terrifies some people
is that a company like Monsanto,
which has just ungodly amounts of
money and influence and power. I mean,
they'd been sued by the
Brazilian government and
Brazil sued them and won. And,
uh, I don't know the exact
specifics of the case,
but it's essentially about those
seeds that explain those terminator
seeds, if you could, and how
those things were created. Okay.
So you touched on three important
points there and we can come back to the
suicides and also Monsanto
being a giant company. Um,
and I should not wear it off the top. I
have nothing to do with Monsanto. I'm not,
you know, I don't work for them. I'm
a scientist at the, wait a minute,
I've read online that you are a shill.
That's right. You are not a chef.
I am not a shell. I'm actually,
I'm a shill for you. I
actually, I'm, I'm a, I'm a,
I'm a, I'm a public scientist. I
work for the University of Florida.
I'm the chairman of a
horticultural sciences department
in a state where we grow
almost no GM crops.
The differences is that I see tremendous
potential for how these technologies
could be helpful for our farmers and we
try to get them excited about ways that
we can apply them in the future. But let
me go back to your last question about,
cause I don't even know much about this
Brazil issue either, but what you mean,
I'm sure you could pull up the article.
We'd see it on the big screen. Yeah.
So your last, the last question
out of that was the terminator,
the terminator seeds and
the terminator seeds.
This is something that never existed in
terms of a product that was available.
A company called Delta pine in land back
in the 1990s develop the technology to
ensure that a genetically engineered
seeds would stay in the fields they were
planted, that you wouldn't have pollen
leaving and pollinating something else and
creating plants and other places.
Pretty good idea for containment.
And Delta Pine and land
had this technology where
basically the embryo of the
seed didn't develop properly.
So it was a dead end.
You couldn't replant
it and get it to grow.
So when Delta Pine and land later
was bought out by the big Yam,
by Monsanto,
everybody saw the terminal value.
It wasn't called the terminator
seed had some other name,
but it quickly gained the name Terminator.
And so these were never grown
outside of a greenhouse.
And the company has said they never will
grow them outside of a greenhouse just
because of the, uh, overlaid
implications of what they might mean.
But there have been
instances of GMO crops,
but by pollination,
uh,
infecting the lands of people who are not
supposed to have these Monsanto crops.
On. And they were sued for having these
crops growing on their land. Correct.
There's examples where people have
had litigation because they've, uh,
they've generated the seeds
that are a licensed product.
So in other words,
when you're a farmer,
you buy the seeds from the company and
it's Monsanto or any of the companies
that sell the seeds.
There's six different companies now
you buy the seeds from any of those
companies, you fill out a form saying,
uh, I agreed to not grow more of this.
And so there are cases where people have
grown more of it and hasn't been from a
little bit of pollen
drifting into a field.
The court cases are all public record
in the ones where they had been
successfully tried and litigated,
they've been for thousands of acres of
plants that somewhat would knowingly grow
and maybe even treat with roundup in many
cases so that they were selecting for
the trait. The intent was to sell
the seeds that they agreed not
to sell. Oh, okay.
So these stories about farmers
that were getting sued because of
crosspollination because they're,
the GMO crops have infected their,
their land is not true. That's
not, there's no evidence in the,
in the record to show that this is
substantiated and what's even Numb, uh,
more scary about that is that is that
when the company has litigated any of
these and one favorable court decisions,
they haven't kept the money
that any damages went back
into the community. So, um,
again, that's, what do you mean by that?
Just went back to the
community that if they saw,
if they sued a farmer and
actually won the case,
any of the funding that was a one is a
penalty from that case was given back to
the community where that
farmer lived back in what form?
I guess just guess just financial
support for whatever I, it was just,
the idea they wanted to get around was
that they were somehow suing farmers to
get rich or to pocket the funds.
And so they created this opera wealth,
this plan or this program to put
the money back where it came.
So where are these farmers get
the seeds then? If they, they had,
they illegally acquired
these seeds somehow. Is that,
what's the implication? Well,
if you were to go buy corn from let's
say Monsanto or Dow or any of the
companies that make it and
you were to grow, say, uh,
soybeans that were roundup resistance
so that you, they resist the herbicide,
you can kill the weeds,
but let this plant's growth through a,
if you were to buy those and you
were to spray them and then, uh,
keep the seeds and then grow a,
bulk them up and then start
selling them out of your garage,
the company would come and
say, no, you can't do that.
So this is what you're doing is you're
taking the corn and the corn itself is
essentially seed, right? Like
the actual, the ears of corn,
you can grow corn from that corn
and that's what they're doing. Yeah.
So they're essentially, and maybe not corn
as much, I can get to that in a second.
But, um, things like cotton and,
and a in soil, you can't, uh, it's,
it's a lot like software and anesthesia.
Bodner dot.
Doctor Anesthesia Bodner is
an excellent example of this.
You can't go buy a copy of,
uh,
Microsoft office and go home and make
a thousand copies and sell them on Ebay
without Microsoft knocking on your door.
This is a technology that takes
years and years to develop.
It's a really expensive technology to
deregulate something like $130 million
sometimes to deregulate one of
these genetically modified lines.
So the company needs to make
money to maintain its R and D.
And so they ask farmers,
who are the beneficiaries ultimately of
this to sign an agreement saying that
they'll buy it every year. So this is
the lawsuit, the Brazilian lawsuit,
if you scroll up, Jim's degree, this whole
thing, it's so they face a $1 billion.
Well, this is in 2013. They lost
the lawsuit. Um, this is, uh, not a,
uh,
a recent article,
but the farmers that were suing for
abusive purchase contracts.
A scroll down a little bit there.
Brazil farmers court actions are piling
up against Monsanto for collecting
royalties on our r one is that
roundup, the roundup ready one, um,
regarding eleague,
uh,
regarded as illegal and for conditioning
the sale of new GM seeds in a,
I don't know what that word is,
intact and Taca Rr two to the signing
of a contract seen as abusive.
According to an article for Valor Online,
Brazil lawyers for the
farmers and representative
bodies estimate the value of
the claims against Monsanto at 1.9
billion Birr Brazilian Brazilian heels,
which is about us. 1 billion
processes have not been completed,
but preliminary estimates say that the
claims may affect the company's profit.
See if you could find a more recent
article cause they lost that lawsuit.
I have no clue. This is also coming
from sustainable pulse and GM watch,
uh, two sources which have nothing
positive to say about biotechnology.
And it wouldn't surprise me if another
other countries did try to litigate.
And these kinds of examples, they mean
it's anybody can sue a company, you know,
anybody can do it.
So it's a,
it's possible that these things
were brought before these, uh, uh,
governments saying that these were unfair
practices to farmers to make them sign
a contract and then
repurchase the seed later on.
So they seeds that you
were talking about before.
How did these folks get
them then have the, the,
if they're getting enough seeds to plant
thousands and thousands of acres, uh,
illegally, how are they doing that? Well,
you just saved the seeds from
the previous year instead of,
instead of processing and you know, you
can imagine a corn, corn cob has, uh,
several hundred kernels and each
one of those represents a new plant.
So you can have x amount of your
acreage dedicated to seed production.
So essentially all you would
have to do is buy, you know,
a few thousand ears of corn and you'd
be able to plant just a giant area of,
you know, and I wish I knew the number off
the top of my head, but I don't, but um,
it would be able to
plant replant more seats,
corns a bad example because corn are
hybrids and it without going into a whole
genetics whiteboard thing here,
you're,
every corn is made from two parents
that are genetically very different.
But when you combine them together,
give you a hybrid that when you
cross a hybrid with a hybrid,
gives you a mixture of seeds that don't
give you any uniformity in the next
generation.
So since the 1930s,
the seed companies have been able to
resell that hybrid seed to farmers every
year because there's nothing to be
gained in, in producing your own.
And so corn isn't always the best example.
And the companies have used genetics for
going on a century now to protect their
breeders interests. So
the original corners that
someone's phone, what was that?
The original corn,
uh,
before it was modified at all was that
corn that you get like for Thanksgiving,
but you hang on your,
your
door that nobody eats that weird
colored funky looking corn and it's even
smaller than that,
right?
Because the original corn was called
Teosinte and [inaudible] was a basically
growing on a Bush and Mexico and it gave
you 13 little hard kernels on a stick
that an implant would
produce some of this.
And it's now being thought from
archeological evidence that uh,
people's would take these little
corn cobs, which to call it,
that is kind of strange,
this little stick with little rocks on
it and stick it in fire and pop it and
eat it like popcorn
because it's too hard to,
you have to use a lot of water in
grinding to make any food out of it.
But you can imagine how exciting it was
when you were a person who is using us
for sustenance.
When you found a [inaudible] plant
that may be made twice as many,
or maybe instead of 13 kernels,
gave you 26 and so you would select
those implant them the next year.
And it's really interesting that now you
can go back through the 10,000 years of
corn improvement.
And we've been able to identify the
genes that were at all of the critical
thresholds that shifted this thing from
being a Bush with lots of little sticks
of kernels to being what it is today.
And it really is just a small
number of genes that were changed.
So before they started modifying genes,
how do they select, like say, how do they,
cause before any genetic modifications
are done in laboratories,
they had turned this GOC
what I say [inaudible] or
maize as we used to call it.
Right. That was the Indian
word for it. Even now,
even according to that
commercial at RBS. Yeah. Um,
well the maze is kind of a general
term for everything from a field corn,
which is what we think about,
which is fed to animals,
which 80% of GM crops go
to animal feed. And, uh,
we differentiate that versus a
what is typically eaten by humans,
which is usually sweet corn varieties.
So how did they turn it before there
was any genetic modifications done in
laboratories? How did they turn
that corn into what we now,
which is delicious and sweet and you put
butter on it, it's fantastic. Oh, sure.
Did they do that? Yeah, actually.
But it was all just random mutations.
DNA referendum.
Yeah.
DNA replication is a sloppy process and
funny things happen when you, uh, from,
uh, environment. So in the process
of replication of DNA itself,
you can make errors, um,
cosmic radiation, um,
just a chemicals in our environment,
natural chemicals that are out
there can induce changes in DNA.
And these kinds of mutations sometimes
very rarely result in a change in the
plant that's beneficial and at least,
or at least from a human perspective.
So in all the plants that we've had,
all the plants that we have,
the significant amount of change has
come from random mutations that change
genes in ways we don't understand pieces
of DNA that get up out of the genome
and sit down somewhere else randomly.
They do this all the time. Um,
viruses in the plants that get into the
genome and sit down in places that we
have no idea where.
So genetic modification is something
that's ongoing and constant andF in a
factor in every genome
including our own. And so, um,
what we're seeing today is just the,
uh,
the long term effect that of humans who've
been able to put all the good traits
in one place.
So when you see those tomatoes that are
in the supermarket that are Pale and you
could play basketball with them,
those hard tomatoes,
and then you compare them
to like heirloom tomatoes.
The only difference between those two
is that someone had found some tomatoes
that had grown extra firm and selected
those and use the seeds from those to
create more similar tomatoes
and only select the dose.
Right. So you, you, you frame two
cool things here. So heirloom,
what does an heirloom and an heirloom
is a tomato without standing eating
qualities that can't work in production
commercially cause it's too mushy.
It's too mushy. They don't last long and
they break down. But on the other hand,
so this is what the problem is with
our food. When you talk about tomatoes,
strawberries, blueberries, things
that these are non GMO by the way,
there's no GMO tomatoes or strawberries.
Not at all. People would say there are,
the problem is is that plant breeding
over the last 50 years or say over the
last 100 years, the, the objectives
of the breeders has been bigger.
Fruit uniformity, big
yield, disease resistance,
nothing about flavor and aroma.
So to meet production characteristics,
which is what we've been
selecting for breeders,
have been looking for these kinds of
characteristics that don't involve the
consumer.
And so our decline in the flavors and
the quality of fruits and vegetables is
directly related to the mass breeding,
not anything to do with GMO.
So when you say genetic modified
in, in that, in those terms,
they are kind of genetically modified,
but they're not modified in terms of being
in a laboratory in human beings doing
some funky stuff with jeans.
They're sort of modified almost
naturally and just selected for those
modifications.
And,
and some of the things that we've selected
for have been the ones that didn't
kill us when we ate them or the things
that didn't make a poison that, uh,
or something that tasted horrible. Um,
plants make lots of funky compounds.
And so this was an opportunity for a,
so what we've seen in our stores
right now is the residue of,
of thousands of years of human selection.
And we can call it genetic
modification if we want to,
but we can differentiate it from
what we do in the laboratory,
which is now we can call adding a
transgene where transgenesis moving a gene
from one background of genetics
to another via laboratory.
And these selections that people
have moaned about and I have as well.
I mean,
it's horrible when you're going a sandwich
and has a pale tomato on it because
they just taste awful though.
So there's,
there's no science involved in any of
that other than selection. There's no,
there's no,
there's no like injection of some alien
sort of genetics into those things.
Alien to the plant.
Now there is no, no syringes. I'm
like that. And actually, you know,
it is more an art than a science being
a plant breeder is the most kick ass
career these days and has
been for a long time. Um,
plant breeding is essentially inventing
the next generation of food and all
we're talking about is a mixing pollen
from things that maybe normally wouldn't
cross together, like something
that nature would never cross.
But you got this cool tomato from Europe
that has great qualities and we can mix
it with this great production quality
tomato from that grows in Florida where
nothing else can grow.
And now you mix these two together and
you get this beautiful tomato that works
well and everybody's garden. That's where
we're going now. But that's not GMO.
That's just using other types of
technology to facilitate this net,
this breeding process that breeders do.
And how would you splice those two
together? Like how would you take it?
Tomato from Europe and a tomato from
Arkansas and some hard another make them
work. They'll, most of the time it's as
simple as plants. Sex, you just, uh, you,
we masculine one of them.
Uh,
you had rip all the male parts out
of it and then you add pollen from a
different flower and it's very simple
and that's what people have been doing to
create hybrid varieties for,
for centuries.
So that is not considered genetic
modified or it is wellness.
Back to the confusion.
It is certainly a genetic modification.
You're ramming together genomes that
never would have mashed together in the,
in the wild never. But, uh,
in creating a product that humans
have never seen or tasted or tested,
but yet we find this very
acceptable and very, uh,
even though it's a very random process,
we don't know what kind of, uh, uh,
those, those transposable genes, those
things jumping around genomes. Um,
two of the main corn types have
500 different genes between them,
meaning one has 500 genes
the other doesn't have.
So you're mixing together things that
have no commonality other than the basic
core guts of, of genes in
the genome. So this is not,
I don't think those splicing of
things is not what terrifies people.
What seems to terrify people
is the introduction of
things that are not supposed
to be in the organic plant.
And this is something that,
that really bugs people.
And the real,
the real fear is of disease as of cancers.
And there's all these studies that have
been done supposedly of rats that got
cancer from some sort of round
up crap. Like explain that. Okay.
So let's, uh, we can go,
let's dive into that.
So when we're adding genes across,
let's say,
species or across kingdoms
through a laboratory,
and that's what people I think are
really, uh, get strange about it,
really don't understand.
Um,
this is the part where it's actually
terribly simple and we've been doing this
since the 1980s introducing them
to the plants since the 1980s.
I've been studying it since then.
And uh,
the best example is insulin that the
human gene for insulin is cut out of the
human genome,
placed into a bacterium and then
gigantic fermenters of bacteria.
So we're talking like an organism that
is so different from humans and I then we
pull out the insulin and we use this
to inject in the patients rather than
relying on isolating it from
calf or a cow. I'm pancreas, um,
where there can be all kinds of allergic
reactions and all kinds of other issues.
So here we have a source of insulin that's
human insulin that's coming through a
GMO intermediate that allows humans to
live at for a low cost medicine that has
no side effects.
And there's a bunch of instances of
that and aren't there. There's a bar,
it's not just insulin that they
done with breeding it with bacteria.
It's a bunch of other things too.
Right?
Right. We email the main enzyme for
cheese making is called Chi Mohsen.
And as a camel gene that's expressed in a
bacterium and Hamill gene, yeah, it's a,
it seems to be the most efficient at
doing the job that Kim Wilson does. Okay.
How the hell did anybody ever figured
that out? Yeah, you just test everything.
You know, you'd try
everybody's different. Uh, it,
it's one of these
enzymes in the gut of um,
one of the chambers of the gut
of the ruminant stomach. And uh,
the camel seemed to have the one that was
the most active in vitro cause you can
do this test,
you put the different enzyme in a test
tube and see which one converts the milk
into, uh, the cheese stuff faster.
And then you were able to, uh,
figure out Campbell one just because
it's a better enzyme for whatever reason.
Now you use that one in
bacteria and 95% of cheese,
it uses a GMO intermediate.
That is
insane.
How the hell did anybody ever come to
the conclusion that a camel would produce
best cheese? Yeah, but that's
what we do. That's what I do.
And that's what my colleagues do.
You know,
we've got this really cool system of a
public universities where we're using
money from public funding,
from you know,
your tax dollars to solve problems
like how to make better cheesed less
expensively.
Um,
that's our main thing as a land grant
university and a, and so this is,
these are the basic
science questions that we,
that we strive to answer and I
think we are doing a good job with.
And that's why this GMO thing is so
frustrating because we're so down in the
Monsanto noise or so under noise that
we have solutions that we can't use.
So like the camel gene, you know, it,
things that we don't think
of that we figured out.
Is it the,
is it because of the name because that
name is associated with this big evil
corporation that all GMO foods are
sort of looked at in this regard.
Because I mean people aren't freaking
out about camel genes and cheats because
they didn't know about it,
but everybody knows about g m o s and
they instantly connect that to Monsanto
and they instantly
connect Monsanto to greed.
And callousness and Indian farmers
committing suicide as we're talking.
Oh yeah, we got to come back to
that too. Don't let me walk on here.
That hidden that. Um, but it,
this is the problem though,
is that when you look at the real
solutions that are there in science,
the stuff I care about, you know,
Monsanto, if they went away tomorrow,
it wouldn't affect the fact
that the science is really good.
So they're a company that's
profiting off of the science. Well,
they sell a product of farmers.
Farmers want improved crops that dead
take in the big deal for farmers.
We have 1% of our people in this country
are farming to feed and clothe the rest
of us. It's such a small amount
they're getting by on narrow margins.
And when you're talking
about the disasters that come
from heat waves and floods
and everything else, they're operating
just by breaking even. And so, uh,
farmers who can get improved seeds
that maybe don't require an insecticide
because the plant makes
its own protection.
That saves a farmer big bucks
in terms of fuel, labor, uh,
products that they don't have to spray.
And so farmers have adopted the GM
technologies faster than cell phones.
I mean these were,
these went from zero to 95% of acreage
and just a couple of years for five crops.
So farmers by the crops,
Monsanto makes the seeds,
Monsanto makes the seeds, the farmers
want the seeds and demand more.
And that's why Monsanto stays in business.
They make a product that farmers use.
Um, the Indians. Yeah, Indian
farmers committing suicide.
What's the story behind that?
So the best place to get information
on this comes from academic sources.
And if you look at Ronald Herring,
who is a professor at Cornell University,
he's looked at this question very much.
Suicide is a major issue in
India and it's very common.
And now more than ever among young women
and certainly is an issue among farmers.
Uh, they plant a very risky crop and
that's cotton. Cotton is a, is a,
uh, difficult to grow crop that in
most areas requires lots of water.
And if you don't get monsoonal rains, your
crop fails. So where this, uh, idea that,
uh, Monsanto crops where
somehow causing farmer suicides,
it comes from the idea that
the seeds are more expensive.
Farmers go into debt to some degree to
buy them, and then when the crop fails,
they lose the money.
It doesn't have anything to do with
Monsanto per se or with those particular
crops. The other big issue you have is
because these crops, so these are, um,
cotton plants that make
their own insecticide.
They make a protein completely
a benign to humans that, uh,
protects the plant against the,
uh,
against the weevils and other
critters that burrow into cotton.
And so farmers don't have
to spray pesticides and,
and it's a huge deal because it allows
them to farm with fewer without having
the cost of, they all want this. So
there were many of them want this,
they buy the seeds.
Now the problem is,
is there's a counterfeit seed market
where people are selling something that
isn't legit and there are the legitimate
problems with farmers who have,
who commit suicide
because of indebtedness.
But I don't know how much we can
directly blame that on the company or um,
or its agents.
So if someone buys a Monsanto cotton,
say the buy cotton seeds
and you grow cotton,
that farmer has to make an agreement to
not use that cotton to plant more cotton
that they have to buy more seeds.
Is that not the case?
So that's where it gets confusing with
people because they're like, well, why?
It's a natural process. It's a natural
process. If you buy that corn, I mean,
and you take that corn
and continue to grow corn,
that's always been how farmers have done
it throughout the beginning of time.
Now all of a sudden some company comes
along and says, no, we own that corn.
We license you that corn.
You grow the corn once and then you
have to continue to buy seeds from us to
grow corn.
That was never the case before in human
history is one company comes along and
demands that.
And that was connected to the suicides
of these people in India that this is a
totally new situation.
Actually. He very, very much
not a new situation. Um,
plant per plant variety protection and
protection of plant genetics has been
around since the 1930s.
And farmers as I mentioned before,
had been doing this
strictly by using hybrids,
which don't yield decent
plants in the next generation.
So you had the buy him from the company
every year more recently. And you,
if you wanted to,
let's say you bought an apple tree for
your apple or apple orchard from Cornell
University,
the one that Cornell University devised.
So we don't even talk about Monsanto.
Let's say a a public university. Uh,
the apple trees are all
propagated by vegetative cuttings.
You cut off the little branch,
he grow roots on it,
grow new tree and you sign a
licensing agreement non GMO.
But there's things like
that, Straw strawberries from
University of California,
you sign a licensing agreement
and what does that entail? It,
it says that you will not propagate
those plant materials as a farmer,
that you'll use them to grow your
crop and that when you need more,
you'll buy more. And the reason,
and when did, when was this done?
All these have been done for,
for decades and,
and it's more and more upon the 70s,
the 80s. Like when, when was this built?
One of the started started back as long
as the 1930s but he wasn't really done
very often. You really started to see an
escalation of plant variety protection,
non Gmo plant variety protection,
um, in the last couple of decades.
So in the 1930s did they w let's say with
apples or something like that, someone,
someone figured out a way to selectively
breed a really excellent apple.
They protected those seeds
to the point of view,
bought seeds for those
apples and planted them.
You are not allowed to extract the seeds
from the apples that you planted and
grow new seeds.
So la, but yeah, it's
sort of, you couldn't,
apples aren't apples are propagated by
the cuttings rather than seeds because
every seat is a genetic mess. Um, you
wouldn't, you can plant an apple eat,
buy an apple red delicious apple.
You can plant the 20 seeds inside and
you're going to get 20 plants that are
nothing alike and none of them will
have decent fruit. None of them.
The ones that have the,
the blockbuster traits,
and this is why there
has to be protection. Uh,
for us at University of Florida to grow a,
a new orange variety might take 30 years.
It might take a acres and acres that
costs the university hundreds of thousands
of dollars a year to borrow or to
lease. Uh, the pest treatments,
the fertilizer, the water, the labor,
it costs hundreds of thousands,
maybe a million dollars to bring that
new variety to market and to have to just
give it away is it ends
a breeding program.
So it wouldn't the solution be to publicly
fund the research so that the people
benefit from it.
So instead of a large corporation being
able to lock down this perfect orange
that you've developed at the
University of Florida instead,
the taxpayer's dollars,
which goes towards the research,
creates this beautiful plant that
everyone is allowed to benefit from. Well,
that's what happens. What happens is
that the public good or the, or you know,
public research, publicly funded says
you get a little dribble of dollars.
But our,
our breeding programs are very much self
sustaining in many cases that you need
to commercialize your best selections,
are your best fruit in order to be able
to keep the breeding program going.
So the university has to generate money
through its breeding program and then it
has to protect that money to ensure that
they will continue to receive money,
uh, from all the different things
they developed in their lab,
which will justify the amount of money
that you spend on your research. And,
and it's not much,
I mean we get a tiny bit that comes
back in terms of individual, you know,
the percentage,
it's not much at all,
but most of it goes to the breeding
programs that allow them to continue to be
leading breeding programs and hire people
and leased land and produce the next
varieties for the public.
And the only way to do that as to make
sure that people don't take your orange
and take the seeds and plant new oranges.
And cause if people do illegally
propagate this and compete against the
nurseries that are doing it
legally and selling at the farmers,
you have a couple of problems.
One is you lose control of the,
the product quality. Is it really true
to type what people say it is? Um,
and farm,
the really the beneficiary is the farmer.
We make something that the farmer and
wants and that the farmer is desperate for
our farmers need.
And we have a,
an orange problem right now
in Florida that's coming here.
We have 60 million citrus trees that are
dying and we're doing everything we can
to identify resistant
material. Not Gmo, but uh,
something called citrus greening disease.
Huanglongbing it's a disease.
That's a dude. Yeah. Yeah. Seattle
is Bruce Lee movie jail. Uh,
he was uh, the um, uh, citrus
greening disease is a disease of,
or the bacteria were bacterium blocks
the vasculature of the orange tree and
it's spread from tree to tree with
something called a [inaudible].
It's an insect and there's Jillions of
them and this thing bites one infected
tree goes to another and now spreads
that bacterium that can live in that tree
for five years before
there's any symptoms.
And then the tree just gets
sick and starts to die. Um,
we've got an orange industry that is half
as big as it used to be and we need a
solution. And that's why
we're, um, and so if our,
it's our breeders are making
everything they can to, to
generate new trees, uh, accelerating
the process, everything they can.
And if they can get that new tree
after they spent millions of dollars,
some of them from the Usda
to identify a solution,
there has to be a way for some of that
funding to come back to the program to
invent the next generation so that now
we're ready when the next threat comes.
So what would be the solution like say
if you have some sort of a bacteria
that's infecting these,
these plants and killing these oranges,
what could be a potential
solution to that?
And will it be the ramifications of you
didn't come up with a solution? Yeah,
so the,
the cool part about this is that being
where I am at the university and I'm the
chairman of a department
that does everything from
organic and sustainable, uh,
biology all the way through space biology.
You see people attacking this from so
many ways. We're changing the plants,
nutrition or changing just the root stock.
So I'm citrus trees are a bunch of routes
in us in a science. You Glue together,
you graft them together,
talk about a Frankenfood. Um,
we're building root stocks
that can generate resistance
to the bacterium so that
now when you graft on a scion,
maybe it will be resistant. Um,
we're doing everything
from insect control.
We're doing everything from a
essential oil treatments, uh,
novel drugs that are used in humans and
approved for humans being applied to see
if they can kill the psyllid ordered an
antibiotic or something like, well, um,
it's hard to do antibiotics because of
the resistance factor that people are
resistant to using antibiotics or on
trees because they're afraid they'll get.
So this is why this is the defensive,
weird science environment that we have
to work in as public scientists were
trying identify compounds that are
approved for use in humans or approved for
use on food that might have a shot at it.
And we're trying everything.
The one thing, some of the things that
have worked very well, our GMO solutions.
And so as a company in Florida that is
looking to commercialize a spinach gene
in orange that solves the problem,
we have a couple of them at the University
of Florida for at our Lake Alfred
facility where there are
genes that directly affect
the bacterial growth and uh,
they work well and they're
not harmful to humans.
And the trees are now five
years old with no symptoms.
So here's an example of a GMO solution.
It's not Monsanto.
We can't solve this problem with
breeding, uh, not easily anyway.
And here's something that
we can solve this. In five
years, thousands of families,
thousands of Florida families, thousands
of California families are watching.
They're watching their groves,
waiting for the yellow symptoms to appear.
And we have solutions,
but people will fight us tooth
and nail from applying them.
And that's where I's a public scientists.
That's why I want to be here to talk
to you because I'm looking to appeal to
people's intellect to divorce
the technology from Monsanto,
divorced this technology that
that you have in the public sector
that can be used to solve public problems
that are important. So there's a,
there's a tremendous amount of fear
that's attached to the subjects.
And with that fear there's
often very little investigation,
which is unfortunate,
but it's also very rare to get a person
like you to sit down and talk to them
and explain this and it takes a long time.
And so I really appreciate you
being here for this, but there's,
there's a lot of fears that people have
that are founded in fact and founded in
actual consequences like mercy. You
know what, Marissa come from it.
It's a medication resistant strain of
this horrible staph infection that people
get, but it's staff. I've had staff,
it's horrible, it's nasty. And the,
the antibiotics, he take a ruthless and
they leave you like a Zombie. The DF.
I had a headache. I felt terrible. I
mean, it was like, it was really weak.
I could barely open up a jar of
pickles, you know, the feeling, the,
the medication has created a
resistance to this medication.
Bacteria that have survived the result,
the medication and have grown
stronger because of that.
And that is a fear that
people were worried about,
that there's a balanced in nature and
that when you screw around with that
balance,
there's unintended consequences and
oftentimes they can be deadly like Mercer.
And this is something that I think
people are, I mean, it makes,
it gives them cause to worry about
someone putting antibiotics in their food,
whether it's in their chickens
or whether it's in there,
which they've started
to do less and less of.
And I think it was Tyson
foods that, um, uh,
publicly stated that they were going
to significantly decrease their use of
antibiotics and try to cut it out
entirely because of public concern.
I think it was Tyson foods. See if that's
true. Um, but this is a real concern,
right? I mean, doesn't that make sense?
That people were worried about that? Well,
absolutely. I think, and I'm
not so worried about the,
that the meat industry in antibiotics,
like that doesn't phase me too much,
but the idea of Murcia
okay. And all of our, uh,
resistant bacterial strains that comes
because of an overuse of a silver bullet
technology. These things come
about because the mom has a,
a screaming kid who says he
must have an ear infection.
So I'm in a demand from my doctor that I
can get antibiotics. Um, it comes from,
uh, you know, those of us saying
not taking them correctly, you know,
taking them for a few days and then
not taking the whole bottle as we're
supposed to bill. See, I've been told
recently that that's not the case.
That that was what they had discussed.
They had believed that for
a certain amount of time,
but now they no longer believe that
it's necessary to take a full, uh,
that doesn't do anything bad to create a,
uh,
or to take a shorter dose of it. Okay.
I don't know the literature on that,
so I'll have to kind of get back to you.
So much science I tried to shoot from,
you know, the stuff I'm really solid
on, but the, the long story short is,
is that in, it came up a lot
online. If we can segue into that.
They talk in the Twitter feed before we
talk a lot of concerns about the super
weeds issue.
And it's the same idea that because
the roundup resistant technology has
been so successful for farmers that it's
what they overuse or they constantly use.
Now you see resistant weeds that invade
those fields that are resistant to the,
to the compound just like in Murcia.
Um,
and it's from using a
silver bullet technology.
The reason that that's a
problem is because the process
to come up with the next
generation of,
of solution is so arduous and so expensive
that we stick with the old technology
and we can't come up with something new
fast enough.
So the silver bullet technology,
this antibiotic that we've created
to deal with very specific infection
infections, it works. It's very
effective. So people use too much of it.
And because of that,
then it creates this medication resistant
strain of this and there's not enough
research done to fight off that medication
resistant strain of it because it's
so cost prohibitive to do the,
the work to create a medical,
a solution in the first place.
I think you're right.
And I think because the main issue,
remember go back to this idea that DNA
has natural mutation and natural problems
in this replication that give
new information in a cell.
And when you get that Murcia infection,
those cells are dividing every 20
minutes and you have millions of them.
And so the chance of one gaining the
ability to metabolize your antibiotics is
actually pretty good.
And when you're talking about billions
of cells over many generations,
that's where these things come from.
It's kind of funny because actually I
have an appointment on Wednesday morning
because something out of my lab,
I have something that looks like it
would be a potential ability to make the
next generation of mercy. We're
actually going to test it on Murcia. Um,
and something that I came up with plants
that that work process we're patenting
that makes new compounds that could be
very helpful against other creatures
outside of plants.
Okay. One of the things that
troubles people the most about,
um,
genetically modified things,
whether it's foods or whether it's animals
or anything that were messing around
with is the potential health risks
for the people that consume them.
That is a, the biggest problem.
Probably the biggest concern.
People were worried about cancer and
I've seen people tweet this at you.
You're a scientist but you're not an
oncologist. You're not a cancer expert.
You're not dealing with people
that get sick from certain things.
What evidence if any, is
there that medication? Uh,
or rather that I'm genetically modified
foods cause diseases in people cause
sickness and people. Yeah.
So this is the, is the
big issue. Let's start,
let's look at that backwards.
We've been growing these things in
eating them now for 18 years and studying
them a lot longer. 30 in terms of feeding
them to animals and everything else.
There has not been one case of one single
health effect that's been attributed
to this. Um, so it looks
like it's, I mean, in my
perspective, this has got to be,
these are some of the safest products
in the history of humans. Um,
and so we haven't seen anything
come out on the other side of this.
These are some of the most
tested crops in the world.
They start on the drawing board.
When you say you're going to take a
gene that from bacillus thuringiensis bt
gene, um, the thing that we use in,
it's actually called cry one a or whatever
it's called cry is the acronym. We,
we'll get into details.
You take this gene from the bacteria,
a bacterium that's used to
protect organic produce.
It works fine there and you take
that gene, which encodes the protein.
So it's the information from the cell
that allows the cell to create this
protein that targets the gut
of a lepidopteran insects.
So the Caterpillar of, of certain
birds, I'm sorry, not birds,
butterflies and moths. And uh,
now the plant makes this protein.
You can do the tests in vitro. You can
say, does this protein affects cells?
Does this protein effect animals?
When you feed it,
does it affect animals that you
feed in a tremendously high levels?
All those tests are done ad nauseum
and this is a natural protein that's
digested just like any other protein.
So is there any risk
at all of messing with food and
introducing antibiotics in food,
whether it's in the tree of uh, orange,
uh, and the, the, you know, is it,
is there any risk for
humans that consume that?
Absolutely. Absolutely. So
I have to answer it like a
scientist. Okay. All right.
You should, you can never say there's
no risk. And what we have to say is,
is that there's risk in
anything we do with genetics,
but we live in a time where we have
this unbelievable sensitivity to detect
something in a plant. We can look at
the metabolites that are, we can change.
Take a plant as it is,
add a gene and see what changes
with unbelievable resolution.
We can look at every single
protein. We can look at, uh,
every single gene that's
turned on or turned off.
We can look at where the gene
that's added is integrated.
We can understand metabolite profiles
are screened for specific carcinogens.
It is so easy right now to be able to
do a very careful assessment. You know,
I'm not in this ballgame to hurt people
and farmers aren't either. I mean,
they're there. They want to produce
wholesome food for people. Um,
my job as a public scientist is to use,
you know,
my ability to dream and think of ideas
and solutions for public benefit.
You've got tens of thousands
of me out there. Uh,
the person who found something wrong
would win a Nobel prize for it.
It's that much of a big deal.
If there was something wrong,
but to play devil's advocate,
sure.
If there was some sort of a reaction
and 1% of the people are less than what,
let's say one 10th of 1% of the people
that was deadly, but the company,
whether it's the big M or you know,
some other company is making
$1 billion a year off of this,
there would be a tremendous amount of
pressure to continue that money flowing.
Whether it's through,
I'm not saying it's through scientists.
I certainly wouldn't think it
would be through people like you,
but I would think that somewhere locked
away in some office high and a gun
turret is some evil asshole who owns a
giant steak of the corporation and he
says like, let them die if they eat
our colo care. It's not about money.
There's there's that.
That's the thought.
That's the big worry is that they
would hide it. Like you know,
the story of GM and the ignorant shit
condition switches. A great example.
They hid the fact that their ignition
switches were faulty and people died and
now they're being sued and it's horrible.
AndW th that's GM.
I mean they made the corvette, they
made the Bel Air. I mean this is,
how is this possible that people
that make Cadillac would be evil?
The first two letters of GMO?
No. Right. That's the conspiracy.
There's also GMT, which
is just a time. Yeah. Oh,
but the big deal is I, I,
and I, I agree with you.
Like when you start talking about money,
you can look at many
examples throughout history.
Whether you're talking cigarettes,
you're talking, you know,
where you see examples where money
has bought influence and sure.
But the beautiful part of this is that
science always wins and that you do find
out the truth comes out eventually.
And for these companies that are
producing these products, in my opinion,
and I'm not with these companies,
I can't tell you how they think they
stand to make a lot more money by making a
product that's thoroughly tested and
being clean with anything they would find
that would be problematic.
The other thing that's really
important here is that we know,
so when you say you're going to move,
let's say, uh, now we're gonna move,
talk about rice that you can
add a jeans too to make it, uh,
have high Beta carotene content, higher
vitamin eight, kg of golden rice and rice.
You know what those genes do
cause we studied them and carrots,
we understand the products they produce.
So there's a plausibility
aspect to this too,
that when we take this from carrot and put
it in rice, what's the difference? Now,
maybe there are some differences
and we can test for those,
but it starts out with the plausibility.
This isn't magic and Voodoo and
weird back room. My, you know, let's,
let's see what this lever does.
So the idea is that if you eat
carrots and rice together as food,
that's not much different than splicing
carrots and rice together and likely if
you're not allergic to
either one of those things,
you're not going to be allergic to this
rice though. You create. Absolutely.
And even if you are allergic to carrots,
taking one gene out of it that doesn't
have a immunological footprint.
And then on a antigenic
footprint in, in humans, uh,
like the jeans associate with Beta
carotene production don't have,
you'd be able to move those into rice
and have no problem. That's a good point.
The, the point of allergic,
because biodiversity is, is,
is a huge issue when you're
talking about foods in general,
that some people have
extremely different reactions,
whether it's to peanuts or to shellfish
or to a variety of things that most of
us enjoy.
But there's a few people that have severe
reactions is very same thing and this
is natural, completely,
totally natural. Um,
this is the question when it
comes to certain types of,
if you're dealing with these outliers,
if you're dealing with this one 10th
of 1% of the population where this,
this chemical reaction happens inside
their body, completely natural.
Um, we, should we stop
the production of peanuts?
Should we stop the production
of shellfish? I say, fuck no,
I love peanuts and I love shrimp.
But if you're dealing with a medication
that does the exact same thing and
reacts with the bio diversity of the exact
same percentage of the population and
could potentially be fatal like
shellfish, Ken, like peanuts can be fatal.
People have died from them. Um, what
do we do about that? Yeah, and this is,
this is actually the dilemma,
right? Well, it is, but it in a way,
it's a dilemma that this kind of
trenchgenic or GMO technology can solve.
Um,
what's really interesting about that is
we know what the food allergen proteins
are very well. Uh, you know that the
protein and peanuts, the proteins and soy,
the proteins in wheat that cause, um, uh,
that cause allergies and you can
turn those off and make them go away.
I'm using transgenic
technology and it's been done.
We have allergy free peanuts in the lab.
So there's peanuts that people have
commercially available. No, no,
because people are afraid of this
stuff. This is what kills me. Oh,
here we are making solutions.
We have,
there's wheat that still makes decent
bread where the gluten and Gilad or the
glutens are the gladden and the other
one lieutenant had been shut off. Um,
it still makes decent bread.
You'd have soy that you can
decreased specific allergens.
We know what the allergens are in food
and can turn them off and sometimes it
makes the plant a little different
or makes the product that, you know,
like the wheat when you
take out the major glutens,
it could change the bread structure,
but it still seems that the other ones
kind of ramp up to, to compensate.
So we can make a better product
using this technology. But we exist.
I mean, these things exist. Show
they're not, they're not, uh,
some wild fantasy of the future.
It's just that they would never be
deregulated because of the costs.
And because the industry is associated
with them, the peanut industry says,
no way.
We don't want people boycotting peanut
butter just so just have a few kids,
you know, have problems with
the allergy instead. To me,
that's a total injustice
that drives me crazy.
So you feel like this could
all be eradicated. Um,
but in nature,
these things are radicating and in a much
more disturbing way and nature of the
people that are allergic to peanuts
eat them and die and it's no longer
expressed in, in the genetics. That's,
that's the natural method of doing it.
The, the concern with any of these Jamal
genetic modifications to the lay person,
which I am most certainly lay,
um,
is that you are creating
something that shouldn't be there,
but you are creating something and you
don't want the consequences of this.
Like the wings of the butterfly and
the create the hurricane. You know,
that stupid fucking,
that shit drives me crazy.
That's not how goddamn hurricane
is made. Assholes. Water flies.
Don't make hurricanes. Shut
the fuck up. No, no, no. It's
a chain of events. It's no,
it's not. No. It's fucking weather
system. It has to do with the planet.
It has to do with the atmosphere.
It has to do with magnetics and
us do a lot of different shit.
It doesn't have to do with butterflies.
And See, that's exactly it.
We can sit around all day and talk about,
well,
what are the unintended consequences? And
you get this all the time. What are the,
what if? What if? What if,
and I can tell you that today on June 4th,
2015,
20,000 people are going to die
because of insufficient nutrition.
That's a problem that
I can tell you exists.
I can tell you that kids will have
allergic reactions to peanuts. Here.
I can tell you that there are 60 million,
uh,
citrus trees dying and these are
problems Monsanto is going to fix.
These are problems that I need to fix,
that guys like me,
people like me need to fix.
And we're being handcuffed by an
irrational fear of a good technology.
And do you think that this irrational
fear of a good technology comes about
because of what they consider
to be a greedy corporation?
So there's fear of greedy corporations
because we, like we talked about with GM,
I mean we could talk about,
we could talk about other
corporations that have moved into, uh,
countries that are poverty stricken
and taken over and abused their natural
environment.
And that we associate money with WWE,
especially corporate entities with this
idea of constantly needed to make more
money every year to justify what
they're doing to their shareholders.
I mean, this is the reality
of these businesses, these
infinite growth businesses.
And we associate them with callousness.
We associate them with not caring about
the people who work for them or the
people that they affect in the
environments that they build their plants.
And this is one of the main
concerns that people have,
is the diffusion of responsibility
that comes with being a part,
a single piece of a large entity that
has ultimately doing at least some bad,
right. No, I understand that. You know,
and as in the old punk rock guy and he
says that your, wait a minute, hold on.
Slow on. You were an old punk rock
guy. Yeah, I played in a, yeah,
I played the guitar for insane war
tomatoes for a, for awhile. Yeah.
Insane Ward tomatoes did send me,
sent me a little insane more tomatoes.
How did it go? Like, oh well our best ones
were called Iraq. You suck a rock. Yeah,
we had a, we did Tom called spirit
of Elvis where a giant dancing dead.
Elvis would come out on stage. And
uh, and uh, did you get the name? Uh,
I don't know. I know it
was, it was a, there was we,
while we were called dangling units, but
then someone already had that. So it was,
it's kind of spinal tap.
So we were in saint [inaudible] tomatoes.
We were the coolest band that no one
ever knew of. Fucking video. No. El Yeah,
there you go. High Rock. You
suck. Oh, that's just longer.
So in this you'll sure that's,
I live in an asshole.
I like how you didn't say the word
cause you're respectable now. Well,
I am a professor. I know. This'll
do. What did you do in this band?
I played guitar for maybe the first few
years and then switched over to bass.
Did you sing it all?
Uh,
I think you can hear me up right here.
I do.
I have a little thing here
coming up in a second here.
Kind of Motorhead he before. Well,
not bad. This is good workout music.
This is me here
where you jumped in there and then here.
That's you. Yeah, that was
me. What year was this?
No, this was a 1989 maybe 88 how old
were you back then? Uh, I don't know.
22 I was 20. 22 how old are
you now? 48 yeah. So we,
and we played all over the place.
We did a lot in, uh, in Wisconsin.
We were real big and we had
the costumes we had. I'm like,
I had a Gene Simmons outfit that I wore
with gigantic high shoes and the guy who
was the singer dressed as a tomato and
lit himself on fire and it was before
great white, um, wow. Uh, all
homemade gas pyrotechnic show,
she was fantastic. And the eight
people that came to see us loved it.
You got eight,
we've got eight and they were all put in.
The best part was we would pound our
audience with uh, produce at the end.
We throw tomatoes at him. Will you will
involve in, in agriculture back then?
Um, not really. I was, I see. I
haven't even been until very recently.
I was a basic scientist.
I studied the nuts and bolts of DNA
and nuts and bolts of plant physiology.
And um, but at this time,
if you're 22 back then,
you presumably had gone to
college already. And were
you studying agriculturally?
What was the connection to tomatoes and
people throwing vegetables at you? Oh,
it was that just luck?
No,
just coincidentally it was cheaper than
throwing jars of pickles was and, and uh,
but you know what I'm saying?
Produce was involved in your,
even in your punk rock. So we've
gone full circle. Yeah. It's odd.
I didn't have an egg. That's
a coincidence. More than,
because it's a funny one,
isn't it? That's a good thing. I didn't
want to study reproductive physiology,
I guess, you know, throw ovaries at the,
but we'd be the best thing that could
throw, I would think. Dick's. Yeah,
but, but going back to answer your
question, but, so, so the guy in me who,
who doesn't, who hates his cable
company, who hates his, you know,
the people who sell them
gas, all that stuff. Um,
I look at companies like Monsanto and
others as being the way that farmers who
are my real clients are enabled. And, uh,
so whether or not I like who
they're buying it from, there,
the folks who are the ultimate
beneficiaries of the technology.
And the other thing that's really, um, uh,
and so the other exciting thing for
me is when the small companies can use
something like GMO technology
to gain a unique market niche,
like a Oakenoggen specialty fruits.
They make this apple that doesn't turn
Brown when you cut it and they have four
full time employees. Are they
from Oregon? They're from um,
Washington State Canada. Is that, what
is Oakenoggen mean? Does that, uh,
a location or an Indian word?
Yeah, I think it's both. I think
it's uh, but they, um, they grow,
they have this apple that when you cut
it doesn't Brown, which is a great trait.
It uses an apple gene to turn off
an apple gene and a, in other words,
the GMO modification puts this gene
in backwards so it shuts off the,
in the innate con, uh, construct
DNA a gene. It turns off that gene.
And then, uh, the apple
doesn't Brown when you cut it,
which is a great trait if you want to
have apples and process products or apples
as, you know, sliced apples in bags or
whatever. Uh, four full time employees.
So my whole thing is go ahead and hit
your Monsanto march against him, whatever.
I don't care.
But do you realize that when you dress
like a B and lay on the ground and go
into convulsions and say that
this is biotechnology that's bad,
that now you're affecting the
people who would buy that apple,
the people who I would come
up with a solution for,
for the the people who need bananas and
Uganda or the people who eat rice and
southeast Asia that needed more
nutritious rice that by mixing together
biotechnology and agriculture and
conflating that with companies and things
companies did or didn't do,
you automatically take technology out
of the hands of the people who in the
people in the solutions that we care
about how things like the environment,
things like farmers, things like
the needy. We have those solutions.
And that's the thing that just by the, by
the Monsanto phobia is dangerous. Well,
I think a good part of what the problem
is, it can be attributed to the,
the idea of people not being responsible
for actions because they're part of a
collective group being concur.
Completely unnatural.
And I think that if people had actual PR,
if the idea of a corporation was,
uh,
was not that that corporation would
be immune to the actual people being
involved in that corporation wouldn't be
immune to responsibility for everything
that the corporation does. And it's one
of the reasons why businesses get an LLC,
right? Uh, limited,
whatever it is, corporation,
the idea is to protect you somehow
or another creates some sort of legal
definition of you that's different
than you outside of a corporation,
which is weird. You know,
it's like people, you're,
you're a fucking dude. Okay?
If you're a dude, if you call yourself
Kevin Folta Llc, I'm still talking to you,
man. You're right here you
sit. You're the same guy.
But if you do something under
the guise of your corporation,
there's a completely different legal
ramification than if you do something on
your own, like bankruptcy,
things on those lines.
You're not as responsible for debts.
I think that might be the problem though.
The problem might be like,
I know that you're a decent person and a
nice person and I know that what you're
trying to do is noble and just and
true and in the vein of science,
I I 100% believe that.
I think that what people worried about
is when someone like you gets to working
for some big giant group.
This is why people keep saying that
you're some sort of a shell or that other
foot,
let's say take you out of the equation,
but other folks that are working for
Monsanto, they're doing and they're money,
but the corporations give a fuck about
people. That's what we have to stop.
We have to stop this idea that a bunch
of people together collectively can do
something that's really unethical and
they can do it and ruined in natural
environments and not be
responsible like the BP oil spill.
I mean everybody knows there was all
kinds of fuckery and shenanigans that went
on to protect the people that were
involved from that BP oil scandal.
Those people that had been profiting in
insane sacrilegious amounts of money for
a long period of time.
When it came time to pony up that money
and clean that fucking mess up, boy,
did things get weird?
You know,
boy did things get legal and complicated
and people were giving nondisclosures
to sign to make exorbitant monies for
clean up and people were paid off and
there was a lot of fuckery involved.
That is what people worry about when
it comes to genetically modified foods.
What we're worried about is the,
the method of action that
corporations have been proven to take.
That is to protect the
corporation as a it, as a unit,
and to do so an act collectively in
a way that you would never act as an
individual. No, I agree Joe.
But I guarantee you that 90% of the
people that went to march against Monsanto
drove a car that used oil that may,
it came out of a BP. Well, sure.
And so here's an example though. You
know, go ahead. Hate a corporation,
but they're still using the products
and uh, and no one's trying to shut off.
No one's going to the gas station and
knocking the pump out of my hand when I
would go to stick it in my car.
Yet there are people who would feel very
comfortable depriving farmers have the
right to buy the seeds that they
choose. And so for, to me, again,
if there's a social business issue
here that needs to be remedied,
there's gotta be another mechanism to do
that. And I'm fine with that. Go ahead.
Hate any company you want. All I'm
saying is, let's not talk about that.
It's not put out the, the bullshit
that says that Gmos caused cancer.
Gmos are causing autism. That the uh, uh,
the herbicides associated with it are
cause autism. All of that is crazy talk.
That takes us out of our
problem solving mode.
It distracts from what the good
things that we can do with technology.
What is collective evolution.com?
Is that a,
is that a reputable website? Not so
much there, there one that has a, they,
they're also one that isn't
really, uh, excited about, uh,
biotechnology and other corporate
stuff. I mean like nation, a change.
There's a whole bunch of them and I read
those things and I would say 50 to 60%
of the stuff. I'm right there with Ya.
You know, I'm a politically a lefty.
I'm a American college professor. You
know, I, um, I love seeing social justice.
I love seeing a social progress.
I love those kinds of,
I mean it's stuff that I fight for,
but these are examples where I see the
technology that can actually enhance
those things and that we can wrestle
it away from the big corporations if we
only stopped making a fabricating
information about them. Yeah.
Well obviously this doesn't have anything
to do with social justice or anything.
Um, but there, there's this study linking
Gmos to cancer, liver, kidney damage
and severe hormonal disruption,
disruption in rats. Right? Uh,
that was one of the collective evolution
had written a story about, well,
they covered it just like
everyone else did. And what is,
what was the study and what,
what's wrong with the study?
I think they're mixing together
two different studies there. Um,
but the main one was one done by Sara
Leeny in 2012 and they used a limited
number of rats,
which are called Spragg Dawley rats,
the rats that are good cancer models
because they're prone to cancers.
And so as you're testing
different compounds against them,
you'll have a model which is a at
least susceptible to developing tumors.
And so if you're testing the, the
toxicity of different compound compounds,
you would use this rat strain. The problem
is that by two years into the study,
75% of the rats have,
or 77% have tumors.
So Sara Leeny chose this
to do a two year study.
He showed that the rats got tumors and
in in the paper they even show in the
table two in the control aisle that
even the controls got tumors look at the
same amount of tumors. Well, they,
it statistically, yes, I mean they,
they showed fewer. But you know,
when they talk about like, you know,
they talk about five versus
eight versus nine, um,
statistically the numbers were too
small to say that that was a significant
difference. So when you
say five, eight or nine,
you mean percent or number rod
and out of how many? 20. Okay.
So that could be just an issue with
the particular group of rats you had as
opposed to you would have to do a much
larger study to get a good baseline.
Is that what he was in
the statistical noise?
So 20 rats seems like a real
low number to test things.
Almost 200 overall.
But it was broken into groups for this.
But the main thing in this though and the
place that really colors it for me and
I don't know, do you have the picture
of the lumpy rats on your screen? No,
I'm sure it's in your show. Know the
famous picture of the three Loci rats. Um,
note that the author's show,
three rats, one that got GMO food,
one that got roundup, one that got GMO
food plus roundup and they call it GM.
Oh by the way, which scientists would
never do. We'd put in the transgene name,
the neglect to show you the
control rat edge control.
Rocco fucked up too. Well, insignificant
number of them did. But if you show us,
but I can, how do they, how do
they, what do they do, you know,
how do they show that picture of these
grants that are grotesquely malformed?
Which if my lab rats go to
that, yeah. There they are.
If my lab let rats get to that stage
or any, any lab in the United States,
let their rats get to that stage,
they'd be shutdown. That's animal abuse,
um, to, it's inhumane treatment
of animals. Is it? Well, I mean,
that's something that I feel
pretty strongly against. I, I,
I really severely disliked the idea of
testing things on animals in the first
place.
But it seems that that's where a lot of
the big improvements in medicine have
come from. It's a real
moral dilemma. I mean, I
think using animals, especially
intelligent animals, like I'm, I'm,
I saw a fucking seaworld
commercial this morning.
They made me want to throw a Mug at my
TV and they were talking about how happy
these whales are in a fucking
swimming pool and this guy's like,
our whales are happy and we love
them. Like, fuck you. You do.
We haven't stolen a whale from
its family and over 30 years.
It's like a slave colony telling you
how these people been born. Slaves.
Don't worry about it. They're happy
being slaves. We loved them here.
If you had that exact same Goddamn
seaworld commercial and you had it about
human beings,
you would think those people would be
thought of as some of the most evil Fox on
the planet. But they don't
think of Orcas as human beings.
Even though we'll have a cerebral cortex,
a 40% larger than a human beings,
even though they have dialects,
they have a bunch of different
words for all sorts of things.
And we didn't even understand
what they're saying.
They have super complex methods of
communication. They're very human.
Like we,
they deals don't alter their environment.
So because they don't all turn their
environment and they can't smile at us,
you don't have articulating lips.
We choose to think of them
as being inferior to us.
And it's acceptable to have them in
a fucking swimming pool, you know?
And I think that's dark.
And I think that's really evil.
And I think one day when we figure out
a way to interpret what they're saying
and have like a Google translate for
killer whales, it's going to be a mess.
Seaworld, they're going to go to jail
immediately. I don't even wanna watch him,
man. It's fucking horrible. We love them.
Fuck you. You do. I don't love them.
If you love them and they were people,
you'd let them go.
I figure out a way to let them go.
You fucks.
I even look at zoos when I go to
zoos and you'll see that Cheetah,
this damn thing is supposed to be running
75 miles an hour after an antelope and
it's sitting there laying on a shelf
exam and all its reward system.
It's genetic reward systems are there.
They're not satisfied like a,
like a lion killed a woman and the woman
who is a game of Thrones expert editor
to hear about this,
she was at a surf park and the
fucking hard irony of it is she's a
conservationist.
She loves these animals and she,
she wanted to take photos of them and
she wants to protect them from poachers
and she left the window, open the fucking
lion. God her jumped in the cage, uh,
jumped into the car and pulled her out
and killed her in front of everybody.
And it's, it's, it's horrible.
It's horrible, horrible thing.
But that's what lions do. I mean,
that is their reward system.
That's why they're here in 2015,
they have a Predator prey reward system.
That reward system isn't being recognized
at all in zoos. That's one thing.
One aspect of their life.
It is probably as satisfying and is
primal is intercourses to them and they're
not being allowed to express it. And
that's a fucked up thing. I mean,
zoos are,
I don't care what anybody says,
they're doing all this great
work to do all this great work.
They're doing it the wrong way. They're
doing it the wrong way. You know,
it's just, you can't lock a monkey in a
fucking cage and people just stare at it.
That's gotta be torture for that
little thing. There's a monkey had,
I think it was the Colorado,
the
one that I think it was Colorado.
I forgot which is do,
it might've been the one in Griffith Park,
but whatever the fuck it is,
there's a monkey that was howling like a,
a like a mad man.
He was just holding onto his cage going
just
screaming into the night.
And you're like telling me that's any
different than some guy in a psych ward
who's trapped in aliens with giant fucking
watermelon sized eyes are staring at
them all day. How is that any
different? It's not, it's not. I agree.
I mean I have a hard time with, especially
with mammals, like I can't, I don't,
I choose not to get involved in
that. I know there's, uh, you know,
educational aspects of zoological
terror. Um, and you know,
turtles. Maybe I don't freak out so much
about, you don't seem to give a fuck. Oh,
they kind of like it. I mean, you know,
it's like a food water brings or that,
that doesn't seem to get too weird,
but I can get it to chimps and shit.
Even big cats.
You just see those things that bears,
I had a joke about it
though that some animals,
the zoo doesn't seem to bother and lecture
graphs to Raf don't seem to mind at
all.
Like they let them feed babies because
the joke was that their drafts to like
another day with no lions and the like,
if somebody came up to a giraffe
and said, listen man, um,
I'm going to give you free food, there's
going to be no predators whatsoever,
but you can't walk as far.
They'd be like, fuck yeah,
let's do this. Because it's the giraffes
life is goddamn terrifying all day.
So for giraffes, the zoo doesn't
really seem to bug them. Like,
especially if you go to like San Diego,
which has an awesome wildlife park,
it's huge.
Like as far as zoos grow,
that places top of the food chain because
that place gives them enormous spaces.
But again, the predators aren't allowed
to express being a predator. You know, we,
there was an Iraqi zoo footage,
see if you could find this.
They let it go loose and an Iraqi zoo
and this is how they feed their lions and
soldiers.
This is how soldiers film this at the
beginning of the war and they just,
they just have a goat and the goat.
It's fucking Triassic park.
The goat is just a lead out of this
gate and the goat walks up and the lions
realize that the goat
is there and then wound.
They're all on them and they
tear this fucker apart. Yeah.
That's how zoos are supposed to be.
That's what his God damn zoos should be.
What we're doing is bullshit. You
give them a plate of meat. You know,
we're at a zoo, Portugal on. My wife
and I were there a few years ago.
I was there for a conference and we went
to their zoo. It's a really nice zoo.
The zoo in Lisbon and one of the monkeys,
you know the big cage full of monkeys,
like a million of them in there.
I was like 30 or 40 monkeys in one cage
and then one of them comes out between
the bars and starts walking around.
They just came out of the cage
while walking around. And you know,
it was pretty funny because
all the parents are letting
their kids touch it and
stuff. Jesus Christ, bad
bed, primate decision,
you know that's a sh. Yeah, you're the
dummy, not the monkey. No, here it is.
Look at this. These, these goats,
they just opened the door and they let
him out and then they released the lines.
They open this gate and the
lines just come Sharjah and then,
cause they know exactly what the
fuck is going on. And you know, Eh,
I remember people watching
it saying that it's cruel.
This,
the reason why you think it's cruel is
because we have been sheltered in some
weird way to think that our way of
living should be imposed on animals.
And that's crazy.
That's crazy thinking.
The idea that you should give a look at
this, the lines just jump out and boom,
they take these goats
down and they all jump in.
They all know what they're doing.
This is what they do every
day and this is how they eat.
But the idea that this is somehow brutal,
God dammit,
this is what it's called being a cat.
This is what cats do.
What you're doing is brutal by
giving them pre cooked meat.
They're not allowing them
to express this charge.
They must get the bond and community
that they generate together because of
killing and surviving
off that kill together.
Human beings have it and I guarantee
that lions have that as well.
And you're not allowing them
to bond in the same way.
So part of establishing the pecking
order in the communities as well,
who is the better hunter? Learn from
that hunter. Look how he bites that neck.
You know, they all, they all
learn from each other. They, they,
the mothers teach the babies how to fight.
They teach them at a trip things
and chase things. How do they,
they play with each other. You know, they,
they trip each other just like
they want a trip game and we don't,
we don't allow that.
It's fuck
now nature is cruel. I mean it's
the way it, the way it works,
it's more cruel to not let
them express their nature.
This idea that you feeding them an animal
that somebody killed nowhere near the
cat is somehow or another more ethical
than letting the animal kill the cat or
the cat kill the animal.
It's true. It's just fucking
idiotic. It's a crazy picture.
This video rather, it's just,
that's what they do, man. Well,
don't say the Iraqi's never
gave us anything and that
they gave us a little bit
of that.
But do you think that there is,
there's an ethical way to do tests on
animals that would satisfy everybody
almost? Is there a way, I mean, what, what
ethical way would there even be? Yeah,
I think, well, it then, and
I think we have to go back,
and this isn't my area by any stretch,
but animal testing is a really important
part of biology and really important
part of pharmacology.
Um,
when you look at how animals are
used as drug models, like round,
right now we have,
we have animals like mice that express
or don't express a gene associated with
brain function that we know is
impaired say with als in humans.
So essentially we have these
mice that will develop als.
So now you can use compounds to
see what solves that problem.
You can build these models or f cancer
models are many in animals where you have
these animals that are predisposed to
specific kinds of cancers or ailments that
now allow us to do testifying them.
And I think that's a really
important role for this, that, uh,
that animals can help us identify
problems that help the human condition,
which then can help us help animals.
Is there a way to do it though
that's going to make everybody happy?
I don't think there is one of those things
we have to say we're better than you.
Well, or, or that we have to say that
these are a, that this is a, it's just
like when we raise animals to eat them, I
guess. I mean, we're, uh, it, it's, it's,
there's a purpose for these animals
that we bring them into our provision.
We raised them humanely
and we are various,
and these animals that are in these drug
experiments by definition have to be
very carefully, uh, um,
uh, they have to be happy.
They have to be as happy as you can be in,
you know,
as a rat in a cage that happy well because
there's physiology that's involved.
And if you start seeing,
if you have rats that are living in
conditions that are subpar or animals that
are mistreated,
they won't give you adequate results from
your experiments that you need to have
incredible control with animals
that are well cared for and a,
and give you a solid physiological
baseline where the only way,
the only information being
introduced is through your treatment.
Do you know, uh, being a speciesist is,
have you ever been accused
of being a speciesist?
I got a feeling I will be shortly.
This is speciesist thinking the
thinking that you and human life is more
important than other animals.
Yeah. No, it it,
I don't know if that's necessarily
the case that were more important,
but we certainly have more faculties to
be able to control the hours outcomes
of certain situations,
but of rats were smarter than us
then decided to do tests on humans.
It would really suck, wouldn't
it? So screw them, let's,
we're not very smart, right?
I mean, we're very smart
for, for other animals,
but we're not very smart in terms of,
there's a lot of shit that human
beings do that we probably shouldn't do
collectively, like pollution, destruction
of the environment, so on, so forth,
proliferation of nuclear
weapons that that's not smart.
There's a lot of stupid shit that we do.
So I think that we're incredibly
smart for being an animal,
but we're not necessarily smart in
terms of the universal potential of
intelligent life. We're not,
we're idiots. That's why,
I mean it's like there's a million fucking
arguments you could make all day long.
The gay marriage thing, the
marijuana thing, the war thing,
there's just so many
stupid contradictions.
The way human beings exist
and live their lives.
If there was something that was
far more intelligent than not.
It's like as intelligent as we are to
pigs or as we are to things that we think
are smart, like dogs are fairly smart.
What come test would they do to us?
You know,
you ever think of that doesn't know.
I never really think about that very much.
I guess the analyst Lady sees this.
Yeah.
There's only one way to get that smart.
You've got to fucking keep fucking
pink pigs and let the coolant,
I think that he wouldn't needles and
shit. The main idea is that we've, uh,
we've evolved as a species for a long
time away from our common ancestors.
You know,
the other primate ancestors because of
our ability to control situations and
because we make decisions that ended
more favorable outcomes for whatever
reasons, those are for us.
And so even though we're not,
even though we do a lot of dumb stuff,
and I'm with you on that,
I think we do an awful
lot of smart stuff too.
And I think the human capacity to create
change that's favorable for humans is,
is immense.
Maybe you can do your own documentary.
You know how Al Gore had that one,
the inconvenient truth about uncomfortable
truth and the uncomfortable truth
being you got to crack some eggs to
make an omelet and a, there's a lot,
there's a lot going on and try to keep
human beings alive and sometimes you have
to make a decision. I forgot who
Nick Depaulo, one of my buddies,
hilarious standup comedian had some joke,
I don't want to fuck the joke up,
but it was about, uh, doing tests on a
monkey to find, you know, to cure aids.
And it was fucking hilarious.
But he is, I don't, I don't,
I don't remember how the joke went,
but it was something about battery
cables and it was very funny.
But the idea of being,
it's like, yeah, yeah.
I'm saying I'm more
important than a monkey.
I'm saying my mom who's dying of
cancer is more important than a rabbit.
I'm saying that, I'm saying that a rat
is not as important as my children.
I said it. Sorry, I'm a
speciesist. No. But, and, and,
and I think that human progress has
shown that sometimes the pendulum swings
swings a little bit too far the other way,
you know, we can think of examples. Um,
but yeah, as soon as, again,
as soon as you look at instead of whether
it's money or the results being more
important than the actions
of the individual and the
actions of the individual
not being ethical, not that's not
important. What's important as a results,
that's when we run into
problems. But that's, and so
even the circle it back then,
you know,
this is why being a scientist is so cool
is because I'm bound by data and I'm
bound by a hypothesis that I test
using the best available tools.
And being a public scientist is really
cool that the people who choose to do
this like me,
and there's a lot of them in this country.
We are really operating in the public's
trust, in the public's best interest.
And I think that when we see,
um, uh, unethical behavior,
when we see, um, um, let's say, uh,
interpretations of data, which suggests
that maybe we're going the wrong way,
these things are caught in
the peer review process.
These things are caught when our grants
are evaluated and they're debated in the
scientific literature.
And so when we making steps in progress,
these are very careful
guarded, um, uh, uh,
reviewed rereviewed steps
that we're doing as,
as a public science enterprise.
And this is what's why I
wish we had more support. Um,
I'm not here to complain about that.
Um, I wish we, and that, you know,
people say that, you know, oh, you're
from Monsanto and we, you know, we're,
we get nothing compared to what they
have. I mean, we're a university,
we get something like 3% of our
support for corporate entities.
Everything else comes from grants
that we go out and get. And so this,
this is what's so important about having
an active public science enterprises to
keep all that other stuff in check.
I think it's also important to try to
understand the whole process that's
involved in,
in science that the average person
who doesn't have background in it,
the average person who didn't take
science other than the classes where we
dissected frogs and high school, it's,
there are ignorant of the process there.
You know,
the process that creates this data and,
and they don't understand where we are,
where we come from and what we go
through. Um, if you talk to anybody,
they'll tell you, well, you know,
universities are just paid off by
the companies and the companies,
but somehow that sometimes that's
the case, right? Well we'll,
universities do have contracts
frequently with companies. Um,
it happens all the time, but that's
because we're the experts in other fields.
It's a much bigger issue financially.
Like it's been a big issue in the setting
of regulations for the stock market
and things like that the
people did at university.
You know what I'm
talking about? Those, uh,
economics professors who have made
recommendations and then wound up getting
these huge jobs with the banks after
it was over for millions of dollars.
And that's wrong too though.
I think what's really important
though is that a lot of the companies,
pharmaceutical companies will
come to a medical school and say,
we need you to do this clinical
trial because you are the experts.
You're the ones who know this. We
trust you. And if it doesn't work,
you give better. Tell us no one's
giving us money to make them happy.
No one's telling me.
And this,
this one pisses me off all
the time because out of
everybody you meet in science,
you know,
there's so many of us that really do
claim to have integrity as a first level.
Um, I would never do something because
the company told me to do it or because a
company paid me to do it. The punk
rock and you would not, that's right.
You fight that power. Oh, I fight the
power. No, because, because seriously,
at the end of the day, you know,
I'm not a religious guy. I'm not,
I don't believe that there's some
great reward for me. Um, you know,
what I'm leaving here is, is a, a
legacy, you know, like a product of,
of my work and my record and
I don't want that tarnish.
I believe you 100% and I'm, I'm,
I'm certainly not questioning that.
I want to tell everybody if you,
the thing I was saying about
mathematics professors,
you should watch a documentary
called inside job or an inside job.
It's all about the financial crash. It's
fantastic. It's really, really, really,
really well done. Documents
that, but people aren't
worried about people like you.
You seem to be a great guy. What they're
worried about is evil scientists.
That's what fucks up every science fiction
movie. Did you see 28 days later, no,
28 days later and one of the greatest
Zombie movies in the history of the known
universe.
My personal favorite starts out because
of a medication that was created,
something called rage.
I forget what,
why they created it for
soldiers or something like that.
It infects these chimps and then
these chips get it. They bite people,
the people get it, and then be the
Zombie outbreak takes over the world.
And kills everybody except for a few cool
human caterpillar. Yeah. Well this, um,
that's different. But this a, I think
you mean senopy human centipede. Yeah.
Don't watch that. Don't, that's
different. Um, now this is a,
this is a fucking awesome movie. Human
centipede was a goof science, Fun,
evil science, but he was an evil
sign. Yeah, that's a good point.
But the 28 days later was
about a medication that
they had intended for human
beings and it went terribly wrong.
Well that's,
that's the kind of scientist
that people were worrying about.
People were worried about the evil
people that are creating. I mean, look,
there have been scientists that have
created a weaponized drugs or weaponized a
biological weapons rather,
that they can use on people's,
you know, certain, I mean,
those are created by scientists like
poisons that have killed untold numbers of
people were also created by scientists.
So absolutely not just guys like you were
worried that people are worried about
people that are way fucking smarter than
them that might be plotting some evil
shit. Yeah, that's happened. Well,
it's happening. And then you look at,
people always bring up in the GMO
discussion. Agent Orange, yes.
Which is an herbicide called two,
four D and a number of herbicides were
combined and there was this whole rainbow
of herbicides. It call your agent Ballou
agent Green Agent Orange was this two,
four d stuff, two, four, five t there
they're what they call synthetic auxins.
They make plants grow to death basically.
And the government was able to weaponize
a legitimate product for a warfare and
nothing to do with an evil
scientists necessarily,
but it was implementation potentially by
people who had an agenda to be able to,
uh, expose an enemy in
a jungle atmosphere. Um,
along with the purification of those
products. Two, four, five t, um,
was the main one was dioxin,
which is what kit which would
killed people in her arms, harmed,
harmed our own soldiers.
That is one of the scariest things about
human beings that were willing to kill
your whole forest to find you just
stop and think of how fucked that is.
We're looking for a man. We can't
find them. We're going to kill.
Everything was going to kill every
fucking tree, every Bush, everything.
We're going to kill the whole forest and
flush them out. Yeah. The daisy cutter,
you know, basically, you know
the chemical daisy cutter. God,
that's so crazy that someone,
okay. Dot. Someone said, yeah,
you can ruin the entire ecosystem.
Yeah.
Go and go there and kill everything that
moves so that our boys can go in there
and kill the people that are hiding in it.
But this was a,
but this is an an an interesting example
that here you had something that a
rather a really great scientist came up
with. Arthur Gauston came up with two,
four, five, two, four d to control
plant growth and control weeds.
And it's a relatively useful
compound that we've had for 70 years.
But yet people will say, you're
using agent orange on corn. You know,
we're not using agent orange.
Here's a,
it's a growth regulator that was part
of Agent Orange that humans decided to
weaponize against other
humans. So the, that was,
that was the created first. And then
human beings took this and said, well,
there's some sort of a
weaponized application of this
very beneficial discovery.
Right. And then in, in a,
in a compound that can be used safely
in an agricultural context and has been
since the 1940s,
see,
against not people worrying about the
scientists are worried about the evil
people that control the scientists and
take that stuff and turn it into this and
then spray it in Vietnam. Yeah. If it, but
we can't go forward worrying about the,
about the small number of evil people
that might be out there cause they're
going to do it there.
You know,
there's always going to be some
guy who finds a way to, to,
so Obama knew his underwear,
but that doesn't mean we
outlaw underpants. You know,
we have to, we could.
Um, but, but the idea is,
is that we need to think about what the
science allows us to do and not about
the,
I mean,
certainly be aware of malevolent uses.
Um,
people could genetically
engineer viruses and I,
I believe I've heard about the
Russians doing the sit back in the,
during the Cold War days to,
uh,
say engineer a antibody that
would attack Human Myelin,
which is the stuff that covers your nerves
so that you could essentially infect
people with a virus that would
kill them because of paralyze them.
These kinds of things were discussed
and biological agents and biological
weaponry is there,
but as it has power in that dimension,
I think that the main
conversation here is,
is really how do we take the same
technology and use it for good?
Essentially what we're talking about is
really what I was saying before is that
I think a lot of your hate comes from
people that are terrified that they don't
understand what's going on.
You know, and that's me. I've,
I've been into that, but I asked a lot
of questions and I, I trust you. So I go,
all right, it seems to make
sense. But realistically,
when you're talking to me
about the expressions of
genes, my brain has just gone.
Those are a bunch of noises that
represents some things I don't totally
understand. Well, let's talk, well,
let's talk about things that we can make
talk about. No, no, no, no, no, no idea.
Not saying that there's anything
wrong with it. I, I'm, I'm, I'm,
I guess I'm kind of giving
you an opportunity to say
what are things that you
care about that I could fix or
scientists could fix? Like what are some,
what are some concerns
about food that you, um,
the interview interviewee becomes
the interviewer. Um, what,
what are some things that you would worry
about in terms of food or maybe food
abundance or, you know,
what would you like to,
abundance is always a big
concern for everybody,
especially when you look at parts
of the world where you see these.
Like I have a good friend named Justin
wren. He comes on the podcast and he, uh,
used to fight in the UFC and now he
works in the Congo building wells.
He's an amazing God. And he does this
thing called fight for the forgotten.
And he goes to the Congo and he did it
with some money that viewers generated to,
they built a bunch of wells that are
listeners of the podcast generated through
bitcoin and then I matched the
donation and he built these wells.
He's just this guy, guys dedicated
his whole time to doing that,
to give these people
clean water like that.
I think maybe that's not even
scientific other than the ability to,
somebody obviously had to invent these
water pumps and filters and figure out
how to make these, these wells
portable and functional. The,
that's really what needs to be done.
We need to figure out a way to take the
worst parts of the world and bring them
to a higher standard of living and give
people the opportunity to not live on
dirt floors with a drinking muddy
puddle water. Yeah. You know,
I mean the fact that that it takes a guy
like Justin to go down to the Congo and
dedicate his life to that and a bunch
of other brave people that are doing the
exact same thing,
but that country's never talk about it.
They'll talk about all sorts of issues
that are going on in the environment,
all sorts of things about the,
what happens if the ocean rises
and we lose Malibu? You know,
like everybody's freaking out,
but no one's freaking out about
these poor babies with distended
bellies because they're
filled with parasites.
This is a huge human issue and if
they were white people that live,
they looked like they were from
Norway and this was their problem.
If they were all beautiful people that
live over there from the game of Thrones
and they all had distended bellies,
everybody would be freaking out and they
want to go over there and save those
folks. And it's, it's,
it's one of the more disturbing and sad
or aspects of humanity. I don't know.
I mean, science can help
certainly with medication,
with antibiotics and antiviral drugs to
help these people that have all these
parasitic infections,
which is incredibly rare in these tropical
rich jungle environment. You know,
that's,
I think what would be the thing that I
would look forward to the most depicts
the world and stop this whole
killing other people. Shit.
Let me, let me, this is really a perfect
example. I'm glad you brought that up.
The the especially with
Uganda, with Congo, um,
because Uganda is the one who I just
met a scientist this weekend and uh,
he's a a plant breeder
by trade who he said,
I'm here in the United States. Everybody
is screaming that they want choice,
they want GMO versus non Gmo.
He says over by us,
we just want food and a very sincere man
who is desperate for solutions for his
country and I'm going to work with him
and there's three things that could
really help Uganda right now and that
are actively on the ground there.
Three solutions for problems they have,
they have something like 70% of their
calories come from or carbohydrate
calories come from bananas and a,
not like bananas we have,
but African bananas and bananas
get to have two problems.
One of them bill to
bacterial pathogen problems.
They get what's called does anthem
Mona's they get Phytopthora.
There are genetic engineering solutions
that are in place that can solve both of
those problems.
There's also an issue that people
there have vitamin a deficiency.
So there are going blind along
this golden rice line. Um,
you're looking at 250 million to
500 million blindness as a year. Um,
and most of it and kids and
half of them die within a year.
And it's all because of a
vitamin deficiency because
of vitamin a deficiency.
And now they have bananas that have
the genes from a banana that produces
vitamin a that's kind of
agriculturally useless,
but they moved those into the
production banana from the Congo.
And this is from Uganda.
And this is a,
a gates foundation sponsored stuff.
And other people have done this.
So now they have a banana that produces
vitamin A or B, well Beta carotene,
which is converted to vitamin A and then,
um,
it resistant to the two main diseases.
And it can't be used.
And you've got Greenpeace and other
activist organizations on the ground.
They're fighting it and they're telling
people that this is just the westerners
coming in to take over and give you the
food and the technology they reject.
I'm saying that will cause sterility.
Who's resisting like this, whose,
whose these are,
these are very wealthy western funded
organizations that are opposed to genetic
modification.
They know that if you Ganda Develops
these products and is allowed to give them
to their people and they solve a problem
that now the house of cards in the
Western world falls
down. So you really believe that there's
a conspiracy to keep these bananas out
because if the bananas
go through and do good,
which they think with you think they
will for sure the science says they will
and that these people
think it will as well.
And we'll open the door genetic modified
foods going into these countries and
they'll lose the battle. So because
of that, they're willing to sacrifice.
He's people getting this vitamin a rich
banana. It's not a conspiracy. It's,
if that sounds very conspiratorial, it's
true. It's, it's clear as day these, uh,
and, and uh, in China they tell
people that it will cause infertility.
Well that is a conspiracy.
When you agree, well,
I guess a conspiracy as
inspires and arrangement of it,
I guess that is a concern. It's unethical
and it's untrue. Right? Um, but it's,
it's something that is, um,
yeah, and it, but it's a,
it's very transparent is
what I guess I'm going for.
This isn't some secret
clandestine operation.
This is something that is
very well understood that
this is what they're doing.
But to play devil's advocate,
isn't it possible that they really
truly are concerned that a company like
Monsanto would get their monetary hooks
into a country and start fucking around
there and doing a bunch of unethical shit?
Sure.
That's what they're worried about.
And I think that's something
that they would be worried about.
But let's not throw the baby out with
the bath water. Well, no, let's not.
Let's not, uh, accept
phantom fears for real fears.
We got people that need problems
and let's not say, well,
maybe Monsanto will be involved,
so let's not allow it. Um,
let's let them use the best technology.
And what have you tried to license this
technology and profit from their use of
it? No, these are, these have,
it's so funny about this is that these
are laboratories there that said we want
biotechnology and they're developing their
own labs and their own stuff. Um, this,
uh,
professor I met this weekend,
I'm going to go there next year to help
him set up a lab to grow coffee in,
in a culture. I'm not GMO coffee,
which may be an interesting idea,
but their issue is,
is that they can make a tremendous amount
of money by growing coffee for farmers
or farmers can grow coffee and
have a very profitable operation,
but you can't grow enough plants of the
types that are resistant to the diseases.
And so we're going to help them do that,
um,
in a in tissue culture where we can
propagate tens of thousands of plants very
quickly in a jar rather than by seed.
Um,
he's actually going to sponsor a student
to come to my lab to do that and I'm
going to go there and help him. But
this is the kind of place where we can,
where you can solve a problem with this
kind of technology and where we're being
blocked. And to me as a scientist, I
think of the 20,000 people who die. Um,
I, I talk about it when I give talks and
I can't help but get tears in my eyes.
When you think about the malnourished
people I've met in my travels who, um,
who changed me, um, you meet them one
time and it, it, you know, you wait,
especially when you shake their hand
and feel how weak and small they are and
you dedicate yourself to, um,
how you're going to fix it.
And to have people say,
well, it's all Monsanto.
It's going to give you cancers and
all this stuff. That's not true.
You block the investment in technology
and the application of technology that
can help. And so when, when we
have this kind of conversation,
I think about the allergy free peanuts,
I think about the golden banana as
the golden rice, the, uh, you know,
all the applications we have there.
So there's countless and we can't use
them because of a fear of the technology.
And you feel it just an ignorance
with technology and, uh,
they've an ignorance of
biology and genetics. But you
also think that this there,
they have to be aware of this too,
in order to make this grand conspiracy,
to try to keep this illegal,
to keep this out of this country.
They have to be aware that
they are preventing good.
They have to be aware. Yes.
So that's, that's Kinda
fucked up. Yes. And I, and I,
and to be on the good side and I
supposedly the progressive side,
the rightful side,
the side that everybody wants to
support and anti GMO causes everybody's
terrified of Gmos. Yes.
And, and that's why in the,
and the reason for this has
been so, you know, we've, uh,
you talk about the companies that,
that do it,
they totally failed when they rolled
out this technology. They didn't say,
here's how it works and let's, let's,
let's, uh, take care of your fears.
They rolled it out and said,
here's what you get. And, uh,
people equated this with Frankenstein
and, and, you know, evil scientists, uh,
we didn't get good education upfront.
Then over the years,
there's been a machine of
documentaries, uh, books, uh,
the people who sell the books and
documentaries about the dangers of this.
They're the ones who are making the
profits. They're the shills, right?
They're the ones that if they can
make a dollar by scaring you, uh,
with their product, uh, and
so they've been running free.
Scientists like me have totally screwed
this up too because the first time I
talked to a public audience about
Gmos, 15 years ago, I sat down and I,
I bombed them with science and I told
them about how it's done and details that
they didn't need. I turned off more
people than I, than I converted.
And only in the last three years really
have a scientists got together and said,
this is a crisis that our technology
can't reach those who need it.
And we need to rethink the way
that we talk to them about science.
And it's not about beating people
to death with the Science Hammer.
It's about sharing ideas and things that
we all really want and our solutions
that we can use and,
and really separating a technology
that's very good from companies that,
you know, good, good, bad or whatever
we need to know the technology is good.
Yeah.
What do you think initially
caused the fear of Gmos?
Do you think it was,
was there any particular story that
came out that misrepresented it,
that became viral or what,
what was it that started off this big
fear of this aspect of science and I think
there's always been an environmental
movement that has decried the use of uh,
any kind of chemicals and farming
and good reason, good reason.
And I understand that cause you got
DDT and all these great examples
back know a guy who's got bone cancer
and all these kids who grew up with had
cancer as well because they all live near
a golf course and this shit that they
used to the use the spray on the golf
course got into the well water and cancer
was rampant in their small community.
These examples are in, you know,
when you go out, I went out to Hawaii to
talk to them and they all talked about,
you know, back in the day when the, you
know, they would, they would, you know,
grow the cane and they would use all these
chemicals and whether the stories are
true or not,
I think there's a certain
level of understanding that
we did things differently
back then. And we weren't in places
like South America, they still do this.
Um, you know, and uh, if a little
bit works more is better. Um,
here the regulations are really tight
and how you can use a compound and how
it's allowed to be used and the residues
that are present are all very well
monitored. And, uh, I think
that the times are changed. But,
but going back to your question of,
you know, where did this come from?
I think people had,
it was an environmental movement that
was certainly on guard and I'm glad
they're there.
I'm very happy about that.
The problem is now that anything
that any of their former foes in the
environmental movement would produce. You
know, Monsanto Coulda came out with, uh,
you know,
the duck that makes gold,
the golden eggs and they would've
said the gold is poisoned.
Anything that comes from that company
is going to be tainted just by name. Um,
and,
and that's where I think a lot of this
comes from and that when they came out
with, um, uh,
the tomato and back when it was on
the market or any of the products that
they've made, it hasn't been, let's
think of what we can do with this.
But here's just another way that this
company is rolling out a product to gain
world domination of a food supply
and make money off chemicals.
It's because of what we discussed earlier.
There's,
or I should say it could be because of
what we discussed earlier because people
have an inherent distrust in folks
that are willing to copyright life.
The idea that you own the copyright to
some corn and I know that you genetically
modified it.
I know that you changed it,
but what it is now it's life and if you
do that to a pig, what happens then?
If you do it to a pig, why can't you
do it to artificial livers? You know?
Why can't you do it to all
sorts of things? You could,
you could all of a sudden copyrighting
entire human body and own a trademark on
human bodies.
You could specifically design a type of
human that the only way you can get your
kid to be Alpha Beta 16 is you got to get
the Alpha Beta 16 Monsanto gene inside
of your kid. I mean this is not
outside the realm of possibility.
This is within a hundred years from now,
there'll be doing shit like that.
That freaks people out that a corporation
could own human life. Well, yeah,
I mean it's an interesting, actually,
it's kind of a little bit off topic,
but they have that now three parent kid,
you know where they've missed
the mitochondrial par with
what in the actual fuck
is going to happen with that
kid. The file. What if he
comes out evil? Then what?
Then what? Well, what if he's, what if
he's one day they're going to fuck around,
create the antichrist, right. I
mean this is where it comes from.
It's an interesting thought.
You know, plus you're buying
more presence at Christmas for your,
you know,
multiple parents or when a kid will.
Yeah, a lot of burden on the kid.
If the parents get divorced, the
custody, the custody will be a mess.
And if they disagree with the way they
raised the child and then you'd have to
like agree like it's hard for a husband
and wife to agree on specifics as far as
language to be used to how
to handle certain situations.
You got three people in,
in trying to be the dad of the good news
is child support will be half of the
price. How many dads and how
many moms? It broken down.
I don't think it's two mothers cause
there's a mother that provided the nucleus
and a mother that provided the rest of
the cell Goo and then the dad just sperm.
Good luck with all that. That
guy is a pimp by the way.
But, but the whole idea of,
but the cool part about this though,
as we wander into the mad scientist realm,
again,
let's think of things that have been done
that are really positive and then even
our patented technology.
So you've got a pig that was
made that has a better ability.
It has a gene that it makes saliva that
breaks down phosphorus better in its
food and phosphate.
So what did,
what it allows the pig to
do is have less toxic waste.
They called it the and viral pig and it
has a cause. Pigs, uh, you know, they're,
they're uh, effluent is, uh,
is a problem and to have keep it out
in the environments a good thing.
And so they made the inviro pig and a,
at the viral pig is a, is a crushed idea.
Now they, they're only a few embryos
left in the tank of liquid nitrogen. Um,
they made,
this week I heard of a salmon that they
put a salmon gene into a salmon to make
it grow twice as fast.
Um,
it was originally developed in 1989 and
that the company that's been trying to
get it approved has been
added since the 90s.
And they've got all of the approval
but it's never been finalized.
And the beauty of this fish is it
grows to harvestable size as I,
you know, a farmed fish in half the
time. So you're using half the stuff,
half the food, half the resources to eat,
make the equivalent amount of protein.
But what of these fuckers
get out into the wild? Yeah,
they thought of that spawn trout.
Oh they're all females.
And Dan,
they're triploid so they have an extra
chromosome that makes them infertile.
But design is how every bad horror movie
stars. Absolutely. One of those things.
And all of a sudden it
becomes like a crocodile man.
That's like the creature
from the Braca goon let's,
it could be a salmon that you guys
fucked with. It turns into a person.
But this is it. See that.
It's so funny cause it,
cause we always spin
off into this and you,
especially when we go into this idea that
my fault and I'm sorry but this is a,
it always goes back to what is
the way that this can break bad.
That's how I look at things and and
being an eternal optimist I think of what
are the good things we could do with this?
Well I expect no less from a guy who
had a song called I live in an asshole.
I would think that you would be the
eternal optimist to its social commentary
from a,
you know me just obviously we're having
fun but it is the kind of thing where my
job is to sit around and figure
out how to solve problems.
And so when you can come up with a fish
that gets to eating size and half the
time,
which could in theory really relieved
pressure on wild salmon fishing and put of
put food into the high protein and good
food into the hands of people who don't
normally afford fish like me, I
don't buy it. The cereal aisle,
logical stuff like that scares
the shit out of people. It's like,
you know what a lager is, right?
Sure. You saw of Napoleon dynamite.
It's a cross between a lion and a
tiger. It's an enormous, enormous cat.
It's the biggest cat we
know of. Right? I mean,
I think something happens in the jeans.
Uh,
I believe it's a male lion and a female
tiger. I might have it backwards,
but the,
the,
the gene is for regulating
the size of the growth is not,
it's not the same.
So something happens in the cross where
it becomes infertile because it's a
hybrid,
but they grow to enormous sizes.
Like look at the size of
that God thing. Yeah. It's,
it's some weird genetic modification,
but you know,
not through a scientist in a lab
through just crossbreed. Yeah,
that's a hybrid vigor. Yeah. It's um,
it's a case that when you mix up, um,
genomes that don't normally
match and Jesus Christ,
I wouldn't, I wouldn't be grabbing
it like that. Cause it, Lord,
what does she handing it beat
on the stick? Some food. Well,
you got to keep those things soup or
fed. Yeah, I've like really, really,
really fed like so they don't
even think about eating you,
but it goes back to our corn.
You know,
this is why we have great corners because
there are two genomes that wouldn't
normally get together that humans
put together. Seedless Bananas,
which are all the ones we have are have
an extra set of chromosomes. Your seeds.
Seedless watermelon hasn't
separate set of chromosomes. Um,
we've been mixing together
plant chromosomes in ways
nature could never intend
for decades.
And here you add a PR with great precision
one gene that we know what it does to
a salmon, we can monitor
it, we understand it,
and it has a beneficial
product that can help humans.
And they grow these things in tanks
and Panama. They can't escape.
They're inland Tan.
One of them is going to get super smart
and figuring out how to crack the and
evolve really quick and get legs and
leave dude, solid movie, but see that.
But that's the,
that's the,
there's all these precautions that
are put in place to make sure that,
that these things can't happen.
And of course, you know, you can,
we can always think of the example
in all the thalidomide, you know,
now you got flipper babies, you know, um,
you can always think of
examples where it didn't work,
but what we tend to dismiss are the
hundreds of thousands of chance of things
that worked better than
expected. You know, the, uh,
the thing that makes your
computer grow better,
that you can have the equivalent of the
Apollo landers a firepower in terms of
computational ability on your wrist.
You know,
even more than that and these,
but these are the kinds of breakthroughs
that we take for granted. And we,
and we ignore a always,
but we have to stop worrying about the
what ifs and start worrying about the
what cans.
And that's
where I really want to try to get
people to refocus. Does Gmo discussion?
What are your pressing problems?
What are the things that
science can do for you today?
And I think that that's where
this gets super exciting.
But you can understand
why people are worried.
People who don't understand the science
or it's never been explained to them.
Certainly I don't know anybody like you
and they could sit down with like if we
do this for three hours,
is that even enough?
I mean it's not really like you could
probably explain this shit to me for
months and I would just be be slowly
working its way into my understanding.
But people worry about what they don't
understand and they really worry about
human beings,
quote unquote playing God and manipulating
genetics and manipulating life even
though that's kind of what
we always have done. Yes,
and there's a great radio lab
podcast on the Galapagos Islands.
It's really fantastic.
And one of the things about it is their
attempts to keep invasive species from
entering the Galapagos
islands and the plant species.
We're going there from the bottom of
people's feet where they had stepped in
seeds and then they stepped on the grass
and these new species of grasses grow
and pirates had left goats on the land
so that they could come back and they
have a food source when they
would land on the island again.
So they had these invasive goats species
that were living ultra and they realize
like there's no fucking way you can't,
like everything used to be somewhere
else and then made its way across.
But when we start monkeying with those,
everything's,
that's when people are worried
because of certain outlier examples.
When you forget about all
the crops that we plant, oh,
there was a totally unnatural,
right?
I mean an orange grove is like
the most unnatural shit ever.
You've dug a hole in the ground,
put some trees that were never
going to be there and you, you,
you got to have whole irrigation system
and good of Napa and look at the Wa,
the wine vineyards,
that's fucking totally unnatural.
That should just doesn't exist.
You're never going to walk through the
wilds of some uncharted land and find a
fucking wine vineyard doesn't exist.
You have to grow that shit.
You have to make that
apart of the environment.
But sometimes it goes terribly wrong.
Like they introduce rabbits in
Australia and they don't have predators.
So the rabbit just fucking went crazy
and ran through the entire country.
Like they have a huge rabbit problem.
So then they brought over foxes.
They will bring over foxes and
cats and we'll kill the rabbits.
But then those foxes and cats don't just
kill rabbits. You fuck, they didn't.
Jeanette genetically engineered foxes
that can only look at a rabbit as a
Predator, as a food source,
rather, they kill everything.
So they were responsible for
like 30 something extinctions
in the entire country
of Australia.
It's fucked.
They have these fucking foxes running
around just killing everything. So they,
they're so bad that they have a problem
with their sheep were the foxes are
grabbing the baby sheep
as they're coming out,
which is apparently like
standard Predator behavior.
And this is freaking
people out because they,
this is all because humans metaled
introduced an animal to a place where it
didn't belong.
Then you tried to introduce a Predator to
compensate for it.
And you see this chain of events that
it's really a problem and a managerial
nightmare for people that, or they'd have
to manage the wildlife down there. Yeah.
But this is so,
but all these examples happen and
certainly things do sneak out of here and
there. You got to go
with that. But you know,
when we want to talk about
releasing a new plant variety,
and we're not talking GML,
we're saying let's say a new
elite strawberry that we know, um,
or sorghum or whatever that comes
to our university. What's a sorghum?
Cause I like strawberry. It's a kind of
grain crop that is indigenous for Africa.
They use it for a biofuel now to try to,
but strawberries or whatever, we have, uh,
the evaluation it has to go through.
You have to grow it for many seasons,
multiple locations.
Evaluate.
Is it invasive or does it have the
potential to be invasive? And if it does,
we can't release it. Um, we have to
evaluate all the different metrics.
And these are not GMO crops.
These are just regular crops to,
these are just selectively
bred crop selectively bred.
So you would establish that the
seeds will grow this big, fat,
juicy apple size strawberry.
They're super juicy and delicious and
you have to do it consistently and
continually an isolated and have it down
to one. See that you could give them,
they can test themselves.
Well essentially we are one plant
essentially the see the strawberries are
another good example where you can't take
strawberry seeds from a strawberry and
plant them and get any two plants to
look alike. That's so crazy. So you guys,
how do you get those seeds
then? Now you, every,
every plant comes from other plants.
They make the little runners.
And so one plant that the
strawberries that you get,
the strawberry plants you buy, they're
all clones. Just like the bananas,
just like a blueberries. Oh, I see.
So they're not grown with seeds.
They're grown with a segment of the
plant that you then replant that you're
replant. So they're vegetative. Oh
Wow. So it's like weed. Uh, yeah.
That's how I know about clones. So
I hear, I know dudes who grow it.
That's the idea is that we're
able to vegetatively as they say,
propagate these things.
But all of this stuff is so carefully
evaluated and what GMO it goes through FDA
to make sure you can eat it.
Then it goes to EPA to make sure that
it's safe for the environment and they
look at how does it affect insect
populations are pollinators or whatever.
And then that goes to a USDA who then
test for farm application and invasiveness
and the farm.
So these things are crazy tested
and all the what ifs are really well
established.
Because if there was,
and I always have kind of the way I
think about this as if we do want,
assume companies are money
grubbing and horrible. Um,
if something were to go wrong,
it would be the end of the
company and gigantic lawsuits.
And so in self preservation,
let alone profit to make a decent product.
These things are extensively tested.
So what,
what do you think is one of the top
unwarranted concerns that people have over
genetically modified foods?
Well,
I'm glad you asked that because
I don't mean to be just um, uh,
hate when I come off as being just a,
uh,
too excited and ambitious the technology.
Cause there's downsides to everything.
Um, but you have to weigh the
risks versus limitations or bed,
which versus benefits.
And some of the things that we've seen is
this resistance to weed, to herbicides.
So one of the most useful GMO crops is
this roundup ready or really what it is,
is glyphosate resistant? Glyphosate is
the chemical roundup is the brand name.
It's off patent now.
So many companies make glyphosate.
So I tend to go a glyphosate
when we discussed the trait,
what it allows a farmer to do is plant,
say soybeans,
you plant the soy beans and then as the
soybeans start to grow and the weeds
start to grow,
the farmer goes over the top with a,
with an application of the stuff
called glyphosate that kills the weeds.
But the crop keeps growing through it
and as the crop grows it shades out the
weeds. So then the crop is
the only dominant thing there.
The amount of glyphosate
that's applied is about um,
you know about a mug worth per
acre in terms of active ingredient.
It's a very potent chemical that disrupts
a very specific part of the plant's
biochemistry.
It can't make me no acid,
so can't make proteins specific proteins
and the chemistries, well known,
we understand what it affects in.
You don't have that pathway.
So it's a very safe chemical for humans.
Lately it's come under a lot of fire.
I'm actually now that people
aren't attacking the gene
insertion process or the
portraits themselves,
they're going after the chemicals
used in the process of using just that
chemical over and over again on,
on on land.
We've talked about this idea with Murcia
and what mutations and with the one
that happens to figure it out surviving,
there are weeds that can
grow through glyphosate.
And when that one we'd can grow
through because of a mutation,
now it drops it seeds and pretty soon
you got a major problem because all the
rest of the competitors are gone.
And these weeds take over and now you
have to come up with other methods such as
plowing or uh,
other herbicides to get rid of them.
So this is still confusing to me.
You,
the plants are all coming from clones,
but you sell people seeds.
So where do the seeds come from? Why am I
dumb? No, no, no, it was this confusing.
Well, we're, we're literally
literally talking apples and oranges.
So we're talking about clones. We're
talking about things like strawberries,
oranges, apples. When we're
talking about soybeans or corn.
So if somebody buys those, those
strawberries, yes. If you like,
you make this mega strawberry,
how does someone get a seed to
plant for those mega strawberries?
If it's all clones, new
clone seats, I know that they
just take the clonal plants.
So strawberries make runners.
So you have a plant that then makes a
little daughter plant that comes off it
and then you just get those
daughter plants and plant
those in your field so you
don't sell them seeds. You sell them
plants. We sell them. Well not we, not me,
but um,
but our nurseries.
So if University of Florida comes up
with a new strawberry, that's fantastic.
They'll take that foundational plant,
do many years of to make sure it's good
and consistent and many different places.
And then that plant will go to a nursery
where it's propagated by by experts who
make billions of plants and a couple of
years and then they sell those plants
back to our farmers.
But when a person would go to the
store and they would buy seeds,
like say heirloom tomato seeds, how
would they make those seeds? Yeah,
those are seeds that come
from heirloom tomato.
So that comes from what you think of
as single seed dissent. In other words,
you have a tomato that has some
good qualities than its seeds.
Also have the similar qualities they've
been inbred so that essentially there's
no genetic diversity within that fruit,
that every gene,
rather than having a copy from mom and
a copy from dad that are different,
they're all the same or
at least very narrow.
And so this way you can have seeds from
that same parental plant that look very
so that what you plant will come out to
be very similar to the parent that it
came from.
But this is where it gets confusing to
me because you were telling me that if
someone took like one of
those tomatoes and grew,
uh, took the seeds from it and
tried to grow tomato plants,
they would not be similar
to the initial tomato. Well,
the heirlooms probably
would be because of those,
because they're so well
in bread. Okay. Okay. So,
but a regular tomato of
Monsanto grown regular tomato,
a hybrid tomato that came from
two very distinct parents,
that thing's going to be a genetic
mix of many different traits.
And that thing will give rise
to many different progeny.
So if you got a tomato from the grocery
store, one of those Pale, funky tomatoes,
the cut up and like Carl's
junior and you get your burger,
that just looks like or sad if you took
the seeds for an that you could possibly
grow different kinds of tomatoes.
Yes. Wow. Yeah. And so, uh, but,
but with things like click and suck,
the could be like,
or Cooper or it could be the next, uh,
the next best tomato you've ever tasted.
I mean,
it could be that the chances are no,
because they've been breeding
out all of that stuff. Um,
we do have tomato plants
at home. Yes, I do. Yeah.
I'll send you some seeds for one
that you will start. None of this is,
this is amazing. So a guy at my, uh,
in my university named Harry Cli, he,
they did sensory tests on hundreds
of people and they asked them, well,
what do you like about a tomato?
What?
And they tested all the heirlooms on
them and they tested what heirlooms they
liked and which ones they didn't.
Then they took apart chemically what's
in each one of those kinds of tomatoes
and they analyze them by,
by maybe what the consumers were tasting
in the volatile components in the acid
balance and the sugars.
And they were able to come
up with a recipe for the
perfect tomato and then they
made hybrids that would
fit that expectation.
And they came out with two new tomatoes
called garden jam and garden treasure,
which are just going to be
used in the whole market,
but there tomatoes that have exceptionally
high flavor and it's one of these
heirlooms, Brett, against the
University of Florida, um, uh,
production tomato.
So one of the more regular tomatoes
and the result is outstanding.
It grows in Florida where nothing,
everything wants to die in Florida. Uh,
you know,
it's a really harsh environment,
but now these are tomatoes are fantastic
and they do really well out here.
And how do they establish those seeds?
Then they just do it enough generations
of very specific tomatoes where they're
confident that the seeds will yield
the same type of tomato while the two
parents are very well the eye,
very, very standard genetically.
And then those two parents
get sent to a place like,
I don't know where they did these,
but it was some place like Costa Rica
or something where you can generate huge
amounts of hybrids where you have people
who will hand pollinate flowers with
the one pollen from the other
and then generate the seeds.
And so that's how hybrid seeds are made.
So they're making these seeds by hand
germinating or hand Paul and hand
pollinated rather. Yeah. And,
and the result is fantastic because
it's a combination of the best of the
heirlooms versus the best
of the production traits.
And this is what's exciting for me as
a scientist is that we understand more
about what the consumer wants now.
And we also are understanding more about
the chemistry of fruits and vegetables.
So even without Gmo,
we can understand the genes that
cause people to like tomatoes. Like,
what are the components of a tomato or
a strawberry that people just love and
then identify those compounds in breed
them back in just with traditional
breeding.
What is the pollination process like?
Because I watched this thing about,
um,
in China they had areas where they had
decimated the bee population so badly
that they had a hand pollinate
a lot of their plants.
And by sheer luck they found out that
hand pollination is far more effective.
And if they paid people,
whatever the owl hourly wages is actually
more cost effective to fucking get rid
of the bees, which is horrible
to find out what these people,
it was way better cause apparently
bees are just kind of random. You know,
they're not,
they don't do the best job,
but they don't know what
the fuck they're doing.
They don't know that they're carrying
pollen on them, you know, they're just,
they're just kind of doing it. It's
not like a very specific goal for them.
But when it's a specific goal,
and I usually like these artistic paint
brushes and brushing pollen on it,
the effectiveness was like way,
way better than just allowing
nature to run its course. Yeah.
It may have been the case in China and
it depends on the crop too because a lot
of things are wind pollinated.
So if you eat maculate,
all of the plants that you
plan to be the female parent,
if you cut out all the little stamens
and anther's the male parts, you know,
you had to take out a all
rude. Yeah, I know it.
You have to be careful when
you look online how to do this.
And you should look up pictures of Bruce
Jenner pop up, Google emasculation it.
Uh, so you'd go to [inaudible], you
pull out all the a star, he's a hero,
you pull out all the time of her,
you pull out all the stamens and then
now this plant can only be fertilized by
what comes from,
you know,
you plant the adjacent rows of the
pollen donor and now bees and wind and
everything else will take care of that.
So these people hand
pollinate these plants,
then grow tomatoes specifically from
those plants and then sell those seeds or
use those seeds to grow more me.
How many generations do they do it?
They're confident that they can
get a seed that if you get it,
it will grow that same specific
tomato that you guys engineered.
So the seed that comes from the tomato
that results from that pollination,
those seeds are hybrids.
They have the combination of the mothers,
the mothers traits and
the father's traits.
That seed is the one that would go to
you as the consumer that now you would
grow a tomato plant that would produce
outstanding tomatoes. Wow. After that,
it's a crap shoot because genes in
cells, when you're uh, you know,
making your, your gametes are male and
female reproductive components, you're um,
going through homogenization is that now
you lose control of what genes are in
the next generation.
So that's the problem.
I think this is a mind blower for people.
This one right here is for me because
I never really thought that the tomato
that you got,
like if you've got an heirloom tomato,
wouldn't necessarily grow
heirloom tomatoes from its
seeds because it's just not
the way it works.
I mean,
I would have always assumed that you
would be able to get it that way,
but you telling me that you,
you what you guys had specifically done,
that you had a hand pollinate in order
to ensure that that would create those
certain types of tomatoes.
That's fucking nuts.
That's it's the way it goes now
when you make hybrids and, and,
but there's so much more cool stuff in
plant genetics that we can do because of
this kind of thing.
It's very cool,
but it's disturbing again to dummies like
me because then all it comes up like,
whoa.
People are in charge of the process of
creating this very specific form of life.
I mean that's really what that tomato is.
It's a living thing.
It's a very specific type of
vegetable or fruit, right?
Technically it's technically a fruit,
a fruit like botanic that
human beings are you,
you guys are the mothers
of these special tomatoes.
I mean essentially it needs people. Oh
sure. Ask me about seedless watermelons.
I mean [inaudible] the fuck is
that about your to hear though?
Is that worrying what came first? The
chicken or the egg? It doesn't make sense.
There's a case where you're
using chemicals to change
the number of chromosomes
in a cell. So now this plant
has twice as many chromosomes.
So now when you cross it against one that
has the normal amount of chromosomes,
the other results,
so we'd have let's say a two,
two times to chromosomes and the next
generation you would cross it with
something that has the normal set,
the resulting ones have
this weird intermediate set
that can't be fertile. Okay,
I'm going to play the part
of the dumb hippie man.
It just doesn't feel right with you.
Just like fucking with nature and
not knowing the results. I mean,
the world has like a a biological
system and you're just tampering with it
without totally understanding
ramifications of what you're going to do.
And there's all sorts of cancer and autism
that exists today and a lot of it is
because of scientists.
Ignorant to think that they're so smart.
You're smarter than nature,
you're going to play God with tomatoes.
I just think that's fucked man. Yeah. So
that's my, my role. It was pretty good.
Right? Well I've met that guy over and
over again. What do you say to that guy?
Well, the thing that breaks my heart is
that I liked that guy pretty much to,
I mean, you know, he, he,
he's, he's not in my, not up
in my face about anything else.
He's doing
his thing. We listened to the
same music. Probably we, you know,
we're both in the worrying
about the environment. You know,
we're on the same page with 90%.
It's just that he worries about this
in this one aspect of food production,
that humans have always changed food
and we've just now learned how to do it
with precision. And so this is what,
where he's got a kind of, you know,
have a little come to Jesus moment here
and say this is science working for him.
I think again it goes
to that is is a very,
very complex issue that doesn't have a
lot of black and widen and it has many,
many shades of gray and like all things.
There's pros and cons to
the application of it,
especially really complicated things
like anything involving biology,
there's pros and cons.
There's variables that we can't control
with with our consumption of food.
With the are the level of pollution
that we allow in the environment.
I mean there's, we have like
dedicated numbers or, or,
or dissed prescribed numbers
that you shouldn't go over.
Like if we go over this
when we fucked up that area,
we've got to get out of there.
I mean there's spots that human beings
can't go to right now because of chemical
dumps or because of
nuclear reactor accidents.
There's spots that we've totally
ruined and this is just a Po,
but we also have fucking power
everywhere. Right. You know,
we also have elect you me, yeah,
this some bad shit has happened,
but look at all the good shit.
It's 7 billion people on the planet.
There's never been numbers like that.
Just don't,
the only reason why there's numbers
like that is because 100,000 of them are
smart as shit,
and those really,
maybe a million might be a
million at a 7 billion, right.
That have been responsible for
putting together this amazing society.
It's not me, but those
people that have, yeah,
there's been some mistakes along the way,
but I think without that innovation
in that thirst for improvement,
that people seem to just,
we just have like inherently like a
guy like you when you're talking about
these,
the application of these technologies
and the application of this science and
this work, you get all jazzed up. I May,
Sr you almost started crying when you
were talking about these people that you
had met that were amazing,
hated you have a deep connection
to this and then so you,
you're fucking important as shit, dude.
Well, you're more important than Jay Z.
I just said it.
I'll take that.
But you know, you know, who is responsible
for a million of those 7 billion?
Do you know a named Norman Borlaug? No.
You see the guy that created golden rice?
No. Norman Borlaug. He did more than
that. Norman Borlaug was a, a wonderful,
simple, uh, it came from
a farm background, uh,
became a scientist in studied ways that
he could try to solve problems on the
face of the earth for the hungry
and especially in India and Mexico.
And his idea was to take the kind
of plants that may never be able to,
uh, uh, makes naturally and make
some crosses a dwarfing varieties.
So plants that were lower to the
ground that would have fewer problems.
And he made these crosses that really
would go to feed a billion people.
And, um, you know, scientists, me, you
know, I look at him and I, he's like a,
he is the ultimate hero to me. He is a
guy who should be a household name here.
Um, you know, I stand on the shoulders of
a giant and he passed away in 2009. And,
uh, those of us who have heard
about him, I've read about him, who,
who had a chance to see him speak.
It changes us because it was,
it was his,
his compassion to take care
of the needy that drove him.
It wasn't about making a dollar.
It wasn't about Monsanto.
It was about being the guy that when
he came to the village, everybody said,
let's, let's take them out to our best
restaurant because here's a guy we like.
Um,
uh,
he was a guy who insisted if you visited
his campus to carry your bags to your
car, um, despite the fact that
he was a Nobel laureate. Um,
that's the kind of role models
that we have in science.
And this is the kind of role model that
other people have to be aware of that
for every Norman Borlaug, uh, it's going
to take a few million evil scientists.
We have to understand that. And he
made that he made crosses that were,
were amazingly diverse and that Brock
plants together that couldn't survive,
that would never happen in the
wild and fed people because of it.
See, he's the good scientists. You're
the good scientist in the movie too.
So when the evil scientist come and
they tried to take over the world,
we need you to be the ones that sound
the alarm like in every good movie,
like the day before tomorrow, whatever
that is, day after tomorrow. Right.
You need the good scientist to figure it
out. The Shit's going wrong. Well, yeah,
and then, but and then that's in there
on surveillance. I mean it's not just me.
There's thousands of me, much more
on surveillance now than ever before.
Right before,
but not just because we're aware of it,
but because of the tools we
have. And it would be, to me,
it would be a career maker
to find something wrong
with a Monsanto product and
report it in the best journals.
But when you worry though,
like a good Russell Crowe movie that
would come after him. Not at all.
You wouldn't work. I'd say the very least.
I would say bring it on yet. No, totally.
I'm, wow. I am fearless. I, I, I
love talking to the Anti Gmo crowds.
I mean I go into a, and I'm the one they
call because they know I'm reasonable,
but I go in the places and people will
get in my face and yell at me. I'll have,
uh,
people come up and scream in my face
about how my company has given their kid
cancer. Um, I mean I get,
I get some heavy shit and it
happens often, but the idea is,
is to get into those rooms and get into
those spaces just like we're doing here
and have a conversation and introduce
people, the technology and get them to d,
Monsanto wise,
this talk about ways that we can make
it work to make a plant products that
would require fewer
pesticides like the bt has.
How many people have come up to and
yelled at you that you gave one of their
loved ones cancer? Um, to, to, yeah, one
of them was in Hawaii. It was a woman,
beautiful woman from Brazil I think
originally who had a child who had um,
uh, who had cancer and she said, here's
what your company did to my child.
And, um, and I accompany, did she
think you were representing? Um,
I assume the big hammer, one
of the big companies? Um,
and the reason I was there was because I
was invited by the companies to come to
the island to talk to people as a neutral
party because they were having a lot
of conflicts by Monsanto. Well, no,
I was invited by the Hawaii
Crop Improvement Association,
which is like a group of a
whole bunch of companies.
And they said they're not listening to us.
They don't care what we think.
What about an independent scientist?
And when I came there,
I made it my business to not hang around
with the Syngenta's Monsanto's dials.
I didn't want to talk to
the other scientists. Um,
I wanted to talk to the farmers and I
wanted to talk to the people who were
afraid and the people who had concerns
because I could help them understand. And,
and, and that was what my goal is,
to help them to talk to them. And,
and anyone who was there,
even people who are adamantly anti Gmo,
I think many of them would agree
that I was very, I was often,
I mean it was very peaceful
and very quick to engage them.
That when I saw people in the audience
at a farmer forms where I was speaking,
I'd see them shaking their
heads and going, no way, no way.
The minute I was done in the applause
was over and the questions were answered.
I chased them out in the
parking lot and said,
I need to talk to you because this is,
this is where this
conversation needs to be.
It needs to be one on one over a pizza
and a cup of coffee. It, he can't be,
it can't be on the internet where
there's noise from, you know,
documentary sellers and, and,
and people with agendas were,
what about face to face and this woman
is yelling at you that you're responsible
for? Yes. Her child being ill. Like what
do you say to someone like that? I said,
I'm really sorry for what's happened and,
and I would love to help you solve this
problem or not let it happen to somebody
else. And I, I said, if there is something
here on the island that caused this,
we need to understand it and we
need to get to the bottom of it.
But as a scientist,
it's not GMO crops.
I mean there's nothing that I can think
of that's plausible or no evidence that
I know of that would point that way.
And then I told her about the, uh,
state USDA, the person I gave her the
name of the estate, Usta Person. I said,
here's the person you call and tell them
where you live in and have them come
talk to you about it and analyze
the patterns. And you know,
that's the kind of issue was this
was from another country in Brazil.
This was in a, she does. She
was from Brazil. I think so.
So was she living in Hawaii
when this happened? Yes.
So there's something that they
had dumped in Hawaii, wasn't it?
Was the United States.
Yeah. That's the allegation.
A lot of the people on the confused.
I thought she was,
cause she flew from Brazil
to talk to you. She was, um,
I had a conversation with her and I think
I got that information from her at the
time cause she had a very strong accent.
But there's a lot of very strong anti
GMO sentiment on the island of Hawaii and
in Hawaii actually throughout the state.
Well,
I mean how could it not be sure
if you look at what they have,
they have paradise. Yes. And they're
like, what are you going to do?
Are you going to fuck with
paradise? Ah Dude, we're okay
over here. Well down here,
which are fucking funky
bananas. But here's, here's
the deal is that uh, our, uh,
our, our, our farmers rely
on on this because Hawaii,
you can grow three seasons of corn a year,
so you can use it,
but they use it for seed production.
You generate the seed that's planted in
Iowa on Qy. Wow. That's amazing. Yeah.
And so,
and you can do three seats,
three seasons a year,
whereas the amazing weather rather
than to on the mainland or one.
And so you're able to sell the farmer
cheaper products or keep the cost under
control of a product. Plus the
environment's perfect. It's dry,
the seed is of good quality.
So they do a lot of seed
raising on Hawaii and um, and,
and very strong anti sentiment.
And I understand that um,
it is a beautiful place but it also
employs lots of people on the islands.
I think one of the things
that you discussed and we
talked about earlier that I
thought was really fascinating was this
idea that planting crops isn't really
natural because I was a pass
through Alberta this past
weekend and I was driving
through these enormous agricultural
areas and I was thinking to myself like,
well this is really crazy like that.
We do this,
we just take over these giant swaths of
land and fill it with shit we can eat.
And then we run over it with
giant machines collecting
it and then bundle it up
and sell it throughout the world.
Like this is,
it's a really bizarre practice
and it is absolutely unnatural.
Absolutely. It's a, and if you look at
where the crops came from that we grow,
I mean corn doesn't belong in the, in
North America. I mean it was, well,
I came from southern Mexico. Uh, it wasn't
in the United States and Canada. Anyway,
um, if you look at a map
and I'll show you when,
maybe later Urfi you look up crop
domestication, our centers of origin of,
of major food crops. You see that, uh,
there are maps in Google images that
show that you s you have sunflowers,
maybe some progenitors to strawberry and
blueberry and maybe some kind of brass
cause that might be like canola.
But for the most part,
there's nothing that comes from here.
No two tomatoes are from South America.
Potatoes, peanuts saw a
citruses from Southeast Asia.
Apples are from cosmic Stan. All of
our, all of our cabbage, Kale, Broccoli,
cauliflower, all that's from the
Middle East and Mediterranean areas.
So nothing's from here, dude. Kale
is totally natural. Fuck off. Uh,
yeah, so this is a good example here.
This, um, but that talks about, you know,
some of our major crops.
I'm certainly there.
Sorghum yams and potatoes came from
South America. Peanuts, South America.
Wow. African rice. This is nuts.
There's lots of good example. Osh.
Yes, squash came from a south. Well,
it's also from, uh, Mexico
along with beans. Uh,
close to where I'm amazed
was a domesticated.
So there's some kinds of squash that were
native to North America, but not many.
Look. S Paga, what does that
PE Peppo Peppo keep us flash.
So people's like, uh,
like, um, uh, the, uh,
any kind of a Q Courbet's like a pumpkin's
and like the squash is quickness is
like we have,
it's weird when you look for Yams.
I know creepy little island in the
middle of nowhere, but that this
is, that they love that stuff.
The HR something there that,
that's where yams come from, but
they take a, but this is the,
this is all of the movement from those
crops was human mediated. Humans drag
that stuff around.
Chenwa and so all of our domestication
that we've done has been human
facilitated and the genetics
change accordingly. Oh,
so there's some yams that are also
from South America, it seems. Oh,
at central. That's South America.
South America there. But what,
but this is the beauty of this.
If you look at strawberry,
it's a great story because strawberry
grows naturally on the forest floors of
North America and also from Chile.
But the two are two different species.
So there's two different
kinds of yams then.
And it's like you different
species that says it is.
It's got two different names.
Two different Yemenis.
That always weirds me out too. Why
does it have to fucking names? Look,
it's got a rapper name. It's, you know,
it's coolio as your name's not coolio.
What's your fucking name? You know that
guy? What's his name? Two Chainz, Bro.
That's not your name.
It can't go on.
You can't go on CNN and debate Nancy
grace about pot. You don't even,
you don't have a real name. Your
name. See goddamn name. Yeah,
but this is a cool story. If you look
at it, look at this though. Like Yams.
Why do we have to, what's this? What's
your fucking name, dude? It's, no, it's d.
What does it, how does, I don't even know.
I don't even know what the genus is on,
on that. But you know, gee, try,
try for the d trip it up versus
the Alotta and they're just,
they're just reproductively isolated. And
so they are essentially the same thing.
Are they interchangeable? They're
probably two species from the same genus.
So they're related,
but there's reproductively isolated.
Why do they have wrapper names? They
cause they can't cross with each other.
Unlike rappers say can't
cross with each other.
Why don't they have their
name then? Why didn't we, why?
Why do we have to dumb it down?
Just call it Yam and Yam.
Why isn't one D Trifecta and one
d alerta [inaudible] what it is.
It's the m one and m two or I've,
but nobody thinks about it that way.
You go to a supermarket,
it doesn't say that.
Well because the ones you get in the
supermarket are probably just one kind.
This other thing is probably, uh, some
freaky. It doesn't work in production,
but it is ultimately very fascinating
to look at this map and think about what
it must have been like,
of course,
to be people that were traveling all
over the world looking for plants and
looking for spices.
I mean,
that was like a big part of the whole
trade where they would get on boats and
travel to foreign lands. They were trying
to find plants and spices and shit.
Oh yeah. Well, let me tell you,
the strawberry story is so cool that
they grow in the forest floors in North
America. Like, you know, uh,
we eastern seaboard and people were
dragging them back to the, uh, to the, uh,
to Europe on colony ships and 15 hundreds.
There's lots of them going back and you
can find accounts in the literature. Um,
and then in 17, 14, there was a spy who
is going to South America, French spy,
who is going to Chile to look at,
uh, of a Spanish fortifications.
And he found a, uh, kind of
strawberry that was being
grown by indigenous peoples.
And he brought this thing
back to, uh, to Europe. And he
wasn't. Then, unfortunately,
these flowers were only male there.
It's like you,
you had a problem where these
plants couldn't self fertilize.
So these plants from South America
and these plants from North America
made their way to the botanical
garden in Versailles where a teenager
essentially started to identify crosses
between these two species that came in
different places because
of spies and colonists.
And they're the pollen got together to
make our modern day strawberry. Whoa.
It's got, it's got four complete sets
of chromosomes. So it's a genetic mess.
Um, but it's something
that we all love and enjoy.
And in my lab helped and sequencing the
genome a few years ago. It's a, this is,
this is how cool that, that plant
domestication is. There's so many stories.
Every one of these plants has
a really cool, articulate,
articulate story about the way
it came to be on our plate.
I just think plants are absolutely
fascinating. Like I said,
I know guys who, uh, grow marijuana
and they use clones and I,
I had no idea what that even meant until
I went to this guy's greenroom and I
was like, wait a minute, you take a,
okay, so you take a piece of this plant,
you grow more plants.
So he had gotten arrested,
he was on the first guys
to get arrested for uh,
the medical weed and Tom
Mccormick and his, um, his setup,
the way they had charged
him for individual plants,
they had said it's clones were individual
plants. But if there were like in bulk,
if there was all on one plant, it
would be legal. It would be less,
less illegal.
Like to take that plant and clone it,
then it becomes a unique
object in and unto itself.
Cause that could be used to drove,
grow more illicit drugs.
Right. It's an independent entity.
Yeah. I always thought it was seeds.
Now it's funny because the, so my main
research, we didn't talk about that stuff,
but I work with identifying
genes associated with
flavors and strawberries and
things like this, using genomics
tools. But I also do a lot with light.
And so I do a lot with led and a lot
with how you are able to change plant
traits using lights. So make them taste
better or change the way they grow. Wow.
And, uh, I've been getting emails. I was
kind of one of the first folks in this,
well shouldn't say that I was in the space
early back in the late nineties. And,
um, I've been getting
emails from like, you know,
stoner eighteen@aol.com for years and,
uh,
people asking about how do you grow a
plant that you would want to grow under
what color lights? Because there's
so much of, um, of that production,
which has been brought into
controlled environments. Um,
I'd never was able to answer the questions
very well because we're forbidden to
work on such products, um, you know,
at our university anyway. Um, and,
uh, but, but there's,
but the using light to control those
aspects of plant growth and development is
something they're really interested in.
That's fascinating.
Is there any benefit to growing plants
in sunlight as opposed to artificial
light?
Well, this is, um,
this is actually a really big part of
my program is I do what's called plant
whispering.
Wait a minute. You probably
that music, do you play your,
your punk rock next to them and
they grow aggressive? That's right.
I'm sorry. What's fight or fight?
The power plant was Flint with Sprig
is basically where we use light as.
So if you think about a plant,
plants have 12 different light sensors
at least that listened to different parts
of the spectrum. So plants
can see red, blue, green,
even the red light that's off the end
of the spectrum that we can't see.
And they can see UV.
And so when we give different pulses or
different treatments at different times
of the day, we can change the way a plant
grows. What metabolites it accumulates.
Maybe the flavors we can make. Cilantro
tastes absolutely horrible. If you,
if you know, if you like it, we can
make it taste. So cilantro really,
it's a difficult to eat. Um,
but we can change plant flavors,
we can change their colors,
we can change any of their attributes.
And now we're trying to understand how
we can give light treatments to plant
materials like harvest strawberries,
treat them with light before
they go into the supply chain,
before they go to the store and through
all the refrigeration and have them
change their gene expression patterns so
they come out the other end better and
last longer in your refrigerator
or last longer in your countertop.
So our idea is is to essentially change
the gene expression in fruits and
vegetables using the language of
light to dictate how they decay.
And my feeling is is that we've got um,
you know that you saved 7 billion.
Now we got 10 billion,
three more billion coming.
We have to use the same space right now
if you buy a tomato at the store or you
are, let's say you pick a
tomato off the plant in Florida,
the odds of that tomato being eaten by
a person are one and two 50% of our food
is wasted. And one because it goes
bad, it either goes bad or, or, or,
or spoils. And in the developing world
it either spoils or gets a infestation.
And one place where we can really solve
the problem or address the problem of
the 10 billion is in
postharvest technology,
but they called postharvest
and this isn't GMO stuff.
This is the other thing I do. We, um,
we're really dedicated to the idea of
getting more food for people by having a,
uh,
by having a more food last longer and
using these kinds of light treatments and
other kinds of, uh, uh, Ma mild chemical
treatments or washes or whatever.
This is one part of it.
Make what we have last longer.
So would this involve artificially
growing these plants and their artificial
lights or what did it involve like growing
the seeds from the plants grown from
artificial light and how would it be done?
I think if you,
that you'll see a lot of this online
these days that there's a lot of companies
that are starting and abandoned warehouses
and places where they use led lights
to do what's called vertical gardening,
where they grow plants in city centers,
um, where you don't have
the transportation costs
and the carbon footprint.
So you can bring plants to market cheaper
and maybe even higher quality products.
So, um, what I think about it, and this
is where we think about this versus Gmo,
Gmo, we change one gene.
We know exactly what it is.
We understand it emo or
environmental modification of plants,
which is what I like think of plant
whispering. We're changing lots of
genes in ways we don't
necessarily understand,
but we enjoy the outcomes
and people don't really care.
But that's what freaks people out because
people know that like light is not an
artificial lights, not necessarily good
for human beings. Like if you live in a,
a room filled with fluorescent light,
you'll get vitamin D deficiencies, right?
Yes. Oh, is that similar to the light
that we use for plants? And if so,
is there a concern that there's a similar
negative reaction somehow or another
in those plants where they wouldn't be
as healthy as they would be in natural
sunlight? Sure. That you
can have cases where, uh,
plants since your whole
metabolism is driven by light,
the whole material photosynthesis,
that if you have problems
with your light sensing,
that's why you have 13 different
light sensors that control, um,
your growth and development because
you're paying attention to every aspect of
that ambient environment
and making very good, um,
let's say predictions or conclusions based
upon the information you get from the
spectrum. And that's where, uh,
we've been actually thinking where we've
applied the idea of manipulating the
spectrum to change the way
the plant grows. Ultimately,
anything that isn't beneficial,
we're not interested in,
we want to grow better food that's more
nutritious and last longer so that we're
able to grow things more sustainably.
Are these lights normal lights or are
these lights like some very specific
growing type lights in?
They give off a very specific spectrum
that's not like normal led or fluorescent
lights.
Are there specific combinations of LEDs
that are computationally controlled?
So it's controlled at a certain,
what would you say amperage?
Like what would you say as far as wattage?
Well, there, what is the light? The,
what's that media? You kind
of got it. It's um, these,
they're all at different. Um,
in the light business we call it fluence
rate the number of photons that are
produced per cubic foot or
per square meter. The idea is,
is that some of the photons we produce
that gift plants information you can't
see, so you can't really call it
that, uh, you know, intensity. Um,
the stuff that's in UV and off the end
of the red part of the spectrum, it,
it has information for plants
that's really potent, but it's uh,
not information that you can see,
but the plant makes,
if you put a plant under far red light,
the stuff off the end of the red part
of the rainbow, the plant goes buzzard,
it gets, starts growing really lanky and
long. It accumulates specific pigments.
It,
yeah.
It allows you to manipulate the
plant size and body of the plant.
And does it have any consequence on the
actual product to the plant produces
that's consumed by humans, whether it's
a tomato or an avocado or whatever.
Is there anything about this light that
changes the actual food that you eat?
Oh sure. Yeah. And we, what we use it for,
and we've done most of our experiments
on sprouts, like Kale sprouts.
We can make Kale sprouts changed the level
of glucose scintillates which are the
anticancer compounds. We can increase
that stuff just by using light.
We can change, probably give you
cancer when that be ironic. Well yeah,
you also can change the uh, like
the attractive colors, you know,
make things that are purple or green.
I can make a others a
kind of lettuce can grow
under eight different light treatments.
That gives you essentially eight different
kinds of lettuce leaves that taste
different. Look different,
tastes different, look diff. Wow.
And is it discernible to the naked eye?
Like would I be able to walk in there
and know which one is given off?
Which thing? Or was it
just a no, it's just,
it's a recipe of light that gives us a
given output. You know what I'm saying?
Like if you had four different rooms,
you are growing for
different kinds of lettuce,
would I be able to walk in those rooms
and discern that there's any difference
in the light of each individual? Sure.
Oh, you would like crazy. Yeah. Oh, okay.
It's um, there's a lot of this stuff
you can even find online with like, uh,
if you look at like led and plant growth,
you'd see all kinds of different
ways that people do this.
The problem is that most places stick
plants under a purple light or under a
pink light and they get some effect. Um,
what, we don't want to just grow a plant,
we want to tell it how to grow and I
think the future of growing plants in
controlled environments will be deeply
rooted in this ability to control how
they grow. The keyword is control,
man. I know what you're trying to do.
Trying to make lettuce. It fucks with
my head. I know what you're doing dude,
with your light fee.
I just seems like that's the thing that
people would be worried the most is that
there would be some sort
of nutritional deficiency.
And something that's grown with artificial
light that growing something in the
sunlight is somehow or
another better for you.
Does that make any sense at all or is that
just total nonsense? It could be true,
but that's the idea is that we might
not be, well, what we're looking for is,
again, we're not looking for like
the uh, the, you know, the, the, the,
the deleterious result.
What we're trying to do is what is the
combination of variables that we can
control to make something that's better
for people. That's what I'm dedicated to.
That's where I want to go there.
So it seems to me that there's just
a giant positive aspect to this about
keeping food for longer,
feeding more people,
giving people nutrition and
areas where it's unavailable.
It seems to me that is a massive,
massive positive benefit of it.
What can we do to medicate or
prevent any negative aspects of it?
You know, the, the negative aspects
of it being that somehow or another,
it could harm people somehow or another.
The corporation's behind it would act in
a greedy way that would be detrimental
to the area where the crops are grown
or whatever. What can be done? Yeah.
I think in,
in,
I guess I'm kind of a tooting our own
horn here by saying we need to support
public science.
You know,
we've got this group of people like
in the land grant university system,
this was a brilliant idea that came out
of the moral act back in the 1860s where
they established a university
in every state that's job was,
was to take care of the public need,
where you train the students,
you help to farmers,
you do the research that puts you at
the cutting edge to help the farmers and
train the students. And that's
a model that's still here today.
University of California Davis is
the best in the world at this and a,
and they're amazing at the things
that happened there. The problem is,
is that as a nation, we've been less
excited to fund science right now.
If I write a proposal to the USDA
or National Science Foundation, um,
the odds of it getting
funded are between five, 10%.
And if you think that they have these
competitions once a year, you know,
you may go 10 years without
getting a research award.
A lot of labs are closing up.
We're not training students like we
used to and it's because of there hasn't
been this public demand to fund science.
And I think a lot of that comes from,
they go, well, people are scientists.
They're are just in the
pocket a Monsanto anyway.
Why do we care when
that's totally not true.
The best defense against an evil empire
is your public scientist and we're,
and we're struggling for tools right now.
How does one get hired?
Like if one is going to
college and you're graduating,
you're getting your master's in,
whenever you're getting it in and you
get recruited by a company like Monsanto,
has that happened or do you go
to them and look to get a job?
Like how does a scientist become a
good scientist like yourself or an evil
scientist?
Like,
even the most evil we would think
the guy who created the atomic bomb,
but Oppenheimer wasn't evil at all and
he was actually really disturbed by the
whole event,
the thing that he had created.
She was a part of this scientific
process that ultimately seemed necessary.
The time being the first person
to come up with this bomb.
So how does one get high,
but that's very distracting.
But how does one get hired like out of
college and how many scientist as more
like a company like Monsanto employed?
Well,
Monsanto is I think 24,000 employees.
But Dick,
how many of them are scientists?
I don't know. I don't know.
Probably a good chunk of else just takes
out the garbage. But, but to be honest,
that, you know, I know lots of,
I do know lots of people who work there
and lots of our former students from our
program have gone there because they're
hiring, you know, universities aren't.
They are. And uh, but
just to give you an idea,
you go through at least
four years of undergraduate.
You require sometimes a master's degree,
sometimes as a phd.
That takes you four to seven years.
Then you're talking about post doc time
where you're looking at between one in
six years. So you're 35, 36,
37 years old before you ever even
get a job. And that is insane.
And that's if you in, in academia where
I work, it's so rare to get a job.
Um, it's really tough getting
academic positions. Um,
but the companies are
happy to take these people,
especially people with good backgrounds
in plant breeding because Monsanto at
the end of the day,
they're not a GMO company.
They're not a chemical company anymore.
They're a plant genetic improvement
company and they're working on breeding
plants so that then you can add
that gene to the elite background.
There's only so much you can do with a
GMO transgene the rest of that has to be
done by breeding. And, uh, lots of plant
breeders, like people come through my lab,
uh, the two plant breeders to my lab, one
of them got snapped up by one company,
another one got snapped up by
another. Um, right out of the PHD,
each one of them into a six figure
plus salary plus all kinds of benefits.
Do you ever think about
going over to the dark side?
I've been recruited many
times and forces with you,
but it's my mission. You
know, I, I like, I, I like,
how are you staying with
my star wars terminology? I
could, I could, you know, um,
my, my Yoda said, stay in
university. You must. Um, I was, um,
my,
my whole thing is I think I like being
in the public sector because I don't like
to have secrets. I don't
like to have proprietary
information that I can't share.
My whole thing is, and I've, and
I've been this way my entire career.
When I got the first little
bit of strawberry sequence
information with $1,800
grant that I got from the Florida
Strawberry Association, um,
we got the first little bit
of strawberry information.
We gave it away because the idea was to
spark more research and more discovery.
We could've sat on it and
use it just for our lab.
But you guys live the Elon
Musk's of strawberries. That's
the idea. You know, you,
you make it, you distributed
your work faster, open access,
open source as fast as you
can. And, um, so, uh, but,
but this is the main thing with the
companies. You know, for me it's about,
it's about that role and I like to work
synergistically with the companies.
I don't, you know, I have good
relationships with Monsanto employees,
Dal employees, you name
any company because we have
the same clients, you know,
my job is to make sure, uh, farmers
know how to use Monsanto products,
Monsanto seeds. So I need to know
what the company's up to. Well,
it's just,
it seems so crazy that it's so easy to
get hired by a giant corporation and
difficult to get hired by
public universities it seems,
but it's totally logical.
Obviously there's going to be way more
people that are pursuing a degree in
science and there are openings.
So is that difficult to encourage young
people to get into science because of
that? When they look at job prospects,
is that a real issue? I think it is. And,
and really one of the funny
ironies here is that back in 1999,
Monsanto actually gave my university
some money towards a position.
So they said, you guys are short on
faculty here. Let's start one there.
And they hired a guy who's never done
anything for Monsanto ever since has done
some beautiful science for
the public good. And, uh,
we're always criticized about
that. People say to me, well,
you've got that position
in your department.
That must mean everything you say has
to go to. It's like, totally not that,
you know, I'm grateful that
companies do anything for us.
If, if anything, you know,
like if, if anybody wanted to
build a new building on our campus,
I wouldn't say no, but that doesn't
mean they're going to get any favors.
So when you,
okay,
if you are involved in
any sort of a project,
will any sort of a scientific
analysis of something,
are you required to release the results
to your superiors before you go public
with them?
Or is there no obligation whatsoever?
You could just tell anybody at any
time what, what you've discovered.
He had no obligation. I research,
I research what I research and um,
w what I can raise money
for from USDA, NSF, Nih,
wherever I can get money from public
sources, uh, even strawberry industry.
I can do some strawberry industry
sources that give me some funds,
but that no one goes,
there's no filter. And
sometimes it's good to have people
read just to make sure you don't say
something dumb, but there's nobody who
ever says, no, you can't publish this.
And if they did,
I'd publish it anyway because this
is about science and the truth.
It's not about making anybody happy.
Well that's the big conspiracy.
It was always the big conspiracy in
almost anything that's in the public eye
when people are allowed to scrutinize
something from the outside.
And guess what the process is. I didn't
know. And that's what I had to ask you.
You, you could have easily just said
to me, I mean, as far as I knew,
you could have easily just said,
well,
everything that I do has to go through
a board and they have to devote on
whether, I don't know, I have no idea.
And most people in that same place. Yes,
I've been accused of uh,
like with different jobs that have had
different shows and even working for the
UFC have someone telling me
what I can and can't say.
And that's just not the case.
But most of what I do is super simple.
I'll just talking about fights,
like if someone told me not
to talk about something,
it would be like not much significance.
Okay.
It's just about a martial arts event
while you're talking about is these
discoveries that could potentially impact
untold thousands of people in a very
beneficial or in a very negative way.
So everybody's got that worry people.
But again,
it's being on the outside.
That's what
I totally get that because when,
and especially when we're in a country
where we're all pretty comfortable and we
all have plenty of food and we have a
few bucks in our wallet to do stuff that
we do tend to focus on the,
the worries and I'm the what
ifs because everything's fine.
We're afraid of something
upsetting the apple cart.
But I can tell you as a scientist that
if I were to find something like just
through some process,
through some experiment,
find something wrong with a Monsanto
product or a dow product or whatever,
I don't like to just pick on the big m
I find something wrong with a product in
agriculture that would shift the paradigm,
that would change it from something safe
and used everywhere to something that
we better have some alarming care with.
Um, that would be something that it,
when I published that it
would be on the best journal,
it'll be in science or nature and then
it would be replicated by other labs
right away. As soon as it was
published, I would get huge notoriety.
I'd get grants forever.
I wouldn't be in that 5% anymore.
I'd be getting leading grants because
I was the guy who broke the rules.
I was the one who broke the paradigm and
probably get a Nobel prize out of it.
So you don't,
you don't think to do would
be any negative repercussions
before it was clearly
established that you are
correct. I mean, if you're,
what like we were talking about before,
if it's involving a corporation that's
profiting in the billion dollar range and
making an insane amounts of money and you
have some information that would put a
monkey wrench into the gears of
this incredible moneymaking venture,
you don't think would,
could repercussions. No, I'll tell
you exactly what would happen.
And I'm sure this is what would happen.
The first people I would let know
would be the company that makes it,
gets your product off the market.
Here's what I got.
And then your brakes would fill in your
car, arsenic would show up. Tuna fish.
Well,
let's see. That's the kind of stuff
that you only movies and, yeah.
And then once again, going back, you know,
Dr Evil, you know, um, but, but it's,
I think that a company
who would make them, who,
if someone were to reveal a mistake,
they would be the first ones who
would want to know. And they might,
because they would have proven
though by history and in an ancient,
and when you go back and you talk about,
sure. Things like hobby GM, right?
How about this whole fucking ignition
thing? We talked about it earlier today.
They knew and they kept
their fucking mouth shut. No,
it's a good point. You know,
and it's,
and it,
it ties in with my kind of naive idealism
sometimes I think everybody's going to
do the right time. I know. Honk rock
hippy, I know, but at the same time,
but the other side of the coin
is, is that, uh, if I were,
if I was the guy who discovered
the ignition issue and I were in,
I was an investigative reporter and I
was able to put together seven or eight
cases of this and we'll tie it to the
ignition and did a study that analyzed the
mechanism of failure.
And I went to GE or GM and said,
this is a problem. This doesn't
work. And they refuse to respond.
I'd put this in the newspapers
that I would look at it,
I put a blog that everybody would see.
I'd come here and talk to you about it
and I would blow the lid off of that and
I'd get a Pulitzer Prize.
Right. An awesome book. And the book would
get published and you'd make kazillions
well hopefully, and it's a, but this is
how it should work is that we got to have,
but those are scientific processes that
go through a series of steps to develop
evidence that's analyzed to come to a
conclusion and then we can shape policy
based on that. And that's
where I get excited about,
about what we can do at sign.
Well there,
I mean there's reasons that people were
worried though about information leaking
out that could harm companies.
I mean he's reasons why people shield
their identity when they're leaking
certain information because if
they get caught and then those,
those companies get really pissed off
and they, even if it's just lawsuits,
I mean any company like Monsanto could
cripple any normal person just with
lawsuits. You would never be able to keep
up. They're just smash it with lawsuits.
When you are in charge of
this kind of information,
obviously we're not talking about the
conspiratorial stuff we're talking about
like the nutritional things, like the
bananas that you're passionate about,
that the vitamin A and m.
Um,
what is that feeling like when you,
you,
you're being ignored or you're being,
either it's a conspiracy by these
companies that they don't want,
or these people that they don't want
to open up the door for genetically
modified foods or it's ignorance to the
science involved with these people and
they're,
they're massive amounts of blindness.
What does it feel like
to be the guy who knows?
Because that seems that's
gotta be a crazy place to be,
to be the scientist who actually
understands the mechanisms involved in the
creation of these very organic products
that were manipulated by human beings
and how they could benefit human beings.
Nobody understands you.
They're all thinking you're fucking crazy,
or you're a shale,
or what does that feel?
And it's horrible.
But this is why I appreciate you so much
and letting me do this and why people
like Kara Santa Maria who has been so
helpful and talking about the GMO issue.
Um, it, it is an opera.
Anytime we can talk about this and
get people to understand, you know,
where I'm coming from, that
there's trust here. Um, Joe,
every night I answer 30 minutes to an
hour of emails from the concern public who
asks questions to me about this.
I was watching your Twitter today,
your feed between yesterday
when I announced it,
you were going to be on and
today, dude, you've been nonstop.
I mean your tireless with this stuff.
You have a real,
an incredible passion for this.
I've done Reddit's where, um,
I would say I'll come on with
an ask me anything for, uh,
two hours and I'll stay on for six.
I'll stay on,
I'll answer a thousand questions. Every
one of them hand done. What? I mean,
I'm not cutting and pasting.
I'm addressing that person's concern
because this is how we're going to change
it.
It comes from talking to people who have
concerns and and people who are worried
and help them understand the science.
Because if they get this,
then they're less likely to worry
about the real problems and ever.
That's why we were that the artificial
problems and start focusing on the real
problems.
And how important is it to fund more
public science and to try in some way to
make more people attracted to what
you're doing as opposed to going over to
these universities.
Because if people really are concerned,
like probably that's the
best way to deal with it.
The best way to deal with
sciences to fund science. Yes,
100% it's the fun science and make sure
that public scientists have the tools
they need to maintain.
They don't get corrupted.
The idea of being corrupted seems so
tempting. Well, but it, but you know,
when we had to have to be careful because,
because companies can't fund individual
laboratories or programs or universities
and, and it doesn't
necessarily mean corruption.
Of course they can be very beneficial
and then they can help us a lot. And,
and I would love to have Monsanto hand
me a check for 5 million bucks and say,
have at it. Do what you want.
I bet it's on the way. Right?
I been waiting an awfully long time
Joe and people have been saying it for,
for 20 years now that I should be
getting everyone ready. They're ready.
They're writing that check right now.
They're just licked the pen. But a movie.
The other really cool thing
though that we can do is,
is I think get kids fired up
about science and with kids.
I find that this idea of genetic
engineering isn't a big deal to them.
That they kind of get it and they see
it's kind of like molecular Lego's.
They kind of get the idea that you can,
uh,
take something out of one thing and
move it to another. You can move traits.
You can. Kids have this kind of, uh, uh,
modular understanding of the world anyway,
that they're comfortable with bits and
pieces coming together in different ways
to make different products.
And when we talk,
I spend about maybe two or three mornings
a month with third to fifth grade or
seventh graders, mostly third and
fifth. That's, there's a lot of fun.
Third graders have the best. And we talk
about how to solve the citrus problem.
And I told her graders, yeah, how
many of them say magic? Uh, well,
you know what they say even crazier
stuff, which is great. Well, and start us,
I'll give you an example.
Like I show them my way.
I teach this as I show them what
the problem is, that there's a,
an insect that moves a bacterium to a
tree that get sick and it dies from bad
nutrition. And I'll say, what are the,
and I'll show them all that and I'll say,
okay, stop. Now you guys are the
scientists. Give me a solution.
And the hands go up. And one of them
will say, give it better nutrition.
And then another one will say,
uh,
maybe you could cross it with a tree
that doesn't get sick. And they get that,
you know, they're, they've, they've
got sex figured out. Well by then, um,
then you talk about, um, uh,
then one of 'em will say in the funny one
was build them in a dome under the sea
where the bug can't get to them, you
know? And, and the challenge for me,
that one's awesome. Yeah. Well I, I
told the teacher to keep an eye on,
the cool part about that
though is that he's right.
If you could isolate the
things from the insect.
And so my challenge as a teacher in that
scenario when I'm interrogating their
interest in science, is to somehow never
tell one of them that they're crazy,
that I have to take whatever answer
they give me in somehow loop it back to,
well, here's how you're writing,
how it just might work. Oh,
I see a hundred percent attempting
encouragement of curiosity.
I am getting kids to creatively solve
a problem and a dome under the ocean at
Dome under the ocean and you know
what? And, and when you do that,
but then when you,
then I should do that.
Then I go forward into the slides
about how we are solving the problem.
I can say, you know, Dave, you raised
your hand and said, use better nutrition.
Look at how they're using
nutrients to make it better.
Someone else said you control the insect.
Here's five ways they're controlling
the insect. It shows these kids,
they validate that their suspicions about
science and that their creative juices
that solve the problem were correct.
So how do you address the kid
but the dome onto the ocean?
What do you cause there's so many
fucking problems with that idea. Well,
I tell him in school, but there's a whole
photosynthesis issue. There's oxygen.
You'd run out of air.
Yeah,
there's Kranz and paint and
things in the world needs artists.
And I kind of can steer them that
direction. So what do you I I,
I'm very like Stephen King,
like the Dome Mu Three road.
I made a whole fucking ocean garden that
way if there's ways to tie them back in.
But I think the whole idea is,
is that they're so used to their
teacher saying wrong. That,
here's a case where I set up a situation
around a real problem that's in their
state,
may be in their yard that allows them to
actually exercise their science muscles
as little kids. And I think that's
a big way we changed this. Yeah.
That is a really important point
when it comes to human beings,
little children is figuring out a way
to not make their curiosity in negative,
you know, don't scold them for having
a ridiculous imagination, you know,
express the issue with it
or how it could be. Right.
And why it's probably
wrong, you know, but,
and you got to figure out a way to reward
them for taking that chance to come up
with this dome under the
ocean. Cause that, who knows,
that kid might have
three of those that suck,
but one of those that everybody
goes, hey, wait a minute.
Well that's the paradigm shift. Goddamn
point. Yeah. That's what we want.
And there's a great video,
a great ted talk by named Alison Gopnik
and Alison, I forget where
she's at, maybe Berkeley.
She is a a scientist who studies the way
kids think and she shows that children
when they're born and through the next
few months are actually the smartest
they've ever going to be in terms of
their ability to test hypotheses and
synthesize information. And she shows
the way kids do this. And so, uh,
that maybe I don't want to be like an
indictment of the way we train people,
but there's a certain amount of curiosity
and exploration that we tend to break
out a kids. And I think,
um, as, as an educator,
as someone who was really
committed to education,
that getting to kids is the most
important way to get science to improve,
get them so excited about the
cool things we can do. And uh,
it breaks my heart when I have a kid show
up at the march against Monsanto who's
holding a sign saying,
your science causes autism.
It doesn't.
And here's a kid who's going to now go
through life thinking science is evil and
done by evil people with evil
intentions. When, uh, when really we're,
we're trying to get that kid may hold the
solution to the next big citrus crisis.
Yeah.
It's,
it's unbelievably ironic that so many
anti-science websites are online.
I mean,
just the idea.
How the fuck do you think that computer
got built on? Exactly. All natural,
all natural is an apple.
This is not an all natural computer
you're typing as recipe through. It's, um,
yeah,
I think it's really important that people
recognize that science has brought us
virtually every single thing
that you enjoy today, uh,
outside of the natural world outside
of coconuts falling and you eat them.
You know,
there's,
there's so much that we have relied
on science about the way we stay warm,
the way we keep things cool,
the way we communicate with each other.
And this fear that people have
about foods being modified,
I think is, it's, it's a big one and it's
one of the biggest ones in this country.
And so to have a guy like you come on and
express why we should be concerned and
why we shouldn't be concerned. And why,
what, what the positive aspects of our,
I think, I think it's really,
really important, man.
I think a lot of people need to hear
what you have to say and they need to be
able to listen to it from an objective
standpoint and understand that this is a
very complex issue. It's a very
complex and it's very important.
I appreciate that.
We'd have time to talk about it because
it's something that I really encourage
people. There's places where
you can get great resources. Um,
there's a blog called biofortified.org
which is written by scientists who are
independent scientists and it really
is just an information hub about this
particular topic. And, uh, some of
the articles are, articles are clever.
They're all written very softly.
There nothing is, you know,
[inaudible] it's all really about
the science and it's independent.
It's not funded by any of the companies.
Have you ever thought about doing a
podcast cause you'd be excellent at it?
I would love to do it. There's some
funny things about that. Um, uh,
he can't talk about anti podcast
clause and your university contract or
something. No, I have a podcast.
I do, but I don't do it as
me. Oh, you son of a bitch.
I do it as I do it as a character.
And it was no dare you,
you can't talk about it.
And I can't talk about it because,
did you mention it for them? They're
going to find it. They're gonna find it.
And I guess the problem is, is that
wants things from me. I know what the,
once the cat's out of the bag,
the funny part is, that's too bad.
The reason I wanted to keep it secret
though, and maybe here's my appeal to,
don't go look for it. Okay.
But it's still secret.
What's it about science and you're a
character on a science podcast. Yeah.
Ooh, I'm a moderator who taught
him. They're gonna know that.
And I guess I'll figure it out, but
I'll keep it going anyway. I mean,
keep it going.
Don't admit to it,
no matter what Colbert did it for
how many years, you know? So, uh,
and it's very much along that line. It's
very much along that line. It's a, it's,
it's a lot of fun talking about the
play a dummy or a smart guy, uh,
a dumb smart guy.
Oh,
so you play a guy who doesn't understand
the science and you have to correct
people or they have to correct
you. Is that what happened?
Or something like that.
So you played the antagonists and so
they come along and then they have to use
you as a tool to get to
the root of the problem,
the ignorance of people that
was signed essentially. Yes.
And then some stuff that's completely
off the wall and it's, but it's, it's,
it's really fun because it's a great
way to get the science out there and it
allows me to have some fun as a, uh, as,
as a character that I couldn't have as a,
uh,
established professor and chairman
of, of, of a, of a department.
Totally understood. Yeah. That also
is now linked to a great song online.
Well, you need his rapper name, you know
how yams have their own separate name.
It'd be Yam. And then they have the other
thing. You need a rapper named dude.
Yeah, I do have one. I like, what is it?
Write it down. I'm not going to say it.
I hope it's like Kaiser San Jose. Most
things are, it's one, it's one better.
You can even, you can even look it
up online here. Okay. That's it.
I can't talk about that. Don't talk.
It just doesn't violate your trust.
I think it's good because the thing is,
is that I do want to talk to people who
don't agree with, um, technology. Well,
why don't you do this?
Why don't you have a podcast where people,
instead of like you've seen you, I've
seen rather you spend so much time typing.
I'm sure you can type or you can talk
while they're quicker than you can type
all that shit out.
So why don't you just take those
questions and have people send them to you
every week. And if they're not
redundant, just that way you can choose,
you know what you've already
dressed and you could say, hey,
we covered that in podcast two or three.
You would have a kick ass podcast man,
I'd be happy to support it too. Well,
why don't we, why don't we talk about
that and I always so easy to do.
The one I wanted to do was the uh,
crop domestication podcast where I talked
about finally someone's doing that.
I wanted to know the
one we talk about this,
the strawberries and the yams house stuff.
I wanted to talk about each one of
their stories and how they came to be an
interview,
the experts and so great idea and it,
and so all these things
are kicking around.
The problem is is I have three full time
jobs. I mean I'm an administrator, um,
for a department of 59 faculty.
I'm a full time research scientist and
I'm a full time science communicator.
And so, um, I literally do work 6:00 AM
to midnight seven days a week. And uh,
and except for exercise time, you know,
the stuff I do there I am, uh, I'm,
I'm in this,
what are you hiding from?
What are you running from running from
something? No, I don't know. I guess.
I think a lot of work, I guess I guess
when I'm running from is uh, I'm, I'm,
I'm running from,
um,
I'm waiting for one of these things to
wear out where I can just cut it back to
two.
That's an amazing work ethic that you
have and I can understand why you wouldn't
have enough time, but if you have
enough time to do all these tweets,
I'm saying even if he just did a
half an hour once a week. Yeah.
If you just for a half
an hour once a week,
just got a collection of maybe you can
get an intern to collect some of the best
questions. I'm sure somebody be happy to
do that. You press record on an iPhone,
that's all you need to
do. I mean, the, the,
the quality of the recording you get from
a regular iPhone is pretty much worth
it.
You can hold it up to your mouth and just
go over the piece of people could hear
you turn the paper. Okay. What
do we got here? Okay. This one,
this is important and just ramble into
the microphone and I'm telling you it
would be popular as fuck and you'd be able
to quit your other jobs. None of that.
And that works great. Actually, I have
used the iPhone in my character issues dot
and a, and they got a nice
mixer at home. I pumped,
punch it through the mixer so
you know how to do this stuff.
This is all second nature. I mean,
I used to be in a band, you know.
Oh that's right. I know. But I imagine
there's a couple things I would,
and I love doing this kind of media stuff.
It would be a really
easy thing for me to do.
It's just a question of where to
wedge it into a full schedule.
You really gotta try it.
You really,
I think you'd be excellent on it cause
you're were really great today. I really,
really appreciate talking to you. Do you
ever feel like moving out of Florida?
Cause it's too stupid. Um, you
know it the first be honest. No, I,
I, I, I've actually, I really love
Florida. I really it, you know why though?
But it's my job that does it. I
never planned on being there. Um,
I only Gainesville, yes. I used
to live in Gainesville. Yeah.
My Dad went to the University of
Florida. I didn't know that. Yeah.
My stepdad went there for
architecture or something. Well, I,
I totally admire the faculty there and
when I had the opportunity to apply there,
I applied and thinking there's
no way I'll ever get the call.
And I got the interview and then
I interviewed and I thought,
there's no way I'll ever get the job.
And then when they called me for the job,
um, you know, I showed up and I,
I've always felt like the, uh,
the guy on the all star team who just
gets to put on the team because he's,
you know, the, uh, his team didn't
have anybody else. I, you know,
I'm so surrounded by good people. I always
feel very dwarfed there. But, um, uh,
12 years later, they are, 10 years
later they put me in charge of it.
So I must be doing something right. But
you obviously have a real passion for it.
And like I said,
you're in Florida.
You got to be the smartest guy in Florida
by far. It's you and Billy Corbin.
She get together.
He would dominate Florida level.
He is the director of cocaine cowboys.
I don't know him. He's awesome.
I thought you meant the smashing
pump. No, no, no, no, no.
The thing in Florida is every time the
news story breaks about, you know, the,
the guy having relations with a sandwich
or you know, uh, Florida, I go home.
Please don't be here.
Please don't be a thing.
If you've ever seen the Florida
man Twitter account, no.
One of the greatest fucking things
the world's ever known. Okay,
I'll watch your spare time.
Go to the Florida man Twitter feed and
just read like fucking crazy how many
morons or are in Florida. Yeah. It's
all true. I mean, I, you know, I, I,
I have a great relationship
with the growers in our
state and the people who are
doing the farming and the
people in those industries.
There's a lot of great people in Florida.
Don't get me wrong. No, no, I'm not.
But there's a lot of morons too.
Absolutely.
I'm on the morons in California and that,
but that's why it would be hard to
pull me away is because you develop
relationships with these people who are,
who are seriously struggling.
And you look at the citrus
industry, strawberry industry, um,
with the competition they're
getting is unprecedented.
And these are folks down the highway
who are farming to feed us good food and
doing everything they can to stay afloat.
And I am so glad that to be all
the work with them, Kevin Fault.
But thank you very much. And please
do a God damn podcast where you serve.
These people would love it.
I think you could help a lot of people
by answering a lot of questions like you
did today. You were fantastic. I
appreciate the hell out of you, man.
Don't do it very, very much. People.
You can follow him on Twitter.
It's Kevin Folta,
f o l t a on Twitter.
Your website is k Folta at blog spot.
It's a blog called illumination.
Beautiful. Is there a link to that
from your Twitter feed? Um, but yeah,
just somewhere in there. Okay. Okay. All
Right, ladies and gentlemen. That's it.
Goodbye. Bye. Bye. Big Cast.
All right.