Hello Freak bitches.
I'm just something has hit the Internet
that I need to show you.
I guess it may or may not be legit,
but I decided to retire young thanks to
the cheese catches later.
Conor mcgregor.
He's trolling you think so.
Fuck yeah,
there's a lot of people have been
hitting me up telling me to show you and
no one knows what's going on.
I decided to retire young,
which means like 34 eventually.
Listen man.
Unless he got fucking head kick today
and knocked into oblivion.
The idea that he's going to go out on a
loss like that to nate Diaz Hook.
He's got plenty of cash.
If he wanted to retire young and step
away,
I mean I guarantee you,
he probably made somewhere in the
neighborhood of 5 million bucks of the
Aldo fight.
He probably made more than that for the
Nate Diaz fight.
I would.
I would imagine after he spent a fuck
load of it,
he's probably still got a few million
bucks laying around.
He's a hero in Ireland.
He could always make money.
You can always run a gym and be fine,
but if I had a gas,
it doesn't make any sense.
The only reason why it would make sense,
the only reason why it would make sense
as connor had actually thought about
retiring from mma before he got the call
for the UFC.
There was a point in time where he had
some friends that were experiencing some
serious health issues from fighting and
then most recently that young man from
the Portuguese guy died in an mma
contest,
which I think took place in the UK.
What wasn't he involved or related in
some way to one of those guys that just
died too?
Didn't he know him?
Are trained with him?
I think he trained with the Portuguese
guy that just died recently.
It is entirely possible in that sense,
but if I had to guess,
there's no way he'd do it like this.