Her low freak bitches.
A lot of times it's just giving people
information right then and there and
saying,
you know,
getting people riled up and excited and
giving them the support to do it.
So,
um,
we're going to do about a 40 city tour
of solutions grassroots in New York
state in February and March.
So we'll do like three or four towns a
day.
Um,
and I'll,
I'll be doing that with Zephyr teachout
who was incredibly popular,
um,
candidate for governor who won 35% of
the vote against Andrew Cuomo and his
last election.
Um,
and a number of musical guests.
I think we're going to be doing that in
February and March.
We'd love to do the solutions grassroots
tour in California.
Um,
I'd love to do it in other states.
So you can go to solutions,
grassroots.com you can sign up there.
You can,
there,
there are links that directly you can
buy solar.
Uh,
you can buy wind power,
you can do all of that at a consumer
level.
But more importantly,
what we're trying to do with solutions
grassroots is getting grassroots,
um,
energy movement towards getting
ourselves off fossil fuels.
Because you know this,
even though like you can map this out at
Stanford and you have these great,
amazing celebrities all talking about
renewable energy,
the people have to get it done.
We have to get it done.
We have to say,
you know what?
I don't want to buy oil and gas and coal
to heat my home to power my home
anymore.
I don't want to do that anymore.
I want to get off of it.
You know?
Um,
some of the resources are very
expensive,
like buying an electric car that's out
of the range for a lot of people.
But getting solar on your roof actually
is economic.
It makes sense.
Getting a buying locally sourced wind
power is possible in a lot of states.
It's not in California,
I don't think,
but it is in New York state.
There's a company called ethical
electric that we have a link
to@ourwebsitesolutionsgrassroots.com.
Or you can just basically say,
you know what?
I'm going to buy wind power instead of
buying electricity from coal or oil or
gas.
And um,
you know,
you've done a huge amount right there.
But the biggest thing that we've done in
terms of all this stuff,
New York,
by stopping fracking kept the equivalent
of 57 million cars off the road just by
keeping that stuff in the ground there.
And I think the equivalent of taking 72
coal fire power plants offline for a
year,
the movement is actually going to help
solve these things.
Um,
so it's,
it's like how do you get people
together?
Well,
we just get together,
have a film screening.
There are a lot of great films on this
stuff.
We have a tour,
we have a talk and you start organizing
locally,
I assume happened.
I just bought a new book that I highly
recommend about dolphins.
It's called wet goddess,
but it's available on Amazon.
It's about a relationship basically like
a person in a 50 shades of grey for
dolphins.
Yeah,
it really is.
Did you actually read it now?
I'm ready.
I just got it just delivered today.
But it's,
it's a,
it's a goddess.
That's so funny,
but it's a,
yeah,
I bought two of them.
You can never have
too many.
I like the cover.
It's just like,
it's kind of like a scrapbook with
adults.
Why did you buy two?
Why did you buy too?
I just feel like it's not going to be a
for,
I don't know.
It's not going to be around for long.
You're holding onto it.
You're going to be a hoarder from
dolphin porn.
Well,
look at this.
I mean like they're used,
they're going for $61
yeah.
See,
I think there's a big mark.
Well look,
this one's 900 wives.
Fuck.
How is that?
Is that probably not all paperback?
That's gotta be the hard copy.
That's to actually get the dolphin to
fuck you.
It's a code code underground.
[inaudible] about,
look at the spout on that Dolphin.
You just buy the book and inside the
book it's just directions to this place
in San Diego.
That's one of the weird things about
people
when it comes to stuff like,
like a dolphin porn or something like
that.
You would think,
well,
who the fuck would be into that?
And then you put it online and it
attracts a whole community.
And the next thing you know is a message
board all filled with people that are
talking about their dolphin porn and the
Dolphin love and their kinship of you.
If you've heard about that.
Some people,
they don't want to be judged by being
akin to certain animals.
They feel like their Fox kin,
like they feel connected to a Fox.
I,
I don't,
I can't,
uh,
I can sort of understand to a certain
degree.
I did this movie a few years ago and I
had to ride an elephant in it and when I
was standing there with the elephant,
the way the elephant was looking at me
and I was looking at her,
I really felt like,
I was like,
I really love you elephants.
Like I genuinely felt like,
I think I have a crush on this elephant.
Not in a sexual way.
More like,
I just want to hug you and love you.
Yeah.
Trainers have to fall in love with their
animals a lot too.
I don't understand.
Beat them.
I'm like,
stop fucking hitting him.
But that spiked fucking stick.
Yeah.
There are people that believe that they
are akin like,
like they're somehow or another,
they should have been this animal
instead of a person.
You know?
Some people think that they were born
male,
but they really should have been a
woman.
Yeah.
Some people think that they were born a
person,
but they should have been an elephant.
Yeah.
That's,
that's a,
that's a little mental.
Is it though for you to judge?
I'm just saying people don't,
people don't understand does it?
There's a whole tumbler blog about it.
Good Lord.
Do they try to manifest physically into
these things?
Uh,
well some of those folks that are
fluffy's are furries.
Gabriel,
and he's flapping.
Yeah.
Some of those people,
I'm sure that's what they're doing
there.
They're wishing that they actually were
some weird animal.
Yeah.
I think that's escapism.
What do you think?
I think a lot of what people do is
escape is I'm including being into shit
that everybody just accepts.
Like being in a dungeons and dragons,
that's escapism.
Being into cosplay.
That's escapism.
Like at what point do we decide it's
fucked up?
Like it's okay if you want to dress up
and reenact the civil war,
why is it fucked up?
If you want to pretend you're a fox,
like you're not a soldier from 1800
you'd Douchebag,
okay?
You're an asshole who wishes the south
one and you're putting on some ancient
stuff and using a musket,
right?
That's what you're doing.
W you know,
why isn't it?
Why is that okay for you to pretend you
were born Arrow with no internet for you
to pretend that you were born in the
time where there's no cars?
That's okay,
but it's not okay to pretend you're a
fox.
Hey,
see what I'm saying?
It's not okay to be a Fox show live and
let live,
live and let die.
It yourself to see dad,
Dad,
dad.