That what's her brother,
welcome back here.
I'm back.
You're one of the few college professors
that I was a sense of humor about
yourself like that.
Well,
you can,
you can joke around about that.
Exactly.
It's,
it's,
um,
I was talking to you before the show
started about this recent article in the
Atlantic and as soon as I saw it I was
like,
oh,
this is just right up your alley and is,
it's the coddling of the American mind.
And this article is all about one of the
things that you have been talking about
a lot lately and um,
uh,
it's been on a lot of people's minds
that work in academia because it's,
it's,
it's very confusing and it's very
frustrating.
But there is severe limitations on the
words that you can use and the thoughts
even that you can have in this article
is all about trigger warnings.
And uh,
and in one case,
here's,
and there were professors,
listen to this law.
Students were asking fellow professors
at Harvard not to teach rape law.
And in one case,
even use the word violate,
as in that violates the law.
Less it caused distress.
This is the article is called the
coddling of the American mind.
It's in the newest version of the
Atlantic Dot Com.
It's just a couple of days old.
Um,
and it is,
it's fucking crazy what's going on with
kids today.
And this,
this article gets into it and one of
them was about something that,
um,
uh,
there was a professor for protecting
himself with a pseudonym and he wrote an
essay for vox called I'm a liberal
professor in my liberal students,
terrify me,
right?
What the fuck is going on?
Like what is going on where people are
getting in trouble for words like
violate.
Well,
by the way,
one of the authors of that article is a
good friend of mine who is director of
fire.
I can't remember the name of the
accurate,
what the acronym stands for,
but he basically goes around,
his organization,
goes around trying to protect freedom of
speech first amendment at campuses,
precisely because of the unbelievable
chilling effect of these types of lunacy
movements.
It's very strange.
And you know what else is strange?
It seems like you're not allowed to be
conservative in a university and what,
and by conservative I don't mean
restrictive of other people's liberties
like anti gay rights or anti choice or
anti.
I'm talking about fiscally conservative.
I'm talking about being a person who has
the ideas that some in the Republican
Party,
a spouse,
you're not allowed to.
So I'm not sure if we discussed this
before,
but even if we did,
it's worth repeating.
I talked about an article,
an article that was done by some
colleagues of mine.
I don't know them well,
but some,
some academics
where they looked at the political
affiliation of professors at top.
I think it was California and schools,
uh,
whether they identified it or whether
they actually had democratic affiliation
or Republican.
And as you might imagine,
it was extraordinarily skewed towards
Democrats.
But then depending on the field of
study.
So for example,
in sociology and in the humanities and
in women's studies,
women with a y,
by the way,
please don't write women with an e.
That would be sexist at even,
as I just said,
the women oftentimes and women's
studies,
they,
they think that to have men as part of
the word women is itself a form of
aggression.
So they've altered the spelling to
weight men.
Oh no,
that's not real.
So you see,
I know your audience already has the
price of admission covered.
Would that story,
but it's still the word women,
right?
So anyway,
so the same word.
Why?
Why do you have to change the letters?
So in sociology,
do you train,
change the word trigger because it
sounds like the n word or a serious.
You're getting triggered.
I'm triggered,
triggered.
Well,
I'm fucking triggered.
If I was black,
I'd be super triggered.
Well,
I don't know if you noticed some of my
tweets.
Now whenever I tweet anything,
I put a trigger warning trigger warning.
It's not become part of the vernacular
to make it sit there article.
It's too close to the n word.
Way Too close.
I'm triggered.
But anyways,
to finish the point about the study,
44 to one ratio in sociology.
So imagine if you are a student,
take doing an Undergrad in sociology,
right?
It's not a very good thing to have.
Almost all of the professors that you
will ever come across be of one
particular persuasion.
Now some people will write to me and
say,
but what do you mean the Democrats have
everything,
right?
They have truth on their side and the
Republicans are a bunch of hacks.
Now when it comes to evolution
evolution,
that's true,
right?
If,
if,
if on average republicans are more
likely to deny evolution than that point
is well taken,
but when it comes to issues,
is the death penalty,
right or wrong?
What's kind of fiscal policy should you
have?
What type of foreign policy should you
This is not a one plus one,
you know,
scientific equation,
so you should be exposed to multiple
viewpoints,
but of course you shouldn't be because
you should only interact with people who
are similar to you will that.
That is a problem with a lot of people
that go to college,
graduate,
get their phd,
get their doctorate,
and then start teaching and never enter
the real world,
right?
They stay in this sort of insulated
world of academia and then they espouse
these same ideas.
They promote these same idea that they
promote the same way of thinking as if
this is the real world because this is
the only world they know true.
You know,
one of the things about comedians is a
lot of them are really,
really crazy and fucked up and they do a
lot of drugs and they're just out of
control and not and they kind of forget
that other people aren't like that and
sometimes I'll bring like
one of my regular friends around like
the comedy store and around some of my
Canadian friends that are fucking crazy
and they'll go,
Jesus Christ,
these guys just talk about ridiculous
shit that they did.
Like it's no big deal.
And I'm like,
well,
in their world it isn't a big deal in
their world,
this is the normal world and everyone
else is civilian.
That's how they look at it.
That's how you know the quote unquote
hardcore comedians look at it.
I think in academia you have a similar
sort of a situation where they really do
believe in microaggressions.
They think that microaggressions are
real.
There was a fucking.
This is one of the parts of the article
that was really hilarious.
There was a.
They were trying to raise awareness
about microaggressions,
but in doing so and raising awareness
from microaggressions,
they had to give examples of these micro
aggressions which triggered people and
it's an infinite loop of victimology.
So this guy had to apologize.
He apologized for triggering people with
his micro aggression.
Examples of them were like,
aren't you all supposed to be good at
math to Asians like that?
That is a micro aggression.
I mean,
is it a microaggression to say good
things?
This is what confuses me because like if
you said to a black guy,
you guys all have big Dicks,
right?
Is that a microaggression?
Because then that's saying that
perpetuating racial stereotypes,
right?
It is,
but isn't it a good stereotype?
Like everybody wants a big tick,
right?
Right.
Allegedly.
Well,
here's another microaggression that I
thought was hilarious.
I'm colorblind.
I don't see race.
That's a microaggression.
You should see race.
Yes,
you should see race.
So Steven,
Kobe,
when he says he doesn't see race,
he is engaging in microaggression.
Microaggression,
go American.
The word American by the way,
is an aggression.
It's Americans that aggression.
Yet,
how's that?
Well,
because you're surfing all of the
America is to imply that it's only the
United States of America.
Somebody saying that it's America.
It's as if the rest of the countries
don't exist.
Wow.
One of them is America is the land of
opportunity that is a microaggression
and a white.
Is that one offensive sense or here's
another microaggression.
I believe the most qualified person
should get the job.
Oh,
that's illegal.
That's a meritocracy.
That's bad.
How is that possible?
How could it be bad for the most
qualified person to get a job?
Isn't that the whole idea of job
applications?
We have a sponsor for this podcast
called Zip recruiter,
and one of Ziprecruiter's thing is like
if you want to fill it,
if they're trying to fill out a job,
it allows you to post to like 100 plus
job sites with one click and the idea is
to find the most qualified candidate,
which in turn gets you the best person
for the job,
which is a microaggression.
So ziprecruiter is a micro aggression
company.
God,
how horrible.
It's lunacy.
I mean,
you wonder if at some point there'll be
some sort of auto correction of all
this.
I would hope so.
Right?
I think that that is what's going on
with a lot of our culture.
I think what a,
what a lot of our culture is,
is an auto correction for the ignorance
and hypocrisy of like the sixties and
seventies and the eighties.
And so we're going away the other way.
Right?
You know,
with like,
did you see Bernie Sanders speech get
interrupted for black lives matter?
Who doesn't think black lives matter?
I mean,
I want.
I want someone who doesn't think black
lives matter to speak because I.
all I've heard is people who,
who agree black lives matter.
I mean everybody agrees.
I don't,
I don't know anybody who doesn't think
that these shootings,
police shootings are horrific,
but to,
to interrupt a guy who is easily the
most liberal.
That's what was going to say is that of
all the candidates for president,
a guy who is the most diverse,
that guy will march with Martin Luther
King know he marched in the civil rights
movement.
He's been a civil rights advocate since
the 19 sixties and they interrupt his
presidential speeches.
You don't have a theory that a lot of
these,
a lot of these folks,
you know,
the Chegg,
Aveiro wearing tee shirt wearing guys,
they want to feel part of a greater
cause.
Yes.
So even though many of those battles
have passed them by,
they had been won civil rights.
I mean,
of course there's still racism,
but in terms of institutionalized
racism,
we certainly are much better than we
were 50 years ago.
But yet,
you know,
they're young kids,
they revolutionary.
They're wearing Che Guevara.
You know,
Viva La Revolution and they have to
engage in this kind of behavior.
Thirty years from now,
they'll watch that youtube clip and
they'll think they're a bunch of
buffoons.
I think that's a very valid possibility.
I think another possibility is that when
you look at people and they,
they,
they're,
they're trying to find like causes to
support.
I think there's a lot of people out
there that are just fucking assholes.
Right?
And what they're doing is trying to find
something that allows them to get out
that asshole of aggression and be
justified.
Right?
You know,
something that allows them to be
righteous,
like black lives matter.
You fucking pizza.
And there's screaming at someone who
believes black lives matter,
uh,
screaming.
Someone was not even remotely racist,
but they will.
They will yell it in your face the way
they did at this Bernie Sanders thing in
order to just get their rocks off.
Whatever personal frustrations,
whatever psychological failures that
they have got bouncing around inside
their head,
whatever closed loop thinking they have,
they're using these valid points and
these things that a lot of people think
about as a sounding board,
which is why they're the ones who are
interrupting.
It's not that this,
this demands attention at this moment in
order to solve a problem because there's
a fucking fire.
We have to put this fire out right now
where people are going to die.
No,
this has nothing to do with that.
It gives them the opportunity to grand
stand,
to take a moral high ground and his
scream out and beg for attention and to
be good because nobody can.
You can't say it like racism fucking
sucks.
Nobody can say,
hey,
it's not that bad.
You know,
he can't say that.
So you can.
You could be like super aggressive and
really shitty and confrontational and
insulting about a cause you believe in
and that is one of the problems that I
have with this whole social justice
warrior movement because I find a lot of
these people that are involved in it to
be asshole human beings and even though
I,
I agree with a lot of what they support,
I think they suck and when I go to their
twitter pages and I look at what their
interactions are,
all their interactions are insulting
people and getting angry at people and,
and,
and it's all negative and I see if I can
please interject.
I think they don't have an ability to
accept that people might have differing
opinions.
Right.
You and I can debate many issues and yet
we can leave here both being respectful
of one another and so I think that this
course is.
I'm right.
If you think otherwise you must be an
asshole and I will shut you down.
And so they really don't have this
capacity,
this critical capacity to engage in
reasoned dialogue.
I saw it.
I mean,
I'm lucky in that I don't really get
many of these,
uh,
social justice warrior trolls.
I mean 99 percent of the people that
interact with me are very nice and very
sweet,
but that small one to five percent group
that,
as you mentioned,
are real assholes.
It's almost impenetrable to try to speak
to them.
Right?
I mean,
I engage them in a very dispassionate
manner,
you know,
hopefully providing them with facts,
trying to be polite,
but I am an asshole simply for
disagreeing with them.
So most of the people that I've blocked
the aren't that many,
but the ones that I've,
that I've blocked,
it's because I try to engage them and
the only way they could engage in return
is to insult.
And so it's a real,
it's a,
it's a real breakdown of civil
discourse.
And also insult when it's just a matter
of opinion about things that are
debatable.
Exactly.
Here's one that,
you know,
the story about Occidental University or
Occidental College College College
Occidental College,
where there was two students that got
drunk and they're a boy and a girl.
They texted each other and the boy and
the girl had sex and the boy got accused
of rape and kicked out of the school and
where the girls stayed and I was like,
well,
that's crazy.
Like first of all,
you're,
you're changing the rules of human
behavior because people have been
getting drunk and having sex since the
beginning of time and so to call it rape
now,
after all these years,
just on a whim,
especially when two people are
consenting adults,
they're consenting adults.
They can go to war and when they can't
really vote yet or 18,
right?
You voted 18.
Yeah,
you can't drink.
They can't drink it,
but they're kind of Montreal,
Canada,
Montreal and you're crazy country.
But the idea that the boy is responsible
and the girls not to me seems ridiculous
and it seems contradictory to the whole
idea of feminism in the first place is
that we're equal now.
If we are equal,
why are we not equal in terms of our
ability to take responsibility for being
under the influence?
I mean if your.
If you are responsible for being under
the influence when you're driving.
If you're responsible for being under
the influence,
if you commit violence,
why you're not responsible for being
under the influence when you have sex.
If you're a girl,
that's crazy.
Well,
when I said this,
Oh my God,
the amount of people that called me a
massage and vanilla rape enabler and
enablists and ableist piece of shit like
they just.
But it was all insulting.
It's like how can it be insulting when
this is a debatable point?
Was this co?
This is a clearly rational,
debatable point.
You talking about two human beings that
are adults that got drunk,
but the male is the rapist like that.
That's ridiculous.
There are now,
I don't know the exact details,
but they are now on some university
campuses.
You actually have a consent form where
you sort of go through the iterative
steps as you're starting to engage in
sex.
So we are now in the foreplay stage.
Do you hear by consent?
And we pulled some like,
uh,
I think putting on Barry White music
might be a bit more mood inducing than
signing a.
it's a legal document,
white music as rape enabling.
Because what you're doing is you're
coercing you or making the women
aroused,
hence they don't have all their
faculties for Barry White is a genocidal
rapist.
Well,
that's,
that's the language that they're using
is I was unable to consent,
right.
Which obviously there's,
there's a scale,
right?
We can all agree that there is a level
where people are at.
You are breathing deeply into that
mixer.
So we had an issue with it the other day
because it's better because,
uh,
yeah,
we got to.
My friend Barry Crimmins was here and he
got a little hammered and he was
breathing into the mic.
I got like 100 stopped people from
breathing to the mic.
Tweets.
What is this,
Jamie?
Is this real?
Yeah,
this is.
Jake was drunk.
Josie was.
Oh,
that's right.
I've seen this.
Jay Can Josie hooked up?
Josie could not consent.
The next day jake was charged with rape.
There you go.
What the fuck is that?
That's a real poster.
I,
I tweeted that.
I remember this.
You know,
for example,
if a,
if a high status male seduces a lower
status woman,
that itself could be construed as a form
of rape precisely because his powers so
intoxicating like a professor and a
student perhaps,
but in that sense,
I mean you might have an ethical
boundaries,
right,
but I mean forget,
I mean just a guy who meets a girl at a
bar and he happens to be a professor.
The rich man and a woman,
right?
Some of the virtue of the difference in
hierarchy,
that itself could be construed as
coercive because she wasn't able to
control herself in the face of this
overpowering man,
not physically just because it was high
status.
Well,
the reality of being a male is if an
attractive woman comes onto a man,
she's raping them because you're.
You have no control.
Like of a beautiful woman comes onto a
guy like Jamie had a bar that poor kids
fucked.
Look at them.
This is Jamie.
Jamie looking them over there.
He's fucked.
If some traci lords in her prime looking
chick comes up.
Jamie,
that's a reference from La.
I met her.
She still,
she wasn't she a porn start at 15
because she fit easy,
not breck in the party.
Um,
yeah.
I believe she was lighter weight.
Since we're on a porn references.
Can I tell you maybe the greatest?
I,
yeah,
I received a lot of comments on my
stuff.
Maybe the greatest one I've ever
received.
Somebody wrote,
I hope I'm getting the exact quote in
reference to me.
He wrote,
this guy is the Ron Jeremy of
evolutionary psychology.
I said,
that's it.
I,
I could drop the mic and just,
you know,
retire well that means you're disgusting
but effective fat and sweaty and Harry,
that's what you're saying.
Well,
the whole thing about Ron Jeremy was
ron.
Jeremy existed in an era where the guys
were supposed to be gross because people
watching porn.
We're all guys.
So you wanted like a guy who is
disgusting to be getting late.
So you like,
I got a chance this could happen.
Look how hot she hasn't.
She fucks Ron.
Jeremy.
Oh yeah.
Um,
nowadays the men are equally
unattainable as well.
And the idea is that the women watch it
with men,
right?
Allegedly,
I don't know anything about that.
No,
I'm sure porns raping their culture.
Anyway,
that was contacted once a by a former
porn star who had already uh,
you know,
he had,
he had the hat,
had the NBA,
I think an Mba,
and he wanted to pursue his phd with me.
He actually came up to Montreal,
spend a few days with me,
visited my lab and then ended up,
uh,
not,
not going on for a phd,
but uh,
so that's my,
uh,
the closest I've come to a porn star,
a guy who almost became a doctoral
student.
That's interesting.
Well,
I can't even say his name.
I think a man who does that has a bit
more freedom to move around over a woman
does that.
She's sort of labeled by our culture and
some sort of a weird way.
Maybe less so in Canada.
So in Canada I think in terms of as,
or a little bit more loose sexually.
Well you're,
you've been to Montreal,
you were there recently,
you see that,
I mean every second to store stores.
A strip bar.
Yeah.
You guys have a lot of strip bars up
there,
but it's also just the way people talk
and act about sex.
It just seems,
doesn't seem shameful,
less puritanical.
We're,
we're so fucking boys in Quebec is even
more so what you're saying because it.
Exactly.
So it's good that European vibe.
So,
so in the,
in the context of Canada,
you know,
some of the Anglo Saxon provinces
historically might be closer to
Americans.
Munter,
Kobeck.
It's a free for all.
Yeah,
cut back is crazy.
So like the,
the more um,
conservative spots are where there's
very few people and everyone's scared
and you believe in Jesus more.
Don't go to Saskatchewan if you want to
get lucky.
Oh really?
Joking.
Saskatchewan,
Saskatchewan right now they're fucking
warming up their fingers for hate mail.
But um,
that's how it is in America too.
It's like the spots that are like,
really,
there's not a lot of people there in the
middle of nowhere.
There's fucking church everywhere in
those spots.
Yeah.
I found that in a Latin America or
Central America.
I was in Costa Rica recently,
and the poorer the neighborhood,
the prevalence of churches was like
through the roof.
It was crazy.
We were driving to the cloud for us and
as we're driving up there,
you pass her all these really small
rural communities and you see a lot of
churches.
Yeah.
When people,
I guess they need hope in those spots
that are kind of solves the biggest
potential mortality,
by the way.
Speaking of mortality,
let me do the segue.
It is your birthday officially.
The Godfather is hereby wishing you a
happy birthday.
I thought,
what can I bless?
What can I get Joe as a gift,
by the way,
I owe you a copy of my.
One of my books signed.
Forgive me.
I didn't send it,
but this guy has got fame.
He's got the looks.
She's got charisma.
He's got money.
Keep going on and get them.
Anything good except I couldn't get him.
You just 11.
Yeah.
I don't want anything people keep
giving.
Jamie gave me seven.
Cool though.
But,
you know,
I think that um,
the uh,
existential angst of a,
of death being solved by religion for a
lot of people is like a nice little
scaffolding to just sorta like carry
your way through life.
You know,
people have gotten angry at me for
suggesting that I'm not suggesting it
for you or for anybody.
I'm not.
I mean,
I'm not suggesting there's a lot of
things that people do that I wouldn't
want to do that they do to kind of get
by in this life or it's takes Xanax or
uh,
you know,
or drink every night after work in order
to keep from kicking their dog.
I mean,
I don't know what the fuck is going on
in your head,
but for a lot of people in these bad
rural type situations,
it seems to be like,
it seems to be a common theme.
Right?
And if you really look at everything as
being natural,
which is I what I try to do,
you know,
that term nature,
everybody wants to look at that as like
wild life outside of cities.
I kind of look at everything as nature
and I look at human behavior patterns
and how much they repeat themselves as
being pretty natural and these weird
little spots where there's not a lot of
people,
it seems to attract a lot of churches.
You know,
I,
I wrote an article on that point that I
think maybe a year or two ago looking,
it was somebody else's research that I
was summarizing,
looking at the content
of prayers.
So what is it that people pray about
money as an example,
but as a function of their income
status,
socioeconomic status,
and as you might predict,
uh,
the content of what I pray to God about
drastically changes as a function of
where I fit in that hierarchy.
What do people that are really rich pray
about?
Maybe health must be right?
Yeah.
Health and family and stuff like that.
Uh,
it's,
um,
it's one of those things where I,
I reluctantly,
I'm not just accepted but I can almost
supported because you mean religiosity.
Yeah.
For people that are in bad places and
bad situations,
I see that it helps.
Well,
so chapter eight of one of my books is I
titled it very provocatively perhaps
marketing hope by selling lies,
right?
And I give different examples of hope
peddlers,
a medical quacks,
a self help gurus,
and of course I argued that the greatest
peddler of hope is of course religion.
Uh,
and so you're exactly right.
It's a,
I think it takes almost a maladaptive
honesty to not believe because it is so
much more comforting to believe.
And also the people that decide not to
believe.
It's almost like they have to try so
hard in those areas to not believe that
they become angry about it.
They can become angry about their
disbelief.
Right.
You know,
I'm a nonbeliever,
but I'm not angry.
I'm very gentle.
You will.
You're very intelligent man.
Well,
you recognize these patterns and not
succumb,
but for a lot of folks,
for a lot of folks also,
you're dealing with so many people in
your community.
There are also a part of that.
And then the church becomes like a sort
of a community center by proxy.
What David Sloan Wilson,
who's a evolutionary biologist,
a good friend of mine,
very famous biologist,
he looks at the evolutionary roots of
religion and he actually argues a great
book I'm doing is plugging for him now
that I think he wrote in 2002 Darwin's
Cathedral where he actually demonstrated
or argued that groups that are religious
actually out survive.
Those that are not using an argument of
commonality,
right?
Groups that are religious are more
cohesive.
Band together are more communal,
therefore they should be able to survive
other groups.
Now,
his,
his theories are a bit contentious
because many evolutionary psychologists
and evolutionary biologists reject the
idea that evolution can happen at the
group level.
They argue that evolution should happen
at the individual,
at the gene level,
and this is a fight that he's been
having for many years now,
but that's one example where you could
actually study religion not only from a
scientific perspective,
but from an evolutionary perspective.
I have a friend who lives in a married
male and female are married in a sort of
a rural area and a long time ago I was
having this conversation with them,
um,
where the,
the wife was
just sort of explaining how if it wasn't
for religion,
her and the husband wouldn't be together
and the way she was saying it was
counseling,
her husband was dumb and like he needs
something to keep him like on this good
path and pattern.
And they'd been married for like at the
time,
I think like 15 or 20 years.
And she was like,
do you think that we would have still
been together if it wasn't for our
belief in God and Lord and whether or
not an edge goes whether or not it's
real.
Wow.
And I was like,
Whoa,
this is some heavy shit.
It's almost like she's given her husband
some sort of placebo to like,
keep this guy from drinking and fucking
getting on a train like a Hobo or
whatever the hell she do.
You know,
like God kinda kept them together and
kept the family together.
But she was looking at it in a very
pragmatic way and I was like,
wow,
this is deep,
you know,
the Middle East.
And I've seen it in my own family.
There was this incredible fatalism that
comes with religiosity.
So I have a family member of.
I won't mention who it is,
who's was Ariel Helwani not are you
highlighted by the way?
Shout out to my nephew and to all the
twitters,
twitter is out there.
He really is my nephew.
He's my sister's,
uh,
son.
Uh,
but anyways,
so this male member,
uh,
not rel a shout out to Ariel,
he,
he views everybody.
He was everything through the lens of
it's God's will.
So if he opens up a store and the store
doesn't do well,
well it's not that he might have made
some bad poor business decisions.
It must be God's will had God wanted it
to be differently than things would have
turned out differently.
And,
and that type of fatalism is actually
quite a depressing and that it doesn't
allow for a feedback loop.
Right?
I mean,
you don't get feedback from the
environment that says change course of
action.
If everything that happens happens
because it's God's will,
then you really just an empty vessel
that's just executing God's will and so,
uh,
and you see that a lot in the Middle
East.
If God wants and child life,
God,
this,
if God,
that if it meant if it was meant to be,
it's really part of the loss of the
Arabic language,
the practice and feedback loops are what
it's all about.
I mean,
that's what life is when you're opening
a business or doing a sport or you know,
whatever the fuck it is.
Practiced resume reviewing data feedback
loop making possible corrections,
objectivity.
Yeah.
All those things are what makes people
improve.
And matter of fact,
I read an article recently about music.
Were there,
were there were discussing music that
the inherent qualities of someone's
music or really just a lot of what makes
a great musician his practice and
feedback loops right there.
I mean that's really what it is.
Not God's will but,
but if you believe that,
you know,
it's limiting and empowering at the same
time.
Exactly.
Because if you also are involved in this
practice feedback,
but you really think God's
on your side because you play a mother
fucking mean acts,
there's actually a psychological trait
that maps onto what we're talking about.
This.
It's a locus of control.
Are you familiar with this term?
Do you know what?
No,
I'm not.
So locus of control is basically ideas.
Some of us are internally driven in
terms of our locus of control,
meaning that we attribute things that
happened to us,
to us,
I did well on the exam because I studied
hard because I'm intelligent.
Okay.
Versus external locus of control as you
attributed to environmental factors.
I did poorly on the exam,
not because I didn't study,
but because the professor is an asshole.
He's an Indian.
Right?
And so people who score high on external
locus of control,
then you can predict certain other
behaviors,
for example,
they're much more likely to be gamblers.
Right?
Precisely because it's fatalism,
right?
I mean,
my turn will come.
It's written in the skies,
uh,
the black.
It should be up soon,
right?
If you're internally locus of control,
then you know that all that stuff is
random and they're red and black or just
they come and go depending on how that
ball drops.
Exactly.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people do really firmly
believe in that.
Yeah,
and it's sort of there.
That's how they get through this life
and it's very much a blinder.
It puts them in a very narrow channel.
It's very difficult to escape.
Once you have that firm belief,
you know of have that.
These patterns are sort of clearly
established.
It's going to be my time.
My time is coming.
Well my time.
Going back to the gambling casinos,
actually our operators are very spot.
They play on that cognitive illusion
because what they do is they give you
this card where you keep track of how
many times it's come on read and how
many times,
how many times the number 13 has come as
a complete illusion,
right?
It's giving you a car.
You could take a car so when you play
relapse.
Exactly.
So if you go to the Montreal casino,
you can get those cars.
Oh look,
13 has come up 14 times,
but I think 37 is up.
Should be up soon.
Right.
What it's doing basically is it's giving
you a sense of control over otherwise
completely random events.
Right?
Each of those throws the ball are
independent events.
I mean,
unless it's a rig machine,
so the casino operators understand you
and psychology and they play on it and
then the idiot succumb to it.
How rude.
That's uh,
the,
the.
But what's crazy is when luck is on
their side,
it seems real like when you get a hot
hand,
like,
I don't play craps,
but I've seen people play craps and they
get a hot hand.
They start rolling dice,
right?
And they feel like they can lose and
they'll go on a hot streak.
They'll go on a hot streak with,
with Black Jack as well.
They get the right cards,
poker and it feels like it's happening.
But because that hot streak is itself a
random pattern,
I'll tell you a great,
great story and I'll
actually mention who it is.
I hope he won't be upset if I mentioned
this.
It's my father who is a avid six,
49 player.
I Bet your dad doesn't listen to this
shit.
Probably not 6:49
basically is a.
is a lottery game played in Quebec.
You,
you choose six numbers out of 49.
Your chances of getting it are,
as you know,
infinite.
There's really small and so one day he
had called me at the office at my
university office,
said,
hey son,
I'm,
I'm playing some,
some,
some cards.
Give me six numbers and say,
oh,
that I have some students in my office,
can I call you back because it just,
just give me six numbers.
So I said,
all right,
one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six.
So then he goes,
well,
if you're not going to take the damn
game seriously,
why am I calling you right now?
Why did he do that?
Because he actually was convinced that
the numbers one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
and I bet some of your listeners will,
will also think that the numbers one
through six are,
is,
is less likely of a combination to come
up than any other combination of six
numbers simply because it has the
illusion of of looking ordered.
Right?
But it isn't.
It is just one of the 14 million
possible combinations that I think it's
one out of $40 million.
So again,
these,
these biases,
these cognitive traps are so alluring
and it's so easy for people to succumb
to them.
Is it single digit numbers can be
doubled if it goes up to 49,
49 digits?
No,
no.
Forty nine numbers.
One to 49.
You pick your six,
12,
18,
39,
42.
And so I just picked one through six and
he was absolutely convinced that that
combination of six numbers is simply
that you're a fool.
I'm an idiot.
The lottery itself is such a trap.
My grandmother used to only talk about
the lottery.
She talked about the lottery and dead
people that were talking to her.
My grandmother was like,
she was crazy and she,
uh,
she firmly believed that she had some
psychic ability,
right.
And uh,
she's always like,
I knew that number was going to come up.
She would always tell you I was going to
bet that she would talk about what
number she was going to bet and I was
going to bet nine that didn't put it in
and you know,
19 through sick too,
you,
she rattle off whatever the fuck the
number was.
And this was back in the day in New
Jersey where I'm the,
they would play the numbers,
which is like this local created sort of
lottery that the mob ran.
It was this weird thing and my
grandmother was a part of it.
She would like help run the numbers.
Nice.
Yeah.
She,
uh,
I don't know what her function was,
but she was a part of it to the point
where she got arrested and did six
months in jail and they're running the
numbers and she wouldn't,
she wouldn't rat anybody out.
So,
uh,
you know,
my,
my grandmother would like a knit,
like little scarves and shit for the
guards.
And do all kinds of weird shit.
I didn't find out about this until later
when I was a kid.
We just thought grandma was just fucking
busy traveling or something.
We had no idea where the hell she was.
We'd go visit grandpa.
Where's grandma?
Couldn't find her.
She was,
oh,
she's visiting your aunt Mary or she's
a,
you know,
it was always like.
But really she
was in the pokey.
Right.
Doing hard time for numbers.
So speaking of kind of Kooky a family
members,
I have a paternal aunt and I've actually
written about this general what tasks
geography is.
It's a fancy term for something that you
might otherwise not.
Does that term go.
So Tasha Griffey is the reading of your
fate since we're talking about these
issues through a.
In the Middle East,
we do it with the tea leaves or that you
could do with [inaudible] or you could
do it with the residue.
That's what you flip over the coffee
mug.
That right.
So the residue that's left,
that's what you read.
So this lady would come over to our
house and that was,
you know,
maybe a seven,
eight,
nine year old boy and I already knew
that the Jig was up on this thing and
she,
when she would come over,
it would be like the pope is visit
thing,
right?
And lower rise coming over to tell us
about our future.
So then she would start,
she'd look at these,
these,
these random patterns and the things
that you would say are,
you know,
I see happiness in your future.
Well I could have a good bowel movement
later and that's happiness.
The Dallas cowboys could win.
That's happiness.
My wife and I can have sex tonight.
Then that's happiness.
So there was no way to falsify her
profoundly general prediction,
right?
She,
she,
she never.
She never looked at the,
at the residue and said,
you will be getting a 13 point seven
percent increase in your income.
Right?
Specificity is the enemy of these
fortune tellers.
Right?
So they give you these vague predictions
which you could then fill into your life
in any infinite number of possible ways.
Yeah.
We had this guy on the Scifi show that
it did,
his name is Bennett check and he's a
master at what he calls,
they call it mentalism or something like
that and he's a mentalist.
And uh,
he is one of those guys that will tell
you absolutely straightforward.
This is bullshit.
I am,
I am using tricks and I won't tell you
what the tricks are,
but I will tell you right now,
I am not a psychic.
This is not magic.
Magic is not real.
He actually gets angry at people that
pretend that they could read,
like you remember,
there was a whole series of those shows
that they've since pulled off the air,
but where there was psychics and you
know,
they were like,
there was like the long island medium,
right?
Remember that?
And they were talking to people's dead
relatives and all those are some that do
with dead animals.
It wasn't one of those things.
There's one,
it's.
So there is a cross species psychic.
Can you imagine your fucking dog doesn't
say Jack Shit to you when he was alive,
but when he's dead,
he starts talking to psychics.
That's right.
Yeah,
man,
I didn't like the way you pet me,
bro,
at the back of my head like I'm an
asshole.
Right.
Well,
this,
um,
this idea that someone can actually read
into your past and pull this information
is so appealing to people that they
mistake the way the person's questioning
them and the clues and the little bits
of information that they give and how
this person is really just good
at forming puzzles based on pattern
chunking.
Exactly.
They just know how to.
They know they've done this so many
times they know how to get it,
but this guy,
even though he told me what he was
doing,
we had some people in the audience.
We had a small audience and we had him
perform these tasks and these folks have
them come up and he would ask them
questions.
It was amazing.
I mean,
he's just really,
really.
Despite the fact that you knew all the
tricks,
it was easy to sort of succumb to the
illusion.
Here's the thing though,
I don't know the tricks.
I just know they are tracked.
She wouldn't tell us what the tricks
were,
but he said,
like,
I'm telling you,
I am not a psychic by any stretch of the
imagination.
And he did a bunch of other cool stuff
like you bent spoons and stuff like that
with his mind.
Right?
It's bullshit.
He's like,
it's all bullshit.
I'm using trickery.
He goes,
but I won't tell you how I do it,
but I'm not magic.
Which would be really rude if he
actually was magic and it's just like
his,
his shtick is calling out all these
other people who were also actually
magic.
Imagine that it was like a sellout for
all the real magic people.
Right.
My sister was in high school.
She went to one of her friends,
uh,
hired a psychic and they all sat around
and this psychic would like,
slowly but surely read them.
I was,
I was very,
always very skeptical of stuff like
that.
From the time I was little because I
knew my grandmother was fucking crazy
and she always claimed to be psychic,
but listen to my sister come back.
She would tell me all this stuff,
you know,
she knew all about this and she knew all
about that and she knew about the time I
did that and I'm like,
didn't you know about all that stuff?
She's not telling you anything you don't
already know.
So she's telling you stuff you already
know.
Yeah.
I'm telling you.
It was amazing though.
I was like,
how is it amazing that she tells you
shit that you already know what?
That's not amazing yet.
There's a study,
I can't remember the exact reference,
but you could take the astrological
predictions,
you know,
the twelfth and you're giving it to
people randomly and anyone that I give
you,
he'd be able to argue that perfectly
fits you.
Right?
Of course.
I see.
Because it is so vague that you could
infuse your life into any one of these
sort of vague the script for this.
So yeah.
Yeah.
They're ultra vague.
But those are stupid.
Like,
those today will be an amazing day for
business.
Like fuck,
you know,
you want to know specifics.
Right.
But I had a friend who ran into someone
in Venice beach and uh,
the guy was like,
one of those save the rain forest type
dudes.
He had like some little stands up and he
said,
if I guess your birthday will you listen
to me?
And my friend was like,
go ahead.
And he gets his birthday on the day and
then he was,
wow,
the fuck did you do that?
He goes,
will you listen to my story now?
But the rain forest.
And he goes,
do that to my friend.
He brought his friend over and he gets
his friend's birthday to.
Yeah.
To what?
Let's say.
I don't know,
man.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm reserving judgment on that story
too.
Know it's a true story.
My friend definitely didn't lie.
He's because he's baffled by it.
Here's where I told Penn Jillette
obviously.
Yeah,
yeah.
Musician,
magician rather.
And a good friend of mine.
And so I said,
how's this guy do that?
He goes,
there's,
there's techniques you can do that.
How do you deal with it?
Man Guys shows up and he says to you,
you know,
I can guess your birthday.
He doesn't know you.
You don't know him.
How the fuck is that possible?
And he told me there's techniques.
I'm like,
what the fuck,
man?
There's 365 days a year.
How is that guy going to guess that
William stumped and it's not even one in
365,
right?
The odds of you nailing it,
it's probably higher than one and 365,
right?
Isn't that work?
That are.
There are interesting probabilities.
What,
for example,
if you were to say how likely are to
people in a room to have the same
birthday,
that number,
and I don't remember what I've seen a
lot longer than you think it is a lot
higher than you think.
Exactly right.
A lot higher than you.
And I remember when,
when I took probability and stats,
uh,
you know,
as a math on the ground,
that's one and sort of the classic
examples that you,
your study precisely because it is so
counterintuitive.
Yeah.
There was a show where someone did that
and they went into,
it was like one of these conmen dudes
went into like,
he bet people and he went into a Oh,
like a restaurant and he had like the
day to find two people.
Yeah,
like certain amount of time to find two
people that share the same birthday that
worked there or that,
uh,
that we're in a customer's there and he
nailed it in like an hour.
Yeah.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
Cool.
Just a bunch of people coming in and you
get like a May twelfth or whatever the
right.
Yeah,
but,
but the idea that someone could just
point at you godfather,
I believe your bus stalling and Axon
came out there.
Gad Fad,
fad,
the um,
you know,
I don't know how anybody does that,
but according to Penn Jillette,
I got to listen to him though because
he's a fucking magician and those guys
were all tricksters.
They know how to do shit.
Like one of the cool things about Penn
and teller,
if you ever go to wash them,
is that they'll tell you it's bullshit
while they're doing it.
And you have no idea what the fuck they
just did,
how they did it.
Incredible.
Yeah.
That's all really sneaky stuff is just
managing illusions,
right?
I mean,
that's what they're doing.
Yeah.
And that's what's really cool about the
band check character was that he was
like really adamant about that stuff and
very angry about people steal money from
folks by claiming to be mediums and
talking to their relatives.
And he's like,
I just think that anyone who would try
to give someone hope that perhaps their
dead relative is talking from the grave
and telling them important things they
need to know.
But meanwhile they're just making it up.
It's just a foul,
disgusting human being.
I'm with you.
My grandmother would have bought it,
hook,
line and sinker.
She believed it,
man.
We had a dude a dye in my grandmother's
house.
There was a guy who,
um,
during,
I think it was like the fifties or the
sixties,
you know,
they were pretty poor and there was this
guy in the neighborhood who needed a
place to live
and he would pay them to rent a room in
their house.
Is Pretty common back in those days and
you know,
sometimes we'd eat dinner with them and
what have you.
And he died in his room one day and uh,
they believe that this guy was talking
to them.
They believe this guy was in the house
and that she would,
uh,
go up into the attic sometimes and he
would be up there and she would see him
and talk to them.
Oh,
freaked me the fuck out,
man.
It's very creepy.
Did you ever hear,
I'm not sure if I'm going to get her
name right.
I think it's Emily Rose.
Others that name now,
the youngest woman or girl to ever
publish.
It's kind of relate to some of this
hocus pocus stuff that we're talking
about.
Youngest girl to ever publish a paper in
Jama,
Journal of the American Medical
Association,
a very prestigious journal.
I think she was maybe nine or 10 or 11.
I discussed this in one of my books.
Um,
and basically as a great four or five a
science project,
she wanted to explore touch therapy.
Gee,
are you familiar with windows?
So touch therapy is one of those
quackery.
But I'm triggered right now by you
saying,
right,
right.
Just triggered me.
Right,
right.
Uh,
so basically it's the touch healer has
some sort of energy and in his or her
hands that they can sort of levitate
around your pain area,
like Reiki,
Reiki,
whatever.
Yeah.
Right.
And so she wanted to test whether those
claims were true.
So she set up a extraordinarily simple
experiment to test their abilities.
And so what basically she did is she
would put out her hand and then they had
to determine whether it's her right
hand.
In other words,
there's,
there's a,
uh,
a barrier where they can't see which of
her hands is out and they have the
ability of touch.
They should be able to predict whether
on the right or left,
this is where her hand is.
And of course they ended up doing worse
than random.
In other words,
less than 50.
I mean,
you have one in two chance of just
guessing randomly whether it's the right
or left.
Right?
And she demonstrated that these touch
healers,
who supposedly are able to cure cancer
by levitating their hand over areas are
not even able to predict whether the
hand that's out is on the right or left.
Right.
I mean,
so imagine what an elegant experiment
that is.
And it was published in that journal
now.
What do you think those touch healers
came back with as a rebuttal?
Can you think of anything new other than
that?
No,
they basically said that when you,
when you set up these types of
experiments in a laboratory that ends up
wait for it affecting the energy fields.
And therefore by testing our abilities,
you are ultimately removing our
abilities.
Therefore it's an unfalsifiable
position.
It's not science.
I have heard that expression.
I've heard that thought of when people
were talking about people who don't
believe in psychics.
Right?
And that if you talk to a psychic but
you don't believe in them,
your negative energy,
the fears with their gift.
Exactly,
exactly right.
So how could you ever tested right?
Can that.
That's why.
That's why all of these sort of quackery
movements are part of the sort of non
science epidemiology,
right?
Destiny,
The idea of destiny.
If I walk out of my house now and I get
hit by a car,
that was my destiny.
If I go ahead,
oh no,
please go to.
If I walk out of my house and I don't
get hit by trucks,
that was my destiny.
So what state of the world would have to
happen for it,
for me to be able to test the destiny or
not?
This thing,
I can't.
Anything that happens is my destiny,
right?
So it's unfalsifiable.
You know,
I have a,
uh,
a little piece of Hocus pocus that I,
I don't,
I don't necessarily believe,
but I,
uh,
entertainment from time to time and that
is synchronicity.
Like when you're discussing an object
and then something will come up,
whether it's on television or the news
that just perfectly fits into what
you're talking about.
And you're like,
well,
how God damned convenient is this.
Like I was having a,
um,
a text,
a conversation with a friend of mine
this morning and he lives on the east
coast and I live in the west coast.
We're going back and forth and he's
having health issues and he's going to
talk to a doctor about probiotics and
while we're having this conversation,
I go downstairs and I'm about to work
out.
I turn on the television and good
morning America is having a,
an expert discuss probiotics and how gut
health can affect all sorts of various
things including your mood,
all sorts of various illnesses.
And like literally at the same moment
I'm having this text conversation with
my friend.
So I take a photo of the television and
I sent,
I sent it to him and like,
how crazy is this?
Like we're talking about this and Bam,
it's on tv like that.
Can I,
they mystify that story.
Why would you want to fuck it up for me?
Man would do apologies.
This is actually called the cell a bias.
So for example,
if you say,
uh,
you know,
every time I get in the shower,
the phone rings,
right?
Right.
Habits me right now,
what?
What are the events that you're not
coding in your brain,
so the other times the phone rang,
no locks on the phone can ring or cannot
ring,
and you could get into the shower or not
get into the shower.
So it's a two by two matrix.
The brain is only coding the instances,
the cell a bias.
One of the biopsies were the two events
happened,
the phone rings and I get in the shower.
The three other events.
Your brain never codes because they're
not events.
Therefore you end up overestimating the
likelihood of that event.
Oh my God.
Every time the phone rings,
I'm in the shower,
so this is what's happening with that
probiotic story,
right?
There's a million other times that you
spoke him about something else and then
you turned on the TV,
but there wasn't to use your term
synchronicity,
but that one time where it happened,
you code it as as something magical and
mystical.
No,
you're not.
You don't seem very buying your fucking
bullshit or all men.
So you're sticking with your magical
thinking.
Say The universe is a all working
together to sort of.
That science stuff is overrated.
I hear a lot of it's bullshit,
Bro.
Right here.
A lot of it is guesswork.
They don't know what to do.
I just think that it was a beautiful
coincidence,
but that's how I look at it.
And there's a series of these beautiful
coincidences that happen all the time
when you're tuned in the vibe of the
universe,
man.
Wow,
whoa,
Whoa,
whoa.
I need to recover from that.
A lot of people believe that.
Right?
Is that.
So that's a big one,
isn't it?
The vibe of the universe at moving away
from spiritual death or do you want to
talk about some real science or do you
want to join the uh,
no and absolutely.
Yeah.
So man,
I really believe that.
I think it's fun.
I mean,
for people listening,
is he serious?
No,
we're,
we're joking around.
But um,
it is weird when stuff like that happens
and you do wonder why do you familiar?
I'm sure you are with simulation theory.
Tell me a bit about it to see what you
mean.
Simulation theory is the idea,
and this is not just being bandied about
by Comedians,
but by actual physicist who contemplate
the,
when you extrapolate the nature of
technology and where we're at now and
what's possible today with Oculus rift
and all these virtual reality programs
that are developing that are
extraordinarily effective.
I mean,
I haven't seen the newest version of
oculus rift,
but apparently it's in four.
K is,
are what?
Immersive games,
not games.
Um,
oculus rift,
they,
they're going to apply at the games,
but what oculus rift is a,
it's like a ski goggle thing that you
put on that is a virtual reality
program,
uh,
that runs while this is happening and a
lot of what they're doing when they're
running these just recording these
incredible scenarios where you,
uh,
apparently they put cameras all over a
person's body and they have them go
through these rooms and then they take
all of the data from all of that and
then,
uh,
put it into this program so that when
you're wearing these goggles,
you can look around up and down and
there is data.
That's what it looks like.
Oh,
cool.
There is data for every single aspect of
the room,
every single area of the room.
So as you look left and right,
all that's been covered and it's all
computing,
so as computational power and video
cards and all these different things
that can compute the visual images as
they improve and get better and better.
It's gotten to the point now where it's
four k,
four k is what this television right
here is,
which is the latest,
greatest version of hd.
It's very high resolution,
beautiful images.
And my friend Duncan put it on,
try it out at one of these developer
conferences and called me just screaming
and raving.
He's like,
this is bigger than the Internet.
This is bigger than the wheel.
This is the biggest thing.
He's like,
this is gonna fucking change everything.
Um,
he walked into a room in this virtual
reality demonstration and there was a
man playing the piano piano.
What does that man playing the piano?
The Piano sounded more a more realistic.
As he got closer to it,
it got louder.
Um,
he could see the man playing it.
He would step to the side and see the
man playing it,
look over the top of the piano,
see the man playing,
go underneath the piano and see the man
playing.
He's like,
this is fucking crazy,
and it really looks like there's a guy
in front of you playing the piano,
but nothing's happening.
The idea being that if that technology
exists today in 2015,
there is going to come a time whether
that time is 100 years from now or a
thousand years from now where there will
be an artificial reality that is
indecipherable from the reality that we
live in right now from this touch,
feel,
hear,
see reality,
that we just all accept as real.
That there's going to be something that
is artificially created but is
indistinguishable from what we're
experiencing and if that is true,
how do we not know that we haven't
already been in it?
How do we not know?
Because if we're not talking about
Voodoo,
we're talking about technology and we're
talking about pretty trackable stuff,
like if you follow Moore's law,
if you follow the any of the
technological laws of extrapolation from
the point that we're at now,
to the point that they're projecting
just within five,
10,
15,
20 years,
they're talking about incredible.
So if you've seen magic leap,
if you seen them.
I was going to say I haven't seen the
matrix either,
but it sounds like that's sort of the
simpsons.
Yeah.
Well it's similar along those lines.
Matrix seemed like a total horseshit.
Just when it came out it seemed like,
wow,
this is a cool science fiction movie
about some shit that's not real.
Right.
I never could be real,
but now the matrix looks closer and
closer to reality with every passing
day,
with every passing year it looks like,
wow,
it's inevitable whether it's 100 years
from now or whatever,
they're going to be able to give you an
experience that is indistinguishable
from this experience that we think is
real.
You know,
my only sort of jumping point for him
while he's talking about when I was a
student in computer science and math,
I took artificial intelligence,
but now this is going back to not to
date myself,
uh,
you know,
the twenties,
1985,
about 1984 85.
And at the time one of the things that
we had learned in that in this course
was.
So do you know about how now there are
computers that can easily match,
uh,
the grandmasters and chest?
Yes.
So at the time when I was in school,
some of the early versions of those,
uh,
computers,
we're just about at the level of the
grand masters.
And so one of the assignments that we
had to do in that course was to develop
an algorithm.
So if you look at the chest,
a decision tree,
the number of nodes that it has is
something like,
I can't remember the exact moment.
You could probably pull it out
something.
I tend to the 100 possibilities.
And so it will take you more than the,
the,
the age of the universe if you want it
to exhaustively search through every
possible option to rather what you have
to do is use some sort of search
algorithm to prune out to weed out huge
parts of the decision tree.
You see what I'm saying?
So that way,
this huge decision tree,
you only go through the parts that seem
promising.
And so we had,
we didn't do it for chest with the
different other game,
but at that time I already had founded
almost mystical,
uh,
the type of stuff that we were learning
and ai to try to sort of model this
artificial intelligence that could mimic
the capacities of a human grandmaster
player.
And what you're talking about,
of course,
as many generations ahead of that.
So incredible stuff.
Managing,
managing generations ahead of that.
And again,
you're talking about 30 years,
it's not that long.
It's really not in terms of culture,
it's like if you went by,
if 30 years went by in the 12 hundreds,
nothing will change.
True.
Nothing.
And 30 years today is almost an eternity
when it comes to technology.
Well actually yesterday we were sitting
at the beach in Laguna,
my wife and I and the kids and uh,
I asked her and I,
I wonder if you have an answer to this.
I'm sure we could pull it up.
How many people today still use non
smartphones,
right?
I mean,
I,
I joined the fear but so probably you
think like five percent.
Um,
if I had to guess,
I'd bet it's less than that,
but it's about 10 or I bet it's a
rather.
Um,
one percent.
No,
I was going to say three.
But I would say,
um,
I would bet that out of all the people
that use cell phones on a regular basis,
yeah,
I would say it's less than five percent.
I would say it's probably around three
or something like that.
Less than 10 for sure.
What do you think,
Jamie?
What would you guess?
Three?
Like three percent if you like,
if you see people that are walking
around.
I'm trying to think.
I mean,
last time I saw,
I can't remember the last time that I
saw somebody sort of flipping a phone.
I think my mom has one still write text
me.
It's pretty obvious.
You're still like let her,
you choose you.
If you have an iphone you use you
instead of why are you.
You're lazy bitch.
Just write why.
Oh,
you.
Jesus Christ.
I'm not going to agree with that
sentiment,
mother.
No,
not my mom.
My mom has.
She doesn't have a smart phone,
right?
Least.
I don't think she does.
Um,
what uh,
what is the percentage Jamie percentage
of people that don't use smartphone?
Just all.
I can find this.
There's two thirds of American adults
have a smartphone.
So I guess it'd be that one third don't.
So I don't know if that's a fit.
Yeah.
What does that mean though?
Was that kind of follows?
A lot of them may not have any phones.
They're fucking animals.
If you're living in 2015,
you don't have a cell phone,
you're some fucking barbarian creature.
That doesn't make any sense.
I've got A.
I've got a good jumping point from
because we were talking about
innovations.
You ready for this birth order and
innovations birth order,
your birth order as far as like where
you were born,
right?
So you ready for this?
First,
I'll give you the background of that
story and then I'll tell you about some
research that we did in a consumer
context.
So there's this gentleman by the name of
Frank Salloway.
He's a historian of science and a huge
Darwin supporter.
He wrote a book in Nineteen Ninety six,
highly recommended called born to rebel
where he looked at the 28 most radical
scientific innovations and the history
of human thought.
Okay.
The reason for 28,
there's nothing magical about number 28.
There was some criterion by which
something got into that list or not.
So he looked at the 28th most radical
scientific innovation theory of
evolution would be one,
right?
Something that really changed our
understanding of the world and then he
looked at the birth order through
historical records of either the people
who espouse the theory or those who were
the staunchest,
the tractors,
opponents to the theory.
And what he found is that the later
borns,
we're much more likely to be the ones to
espouse the radical scientific
innovations.
Wow.
Now,
I'll explain in a second why,
uh,
so he argued basically that when a child
is born,
the first sort of adaptive problem that
he has to solve is how to maximize
parental investment to,
to,
to himself or herself.
And the way you do that is by occupying
a unique niche in the eyes of your
parents.
So if your firstborn,
uh,
there are no other niches that have been
occupied.
So for example,
in each would be I want to be a good
boy.
I want to be a rebel would be another
niche,
right?
So that he called this Darwinian
partitioning niche hypothesis,
right?
So it's,
it's,
it's a positioning proposition,
right?
How do I position myself to be maximally
different from all the other children?
So the first,
the first,
uh,
born has nobody,
all the niches are available as you go
down the cip ship,
there are fewer and fewer niches that
are available.
This forces later barns to be more out
of the box thinkers to be more
malleable,
to be less rigid,
to be less conforming.
And,
and the data was actually quite
astonishing.
So for 23 out of the 28th radical
scientific innovations,
that's exactly what he found.
Incidentally.
Do you want to guess what the
Godfather's birth orders last?
Thank you.
Fourth of four.
That's why I always said expect great
things from the Godfather.
It's meant to be.
But,
but anyways,
so,
so we took this idea and we applied it
to,
since we were talking about adoption
of phones and cell phones,
smart phones,
we applied it to the context of are you
a product innovator?
Jus adopt something early or late and so
on.
And we exactly replicated celebrates
findings.
Firstborns were much more conforming
later.
Bourns were much more innovative in the
product context.
So we took the idea of way and applied
in a consumer context that actually
makes a ton of sense.
Another thing I think could possibly be
a consideration is that when you're
younger you get fucked with by your
older brothers and sisters because they
can,
because they're tired of taking shit
from the parents and you're forced to
think outside the box because you got to
work around.
Those fuckers are constantly trying to
mess your game up.
At every point in turn they cheat,
they make up rules.
They tell you what mom said,
well mom didn't really say anything yet.
You get in trouble the last born now,
first hot.
Okay.
I know devious.
I don't do that.
You're not supposed to have all these
statues as the firstborn.
There was no.
Well,
only in only in the conforming sense.
On the other hand,
you could argue that maybe within your
social media this is conforming,
right?
So it could be.
Yeah.
Or you just liked tattoos or he just
liked that it was.
And you're not scared of pain.
Right?
I think that's more likely,
right?
Oh yeah.
I think it's fascinating when you look
at what causes someone to be innovative
and what causes someone mean.
It's one of the things that I've thought
of as a parent and um,
many my friends have the same issue.
It's all my interesting friends came
from fucked up childhoods.
All my interesting friends had parents
that were a mess and they all childhood
was chaos and it forced them to develop
a unique character,
right?
All of them.
And I'm trying my best to make my
children's lives as easy and comfortable
as possible.
But in doing so,
am I hampering them right hampering
their development and some sort of a
whiteboard or around them,
around them,
smack on every now and then just to keep
it,
push them my way.
No,
just I think that there's other ways,
and this is my theory,
there's other ways to encourage
innovation or creativity or to pursue
your passions and dreams.
And one of the things that I'm also
quite shocked at,
um,
with having children is how absolutely,
absolutely unique.
They are right out of the box in a happy
environment with no stress,
no financial issues.
No,
there's no arguing and screaming from
the parents,
like what is it about kids had to those
right out of the vagina are just a
totally different person,
like from day one made from each other.
Yes.
So different.
That speaks to the fact that there are
an innate elements to our personhood,
right?
Or astrology.
Astrology,
yes.
Yes.
Maybe that's real.
That's what it may be.
You need to just come over to the
mystical side a a little bit,
Mr.
Simon to do that.
Have you ever talked to someone who can
read those?
My wild fennel aunt.
Oh really?
What?
You already forgot what we spoke about?
No,
but can she read those charts?
she could read the.
This,
the,
the coffee stains.
No,
but that's nonsense.
That's talks about astrological stuff.
Yeah.
You know those people that can read
those things were mercury's in
retrograde and they know we're Pluto is
the time your dad came and your mom.
I think I can figure that stuff out on
hung around in those circles,
so unfortunately not enough.
Apparently there are people that are
absolutely consumed by the Uber Complex
aspects of astrology,
like real astrology now,
like the stuff that you get in your
Sunday paper,
Oh,
I'm a Leo,
so today's a good day to take a shit or
whatever the hell it would be.
Right.
All those really random,
but apparently there's just volumes of
books written on constellations and the
alignment of these constellations and
where the stars are at any particular
time and it's dependent upon what time
of year,
what time of day do you buy into that in
any way,
shape or form?
Because there are a lot of people that
believe that Leo's have a very distinct
personality and have distinct
personality traits that are trackable.
I don't care about Leo's.
I'm libra telling me about.
I don't know,
but I'm Aaliyah.
I don't even understand the good
looking.
Very charismatic.
Very brilliant.
What happened to you?
I know I hired.
That's the outlier.
I'm the black sheep.
Wait a minute.
Black sheep.
That's triggering tracy.
Yes.
You.
Then you said trigger,
which is even more of a trigger,
right?
Oh my God.
I'm so triggered.
I didn't even know what to do.
Here's another one that I wanted to
bring up with you about that trigger
ship because it was something that you
were helping about.
You sent me and I went,
wow,
we tweeted it.
Oh my God.
It was.
It was about.
I was so angry.
The woman who was a professor or Kipnis.
Yes.
Explained the story because I'm.
I'm searching.
So basically the idea is that there's
all these movements about,
you know,
how horrifyingly violent campuses are in
terms of sexual violence,
which is of course not true.
And she had written an article where she
was criticizing that position,
sort of the lunacy,
the hysteria involved with that
narrative,
right.
One out of every five women will be
raped on canvas,
which is complete nonsense,
isn't nonsense.
What,
what,
what are the actual numbers?
So I don't,
I haven't studied it carefully,
but I thought that was true.
Well,
because it depends how you defined.
Right?
So I think if you look at them exactly
right.
Right.
So the,
so exactly the male,
because the male gaze is a form of
visual rape.
That's why,
by the way,
that's why I've written an article about
this.
You should check it out.
Uh,
the bikini is patriarchal oppression.
While the Burka is liberating.
This is western feminists who argue this
and they argue this because.
Exactly using the argument of the male
gaze,
since the Burka liberates women from the
male gaze and the bikini draws the male
gaze,
the bikini is bad.
The burke as good.
What is the grape smuggler?
What's the grid smarter?
That's where men were a little,
little,
tiny little John Claude van Damme
underwear.
Things that people were like in France
and stuff,
you know,
it was a little bikini that,
that reference went over my head.
Oh,
you mean like this?
The little speedos?
Yeah.
Speedos,
but.
Well,
women don't respond to the visual
stimuli the way that men do too.
Where?
Oh,
you say that.
Evolutionary psychology.
Come on.
Listen,
when girls see channing tatum doing that
Magic Mike Shit,
dancing around on stage,
you tell me the not responding to visual
stimuli.
Get the fuck.
I hear a bunch of convenient bullshit by
guys who have shitty bodies.
We don't want to think their girlfriends
drooling a channing tatum with his
little fucking daisy dukes on or
whatever.
He's wearing his construction,
so you actually think that is in that
men and women are indistinguishable in
the manner by which they respond to.
It didn't say that.
I didn't say that,
but they absolutely respond visually.
That's the reason why men want to have
six packs wise because girls get excited
by it.
It's very simple.
I just don't think it's the same sort of
stem.
I think there's there's pursuit stimuli
where a guy will see a girl who's got a
hot bag into bikini and go,
oh Jesus,
and they literally go running up to them
to try to talk to them.
Yes.
I don't think that same thing happens
with females to males as much,
but the idea,
but I think that's also just gender
roles,
has deal with testosterone,
has to deal with many,
many things.
Culture,
the normal behavior as far as male,
female behavior.
I think both sexes,
when they look at each other,
are looking for a important cues that
are relevant to the American market.
So you're absolutely right that women
are looking,
for example,
they like tight buttocks because that
sends an important signal for size and
shape of the sperm point nine waist to
hip ratio on a mass of the swimmers.
The male swimmers build is very have
wide shoulders,
thin waist.
So,
so I'm not suggesting that women don't
respond to visual cues,
but they certainly don't respond nearly
as much as men.
I think they respond probably in an
equal,
uh,
within equal intensity but not act in an
equal intensity and certainly not act in
a threatening way.
And that's where the male gaze comes in.
So why aren't there a million a male
stripper shops targeting heterosexual
women?
You should get into that market like a
lot of.
Well,
there is a lot of male strip shows and
in fact in vegas,
those are the things that they advertise
the airport when you go there,
the thunder down under and all this
jazz.
Bunch of guys with their shirts off
sweaty,
but women don't feel comfortable going
into those environments the way men feel
comfortable.
So they go in these packs of wild
estrogen creatures and they scream and
yell.
I used to have a bit about it that it's
a totally that ladies'
night out.
It's a totally different kind of
experience when they go leave,
they scream and cheer and yell.
Where guys sit there and don't say much
of anything.
He just kind of stare like that speaks
predatory.
Exactly.
There's definitely a difference.
It's sisterhood of the pants or
whatever.
That right there.
They're banding together,
right?
I just think that women don't have the
correct outlet,
which is why when a book like 50 shades
of grey comes out,
they all go fucking bananas.
Like finally we've got a channel to to
funnel.
All of our sex urge is through right
now.
You see them read their reading porn on
planes.
You're passing by on planes.
They're reading gag porn.
Well,
by the way,
if you want to understand male versus
female sexuality,
I don't you do,
but please,
if you.
If you want to understand male sexuality
than you do a content analysis of
pornography.
If you want to understand female
sexuality,
you do a content analysis of romance
novels.
It's true,
right?
So if you look at the archetype of the,
and that's going to speak to your six
back about the pretty guy.
Uh,
if you look at the archetype of the male
hero in romance novels,
irrespective of which culture the
romance novel is written,
and it's going to be Romania or Egypt or
your Newport beach,
he's always the same guy.
He's a tall guy.
He's got a six pack.
He's account meaning,
right?
He's also a neurosurgeon.
He wrestles alligators on his six back.
He's reckless.
He's risky,
but only to be tamed by the love of that
one woman.
Right?
So I've already told you about the every
single archetype that you've,
I mean the same archetype and every
romance novel.
The reason why the archetype is there is
because it exactly caters to women's
fantasies.
And sometimes he's like half a chick.
Like he's got long hair and like very
chique like behavior.
He wears,
like flowing very sheer shirts,
which no guy in their right mind would
ever wear.
And if you did where women would mock
you,
right?
Right.
If you were,
if you have long flowing fabio hair and
you had like a,
a,
like a blouse on and you went out to a
nightclub,
people go with a fuck is wrong with that
guy.
But in a romance novel,
you're on the cover baby.
Well,
because you have to also send out some
cues of sensitivity,
right?
Is that what that is?
It's an artistic.
It's a bit sensitive.
So.
So guess it's just not a real person,
just like the vampires when there's a
reason why women fell in love with those
fucking stupid vampires.
Like why?
Why is that?
Vampires that don't even burn up in the
sun.
They sparkle like what was all that
about?
Um,
I dunno.
Those narratives on dairy,
you twilight,
goddammit.
I don't watch that stuff.
Sorry.
New.
I'm too busy watching Lionel Messi a
right,
right.
Well,
those books sold fucking millions of the
vampire ones.
Yes.
Millions and millions of copies.
And they were essentially a form of
romance porn vampire bullshit for
chicks.
And again,
these men in these books,
these vampires,
they didn't exist.
Not only did they not exist,
they didn't make sense.
Like the main
one,
that one that uh,
you know,
there's Christian,
whatever the hell her name was and ed,
whatever the fuck his name is rob,
whatever the fuck his name.
I don't know any of those that carry
out.
The guy was supposed to bleed like 90
years old or something like that.
He got,
he got like in the Spanish plague is
when he died and that's when it became a
vampire,
but he has to still go to high school
because when it became a vampire he was
like 17,
so he has to show up and go to high
school with all normal people.
But he goes to high school in the
Pacific northwest because it's never
sunny out.
So he doesn't glitter.
It's one of the dumbest fucking books of
all time.
Why don't you get watch that stuff?
Well,
I didn't talk.
Know a lot about a lot about it.
I've watched little moments of it before
I panicked and shut it off.
Right.
I actually did watch one of them,
I think I watched the second one anyway,
point being watched.
The one with.
They became Werewolf's.
It was fucking so stupid.
It made me mad.
But point being like,
this guy is 90 fucking years old and
he's hanging around with 17 year old.
That guy's an asshole,
right?
He's pretending to be 17.
He falls in love with the 17 year old
navy and had sex with her eventually,
which is pedophilia and then we're
really pedal.
Not just pedophilia but like,
what the fuck is wrong with you?
What do you have in common?
You've been around for 90 years and
you've got something in common with this
girl who's 17 years old.
It's fucking ridiculous.
No more than 90 years really because in
the 19 twenties or whatever the hell it
was,
we're assuming that he was 17 years old
then,
so he's more than 100 years old.
It's,
it's the dumbest fucking book of all
time,
but it was huge.
Women loved it and it didn't represent a
real person and he represented the exact
opposite of a real person.
Like what guys like actually exists,
guys like sluts.
Okay.
And those are real.
And I,
when I say slots,
it was all due respect.
I'm not slut shaming,
which is by the way another trigger.
Yes.
Don't slut.
Shame is because then you're,
you're mocking girls for their ability
to choose their sexual partners as part
of the patriarchy.
Yes.
Yes it is,
right?
Yes.
I'm strongly against the patriarchy.
Are you going to get in trouble for this
podcast and the way he's not at all.
Last time you didn't know.
No one said anything and I mean some
trolls.
Do they usually it was a Jew that you
choose.
You Ju Ju got mad at you for being
Jewish.
Julie's as Zionists shields.
June.
Uh,
that's usually the extent of the
negative stuff.
I've done a damn sign.
The shills yeah.
Let's go back to your friend Laura
Kipnis did say her name,
Kiss Kiss,
Kiss Laura Kipnis.
She is a professor at northwestern
university.
So she wrote this essay,
a chronicle of higher education.
And in the article in the Atlantic it
brings it up describing a new campus
politics of sexual paranoia.
And she was then subject to a long
investigation after students who were
offended by the articles and by a tweet
that she sent file filed a chapter nine
complaint against her.
Now what does that mean?
I think it's that,
uh,
you know,
women should have equal access to
education and so on.
I'd be in a safe,
you know,
like she was somehow suppressing.
Well because by her,
by
her,
uh,
making light of the endemic sexual
violence on campus and quotes,
she was condoning it and therefore she
was making all these women feel unsafe
and unwelcomed and threatened on campus.
And so two students,
uh,
started that process.
Now I don't know the details.
I mean I'm not a constitutional lawyer,
but basically once sort of the,
the complaint is filed,
then sort of the train starts and it
becomes this orwellian thing that that's
just,
I mean it's just,
it's,
it's a complete nightmare.
And so I read that stuff and I just got
so angry and I spent pretty much that
whole day rallying up the forces in your
kind enough to treat it and just,
you know,
your tweet got me something like 100,000
views.
Uh,
and then I communicated with her because
I wanted to send her a signal that,
you know,
there are some of us that still have to
stickler fortitude that are willing to.
I mean,
in academia you shouldn't even say
gesticulate trigger that it's for men.
Why counterparts compatriot.
Sure.
Uh,
and,
and so,
you know,
I just wanted to,
to tell her that,
uh,
some of us were supporting her.
Yeah.
I read it and I thought it was really
serving.
I thought it was really disturbing
because it just seems so common.
That's the most disturbing aspect.
There was not some unusual occurrence
where kids are freaking out about
nothing and overreacting.
Where you could look at it like,
what is this?
It's like,
oh,
this again,
you know.
And that's what bugs me the most about
it.
It's this,
again,
it's the idea that looking at data and
looking at the realities of the climate
of free speech on these campuses and how
it's oppressed and it's not free speech,
you are free to think as they do know
and if you don't think as they do,
you're not free.
That's right.
You know,
this issue of how cowardly most
academics have become.
And I,
and I say this,
realizing that I'm going to piss off
many of my colleagues.
I'm astonished how academics who are in
the business of engaging in public
discourse are so tepid because they've
been silenced and to fear.
And I mean,
I see it in many,
many different ways,
but I'll just share one example which I
think I shared in another show recently.
So if I put up a,
a,
a clip on facebook,
have a Iraqi astronomer who was arguing
that,
uh,
in the Koran it says that the earth is
flat and it's clear that the earth is
flat.
Okay?
So I shared that clip to demonstrate
sort of the lunacy that,
uh,
you know,
religious dogma I can have on an
otherwise supposedly intelligent person.
I mean Iraqi astronomer now,
what do you think the reaction was of
Islamophobia?
Zionist asshole.
He's allowed to have those thoughts.
He's part of a suppressed culture,
right?
So she didn't,
she didn't have the courage to tackle me
that way,
but she wrote on my publicly not
privately,
uh,
this wasn't academic white woman from
California who's written with guilt and
hate her in a.
She wrote to me saying,
you know,
don't you think that,
it's bad of you to be sharing this,
don't you think it's bad that you're
sort of stigmatizing them?
So step for a second and think about
what this means,
right?
This scientist,
colleague of mine was not offended that
a fellow scientists would actually hold
such a astonishingly false position.
Right?
He's a member of the flat Earth Society.
Rather,
she was offended that I would point to
his lunacy.
So that I think that small anecdote
really captures the culture of fear that
you see on campuses.
And in a sense,
if I can sort of toot my own horn,
I'm,
I'm really a very rare breed,
sort of the guy who walks around not
caring a saying it as it is,
because that's my personality.
I can't be anything else,
but you also are a very open minded guy
and so when it comes down to like the
core values of these people promote,
whether it is a lack of racial
insensitivity or racial stereotyping,
gender issues,
whether it's sexism or homophobia,
you're,
you're on the liberal side of all that
stuff.
But so you're.
So you're essentially a liberal,
right?
If I can say I'm a true liberal,
not the liberals that exist today
because the liberals have today as our
common friend,
Sam Harris and Ayaan Hirsi Ali have
said,
have a huge blind spot when it comes to
certain issues where they fall really on
the wrong side of the issue.
So a true liberal is one who doesn't
Miss Ward,
who doesn't fall prey to cultural and
moral relativism.
Who doesn't say,
well,
who are we to judge the cutting off of
Clarissa's of women?
That's their culture,
right?
So that's a true liberal,
so not a true liberal.
They're not,
they're fake liberals.
Well,
I think what they're doing is they're
subscribing to the current trend of,
of discourse.
Right.
And the current trend of discourse is
anything Islamic,
leave it alone.
Yes.
And uh,
I think a lot of that's being a pussy.
Yeah,
I really do.
I think a lot of that is cowardice.
They're afraid of backlash.
They're afraid of a label.
Islamophobia is a very strange label
because there's no Christian have phobia
and even antisemetic,
you know,
there,
there's a certain amount of antisemetic,
a logic and thinking that is promoted in
certain Islamic cultures that's ignored
as well.
So you can,
you can get away with that in certain
ways.
Like,
did you see that video of the guy that
was walking through Paris dressed in a
Jewish way?
Yes.
Whoa.
Was that fucking disturbing?
If,
uh,
if you haven't seen it,
it is.
It's just showing how openly in,
in the most sickening way openly anti
Jewish.
So many people are in,
in Paris,
by the way.
I should make it clear.
And of course now there'll be the hate
comments.
Uh,
it's not anti Israel,
right?
It's,
yes,
it's anti Jewish.
It's antisemitic.
One hundred percent.
I don't like the term symmetric because
some medic is like some many people.
It's represents a lot of people that
aren't Jewish.
It's anti Jewish,
right?
I mean,
although the term is understood,
typically symmetric means it's
anonymous,
but your point is well taken.
Why is his antisemitic?
Because there's a lot of Semitic
cultures that aren't Jewish.
I don't know the sort of the original
historical context for why that tool
when you want to appear to be smart,
you say antisemetic,
you don't say anti Jewish.
That's right.
It sounds a bit more.
More educated,
more educated since confirmed dummy.
I can go with anti Jewish.
Well,
pick up the route.
Can't be.
You can't be a dummy and a good comic,
which you are.
Because as I think we might've discussed
before,
or maybe we didn't,
there was a correlation between being
funny and being highly intelligent.
But whether you probably have.
There's a type of intelligence like
mathematically on basically retarded.
I'm really,
but you probably have good social
intelligence,
right,
because I'm able to come up with those
anecdotes,
right?
You actually have acuity to see patterns
in terms of social interactions.
Otherwise,
what will be much for Pat,
myself on the back.
So I'll let you do that real quick and
then we'll move on.
Well,
I'm overwhelmed by your charisma,
Joe.
Thank you very much sir.
But getting back to this video,
um,
I didn't see anyone freaking out over
it,
but anything that may be a Sam Harris,
our friend would say over overblown and
blown out of proportion to the extreme
because it's a target because that label
Islamophobia is so.
He's like when Ben Affleck that fucking
dumb ass when he went after him on the
bill Maher show and just like really
like,
it was such an obvious ploy to like fit
into that idea.
The eye.
It wasn't like a well thought out,
well examined point of view.
It was like,
I can't believe what you're saying.
What you're saying.
So racist.
He's arrogant and his ignorance.
Yes.
Arrogant in the fact that he felt like
this was an easy thing to pull off.
That's what.
And he'd get the applause from the
audience.
He was searching for Social Brownie
points,
surfing Social Brownie points,
going back to the,
to the anti Jewish stuff.
I mean,
I grew up in Lebanon,
as you know,
and I'm Jewish,
I mean an atheist,
but I'm Jewish.
Tough accent by the way,
for anybody who's going to write and
say,
well,
how could he be Jewish and atheist?
You can be both.
Some of the most famous Jews were all
atheists.
Judaism is more than just adherence to a
set of religious narratives,
right?
There's a cultural element.
There is a historical element.
There are all sorts of fastest to being
Jewish that don't necessarily mean you
have to believe in Booga Booga stuff,
right?
Booga Booga not going to get hate mail
from the rabbis hate from the Buddha.
Buddha too.
But anyways,
uh,
so I grew up in Lebanon,
now you might say,
oh,
but Lebanon was such a progressive,
tolerant,
wonderful place where everybody got
along.
I wouldn't say that I used to date a
Lebanese girl.
And what did say she told me it's
fucking craziness.
Was it that she was.
Well,
she grew up in America,
but her family was from Lebanon and she,
you know,
well,
the,
the typical sort of narrative that you
hear is that Lebanon was of all
countries in the Middle East was the
most progressive one and have to some
extent that was true.
But what they don't understand is that
progressive in the context of the Middle
East is very,
very different than progressive in the
West.
Right?
So if you were Jewish,
you were quilt tolerated.
That means that will tolerate you until
we no longer tolerate you.
Enhanced.
That's why we left Lebanon because we
were going to be executed.
Right.
Uh,
so,
uh,
I grew up sort of with a dark secret.
I'm Jewish.
I mean,
right.
You didn't wear a star of David.
Now if people wanted to find out if you
were Jewish,
they could easily do that.
They could go to synagogue on Saturday.
And so it's not as though it was
absolutely hidden,
but you certainly,
you know,
know your place amongst the greater
crowd.
You're a minority and we tolerate you.
You live,
if you like,
if I don't know if you know the term,
do you know the term?
They may know them as a second,
third class citizen as enshrined in the
Islamic texts for people at the book,
meaning Christians and Jews.
Meaning monotheists,
right?
Not,
not the Pagans,
not the polytheist,
not the Hindus,
not the,
not the Buddhist,
not the atheist,
but Jews and Christians under Islamic
law could be afforded protection as long
as they paid the right.
That means they pay sort of a poll tax
to be protected by their Muslim
overlords.
Whoa,
okay.
That's called to live as a Dhimmi.
Okay.
So in Lebanon,
you didn't officially have to pay that
poll tax,
but what you did is you knew your place.
So for example,
my brother David,
who was a,
you would like this because you're a
fighter,
a guy mma guy.
He used to be in the Olympics and judo
and Nike 76.
Well,
in,
in the early seventies,
he had won several Lebanese
championships and then one day he was
visited by some guys who told him that,
you know,
Jew,
boy,
it's time to sort of stop winning.
So it's time to retire or else you end
up at the bottom of a river.
Then he left to pursue his career in
judo and France.
This was before the civil war stuff.
My,
my,
when we,
when we escaped Lebanon,
I mean,
literally we're escaping execution when,
when the,
uh,
this is the first time that anybody
hears this particular story.
So you're,
that's your birthday gift.
So,
uh,
as we,
as the captain said that we were out of
Lebanese airspace,
this is when we're leaving Lebanon to,
to immigrate to Canada.
Uh,
and he says,
we're out of Lebanese.
My mother takes out a star of David,
puts it around my neck and says,
now you don't have to hide who you are.
Now this is in progressive Lebanon,
pluralistic Lebanon.
So now,
now watch what's gonna happen.
Now I'm going to receive comments of
people saying what a hate monger he is.
He's just trying to make those other
folks look bad.
So my whole personal history as somehow
negated,
I'm either making it up or
why am I talking about this?
Why are you making.
So I'm the hateful guy for mentioning
that I escaped execution of others.
Well,
I don't think you should pay those
people any minds for certainly not
address them when they're not even
communicating with you.
You like sort of artificially bringing
up their voices and then responding to
their voices.
There's no need for that godfather move
on.
Um,
but this,
uh,
it,
it disturbed me that this video wasn't
this video of this guy walking through
Paris.
Was He,
he was a Jewish gentleman who was
dressed as,
he was exciting.
He was,
it was,
it was like that girl that walked
through Manhattan and got all the cat.
Exactly.
That's exactly the idea behind it was to
sort of.
There is everybody knows it's similar.
There's an almost the identical clip in
Cairo.
You could look it up on youtube where a
guy where's sort of the aesthetic look
and he starts walking around Cairo and
it's not pretty.
What lucky you didn't get killed,
right?
It's just so fucking crazy that we're in
this world where we're at now where
people are so terrified of the label,
Islamophobia and of Islam,
of what happened with Charlie Hebdo.
Yes.
Things along those lines.
The Charlie Hebdo,
if you don't know the story,
it's a magazine and Paris,
they would draw these cartoons of
Muhammad and they were uh,
all the cartoonists were killed by
gunman,
Muslim government.
So what does it say right here?
Scroll down to the top please.
Jamie walk.
Watch the abuse the Jewish man gets as
you walk through Paris.
And this is from [inaudible] dot com and
it's just fucking crazy.
The team film for Ten hours to get 90
seconds of material that they had to go
to the roughest parts of Paris to get.
Oh,
so they're saying,
okay.
So this is very similar.
Right?
So,
um,
so what they're saying I guess is that
they really kind of blew it out of
proportion because they edited it down
from this 10 hours to get,
to get 90 seconds.
Is that what they're saying?
Jamie said 90 seconds.
Yeah.
Okay.
I,
you don't need to watch the youtube
clip.
I just have to tell you about my
personal history in Lebanon.
Do you want to hear some more stuff?
I'd love to.
I'm maybe nine years old.
Uh,
maybe the equivalent of great for here.
Great.
Three or four teacher says,
okay,
everybody,
here's the exercise for the next
whatever,
half an hour.
Get up and tell the class what you want
to be when you grew up.
So,
uh,
hi,
my name.
I want to be a soccer player.
I want to be a policeman.
I want to be this.
He gets up,
I remember his name.
I actually couldn't even recognize his
face and the old photos.
It says,
when I grow up teacher,
I want to be a Jew.
Killer,
killer,
killer.
Everybody breaks out into applause.
Now,
does that mean that everybody in Lebanon
was this Rabid Anti Semite?
Of course not.
But is,
is,
is our dose feelings pervasive through
out every social fabric,
whether it be on TV and political
speeches and dramas and soap operas.
It,
it's everywhere.
It's endemic to every single DNA of
those societies.
Uh,
and so that's why you have these types
of problems.
I'll give you another quick example of
school,
but that one real quick,
if you don't mind,
please do.
So now we're getting into some serious
nine years old,
nine eight,
10 minutes radios in that area.
And um,
what,
what was going through your mind?
And this is a time where you kind of,
you as you said,
you knew your place,
so you,
you,
you didn't,
you didn't openly talk about your
Judaism or.
Yeah,
I mean you're just,
you know,
you did.
People know you because you know,
you're Jewish so it's not,
it's not.
Your students did know I was,
I was a student,
but do you think this too,
I mean,
just your students follow suit?
My cohorts.
I think many of them probably didn't
know that I was Jewish.
Uh,
uh,
I'm almost certain.
I mean,
I don't know,
I didn't sit there and talk about these
issues as a kid said Ju killer.
Whoa,
what the fuck man?
What,
what did,
what did that feel like?
Well,
it,
it feels like you're different.
It feels like you're in a precarious
situation always.
It feels like a,
you know,
uh,
and French.
There's an expression swab bell,
which means a,
be pretty and sit quietly,
right?
Uh,
that's what it know your place.
Okay.
So that's what it means to be tolerant,
right?
To be tolerated.
It's not,
it's not that you're equal right here.
Never equal.
You can't be prime minister of Lebanon
as a Jew.
I'll give you another quick story.
Uh,
uh,
there was a general Egyptian politics
from say the seventies.
There was a Abdulnasser was a famous Pan
Arabesque who brought together the Arab
world.
He was an Egyptian,
a president who,
who was viewed as the hero because he
was going to sort of unite the Arab
world against the colonial powers and so
on.
And so he was this kind of larger than
life superhero of the Arab world when he
died in 1970,
as often happens in the Middle East,
there are all these incredibly sort of
violent demonstrations on the streets.
And I was sitting in my house.
I was maybe five years old,
almost six.
And as this mass of people pass,
by all you hear that the Jews,
the Jews,
what,
what did the Jews have to do with this
politician passing away in Egypt?
But that's just the reflex,
right?
I mean,
it must be some Zionist conspiracy.
It must be.
So I'm sitting there sort of hiding in
my balcony as these people are passing
and it's etched in my memory,
the chance of death to Jews.
And there are all these sort of Arabic
chance that I could repeat now that you
know,
people wouldn't understand them.
That's just part of how things were.
Now,
does that mean that on every single day,
every single day of my life there I was
being persecuted.
Of course not right.
I mean I lived a normal life until I was
going to be executed.
So that's the reality of the Middle
East.
And that's why today you almost have no
religious minorities to speak of and you
were in the Middle East,
right?
I mean,
the remaining bastions of Christianity
in the Middle East are now either being
clobbered or they're forced to leave
right?
In Iraq,
in,
uh,
the cops in Egypt to some extent now
we're seeing it also in Nigeria.
Uh,
and so,
you know,
this idea that we all kind of coexist in
the released.
This is Bologna.
It's not true.
You're tolerated at best.
What are the,
what was the percentage of people that
were Jews in Lebanon when you were
there?
So at the,
so we were part of the last remaining
Jews in Lebanon at one point I think I
could be off on the numbers and you'll
correct me if I'm wrong later,
maybe in the descriptor,
maybe 15,000
at most.
15,
$20,000
out of a population of about maybe $3
million at the zenith.
Right?
So a very small minority.
Now when Israel came along in 1948,
it made it that much more difficult to
be Jewish and Arab countries.
Now this is not to give cover to
antisemitism,
which is independent of Israel,
right?
Antisemitism has existed for 1400 years
in those parts of the world
independently of Israel.
But once Israel came about in 1948,
it just made it that much more
precarious for Jews to live in Libya and
Iraq and in Egypt and in Syria and
Lebanon.
And so they'd be these mass exoduses of
Jews from Arab lands,
sometimes forced other times by choice
because it just became untenable for
Jews to be there.
We were part of the last wave of
remaining Jews because we were very
entrenched within Lebanese society.
Uh,
but then once the civil war started and
it just wasn't possible to be there in
Lebanon,
you had these internal ID cards that you
carried around like a passport,
but internally that stated your religion
on it.
So in the context of the Lebanese civil
war where they would set up these
roadblocks,
these militia would set up roadblocks.
If you get to a roadblock and somebody
says in Arabic,
you say how we give me your,
your,
uh,
your ID card.
Well,
that ID card has your religion on it.
If you're the wrong religion,
it's good.
Bye.
Well,
that was what's going on with the Sunni
and Shiite in Iraq.
Exactly,
exactly.
Roadblocks,
roadblocks to kill people.
Well,
the problem in the Middle East is that
you have endless abrahamic religions.
And again,
it's not just the Mazda,
and I'm not trying to be relativists
here,
but all the abrahamic religions sort of
have a narrative of uniqueness and it's
very,
very hard to coexist when you know,
each of us is the chosen people.
I have my theory about the Middle East
and my theory is that they're the
townies of the world.
What does that mean?
The townies are the people that never
left their neighborhood.
And if you,
if you look at the cradle of
civilization,
it's Babylon.
It's sue mayor.
So that's the oldest written language,
oldest mathematics,
that's where Iraq is,
right?
And that area is a clusterfuck today.
And everybody moved out of there.
Everybody moved out of Africa.
Africa's chaos,
right?
We all know that.
Um,
I
think that much like small towns,
you grow up in and if you go back,
there you go,
Jesus,
he's fucking assholes are still hanging
around the high school,
you know,
being annoying at the gas station.
They,
the same people there.
They're stuck in the same way.
They have not evolved,
they have not moved past the rest of the
world has and it seems like with a lot
of these religions,
they're so rigid in their ideology and
the standards of their behavior and the
classifications of the individuals that
are involved in it,
that it's almost inescapable.
These rigid ideology seem like it's the
idea of progressive thinking or
progressive thought.
It's almost.
They're almost mutually exclusive.
You can't have that and exist in that.
In that form.
Coalitional thinking is a endemic part
of human psychology,
right?
The idea of us versus them as part of
human nature and what these Abrahamic
religions do is they take this and they
put her on steroids.
Right?
I mean it it.
It is a great study.
I can't remember who it is or I might
punch it up a bit,
but it goes something like this.
You're bringing people into the lab and
you make them wait in the waiting area
and you just put a sticker either blue
or red on them and then you say,
Oh,
you're not going to come back in a few
minutes.
I'm going to go off to do something
else.
I'll be back in a few minutes.
The real point of the experiment is to
see what people ended up doing during
that time that you're out.
What do you think happens?
The people who have the red sticks read
the stickers,
start speaking to each other and the
people,
right,
so you're taking a completely random
queue and you're forcing people to
assort along that cute right now,
it's no longer matters what my sexual
orientation is or whether I'm Muslim or
Christian or Jewish.
It's red people band together versus
blue people.
There are various versions of this
experiment that had been done and in
classic social psychology,
but what that speaks to is this,
a inextricable,
this,
this inescapable trap of coalitional
psychology and that's what happens in
the Middle East.
Everything is viewed through the prism
of my faith and anybody who's not my
faith is the other and the other is not.
To be trusted is to be hated as to be
scoring that.
Now,
that doesn't mean that every single
person subscribes to that,
but it certainly means that the
narrative,
the religious narratives certainly
condones that,
so yeah,
with rigid ideologies and tribal
behavior and then add that to a very
harsh environment,
physical environment where it's just
unforgiving.
It's real hard to move past that real
hard to find forgiveness and
enlightenment and see in and matter of
fact.
That was one of the things is another
issue that I think,
I believe it was Michael Shermer who
wrote an article about the difference
between Islam and some of the other
religions is that they never went
through the enlightenment.
Right.
Well,
I think one of the problem,
one of the.
You now see many a vociferous in public
intellectuals that are coming out to a
call for an reformation,
but that's actually been happening for
1400 years.
The problem is it's easy to call for a
reformation if you assume that there's
something to be reformed.
If you think it's perfect.
There's nothing to be reformed right
here in PA state for even considering
that,
but if you're going to reform it,
how do you go about doing that?
When one of the tenants,
the tenants,
is that in Arabic you say a kid,
meaning every single letter of the Koran
is immutable,
is eternal and it's perfect.
Well,
how can you have an exit?
Just how could you exit just as like a,
I'm not pronouncing it right,
but like how could you interpret texts
or reinterpret texts when in reality you
doing that becomes a form of
sacrilegious.
Right?
So that's the problem in the context of
the other Abrahamic religions,
there was the capacity for the light of
reformation to squeeze its way into
those little holes so that there could
be new interpretations and so on.
In Islam it's a bit more of a challenge.
So what about people that are Islamic
reformers?
Who are the members of the people in
the.
There are people today that considered
themselves Muslim but also are atheists.
There are people that consider
themselves Muslims,
like you consider yourself a Jew but
you're an atheist.
Right?
What about those people that don't
aren't so ideologically rigid,
rigid?
Think they all moved right there.
Don't move down,
and they certainly never openly stated
they're not unbelief in the Middle East,
during Ramadan with that.
That would not be good.
Don't be good.
They'll fuck you up if you eat during
Ramadan.
Right?
Well,
and certainly isis now has killed many
people who violated a Ramadan rules,
uh,
now,
of course,
then you'll hear back that they're not
really.
They're not Islamic,
right?
I do hear that.
Listen,
I've engaged people in various forums
where we start chatting.
Then I'll quote something from say,
do you know who he is?
He's the spiritual leader of the Muslim
Brotherhood.
One of the foremost leaders of the
Sunni.
A Sec.
In terms of as a religious scholar,
right?
I mean all the perfect right pedigree
from an scholar scholars,
Islamic scholarship perspective.
So I'll quote something by him.
What do you think there were about the
Olivia,
but he's not a real Muslim.
Then I'll quote something from the
college of the so called Colophon Lysis
who has a phd in Islamic Studies.
What do you think the answer is not a
real Muslim then I'll.
Right,
so.
So it's play.
Hide the ball.
Right?
So.
So if you have so much duplicity in your
discourse that guys who by definition
are leaders and experts of Islam who are
then being a.
You pretend that they're not Muslim
because they say something that you,
you find objectionable than how can we
have an often and honest discourse you
can't,
so how do we fix that?
That's my my,
my,
my running.
By the way,
my last podcast.
How do we fix this?
I think we fixed it with everything by
having people who have the courage as
many of some of your guests have and
maybe I can include myself in this group
who are open,
who are honest,
who are reasonable,
who are not filled with hate to who are
dispassionate.
Also,
they moved all of the moved moved out of
the Middle East.
So you're just saying that they can't
implement these changes on the ground.
I'm not saying that,
but I'm like,
how do you.
And I'm not sure if,
I think if I've got the answer then I
would be getting the Nobel prize.
Who is the writer?
Uh,
something Roy that was hacked to death
with the machete rails?
Yeah,
there has been for them so far.
Yeah.
He was somewhere else doing a,
it was some sort of a speech on his book
that he wrote back to Bangladesh was
hacked.
Yeah.
Hacked to death by machetes.
Um,
on the street in front of his wife was
hacked up to was horrible.
You know what the response is when I've
challenged people on that.
What they did was not Islamic.
Right.
Look,
let me give you an example.
Uh,
there was a,
uh,
a recent Orthodox Jew who in the gay
pride parade in Tel Aviv that Ed did you
have on this?
I did hear about this with stabbing
people.
Stabbing people,
right?
Yeah.
I mean,
he didn't do this because he was
alienated.
He didn't do this as a response to the
financial crisis of 2007,
2008.
I'm using examples,
by the way,
from Russell brand's luminary analysis
as to why people join isis.
It has nothing to hold up.
Russell brand thinks that Russell and I
actually,
I did a youtube clip,
uh,
on my youtube channel where I basically
covered all this.
The comedian Russell brand.
Oh yeah.
The luminary.
Luminary sarcastically.
Yes.
He basically was arguing that,
uh,
he,
he came up with every single possible
cause that you could think of other than
religious fervor to explain why people
move 4,000
miles away to join isis.
It was due.
So let me give you a few.
There were about maybe seven or eight.
I covered on my youtube clip,
but I'll,
I'll try to come up with three or four.
They were alienated.
They felt that they weren't part of the
political process.
Want to say it the way he says it?
I,
I can't,
I can't really alienated,
didn't feel like they are part of the
political process.
Yeah.
I can't do it as well as you can.
Uh,
they were,
they were upset about the financial
meltdown in 2017 financial meltdown.
They hated greedy,
rampant evil capitalism.
Capitalism,
right.
My son,
all the right words.
Very good.
Uh,
so I mean,
I mean really that's,
that's the reason why people join.
I mean there's nothing to do with
religion,
absolutely nothing to do with it.
So how could we have an honest discourse
when this is the kind of nonsense that
you keep hearing,
but you're talking to comedians and
again,
you're talking to a comedian right now.
So any logic out of this healed.
He hit some,
some people actually challenged me to
say,
well,
why do you even take the time to counter
this guy's views?
Well,
and my answer is he's got a lot bigger
platform than I do,
right?
He has much more power to influence
minds than I do.
It doesn't matter that I might be better
equipped than him as he's an athletic,
as there's been athletes and that sort
of thing.
Exactly.
And it seems like they're both kind of
fishing for social brownie points
instead of calling it Islam or instead
of calling it anything,
if you just looked at it as a pattern or
behavior,
and if you looked at that pattern and
this ideological pattern or behavior
that would seek out to murder people
that don't agree with those thoughts,
any rational person would go,
well that's crazy,
right?
That's these,
these people are fucked.
Like,
this is bad,
we can't tolerate this.
But once you start calling it anything,
whether you call it Islam or just fill
in the blank,
make up your own name for it.
And then that becomes an oppressed
segment of our civilization,
or at least a thought of as an oppressed
or boxed into that political,
uh,
sort of a segment where you're,
you're not supposed to shit on it
because it's thought to be marginalized
already and you're just piling on.
But do you think that.
So there are 50,
I want to go back in a second,
the Jewish guy.
But let me answer this last point you
made.
Do you think that in the 57 countries
that are a member of the Organization of
Islamic cooperation,
the OIC,
a Muslims are marginalized?
No,
right?
And most of those 57 countries,
they constitute an extraordinary
majority,
if not complete majority of it
something.
So this,
this narrative that Muslims are
marginalized.
I mean,
it's really laughable because I mean,
if you think about Saudi Arabia,
Yemen,
Kuwait,
Egypt,
Syria,
Iraq,
and on,
uh,
they're not marginalized.
They constitute 99 percent,
100 percent of the population,
right?
If anything is the religious minorities
that are no longer existent there that
have been marginalized,
right?
So it's eliminated,
eliminated,
or exit or genocidally removed.
So this,
this,
this isn't,
it's an informational war.
Yes.
Now,
but that's,
that's the most important part.
It's an inflammation of war and that
information and ideology that it,
it's,
it's these things,
these,
these are thoughts and patterns.
Instead of calling them religion,
instead of calling this,
this cherished tradition or cultural,
uh,
this,
this ancient thing that you're supposed
to worship instead of calling it that,
it's,
it's ideas.
These are ideas,
these ideas that this ancient script is
directly handed down from God that every
word is perfect.
If that's not preposterous,
you tell me what the fuck is because I
get real confused when people who grew
up without any science,
I mean,
they literally knew almost nothing when
they wrote this in comparison to what we
know today.
Obviously back then there were scholars,
but right in comparison,
it's,
it's laughable to think that anybody
had all the answers in 1200 or years.
The Koran,
Britain supposedly in terms of the
revelations.
So 600 something.
600,
so 680.
Yeah.
About 1400 years ago to try reading any
and textbook book from 1400 years ago
and finding correct information.
Right.
What year was Galileo prosecuted?
15 something that's going back to the
Jewish guy.
Uh,
I tweeted about it and I shared it.
And of course,
uh,
he undoubtedly got his ideas from,
I think reading leviticus where,
you know,
if you lay with another man,
you should be killed.
And so on.
Right?
So if I make that claim right,
which is an absolutely correct claim
that for this guy who took his old
testament very seriously and then went
around knifing people,
it's an absolutely appropriate claim to
make either didn't get attacked as
antisemitic.
Right?
I mean everybody says,
yeah,
no kidding.
An Orthodox Jew,
which is very rare for an orthodox Jew
to go around killing people.
But the fact that I made that,
I could make that link,
there was no blow back,
but unfortunately the West has now been
convinced that if you ever make that
link for one particular religion than
you are hateful.
That's a profoundly dangerous situation
to be in.
You seem to,
it seems to be legal in this game to a.
You can shit all over Christians.
Yes.
No.
As a matter of fact,
as a matter of fact,
if you do that,
you really progressive amongst my
academic friends.
If you repeatedly demonstrate what a
bunch of buffoons,
uh,
these Christian Pixar,
than that garners you Brownie points.
Yeah.
Why are Christian Hicks?
I'm any less profound than these,
you know,
because because it slices for Islam,
wrongly is associated with Brown people
and you don't mess with that,
but a lot of baptists are black.
True,
true.
Do people mock southern Baptist as much
as they mark like a.
that's an open empirical question,
right?
Yeah,
that's a good question.
I bet they kind of leave that alone.
I start singing and chanting against
folks.
That's right.
It's a lot of people involved.
Yes.
Solfa old apostolic is ridiculous.
It's funny.
So it's a,
it's,
it's tough dealing with all this stuff
on a daily basis on twitter and so on.
Well,
people don't want to be judged in a
negative way and especially in this
society,
in this culture and this easy to,
uh,
act culture because it's really easy to
make a tweet about someone or write a
facebook post about someone or a blog
entry about someone attacking them.
And then once you've done that,
boy,
you have opened up the flood gates and
they will just experience all sorts of
pylons from all these other people that
are either agree or support or or don't
want to be labeled such themselves.
So they'll attack you to make sure
everyone knows that they're not like
you.
Right.
It's interesting that you say that is
because some of the biggest blow back
I've gotten on my public facebook page
has been,
whenever I've called out Russell brand
on something,
apparently some of my fans are also
Russell brand fans,
which I don't know how these two
worldviews can,
can coexist,
but they got really upset that,
you know,
I was being elitist.
You know,
he's doing a lot of social good.
Yes.
Some of his stuff is quackery,
but he's a good guy.
His heart is in the right place and I'm
being an asshole for criticizing him.
And I really,
really at Vitriol for some of these
folks.
And you don't know,
you've never lived in the middle.
Oh wait.
Oh wait,
you've never heard anybody yell,
killed it.
Oh,
you did.
Now incidentally,
I should.
I should mention that my first exposure
to Russell brand before I knew about all
his funny movies.
Well exactly,
and one one in one in particular,
which I must have seen about 10 times a
forgetting.
Sarah Marshall.
Great movie.
Uh,
and so I've sat there and laughed and
thought it was a very funny guy.
And then I came across his political
rants and I no longer thought he was
such a cool guy.
Well,
as I've said on twitter,
I believe that he is neck deep in hippie
pussy right now and really has no idea
what's going on.
I think they cut off the circulation
when there's that much hippie pussy
coming at Ya.
I think the circulation to your brain,
it's very hard for the heart to pump it
through all the kisses that he received
on his neck.
It right.
That's the going theory.
Okay.
That's a pretty good one.
Oh,
do they throw themselves at that poor
guy?
Really?
Oh yeah.
I'm sure.
Looking at this beautiful.
Okay.
Used to date Katy Perry who was married
to her son.
So what,
what happened to that list?
Full Union had to save the world,
Bro.
Popstars.
That's true.
That's all that frivolous shit.
Yeah.
She was religious.
She was,
yeah.
I mean,
I don't know her exact story,
but apparently she was very,
very religious and her original sort of
foray into the music industry all about,
you know,
sort of Christian religious music.
Yeah.
And then when that sort of didn't stick
then she became,
you know,
kind of deviated from that and became a
pop star.
But her roots are very much a Christian
based.
Well,
you know,
I think that a lot of these folks with
that,
they're trying to do good like a
russell.
Um,
I,
I probably,
I mean I probably get along with them.
Great if I sat down and talked to them
and I think he,
when I hear him talk and I hear the
things that he's saying,
I feel like he is doing a lot of good.
I think he is opening up a lot of
people's eyes because he is a very
public figure and he is saying a lot of
things that make a lot of sense about
the financial world,
about,
about war.
And about the nature of controlling
natural resources.
There's a lot of things that he says
that I agree with,
but I think that when you get caught up
in that world,
there are some very clear sort of
behavior patterns that you have to
subscribe to.
And this Islamophobia label is one.
You want to avoid all fucking
costs.
If you get hit with that one,
that's a heavy one today.
So heavy one and this politically
charged world,
you know,
I mean,
I made this point on a show recently
that,
you know,
in the West,
uh,
the Islam narrative doesn't yet have the
power to literally be had people.
I mean,
if,
if you say some really nasty stuff
against Islam and the Middle East,
what we can solve that problem easily,
we get rid of you.
But in the west,
what you could do is you could be head
somebody's reputation,
right?
I mean them and metaphorical beheading.
And that's what happens to guys like Sam
Harris and Ayaan Hirsi Ali.
Uh,
unfortunately,
uh,
you know,
this,
I've never really faced this kind of
blowback.
Uh,
maybe because I'm somewhat more measured
in how I speak,
I'm not exactly sure why you're also
talking about your personal income,
uh,
which gives you more authenticity
whereas Sam is viewed as some white guy
who's speaking from a fucking cracker.
Exactly.
Uh,
but I mean,
that's really what you see there are all
these guys.
I don't know if you know about them,
I won't even mention them.
So I don't give them any,
any airplay that go around pretty much
blaming everything on.
So called new atheists.
So.
Right.
Richard Dawkins and Sam Harris Are these
sort of evil patriarchs before he died
just before that.
And you and use the fourth horseman.
There's another Daniel Dennett dude.
Yeah.
He said,
are you joking?
Are you being serious?
I don't know.
Yeah,
he's a,
he's a philosopher at a school in Boston
actually,
but maybe brandeis,
I'm not exactly sure.
One of those schools.
Uh,
but anyways,
uh,
they go around just smearing these guys,
their hate mongers.
They're evil.
A lot of gravity attached to that.
Exactly.
And,
and now people who want to come into the
discussion have to really think hard
whether they want to be exposed to this
kind of blowback.
And so you get self censorship,
right?
Yes.
I mean I've had,
and I don't think I've shared this story
ever again,
so double happy birthday.
So I've had my wife,
so I opened up my laptop and I start
typing something and she'll come around
nervously looking at what I'm typing.
I say,
well,
what?
Why are you hovering over me?
And she said,
and I mean this,
this should give chills to anybody
listening to this.
Just like,
remember we have two children.
Oh God.
Right now I'm thinking in the 21st
century a professor in Canada now,
even if my wife,
my wife,
we're paranoid.
Even if she's overestimating the threat
of the risk,
the fact that she has the,
reflects the intuition to actually
engage in that behavior,
to have those thought patterns,
as you said,
is,
is really demonstrating that the
canaries singing in the proverbial coal
mine and it's not pretty right now.
I have two choices.
At that point.
I could either tweet whatever it is I
was tweeting,
right,
or I could say,
yeah,
you know,
she might be right,
let me engage in self censorship and
every time that someone who otherwise
would be weighing in on the conversation
engage in self censorship,
the other side winds,
and that's where we're at now.
So to answer your question,
how do we resolve this issue?
Hopefully people grow a pair a and start
weighing in on the matter.
Well,
it wasn't that one of the arguments
about publishing the images from Charlie
Hebdo that no one wanted to do exactly
that.
Astonishing these people lost their
lives and the fight of a fundamental
right,
the foundational bedrock of all our
freedoms is freedom of speech.
They lost their lives defending that and
every single western media coward and
decided not to show it in every single
one.
I mean pretty much every single one.
Yeah.
Every single magazines.
I mean New York Times didn't last treats
titled in the time did it.
I mean,
nobody did.
Right?
As a matter of fact,
there's one guy as relevant and Canada
who,
who published the original in 2006 and
he was taken to a hate speech tribunal
in Canada.
Right.
I mean,
think about it.
How or William is that a guy could be
taken to a hate speech tribunal for
publishing these cartoons.
It's astonishing is supposedly the
cartoons are offensive.
I've seen some of the cartoons and I
just thought they were kind of stupid,
you know,
they seem a little on the racist side,
some of them,
but the idea that these kids get you
fucking killed.
Do you want me to show you the cartoons
that are published every day in the
Middle East media about Jews couldn't
have managed care,
so you know what I mean?
Now the reality is we should all try to
get along.
We should all be respectful of one
another.
You shouldn't go out of your way to harm
other people's feelings,
but when it comes to testing the
boundaries of freedom of speech,
there should be no boundaries that can't
be crossed.
Yeah,
there should be.
There should be.
There should be no boundaries.
It should be okay,
I mean,
I agree with you,
but when the,
when these things come up where your
life is at stake,
like your wife hanging over your
shoulder saying,
remember we have children and these
people that have no time magazine,
that Own New York Times,
Los Angeles Times,
they think about publishing these things
and they just back off.
They back off.
They have families,
they have lives.
They don't want to be the sacrificial
lamb.
They have to put a name to those
articles and they publish them and they
know that the editor knows,
the publisher knows.
They all know that someone's going to
find out who they are.
And that's crazy,
right?
Look,
I understand that pragmatism,
but,
but we all have to weigh in,
in some form or another.
And they failed.
They failed,
they failed.
They failed.
Free speech.
Took a big blow to the Charlie Hebdo.
I don't know if you know this.
Now here's the kicker.
You want to talk about Chutzpah,
right?
Sure.
So,
uh,
one of,
I can't remember the organization,
one of the sort of Islamic organizations
in the US gave an Islamophobia award to
the slain Charlie Hebdo folks.
So not only the dose people die for
drawing cartoons,
they were,
they were smeared post mortem.
I mean it's,
it's,
it's a level of diabolical grotesqueness
that's unimaginable,
right?
I mean let,
let them,
at least in piece,
right?
So this is a real big battle of ideas
and we all have to weigh in on it
and I think that there's a lot of folks
that do not want to die like that and
they also don't want to be confused with
those folks that were drawing these
cartoons.
They don't want to be lumped in in any
way,
shape or form.
So they will come out against it.
Allah,
Ben Affleck in very strong fashion.
They will let everyone know that they
are not on that team.
Yes,
they do think it's racist without any
consideration whatsoever for the,
the,
the overall effect of those words of,
of calling something like that.
Islamophobic or what is Islamophobic?
What you're talking about,
a fear of an ideology that is so rigid,
they'll kill you for a cartoon that
doesn't scare you.
You're not phobic of that.
It seems to me,
and I'm not saying you shouldn't be
Muslim,
it should be whatever the fuck you want,
but as soon as it comes down to killing
people over cartoons,
we have a very weird problem on our
hands.
Right?
And when we're dealing with an entire
chunk of the western world that thinks
that that's okay,
that,
that should be overlooked,
but you can shit all over.
Christians are shit all over.
Mormons are shit all over anybody else.
It's safe and it's okay.
Well,
book of Mormons,
right?
Think about the play.
I mean,
people pay money to go and watch actors
making fun openly about her religion.
Try to do that with one particular
religions.
Try to do the book of Koran,
right?
Try that out.
Right?
So I mean,
I don't know if you've heard the term
bigotry of lowered expectations.
Are there are different versions of
bigotry,
of softened expectations?
The idea is that somehow Islam should
not be held to the same standard as
every other ideology because you know,
they'll go crazy what?
That that itself is racist,
right?
I mean,
right.
So when I gave you earlier the example
of the Iraqi scientists who said that
the earth is flat,
right?
And the,
and the lady writes to me,
well,
why are you criticizing this guy?
She's actually racist,
right?
Because she's saying that somehow this
guy doesn't have the capacity to be
criticized.
Whereas when I criticize the rabbi that
I went to visit,
this is a true story.
I was invited to a rabbi's House for
Shabbat Dinner,
Sabbath dinner,
and as I entered the house,
he introduces me to everybody and says,
well,
this a,
this is a professor,
blah,
blah.
He studies evolution,
but everybody knows that evolution has
been falsified.
So I'm not sure what he studies.
Right?
Well,
that,
that guy was being an idiot right now,
how come when I criticize this rabbi,
it's perfectly fair game.
How come when I criticize the Republican
senator who denies evolution because
of his Christian faith?
Because he's a young earth creationist,
that's perfectly fair,
but if I criticize the Iraquis
astronomer because he believes that the
earth is flat,
that's racist.
Well,
it's human folly.
You know exactly what it is.
I mean,
we.
We're in a very weird predicament with
this one very large segment of our
population on this planet.
I mean,
we're talking about a billion people.
One point six,
one point six point six.
That's a large chunk.
God Damn.
That's a lot of fucking people.
Now Do,
do,
do you see,
how do you see the trajectories of Alpha
brand?
Do you see this ever the pendulum
swinging the other way?
What would you,
what do you think would be the catalyst
to redress some of this ground folly at
go ahead.
Psychedelic drugs for real thing that's
going to work.
They need to talk to the real God.
Have a real conversation with homeboy,
right?
And the.
And the only way to get to him is
through psychedelic drugs.
I think that's the best way.
Okay.
It gets your rice,
almond atheist,
because I've never taken a psychiatric
drugs.
Psychedelics.
That was the kind of thing you never.
Here's,
here's something.
I've never taken any drugs.
I've never smoked a single cigarette in
my life.
Wow.
Mike,
what about you get drunk?
Very,
very rarely.
As a matter of fact,
the first time I ever drank,
I used to be a very competitive soccer
player.
I was maybe 22.
I had very long hair.
Very proud of my son Sonia and hair.
A bunch of soccer players on my team
held me down,
brought scissors,
put out your hair and they said you
either drink today or the hairs off.
That was the first time I ever drank.
I must've been 21,
22.
So.
So my only vice has been maybe my a
dietary choices,
but you still drink occasionally.
Occasionally we'll.
That's a drug,
right?
So how can you say you don't do drugs?
You know what I mean,
but I don't come on.
That's just as as much of a blinder is
religion is the idea that you don't
perturb your consciousness through a
very distinct method.
Right.
I have a glass of wine and get fucked
up.
You throw them back,
you get crazy smashed glasses inside the
chimney.
If my wife is watching right now,
she does have a photo of me drunk on a
absence.
No,
no.
We were at Club Med and I had drank too
much and I'm totally sloshed.
So that photo exists somewhere,
so maybe she'll just club med.
So maybe this bastard,
right?
Right.
To her.
Maybe she'll release it on twitter.
Um,
there's,
I think there's certain psychedelic
drugs that could help people,
uh,
alter their perceptions of this world
and give you a reset.
And that's what they do.
I mean,
I think is a very long conversation that
I've had many,
many times on this podcast and we could
have it some other time maybe if you
would like to off air or whatever,
but there are,
there are psychedelic drugs that are
most likely the of all religious
experiences.
In fact,
there's a scholar out of Jerusalem.
I'm pretty famous guy.
I forget the argument,
but what he's essentially saying is that
the burning Bush that Moses described
was most likely the acacia tree or the
Acacia Bush,
which is very rich dimethyltryptamine,
which is the most potent psychedelic
drug known to man.
And I've experienced this particular
drug and this particular drug gives you
a very intense feeling of joining with
the mother,
with communicating with God,
with,
with getting in contact with some
intelligent power,
some intelligent mind,
something that is above and beyond what
exists in our normal dimension that we
exist in and it's filled with complex
geometric patterns and communicate with
you telepathically.
It is a very,
very crazy experience.
And one of the things that happens in
these dmt trips is that they give you
like lessons of how to live life.
And the lessons all seem to row there.
You never have like these psychedelic
dmt trip.
So they tell you what you need to do is
rape more and beat the fuck out of
people and steal as much shit as you
can.
It's more like love,
like love people.
Love you,
love the love yourself,
love everyone around you because don't
worry about all the bullshit,
just being nice to each other.
Just have fun.
Just enjoy it.
Spread it and don't lie.
Don't lie,
don't deceive,
don't deceive yourself,
don't deceive anyone else and don't,
don't lose perspective.
You're going to be here and then you're
going to be there and you're going to be
here and you're going to be there and
it's going to go on and on and on.
It's this perpetual cycle that continues
from birth to death through infinity
infant testimony.
Part of an endless cycle,
and this is the experience in a
nutshell.
This is what you get out of it and very
similar to the idea that you would come
out of this experience with a set of
tenants,
set of rules like most this commandment.
Sure.
It totally makes sense that Moses could
be this guy who was into smoking dmt and
telling people,
look,
we're fucking up.
We're having all these sword fights and
shooting arrows at each other and
poisoning our neighbors threats from a
Jewish extremists though I doubt it
because this guy in Israel,
I know you are,
but this guy in Israel Sivia find a and
find that article,
but it was a pretty interesting paper
because this is a,
you know,
a real academic who is basing this on
years of research.
Well,
isn't it the case that many religious
rituals of various cultures engage in
these types of consumer authority
behaviors?
We absolutely,
as part of their religious rituals,
correct wasn't matter of fact,
John Marco Allegro,
who is one of the main,
um,
scholars that was assigned to decipher
the Dead Sea Scrolls,
which is the oldest version of the Bible
known right.
Um,
and also I the only version in Aramaic,
it was found in these clay pots and
Qumran in 1940 something.
It took forever for them to decipher
these things.
And this Guy John Marco Allegro,
worked on them for 14 plus years and he
was the only agnostic on the committee
that was assigned to decipher it.
He was originally an ordained minister.
And over time he became disenchanted
with the idea of religion when they
found all these contradictions and
religion and these comparisons to other
texts.
And he realized that a lot of it's
probably bullshit.
And so he wrote a book called the sacred
mushroom and the cross.
And after 14 years of deciphering the
Dead Sea Scrolls,
it was his interpretation that the
entire Christian religion was a massive
misunderstanding that what it was
originally about was the consumption of
psychedelic mushrooms and fertility
rituals.
Wow.
And that it was a fertility cult because
back then it was all about.
It wasn't about birth control,
it was about get pregnant because
there's not many of us.
We need more and the Romans might
becoming and in my fucking kill
everybody,
women need warriors.
We're going to need a large group of us
and we can't let them know about these
mushrooms.
And he even traced the Etymology of the
word Christ to an ancient Sumerian word
that meant a mushroom covered in God's
semen and what,
what they,
what they thought was,
according to John Marco Allegro,
what they thought was that when it
rained,
that was god coming on the world,
Kinda like a cosmic cosmic money shot.
And that these mushrooms would grow out
of the ground.
Like,
you know how it is when you have a rain
and then you go outside in the morning,
you see mushrooms that are already
grown,
like they weren't even there last night
and now they're there.
They grow so quickly and then you would
find these and they would eat these and
have these intense psychedelic
experiences of course.
And so if you.
Okay,
hold on,
sorry.
So we'll leave it up.
Leave it up so that these people that
would experience these would have these
intense transformative trips and without
any science,
without any knowledge of what the
components of these mushrooms are,
which is very similar by the way to
human neurochemistry.
DMT is nn dimethyltryptamine and that
exists in the human brain.
It's produced by the liver and the
lungs.
And they have now have proven due to
this guy,
Dr Rick strassman's work.
He wrote this great book called Dmt the
spirit molecule.
He's a professor at the University of
New Mexico and Got Dea approved clinical
track tests on subjects using dmt.
And,
uh,
this cottonwood research foundation that
he helped start,
has proven that it's produced in the
pineal gland of live rats and the,
what?
The pineal gland is the third eye.
It's in reptile that actually has let a
retina and the Lens,
I mean,
it literally is in the center of the
brain where the third eye is in eastern
mysticism.
It's producing this intense psychedelic
drug.
And that's what this Hebrew University
researcher Moses was tripping at Mount
Sinai is,
I mean,
is he high?
Obviously they'll know this literature
is he viewed it as a sort of outlier,
quack.
You would have to research it and find
out more about it because I did a
cursory examination because I'm so
familiar with the drug and it only makes
sense to me.
Um,
this is,
uh,
he visited the Amazon and drink Iowasca
and uh,
he has this idea of that,
that is what this was probably all about
because Iowasca has been,
they believe it's very difficult to find
out what,
when the,
uh,
the Amazonian indigenous people were
drinking this brew.
But IOWASCA is a form of DMT and much
like the acacia bushes,
very rich and dmt thousands of plants or
Richmond Dmt,
DMT,
existence.
Lance.
Sorry.
But what they're doing with this Iowasca
is an orally active version of dmt
because it has,
um,
it has one plant that has dmt in another
plant that has something called an Mao
inhibitor because dmt is broken down the
gut by something called Mano Amy,
not oxidase.
Cool.
A Gino.
This ritual,
one of the Amazonian tribes.
I discussed this,
one of my books with the bullet ants.
Are you familiar this?
Yeah.
Incredible.
I mean for mean just mentioned briefly
for your viewers who might not know it
because I think they drink some
psychotropic.
Yeah,
I think they do.
I think it might be a tumor or
something.
One of those.
There's a bunch of different crazy
psychedelic drugs that they take down
there.
But apparently.
So they,
they basically have to.
They,
they sedate these bullets pants.
And then they were these smoke,
right?
Which spoke.
And then they wear these gloves were
they then sort of weave the ants into
the glove as the ants come out of their
stupor,
they start biting the wearer.
Now,
one bite from that ad,
I mean it's called bullet pad because
the pain is greater than if you were hit
by a bullet.
Apparently it's the highest,
you know,
pain and do same thing in nature and
they have to do it 20 times on different
occasions before there's sort of
accepted into manhood or whatever,
the gds.
But,
but I mean,
the,
the point that,
the link to your story is that I think
they're under some psychotropics.
Uh,
yeah.
Here it is.
Those admits.
My friend Steve was bitten by a bullet
ant.
Really?
Bolivia.
Yeah.
He got bitten on his heel.
He said it was unbelievably painful.
They said it lasted for hours too,
he said,
but he said when it was over,
it was really weird.
It was so painful that he was delusional
and he couldn't even remember which
he'll got bit crafter.
It was over because once it subsided it
was like he like woke up from a transfer
credit and he said it was really,
really painful.
That's really difficult to concentrate
on anything.
This slightly less spiritual.
Can we segue from the money shots to an
actual study on money shots on sperm?
Yes.
Yes,
and I at the reason why I thought about
this,
because I know that in your own
Scada,
fucking one track mind because I know
that by the way,
thank you very much for inviting me to
your show in Montreal and to the the
UFC.
That was really fun.
I'm glad you had a good time.
And so when,
when I was at your show with my wife,
I think you had a little bit on sperm.
I can't remember what it was.
I'm sure I did.
Yeah.
Anyways,
I think I might've sent you a direct
message that kind of spoke to some of
the issues that you raised.
So here we go.
Let's talk about the science of sperm
and porn.
Get ready.
Yes.
So this was a study done a few years ago
by some colleagues of mine where they
wanted to look at the content of porno
movies.
So if you think of the typical male
fantasy at men who wants to have sex
with many women,
right?
So most societies are polygynous,
meaning one man with multiple women,
right?
That's how it should be.
God dammit to hell.
Most societies,
most societies,
85 percent of societies,
uh,
have historically condoned polygyny.
Oh,
what the fuck.
By the way,
people wrongly say polygamy.
Polygamy just means one with many.
But polygyny is one man with many women.
Polyandry is one woman with many men.
So,
so stay with.
That's horseshit.
They are very,
very.
There are very few societies that have
that.
I've been telling everybody that's Jamie
because of paternity uncertainty about,
oh,
of course.
Right?
So here it goes.
So,
so polygyny is what men want.
One,
basically,
heroin building,
one man with many women.
Yet,
if you do a content analysis of porn
movies,
what you find that that study has been
done by a guy by the name athlete,
Nicholas Pound,
uh,
that,
that's a shout out to this guy.
He owes me now.
So he did a content analysis where he
showed that polyandrous depictions are
much more common and porn movies,
meaning one woman with multiple men,
right?
Okay.
And so these.
And he argued basically that the reason
for that is because it's,
it's an excitatory q for sperm
competition.
Okay.
So watch this now.
Uh,
so then these other researchers came
along and said,
well,
how could we test this?
So what they did is basically they,
they asked men to take one of two images
home either with women having sex or one
woman with multiple guys,
polyandry,
and then masturbate to those images and
then bring back their sperm to the lab
to be evaluated,
or as I like to say,
the fruits of their manual labor and the
guests.
What they found that the sperm that
originated from the masturbations to
polyandrous images were much more,
had greater motility.
In other words,
they were more vigorous,
they moved a lot more which supported
the idea of sperm competition,
and this is exactly what you get an
animal husbandry right when you want
your stud to be riled up to have sex,
you often will show another male having
sex with a female and then this will get
a rise out of him.
So this explains the,
if you like,
the disconnect between how come men are
so desirous to have sex with many women
at once and yet you will,
and then that's what you would think
would be the picture.
That informal reason,
that's not what you get.
You get a lot more of two,
three guys on one woman,
so now I have elucidated the mysteries
of porn for you.
That makes sense on a biological level
because the more promiscuous the females
are around,
man,
the larger their testicles are testing
language,
right?
The testicles grow and they produce more
sperm because of the competition.
As a matter of fact.
So that.
Let me jump on that.
So if you look across primates at the
size of the testicle,
of the males of that species as a
function of female promiscuity and that
species,
you see a perfect correlation.
So mountain gorillas,
little tiny balls,
little tiny Dick.
Very good,
right?
They're usually impressive,
but they have a complete sexual
territoriality.
Yeah,
they fucked up.
They became too powerful.
Chimps on the other hand,
massive testicle.
They're walking testicles basically,
right?
Precisely because it's an adaptation to
female promiscuity.
Within that species.
Humans are closer to the chimp.
End of the scale for care.
We are now speaking about the thought
police,
right?
And all this bs stuff that you see on
campuses when I describe those
particular studies,
the feminists and the crowd will be
very,
very pleased because then I'm
demonstrating that women can be
promiscuous,
that fits the narrative of feminism.
If on the other hand,
uh,
I might five minutes later say,
yeah,
but when it comes to a,
uh,
sexual variety,
men have a slightly greater pension for
sexual variety than women,
then I suddenly become Dr Mengele,
the Nazi doctor.
So,
so basically the evolutionary finding
that I discuss is either liberating to
the feminist if it fits with the
narrative or it is a form of
patriarchal,
sexist,
bs if it doesn't fit bit,
and that again is the problem with what
you see on campuses,
right?
Rather than an open,
honest,
this course about the veracity of
scientific findings,
we judge these findings as a function of
our pet ideology,
the pet ideology when it comes to gender
identification and gender identities.
I think that that's.
There's a real interesting point to be
made with that when it comes to science
too,
because one of the things that's always
being touted about is diversity in
science and gender diversity in science.
But when it comes to what people
actually want to do,
there's been studies.
You give a boy a certain toy or girls
certain toy,
they're going to gravitate towards
things that are more in line with their
gender.
That's that fucks people up.
They don't want to hear that.
That some boys like trucks and some
girls like dolls.
But what it should be is what do they
like and guess what if the girl likes
trucks,
are the boys liked dolls?
Who a fuck,
but let's let the data speak for itself.
Let's try to understand.
I'm so happy you mentioned toy
preference because that's one of my
favorite examples to demonstrate the
lunacy of the whole social
constructivist stuff.
So here we go.
Okay.
So usually in the social sciences or
certainly social constructive as the
ones who argue that everything is due to
stress litigation will use toy
preferences as if you like the starting
point of how gender role socialization
happens,
right?
Johnny is taught to play rough with the
GI.
Joe then start to play nurturing with
the pink doll and that starts the
cascade of arbitrary sexist,
gender role socialization.
So I decided that I wanted to take that
premise on and I wanted to bring data
from a very,
very broad range of fields to completely
dismantled this bullshit.
Okay.
So here we go.
So if you take children who are in the
pre socialization stage of their
cognitive development,
meaning that they don't yet have the
capacity to be socialized and you give
them tests,
let's say,
of eye gazing,
they could either stare at adults or
trucks or play with dolls or trucks.
Then you already see the sex
specificity,
other toy preferences and the priests
socialization stage of their cognitive
development,
meaning they couldn't have been
socialized into those preferences.
Let's keep going.
If you take other species,
you take vervet monkeys and rhesus
monkeys and you take infants of those
species.
It replicates the sex specificity of toy
preferences of human infants.
Let's go on.
If you take,
if you take a little girls who suffer
from something called an
endocrinological disorder called
congenital adrenal hyperplasia.
This is a disorder that masculinize as
little girls and masculinize as their
morphology,
their,
their physical traits,
but it also masculinized as their
behaviors.
Guess what happens to their toy
preferences?
They become more like little boy if you
take.
If you go to Sweden,
which is the,
the,
the most gender neutral country in the
world.
Actually it's been studied as an iphone.
Yeah,
gender neutral household.
So in other words,
basically what happens in Sweden is that
the government has systematically tried
to completely eradicate as a big social
experiment.
Any gender markers,
you remove the gender pronouns,
gender Pronoun,
gender,
gendered pronouns.
That's right.
I mean,
I don't speak Swedish,
but that's what I hear and there's.
There's a scale that that's developed by
a gentleman called hoffstead where he,
where he ranks the countries from around
the world on this gender score and
Sweden is off the chart on it's
femininity.
Okay.
It's just outrageous.
And so if you now go to that country and
study,
it's a perfect field experiment,
right?
Because they've spent 40 years trying to
eradicate arbitrary sexist,
gender stereotypes and therefore you
should see that maybe the toy
preferences would now be no longer like
everywhere else.
Guess what you find in those countries,
it's exactly the same as anywhere else.
If you go to 3000 years ago to funerary
ice
icon,
fear near funerary monuments where
little children are depicted in ancient
Greece and you and you study how the
children are depicted,
the little boys are shown with wheels
and trucks and so on,
the little on our trucks,
but the wheelbarrow stuff and the girls
are shown with dolls.
You could study cultures in various
areas of Africa.
Indigenous cultures as has been done by
a French anthropologist and the exact
same behaviors manifest themselves so
and that just shows you how long we've
been under the oppressive thumb of the
historical.
Very good at it.
That's what it is.
She archi,
exact mass media has been around even
before then,
but how do we explain this written and
clay tablets?
They were bullshitting even back then.
Men are assholes.
Either way.
This this.
You know what the to the to the digit
ratio is.
Are you familiar with that?
Yes.
Please explain so that the two D,
four d is the is the length of the ratio
of your index finger to your ring finger
and at as a sexually dimorphic trait,
meaning that men have much longer ring
fingers than than index fingers.
Whereas women,
the two fingers are roughly the same
length.
Why is this important to this
discussion?
Because that morphological feature is
actually shaped in Utero as a function
of how much testosterone you've been
exposed to in utero.
Okay.
Therefore,
what some researchers have done is
they've looked at the digit ratio of
little boys and then link that to their
play pattern behaviors and again,
what do you find?
Little boys will have more masculinized.
The ratios have more masculinized toy
preferences.
Same thing has been done by the way with
actually circulating testosterone.
You take seven day old children and
until the six months old you measure
their testosterone and testosterone
level predicts toy preferences.
So look how many different disparate
lines of evidence I've just come up with
to demonstrate that it is not due to
arbitrary,
you know,
sexist socialization.
It's very uncomfortable for me that
people want to ignore that and put this
all on cultural ideas and stereotypes
that people subscribe to because they
don't want their child to be ostracized
by the community.
It's,
it's,
uh,
it was very uncomfortable for me.
It,
it drives me nuts because I think it
fucks people's heads up to us because
then they feel like there's something
wrong with them for liking masculine
things.
Right?
And being masculine or liking masculine
thing seems less and less of a favorable
pursuit in 2015 and it's kind of I've
ever been before.
It's like men get kind of shit on in
this society because we get blamed for a
lot of things.
And,
and um,
and I'm not saying poor men and women
because I think being a man is pretty
fucking bad ass.
I like it,
I enjoy it.
But I just also don't think that we're
necessarily evil either,
right?
I mean,
if some men do evil shit,
it doesn't mean that men are evil.
And if boys like trucks or girls like
dolls,
it doesn't mean anything wrong with
either one of them,
but it is wrong.
We try to ascribe
or prescribe it when we try to put that
into some sort of an ideological box.
Yes.
And we dismiss it or we categorize it as
being a part of the problem is with our
culture when it's so clearly a natural
thing.
Well,
I,
I think it stands this lunacy,
and I'm not sure if we discussed it last
time I was on the show,
but this lunacy I think comes from a
good place in a idiotic place.
But the place it comes from the idea
that if something is biological based,
it's immutable and,
and that's,
that's a scary thing,
right?
So people talk about biological
determinism,
which is complete nonsense.
And so the idea of an brain being empty.
Slate.
How,
how's the biological determinism
nonsense.
How so?
Because almost everything is a
inextricable mix of your biology and
environmental inputs.
Uh,
almost nothing that you could think of
doesn't incorporate some environmental
input into whoever you.
So the idea of it being completely
independent of any.
Exactly.
So the idea of nature versus nurture is
really a silly mood dichotomy because
it's a big broad spectrum of inputs.
Exactly.
And so the example that I left the gift
to drive that point home,
some of your viewers might have heard me
say before,
it's the cake metaphor.
So if you take a cake,
you take all the ingredients of the
cake.
Here's the,
here's the baking soda,
here's The flower,
here's the eggs here,
the sugar.
Once you Vegan cake,
once you put it all together,
right?
You're unable to then point,
once the cake is made,
you can't point,
show me where the eggs are showing,
right?
It's an x,
it's an extra fuel mix.
That's the idea of nature versus
nurture.
Makes no sense.
We're this big challenge with this cake.
Of course.
Yeah.
Uh,
so,
so I think it comes from the idea that
it's biology is scary because it's
somehow doesn't carry with a degrees of
freedom.
You know,
if boys are supposed to be this and
girls are supposed to be that,
then we're doomed to those biological
imperatives.
And again,
that's not true.
All of these phenomena fall on a bell
curve,
right?
I mean,
some people are more this way.
Some people are more that way,
so there's nothing really deterministic.
Also,
just another point,
for example,
men have a,
uh,
evolved desire to seek status.
That's the biological imperative because
women desire status and men,
but now the way Joe and Gad go about
instantiating that evolutionary
imperative,
it's completely different as a function
of their idiosyncratic talents that
shows you that it's not right.
It's not that we,
we both have to become comics and that's
the only way to gain status.
What is common to both of us is we both
aspire to ascend the social hierarchy.
That's the common biological imperative.
How we go about it is completely
determined based on your unique
personhood.
So again,
there's nothing deterministic about it.
What do you think it is about the
current climate where people want to
ignore all these biological markers like
you were talking about with children and
gravitating towards certain toys and
testosterone versus estrogen and babies.
What do you think it is about people
that want to avoid these things but
ignore this data?
Well,
it's exactly that.
It's the fact that it's very,
very hopeful.
Oh,
the narrative is very hopeful to assume
that we all start with equal
potentiality with APP that makes us
completely indistinguishable.
That's a very hopeful message because it
basically says that we are infinitely
malleable.
Right.
You know,
had joe had a different upbringing,
maybe he would have been Michael Jordan.
No,
you wouldn't have been.
Right.
They are enabling a black guy.
I was just saying about how good a
basketball thing could be right there.
They are unique,
unique realities about the random
combination of genes that made lionelle
messy that makes it such that not
withstanding the fact that he trains a
lot,
much harder than most other people.
He is endowed with unique talents that
not every other kid would have been
privy to those talents.
I always bring that point up when I talk
about Jon Jones hose that.
John,
how dare you.
Oh sorry.
Former UFC light heavyweight champion.
It was one of the most talented fighters
that's ever lived.
A really tall,
long reach,
spectacular athletic ability and one the
year he was the youngest ever UFC
champion.
Right.
And just dominate which era.
This era he beat Mauricio Shogun,
who,
uh,
for the title and just destroyed him in
his first title fight in the shoguns
like famous world class.
MMA fighters fought the best of the best
throughout history.
And what he,
I always say,
no matter how hard you train,
you could.
If you're just a regular dude,
you're never going to be that guy.
If he trains just as hard,
you're fucked.
Right.
He's just very talented.
Very physically talented.
Yeah.
There you go.
There's where not created equal.
We're just not just not.
I mean Einstein.
Ron,
Jeremy's Dick.
I haven't.
I have.
You have.
I have not,
not in person,
but I've seen it in.
There you go.
As a 13 or 14 year old trying to sneak
into good Lord.
That is impressive.
Yes.
Can I also mentioned that he's Jewish?
Just just to let you go look at that.
By the way,
that the Klan,
by the way,
if you look at,
there's this a world atlas of being
sizes that came out and I wish to engage
in modesty,
but you might want to check the scores
of the Lebanese men just for giant.
Just saying.
I'm just saying congratulations.
Congratulations on your people.
Second place to black folks though,
right there,
there were up there.
They were out there.
Know everyone starts out dates.
Just patriarchy that women have bigger
dicks than men.
Right?
Right.
It's the patriarchy that makes their
clitoris is smaller penises.
Do you find.
Do you think that there's going to
become a time in our lifetimes at all
ever wear this climate is going to
adjust back?
Is it going to take 100 years for just
back to some sort of.
I find that question so,
so fascinating because I.
it's hard for me to predict what the
trajectory would be on the one hand and
on my pessimistic day.
I think that,
you know,
all,
all great empires imploded from within.
You've heard that,
right?
It's not that there's sort of this
hordes of other folks that come in,
it's it's,
it's the empire that becomes cancerous
within itself and it implodes.
I think on my pessimistic days,
I say,
no,
we're screwed.
This is just going to go on further and
further until the whole west collapses
in this grand lunacy that we're engaged
in,
but it's not the whole west.
It's not everyone.
There's a lot of people out there that,
that aren't represented by this
ideology,
but not the intelligentsia who
controlled the information.
Right.
They don't really control information
anymore is my point.
The Internet Internet information.
That's true and it's not even the
intelligentsia that's doing this.
It's children.
It's students that are scaring the fuck
out of teacher.
Right?
I mean,
that's really what it is.
It's like Tumbler and facebook and these
people that formed these insulated
groups where there their echo chambers
and they,
you know,
they believe that this is reality and
they,
they want to yell at it.
Bernie Sanders,
black lives matter,
and then they get the fucking mic,
which is even crazier.
They let those kids who screamed and
yelled,
they let them talk and incredible.
Just like that's the worst fucking
message to send.
By the way.
We will let you have the mic.
We will let you have to stop screaming
at him.
So what's.
Why are you more optimistic?
Do you think that will be?
Yes,
yes.
I think that how would it work?
Because kids today are growing up,
listening to conversations like this and
realizing how retarded these 20 year
olds are and that they're going,
I want to be that when I get older I
want to look at things for what they
really are and I think that as they get
to that position,
this,
this new crop will have grown up and
come out of this dark hole that is the
clan that grew up with social media.
They grew up in these,
these groups with massive confirmation
bias.
Right?
And this confirmation bias I think is
kind of in these certain ways is kind of
dangerous.
You know,
I mean not to blow smoke up your
proverbial behind on your birthday,
but one of the wonderful things in the
last year has been to appear on your
show precisely because I've seen the
reach that you have just in terms of how
people have responded to my work.
Right.
I mean most scientists will toil in
their respective disciplines.
I mean hopefully they do good stuff,
but the number of people that they
ultimately are communicating with as if
it was a very restrained small number.
Right.
But by coming on these types of shows,
that's why I think we were talking
earlier about,
you know,
coming out of your shell,
engaging in the public discourse,
weighing in on these issues.
I always a debate some of my colleagues,
many of whom are very much in the ivory
tower,
right.
We only communicate with other members
of the clergy,
right.
With other members of our restricted the
class of high brow.
And I think that that's not really what
the job of a professor is.
I mean,
that's part of the job we have to create
knowledge and communicated to other
academics,
but if we're good academics,
if we're good men have ideas,
we also have to be engaging the public.
Right?
I mean ultimately the public also pays
for my salary through also.
That's how information really gets
spreaded.
It doesn't get spread by bouncing it
around amongst each other,
like a little beach ball at a concert.
Exactly.
Gets spread by getting it out there into
the great channel of the Internet.
Exactly,
so the number of people that have heard
of my evolutionary psychology work as
applied to consumer behavior and so on
through just having been on your show is
it will probably take me 10 careers
before I could reach as many people
through some other forum and so I agree
with you in that sense that these types
of forums are profoundly important.
I only wish that more academics would
actually have the courage to start
coming on these types as well.
It's very dangerous for them financially
independent and these and these
environments that we have today.
I mean,
you could cherry pick a million things
that are said in this show and take them
out of context and paint me out to be
some sort of a monster.
True.
That's just the nature of having a
conversation with someone where you
joking around.
Whereas if you take it and put it in
quotes in print and you take something
out of the context of the conversation
and put it in print and you could have.
You can infer all sorts of different
ways that this person is trying to
communicate.
That could be construed as being
offensive and then it gets.
It gets gross.
The difference between back then and now
is now you could always just go on a
podcast and talk about.
You could always write a facebook blog
and explain yourself in great detail
with no editorial input whatsoever.
No one can come along and take away from
it.
Or you know,
I've talked to many people that have
written things and then had those
things.
Even publishing online magazines has
those things heavily edited and chopped
up and even had words put in their
mouth.
I had a dispute with this journalist and
we were talking about something and,
well,
why did you save that?
And she goes,
I didn't say that.
Wow,
the editor put that in there.
I go,
you're kidding me.
They can do that.
And she goes,
yeah,
they add things to it.
I know that's fucking insane.
I've experienced something similar to
that on several occasions.
So one time a guy called me when my book
came out,
the book has pornography and it's titled
the consuming instinct and it's subtitle
and he really.
I mean,
the key point he wanted to get to was
that professor sad argues that there is
a gene for porn,
which of course I'm not at all arguing
that.
So I kept repeatedly explaining to him
that to explain the evolutionary basis
of why men might enjoy porn doesn't
suggest that there's a set of genes in
your genome that you know,
that cold for porn preferences.
I explained.
So please don't.
Next day you know exactly what he wanted
to course.
Uh,
but you just learn to.
That's part of the beast.
They don't care.
They're not trying to be honest.
Yeah.
It's not intellectual honesty.
What it is is they're trying to get
clicks to trying to get people to pay
attention to it and that's what they do
and they can do it for now,
but this is a transitionary time between
this time that we're at now where there
is still this a bit of cloudiness,
right?
There's a bit of fog in the air of
information,
you know,
it's just sometimes it's hard to find
out exactly what the fuck is going on,
but that fog is very,
very close to being lifted and sheer
intent I think will be displayed.
It will be a part of discourse in a way
that I don't think has existed before in
the near future.
Right.
I think you're going to be able to know
a lot more about what someone's trying
to portray just in the next decade or so
than we've ever known in the past.
And also the transparency like that you
have like the transparency that not just
in your words and how you,
uh,
you are able to communicate and describe
things,
but also in how you're able to defend
those things.
If something comes up that just didn't
exist before,
he had no recourse if somebody misquoted
you or an eye.
I've had that happen before a long time
ago and like 99,
this woman wrote an article about my
show or one of my cds.
She did a review of my cd and not just
took me out of context,
but completely misquoted me and changed
the words of my bits to make them
horrible and I had a conversation on the
phone with her,
with my publicist.
I'm like,
why didn't you do that?
And she's like,
well,
that's what I heard when I heard your
work.
I go,
that's what you heard.
That's what you heard.
I go,
well,
that's not what I wrote,
but that's not what I said.
It's not what I wrote.
And so you lied.
I go,
you're a fucking liar.
Like,
well,
you're not a journalist,
you're a liar.
And she thought I left the phone.
She started.
I left and hung up because I just,
I go,
well,
we're done talking then.
Great.
And so she goes,
she.
There was a pause and so she says,
the publishers,
your,
your client is losing it.
And I go,
I'm not losing it.
You're a fucking liar.
Do you not understand what happened
here?
So I wrote a story about her in my blog
about,
um,
just I called yellow journalism.
I think it was the title of it,
about how ridiculous she was.
And it was the first time that anybody
could ever do something like that.
Right?
In the old days you would have to get it
printed somewhere,
you know,
to get it printed in a magazine.
Good luck writing,
uh,
an article about how um,
you know,
you wanted to love someone because they
were so full of shit.
I forget what I said.
I was just trying to be ridiculous.
I was trying to upset her,
right.
You know,
but that used to be what they could do,
you know,
that some guy could listen to you talk
about genes and pornography and how men
could be more attracted to pornography
and go,
oh,
I know how to make this fucking
salacious.
I know how to make that guy look like an
asshole.
I'm just going to say,
this professor thinks there's a gene for
they're prints and done.
What can he do?
Well,
what can he do?
What's his name?
What's that guy's name?
Oh,
I don't remember.
And will fight for.
I could probably find that out.
We know what you did.
That's right.
You know,
you did too.
You can't,
you know.
But I mean you've had a platform because
of,
you know,
being an entertainment.
But I'm,
I'm amazed by guys who start youtube
channels.
I recently appeared on a,
on a youtube channel that Scott,
he calls himself Sargon of awkward.
He,
I mean he's,
he's a nobody in the sense of not having
come from,
you know,
an acting world or not being a public
figure,
but this guy is brilliant.
He now has over 150,000
youtube subscribers,
maybe 25,
$30 million viewers.
Beautiful.
Right?
And that's based on merit and start,
right?
This guy would never have had a voice.
What were it?
Not for the,
the,
the mediums that we are now afforded to
us.
And so that's why I just,
I feel like a kid in a candy store to
appear on all these shows because it
offers me a voice to spread means,
right.
I mean I consider my job as a meme
creator mean propagator.
And so any way that I can do that,
including coming on,
you know,
this brilliant podcast,
I consider myself unbelievably fortunate
and I don't see why other academics
don't see the value in death.
Well I think they will eventually in
some do.
I mean I have,
I've had quite a few on now,
but I think that what we're dealing with
is a new thing we're dealing with is
this completely new pathway to for
information to travel and it has to be
kind of recognized and accept and it's
slowly being done.
So like there's a sign in front of the
comedy store and one of the hotels,
like,
you know,
they paint the side,
like a billboard on the entire side of
the hotel and it's a youtube channel
that has millions of subscribers.
So this woman's Youtube Channel,
I've never heard of her before,
but she's got millions of subscribers
and there's a few of those that youtube
has put up all around the city and what
they're getting for each individual
video that they put out is very similar
to what a hit cable show gets.
And that's reality and you can't fuck
with that.
Those are real numbers and real people
that are the same kind of people that
watch television and it's just a new
pathway for information.
It just makes it harder for people to
lie and bullshit.
And like that guy who wrote that
article,
he's just lazy,
he's lazy and just work sucks and his
mind's week.
And so he wants to come up with some way
that he can turn something in,
some click baity bullshit article.
So that's what he does.
He distorts reality to fit his own
agenda and for his own game.
And uh,
and he does so in a way that he doesn't
care for damages you because he has
power over you.
Right?
He doesn't have any power over you
anymore.
No one does.
No one has any power of anyone and this
whatever of mart or wherever the fuck
the guy's name was.
I'm sorry I'm putting,
he's going to get millions of good
friends,
but this guy,
he got there based on merit,
you know,
and there's a lot of those guys out
there now and they cover a wide variety
of topics to whether it's sports,
there's martial arts commentators that
have done that.
There's,
there's people that do that about
technology.
It's just we live in a beautiful time to
174,000
followers.
I mean,
I know it's nothing but that's.
I mean that's what was on television
though.
He's on Fox all the time and he's a
legit journalist for May,
but yeah,
it's beautiful.
And.
But he started out on the Internet as
well.
We live in a beautiful time.
We do.
Speaking of time gotta wrap this bitch.
Oh Nice.
Do we do any promotional stuff?
Do you want to.
What do you want to do?
Just a could follow me on twitter at
God.
Sad,
she had a d,
they could go to my youtube channel
which has got side again,
and he had a great youtube channel.
By the way,
will you sit down,
you talk about a lot of things and you
do speak on,
edited in front of the camera and
express yourself.
It's a wonderful way that,
and you can follow me on my public page.
Glorious.
Let's do this again,
my friend anytime.
Thank you,
sir.
Thanks for being here my birthday.
All Right,
ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back tomorrow.
Until then,
enjoy your life.
Bye.