Do Do,
do four,
three,
two,
one,
and we're live.
Candice.
Hi Guys.
Hi.
Oh my God.
What do you.
What were you saying about hereditary?
That's supposed to be a terrifying
movie,
right?
That's what they said.
That's what they say.
Meaning the media and a like Huffington
Post.
I think so that's why I went because I.
I'm not scared by anything like in the
movies,
so I'm constantly in pursuit of a actual
scary movie.
So I went thinking,
oh,
this might be the one.
It was not.
Damn,
you're that hard.
That no movies get you.
I can't remember the last time I was
scared,
but I think poltergeist when I was a kid
and that's why I'm scared of clowns as
an adult though.
No,
I'm trying to think of the last time I
was really scared and well see?
Yeah,
see they don't make well they're fun.
I like them.
That's how I feel.
I like and I also like a thinking that
something might get me.
I like the suspense in that,
but it never does.
I always get.
It's very anticlimactic for me.
You like thinking that something might
get you scared and it doesn't.
It doesn't.
It does not.
Jamie,
when was the last time you were scared
and the movie said jump scares or that's
like cheap,
cheap scares.
That's not.
That doesn't count.
Just because to make it out loud,
it doesn't get that.
That doesn't count.
I don't go see scary movies at the
theater.
So.
So you're always at home,
so you know.
Yeah.
The strangers.
That one bothered me a little bit.
I was just in the weather.
No,
I was just holding on that list is
something to come in.
I was just sending out my instagram
stories,
instagram stories,
but yeah.
No the strangers.
Did you see that one?
No.
That one was with Liv.
Tyler Stevens tasks on there were
outside of the trying to kill people.
Yeah.
That one rocked me.
Uh,
a little.
A little.
Yeah.
Something about the dark.
Right.
You ever mind fuck yourself and you,
you think that there's like someone
outside,
like you think you hear something,
you open your door and you listen.
And that actually has happened to me.
I had a peeping Tom.
Ooh,
I had a real guy outside of my window,
so I didn't see him.
I only heard him,
oh,
my window was cracked and uh,
he started whispering to me through my
window.
I talk,
I have a joke about it now because it
was only way I could deal with it
without getting too paranoid about it.
So I wrote a joke about it,
but I did,
I did.
But every time I tell people they're
like,
that's terrifying.
And I'm like,
yeah,
that is terrifying.
But at the same time it's like,
was kind of flattering,
kind of flattering out of his way to
whisper all the windows he could gotten
to.
He came to mind,
you know,
so.
But yeah,
we'll see what the guy looked like.
I didn't but my neighbors.
So he came one night and I heard him,
he started whispering to me.
He was like,
can I,
I'll just tell you what he said.
It was terrifying.
I was watching also let me give the
setup.
I was watching Mulholland drive.
Have you seen,
are you a David Lynch Lynch?
That's what I had on,
um,
I'm a David Lynch fan and I had that.
I was probably like 3:00
in the morning and uh,
I sleep with my window open because my
place is not have ac,
but I know what,
what do you,
what?
Do you live in Montana?
Yes,
I had,
I just drove in for this today.
How can I live in la?
I lived at my place is old and I think
what happened was,
is that it was built before ace was even
invented so the windows are even old
school so I can't even put like a
portable fake crank open and the windows
crank open like that.
So you can't even,
I'd have to probably like get the
manager to replace the window
installments before I could even put an
air conditioning.
And so you survived this.
I don't know,
I just leave during the day and then at
night I have fans.
Would that just blow hot?
No,
I know it's awful.
Or I just spend the night at a friend's
place.
That's the move.
That is the move.
I'm like,
I'll be here now.
Now I know the address,
so Chile,
nice and perfect.
It's got its own thermostat.
This room does.
This is amazing.
I hate you.
So we're friends trying to make me feel
bad.
Don't feel bad for your accomplishments.
This is.
No,
that's just.
This is what I want.
I want that pink Himalayan salt light
right there.
That one.
I can take that.
Yeah,
you can take that.
Got.
We've got an extra one.
Random Pink Himalayan salt rocks.
Joe Rogan.
You have a stuff werewolf outside in a
float tank,
whatever.
I don't think it's stuffed.
It's not that.
It'd be like a real thing and then you
kill it.
That is what it is,
right?
That wasn't real.
No matter if it was just a polar bear.
Scary than that.
If anybody were to have a,
an actual werewolf,
it would be you.
Can I.
Can I explain it to my peeping toms
please?
Cute.
So I heard him outside.
It was the summertime.
I think it was probably like July of
this was I think like two years ago.
Yeah,
it wasn't.
It wasn't awful.
It wasn't like it is like now because
this is kind of new.
I don't think La has ever been this hot
in like the beginning of July,
so that's the end of days.
Um,
so anyway I was in my bed watching
mulholland drive and I had been like in
and out of like falling asleep and then
all of a sudden I heard like a outside
of my window.
But I thought at first I thought it was
this movie because I was like,
David Lynch is a weird dude.
Like this is like a director's choice,
like to creep people out to put like
murmuring in the background I did.
I thought that at first.
So I ignored it.
And then like probably 20 minutes later
I was like,
something's telling.
My Gut was like,
that's not the movie.
So I hit mute and all of a sudden I
heard,
come on baby from that sweet pussy.
So you're on the first floor.
I'm on the first floor.
My duplex.
It is.
Well,
you know,
anyone that's on the first floor,
your upstairs neighbors are problematic
because it sounds like they were a horse
shoes and they're bowling all the time.
So yeah,
the whole.
Yeah,
no the whole thing,
living on the first floor is not a good
idea,
but we have bars unlike most of the
windows,
so that's not an issue.
Like I wasn't scared he was going to
come in because the windows open,
but then there's bars in front of it so
I wasn't terrified that.
Um,
but as soon as that happened,
what was funny was that uh,
Ian Edwards,
you know,
very funny comic working with them
tonight.
Do I have at the store?
No Ice House.
The Ice House.
Okay.
Yeah.
No,
um,
he was staying with me at the time
because he had just sold his place and
receding,
which isn't far from here.
And then he was in our extra room at the
apartment.
So I was like,
Ian,
I think there's somebody outside.
Can you like,
do you want to get indigo?
Who that was all I had.
What do you say it about Ian?
You don't think he can protect me?
He's Jamaican.
He's crazy.
I love Ian Hart.
He's not the one that called.
Weighs 18 pounds.
Weighs less than me.
Yeah.
I'm careful when I hug him a hug.
I hug you more firmly than I hug you.
I'm trying to get him to eat meat.
He told me he'll eat all my elk meat.
No,
he said he will.
Yeah,
he just won't.
He said he will.
You don't believe him?
No.
He's lying.
Yeah,
I think he's just doing that to a.
Oh no,
he's asked me several times to try.
Yeah.
He wants me to cook elk forum and he'll
eat it because he'll know it's a hunted
animal because he's a Vegan.
He doesn't want to eat anything that was
killed like from a factory farm or along
those lines.
I don't eat meat either.
Like I do.
Occasionally I'll have fish.
When Ian and I fly,
every time we fly together,
I take a picture of him five minutes
into the flight because he's always like
out cold five minutes and I'm like,
dude,
what the fuck?
It's first thing in the morning.
We're supposed to be like,
you just woke up.
How are you going back to sleep?
He's always so tired and I do.
I go,
dude,
you got to get blood work done.
It's your fucking diet.
I know it is.
You can do that Vegan Diet.
Right,
but you got to be very disciplined.
You have to.
Yeah.
You have to take all sorts of different
moments and you have to use algae if
algae,
and that's the best source of b12.
It's not as bioavailable as animal
sources.
You know all,
all the fat soluble vitamins.
This is just a.
it's a nightmare.
You've got to really be on the ball.
Yeah.
He's not know Ian.
I don't know if he is on the ball very
well.
He was just on my podcast the other day
and he taught it.
It's called the struggle and the
struggle,
so I had about life in Atlanta.
Just yes,
that's an ongoing that in my dating
struggle or the ongoing dating
struggling and not having air
conditioning in.
You had a nice fellow with you at the
comedy store the other night.
He seemed like a good guy.
He has since been recorded.
Yes.
It was very brief.
Well,
you seem like a nice fellow.
I thought so too.
It's not that he's not nice.
He just had lived a lifestyle that I
just can't.
That we're not.
We're not compatible.
We'll still be friends.
I think.
I think we can get to the point,
won't be friends because we were friends
first.
So I think we can maintain that if I
can't,
you know,
the struggle.
Everything is a struggle.
The struggle is real evidence.
That's why I have people on it and we
just talk about stuff that everyone's.
Everyone's struggling with something and
multiple things usually.
Well
I find this is just a rash
generalization,
but I'm good at those.
I find that women when they're in the
prime of their life as a like not,
not like 20,
but like as an actual grown woman with a
career and if they're smart and
independent,
they have a really hard time finding the
right man.
Absolutely.
It's like if you're a that if you're a
Dingbat and you'll,
you know,
you'll morph into whatever lifestyle
your new boyfriend chooses,
then you can be okay because you don't
know who you are,
but it's hard for a girl to find.
First of all,
it's hard for a girl who's strong and
smart,
defined a guy who's not intimidated by
that.
It is you.
This is my life.
I know.
I know so many women who were in my
situation because women in their
thirties independent have money and just
like,
don't need a man,
but just want one.
Right?
But the dudes can't handle it well.
Well,
it's hard.
It's hard both ways.
It's hard finding quality human beings
to spend time with friends,
girlfriends,
boyfriends,
whoever it is.
It's,
it's hard.
It's hard finding the right.
I mean,
yeah,
especially in La,
especially in our line of work,
you know,
we're in the attention business,
and we get attention to professionally,
right?
And make people laugh.
That's the business.
A fucking tricky business.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Well listen,
you have you,
you have one of the healthiest
attitudes,
like you really do.
I always say this about you when
whenever we're at the store,
like you always have these,
you have the grind spots,
you get those grind spots in the store,
you get those 12:00
spots,
1130.
So those are the grind spots that show's
been on for three and a half hours.
By the time you get on,
you know that's rough,
but you're always,
you always have a positive attitude.
Always happy,
always smiling.
Everybody's always happy to see you.
People never like,
oh,
just say like some people do,
but those are the hater.
I don't know who they are.
I don't know.
I don't associate with those people,
but all my friends are always happy to
see you.
You're,
you're very happy,
very happy.
It's my parents love me the Ah,
there it is.
Well that's your fuck.
Then you're never gonna make it in this
town that all the time.
I say if my parents had been just a
little bit more abusive,
pulled the Joe Jackson at least just
wants it twice.
Yeah.
Joe Jackson.
He just passed away,
rip Joe Jackson.
We were just reading about him.
People have been sending me these things
that Dr Conrad Murray says that Michael
Jackson was chemically castrated.
Oh yeah,
I heard about that.
Yeah,
I had.
I said that a long time ago that I
thought he was [inaudible].
Do you know that the word for Toronto is
something that they use to do two young
boys to get them to sing opera better?
You ever heard this before?
I wonder if Aaron Neville has.
I don't think so.
I think he's just doing a falsetto
because when you hear him he talks
like this man,
Michael Jackson also talk like this too.
By the way,
was faint.
Bell is fake.
Did you hear?
I speak it all.
This Conrad Murray,
he taught his voice was like this.
Conrad Murray has a recording on his
phone that he just played.
I just.
There was some documentary I just
watched and it was Michael Jackson's
like last words,
like on his deathbed,
his,
his deep voice
woman to see the door
fuck out of here.
That sounds like your girl does.
It does.
It does like a girl want some Dick.
See that was his real voice to that is
not deep,
but it's not.
Not this joined in a common purpose.
Listen,
when that is his deep voice.
Sounds like he's got a cold.
That's like my eight year old.
Would she has a cold?
No one said it was deep,
but it's not that this is what this is.
And why do all of them.
Why does Janet talk like this?
And the toy.
They all got beaten by their dad.
But what does that mean?
So that now they all have this stay low
key they have to talk to.
If you,
um,
do you read the stories,
the chemical,
castor oil.
This play her a sound of a real cast
Toronto because there's only one
recording from the early 19 hundreds.
It was like some of the last of the
[inaudible] because they don't do that
anymore,
but they used to do it.
It was very common.
People would give their children to the
opera.
Awful.
Will they get us kicked off youtube.
James,
get up,
do some finagling.
We get kicked off youtube all the time.
Shit.
Things that are other people's
copyrights here.
This is a boy is a boy.
Yeah,
this is what.
That's what he needs to look like.
I mean,
you know,
he was castrated,
so he had no hormones.
His body did not produce testosterone
and so this is a grown adult male,
but like saying like this,
why wouldn't they just let the women
saying it?
No,
because it's a different thing to
different sound.
Like the women sound beautiful and they
sound like women,
but there's a sound that [inaudible] has
and that's a Michael Jackson sound.
The sound is a extremely feminine,
not look,
look,
it's real.
Like if you think you see tito and all
the other Jackson's,
they don't sound nothing with Jermaine.
Not No one looks or sounds
anything.
No.
He was definitely the standout.
But.
So you think they did this to him when
he was a kid.
This is where Conrad Murray says,
and he looked.
It makes sense if you look at his body,
if you look at like he didn't have any
muscle tone.
He was very slender.
He looked like he had no testosterone.
You sound like a girl.
He sang like a girl.
Tell him that it's human nature that
actually it's not bad to think about
that.
Think about that voice.
Who the fuck's things like,
that's a man.
No,
you're right.
And I always thought he,
I,
I never pictured him like four.
Took him for a sexual person at all.
Like when people were like they said he
was touching little boys.
I never believed that.
I always felt he was asexual.
I didn't get any type of sexual,
any chemistry or any type of tension at
all from him.
Did you check them out with the Ligo
detector?
I have a gate the gate and I have the
actual.
I bought mine on Amazon.
Yeah,
I think it's entirely possible that
that's true because I've thought about
that.
We,
we talked about that for years.
I was like,
dude,
I'm telling you.
I heard those kiss Kratos I know about
that.
I guarantee you Joe Jackson knew about
that too.
I bet they did that to that kid.
That's awful.
So they did.
They use chemical castration.
I heard that that had happened,
but I always thought it was like for
some reason I thought it was when he was
an adult.
I thought it was like a personal choice
that he made.
Ooh,
whoa.
No.
I think the idea was his dad was trying
to preserve his voice.
I didn't.
I didn't know that.
So wait a chemical castration.
Is that what that means?
But with what,
like,
good question.
Is it something that you take that lid
doesn't like shrivel up your balls,
but like something that just makes you
in like in like you don't have the
ability to produce test
anymore?
Well,
let's find out here it says allegations
are Joe had Michael received Hormone
Jackson when he was 12 years old in an
effort to cure his acting and prevent
his voice from deepening an allegation
Mervis Marie previously made and it's
2016 self published book.
This is the secret life of Dr Conrad
Murray and Michael Jackson.
Hmm.
Yeah.
He said Joe was physically abusive to
him and his siblings were growing up but
never mentioned undergoing any sort of
hormonal treatments.
But this is what Conrad Murray says,
I just don't.
I don't know.
I mean,
who you sound like crazy.
The reason why I believe it is because
of the way sounded just make sense.
And His dad was just a ruthless prick.
He was known as being a horrible person.
Yeah.
But why?
Why would,
why would he only do that to one of his
sons?
Because he was the only one that was
young enough to do it too.
If you look at the Jackson five when
they were taken off like,
oh baby gave me one moment.
He was five,
six years old.
Everybody else was grown.
There was too late.
Yeah.
They were all deep in.
Were already there were already grown
men.
And this was,
this was the voice.
I mean he was the voice ABC.
I mean,
he was so fucking cute too.
They try to keep that going forever.
That's why I think that's unfortunate.
It's scary.
Well he's,
he's a cautionary tale,
you know,
and I think there's a level of fame that
you get to where you just fucked up.
You got to fucking famous.
Yeah.
But isn't it?
Isn't it also like the,
a certain type of person only wants that
level of fame,
right?
Like have you ever thought about like
people who get to like,
for example,
like Donald trump level because it
doesn't just apply to like,
uh,
the entertainment industry,
but like CEOS who these multibillion
dollar own these multibillion dollar
corporations,
like it takes a certain type of person
to even want that type of clout,
you know?
And uh,
I don't know.
I think that there's something in that
as well.
I don't know.
I think there's a pursuit involved in
all of these things where you start off
just chasing money and you start off and
then you get involved in a game and it's
all about numbers.
It's all about putting scores up,
you know?
And I think as those scores continue to
pile on,
you continue to get more excited about
your progress and you want to keep going
further.
If someone makes a million dollars a
year,
they don't go,
that's good.
That's good enough.
No,
they go,
I want 2 million.
They make 2 million.
I want a marriage and they get a
mansion.
I want a jet,
they get a jet,
I want to fucking island.
I have always wondered like when is it
enough for people?
Because like I,
I,
I'm the type of person I don't think I
would be like that.
Like if I had $25,
million dollars and somebody was like,
you have to do this to get another $25
million depending upon what it is.
If it was something that I didn't
believe in or something that wasn't
aligned with my morals,
I wouldn't.
I'd be like,
I already have $25,000,000.
Yeah,
I don't need it that bad.
Well yeah.
I mean that's different though.
You're saying like if something was not
aligned with your morals,
but if you had $25,000,000
and you had an opportunity to make 30.
If it was yes,
but there are a couple extra hours a
weekend.
Is that all it takes?
Yeah.
Maybe just a few.
Five extra hours a week,
an extra hour a day.
And we could ramp you up to $30,000,000
a year.
Well,
I would do that and then we go,
listen,
candice,
we can get you really close to
$75,000,000
a year,
but you're going to have to work 12
hours a day.
Sorry,
I can't come up to you to go kill the
hours.
I can just.
I know what you're saying.
I know you think it's hard,
but listen,
we get some adderall and we've got some
massage therapists that will be on staff
and if we do this for a few years,
you retire comfortably for the rest of
your life.
You live in a Baeza.
You fucking chill out in the hammock.
Oh No,
never happens.
That's the thing that a bs of thing
The hammock never,
never written on the hammock.
You just keep making them.
For me,
it would come.
The only reason I'm working is so I can
stop working.
Oh really?
Yes.
What's going to hit?
What number?
I would be fine with.
I'm gonna.
I'm going to go with a $200.
That's all you need.
Low maintenance.
Jesus Christ.
How much is it to buy an island?
Uh,
depends on where it is.
If it's where hurricanes hit all the
time,
but you get to cheat and get it for 75.
Somebody Richard Branson bought one last
year and right after he bought it,
it got destroyed literally to the point
where there are no living humans for the
first time in 300 years on this island.
Oh No.
He didn't do research.
Well,
it just got unlucky.
He just bought it and right after he
bought it,
it literally the epicenter of the
hurricane washed over it and just the
entire island.
If you're listening to this Richard
Branson,
I'm not.
I don't mean to laugh at you.
Pull up the story.
Branson's island last time you've talked
about it,
a necker
island,
the one that he's owned for awhile,
it was going to be reopened and a couple
months,
so they redid it.
Yeah.
It's like back back those necker.
I don't like the way that like niggardly
that word.
That's a dangerous word.
Like selfish and stingy people.
People are saying don't use that word
anymore because it sounds too much like
that other one does,
but it's not the same.
I know it's not,
but it's tricky.
It is tricky.
You have to pronounce every letter or
delete.
Delete.
Yeah,
that's a problem.
You know what's weird when words are
okay sometimes like pussy cat.
Yeah.
How do you have to have another.
But right now the game,
it's not the same year.
You can't say that on daytime top.
That is weird though,
right?
That you could say pussy cat.
Yeah.
But if you say pussy one,
two,
three cat.
Yeah.
That's like,
Hey,
I don't like what you did there unless
you named your cat pussy.
Oh yeah.
I guess octopussy remember that?
That was a big deal.
Everyone's okay.
Yeah.
No,
I remember seeing that.
Uh,
this is what I think with when we lived
in New York,
it was a movie,
right?
Yes.
Yeah.
I remember seeing it like I was a kid
and I remember seeing it like.
And I was like,
what is a bad word to say it?
That was like a loophole in there.
Yeah.
There's some words that are like that.
Well,
how about a dude named Dick Cheney?
Everyone deserves that name.
Like I don't,
I don't know anyone.
I don't think,
I think that's like one of those older
school ones.
I feel like no one goes by.
If your name is Richard,
you go by Richard or rich.
Now I don't think anybody's like,
call me Dick.
Who?
The weirdest one is Jack.
Like if you're John Your nicknames Jack.
Wait,
no one's name is just Jack.
Yeah,
my nephew's named Jack will.
Who?
But John,
if you use just call me Jack.
The nickname is jack.
I never knew that.
John Kennedy.
These calm Jack Kennedy.
I didn't know that.
Then this name was John.
That's so weird.
It's the same amount of letters.
It isn't it so stupid.
It doesn't make any sense.
Are there any ones like that for girls?
Will there's a.
no,
not that I can think of.
I can't think of one.
Right.
There's no just named him Jack.
It's a completely different name.
It's a totally different name.
Sounds different.
Yeah.
Can we talk about,
since we're on the,
on the nickname thing,
so you know,
we're not allowed to say tranny anymore.
Right?
You just said it.
I know because I don't.
I personally don't find anything wrong
with the word and now someone could very
well say,
well,
you're not transgender candace,
you're not bothered by it.
You know,
it doesn't affect you,
but I don't know anyone that really used
it in a derogatory way.
You know,
I,
you know,
it was just a word that we said to refer
to this type of person,
but to me it sounds adorable.
Like me,
it's just the nickname
for transgender to say tranny.
So like Jennifer,
you call somebody Jenny.
Well there's a lot of policing of
language as of late.
It's ramped up because the Internet
people can complain more,
but I think the problem is that it's
not.
You're not putting any respect on that
name.
Is that what it is?
It's a respect.
It sounds like it's a birdman.
Went to visit Charlotte may put some
respect on my name,
respect of Spec,
put some respect on my name.
Did you see that?
I didn't see the claimant.
Apparently Charlemagne had been talking
some shit about Birdman.
Birdman came in with a giant crew and
put some respect on my name and then he
got up and left.
That was it.
It was the whole conversation.
And Charlotte.
Woody's going.
Okay.
All right.
I love beef.
I love is.
You want to watch short good stars over
his head,
but crazy.
Looked at guys got come up.
Respect ms dot banks.
I'm playing with my fucking name.
All drill.
Y'All stop playing with my name.
Ain't gonna say no.
Most hilarious and put some respect on
my name.
Yeah,
man,
I was.
Were you following the drake and Pusha t
a?
I tried to not try to avoid it because
Jamie brings these up.
He comes in.
Did you,
did you hear about chopping with drake?
Drake has a kid with a porn star.
Yeah,
I get it all from Jamie.
Jamie,
the gossip news.
TMZ of this,
uh,
this studio,
it gives me so much life.
Why do you love that?
I love.
I love hurt feelings,
man.
I love.
I do.
When it's like celebrities.
Oh,
like they can get their feelings hurt up
because all they're doing is bragging
and talking to all the money they have.
They,
if not braggy wrapper is not braggy
rapper.
Yeah,
that's.
that's what I'm talking about.
Like rap beefs.
Yeah.
So if there was a beep between like
Jennifer Lawrence,
Scarlett,
Johannsen,
would you like that?
I mean that also would be entertaining.
That would also be entertaining.
I'm not going to lie.
I would like to see one of them cry.
Whoa,
I'm here for it.
Why do you like hurt feelings?
Because we're all human.
We all get our feelings hurt and it's
nice to bring,
you know,
humbled people sometimes go.
Do you think of you're happier in your
own life?
You wouldn't like hurt feelings as much.
You just talked about me being a very
happy person.
Happier.
I'm not saying you're totally 100
percent fulfilled.
You were saying earlier that you can't
find a good man.
That doesn't mean I'm not fulfilled who?
My Vagina,
but the rest of me spiritually,
emotionally,
you're happy even without.
So you're.
So.
I'm a very happy person.
I've been single most of my life.
I believe it was to mean that you're
happy.
I believe you've been your life.
I've always said that you're happy you.
We just got done.
You have.
How many years have I known you?
You've been nothing but friendly.
I mean,
what's to be mad about?
I'm just a grateful
person.
I wake up every morning and I'm like,
I'm just happy to be living this life.
It's a great life and he's a great
living as a up comedian.
Yeah,
that's about as good as it gets.
Well,
yeah,
that's what you want,
but even people who who don't do standup
want to kind of be stand ups.
They want to do a lot of people do.
A lot of Djs do radio djs secretly want
to be comics.
They think they're hilarious.
There's a lot of them to do it secretly.
Absolutely.
That you come in and do morning radio
and the like.
It's like the closest thing to what I
think,
right?
Because what?
I'm trying to think of another
profession which is like standup comedy
where you can like tell jokes and people
listen to you in the mass in the masses,
you know,
but I think,
yeah,
probably a radio is the closest thing to
them.
Some radio djs are Dicks,
you know,
some of them they get kind of ego.
I think that's really what it is.
They also want to keep you on your heels
because they know that you could do
their job,
but they can't do your job.
Like you could just be a radio DJ.
That shit is hard.
Yeah.
We're kind of doing it now.
We argued if you host a podcast,
you know how to do it.
You could easily take over some fucking
radio show.
Tell that dude that dude to go on your
spot.
Eleven 45 and the fucking oh are after
joey ideas bitch.
Good luck.
Good fucking luck.
That's the I,
I find like with dudes just in general,
because it is mostly dudes.
I didn't,
I don't find women like competing with
me to be funny most of the time that
aren't comics,
but like even do two aren't comedians.
Like if I go on a date with them or were
dating,
it's like they always try to one up me,
they tried to one up you,
even though they know you're a comic
because dude,
you know,
dudes,
they always want to just be that,
you know,
the funny ones,
even if they're not gonna mix,
they want to be the funny one and it's
like you don't have to be in and if
you're dating me like it doesn't,
that doesn't,
I don't need that.
It's always good to have a dude that can
make me laugh,
but I don't expect that.
But could you deal with a dude that's
not funny at all?
No,
no,
no.
He doesn't.
No.
I don't want to do who has no sense of
humor.
No,
no,
no.
Don't want to do no sense of humor at
all.
But I would like a dude who could,
like,
who can riff with me but also not
intimidated by me.
And doesn't feel like it'd be funnier
than does going to be your problem
forever.
What that?
Well then I guess I'll just be single
forever.
Forever.
Get a robot talking about making robot
girlfriends get a sex robot.
A robot boyfriend.
Yeah.
They can open jars.
This is house will be at the fucking
whole cancers.
The door.
Every time his eyes move here.
Like what the fuck?
Candace,
what are you up to?
Well,
he couldn't save me the whole quill.
He fucks me and then he stays outside.
Looks out for petty.
Tom's.
He's stands guard outside my window.
Oh,
I want to have women are going to get
there because I know God's going to get
that hundred percent.
Did you see x Mokena?
I've loved it.
Loved it.
Loved.
It's one of my favorite movies ever.
Yeah.
No,
I watch it every,
every minute.
I can.
Yeah.
I watched that movie at least three
times.
Yeah.
But that scene,
like when that guy had those girls,
there were girlfriends,
you know,
like the Japanese lady was dancing with
my favorite scene.
Yeah.
That is 100 percent going to happen.
That there's no way that's not going to
happen.
Of course it's going to happen 100
percent.
Y'All don't want to talk to women.
Why do you.
Why lump me in with all those other
dudes?
Not You,
not you.
I mean,
you're looking at you.
You're talking to a woman right now?
Yup.
I'm the.
I just realized I'm,
I saw a.
because you know,
I be watching the podcast and so you had
a.
Oh,
another black candice on not too long
ago.
Yeah.
I'm the one that's not in the sunken
place.
Sunken place was the sunken place.
I haven't seen that yet yet.
What are you waiting for?
It's not anymore.
Well,
most boys don't walk on the theaters.
Most movies.
Oh yeah.
You're a celebrity.
You can't go to the movies.
Yes.
Then why do you say you just can't?
You said you can't go to the movies.
Can't go to all of them.
That was a really good one.
You should have gone.
If I go to one movie a month,
that's a lot.
So I miss a lot of movies.
I got a little kids movies.
I have kids.
You know.
I go to see the incredibles.
Did you see the incredibles?
Not yet.
It's really good.
I heard it's really good.
Better than the first one.
Is it?
Yeah,
it's really good.
I wanted to see that the other night,
but I got talked into going to see.
I call it black purge purge.
What's called the first purge you saw?
Did you see the original part?
Well,
now there's a,
there's a black one and it's supposed to
be the first purge.
Then it tells the origin of how the
purge a system started in America
and it's with black people.
I haven't heard of this.
I didn't,
I didn't enjoy it.
I enjoy it.
I enjoy it for many reasons.
Um,
uh,
there was acting problems.
I felt it.
There was acting problems.
Uh,
I,
I don't know the names of the people
that I felt the acting bothered me,
but I didn't enjoy that.
And the story.
I just felt like it's one of those ones.
It's like the premise is really good,
but it's just not executed well.
Like the idea of like,
oh shit,
I want to see that.
And then you go see it.
It was a very,
it was a let down.
So a candice owens is in the dark place.
Is I just sunk into the sunken place.
What do you mean how,
so she's a black chick who's like capen
for trump.
Yeah.
What does keeping like rooting for on
his team?
I've never heard that term.
Reporting.
Yeah.
So I can't,
I mean by nature I don't understand
that.
And she's a woman.
She's a black woman.
You don't understand it.
No,
I don't.
What is there to understand like you're
a womanizer who was also accused of rape
on numerous occasions.
Also been,
you know,
as a history of racism from his family.
Like his father,
his father.
You said it in his apartments,
you said deny a renting apartments to
brown
and black people.
So like that he was raised with that.
So like,
and you know,
calling Mexicans rapists,
like I can't.
There's no explanation for supporting.
Yeah.
I think as a black woman she found a
niche.
She did.
I think that's exactly what it is.
I think that,
I don't even think necessarily she
believes what she say.
It's like,
I think that she was like,
oh,
this is a way for me to get famous
because they're how many black she's,
you know,
she is.
She's like the brand new Omarosa.
She's like,
she's like new Amarosa.
Amarosa was on fear factor back in the
day.
She was,
she's crazy.
She accused me of being drunk on the
show.
Talking to her.
Well,
she didn't make any sense and so as I
was saying,
I don't understand what you're saying.
She goes,
Joel,
you drunk?
And I go,
no.
She goes,
I smell liquor on your breath.
I go,
no,
you don't.
I'm not drunk.
I was high as fuck,
but I wasn't drunk.
That's so bizarre.
Yeah.
No,
I think she's just was like,
Amaros is out of the picture.
I'm a step up.
We think so she could be,
honestly,
have we ever seen Tomi Lahren and her in
the same room?
Because I think she could be Tomi Lahren
in blackface.
Wow.
That's how I feel.
It's rough.
I mean,
what?
I think she needs more than blackface
and need to change the nose a little
bit.
There's more it could have been awake.
There's a couple of those girls that are
like interchangeable,
like there's lauren southern and Tomi
Lahren.
I always get them confused.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You're right.
I don't even.
I honestly don't even know Lauren looks
like they look similar though.
Blond hair.
They're both cute blonde conservatives.
There's a market for that.
Of course there is because that's not
the norm.
Anything that's outside the norm is
going to stick out and going to be like,
oh,
this is trendy now.
Like this is what our.
This is what are a party now is
represented by,
which is,
you know,
and they're expecting that they're going
to attract a younger demographic.
The millennials and it is.
I mean it's working somewhat.
Well,
it's definitely getting there some
attention.
I know it's,
it's hard to tell what someone really
believes and what they want you to
believe right toward the toe.
Like global warming doesn't make sense.
Wow.
That one.
See,
that is to me when she said that,
that's indicative of someone who's
trying to follow a line,
like there's a line that you're supposed
to follow if you are a hardcore
republican supporter and it's like
industry is good,
big businesses,
good regulation is bad,
you know,
and then the big one is global warming's
a hopes for at least global warming is
something that's greatly exaggerated by
these environmentalists in order to fund
our Gore's blah,
blah,
blah blah.
You know,
just go down these lines where everybody
on the left believes one thing and
everybody know there's certain things
where you have to believe you're on the
right.
Absolutely.
Really,
you have to believe you're on the left.
It makes you sound batshit crazy.
Like denying facts.
There's a few of those.
Like if you're right wing,
you have to be pro life pretty much.
Right?
Very few.
Right.
When people that are pro abortion,
which is why isn't that what happened
with right?
Isn't that what happened with Tomi
Lahren though?
Didn't she lose?
She lost some contracts she had.
It may have been with,
I don't remember,
but
because she came out of saying she was
pro choice,
so yeah,
that was the end she suffered.
It's interesting when that happens,
like you're not allowed to have varying
opinions or you know,
it's like an almost cult,
like it's very cold.
Like it's,
it's definitely a tribe.
I mean,
that's,
that's what happens.
I haven't watched that and my wife's
obsessed.
It's,
Oh yeah,
there's a new episode that comes out
today.
I got to watch it but watch one episode
and I was like,
this is just too fucked up to reel to
reel.
You see the parallels like the kids
getting separated from their moms and
it's just like,
this is literally happening right now.
It's terrifying.
Yeah.
That to me is one of the darker moments
of this,
this era,
this,
uh,
the knowledge that thousands of kids get
separated from their parents as they
crossed the board.
Like,
what,
what the fuck are we doing?
Like,
what?
And I don't.
There's no excuses.
A lot of people,
I,
I'm,
there's a video that I made was just a
rant on the podcast about it with my
friend Duncan,
Duncan trussell.
We've met only a couple of times,
but I don't know him very well,
but everyone loves him.
So we did this rant or I did this rant
about it and it got made into a video
and then all these people are like,
you know,
you don't understand the real issue on
the border.
If the real issue in the border
separating parents when their kids,
that's not the real issue.
Fucking idiot,
right?
It's supposed to be keeping criminals
out.
You think that lady and her baby are
criminals.
Criminals.
And it's just imagine.
I mean,
people can imagine what it'd be like to
live in Mexico,
right next to United States.
You're right,
it's right there.
You just walk over there and get a job.
You're right there.
And meanwhile,
over here,
you're far better life right over here.
Your cousin got killed by the cartel for
looking at somebody wrong at a taco
stand.
You know,
and then you just.
Nobody,
nobody ever goes to jail for it.
Do you know how many fucking politicians
they killed in Mexico this year?
You know the,
the,
the number.
Somebody was just telling me.
Yeah,
it's more,
it's more than a hundred this year.
Politicians murdered in Mexico.
The go to place.
If you're going to murder somebody,
right?
Like it's right there and it's.
And they never investigated anything
here.
And what's the number of 3,232
politicians killed this year.
One hundred and 32.
How do we know this?
Mexico goes to the polls this weekend.
One hundred 32 politicians have been
killed since campaigning began.
Fuck,
that is crazy.
Record violence.
All because of us.
This is all because of the drug war.
If we just made drugs legal,
there would be none of this going on.
Yeah.
This is worse than the one Pablo Escobar
was out.
Well,
Pablo Escobar,
it's very similar situation.
You know,
it's all fueled by drug money.
Yeah.
All this is drug money.
I mean,
when you make drugs illegal,
only criminals are selling drugs and
there's massive amounts of money because
people love that cocaine.
Okay?
They do.
Have you ever tried cocaine?
Never,
never made any of them ever.
I've tried.
No I won't,
I,
that's what I won't try.
Like I prefer like I've done shrooms and
weed and that's it.
How often do you do shrooms?
Often.
How often do you do weed?
I don't even like the only way that I
have is given to me like,
you know,
when I'll do light when all judge roast
battle and they pay you and we'd hear
the bag of weed and then it takes me
like years to go through it.
That's how.
That's how infrequently.
Like I'll smoke when I'm with friends
but I'm not,
I don't drink by myself and I don't like
when I go home.
Like I'd had a bottle of liquor,
a vodka that's been in my freezer over a
year.
Now you're healthy.
I'm very healthy and very healthy.
When you smoke weed,
you ever get paranoid?
This one time I did an edible.
I ate too much.
So you know,
Gemara neighbors.
Sure.
A very funny comic.
He gave me an edible one time and this
was before,
like anybody could just walk into a
dispensary because now you just have to
show your id and you can get anything
from the dispensary,
but this is when you had to have a a
card.
So he went in and got it for me and it
was this lemon bar that said award
winning on it and me being the weed
novice,
I was like,
oh,
this is going to be award winning
because of the taste.
Right.
It's like probably upset.
I was like,
this is like a Paula deen recipe,
and so I ate like half of it and I was
by myself and I woke up.
I was laying down and I was in my bed
and I sat up and I said,
am I talking to myself?
I'm not talking to myself.
Oh my God,
I am talking to myself.
I'm not talking to myself.
I and I was saying this out loud.
I have to check.
I went on my phone to get on twitter to
see the,
make sure the world was still happening
because I was like,
I,
I felt like I was in some weird twilight
zone.
It was awful.
So I got on there and then I made my
forced myself to go to sleep because I
was like,
I can't be awake like this.
So I forced myself to go to sleep.
I woke up the next morning,
I was still high for like five more
hours.
It was awful.
Yeah.
I gave my friend and edible and he
called me up a day later,
said I'm still high
a day later if you don't know what
you're doing with it,
because I had a conversation with
someone else the other day and they were
like,
I ate there,
I for Rice Krispie treats and I was
like,
why would you eat four of them?
He called the cops the cops and then
checked himself,
went to a hospital because he thought he
was dying.
Do you ever see the one where it was a
nine slash 11 call?
The cops took weed from these people.
They pulled them over and then the cops
use the weed to make pot brownies and
then they ate the pot brownies and they
called nine one on themselves.
They called for an ambulance.
He said there were dying.
Please send help times moving very
slowly,
but what's hilarious is it's a fucking
nine one,
one call from a cop from a cop and the
cop is calling to get an ambulance.
Can you say the time is moving slowly
and they stole the weed from these
fucking kids and they pulled over.
The whole thing is just.
It's brilliant.
It's so funny.
Oh Man.
It's one of my all time favorite.
Nine slash 11 calls because it's just so
sad.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Can you.
Can you please send help times moving
very slowly.
Want to play it?
I was looking up an article about it.
The cop had to.
He
resigned before he got in trouble for.
He resigned taking the weed and be using
it,
so he quit.
Yeah,
that's probably a good move.
At that point you kind of have to.
Yeah.
He called nine slash 11 and we're
talking about on a podcast years later,
everybody's heard that you'd never that
fucking a guarantee.
The video is probably been played a
million times.
Easily.
More than a million.
Do you have Jamie?
I've found this a shorter version.
Okay.
Listen to this.
Poor fucked.
Just think about this to save
marijuana.
If they had something in it.
I think we're dying.
We made brownies and I think we're that
glow
lady.
Laughing.
See,
pot is something that even when you're
having an overdose,
people laugh at you because nobody dies,
dies and she's on the news.
Those are the stiffest fucking people on
the planet.
You ever meet a real newscaster in real
life once they walk around like this?
Once they walk around like robots.
Robots.
Yeah.
They're like,
hello,
how are you?
Oh,
that's great.
That's wonderful.
They're always scared to say something
wrong.
It's interesting like because it's,
we're all kind of in the,
you know,
that's considered entertainment.
You know,
they're on television,
they're camera.
Do not entertainers.
They just readers is.
What it is is like people who don't have
enough personality to have zero
personality,
that's the whole thing.
If you have any personality to kick you
off the air,
the only thing you can have is you could
be one of those weather girls with a big
ass got fat boobs too.
It's not just the assets to everything.
I noticed that that was the first thing
when I moved out to la.
That was one of the first thing I think
that I noticed what the La,
whether people or the weather women.
I was like,
they are hot.
Hot as fuck this.
Back in Cincinnati,
high heels.
Short skirts,
talking about tornadoes and shit.
Kicking their ass out.
Point to weather patterns.
Yeah.
This one I think South America,
there's one famous lady,
she's like a famous weather cast.
She's like one of the hottest women on
the planet.
Tiny little waist,
giant ass,
big tits.
Whereas a waist trainer mate.
What are you hating on her?
Yeah,
because I hate waist trainers.
Bobby Lee bought me one,
but you'll waste training.
He takes me on the road with him
sometimes and willing.
One time we were in like a cvs and I
jokingly picked it up and I was like,
bobby,
buy me this,
and he did and it was like $13,
but no,
I still have it.
I never tried it.
But they're terrifying.
They like their corsets.
I've read articles that you see you're
not supposed to wear these things
because it binds.
It's bad for your organs,
your organs around the Kardashians wear
them.
But yeah,
so that's why I'm like,
I'm not gonna be happy and promote that
for women,
hurting ourselves.
So what's
a weird thick waste than have a kidney
in my neck.
They go,
yeah,
just like a farm worker waste.
Yeah.
Well not to pick things up.
Calm down.
That carries.
Hey,
I do have,
I have an.
I'm like an athletic build so I don't
have a tiny waist.
Does it bother you?
No,
it doesn't bother me.
I like my body.
You should.
Is.
It looks great.
You look great.
Thanks Jesus.
Conversation.
I never get into it guys.
I like my body like,
dude,
you look good.
Tell me you like my body just bro.
I'm good bro.
My okay,
I got it.
Kind of a thick waste.
I do.
I broke.
I'm allowed to say have a thick ways.
You're not going to say it.
I can say it.
You can't say it growing up thick
thighs,
a thick ass,
but even so like women,
we can say that and we know that men,
some men are a lot of men like it,
but being called fic does net never
makes us feel good about ourselves.
Even if even if we know that men like
it,
it still makes it the back of our head.
We're like,
what does he mean?
I'm fat?
What's all this?
We should have guaranteed this girls out
there that like being thick.
Yeah,
of course,
but a lot of women when they know.
I've had conversations with other women
that had been like,
oh look,
I used to be.
When I was in high school,
I was probably 20,
25 pounds heavier than what I am right
now.
Lots of carbs,
lots of carbs,
lot.
I didn't know how to eat properly
because.
So there was a whole low fat craze.
You remember this when snackwells was
popping,
you remember that and they,
they were like,
no,
fat,
high fat is bad.
So they started doing low fat
everything,
but then they replaced the fat with
sugar so it would taste palatable,
you know,
because if you take the fat out,
the flavors going,
so like how do we get the flavor back?
So they put a bunch of sugar and stuff.
So you're eating like thinking,
oh it's low fat.
I would come home and he'd like a bag of
like low fat pretzels,
things like a bag of those snyder's of
Hanover.
Brett's a bag,
one of those big ones and be like,
why am I gaining weight?
Because I didn't know.
I thought low fat man.
Oh I would.
It's low fat,
no fat.
There's so much of that.
There's so many of those low fat items
that are way worse for you.
Yeah.
I don't even know.
I mean are people.
I don't even think that's a thing.
Now it's gluten free.
Gluten free is what's,
what's popular.
Gluten free.
And
what's the other thing?
I can't think there's another thing
that's kind of trending right now,
but it's not just not just gluten
ketogenic diets.
Is that what you're talking about?
No,
I don't know what I'm thinking about.
I literally had a brain fart,
but there is something else.
Maybe Paleo,
a new trendy thing.
Yeah,
but it's all like nobody knows what the
repercussions of any of these things
are.
Like Paleo might be good for temporary,
but in the longterm we don't know the
damage is going to be doing
well.
Paleo is real simple.
It's not going to do any damage.
Paleo is just real food.
Paleo just means no grain and no rice.
That's all it means.
It just.
No preservatives,
artificial flavors,
no artificial colors,
just meat,
chicken,
fish,
vegetables,
meat,
chicken,
fish,
vegetables.
There's nothing wrong with that.
There's not the.
You don't have to worry about that trend
like this.
Is this going to be able to go like the
low fat trend does.
That's a normal thing for people to eat.
You said fruits to you.
They can do fruits,
fruits.
Look,
this people that eat carnivore diet,
this is the more most recent one where
they only eat meat.
That's it.
No,
no,
no.
That's not good.
How do you know that's not good?
I have a friend with pretty severe
autoimmune disease and it's gone because
of eating only carnivore diet.
His daughter had her hip replaced and
her ankle replaced.
She has terrible arthritis with
carnivore diet gone.
Some people have a really adverse
reaction to carbohydrates,
fruits and vegetables.
Nope.
He's not eating anything and he's been
doing.
He's a professor.
Yeah.
Brilliant guy.
What's his cholesterol look like?
That's the thing.
See you.
People say things like that,
like you just said,
that.
That's not where cholesterol comes from.
Dietary cholesterol doesn't have any
impact on blood lipids.
It doesn't have any impact on your blood
cholesterol.
This is where cholesterol is bad when
you have cholesterol and high
carbohydrates,
because when your body is burning a lot
of carbohydrates,
your body is in fat storing mode,
so if you eat a bunch of fat and
carbohydrates,
you're asking me get fat as fuck,
but if you do just that,
but if you adjust the famil fat,
then your body loses weight.
Believe it or not,
you actually get slim.
Yeah,
no,
I know about that part,
but I didn't know the cholesterol part.
Yeah,
you're not.
If you are.
This is one the important thing for
people.
If you are on a high fat,
low carb diet,
you cannot eat large amounts of
carbohydrates because if you do,
it's just going to go right to fat
because your body just is not.
Your body's going to use what's going to
burn carbohydrates and it's going to
take all the fat you take in and just
store it so you just going to get fat as
fuck.
Well,
without this body positivity,
that's how do you know that's not what I
want.
That you want to get fat,
do you think?
So that can be body positive,
body positive.
Is that what that is?
It's just embraced the fatness.
It's literally just being like if you're
fat,
love your body and that's fine.
Like you can be fat and love your body,
but it's also promoting,
you know,
unhealthy behaviors.
I think also,
and we want to distinguish between the
two.
Well,
we want to give people a free pass by
saying be body positive.
You know,
don't,
don't fat shame,
right?
Like leave people be I have a black belt
and fat shaming or are you good at it?
You know,
you do taekwondo Id fat shame.
No.
Go to a Dojo.
Fat,
stinky armpits.
It used to be easy to fat.
Shame.
Now people are super upset about it.
Yeah.
No,
I know.
I'm not sure it was right.
I'm really not.
Well it's not right,
but I mean you should make fun of
somebody for the way they look.
You know?
I don't think that's right,
but we shouldn't be promoting an
unhealthy lifestyle.
That too.
And also by Tom Secura said that like
people making fun of his weight is a
reason why he lost weight.
He was like fat shaming was very
effective on me.
He lost the weight because people were
fat shaming.
Yeah.
A lot of behaviors.
A lot of behaviors or because you felt
shame and we're in.
We're in a society where like,
there is no shame anymore.
There's no shame with anything.
I know.
I know people that are like proud of
their alcoholism.
I've heard people bragging about Duis.
What?
I'm not kidding.
Hanging around with the wrong people or
they're not my friends.
I just,
I've heard it.
So do you think that that's an escape
clause?
Like they're just,
like,
they're giving themselves an out.
Like I love being an alcoholic.
Fuck it.
Yeah.
I think to them it's because of we're
accepting everything now that it's just
like,
it's,
uh,
it's just fun behavior.
Like I'm fun when I'm drunk and it's
just.
And that's fine.
You can be fun.
But also,
you know,
there's Uber's take a lyft.
Why are you driving?
That's the problem.
Yeah.
The especially today,
there's no excuse for that,
especially in Hollywood.
I mean that fucking comedy store parking
lot,
you can't get out of it because it's
always jammed up.
The lifts and Hoover's.
Yep.
Which is great,
but also it is annoying.
It's annoying.
It's annoying,
but it's great that people are taking
responsibility to drive them around.
The whole thing about Uber says like how
much background check and they do it on
those freaks.
Yeah,
no,
I'm,
I'm positive I've gotten into a lyft
driver or uber driver because I don't,
I don't.
I used to do uber and then they suck,
so I started doing lyft,
but yeah,
I'm sure I got an uber at one point
where somebody was drunker than I am,
but maybe let me get this.
Yeah,
they're not checking them right?
No,
not at all.
Not at all.
I just,
I don't know.
I feel like being.
Because you don't drink at all to you or
do you do?
I just feel like I have such a
nonaddictive a personality and I feel
that most people are addicted to things
and that's why it's also tough for me,
like a dating also.
It's because I know I'd see.
I know that a lot of people that I have,
you know,
been on dates with or whatever.
It's like,
oh,
this lifestyle is not conducive to what
I'm trying to do.
So we just don't click in that way
because you find you go on dates with
guys are getting fucked up.
Yeah,
like a lot,
a lot,
a lot.
So much so.
UHM,
weekend nights.
Yeah.
Weeknights.
Any day.
Is it Tuesday?
Why am I not drunk yet?
Right.
So yeah,
I actually,
the last APP that I got on with like a,
it's a,
it's called meet mindful because I
wanted to find people who were viewed as
somebody who is just more present and
maybe likes themself a little bit more
so they don't have to get drunk all the
time to be with themselves.
Yeah.
How'd that work out?
Well,
they were like,
you got to pay $30 a month.
And I was like,
maybe I'm not looking for love right
now.
I paid,
I paid before for like eharmony.
That's what I paid for that one.
I paid almost $200 for that one.
How would that work out?
Terribly.
And that's why I'm hesitant to pay again
because I got nothing.
I got literally nothing
from that.
So I'm like,
I feel like one sentence,
I thought Ian Harmony,
like instantly find the love of your
dreams and then you sit down with them
on a couch.
They do a video with you,
Joe.
I knew.
Then as soon as I met candice,
she was the one.
I was on there for over a year.
What I called customer service and
complained.
What'd you say?
Where's my deck?
You Promise Me Dick by month three or I
get a refund.
Yeah,
no.
I called and I said I would like a
refund.
Plus like why?
And I said,
these dudes are like,
for like all of them and below they were
just,
all of them were like the worst looking
people I'd ever seen.
And she was like,
we have so many messages that you
haven't responded to.
I said,
did you not hear my first complaint?
Like I'm not going to respond to any of
these dudes.
They were terrible looking and not just,
not just like physically,
but just like the photo,
like terrifying looking like serial
killers,
like don't know pictures of just a
foreheads.
I take a picture properly.
The dating APP world.
It's got to be fucking weird.
I'm so lucky.
I know several people that are in the
dating app world.
If so,
tell me about it.
Or swiping right.
Swiping left.
Pull.
It's awful.
Which one do you swipe right if you like
them.
Which one do you say?
Swipe White,
right?
Mother?
How dare he?
When there was a phase where I was
swiping white didn't work out.
No,
I've,
I've only.
I've dated a couple of white dudes in my
life.
Barely.
Just one of them I think was gay and now
the another one.
Pathological Liar.
I've made it to gigs.
Gay dudes.
I think so.
Out of your study group,
white people are gay and pathological
liars.
Yes.
And that's it.
There's nothing else.
Oh,
the two are not mutually exclusive.
You can be gay in a pathological liar.
You're not even sure.
I'm sure it's possible to have that
combination.
Just sent me up with one of your
friends.
Okay.
I'll try to find somebody for you.
Yeah,
I'll try to find somebody.
Why not a.
not a like MMA person.
Oh,
you don't want.
Well,
how come?
I don't think I could handle that.
It's a lot of muscles.
Muscles.
Not that much.
Like what do you want to do the work.
So like once a week,
maybe twice,
maybe twice.
Twice.
But it doesn't get crazy and go crazy.
No one who gets up in the morning and
runs early mean I can do that.
I'll be meditating while he was running.
Running,
running.
So that's fine.
That'll work out.
Yeah.
But I just don't want someone who like
might be on steroids,
might be,
might be.
Might be.
Okay.
I'll keep it in mind.
It's got to be hard.
Like when you fill out one of them,
eat harmony things.
What do you have to write?
You write what your occupation is,
what you're looking for.
What do you write?
What you looking for?
Do you ever ride?
I'm just looking for Dick.
No direct.
I'm looking for a meaningful
relationship with the person of my
dreams.
Women already have to swat the dicks
away without writing.
I'm looking for Dick.
Swat is Dixie.
Walk outside and it's.
Hey,
get out.
Dick's.
Nope.
So yeah,
no,
you can't write that in.
If I wanted that,
I'd be on tinder.
You know,
those tended to move.
She would just want some Dick.
You're so lucky.
You don't know about any of this.
Tinder is the Dick App.
That's it.
So if you just want some Dick and even
bumble is kind of turning into that,
do you think that bumble is a new one in
not new anymore?
A newer one is coffee meets Bagel.
I was on that one for a minute.
I was reading this thing that said that
there's a car.
This was made me angry that it said his
tinder and Grindr.
Are they responsible in any way for the
spread of stds from their apps?
Of course.
No,
they're not.
Of course they don't,
they don't owe a goddamn thing.
You can't be in their dicks and they
absolutely like they're not,
they're not.
They shouldn't be sued,
like that's ridiculous.
But were saying,
should they,
should they take responsibility?
Take responsibility.
No,
but I guarantee that more people are
hooking up because of this things,
right?
These,
these apps and doing it unsafely.
So what,
that's not an any skin off their back.
No,
no,
I know.
I'm just,
it's a weird time where like people
getting in trouble for things that other
people are doing.
Yeah,
absolutely.
You want people to be responsible.
It's taking personal responsibility for
their own mistakes.
Like,
yeah,
put a condom on.
What are you talking about when you did?
Yeah,
I've heard stories about like,
hey dudes,
man,
they're so trifling.
Look,
my friend is a gay dude,
was telling me about what the behavior
and gay,
uh,
in gay gyms,
how like they have in the shower,
there's a signal so that if you,
if you want somebody to come up in there
and just ram you and you leave the
curtain partially opened and that's kind
of like a signal to be like,
okay,
if you want to come up in here and get
some you can.
And I was talking to a friend,
I'm like,
what if you didn't know that rule and
you accidentally leave the curtain open
just because you didn't close it
properly.
Jesus.
And all of a sudden some dude is
every time I've been in gyms around gay
people or gay,
I used to belong to Gold's gym on Korea.
It's a in,
you know,
in West Hollywood.
And that's where we used to film
newsradio right down the street from.
Oh yeah.
So that was the gym that I worked out.
It's a gay disco that Jim is a God damn
gay disco.
And when I would go there,
not that it's anything wrong with that,
but when I would go there,
it was.
You would get that feeling.
That girl gets all the time.
Terrified.
Well yeah.
That's something.
All these eyes on me,
someone's trying to fuck you go unsafe
right now.
Yeah.
It's a different feel like girls hitting
on use.
Like if you want you can come over here
guys,
if you want to come over there because
it's a different feeling like Michael
Jackson,
Michael Jackson when he's not using his
falsetto voice.
But it's an uncomfortable feeling
knowing that guys want to fuck you.
Like I couldn't imagine being a girl.
Just trying to navigate my way through
dudes.
It's terrifying.
Swat and Dick's swot and them platinum.
Yeah.
No crack.
Kevin Peeping Toms at your windows.
It's,
it's,
it's a scary world out there.
So your neighbor,
when they found that guy,
was he hot out?
No,
I didn't.
I still don't know what.
He's hot and he said,
I'm sorry.
He gonna be at my window.
Hey girl,
I'm sorry.
I came home from the club.
I was a little drunk.
I've always had this thing for you.
I can't believe I was whispering.
Hey,
your pussy is disrespectful.
I apologize if he said it like that to
take you out for drinks and just we'll
make up to.
I'll.
Sorry,
I'm so sorry.
Well,
you know,
you put it like that.
Who am I to turn down?
Here's my e harmony profile.
The terrifying part is that I don't know
who it was and it could have been.
It could be someone I know and even the
way my neighbors described him was that
it actually,
the way they described him did describe
someone that I know and consider a
friend.
Oh,
but then when I showed my neighbor the
picture of the person I was talking
about,
they were like,
no,
I don't think that's him,
but still now in the back of my head,
I'm like,
what if it was so now my friendship with
this person has been a little strained
because of it.
Because I'm like,
well,
I don't trust you.
Whoa.
I know.
It's weird.
That is weird.
That's the life of a girl.
We have enough to worry about.
Shit that guards won't have to worry
about.
So many things.
There are no girls outside your window
whispering good.
Well they are,
but it's because you dated them before
and you wrong them and you cheated on
them or did something and now she's
stalking you or you found out they're
crazy and they know where you live.
Yeah,
I love.
I'm,
I'm very interested in all of like,
like relationship behavior and like
crimes of passion.
I like all of it.
I'm very into it.
Look those annie shows or like snapped
on oxygen.
Have you ever seen that it's.
It will snap.
Yes.
Mostly women.
It's mostly women.
Sometimes this is a mass oxygen.
It is asked.
Does the women's channel absolutely
lifetime.
Why is oxygen and women's channel
oxygen's like air?
Everybody needs that.
I don't know.
Um,
but yeah,
we were uh,
I was watching a snapped.
I watch it.
Not so much anymore but it's been on for
a long time,
but every episode is like a different
couple and the woman is just like,
can't put up with shit anymore.
Like her dudes cheating on her or like
taking her money or abusing her or
whatever,
and then she snapped and she kills him.
Well,
you always.
Zoe's a spoiler alert for every show.
You know where it's going to go and she
just couldn't take it anymore.
It's in the title g one,
which is going to snap next dick flying
across the.
That's my only thing.
I don't want to be a victim of a crime
of passion.
Just don't you just break up with me.
You don't have to kill me.
Yeah,
I hear you.
That's reasonable requests.
What's the craziest thing?
What's the craziest
thing a girlfriend has ever done to you?
Have you gotten your car key before?
No.
I've been pretty good at navigating
those waters.
I've got.
Oh,
we got pretty good,
crazy radar.
Oh yeah.
The problem is when they're really hot,
they're really hot and they're also
crazy.
Like,
damn,
this might be worth the risk.
That's usually what
I guess.
I don't know if you've seen this.
It was on a,
it was a youtube clip and the guy do a
chart and it was like a chart of crazy
to hotness and it's.
It's like all the hot chicks are always
crazy.
Instead if you'd have to and it
basically tells you in what range you
have to find the normal.
One
woman really funny.
My friend Tony Zara has it best.
He's got a.
He said that there's like erotic in
neurotic and they crossover like a venn
diagram.
They hit this,
hit this crossroad there.
They're like the two interchangeable
things.
Completely closely related,
psychotic,
neurotic and erotic.
Right all together and see if you get
the really erotic women,
they're almost always psychotic or,
or neurotic or crazy.
There's something wrong.
Yeah.
Red Flag.
The really fun ones.
Yeah.
That just the ones that really want to
rock your world there.
They're crazy.
I've heard that and so if you're
wondering,
I'm,
I'm very normal again.
My parents loved me,
which means I don't do anal.
Good point.
That is a weird thing,
right?
If your parents love you too much,
you might not be as ambitious.
I mean,
that is true,
like I wish I told her like I think I'm
definitely ambitious,
like I'm definitely,
you know,
I've been doing this for like 10 years
now and it's like I have come so far.
So it's like,
yeah,
no,
I definitely have goals and achieving
them,
but it's also,
I'm also not like a,
Oh,
we were talking about earlier like the,
the ceos of these corporations,
like I don't have that kind of drive.
Like I just want to do what I love and
make good money doing it to be lifted up
for 10 years.
Where'd you start here?
At the store.
Not Store,
but like in la I started uh,
the first place I got up,
you know,
doing open mics and stuff,
but I didn't want to go to the store at
first because I was like,
I don't want to go there if I'm not
funny yet.
Then who knows,
going to see me and they'll be like,
oh,
she's not funny.
When did you get past the store?
Like December of 2014.
So almost 2015,
you know.
So that was right when I came back.
Yes,
it was right when you came back because
that was right.
I was the first.
Me and [inaudible] were the first people
that Adam passed when he got promoted to
that position.
Yeah.
Because yeah,
I don't know if Tommy was ever going to
pass me.
I don't know
Tommy.
I know it's a whole.
So when.
Yeah,
when I came back there I got to see like
the whole new crop.
There was a whole new crop of people in
the seven years that I was gone.
Was it seven years?
I was gone for seven years.
I thought I'd be gone forever if Adam,
if Tommy had fired and Adam take over.
I was still been.
Which is,
that was the dumbest thing.
Well,
Miss Decision for me,
it was a good decision.
It was good.
It was healthy.
To get away from the store for a little
bit,
sort of changed my comedy,
made it a little less evil.
Blazes so harsh,
but haven't you noticed that the energy
has changed since taking over?
It's a different place.
It's a different place without Tommy.
It's a different place just because of
the vibe of the comedy store is now.
I'm also fortified by the Internet.
It's like people who love the place
because it's this iconic historical
landmark.
It's like the Mecca of comedy.
It really is the Mecca in the country
now.
It's the real Mecca work.
When I was a kid,
when I was first starting out,
I had heard about the comedy store,
you know,
because Sam kinison started out there
and Richard Pryor was always there and I
looked.
That was the place I needed to go to the
comedy store.
When I came out here,
I was already on a Sitcom and I didn't
get passed at the store.
I was a non paid regular,
so I was able to go on at the end of the
shows.
When I first got here,
when I got passed as a paid regular,
it was like the happiest moment of my
life.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
I'm a paid regular at the comedy store.
Like that to me was bigger than being on
a television show.
I'm here,
but back then the comedy store was a
ghost town.
It was deserted.
It was no one.
There you go on a Friday night to be 30
people in the audience.
It was just gross and there was a lot of
boat acts still floating around.
So like something happened between the
Kinison Age,
right?
Kennison age was like 84,
87,
88 and in that time that guy was just
running rampant and destroying and he
was a maniac and he was the top of the
world and then he dropped off and then
he died and then when he died,
that place was a ghost town.
So when I came along right after he
died,
I came along in [inaudible] 94 and there
was no one there.
So it went from being this jam packed,
like literally always here.
Like all these celebrities come to see
Kennison do spots late at night and be
like,
Whoa,
that must have been nuts.
John Belushi be there and Jack Nicholson
and all these different people and then
you go there.
I don't know,
it was John Belushi was probably dead by
then when the John Belushi died.
He died in 18.
80 two.
Yeah.
He died earlier than that.
I shouldn't have said John Belushi.
I might've made that up,
but I know Jack Nicholson,
a bunch of other celebrities use
Kennison and I remember thinking,
man,
nobody famous comes here now.
This is a shit hole.
There was nobody there,
but it's different now.
Now,
now,
now it's every show sold out every show,
every show.
It's nuts.
Last time it was crazy.
I was thinking that the other day was
like,
what a time for me to be like a regular
at the store.
Like it
just happened at the perfect time.
Like it just because I know so many
people that were like were door guys
back when like,
and I've heard stories like bobby would
tell me stories from when he used to
work there and like Freddy Lockhart and
when they were like door guys and I'm
like wow,
that sounds so shitty.
And like what?
They were getting paid.
They're getting paid like $25 for the
day.
Awful.
Yeah.
I met Bob,
he was a door guy at the La Jolla store.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
When I'm at Bobby's like 1994 or some
shit like that.
Uh,
we went to a strip club and he almost
got killed.
What?
I mean,
that sounds about right first I'm like,
what?
Like hitting on some girl and apparently
she was,
she was Mexican gang banger and this guy
who had long black hair and tattoos on
his face in the nineties,
in the nineties,
he had tattoos on his face wasn't even
popular and then the guy,
he was looking over at me and then
they're talking to his friends.
I go,
we are getting the fuck outta here.
I think Jimmy Schubert was with me,
just me and gibby.
Schubert and Bobby Lee.
I go,
we're getting the fuck out of here.
And Bob was like,
those guys aren't going to do shit.
I go,
I will fucking leave you.
you don't have any idea what danger is
like?
Well those guys are going to do
something.
I wasn't worried about fighting.
I was worried about getting shot.
This is going to murder.
This is a bad scene,
dude.
We gotta get Outta here now.
And Bobby was like,
those guys,
you ain't gonna do shit.
I'm like,
who is the smallest person here?
Well,
he was,
you know,
21 years old or whatever the fuck he
was.
He was out of his mind
child.
I mean he's still a childlike in many
ways,
but yes,
it will always remain one way or is a
man.
I tell his girlfriend all the time.
I was like,
you're the most patient woman in the
world to deal with him.
That's an odd couple.
It's a very odd couple.
It seems to work though.
They've been bother.
It's insane.
And they met on tinder.
Kapow.
Yeah,
it worked it.
I know two people that work there.
I said it worked.
And you went because I know two people
that it worked for them.
And also I know a couple is getting
married this weekend.
Who met on tinder?
Well,
there you go.
Maybe it's you,
maybe it's you.
Maybe you need to give tinder second
chance.
No,
for sure it is me because I refused to
settle.
I know for sure it is me.
How do you think using your vision board
and all of your manifesting,
how can you get someone in your life
that you need in your life?
I honestly,
honestly,
honestly I think of your name.
I think of tyrone smoke rocks.
That was my first white man.
I knew you from fear factor,
but I also,
that was a huge,
you know,
for,
for me before I even knew I'd be doing
standup and I'm watching the Chappelle
show and I just remember I love it.
It makes me laugh so much.
Joe Rogan,
my feet are strong,
poses a great character.
I like,
I've tried to do crack impressions,
crack Ad Impressions for jokes before
and I can't because every time I try to
do an original crack head impression
like just from my own,
you know,
inspiration and from watching other like
real crackheads,
I can't do it because the default
crackhead is now tyrone Brigham's and it
just.
And I'm like,
I can't do it because I can't do.
Tyrone becomes on certain people that
create characters that forever.
They're iconic,
that that's the crack head for the rest
of,
for the rest of time out.
It's an amazing show.
Was only two seasons and that it was 15
years ago.
Wow.
And even more amazing than he just said,
fuck it.
And left and left.
Sorry.
GotTa go.
Yeah.
I mean I get it though.
I get it.
I totally get it.
I was on it.
I was on comedy central at the time and
I saw like the management and how it was
working there.
It was chaos.
And then whenever you tell people that
aren't funny,
that are executives,
tell them to manage funny.
You're right.
I don't know what the fuck they're
doing.
They have no idea.
Let Dave Chappelle be David,
trust me,
he's gonna.
Make the most funny and let him and Neal
Brennan go figure out what they're doing
and just get out of the way.
Get out of the way and put ads on it.
Yeah,
and you saw the success of what had
happened with what they did with that.
Yeah.
You know,
they try to do a bunch of shit with him.
They tried to,
first of all,
they're trying to get to change changes,
language,
stop using the n word.
They want me to stop using because they
would get more ads.
It was all about people not comfortable
with advertising with certain kinds of
sketches,
so they wanted to maximize their profits
but so tone down the show,
a little maximize their profits and Dave
was like,
I see where this is going on.
Yeah,
lose complete control.
He just quit.
Yeah.
Imagine the executives when they found
out he was really quitting,
they were like,
he's just joshing yeah,
they probably just bluffing.
Yeah,
he's.
He doesn't like the way you guys are
shaping the show.
So he's going to quit and he's in Africa
now by click,
but we were just to make $180,000,000,
but we were just going to make honor.
Dave just quit.
You guys blew it,
you know,
people don't remember,
but for a while Dave was doing shows and
he wasn't getting paid.
He wouldn't do shows where he got paid.
He would show up in the park.
He showed up in Seattle.
It was like a big deal.
He put up a speaker,
he put up his own PA system and started
doing standup in the park and a crowd
gathered round of course,
and that's what he would do.
He would just show up places to start
doing standup.
That's crazy.
That's what he did.
You know what I met Dave,
I met Dave is like,
how is 21?
He was like 18,
something like that or maybe maybe I was
a little older.
It goes like 24 and he was 18 and he
was,
he would do,
he would do shows outside,
like we would do a Gig.
We a Gig in Montreal and then after we
did the Gig of Macho,
he came downstairs outside of club soda
and he just started doing standup on the
street.
He goes,
ladies and Gentlemen,
Ladies and gentlemen,
gather around.
I got some shit to tell you.
And then he would start doing standup on
the street and he learned it from a
Charlie Burnett.
Charlie Barnett who was a.
He was like an old school New York
character who did a lot of street
comedy.
We didn't.
We have a video of Charlie Barnett.
There's.
There's one online he would do.
Yeah,
like this is what he would do.
Charlie Barnett would do comedy like
this,
like he got these giant crowds and would
walk around like a park and get
everybody gather around and he was such
a showman that people would just sit and
wait and they will do standup.
Here it is in Washington Square Park.
That's insane.
Yeah.
No Mike,
we've got a nice mixed route.
I mean,
look,
when we got,
we got white folks,
black folks.
We got quite a ray guns.
We got a lot of fucking part of Reagan's
but I'm not gonna fuck with them for the
man because y'all born with knives.
Got Me up and I.
He
was.
He would do this.
This is how he would do up anyway,
yell it out in the park.
I got a chance to see him a couple.
He died of AIDS like somewhere.
I think it was in the early nineties.
He died,
but I got to see him.
That's when people were dying of AIDS.
Back back when AIDS will kill you.
Now aids is like the flu.
Yeah,
like everybody got it.
don't whine if got aids.
My uncle's got leukemia.
Don't even have medication for that.
Broke the Charlie Barnett influenced
dave and Dave would do that kind of
stand up,
you know,
Dave would just do standup in front of a
club.
He would just get and people just gather
around and watch him.
And I remember thinking like,
wow,
I'm not really me.
I could never do that.
But man,
that kind of detachment to be able to
just,
just be free in front of a crowd like
that.
That's powerful.
And you know,
we've performed in all different types
of really terrible places,
you know,
when you're coming up and you're just
doing open mics and bars and coffee
shops or whatever.
And I still to this day roll my eyes
when someone's,
it's an outdoor venue because it's just
like a,
you know,
there's nothing to.
Right.
So like the,
the,
the laugh just get lost.
They just disappear into the ether.
And so the arenas too,
when you do stand up,
not that performed in an arena.
It's on my vision board though.
Is it right next to the Dick?
What's your visual boy?
That's weird.
You got anything crazy in your vision
board?
You get a private jet on your vision
board.
Is that.
Do you have one?
It's actually not on my vision board,
but I do visualize it.
Do you?
I do visualize,
visualize,
visualize and meditate.
Do you visualize you strolling with a
tiny bag with a dog in it and you go
like a cigarette holder and giant
glasses.
Cigarette holder than just like,
like stroll on with high heels to let
those tight skirt.
Like,
Oh,
where's my seat?
Whereas my seat in the fuck,
I want it to be bitch.
This is my pet,
my dog shit on the floor and play
motherfucker.
Now my private jet is going to be much
more basic than then.
You know,
I just want to a plane where if like I,
I can fart freely and not have to worry
about other people.
One time I held a Fart from Cincinnati
to Los Angeles.
That's very polite of you.
Thank you.
Firstly,
on a plane.
A lot of people are sneaky on.
No,
but I was like,
I can't do this to anybody and very
considerate person.
If it was your plane,
let him loose.
What if it was your plane and you had a
stewardess still let it loose.
Flight attendance.
Oh,
what's the difference?
Because you can't change it to flight
attendant because they have a male
flight attendants because you can't call
a male stewardess.
Do they really have male flight
attendants?
Haven't you?
I've seen him on the daily mail.
More feminine than me,
but yes,
there's still went to the dentist today
and I had to fill out.
One of them were so like I had to fill
out this form and on the form it said
sex.
It said male or female.
I was like,
where's the other?
Whereas other bitch,
where's uh,
where's Kins?
Whereas other kids,
other kids?
Yeah.
You don't know about other kids.
Don't know what that is.
Oh,
those people that think they're a fox,
they identify with foxes like an Elf.
Can people think they're fairies would?
I'm a wood Elf.
No other kin people think that there's
something.
They're supposed to be something else
there like a person,
but really they're an animal that's
trapped in a person's body.
No,
just crazy.
Are they?
Here we go.
This lady,
when people ask me,
how's it feel to be a cat?
I'm like,
how does it feel to be a human?
Oh,
that's rational.
Whoever you your dad is,
hey dude,
who's her dad?
Fuck you.
Look what you did to the world.
You asshole.
You let this girl.
Lucy thinks she's a cat.
Yeah,
no,
that's,
that's when you have a.
that's a.
that's definitely a mental issue.
Oh,
for sure.
Like Rachel Dolezal,
she's one of document.
Oh,
I'm obsessed with her.
It was boring.
It was just,
she's,
she's going crazy.
She owes money.
She's dead and she's got kids.
I feel bad for the kids,
but who is this dude that she's with?
Who is this dude?
She just had a baby not that long ago.
Some dry works.
Yeah.
I'll just get on my nerves.
Just have sex with anything.
Well,
it's.
If it's everything or nothing,
that dude could have got it from
somewhere else.
If you fucked her,
could he really?
Did he ever pick of the litter dudes who
are unattractive?
Poor,
sleeping on someone else's couch and
they're still getting vagina?
So yes,
they must be good talkers.
Women don't have standards anymore.
You do?
I do.
Well,
my parents loved me many times.
That's going to be the name of my first
special.
Actually know the name of my first
session.
Was I going to be.
I'm a very busy man.
A book.
This book will not be that good because
my parents love this special.
Hang on me funny because my parents
loved me.
It's finished everything with my parents
because my parents loved me.
But you are very funny.
So that doesn't work.
I'm not.
You're not.
You're not crazy.
Like ambitious to the point where you
ruin the step.
Walk on people's backs and cut people
because my parents loved me.
That's what that.
That's where that comes from.
You know that narcissistic personality
disorder,
sociopathy comes from some type of
neglect or abuse in childhood.
Yes.
So,
and we do in this industry attracts a
lot of that now people at Ted tension
starved and they just want fame.
So you have the people who,
there's two types of people in the
industry,
you've got the people who really just
loved the craft of it,
they really are great actors or great
comics writers and then you have the
kind that just want to be famous who
don't give a crap about,
you know,
what it takes to actually,
a hone that skill and become the best at
that.
They just want.
And some of them pretend to be the other
thing.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Which is weird.
I mean,
it's crazy.
People everywhere.
Some of them like pretend to be comics,
like they pretend to be interested in
the craft of comedy and you know what,
when it gets really weird,
when they become famous and then you see
it happens all the time.
You see that they don't.
This is an actor.
They were acting like they're a
comedian.
Yeah.
That's not,
they're not really comic.
But then we let them get stage time.
You and I don't have any control over
that.
Anybody getting stage time?
Yeah.
No,
I know,
but it's frustrating.
Why did you get into it?
I have,
I believe my pain when I was a kid was
just feeling like I didn't fit in like
out there when you were telling me
you're not black.
Like that was my pain because I am black
and so I grew up feeling like I didn't
fit in anywhere where you are at,
you are a certain percentage.
African American.
My parents are black and someone was
white.
Well yeah.
No,
somewhere along the line.
But there's mixes,
there's black,
native American and there's white.
Um,
but yeah,
if you saw my family you'd be like,
there's no white people in this family.
If you saw my family be like somebody
somewhere along the lines to chimp at
chimp.
So many fucked a chimp.
Why do you want to,
shouldn't have,
you know,
I think this is what I think about my
family.
Tiality in
your talents in general.
I feel like,
you know,
people evolved from Apes.
I don't believe that.
You don't believe that.
I think somewhere along the line
somebody went back when they shouldn't
have somebody who went by,
they were like,
well,
you know,
fuck fucking needs apes over.
Get One last shot at the monkey.
She wasn't saying she wasn't talking
back to me.
She never burned my meatloaf banana.
That's all she wanted.
She would let me stick stuff wherever,
wherever I wanted to stick stuff.
She was warm to cuddle with and the
winter months.
Yeah.
Well everyone's African.
Every single human.
If you treat them all the way back that
23 and me.
Shit,
I just did it.
I don't know.
I'm waiting.
Have to wait a couple more weeks.
I'm very excited.
It sounds scared.
Uh Nah.
What could it be?
I'm mostly.
I'm supposed to be mostly Italian and I
have like a quarter Irish in me.
That's what it's supposed to be.
Let's see if anybody was sneaking around
my DNA.
Maybe a German got in the mix or an
African or Moroccan or who knows?
He knows.
He got in the mix back in the day.
Hilarious.
You know,
I'm too.
I don't think I'm going to do one of
those.
I don't want to know,
I don't want to know if I find that I'm
whiter than I am.
I'll just walk into traffic.
Your,
your skin is lighter than mine.
No,
I know.
But so what,
like,
okay,
you have to fence.
Jesus can just settle down.
It's crazy because like you have like me
and my sister were from the same parents
but she had a completely different
childhood than me because no one ever
questioned.
She never got her hair pulled by like
darker skin,
black girls.
Whereas I did.
Why?
Why did she not get her hair?
She's darker than me and her hair is
kinkier so just she just came out
different.
She came out brown.
So yeah.
So we had to complete.
So that's where,
that's where my pain came from.
It was like,
I felt like I didn't fit in,
you know,
so
like the.
So your comedy is so sort of like you
have like a personality that was kind of
compensating for not fitting in.
Yeah,
I started being funny because I,
I felt like that could distract people
from,
you know,
like I'll want them to like me and
accept me.
So the one thing that everyone can agree
on is that we like jokes and I'm like
laughing.
So I became like a class clown and just
when I was like,
oh,
people like me now and I don't have to
worry about them wondering what I am
trying to put me in a box.
It's like I'm the funny one.
That's all the matter.
Oh yeah.
Interesting.
But my pain is not like a,
you know,
there's mild pain.
It's a mile past.
That's exactly how he described it.
Cause a lot of comics were like,
oh it was molested by my father or
somebody.
And it's like,
oh,
that's awful.
I'm sorry to hear that,
but that makes sense.
But yet people always come to me and
they're like,
you don't have,
you're not addicted to anything.
Like you know what I mean?
Vices and you weren't like touched by an
uncle.
So like why are you funny?
And I was like,
well that's,
that was,
that's why I got plenty.
It was mild.
But when you first got on stage where
you work and what we do for a living?
Yes.
Uh,
first got on stage.
I did have a day job at that time I was
working.
Oh my God.
I had,
I've had a few jobs.
At one point I was working at Sylvan
learning center and at one point I was
working at it or doing tutoring.
I was a center director for a,
at Sylvan learning center at one point.
So I was in charge of the facility just
for like where I was in Glendale and I
was also in Santa Clarita.
Yeah.
But I wasn't,
I was an assistant at the assistant
director at the Glendale and I was a
full on center director at Santa
Clarita.
But then after that I also worked at a
nail salon.
I worked at a Vietnamese nail salon for
a minute.
At the front desk.
Yeah.
I worked in Toluca Lake Lake at a place
called oasis nail spa.
Shout out to my,
all my Vietnamese nail technicians who
still work there.
They were very nice and it's right next
to Bob's big boy.
I used to work there.
I actually met a lot of people working
there because it's by the studio.
So like George Lopez would come in
there.
George Lopez was a little his whole.
Well when he was still married,
him and his wife and his daughter would
come in.
Yeah.
So this was before he would drop them
off.
I think that's what it was.
Yeah.
But you know who did come and get his
nails done?
David Allen greer with his.
His wife at the time.
They have since split as well.
That's a bad luck salon.
Has everyone that comes in there is very
get divorced.
I don't think it has to do with a salon
or restaurant.
Of course.
It's the hard tissue being in a
relationship.
You've managed to make it work.
It works.
You can make it work.
You can.
I think it just takes like.
But also I think it's the type of people
you are two.
Yeah.
One hundred percent or your parents
still together?
My stepfather and my mother are still
together.
They've been together since I was a
little kid.
Oh Wow.
Okay.
So it's a successful relationship.
Yeah,
but it's one that started when I was
five.
That's commitment,
but it works.
Yeah.
There.
They're very friendly.
They're very happy with each other,
very friendly to each other.
So I grew up around that.
They were there.
They had a healthy relationship.
I saw terrible relationship with my
mother and my father.
Terrible.
Briefly violent.
Oh Wow.
Dangerous.
Not Good.
Then left that.
And then when we moved in with my,
my mother's parents,
we lived there for awhile and then we
got an apartment after my mom had,
you know,
escape from my dad.
And then,
um,
when my mom met my Stepdad,
it was a totally different relationship.
He's a hippie and he was like,
this really nice guy.
He's into crystals and stuff.
No,
just,
he was just,
he was you.
He's an architect and he was just a
different kind of guy.
Smoked Pot.
Had long hair.
Yeah.
Just different kind of person.
Do you ever wonder about like how you
would have like,
what your personnel would be like now if
your mom had stayed with your dad like
longer?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That wouldn't have been good.
I would've,
I would've been a dangerous person.
Yeah.
Yeah,
for sure.
I,
I carry,
you know,
I have a,
I mean I don't have a tendency towards
violence because I'm not a violent
person in terms of like actual my actual
actions.
But I understand it.
Like gets there.
It's always there.
I just don't let it out of the box and
that's why I got into fighting.
And that's why martial arts.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
It changed my life,
like having,
I think for every boy,
especially every boy that grew up,
I mean obviously,
um,
situations could have been way worse
than mine.
Mine wasn't the worst.
Nobody beat me.
I wasn't terrible in terms of like,
I didn't get abused,
but I saw it and I saw a lot of.
I saw plenty of violence,
so it's like I knew it was a thing and
if I grew up around it,
it would eventually started to affect
me.
And I would have been a part of it,
right,
for sure.
And the problem is you mirror that,
you know,
like the guys who grow up with dads who
beat their mom are way more likely to
beat their wives or their girlfriends or
you know,
or,
or maybe the opposite,
maybe just hate it so much because
you've seen it that you would never
allow it.
But,
but um,
I think for young men like having some
sort of a vent something martial arts
especially because you,
you could actually get out the violence
were you purge it from your system.
You don't have to think about it anymore
as giant.
Is it really because I have no idea what
it's like to be a man.
You know,
I don't,
I,
I think I do have a decent amount of
testosterone for a woman because I was a
tomboy when I was a little girl and I
was never into like dresses and stuff
like that when I was younger.
I never like envision like getting
married and having this huge wedding.
Those weren't my fantasies when I was a
kid,
you know?
And whenever it was Halloween,
I would dress up as a boy,
I would be like Count Dracula and my
sister would be a princess and I'd be
like the hulk.
So I've always been kind of like,
I've always gravitated towards a more
masculine even doing standup.
It's a very masculine thing to do.
And maybe that's why I tried gay dudes
too.
But anyway,
that's neither here nor there.
So is it like hard,
like are you guys constantly fighting
the urge to be violent?
Because I don't know.
No,
not
constantly.
This is how I looked at it.
This is kind of a weird way of looking
at it,
but this is the way I look at it.
I think that every man,
every man who has a functional endocrine
system was testosterone,
has been involved in sports who is
fairly athletic.
There's violence in your head.
So if your head was a house,
okay,
there's a room,
there's a violence room,
okay?
And you can open up that door there.
That door gets opened.
Crazy shit can happen.
Most of the time that door's closed,
but the more fucked up things that
happen in your life,
the more your house gets rocked,
the more your foundation gets fucked up,
the more your joy start to creak and
move left and right,
and things are off center and off plum.
Then that door opens way easier.
That door is leaking that doors like
there's gaps.
Like the framing is not so good.
Right?
Yeah.
The hinges are loose.
Right.
And so for someone who's been around a
lot of violence,
like people grew up in a neighborhoods,
been involved in gang violence,
that kind of shit.
That door is always ready to pop open.
It's just always ready to open.
Whereas someone who grew up,
like my friend todd,
like one of the nicest guys,
super sweet guy,
couldn't imagine a beating anybody up
because he was loved.
Like maybe even too much.
Like it's all love.
So his door is locked up tight.
He would need to get the key from his
mom.
He's gonna get in there.
Whereas I have other friends where they
fucking.
If you're brush up against that too
much.
Yeah.
Like Joey Diaz,
Joey Diaz,
if you,
if you knock on that door when he was
fucking punch you in that violence ready
to go and he doesn't do much,
but if it happens,
if the wrong thing happens,
that door comes swinging open,
you know,
we don't teach,
we don't teach kids how to deal with
their emotions properly.
And did you see that?
The Mr Rogers documentary?
No.
So there's only so many things you could
see.
Well you can take your kids to see this.
I'm in the middle of watching that wild
wild country.
Oh,
I've already seen that.
How good of cults.
Now it's a cult sex cults because I had
a course.
What the fuck's the point number called
get some pussy.
My coat would be a sex cult because
you're a girl.
What would you call me?
What was the last time a girl ran a
call?
By the way?
It might be the first.
Well,
that noble,
the chick who was,
she was kind of running that on her own.
That bitch has lost.
Okay.
Yeah,
I guess so.
But she was running stuff while she was
there because I do never left his room.
Yeah.
But Sheila was only empower because of
homeboy wasn't even Osho.
How do you say that?
That's what he was called after A.
Yeah.
I don't remember his name is.
That would without him and his.
He had to look.
You got to have that look.
You got to love the look of the holy
man.
That's crazy.
Beard and you have to drive around in
Bentleys,
Rolls Royces.
And that's what was crazy.
These luxurious cars.
Do you need.
Why do you need 22 of the same?
That's piss poor choices.
No,
I don't understand that at the time.
Mercedes,
what'd you say?
Try Mercedes or Rolls Royce.
It's something different.
It's very vicious.
And my question is like,
do these people,
when you,
when you're going into a cult,
do they know it's a cult or do they
think it's literally like a legit
religious organization that they're just
doing it.
They
think it's a legit movement,
you know,
like what is a cult,
right?
Because Christianity has often led by
scholars refer to as a cult.
You know,
like there's certain documentaries on
Christianity that refer to is a cult of
Christianity.
Like go what?
A cult is a group of people that follow
an ideology.
They follow a certain way in pattern of
being.
So these people are doing that exact
same thing until someone from like the
fucking FBI starts calling it a cult.
Like you don't
know what it is.
I got a red flag would be is if like,
because you know though is if your
leader is fucking,
you know,
like that to me is a red flag because if
you look at,
if you look at religious organizations
in general,
like the one thing that's frowned upon
and like all of them is like too much
sex or any sex really any type of like
promiscuity.
So like,
and that's a car I think across the
board with religions just in general.
None of them were like this is good.
They're like,
you should have sex to procreate.
And like that's it with the person that
you're married to.
But with that they were,
they were like this group sex.
Like I think we might be in the cult,
you know,
that's a huge red flag.
As soon as the dude starts fucking
everybody's watching and you're like,
wait a second,
how can we get so fucked?
My wife,
she's got a direct line to Jesus that
wouldn't trust that.
That is the thing though.
But that's the thing with men like men,
when they get into power,
anytime a man runs a giant organization,
has all these followers and he gets to
stand on to a stage out in a grassy
field filled with people,
bowing to him,
that guy's going to get his dick sucked.
Absolutely.
He's,
he's got beads on and everyone was like,
oh sure,
yes.
Come come at him.
You can drive rolls Royce number 17.
Come on for the ride.
So do you trust like Joel Osteen?
O'Steen a,
trust him.
How do you think he's like a man?
He tell me he's not trusting.
No,
just kidding.
I was like,
Oh shit guy.
Any money?
The rich as fuck.
I was like,
well this was this.
He had a kickstarter.
Well,
he is absolutely a.
because he's in that celebrity level.
He's on TV,
he's a.
he's a shyster,
thorough shysters.
Just that's what they are.
Dresses real nice.
He talks about Jesus and he gets people
excited and they give him their money.
They give him their money.
That's what he wants and he's got
fucking millions of getting panties
thrown at him.
Didn't get you just get divorced.
Did you get divorced?
Google.
That is probably good and some serious
God loving.
Oh yeah.
He's got a direct line to God.
Jesus said Jesus to blast from this.
Tell me what job said.
I'll tell you what show is that
blasphemous?
No,
it's like he's a leader.
You know what I mean?
That here's if it's long as it's
obvious,
like is a con bad?
If it's real obvious to his followers,
he is not a calm though to us.
It's like Duh.
But like you were talking about with the
colts when you're in it,
it's like,
I don't think they can see it,
but like Jim Baker,
like people that fall back,
but he's still around selling food for
people that scared the world's going to
end.
He sells buckets of food,
but Tammy Faye died.
She died,
she died.
Was Tammy Faye long suffering?
Tammy Faye.
She died from diet coke.
Diet coke did.
Are you serious?
That's what they think.
She drank too much to it all day.
Everyday.
That's stuff's addictive.
It is addictive.
There's something there.
There have been studies that have proven
that there's a.
whatever that artificial sweetener is
that they put in there.
Yeah,
they,
it's,
uh,
it causes you to Jesus.
Jesus and Jim Beggars Dick.
Both those things are addictive.
It's Jim Baker was like a perfect
example though.
If you're so fucking stupid,
you buy into that Guy Shit.
Remember,
lose all of it.
I don't remember him.
I remember them.
I remember growing up and watching like
sketches on mad tv or whatever,
where they will be making fun of him.
He's a guy that his hair slicked back.
He's another late night guy.
He would talk in tongues,
be on TV.
Oh,
the Lord is moving me to speech some
blah,
blah.
He would speak in tongues.
This is one thing you said.
I was listening to what?
I started fucking crying,
laughing.
He said,
every time you write a check to me,
Satan gets a black guy.
Now he does.
He say that every time you write a check
to me,
Satan gets a black eye.
That kinda shit laughed.
That shit should totally be legal.
You're so stupid.
You're like,
holy site.
Nah,
smite the you pull out your checkbook.
Gosh,
my new or fiction again.
A shanor.
There he is.
Look at him.
He's got to speak in tongues here.
Gave me this message.
I don't remember.
This guy have said they're hilarious.
He's hilarious man.
The devil last shit.
And they gave me this mess.
I'm say 10 the devil.
I shouldn't have said that.
That was just him.
He um,
he speaks in tongues and when he.
Is He really old looking though.
Was that him?
That him there,
Tom.
Such a cruel bitch.
Even Robert Tilden went down with all
his money,
but he's still alive.
Huh?
Probably.
But what do you wolfen he's old as fuck
now.
Oh,
Jesus.
I can't be the same guy.
Not Him.
It is him.
Go.
What happened then?
That video boy,
all the whiskey and pussy and coke.
Look at him.
He looks doing coke for Jesus.
No,
no,
no.
We done.
We wrapped.
We were gold underwear.
Ooh.
Someone trustworthy jumps in a private
jet.
15 hookers in there waiting for them so
it touches down to shoot the hookers.
You know too much.
Stop it.
Did they remix it?
Yeah,
it's a remix of him.
Why are they remix and stuff anymore?
I know,
right?
You remember that.
I was
just going to say they're not doing that
anymore.
That guy,
I met,
that guy,
he came to UFC.
Shut up.
Dave did.
Didn't get paid.
They made like a million dollars off.
That song.
Made some money.
He made some money and Dana white
brought them to a UFC.
Is this because he was gay?
Right?
And then then went to church and said he
wasn't gay anymore.
He was ashamed of being gay.
It was very sad because he was saying
that,
you know,
he was ashamed of being gay in,
the church was going to say we're going
to pray the gay away.
It's one of them deals.
So that's a.
That to me makes me so sad.
It does.
It's,
there's nothing wrong with being gay
and,
and this,
this idea that you could change someone
from being gay,
so fucking stupid.
It's like,
just be gay.
You're gay.
It's all right.
It's okay.
You just need better people around you
that tell you you're okay.
Yeah.
And that it's okay to just find other
gay people and you're like,
oh,
you're like me,
but good.
Yeah,
you're good.
You're fine.
You guys are going to be fun.
Oh,
you need to do is move to Atlanta or
anywhere else where the skilled people,
La and La,
you know,
find a gay can still be in the closet
out here too.
There's a lot of people in the closet on
here and I don't get it.
There's people in show business that I
know they're in the closet man,
that God damn closet.
You have a new fan base,
the fan base.
And then when you meet guys like todd
glass who didn't get it out of the
closet,
it was so much happier.
Now he's like,
it's just a giant burden.
Relieved,
relieved off my back.
Like,
yeah,
just be yourself man.
And you know,
plus it's,
the stigma is so it's,
it's bad for everybody.
It's bad for gay people.
It's bad for straight people because
it's even bad for people were homophobes
because they don't realize how many
people are really gay.
And if they did they would probably be
like,
maybe this is normal.
It is normal.
Yes.
Yeah,
it's the beginning of time.
It's no different than having blue eyes
or black hair or whatever the fuck.
Yes.
Trust me,
my dogs K is fuck yeah.
He looks at my other dogs Dick.
Every time my poor marshall,
every.
I'm throwing them under the bus.
Well Johnny cash my masters when he,
he'll,
he'll take a leak.
Marshall come over and lick his dick
right after it takes a little.
I'm like,
get the fuck away from his Dick,
man.
Stop doing that dude.
So depressing gets right up in there
instantly.
How many dogs do you have?
Three.
Two of them are on death's door though.
Very,
very old.
They're ready to go.
Do you recommend getting a dog?
I love dogs.
I love them too.
I just never,
not had a lot of work.
I know I've had dogs since I had enough
money to have dogs.
The moment when I moved to La and I had
a sitcom,
I'm like,
okay,
I'll pay my rent.
I'm getting a dog.
I love dogs.
I just want to make sure that I'd be
able to have like A.
I don't want to have to burden somebody
when I go out of town to the places we
can go that are really good to take care
of.
They'll even trained your dog white and
while they have them so bad you get a
dog girl.
You'll figure to have a dog.
He gonna get out of.
First of all,
when I came here you said,
I looked like I have a kid.
No,
I start.
You know,
I said it.
I think somebody brought it up.
Somebody said candice has a child.
I think someone said it was probably
some grow.
Hated on.
You probably know the bus.
Tennis as a kid at home.
Even know where I got it from.
Somebody brought in a dog cage.
That's why I asked.
You don't know who would be very good at
taking care of a dog.
What kind of dog would you get?
I like really small or really big like
and,
but my,
my place that I have,
I have a nice sized place but I still
would like to have property when I have,
if I have a big dog,
so I would probably want a smaller one
just for the sake of,
you know,
it's limited.
So I really,
um,
I really do like a pugs.
Are you friends with Whitney Cummings?
I'm not friends with her.
We've met,
but I,
I can't say we're friends and talked to
her about dogs.
She's got a shitload of them that
pitches a horse.
She got a horse.
Well wait,
what do you mean she has like that?
You know,
I get the horse part,
but you said she has a dog.
She goes,
no,
look,
she's,
she's very smart and I'll go to her.
Talked to her about dark questions.
She gave me what you're saying,
like how to deal with dogs.
Like you know what she said.
She goes,
she goes,
first of all,
she talks to you like that.
She was,
first of all,
I'm in charge of my house.
She goes,
I don't walk around my dogs.
I walk through them.
She was like,
I'm the Alpha.
She goes,
they don't get to get on top of me.
They don't climb on top of me.
They don't kiss my face.
She goes,
I'm in my bed.
Yeah.
You don't have to have that,
you know.
But I know so many people think I'm
weird because I wouldn't want my dog and
my bags.
Whitney's dogs.
She loves pits.
She does.
That's adorable.
That's a cute little tiny one too.
What does that little one?
What is that?
Hold on.
Oh,
little bulldog.
Yeah.
I like,
I like bulldogs.
I like French bulldogs.
Um,
but I'm also one of those ones that like
those little tiny ones that probably
annoy you.
I like little dogs to you and like your
keys.
I like 'em.
I like Pomeranians,
like dogs in general.
Only dogs I feel bad for.
Or those bulldogs with those fat faces
that can't walk and they can't breathe.
Pugs are like that too.
They have nasal problems.
They're so cute.
The fuck.
Did you do this?
Yeah.
They looked like I got punched in the
face,
but they're so cute.
It's depressing.
It's from all the breeding,
right?
Isn't that how they got like.
Yeah.
Well they've made them that way on
purpose because they want their face to
be flattened out.
So they've bred to that characteristic,
Huh?
Yeah.
Good dog.
Get them in Kansas and I'm not getting
both.
No more realistic for me than getting a
band.
Get a dog and then you have a man and
you go,
well this is one.
Too many things are going to kill.
This dog would kill the man
for 100 percent.
Alright.
Qantas,
we're going to wrap this up.
Anything else to say to the people their
first introduction to you?
I'm on my first introduction.
I think this one wheel well.
We're getting to know one another and
talked about doing this for awhile.
I'm glad we finally did it.
We did make it happen.
Now you're going to come and do my
podcast in Kansas.
When you're at the comedy store,
when are you on the tour?
When?
Where can people go see you just go to
Qantas Thompson comedy.com.
I'll put a post on my dates.
If you're going to do jfl this year in
Montreal,
it's going to be in Canada.
Believe on the 26th of July.
Twenty six,
27,
28.
Are you doing the gala,
the gala?
Oh No.
I don't think I am the TV thing that
they do.
The giant.
Yeah.
No,
I don't.
It's very big in Montreal.
Yeah.
No,
I don't think Chappelle on tennis Canada
stops in comedy.
That calm and jokes by candice on
twitter and Instagram.
All right,
candice.
Thank you.
We did it.
Yay.
Thanks for again.
My pleasure.
Hmm.