Hello Freak bitches were back.
This episode is brought to you by ting.
Ting is the official cell phone provider
for the Jews and his name is boss.
You guys. Uh, Ting is a cell phone
provider. I've got one right here.
This is the thing phone.
This is my Samsung Galaxy
note five. It's pretty dope.
Uh, I liked the fingerprint
thing. It's pretty sweet.
The fingerprint thing is sweet and um,
the fact that it's waterproof is
pretty sweet too. Um, what it is,
is with ting uses is the sprint backbone.
These a sprint network,
but they do it their way with no
contracts, no early termination fees,
no ride alongs or bundling and no,
no bullshit that you
ordinarily have to deal with.
If you deal with most
cell phone providers,
most cell phone providers also have
their billing setup for what they say.
If you have a hundred minutes a month,
but you only use like 10,
which is by the way,
what you probably use,
most people don't fucking
call anybody anymore.
You call someone for 10 minutes a month,
you're a Weirdo unless
you're doing business.
My understanding if you're doing
business. Um, but the point is with Ting,
you only pay for what you use.
They used to have it so that like they
would credit you and your next bill and
knock money off your next
bill if you didn't hit them,
they're ordered a hundred
minutes but you only used 80.
They would credit you that in your
next bill. But then they realize like,
why are we doing that? Why don't we
just charge you for what you use?
Like that's the most logical way to do it.
And that's how Tim does it now.
So I think every cell phone companies
are going to be forced to do it that way.
Cause that's what it should be.
If you use more, you pay more.
But if you're like a heavy data user,
especially ting is an awesome way to go.
Ting uh,
actually just dropped their rates because
of their second year anniversary for
no reason other than they got a better
deal and they said, fuck it man.
We're going to continue this path of
being an ethical cell phone company with,
which is a good idea. The good
ideas, like to not fuck people over,
give them something that's a good service
that you can get at a good rate and
uh, you feel good about the
transaction, whereas, you know,
you get those overage fees or you get
some fucking early termination fee and
it's like hundreds of dollars
and you're like, fuck off man.
You feel robbed while Tane has it set up
so you don't do anything like that. Um,
98% of people would save money with
Tang and that's because they do mobile
differently. The average monthly
bill per device for tin customers,
it's $21. That's a, that's
a pretty fucking cheap.
And if you go to rogan.ting.com you will
save $25 off of any of their devices.
They have a wide range of a cell phones,
including a iPhone fives and all the
greatest and latest of the android models,
including the LG nexus five,
the Samsung Galaxy s five,
which is what I got right here.
And the Samsung Galaxy note three.
If you just can't have it big enough.
rogan.ting.com save yourself 25 bucks.
We're also brought to you by audible.
If you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you can get a free audio book from
the number one provider of audio
entertainment on the Internet.
Audible has been around for a long fucking
time and I've always been a big fan
of audio books. It makes
it so much easier. And um,
if you have this Amazon kindle
fire HD, Amazon has this, um,
it's one of their, it's their version of
um, you know, like a tablet, like a, a,
a galaxy tablet. And wait, if
you get one of those from Amazon,
the kindle fire HD and you get
this thing called whisper sync,
it's fucking crazy. You read the book. So
if you're at home, you're sitting in bed,
you read the book,
and then when you get to a certain page,
it syncs up with the audible
version of it in your car.
So you get in your car and then you
listen to the audio version of the book.
So it's like it keeps going for you.
It's like you read when you can and
then they'll read it to you in between,
which I think is pretty fucking awesome.
And if you want a free audio book,
you can pick from over 150,000 titles,
including life of the party by our pal
Bert Kreischer actually read by Bert
Kreischer and cool.
You can get that shit for free if you
go to audible.com forward slash Joe, uh,
can't say enough good things
about audible. Like I said,
they've been around a long time and they
have over 150,000 books to choose from,
including radio shows, podcasts, comedy
specials, they have all kinds of shit.
They have the opiate Anthony show.
Um, that's not even Anthony anymore.
That's Bert Kreischer think we're violent
and crappy way by planting them in the
guy though. Anyway, audible.com
forward slash Joe go there,
my friends and get yourself a free
audio book and one free month of audible
service. That's right.
Sweet bitches. Amazing.
Also were brought to
you by on at.com and we,
right now it is September 3rd and
it is a 3:00 PM west coast time,
which means there's one day,
20 hours and 58 minutes and six seconds,
uh, to go with the 72 hour sale,
72 hour sale, 15% off everything.
You use the code CEP seven two,
it's like the short for September and
then 72 for the amount of hours in the
sale. Uh, if you hear this after that,
then just use the codeword Rogan and
you could save 10% of any and all
supplements, but it doesn't
work on everything. This
code is 15% code right now.
Works on everything, but on it is
as a human optimization website.
That's what we decided to call a website
where we sell shit that does good
things for you.
Whether it's get you in shape,
whether it's a give you healthy snack
options like the hemp force protein bar,
super healthy, very delicious,
very good for you. Hemp,
very easy to digest. One of the
easiest proteins to digest. Uh,
we have hemp force powder
and that hemp force powders,
the finest protein powder we could
buy, the most expensive stuff. It's a,
all of it comes from Canada
because the United States is,
I'm a fucking crazy place that will be
mocked in the and the future when they
look back at the marijuana laws and
how preposterous they were and how they
affected its cousin.
It's non psychoactive cousin
hemp and that's what hemp is.
I mean it's not the version of
marijuana that you use to get high.
It's a non get you high plant and it's
still illegal because it's related to the
get you high plant.
It's the male version of the species.
The female version of the species
has the um, the buds which you, uh,
you get your THC from. Uh,
to answer your questions,
cause I know a lot of
people have questions about
protein powders that involve
hamp or any products and involve him.
You cannot test positive.
If you have a job that tests you, they
make you pee in a cup. First of all,
if you do have a job like that,
strategize your way to get the
fuck out of that fucking jail.
Some Dick Wad doesn't let you take a
hit off a joint on your weekend cause
they're worried about you
losing productivity for your
fucking slave job and on
Monday, fuck them. Set your
phone down. That's fair
enough. Um, no, just answer it.
Start calling people shit. Fuck.
Oh, I want to do this show.
Um, anyway, uh, hemp force.
You can a, you can only,
you can only test positive if you smoke
weed while you're eating hemp force.
But um,
I should tell you that if you eat bagels
that have like poppy seeds on them or
anything with poppy seeds,
you test positive for heroin.
As crazy as that sounds.
But it is absolutely true.
If you're going in for a heroin
test or any sort of a drug test,
if you eat poppy seeds, you will test
positive for heroin. It's very strange.
It doesn't happen with hemp.
Go to [inaudible] Dot Com oh Anne and
I t and browse our lovely selection of
strength and conditioning equipment
as well as food supplements.
All that good shit and use
the code were rogue Rogan.
You'll save 10% off all supplements.
And uh,
as of today at three Oh four,
Wednesday, September 3rd,
there is one hour, but one day, 20 hours,
56 minutes and 46 seconds to use the code,
worst step seven to to save 15% off
everything that's on it.com o n n I t and
the o desk squad.
Dot TV for all the new cats that Brian
has put together on hats and cats and
hats and tee shirts and all
kinds of different shit.
The Brian has a full fucking selection
of all artwork that he's created.
By the way, if you see all of this stuff
and uh, you, you buy into these things,
you're absolutely supporting the artist
himself because Brian created all these.
He put it together and he used our friends
at Squarespace to design this website
and to, uh, sell it all,
which has been a pleasure.
It's the best website creator ever.
I mean for the money.
Anyone that went to the website and
totally use it. There you go. Squarespace.
She got a free plug. No, no, you
are. I'm 100% supportive view.
I'd love Squarespace. Uh, and
uh, anyway. Desk squad. Dot.
TV or shop squad. What does
it shop? squad.com. Dot.
TV shots shop squad.tv,
which is a link that you can get to
directly from death squad dot. TV.
But Death Squad TV, we'll have
not just this, but the, um,
all the addresses and times for the
comedy podcasts like killed Tony,
which I did with my brother Don.
My rarer what a time we had,
what a time that I left. It was a
very fun time. All that information,
all the different shows that
Brian promotes as well as
his gigs that he's doing
on the road.
All of it is available@deathsquad.tv.
And then shop squad.tv if you want to
just cut to the chase and start spending
shekels. All right, that's it
folks. The Po me, what am I doing?
I got um, September something or
another. I'm in fucking Toronto.
Let me find this, cause I didn't
have it in front of me, but uh,
we do a messy little Joe. I
am doing the Sony Center. Uh,
I liked Massey Hall but
it was already booked,
but I did the Sony Center before
too, is pretty fucking dope. Yeah.
Sony Center for the Performing Arts with
Tony Hinchcliffe. Friday, September 26.
Jody rose, who was supposed to
be here tomorrow, but he had to,
he got an acting gig. The kids got
talent. You can hold them back.
So Tony has taken his place and Joe
Derosa we'll be here next Wednesday. Uh,
in the future I have Rupert Sheldrake
and Graham Hancock are going to be coming
up. Uh, I got a lot of good
guests. Real solid guests.
Mike Dolce is going to be here
next week. Uh, like I said,
Jodie Ross will be here next week. All
right, that's it. Boom. Schelok lock.
Boom Saga. Oh, ice house. Ice House.
I'm going to be at the Ice House in
Pasadena September 12th and 13th.
What does that like the weekend after
this one with Tony Hinchcliffe. All right,
that's it.
Cube's music dominant areas here.
Dominic, me, brother, a
little Joe for fuck sake.
Look at you sitting up there and they
asked me if I was David Letterman and it
will actually tell
everybody about this chair.
This is my latest device to try to
mitigate back pain from sitting.
And it's called the uh, I think
it's called a Sally. Yeah. S a l. L.
I and it's a saddle chair.
It's like a saddle.
So if you see how it's sitting
here. No, no one's endorsing this.
I'm just telling you it feels,
I'm going to tell you this.
They would hate me endorsing
this cause it feels like shit.
It's like the least comfortable
chair I think I've ever sat.
But it's very good for your back
and makes sure that you like,
you can't sit any way
other than like this.
Like you have to sit like straight up.
You can't like slouch in this
thing just doesn't support it.
And when I sit in a regular chair,
by the end of the podcast,
my fucking neck starts
to hurt like my back,
like around here where I've
been injured starts to hurt.
What that like stretch your
asshole out though and like give,
that's what I'm trying to do is kind of
easier for if I ever do wind up going in
the pokey. I want to be
just gaping soon. Um, no,
it doesn't do anything in your asshole.
You fucking idiot. You're sitting now.
It's like your bubble. I know.
I'm certainly easy. No, this
is, you're not listening.
The whole idea behind this is it's
like a saddle. If you sit in a salary,
you actually kind of have
to hold yourself in place.
So by squeezing your legs together,
it's not opening your butthole.
You're actually squeezing
everything tight.
So if you were a Gao and you
wanted to have one of these,
I figured it would probably
be good for the ova.
Jj probably tighten that baby up.
Like women are supposed to like do those
key Glenn not supposed to. Supposed to.
If they care about treaty,
a penis correctly with their vagina,
they do those Kegel exercises where you
squeeze your vagina and you can actually
make it stronger.
There's some crazy bitch and Russia that's
like the world record holder for the
amount of weight she can
carry with her pussy.
But it's something
substantial like 50 pounds.
So she shoves a Dildo in her pussy,
attaches it to a fucking kettle bell
and a and does squats holding this,
this Dildo in her,
in her box just with our shield
puts him like grabbing it like that.
Is anybody else getting hungry? Yeah.
I don't know why I'm getting peckish.
Did you ever hear a
honeysuckle divine? Yes. Yeah.
He's the one that used to shoot ping pong
balls and needed a tuna fish sandwich
with no, where was that at?
Where did she do? She did it.
The truck or their own Philadelphia cause
it was like when we were kids it was
like this big joke about how
many circled the one. But uh,
I was up at the rib and they were
shooting a porn and you know,
these porn girls need so much attention.
Obviously they didn't have anything else
to do and there's no more conversation.
So one girl sits in a Bush,
it goes do your trick. You
know the, the, the container.
There's the gores put in jams at
dinner and she's just pops it out.
But she paid, she hit the girl
too hard. It was so funny.
Girls faces there and you go boom,
it's getting the girl goes, fuck, ah,
big red mark on her face.
And she explained that she could shoot it
out of her pussy. So hard. It hurt. Yeah.
Did you see that fucking
Mantis shrimp that I posted
on my, uh, my uh, my
Twitter page yesterday? No,
you got to see this.
This is the craziest fucking animal
I have ever heard in my life.
If you scroll down, a guy named
Mike Jackson, Esquire, the truth,
Jackson on Twitter sent
this shit to me and it's a,
a murder mantis shrimp.
It's a shrimp that has a builtin weapon.
It's not actually a shrimp.
It's like they explain what it is.
It has a builtin weapon.
Like it has this thing where it's
bodies like got a spring inside of it.
It's got two hammers and it shoots to
hammers out and slams on the like crabs
and killed them and breaks their shells.
Open breaks, open clams and crabs.
It is the wild is looking at the,
in the ocean somewhere. It's called,
they call it the mantis murder shrimp
and they have a video in slow motion
explaining how this shrimp, I never, I
never heard of it either until yesterday.
This guy, uh, who was explaining it, we
should give these guys a youtube page.
Whatever it is, is that him smarter
every day, smarter every day.
That's called mantis murder.
Shrimps Watch, scroll.
Scroll it back just a little bit before,
right where you were just a
little bit there and it show you.
Watch how this thing does.
Turn the volume up.
Watch how it comes out.
It wax this crab and fucking kills it.
Fucking knocked it out.
Watch this. Look at this. Isn't that nuts?
It's got two hammers on the
end of its clause. That's cool.
I never do anything like this exist.
Cool.
How could that be kept almost
all these years, these years,
there's so many animals. Look at
the crab is smashed, it crashed,
crush the shell of the,
the crab.
It's crazy if that thing has been there
and the ocean is whole time and we never
heard about it until 2014 is too
many things to pay attention to.
What I had come here to this podcast to
learn about shrimps that fuck people up
or fuck things up. Um, yeah.
It's not an actually a shrimp.
It's like something else.
They call it a here. I'll,
I'll Google it and find out what
the fuck it actually is. But uh,
incredible with this is that you're just
finding out about boxing gloves almost.
Yeah. Like hammers,
right? Yeah. Look at that.
So the whole goal of the podcast
is smarter every day or the uh,
the show smarter everyday. It's
a really well done show too. Wow.
They did a great job of explaining the
mechanism that this thing has inside of
its body.
It's essentially like a spring.
It pulls this thing back and that
it holds it in place and wait.
It's like locked and then when it gets
close to things it just releases it.
Blanches not a hundred. It has to hit
you because it's underwater. Yeah,
that's right. Close it them and
deep underwater too. You know,
it's not like it's on the surface. You're
dealing with a lot of pressure. Amazing.
Really amazing stuff. The world. Dominic.
A jealous that I forget something else.
The last time we worked together we did
kill Tony at the ice house cause I still
don't go to the comedy store, but the Ice
House, a version of kill Tony, you and I,
I that was more fun than I've had
doing a like a podcast and a long time.
That was really fucking fun
and we were crying lists. So
silly, so silly. The, the,
the, the premise behind kill
Tony folks who don't know,
it's a Tony Hinchcliffe and Brian red
band have this podcast where they do,
everybody does like a minute,
like you have new comics that go up
and do a minute and they have these two
girls were their names again, Sarah
wine shank. Then Kimberly condom.
Very funny gals who do a free,
not a free,
a new rather minute every week,
which if you've ever done
standup before, it's hard. Yeah.
It sounds like a new man.
It's easy, but you know,
they don't get a chance to really
develop it just every week.
They do and do minute and they've
done that since the very beginning.
So their entire standup
career has essentially been
just doing stand up on the
internet in front of everybody that takes
balls. It does. But I was a little mean,
I thought, but I was just
having fun. Yeah. I had to be,
if you've got to go for the jug,
you'll uh, go for the juggler.
I love guys that had a minute and they
came up like with 35 seconds. Yeah.
They couldn't fill a minute and were
like, okay, are you guys from like,
well if you stare at your mirror
and you practice for a minute,
it's most likely not really going to
be a minute when you're up to cause you
gotta be panicking.
You'd be talking faster or do
you ever get nervous anymore?
Ask me that. Yeah, I got nervous
for a film my special in Denver. Uh,
definitely a kid. Yeah, I got a little
eh. Yeah. Cause I was probably good work.
So hard for it. Yeah. It worked
out great, but it was just,
it was so much a preparation for it.
I definitely felt more
intense than a regular show.
Not like you're big and uh, yeah.
I did it a small place though.
Did it at the comedy works well that's
where I'm going this week. This month.
Love that place. I did. He'd do
a good downtown or to the cruise.
She downtown the cruise ship. That's
it. It's like the other place.
Why do you say it's like you're just
like a giant cause it all, it has,
everything has like movie theaters,
restaurants and it's all in one little
block. Oh, I see what you're saying. Yeah.
Downtown is like funkier.
Yeah.
Well downtown's smaller too and it's
like you're stuffed into that really cool
room. That room is special in event.
Well, yeah. Yeah, yeah. That's good idea.
It was fun. I think it's better than
a theater. I think so too. Well, my,
my thought process behind it
was that when you're at home,
you're in your living room, your
living room, it's very intimate.
You're sitting down or you know,
maybe your downloaded on your computer
or you're in your office. But either way,
you're,
you're in a small environment usually,
and you're sitting there watching like
some guy on stage in front of thousands
of people. It doesn't feel, I mean
it's still a good show. Like you can,
you can enjoy it, but you don't feel
like you're there. No, but I watched, um,
I've seen a couple of people doing,
like Sarah Silverman had
once she did it Largo and uh,
I didn't watch too much of it, but I was
like, wow, that feels good. Like that.
She's all in tight like that. It feels
good. Like to watch a show where you're,
you know, you're kind of like
right there. So I decided to do it.
I think it's good.
I had this discussion to be a name dropper
with tosh and with Seinfeld and both
of them think theaters are better. And I
just disagree. And even for Tasha. Zach,
I think he's better in a
club. And so I thought, I,
why can't I just sit on my hands? I'm
looking at people, sit on their hands,
listen to me for an hour and a half
because a lot of these people, you know,
it's like I said,
because I'd rather people be drinking.
I'd rather them be a little
distracted and having fun. Right.
Then focus like it's theater.
Yeah.
There's definitely a difference in the
kind of show that you can do to like,
you can't like bang, Bang, Bang, Hammer.
I'm in a theater because the laugh that
you got to wait for it to roll. Oh,
fucks over the punchlines. I went
to see Louis Black Mean Joey. Uh,
we were staying at this place in Jersey
and we were doing the theater the next
day.
He was doing it on Thursday.
We were doing our Friday and we went
in to watch and I was like, wow.
Like when a guy's on stage,
um,
doing like telling jokes
when people start laughing,
you don't hear anything else he says
until that laughter stopped. Yeah.
And I never realized that because
obviously you're on stage,
you have the microphone,
get the monitors broadcast in your face.
So you hear yourself very loud and clear.
But the audience,
they don't hear you very good when people
are laughing. It's real weird to share.
And then we be,
it's Madison Square Garden and places
like that and you really had to wait for
the wave to come by because otherwise
you ready, you're talking over yourself,
you're talking over the left.
Yeah,
you talk over the laugh and
you kill all the taglines.
Anything after the punch line,
which you know,
but some of those taglines like they have
to be done very quickly on in a comedy
club,
but for it to work.
So there's a totally different kind of
timing in a theater that like a joke
won't work as well in some ways because
like sometimes you say something and
then he'd say something else and you say
something, he'd say something out like,
like those, like everybody's laughing at
the first thing. Then the second thing,
like in a theater, you have to say
it, say it. You know there's a,
there's a big pause and that timing
gets funky. Totally different. Yeah.
I'd much rather do a
club. Yeah, it's the best.
It's just you can't make as much
money and that's the difference.
But there's something to like some
clubs or some theaters like uh,
like Massey Hall, we were talking about
Toronto Massey halls. Fucking phenomenal.
Even though it's 3000 plus people,
it's still phenomenal.
It's like it's the right size.
For some reason,
I was there when night we had Jason
Alexander Spf want to do an Improv.
At the end of the show we had to follow
Robert Schimmel talking about cancer and
killing. He was fucking killing.
I said to Jason, I said, Shit,
molds kill and talking about cancer.
What the fuck are we going to do?
Fly around the room.
Yeah.
He had a whole series
like after he almost died,
I saw him in Tempe and he,
he had all this material
about almost dying.
You know about like he would bring up.
Brilliant.
Do you have to be to make that
funny? He's honest as fuck, man.
That guy was honest as fuck. He was such
a sweet guy too. I ran into him, uh,
after all the cancer stuff, you know, he,
he'd survived it and piece really skinny.
I ran into him at um,
uh, Barnes and noble man,
just randomly and he's so warm,
so friendly.
That really fucking bum me out.
That bummed me out.
The Robin Williams thing really
bummed me out recently and Richard,
Jenny really bummed me out. Those
are, those are the big three.
I didn't see it come
on with Robert at all.
I mean he was supposed to do my podcast
now and I was just going to call him the
silver.
It had a life work today,
well around this week because
what happened was I didn't
call him because I knew
he was upset about the series
not getting picked up and he had,
he had to go back home. These kids
are going to school or whatever,
something was going on in his life.
I said, letting me leave him alone.
I'll call him next week. There
wasn't an next week. Fuck yeah.
And I had to go on CNN and I
fucking hated it because it just,
it just find out a buddy who was dies
and they want to talk about suicide and
hell, he did it. And brain chemistry.
I said, look, I, I'm sad right now.
I don't want to really,
I want to go into this a chemical bullshit
and theory about why can we give them
a moment. Yeah. Dana
Gould wrote a piece for,
I think it was for rolling
stone that, uh, I also, uh,
tweeted yesterday,
let me find it here,
but it is pretty detailed
piece about, um, why
so many comedians are depressed and I
thought brain's behaving badly. Yeah.
It's for rolling stone.
And Dana who is not just a funny,
really funny comic I've known
forever, but very bright guy, very,
very insightful. And
uh, he wrote this, uh,
interesting thing after the whole
Robin Williams thing, you know,
he said something so funny to me.
Uh, we were at the left factory,
I did this bit about mother and daughter
Exchange Club lesbians taking care of
her younger girls sexually.
Right. And vice versa. And I,
there was two lesbians there.
I said, yeah. Did you ever
see it? One of the women?
Yeah, yeah, I've seen, I set a time,
ain't it? It's perverted. And so, and I,
I say something about Dana,
you know,
being married and I get them and they
sit down with him because he's done.
I'm like, guys, I'm, I read 12
years. Of course I fucking seen,
that's one of my favorites.
Dan is a funny guy, man.
The thing about the Robin and
also about rich Jenny that I, uh,
it's not in my wheelhouse
is the depression thing.
Both those guys suffer from
pretty severe depression.
And the more people we talked to,
we had Carrie Santa Maria on last week
who was a friend of ours. He's very,
very smart, very brilliant woman,
and also a neuroscientist. So,
you know,
she's not talking out of her ass when
she explains what's going on in the human
brain. It's just a fucking
disease, man. It's a disease.
And anybody that doesn't have it that
talks out of their ass, you know,
like fucking what's his face?
Henry Rollins said that it was like week
that he killed himself because he had
kids. Not that these people, you know, I,
I see that they want to take a stand
because they find it offensive that Pete
people would be in their eyes what they
would consider so selfish that they
committed suicide. But I think in
talking to people that have had it,
I think it's pretty safe to assume
they're telling you the truth,
that they can't do it. They can't keep
going. Like these motherfuckers when,
when they don't get help, when they don't
get some sort of a chemical help or,
you know, whatever, whatever
it needs to be done,
whether it's at some sort
of a mental imbalance,
whether it can be mitigated
with exercise or diet,
but whatever that state they're in, when
they hit the bottom, they can't go on.
Man. It's, I don't, I don't understand it.
I don't have it. I don't get depressed.
Yeah. I get it to you in
the morning. Yeah. Uh,
then it kind of worked my way out
of it. Uh, the jerky way out of it.
Your to put way up and I stay
in little things in my house.
I come here, come here kitty. Uh,
you hit a bell with Jenny. It
could see something coming. Jenny.
Like he was like,
Richard is always very neat.
It was all disheveled last time I saw him
and Eleanor is such, you saw him at a,
uh, like a supermarket. He
was knocking over things in
the shelves. It was like, oh.
So the drugs were fucking him up.
What drugs was young?
Somebody anti psychotic drugs and he
was supposed to change the prescription
that week. You know, I don't know which
stories are true but Robin, that the
big difference was there was no
indication. Well apparently not.
But Mark Gordon,
who's a,
this God is doctor that have had on the
podcast before sent me this piece that
he's working on,
on the high instances of a suicide in
relationship to a operations and that
people need to, yeah,
that's what over and said.
He was saying that they need to accept
that there's an issue going on with
people's hormonal balances that get
thrown out of whack by a pretty severe
operation like heart surgery.
And he cited the instances of a
hypothyroidism that can be caused by it.
And then the pituitary gland function,
uh,
especially being under for a long
time when they do like those, uh,
like what Joan Rivers just had done,
they put her under for a long time and
now she's still in like critical care.
She's gonna me. Yeah. Yeah. She's
fucked apparently. When you, um,
when you, uh, get put under
for like long periods of time,
they do something like open heart surgery,
which they did with Robin.
It can be really tricky,
like when you come out of it,
like it's like some pretty severe
depression occurs in a lot of people.
So if he didn't, if people didn't see
it coming before you got that factor,
you also have the drug factor that he,
he recently checked himself back into
Rehab again. He said it was no reason to,
it was just like reaffirming
his commitment to sobriety.
But that sounds like some PR, right.
People's idea of what to say for me. Yeah.
Don't tell him, don't tell him you
really fucked up again. Yeah. I mean,
he didn't get, he didn't get caught
drunk driving or anything like that.
Whatever it is,
he decided to check himself and again,
and so there's all those things.
And you know,
he also had a lot of debt, you
know, you know what? A lot of money,
but he was very wealthy still.
I talked to his agent who's a
friend of mine and she was saying,
don't let all these people tell you that
he, um, he owed more money than he had.
He had plenty of money.
He just has this like $30
million house in Napa.
He say she say like a 600 acre estate,
like has some crazy fucking park
essentially in Napa and it's, you know,
$30 million. So, but she said he's
still, he was still rich when he died.
Then you can't say it was that. It was,
um, you know, when someone owes money,
like they have a mortgage, it's not you,
it's not like you can't pay that money.
It's just more strategic.
Like as far as like how much
interest you can earn on your money.
It's smarter in a lot of cases to like
keep paying it off like as a mortgage
than it is just spend the, you
know, whatever he owed on it.
Like it was 20 million bucks
or something like that.
Take the $20 million out of his money.
But she's like,
he could have done that if you want it to.
So it wasn't like he was in broke at all,
but a lot of people thought
that had that had an issue too.
Just the fact that he's the failed
relationships is depressing. And you know,
I know his first wife very well,
but you know the thing about him
when he won the Academy Award,
I'll never forget it because it was
liquid Jamie Foxx when I go, wow,
we beat the grownups. You
know what I mean? It's like
because like they would have ever takes,
I mean they were both series parts but
nobody ever takes comedian seriously for
Academy Awards and Mike
Meyers in Austin Powers.
To me it was Academy
Award winning performance.
I really believe that at that level
because it was funny to me is anything,
but anyway,
Robin was so fucking talented I think
about that was a very talented actor man.
That movie a one hour
photo and you ever see that
creepy fucking movie man? People
saw that one. Yeah it was a no,
it was more of an independent.
That was one of the things that he was
talking about why he wound up doing that
television show.
It was because it was an independent film
situation where he was like constantly
getting these offers to do these films
and they barely even had funding and if
they pay they paid scale and they were
interested was interesting jobs but he
was like the, the big movies had kind
of dried up for him for whatever reason.
Like sometimes guys will,
those movie star guys will
go on these peaks and vowels.
Definitely like Kevin Costner and
he started doing movies recently,
but I remember after waterworld,
it's like a long fucking time before
anybody put that guy on a big movie again.
Did you actually see Robin's new show?
Uh,
unfortunately I watched a few
episodes of it and I understand why.
I think it didn't work. It just
seemed very, very cheesy and I'm,
maybe that might've been one of Robin's
things that because he was still playing
a character that never really
progressed in a way like,
Yep.
So catch up on Seinfeld and there was a,
what do you mean by a character
that never really progressed?
Because [inaudible] if you ever see Robin
Williams like on the tonight show or
any of those shows, he, he always does the
same act where it's very frenetic. Yeah.
Very crazy and very like,
you almost can guess what he's
about to do next, you know?
And to me it was,
I loved it,
but I also thought that when it was
converted into a show was pretty flexible
too much. It was just like, all
right, this is so unrealistic.
Do that when he was on more commending.
Right? Yeah, that's what I'm saying now.
It's kind of like, well, the
difference is he's 60 now.
Yeah.
That was 30 years ago.
Can't be a 30 you could be a 30
year old guy and be like, oh fuck,
I'm craze craze are [inaudible]
I'm from another planet.
But when you're 60 you know,
it's kind of like Jim Carrey doesn't
do Jim Carrey in as much anymore.
Like Ace Ventura. Yeah. Like if he was
still doing ace Ventura, then you know,
then you made it a sick home with a
laugh track. It's like, oh, the loop
man on the moon when he did a, is that,
what is it called? The uh, yeah, yeah,
we did the Andy Kaufman. Yeah.
Like that was a great performance.
That was an Oscar worthy performance.
I mean,
he really nailed Andy
Kaufman and was really,
he really was Andy Kaufman's Rosie.
He did a great job.
But like when he does
the ace Ventura stuff,
you can't really do that when you're
50 years old or whatever it is.
It's probably like 50 right,
right. You can't really do that.
Nobody wants to see you get out
of breath. Prat falls. Well,
didn't Chevy chase like fuck
himself up from pratfalls?
Gerald Ford,
he used to Ford falling all the time.
He was the president at the time because
it's got in Chevy chase was only on for
I think one year. Really. Then Benny
and it became that famous over that,
that one year where he was the first star.
Yeah. From Saturday night live. Right?
Yeah.
Huh.
But apparently all those pratfalls
we're really a, well, I've heard that.
I heard that about the three stooges to
those guys were like punchy towards the
end of their career because they would
smacking each other so much, you know, uh,
getting hit with shit. What's it?
What's it guys? They'd from Jackass.
A steevo. No, and that's
the way Johnny, I saw him,
I seen him at the gym sometime. Right. We
were talking, I said, it's really cool.
You know,
you guys are trained and stuntmen stuff
because we don't know a fucking thing.
This is where just a bunch of assholes.
I started that. I didn't know that.
I thought they knew what they were
doing. Their fucking crazy. Yeah.
That's not a smart thing to do what
they're doing and alligator's biting your
balls. No, they got lucky.
They got lucky that no one ever died
doing that show and then one guy died.
They're getting lucky still.
They're doing it still.
Like they're still filming
stuff together and doing like,
I hate think they might even
be doing another jackass.
What happened with Steven when he
painted that sign near seaworld?
Seaworld socks. He climbed
up, fell a bunch of times.
She want to watch it online.
I mean, I don't know if he
fell on purpose. He's just
just being a silly goose.
The way climbs assign climbs a sign,
it falls from like fucking 30 feet up and
lands on the ground and socio survives
to visit and to see him do
stand up. No, it's bizarre.
Yeah. Well he does like
tell stories, right? Yeah.
But he also like did some physical stuff.
He tries to fall and stuff.
That's what I saw with the live factory.
I don't know if that's
part of his real act,
but some of it involves fire depending
on the comedy club, you know,
and in the fire fight, fire licenses.
He does a lot of different acts.
Like he grew up, I've Ringling brothers
Barney, he graduated from their college,
so he used to be in the circus. A lot
of his shit's like, so he was Lisa.
You imagine if you have
a fucking business.
It worked real hard to put together
a comedy club. You hire waitstaff,
you get everything. We're up and
running and steevo comes to town.
He asked you if he could do fire on
stage and you see your life falling apart
for one fucking Thursday, November
and you're like, no, no fire dude,
no fire. And then he's got the fire.
Anyway, like I wrote it, I wrote it.
I mean cause a fire big.
Yeah.
One day that's not going to work.
One day something's going to go bad doing
fucking getting hit by bowls and get
launched into the air with a blindfold on.
You see that?
This was after Johnny
Knoxville was a movie star.
He was already in movies with the Rock.
Remember he did that movie with the
rock after that puts a blindfold on and
let's, I'll fucking bull launch
him into the air. Unbelievable.
And flips like head over heels,
like can easily land on his neck and
these guys expend so much energy.
There are very mild. I you talk to them,
it very low key. Jim Carrey's like that.
Jim Carrey, he's like, you know,
he's the wacky guy and then these are
you ever talked to him is he's so like
mellow and down there
it's like Steve Martin,
he's almost shy and doesn't really like
to even talk to people. Right. He was,
yeah, he was such a Dick to me. Uh, I was
doing see was. Yeah. He's like, I mean,
you know,
I was doing this thing for comedy central
where I'll be for the awards shows.
We would interview people and everybody
was nice. Jerry Lewis, Garry Shandling,
all these guys, Steve Martin just,
we asked him if we could interview.
He said yeah, and then he wouldn't,
he wouldn't give me one word answers.
And your surreal smug.
I'm picking your fucking
career was predicated by
putting an Arrow three ahead.
Don't don't act so slick with me.
Why is he acting slick with
clumpy? Don't do the interview if
you're going to be like that. Yeah,
that's too bad. That's too bad. I, I think
he was brilliant. Oh, I knew as a comic.
I mean the, the, let's get some all, all
that stuff. Alright, brilliant. Yeah.
I think what happened to him, no, is
overload. Like if you talk to him,
like have you listened to
him rather talk about it.
He talks about how it got to a point
where he can go on stage and anything.
He did. People laugh so he couldn't
figure out what was funny anymore.
They were just so happy to see him
and he was like, this is crazy.
So he just pulled out, pulled
out a comedy. Stop doing standup.
That word crazy. If you couldn't do
that because, yeah, I don't know.
I mean I guess I could really, I wouldn't
have watched it up. Don't stand up.
I could, I wouldn't want to, but I
could. Yeah, I could. You know what, I,
there's a lot of things I want to do,
man. I like doing stuff, you know,
like I'm writing a lot now.
Um,
especially in writing law stand up because
I'm getting ready to do like a whole
new hour. I've got to put together a
whole new hour. So it's really exciting.
But I'm also, I just started writing a
book to writing a script. I wrote this,
not a script, a another book. I'll like a
horror book. Um, I'm a monster movie book,
so I'm like,
I know a bunch of shit I like to do.
So if someone said you can't do
standup anymore, I be like, man,
when miss stand up, but I got to do all
this other shit. Like I don't have the,
I don't have that distraction.
I'm like busy. So for me,
if I do only one thing, it doesn't,
it doesn't sit well for me.
Well you have a career nobody
else has. I mean with the, the,
the fights and everything, it just, the
way your career, where you're acting,
you know, I mean there are
people that watch fear factor.
They didn't know you were stand up.
Yeah,
I did a lot of things that
didn't make any sense. You know,
they don't go together like being
a standup and be in a cage fighting
commentator.
They don't really go together.
That could it fucking great at that man.
It's fun,
but you love it and you know about it and
you break it down for people, you know.
I mean,
I know you don't watch football,
but I watch a lot of football
and this Guy John Gruden,
do you watch football? He's don't
want, he's talks about bubbles,
screens and all this shit. I Dunno.
What the fuck are you still going about?
You can break it down so that a common
person could understand what's going on.
Well, this is a thing that sports casters
would like to do to let you know that
they're in the know. They
use obscure lingo and jargon
and they do it on purpose.
Like I've heard guys do it
with MMA. They were like, yeah,
he's going to hit him with the two,
three, five Combo. Fuck is that,
I don't even know what that is.
Everybody's is different. By the way,
you can't say that because here's your
standard two three to a two is a right
hand. Uh, three's a hook. So it's jab is a
one, two is a right hand. Three's a hook.
But different camps do different shit.
Like some camps have the
like hit him with the Aldo.
They'll come up with names
for combinations that come
up with names for certain
techniques. Like a shovel hook is the
razor Ruddock, the Razor Ruddock you know,
and they'll, they'll have different
numbers. Like instead of one, two, three,
they'll do it backwards.
You know,
they'll have like a 10 strike combination
from like 10 being the head kick,
nine being the need of the body's seven
being the elbow to the head, you know,
they'll have like a bunch of them.
So they'll,
they'll have their own system so that
no one knows what the fuck. Like if you,
you're in someone's corner, uh,
and you're yelling at him with a,
to hit him in the, to, the guy's
going to look out for the right hand.
But if two is a roundhouse kick instead,
or we'll kick or something else,
you know, no one, they won't know.
So like everybody mixes things up.
So when someone's like,
you know,
I think the two three is going to be big
for him in this fight. Like fuck you,
what are you doing? You're just
letting everybody know you're inside.
That's all you're doing.
You're just, you're,
you're giving them nonsense sports guy
talk and you can't do that with fighting.
You know, there's a lot of sports guy
talk, they like to insult like athletes.
I'd like to insult players, you know,
there's like a certain amount of that,
but they don't tolerate, people
don't tolerate that. And MMA,
it's a totally different kind of sport.
The people that have been like
really insulting about athletes,
really insulting about like you like
calling them losers or fat or whatever.
Those people all get ostracized.
They all get pushed out because
there's such a tremendous,
like the emotional burden of fighting.
It's respected.
More the like there's going to be
people that mock people when they lose,
but a lot of those people were
fucking teenagers. A little kids.
People don't know about life. But as
far as like journalists, the Ma, the v,
the vast majority of ones it
like super negative journalists.
They get ostracized, which I think
is a good thing. I'll tell you what,
the time that you invited us in Montreal,
so that was the French Canadian guy,
George Saint Pierre.
That was one of the most exciting
moments I've ever felt in my life.
But a positive energy. Yeah, it's
fucking incredible. That was wild. Yeah,
there are always wild and thank God he
won. Yeah. Can't imagine if he had lost,
but then plus the crowd
was so much class here,
cause I've gone to like
professional wrestling years
ago and they will look like
the we'll cross side and they'll look,
I skate on his face.
Don't say that to Tony Hinchcliffe.
We'll get fucking angry.
Really hit it with the
boy. Tony Hinchcliffe was
reading a book the other day,
a fucking pro wrestling book
on the insides of the business.
He subscribes to the channel and just
sits there and watches every single
wrestlemania over.
And he was trying to explain to me how
they write the story arcs and about,
he was right though. The Brock
Lesnar was going to beat John Cena.
Like you told me how it was going
to happen. It was going to happen.
I didn't know anything. I don't know
anything man. Marcy's going lifted.
It's a show. Well they
had to, they had to, uh,
for a bunch of reasons.
I think they had to for like tax
purposes like that it's entertainment,
sports, you know, it
probably costs them money,
but I think they had to also because
otherwise they could be accused of fixing
contests.
So they think they had us change it from
being a sport to being entertainment.
People didn't give a fuck though. They
don't care. Stop the ratings at all.
I think it's funny when the punch lands
like a foot away from the guy's face,
guy goes flying.
Oh yeah.
Well they beat the fuck out of
each other for real too though.
They do hit each other. Oh,
well they're good athletes.
I mean just flipping in the air and
landed on your butt. I had to hit Kevin.
James would have punch on, uh,
on his show. I can't queens.
And I was so upset because my left
hand is so much better than my right,
but I through this kind of have a fag
punch with my right hand and he goes
flying down.
Why did you have to throw a right?
Because they didn't accept southpaw. Yeah,
they wouldn't, they the camera thing,
whatever it was. Sons of bitches.
I know that's ridiculous.
You should have your ground.
But he'd say, look, I'm a lefty.
I wasn't in a position to
Joe who was a guest star was,
it wasn't exactly an executive producer
director to fucking damn which it around.
Maybe we can go back and change it. We
should go back and post film upside down.
Brian knows Photoshop switch that around
is a clever little son of a bitches.
So when you threw the punch,
when you threw the punch,
how far away from him were you at that
far? And it looked like I hit him really?
And he went down and he comes up
with all ketchup in his mouth and I
accidentally hit a guy in a scene in a,
we're doing that hardball show.
I threw a punch and
they threw like a beer.
I think it was my face
or fake beer and uh,
and I was supposed to hit him afterwards,
but because like the
fake beer hit my face,
I was like temporarily blinded and I
tried to like do it like in front of his
face or to the side of his
face and I accidentally like
nick dumb. I felt so bad.
I didn't hurt him, but it was just
like, what an idiot. And of all people,
I used to do demonstrations,
pulling punches people's face
and I accidentally hit this guy.
Do you VHS copies of this show
and can I transfer the ball line?
I probably have a couple.
There's no,
there's the only thing I've ever
been able to find is like one or two
screenshots.
Sony took it to where they drop
all that nuclear waste in Nevada.
They opened up some canisters and they
dropped all the master tapes in the
nuclear waste so that no one would ever
see. It wasn't Sony Disney, Disney Fox.
That was the first gig. You have
one first clearing your head. Yeah.
If it wasn't for that I nothing else. So
like I would've never gotten news radio.
We're never gotten any of those things
because I got news radio cause I,
it was still out here.
And the reason why I was out here is
for that hardball show. I've, if I,
if it wasn't for me signing a lease
because I wasn't going to sign a lease,
like I was just going to
rent at the Oakwood. Yeah.
You know the oakwoods is a
thing that everybody does in la.
We get when you're getting separated from
your wife, that's too, well, it's um,
everybody does in la when you move to
town because they'll sell their rent.
You a furnished place, like it already
has a TV, has cable, it has a bed
and you can kind of,
it's almost like a,
like you move into an apartment
that's somebody else's shit is there,
it's not bad. Like, you know, they had
paintings on the walls and like, it,
it feels like an apartment.
That's what I got when I first was here,
but it was like, it was too depressing.
There's too many weird people.
There was like a lot of weirdness.
There's like discombobulated souls
wandering around there and I just,
I didn't enjoy the energy. And so,
uh, like any idiot who's 25 years old,
it's convinced as television
show's going to go, I'm like,
this fucking show's going to go. I
got a lease on an apartment, you know,
I rented an apartment like a fucking
moron. And, uh, I signed the lease and,
uh, I bought a TV and set it
out. I didn't even have a couch.
I was watching TV on the ground and um,
then the fucking chuck are canceling.
I'm like, Shit, I'm stuck out here. I
was totally ready to go back to you.
Can you imagine if that
would would have happened,
what your life would be totally different.
Yeah. I would have been a dancer.
I would have been an answer.
Natalie needs a nightie.
I just would have concentrated on that
stand up.
I mean,
I've already done standup TV or are they
already done Caroline's comedy hour.
I'd already done MTV half hour comedy
hour. I was already headlining nationally,
so I was already making money as a comic.
It was like just when it
was starting to work for me,
so I probably would have just
concentrated more on stand up. But yeah,
definitely would have been different.
I never would have been on something
like news radio, that's for sure.
Where you're working in Dunkin
donuts and tower seven who knows?
I wasn't working in Dunkin donuts when
I was 19 I remember bringing you up
Montreal when the club Soda. Yeah,
that was before I was on anything.
That was a long time. You are a completely
different kind of comedian were,
I mean you were, you were always good, but
you were different and you didn't have,
you didn't invest the energy that I
remember that you could do late later on
with the new rules. Why wasn't, I
just wasn't that good? You know,
pretty good.
I was okay.
I just didn't know how to be the best
version of me, you know what I mean?
But, but he didn't have any insight
either. That was the other thing.
I was 24 25 when we met, you
know, when we first hit Montreal,
like was it like 92 or
something like that? I Dunno,
I something like that somewhere
around then. But I didn't,
you know, I was an idiot
of just me being on stage.
It's just like a ridiculous proposition.
Like who the fuck is this guy? Why is
he allowed to talk? You know, so I,
you know what I mean? Well, I don't, I
think it'd be in tough with yourself.
You were, you were pretty
good. You just weren't, I mean,
now you're just so confident. The energy's
all there, you know? It's like he,
I mean, I don't know if people get
too comfortable, but you can see it,
you know how you have like a minute or
like a half a minute or on stage where
there's just,
it's just like thinking there's something
you were comfortable with that now you,
you weren't comfortable with that
then I met then and neither was I.
Right. And what you mean?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Those, yeah,
the pauses and just being in your own
skin and the audience can sense when
you're not comfortable.
It makes them uncomfortable.
Then the whole thing goes
wacky. Yeah. Plus then like
if anything went wrong, the
fucking show was over. I never,
I never pulled myself out
of a downward spiral ever.
Like I would do great. Great, great. Eh,
like once it started going down,
the ship was going to hit the rocks.
There was no getting out of that.
Save yourself. We'll see what,
I had the Improv in those clubs in New
York. Where did you develop? Um, well,
mostly Boston up until, I guess it
was right around the time I met you.
I was moving to New York. It was
92 ish, somewhere around there.
I lived in New York from 92 to 94 and in
[inaudible] 94 I was already going back
and forth to la,
but I'm nine.
All that like 88 to 90 ish night maybe.
I guess it was 1991.
All that was in Boston. And it was, a lot
of, it was, uh, working all these, uh,
outside bar gigs,
the bar gigs and clubs.
Do you remember when it
clicked them for you? Honestly,
as a professional, I don't
think, it wasn't until I was
like 10 years in, you know,
when I did my first, uh, comedy CD, which
is a, I'm going to be dead some day.
I did it at the Houston livestock.
I did that 99. That was when I was,
I felt comfortable enough with what
I had to put it on a CD. And the,
I listened to it today,
I cringe,
but it felt comfortable
enough after 10 years in like,
I think I can release something, you
know? So that's uh, that was one,
but I still am, I, I feel
I'm better now than I was two
years ago. I know I am. I'm,
I'm working on it more.
I work at it more and more excited by it.
I wasn't that happy with my last special,
I was when I put it out and then when
I started going over and I was like,
I could've done this better. I was too
with doing too many different things,
you know?
But this one I did stand up like every
night I did stand up like Sundays.
I did Tuesdays,
I took Mondays off,
but almost every week I was doing Tuesday
at the Haha Wednesday at the Improv.
Oh fuck. Yeah. It does. It does.
I look like I looked at my act now, the
body of my work, if I may, and I know,
I think, who the fuck wrote this? Yeah.
Because how did they get this? But Shit,
I couldn't let go. I had
to write. Sometimes I think
like, you know, she goes to,
they do. They do. You're right. A
lot of go. Yeah. I write every day.
The problem is not, it's not that
funny other than that. Um, prolific,
well that's the difference sheet.
The guy like you and someone who is
not disciplined. Like some people,
they sit down and they write and it's
not good and they just go, ah, fuck it.
And they stopped writing and they'll
take days off and they won't. Right.
But you got to show up. If you
show up, the stuff shows up.
It's really that simple. You know, I
had a guy on the podcast yesterday,
his named Sam Harris.
He's a brilliant guy and neurosurgeon
or neuroscientists rather and uh,
knows a lot about the human mind.
And he was arguing, I'm not arguing,
but explaining the idea
of determinism that uh,
there is no real freewill and that
everything you do is a combination of your
genes, your life experiences, the
environment that you're in. All these,
it was really, really
interesting argument. Not Ours.
There's no free will. Yeah,
he's saying there's no
free will. Um, I see what he's
saying. I see what he's saying.
He's saying that the reason why you act
the way you act is essentially based on
all these factors that you have
no control over, like your genes,
your life experiences,
all these different things.
But as a comic, um, I dunno,
I guess it's all those things that are
leading me to invest more energy into it
right now, but like,
whatever it is, you know,
I don't freewill whatever the fuck it
is that's causing me to be excited about
it. Now I'm as excited if not more excited
by standup right now than I ever have
been ever.
I could see that.
I get so much more for you get on stage
and you were already like in a good mood
because you're on stage. I think I'm
appreciating how awesome a Gig it is too.
[inaudible] I can never lost
appreciation for it, but I, you know,
I compare it to other things.
Oh wait, the other thing is for
me, it's crossing generations.
I appreciate that so much.
And uh, like, I mean,
you're gonna quiz shows like yours
help a lot, but it's amazing to me.
I was in Montreal, true story.
Stop me if you heard this. Oh, oh.
I was in Montreal and this girl and her
mother said that they were related to
come up to me and wanted to fuck.
They wanted that. It suck my fucking,
oh, he goes, the kid was
nervous, you know, and she said,
are you dom Herrera? I go,
yeah. And then she gets a quick
get a picture. I said, of course.
And so the mother walks away to get a
camera and the father, I said, there were,
how old are you? She goes, 12 I go 12
and this is because of the Internet,
you know, I said, and you know me.
She goes, I said, on, she goes,
listen man, she called me. Dude,
you could listen dude. I've ever,
I've been a fan of yours since I
was seven. I said seven. I don't,
I didn't know I had had any single
digit fans. Wow. And that incredible.
That's wild. A 12 year old has been a
fan since they were seven. And she says,
funny is funny. And I said,
you know, we're so different,
which different generations, different
worlds. And she said, I said, well,
I can't believe your parents would let
you watch a pig. Like she goes, well,
you know the Internet.
You can watch anything dominant.
Six years are going to be fucking her.
That's where it gets dark.
I look forward to that show.
You will too.
I know I need two years to get hard now.
Play.
You gave me these six years. Heads
up. Just save up the lows. Oh boy.
Don't have any of those three
quarter erection ejaculation. No.
That's a limp.
Dick lead.
Jerk it off of the limp Dick and you
calm anyway and you're like, oh no.
Why are those words the funniest words?
Limp Dick is,
I used all over the vogue limp.
Dick is always limp. Dick is floods.
It's embarrassing. It's
inherently, I wouldn't know.
Never the El Pomar now. Whoa. Yeah.
Just hey, you're like Liberace.
Liberace.
I one of his balls was a pump was or air
Max. I'm not kidding. No, I'm not
kidding. Yeah, you gotta pump [inaudible].
There's a thing that guys do when
they get erectile dysfunction that a,
they used to do that. Just talking
about it. I don't know about that.
I've heard that a stone like the lion,
the glass white girls shit on him.
I thought that was dating a
guy at heard Danny Thomas.
I was him to together. They jerk
each other off while they watched it,
but that's not a really shit at the fair.
It's that shit. It's shit. No to table.
Yeah, but the biological, you know you're
watching it expand and you watch it.
Yeah.
It's like when a little kid plays a plate
out and they have the factory and they
winded up and it comes out.
That's with like,
you were the one that told me about that
a long time ago when we first started
looking up,
shared on the Internet that some Japanese
guys getting shit on and what isn't.
A lot of videos of people that would like
shit in each other's mouths and stuff
and you can't believe it's real,
but when you watch it,
there's some fake ones like two girls,
one cup they like put ice cream up their
ass or whatever the fuck they put up
there.
That wasn't exactly shit.
Eight parents that you can get some severe
diabetes from that get all that sugar
up your butt hole. But I don't think
they're concerned about those girls.
The first worry, there's plenty of
videos though of people eating shit.
It's apparently it's a genre. You
know, some folks enjoy watching it.
I've had it in my mouth once like, oh, oh,
because he's thinking about asking. He's
like, I shouldn't let me need let me.
Oh No,
no need.
No need to know or knew her very well.
He was sleeping in the same bed as her.
You do a bid on that? Yeah. Okay.
And then I thought I heard it before.
It's a true story.
True story with my happy stories.
The truth
gets dark out there.
That's interesting that
that's a weird fetish.
That wasn't his idea that just an
accident. She was an accident. Right.
Some people through shit and he
chose his mouth like, go, okay,
let's meet here at two o'clock
and I'm a shit in your mouth. Yes.
Get to that point. How do you do on
every pair of perversion there is.
So you get to that point.
Well,
that's why would Sam Harris says it's so
fascinating is if determinism is true,
that means that you're
not even responsible for
letting someone shit in your
mouth.
It's like all these variables have played
a part in your being who you are at
this moment,
lying there on the stainless steel table
by this Japanese guy hovers over your
face. Should have been he's guy.
Yeah, he pulls it, pulls us a sack up.
So's balls. Don't get shit on and dumps
one. Write down your fucking mind.
I don't know why. I don't know. I
don't know a lot of things though.
I don't understand the grateful dead.
You know why there's such a phenomena.
I don't get why anybody listens to
that and likes it. I don't get it.
I understand that you like
it, but I'm just being honest.
No, I don't like not you,
but anybody who's listening to this,
like I get like sunk trucking.
I get a touch of gray. I've, I've, I've
heard a bunch of that are pretty good,
but to be a dead is a little over the top.
My cousin traveled around
the country with them.
I used to used to travel the country. I
mean it went to three shows, but we got,
but he died right when I got into them.
Of course it all that so funny. He's like,
fuck this guy, I'm just going to kill
myself right there. Also about though,
what a lot of people forget is that it
was also people that you knew that also
like the smoke marijuana when
it was really, really illegal.
So it was like this group thing of like,
Hey,
we all like to do psychedelics
and mushrooms and smoke
weed and that's awesome.
Yeah. Well there's also a thing
that happens when you're on a drug,
when you listen to something where it
just sounds totally different than if
you're not on that drug.
That's a,
that's a reality that I
experienced recently with um,
with what's called an ECO row.
An ICO is this thing that, uh,
the play when there's,
um,
Iowasca ceremonies are
going on and if you, uh,
you take DMT and you
listen to this [inaudible],
you see these things like
play out in front of you.
Tony is going to talk about it tomorrow.
Tony and I will talk about it tomorrow
cause we did it together in Texas,
in Texas with these ECO rose.
But it's this crazy
fucking sound that's um,
that's playing that is like,
it's,
it's really wild because the sound's
somehow or another effects the music or
the,
the images you see rather this is it.
This is all these shamans in the Amazon
and they play this and while you're on
DMT and you do this,
the images and these like elves in this
hallucination or whatever you want to
call it, they dance to this
music and it's fucking crazy,
man.
It makes the whole thing
that makes the whole
thing even more bizarre.
But what's weird is that these songs were
actually designed to be used that way.
They were all made by these trippers and
the Amazon and they're all using like
rattles and shit and they're
whistling like, listen to this.
It sounds like really simple music, right?
If you listen to that, and I'm like,
dude, you need to download this and be
like, bitch, get the fuck outta here.
I'm listening to some asshole whistle
and slap his thought. But if you,
if you listened to it when you're under
the influence of DMT, it's amazing.
It's like they danced to the music.
It's really,
really weird with all psychedelics though.
Music is very,
very important with
mushrooms and everything.
Cause I've really changed a whole
mission trip before just on the music I
listened to being like pink Floyd or
doing some kind of more like a drum type
stuff. Uh, I think that would
kill me. Yeah, I'm serious.
I think if I took mushrooms
or anything hallucinogenic,
I'm so close to the fucking edge anyway.
The I need like tranquilizers.
You're that close to the edge.
Well as far as that account
Aerosmith something long
when the world today,
I don't know what it is.
Something wrong.
This is one of my favorites.
I like that.
It's kind of like
the last thing you hear when walking
down a dark alley about to get raped by
some guy was tricking them.
But we feel
he didn't really even think that he just
went with that because he thought it'd
be an interesting thing to say.
The first one I did cause I was thinking
of a guy whistling and you know like
walking slowly down an alley,
stroking his car.
That'd be terrible if it guy
was raping you while doing this.
If you just have your mind went there
and you're getting raped by dragons and
patterns.
Have you hallucinated when right now
have you listen to it? What do you mean?
In real life or drugs, but
drugs. Yeah. Yeah. Hello?
I don't know.
I don't know if I'm really seeing Elvis.
Maybe I'm really seeing now is, but I'm
assuming that it's a Luiseno pot. No.
Well you can if you eat it,
if you eat it and you close your eyes,
you definitely hallucinate for sure.
If you eat a large dose,
like if you have like a cookie,
like a strong cookie and then
you lay down and close your eyes,
you see bizarre shit that would scare
the shit out of him. It should. It's,
but that's a,
that's a part of the whole thing is
that it scares the shit out of you.
And then when it's over you feel better.
I was asking Joey Diaz last night about,
I said, do you ever go a day without
eating pot? It goes, yeah, of course I do.
I said, does it bother?
He goes, no, I smoke.
I tried it once in the 60s.
It's overrated. Yeah. He um,
he's taken it to another level.
He definitely, he does take,
you know, he takes days off of
edibles. Animals can fuck with you man.
They can, they can give you panic
attacks. I've been with Joey when he was
getting like a panic attack.
We were on a plane really?
And is he in these things called Chiba
Chews and we tell you about Chiba Chews
my rare, right. I don't ever eat a whole
cheat, but you, I mean, ever, ever.
So Joey, three of them, the re,
oh my gosh.
Chiba Chews war.
If you a three Chiba Chews and you
listen to this and you close your eyes,
you would see the most bizarre shit ever.
Dancing fluorescent cartoon characters,
fucking and creating new
cartoon characters that
are separating and dividing
like cells.
You'd see your whole childhood
play out in a cartoon form,
like a comic strip. He could see
anything. You will hallucinate.
Like that's a massive,
massive dose of ta.
Now how did he walk from
the plane to the car?
He did and he sat in that plane for five
hours and we flew across the country
and Atlanta go Joe Rogan. I almost
had a fucking panic on that plane.
Was He okay by the time we landed,
basically, yeah, he recovers quickly.
Thc when you will,
marijuana when you eat it produces a
psychoactive chemical called 11 hydroxy
metabolite and it's about five
times more psychoactive than THC.
It's much more like mushrooms,
much more like I'm much
more like a psychedelic than
marijuana because marijuana
is, it gives you high. But um,
that five hydroxy will fucking
kick your dig into the dirt.
It's one of the reasons why when people
eat cookies, they always say, oh,
it was laced, man, it was
laced. That wasn't lace.
That's what happens when you
eat a lot of it. Especially I,
one of the most frightening
moments in my life. I took,
I took a marijuana pill and I was talking
to this guy that turned out to be a
rapist. Turned out to eventually,
he eventually went to jail for rape.
He was a Brazilian Jiu
Jitsu belt and, uh, he, uh,
he fled while he was on
this, uh, under, you know,
they were looking for him cause he fled
and moved to the Pacific northwest,
started doing Jujitsu again even
though they were looking for him,
couldn't stop doing Jujitsu cause
he likes to do it so much. And uh,
I was at this,
uh,
grappling event and he had competed in
this grappling event and I had taken this
pill and I was way too high to be out
in public. This was, it was confusing.
It was like really like, whoa. It was
one of the first times I was ever really,
really big. But he, in this,
he and I were talking and when
we were talking I was like, wow,
there's a distinct like different
thing going on with this guy.
Like this guy has like, uh, there's, uh,
an ability to do things that this guy
has like in his head that might not
necessarily be good things. Like if you
were with this guy in a street fight,
he might like stomp somebody to death.
You know what I mean?
Like you might see him do that. Like
don't do it. Stop doing it. You know,
like he wouldn't, I don't, you know,
there was like an edge that he had that
he had crossed over and I was feeling
that when I was on,
on the pills and then like a couple
months later the guy goes to jail or gets
indicted and you know,
and then flees and then wants up going
to jail later when he's still doing
Jujitsu because they had
found him in some school.
Well cause he's a really high level
black belt is not that many guys that are
tapable of tapping out other black balls.
So when some guy comes in your school
out of nowhere and he started strangling
your instructor, everybody's like, well
what the fuck is going on? Who's this guy?
You've tried to pretend he was some
guy from Brazil and everybody's like,
but he's American. The fuck's going on.
He's in jail now. He's in jail now. Yeah,
but as those God damn pills, I saw him
to his soul. I didn't like it dumb.
I don't even like hearing it.
That's true because I'm
going to get it over the air,
but in the context of that story
is a song any better? Yeah.
I like this. Oh, you
don't like it?
Your highest fucking,
you hear this is the greatest song of
all time. That's why I downloaded it. I,
how do I keep it?
I wanted it to be a part of my life
where they say what language are they
singing? Anything or just making
noises. There's, there's a,
there's words to it. I don't know
what the words are to this one.
There's words to it. Obviously the other
ones didn't know from the Amazon. Yeah,
yeah. That's, that's
the real deal. Peruvian.
So I guess it must be a some form of a,
I don't know what I mean, it's not
Spanish native. Yeah, but Peru,
they speak Spanish mostly.
I think they speak a bunch of different
layers of a native tongue and the Amazon
and a couple of wild shit, man,
that's crazy place to live.
But this is their technology.
This is the,
the technology that
they've invented to try to
enhance or change these psychedelic
trips that they go on. Very, very weird.
You ever get stuck in one you think you
can't get out of, get out of it? No. Um,
I've gotten,
um,
but I had one that I did
a few years back that, uh,
fucked me up for a couple
of weeks afterwards.
It was so intense that for a couple of
weeks afterwards I was really worried
that like reality itself had gone.
The way I described it was, it was,
it reality was too slippery. Like it
didn't, the, it didn't make sense.
Like I get these thoughts in my head,
like I'd be driving on the highway.
I'm like, what if a car flips the
divide and comes towards me right now?
Like I'm like, what am I
thinking this, you know?
And I think where were you working on
then knowing this or fear factor? No,
it was post fear factor. Um, so
nothing just doing stand up. Oh, okay.
Oh you're still at the comedy store
because I remember you talking to me about
this and wasn't,
so that was 2007 maybe 2006
maybe wasn't that long ago?
Yeah.
Yeah. Cause we stopped going
to the comedy store at 2007.
I feel like it was post that
Brian, that's so long ago. Yeah,
I think that bet on the wrong horse.
It doesn't make any sense.
I remember we were in the
back alley behind where I
had a few that fucked me up.
I don't know if this is the same.
Big Life is slippery and you were like,
you just saw a ghost and I'm like did you
do this last night? And you're like, no,
this is like four days
ago. And I'm like, what?
I'm not sure if our timelines are correct
here. Anyway. That's not important.
The important thing was it took about,
I think what was going on for about two
weeks after this experience was that it
was so ego shattering but the, the, the,
the psychedelic trip was so it's so like
changed my idea of what was important
and my position like in my own universe,
like instead of me being the
center of my own universe,
I became like just this piece
in this gigantic fractal.
Like it was, it was very weird.
And it, if you're, you know,
you're clinging to this idea,
like what makes you successful,
what makes you push forward? Well, I know
you personally, I know you enjoy killing.
You like going up there and, and, and
you like being a great comic. You know,
there's
a reason why you're a great comic. You've
worked at it, you like it, you enjoy it,
you go up, you do it and you
take pride in that. Well,
when you have like a really
intense psychedelic experience,
one of the weird things that happens
is like your idea of who you are,
like the youth thing that you part of it,
which was so natural and
normal kind of like dissolves.
So I think my ego by worrying
about all this shit by like,
like worrying about cars flipping into
my lane or weird things happening.
It was almost like my ego was trying
to present me with a bunch of different
dangers. And though these dangers,
you have to prepare for these,
so you have to worry about yourself.
You have to think about yourself.
So it's like, it was trying to
counterbalance the destructive ego,
destructive properties of the psychedelic.
Like the psychedelic was saying,
listen, you can tweak out all you want
about shit. But here's the reality.
The reality is you're a part of something
that's infinite and it goes on forever.
It's infinite in size and it's
infinite in length and it's fractal.
It folds into itself and expands
on to infinity. And you can,
you could pretend you're important
all day long, but you're not there.
It's impossible for you.
You're a part of the universal soup of
not just consciousness but of atoms and
subatomic particles and all these
different things fold into each other.
And it was so,
uh,
it was so humbling that I think
my ego was trying to battle it.
I think my ego was trying to reclaim
ground and the way to do that was to make
me paranoid, to make me
worry about shit. You know,
I usually I'm aware when I drive,
but I don't usually think like
what if a car flips over that lane?
What if a car comes in?
You know,
one of the things that they used to
connect a DMT with when it first, uh,
when their first experiment with it,
they thought it was a causes psychosis
and they thought maybe it exists in
higher doses and in people that are,
um,
and people that are psychotic. That's
one of the reasons why they're nutty.
They're nutty because their
brain is producing all this,
these weird chemicals that have been
shown to be produced by the body that also
produce hallucinations.
And my B.
It's just see that there was a Twitter
images about that guy who was pineal.
Yeah.
Oh yeah, we showed it on the last
episode. We did good. Joe, you when your,
when your original DMT trips,
you talked about how that you met some
kind of like visual spirit or something
like that and he was tailing like 3000
a million times or whenever that was.
Do you still love you talk to that exact
same guy or is there a new guy he got
fired?
It's,
there's a part that you go to that's like
the same place and the part you go to,
it's like these rotating columns that go
on in infinity and it's all like you're
a part of like this.
You see like the gears and the mechanisms
of the universe it feels like and it's
filled with entities like
whatever this thing is,
it's filled with like these conscious
entities where it feels like conscious
entities and sometimes they
talk to you in English and some.
This last time they were there,
were there talking to me and like
a language that wasn't even real.
Like they were talking to
me and like they were like,
there were,
there were saying were like they were
saying like things that didn't make any
sense and showing you things and if you
thought negative in any way, like you,
they would go like, Duh, Duh, Duh Duh
Duh Duh Duh Duh, Duh, Duh Dah, Dah, Dah,
like finger would shake back and forth
and then, then, and then and then, uh,
and then if you calm yourself and
thought positive, that would calm down.
But it was like letting,
you know every time you slipped into any
sort of a negative pattern of thinking.
And it was exposing a lot of the,
the ideas that I was thinking that were
important, that weren't important at all.
So it's all ego based ideas,
ideas about, you know, um,
how you, how you address or
how you look or you know,
whether your car is dirty and
whether you're not, you know,
whether you make x amount a year or y
amount of year, whether you, you know,
with all these ideas that we
have connected to ourselves
that like infest our
brain and there are there all the
time. It was letting me know, like,
you're spending too much time thinking
about stuff that's not important.
It's like showing it to me like
over and over and over again,
but it didn't do that thing where it says,
I love you. It didn't say, look at this.
Like the one time it was like, they
were like, I love you 600 million,
500,000 times, look at this. And every
time they will say, look at this,
it would become this even more beautiful
thing. Well that's good. It was weird.
But this one again,
I did to these ICAROS these songs.
You're going to do it
tomorrow? No. Oh No, no, no.
I get it on this Joe. I can't do, but
the three teaspoons of cough medicine,
they fucking shaky. That's not true,
but you could. You could have a drink.
You can have a little Xanax. Have a little
of that. I don't drink. Was that why?
What happens will be your
heart slows down too much. Oh,
a lot of people die from
tranquilizer. Alcohol mix. Yeah.
I got to wait for those people.
You're pushing for die and we'll see.
You can't take a little fucking Valium
and a little whiskey. Holy Shit.
That's how Merle haggard became famous.
I saw Johnny Cash made songs.
Got To do it,
son makes it up.
All those country music guys
used to fucking party hard.
That was a big shocker to people that
saw that Johnny Cash moving a walk the
line. Everybody was like, what? They were
all pilled up like what the fuck? Yeah.
A lot of musicians, musician, when they
used to call it a, what'd they call it?
Before marijuana was
before it was called weed.
I forget, but anyway, it's like
a grass, maybe grass. Yeah.
What's that noise? That outside?
Yeah. It's that song coming back.
Well, this is a very different podcast
show. I never thought I'd get nervous.
And your podcast nervous.
Well, I started with the,
the head stuff gets me a little does it
then you should do it. Fuck though. No,
we killed me. They, uh, they give you
the finger, they look like jokers.
They have like joker masks on and you
see them when your eyes are open or your
eyes and close,
your eyes are closed.
You see him way more visual.
The visuals are way more potent than
anything you could ever see with your eyes
open. They give you the finger and they're
spinning around giving you the finger.
But they're having fun with you.
They're letting you know, like stop.
I think it's their way of telling
you not to take yourself seriously.
What did it say? Look where we are. Like
you, you take yourself seriously, dude.
Where we're in another dimension
and we're fucking mocking you.
You're creating it right. Your brain's
created. I don't know. Yeah, I would take,
I would think so. You think there's
really something out there? What?
I don't know and this is the
best way to describe it. Um,
I don't know what life is.
I think life itself,
like this life that we live is,
if it didn't exist, if you, uh,
if you, if you said, if he just, you know,
you were creating a universe,
you had no,
no point of reference and he said we're
going to have a bunch of people that the
way they interact and let each other
know what's on their mind is they make
noises with their face and
then everybody's noises
are different depending on
what patch of land you're in.
And those,
those noises represent like shit
that we've written down with symbols.
But everybody's symbols are different too.
Like there's some similar ones that a
lot of people use in different places,
but then the Russians, they change
them up and the Chinese change,
him and the Japanese have their own
system and Koreans have their own shit.
And then Spanish people use fucking
like water slides over the top of their
ends. You know, everything's,
everything's weird, right?
And the only way they communicate
with each other is by doing this.
And then someone came along and they
invented a translator, so you'd take copy,
big slabs of pay of of texts.
You throw it into Google translate and
it spits back up some broken English
version of what that person is saying.
That's just, that alone is weird.
The fact that there's a planet with
these types of people, these entities,
and they're sending photos of each
other, they're, they're fucking,
they're flying and metal tubes.
They're broadcasting video through the
sky and you could pick it up on your
phone and you could watch it. I
mean, that alone is very psychedelic.
It's just, we don't think of
it because we keep doing it.
We what we do as Comedians
is entirely psychedelic.
When you're on stage this weekend at the
laugh factory and you're killing killed,
hello. When you're doing that, you're,
that's like a form of mass hypnosis.
You got those people locked into the
way you're thinking and your doing
something to their body by you talking
and you talking in his expert rhythm of
the master standup comedian and hitting
all the punch lines and thank you.
Good night. And they're
like, whoa, what a show.
They laughed and all you did was make
noises with your mouth that represent
ideas that you can introduce into their
head that they wouldn't have ordinarily
pieced together. Like my
act, I know your work,
but that psychedelic.
So what is going on when you take a drug
and you see these things with your eyes
closed? I'm not sure cause it seems like
they're way fucking smarter than me.
It seems like they're mocking me.
They understand me and they're so beyond
anything that I could ever experience
on this planet.
It seems like if,
I don't know if there is anything other
than this dimension, I don't know.
But scientists seem to explain it
in some sort of a way where I'm,
I'm willing to listen to them, but I
don't, there's definitely something else.
Whether, I mean just the fact that
this is all Adams and it's moving,
everything's moving is beyond
my scope. I mean, I can't,
like if you said something one time, I
think we were sitting on stage and about,
you know,
we have no control over us or a
journey through space as a planet.
And the thing that's interesting to me
is we have absolutely no control. I mean,
if this planet just dropped
for some gravitational reason,
there's nothing we could do.
What if it just started falling?
That's what I'm saying.
Like there's a whole solid system.
Everything's spinning and our pants drops.
What would we do? I mean, well, yeah,
we're going, oh fuck. Getting my salary
ship. Somebody puts something in my drink.
There's nothing you can do. Yeah,
we're fleas. Well, that's not a dog.
That's what cracks me up.
People who are so full of themselves,
but what are you fucking cocky for?
Wouldn't even know what we're doing here.
That's what they do
value. When you do DMT, that's
what those things are doing.
When they're giving you the finger,
they're like, ah, you fucking idiot.
You take yourself seriously
it wouldn't it be cool if it was always
there? Those guys are always around you.
And when,
only thing that psychedelics does his
speed down your timing belt a little.
So you can see,
I'm kind of like where dogs are always
barking at and invisible things and
sometimes dogs.
What if dog seed that DMT the whole
time with you mixed into dogs barking
invisible things to hear sound.
Yeah, let's do you came here
dimethyltryptamine Oh, Rick Strassman
will be on the podcast folks.
He'll be, uh, on, uh, sometime
soon. We're working out the date,
but uh, I'll be, uh, I'll be
talking to him soon. He'll
be flying in. It either be a,
most likely it'd be October.
Looking forward to it. And
Rick Strassman for no one,
if anyone knows who he is, he's
one of the, anyone doesn't rather,
he's one of the first guys to ever
get permission from the Dea to do a
university studies on dimethyl trip to
me and on psychedelic drugs that are
schedule one drugs. And he did this, um,
series of tests out of the University
of New Mexico and wrote a book about it
called Dmt,
the spirit molecule where they were
injecting intravenous DMT into people's
bodies where it's the biggest,
the longest trip. If you smoke it,
it goes directly into your bloodstream,
but your body brings it back to baseline
and about 10 to 15 minutes depending
upon the dose. But if you
inject it, it takes a half hour.
And apparently these people
all had like these intense,
intense DMT trips like when I'm talking
about, but that went on for 30 minutes.
Fuck that. Right. Fuck that again.
Sign me up. So you would
do at 30 minute one. Yeah,
dude, I did five of them the other
day. I did one after the other. Yeah.
We kept doing it to him. It was
amazing. Yeah. You walk out of there,
you feel better about life,
you feel better about people,
you'll feel sorry for like angry,
shitty people instead of being mad
back at them. You feel sorry for them.
And you're not concerned
with any side effects?
No, none. There's none.
I think the side effects that I had
when I did it those years ago when I was
talking to you about it,
I think a lot of those side effects were
based on where I was in my head at that
time,
that it was so obliterating.
And then it took me a while to sort of
come to grips with what I learned from
that experience. But this, this
experience, um, which is, uh,
at least two years since my last one,
this experience was only
positive. It wasn't, there
was nothing negative about it.
It's like I was ready for this experience.
Like instead of it like
knocking me in the dirt,
I had learned enough from
my last one that I had, I,
I came into it with a
good in a good place.
Like you're always going to have like
a certain amount of ridicule from them.
Like you're always getting at, like, it'll
put a lot of your ideas and your, uh,
like a lot of your, like what do you
think is important in a perspective?
So I think like that always happens
because I think being a person stopping at
red lights, talking to people, dealing
with customer service on the phone,
like develop a,
just a certain pattern of behavior that
you think is normal for existing in
society and that that normalcy you
carry around with you like a shield.
And when you do DMT they go gimme that
they throw it away like you silly like
look at all this and they're,
they're showing you this insane
fractal universe that you exist in.
And it's only positive to me, but
that's me. I wouldn't advise it,
you know?
Like I said,
I had that one weird trip that fucked me
up for a couple of weeks and I'm pretty
stable. Insane in comparison
to a lot of people that I know.
So if you're not stable or not saying
or you're having real problems,
I wouldn't recommend you doing it
right here. That's me. That's you.
I would recommend you doing it though.
Yeah, I mean, I'm very,
I've had a few bad trips we've talked
about in the past and I've still done it
even though knowing those bad trips.
But there was also like a recent time
where I did mushrooms where I remember
going, you know what? I
think I'm done with this.
Just I'm not going to learn anything
more from this. This is now.
It's just kind of like me fucking with
my brain that hopefully everything works
out okay. You know, definitely
learned a lot by herself. I'll still,
I'm not writing it off, but it,
there was, that's what I felt.
My last trip though when I was in my trip,
it just getting stuck in there.
Eddie Bravo
two artists. Um, I forgot the gentleman's
name, but uh, he's a really good tattoo.
Two hours to go do the Biomek stuff
on his arm. He did DMT like a hundred.
He's in a row
and somewhere you,
somewhere during
the trip, the DMT entities
like, hey, hey, hey, no more.
Stop enough. Like they were
telling him, you gotta stop
doing this. Wow. But he was,
he was creating all this
artwork and all this.
He's having all these visions and he
wanted to be in the DMT realm more than he
wanted to be in the regular world.
So he's like pulling back from
the regular world. He was like,
he didn't want to interact with people.
He just couldn't wait to get back
to his house to get blasted again.
So he'd go into hyperspace.
When you finally get into just the DMT,
Rome, you just become homeless. Right.
That's what those guys are probably on
the streets. They've done so much drugs.
Most of them mixed with,
you know, you know,
schizophrenia and their backgrounds maybe,
but it,
those are just people that have
fucked their brains up. Right.
I don't know. I mean, I think a lot
of people are just mentally ill.
I don't think they've done it
necessarily to themselves with drugs.
I think there's,
that would be unfair to assume.
I think a lot of those guys are just
people. Look, some people get cancer,
some people have, you know, serious
diseases. I have hypothyroidism.
Some people have, uh, no.
Yeah, yeah, I have that. It's
hereditary. My mother has it.
Um, I take a thyroid medication.
What does, so it, it fixes it,
but, which really fixes it
fun. It doesn't, it doesn't
affect me at all, but, uh,
it would make me real tired
towards the end of the day.
Right when I was on fear factor,
I started getting concerned because
I was getting these weird headaches.
They were weird.
Like at the end of the day I'd be,
I would be so exhausted and I was getting
these headaches where it was like my
head was just compressed and it felt
like the only solution was to sleep.
Like I would fall asleep, like watching
TV and I was like, this is not normal.
It does not. No, no. I know
what a normal tired feels like.
This is not feel like a
normal tired and uh, I have,
they call it Hashimoto's disease and it's,
um,
to some weird hereditary failure of your,
your thyroid gland.
That's part of the endocrine system. Yeah.
Yeah. It's just comes from, you know,
I mean, what, they don't know what it
comes from, but a lot of people get it.
My ex girlfriend had,
I remember he helped her
because she was having really bad
ups and downs and she tried all these
different ones.
Then you turned around to this one.
Yeah.
Armour thyroid.
Armour thyroid is made from pigs thyroids
and it's very biocompatible to human
beings and it makes it essentially
like you don't have an issue.
But I had the other stuff,
the different thyroid medications weren't
the so good until I got this stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. There's a lot of people
that have it, man. Super Common.
Sometimes it's a,
I would never have guessed that because
you have so much fucking energy.
That was what was weird to them. They
didn't understand why I was so lean when,
when they brought me in, they
tested me. They were like,
you know, like how come, uh,
has this affected your weight? Have you
gotten fat? And I'm was like, not at all.
No, because I was, I would
push through it, you know,
even though I would be tired
and forced myself to work out.
And when you're doing Jujitsu, um,
it's so intense that you, you, you,
you're fighting for your life essentially.
When you're on the mat and so there's,
there's no way you can half ass a workout.
So I stayed lien even
though I had this issue,
but it was definitely
affecting my endurance.
Like I noticed a
difference since I started
taking it and now you're back to normal.
Totally normal. Yeah. But um, you know,
people have weird things. I mean you
were talking about kidney stones.
Some people have, you know, some
people have kidney diseases,
some people have failure of their,
their fucking,
the what rich Vos and Bonnie
Mcfarlane have his next door neighbor.
They were talking about it on
the, uh, the radio show today,
who's losing his liver.
His liver is dying.
He drank too much and he killed his
liver and there was waiting for a fucking
transplant. Shit goes wrong,
man. The body, the body
doesn't always work forever.
Nobody gets out alive. Delude.
It's do, do, do, do, do, do
I have a drink? And Again,
oh Jesus, Dom, now you, now you tell
us you want to drink right now. No.
Okay, good. It's a test. That
means you could put it away.
He didn't get all shaky in the head.
Oh, wake up fucking drunk every day.
Every day. Every day. Wow.
Just to give yourself a day off
and I was thinking about that.
Maybe tonight we'll play some pool
after this. Give yourself a break.
You don't want to play pool drunk.
He'd be upset with yourself.
Do you enjoy drinking water? It is
water hard for you to drink. I love you.
A drink of water. I hate water.
Do you enjoy drinking water?
I mean, I like Tang heat water
and why just doesn't do it for me.
I, I'd rather drink Gatorade, but
I bought her. Terrible for you.
Let me, it's not bad for you after you
work out because you need to replenish the
shutters, the lecturer
to in sugars too. Right?
Like one of the best things
after you workout is actually
chocolate milk. Really?
Yeah.
Chocolate milk is great,
especially after you lift weights because
it has a little bit of protein in it.
Um, it has a milk, milk proteins. Uh,
it also has a caisson,
I think it's called,
and a sugar because of the
chocolate syrup and all that jazz.
It actually replenishes your
glycogen. It's really, it's
like the best. That's me.
And chocolate milk.
Sexy as fuck. Where's this show me? That
was all long time ago, man. That's a
early two thousands,
somewhere around there. I,
we've known each other a
long time brother. Yeah, man.
We'd known each other since the 90s.
My brother Dominique,
we played pool at Amsterdam
billiards and like 1993 or so.
You had just gotten that show I think.
I don't even think I had it yet.
They didn't have it yet, so I think
I'd just done your show. I did that,
that showtime thing with you in Montreal
and then we ran into each other.
So it Amsterdam. Yeah, that was great.
The one on the upper west side was great.
The new one's great too. It's on the east
side. I haven't seen it. Where is it? Uh,
uh,
I don't remember the s to see the streets,
but it's like lower numbers
on the east side. It's great.
It's like New York has a bunch of
pool halls, but la, they're all gone,
man. They're all gone. All the pools
when Hollywood billiards, we went,
it was fun too. The other one, we
could take the girls up. Oh yeah.
Hollywood athletic club. Yeah, that
was great. That was back in the 90s.
Thumb a neck bourbon. Still a
good one. Yeah. They still have,
what does it fantasia or something
like that. Yeah. That's a good one.
This is a nice table you got here.
Yeah, that's a good table. That's a,
that's an old gold crown too. That's from
the 1970s. I'm excited to write a range.
Pockets. My friend.
Very small. No, really?
Oh they gonna hurt your soul
going to bring, uh, yeah.
This guy or Nesto Domingez
top pool player. He uh,
he's also a great table mechanic and his
brother has a son rather Oscar Domingez
a top pro. And uh, they, uh, they make
these, uh, these, they cut these table.
I made this, will they, uh,
they, they built the table.
So they make these table openings
like four inch holes. So it's very,
very difficult. It's a normal
one. Five it's a big difference.
My back's going to be
killing me from rack and
that's how I would do if there
was a, if, if I couldn't,
if I couldn't do standup anymore,
I would try playing pool professionally.
I tried going on the tour if there
was a tour tours kind of dead.
Now it's amazing because it's
such a great, great sport.
P needs a television show,
pull needs like Larry the cable guy and
to travel the country. You're right.
They did. It needs, it needs something.
I thought about doing it for awhile.
I thought about doing a show where I go
from town to town and play the best guy
in the house or something like that,
but people would get bored.
I told you this before, you got too
much going in your life to become a pro.
Who took put in the practice it
would take to be a pro. I know,
but I get obsessed, get obsessed
with things, done my room.
You get obsessed with anything.
If you get the old fucking moves back,
you wouldn't try it.
A little bit of pro ball,
a little dribbling between the lanes.
People don't know you're a good basketball
player. Uh, that was like a chewed.
You could beat somebody at horse.
You think, fuck people up at horse.
I had these two kids.
I was in Ohio and I guess they heard I
could play basketball. They said, well,
you're a good basketball player. I
said, well, for a comedian, they go, uh,
could you jump? I go, I could grab the
rim. My height. That's a good jumping.
Where are fast? It goes really
fast. They go, you, you go.
Not what you're seeing now.
You fucking idiot.
I have this fucking bloated
old Chinese man. Fuck I am.
No,
no.
Like fucking 145 pounds a monkey muscle.
When you see,
when you see your face go, Chinese did,
do you have the urge to just walk around,
do whatever, the urge to fight it? I
don't know what happened. Is that as that,
is that a disease?
I didn't look at me.
I don't know what the
fuck happened to my head.
I think it's a lot of it is a water
retention. Alcohol probably. Yeah.
Your body fat rises. Your whole face
gets Chinese, like very moved by.
It should be honest with me.
At my worst,
if I lost too much weight, do
I look beautiful? I love you.
No matter what you look like. Um,
this, uh, it wish you were a hot chick.
This drinking thing.
Um,
is this something you want to do something
about it or you just kinda gotta I
gotta you gotta look for,
you've done it like cold Turkey,
right? Yeah. My doctor said,
just take a half a Xanax and you can,
I said, well, I go get, you know,
I get convulsions and shit if I stopped
drinking cold Turkey. He says, no, me.
I guess because my body was drew from
it all day today. You know what I mean?
That's not like I'm drinking.
I get up and have a drink and then you,
we asked me if I want to drink. Oh
yeah, go for one. It's not like that.
It's just you convenient.
Like it's a pattern that you fall
into when you go out at night.
I love being high and like, uh, I'll
sit there at night and I'll go around.
I'm going to have like two shots and I
go, all right. Six shots. Six shots. Yeah.
I just keep every night. What's your
main drink? Your main, your gut,
which I can reach. Uh, I like,
I'm Jay Jamison.
I looked up dirty martinis. Oh, so you'd
just drink straight with no mixers or,
yeah, maybe start doing large
drinks and then it's like, you know,
like I do Ginger Ale. No, he wants her
get drunk. See, I want to get drunk.
I don't want to get to know.
Trying to like sit there sipping.
I don't want to enjoy it. Like, Hey, hey,
Jackie is open up your Aa.
I put this umbrella and you drink.
It makes it more difficult to find in
the liquid. It's all not all happy.
Got to move it around and
makes you drink slow. Ah,
I fucking hate like Pina
coladas and shit like that.
Do you like getting caught in the rain?
I feel like the smell of the ocean,
of the tastes of champagne. I like Jimmy
Buffet and making love at midnight.
I don't think that was Jimmy Buffet.
If you like Pina coladas.
Who was that thought it was difficult,
but no, I don't believe so. Look it up,
motherfucker.
Shaking the day.
The chicken that they, I feel
like it's something. Someone
else. Yup. Jimmy Buffett.
Is it man?
Don't you bring your primitive?
That feels to me about music minster
rogue. No, it's Rupert Holmes.
Hey fucking knucklehead.
It says Jimmy Buffet.
Rupert Holmes recorded by
American singer Rupert Holmes.
I think it was made famous by Jimmy
Buffett. It's on the midnight special.
Burt Sugarman.
Here we go.
This is Rupert Holmes.
You're both right.
This is the famous one.
Yeah, that's it. It's Rupert Holmes,
so don't trust Brian red band to Google
anything for you that your life on it.
I played Jimmy Buffett's science.
Probably going to sound exactly the same,
but that's probably the one that played
the Jimmy Buffet. I want to hear it.
Jimmy Buffet. Well, this guys, this is
the guy who made that. He had the hit.
The guy who had the hit that was on
the radio is Rupert Holmes. Okay.
You're right.
I think I'm definitely right.
I know how to Google you Google
with your dick or something.
I don't even think you pay attention
to what you write in there.
I honestly thought that that
that was a Jimmy Buffett.
Jimmy Buffett is the fucking
Margaritaville guy and
maybe that's why he's not a Pina Colada.
How did we go over to look at about
the universe? Brian Redman, fucking,
he's the crowbar in any
intellectual discussion. Clang.
Your gears get ground up and then the,
the fucking elves give you the finger.
Look at things like this, like if
you like peanut clot, Jimmy Buffet,
I think that's an idiot that doesn't
know that it's not Jimmy Buffet.
That's just some more on youtube.
Unless Jimmy Buffett actually
sang a version of it.
See if we can find a Jimmy Buffet version
of it, but Jimmy Buffett was wasted,
man. Oh No.
He has a whole fucking station on Xm.
You can listen to Jimmy Buffet.
All of this. I don't think go with
the, if you're in Florida, you would,
if you were in Florida and you're
popping Xanax and drinking booze and just
fucking sitting on the feature,
you still right? No, never.
No. But you'd take a Xanax in the
morning and by the time it wears off,
then you're drinking. That's
how it works. Is there a,
is there a version of it where there's
one that when I was showing, you know,
you're right,
it's mostly all just repaired homes and
Jamie just shoved me something like the
five songs that people think are
from the wrong artists. Oh, okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Because it seems like
it would be kind of a Jimmy Buffet Song,
but I knew it wasn't him and
it's because of Margaritaville.
I think you totally nailed it right there.
I think that's why I'm just immediately
thought it's one of those old ass songs
that you don't understand.
Like, um, like uh,
the things you do for love. Who
the fuck saying that? Like what
the fuck we're looking for the answer.
And I,
I had a copy of that when I was
a little kid. I was a little kid,
like maybe six or seven and we had a 45
of that song and things you do for love
was like, the first song I ever owned was
like, who the fuck knows? See if Brian,
I'll pull it up. Call me.
Hendrix, led Zeppelin,
the WHO?
It's a British band called 10 CC,
10 16 wow. Really? You know,
a friend of mine was on a cruise ship
and Robert Plant was on it and somebody
called, somebody called him led. Oh,
my daughter's name was lit.
What a disaster.
Why would Robert Plank go on a fucking,
why would he ever do that? Do you know?
Wrapped on a boat?
Oh,
I fucking know what to do.
I've been on fishing boats.
I don't like both set.
If I lived near a lake,
I would be in heaven.
If I lived in a lake and I could just
pull out like a nice bass boat out there
and go fishing. I love fishing. So fun.
So primal to some about
catching your dinner. You know,
he's throw that soccer on
ice, filet it, get home, cook
it, eat it. Very satisfying.
Something like caveman style satisfying.
It just feels great.
Have a couple of beers when you're
out there. Castle wine, enjoy the day.
Just go to the seafood
restaurant. Oh, dom, you say that?
Do you ever catch a big fish? It's fucking
fine. Look at me. Do I look like a fish?
I got to put up some youtube videos and
me and Ari, when we were, uh, in um,
uh, Alaska last summer we had a
great time. That was really manic.
We uh,
well that was that part too,
but we caught the salmon run like
right when the King Salmon Salmon,
we're running strong. Oh.
And we caught like seven,
eight fish a day and they
were giant like big 30,
40 pounds salmon. It was
so fun. I got some videos.
I need to put them up on Youtube.
I've had him for a while,
but we had a fucking blast
because we had a gig up there.
We set scheduled a Gig for one day,
but we went fishing for two days before
the Gig. It was so much fun. That's cool.
Did you see the video that
grouper eating a shark? Yes.
Put that shit up.
It's probably going to get us right.
This is the part of the show where we
say this will get us pulled from youtube.
If you, if you're tired of chicken getting
pulled from Youtube, folks go to Vimeo.
Vimeo doesn't pull things like youtube
does for whatever reason. But uh,
this grouper is groupers.
If you don't know,
they get to be like hundreds
of pounds there. Fucking huge.
So this guy is caught.
The Shark and the grouper
just gangs his fucking shark.
He's pulling the shark
in and it's so enormous.
I mean there are like four or 500 pounds
sometimes these Goliath groupers and it
comes up and it,
it's snatches his fucking shark.
Like he's got the shark floating around
at the top and the fish can't help
himself. He's like, fuck it. Here he goes,
look at this thing. Look at the size
of this fucking thing. One bite.
One bite inhales the entire shark.
Fucking unreal.
That's how big Goliath grouper is.
If you catch one of those bitches,
you're going to be pulling that thing
for hours. You're going to be hang on,
Aye.
I don't even like go into a seafood
restaurant and they tell you to cook your
own fish. Do they do that? And
boy I have seen it tell you.
Gotta clean my plate too, Dan.
Thanks. You like you go on a date.
It's like with doing activities,
we're cooking together.
Turn it over for me. I like
tipping fun. Do I take the brand?
I tip in the cheese.
Ooh, that's good too Joe.
People like the Korean barbecue.
We like you have the,
the the hot thing in front
of you and you slap down.
There's a place in the mall out here.
They do that. I love that. It's annoying.
I don't like it at all. No,
it's stupid. Any things?
He smells so bad when you leave.
If I was going to cook myself,
I wouldn't cook like that.
I like cooking over like charcoal,
like like lump charcoal.
Can you get that smoky flavor?
It's more about all you can eat. The,
Oh, was it all you can eat places?
Not all you can eat you,
you choose which meat
group you want. Like you get there be like
an $18 per person, 24, $30 in of the 31.
You get a different menu.
You could just order as much as
you want or you can eat things.
Psychologically it seems a
lower the quality really.
All you can eat Sushi.
Oh yeah. But Brazilian
steakhouses. Oh, that's fantastic. Those
two. Haas Korea's, we have that card.
Yeah. Like green on one side of
red on the other. When it's red.
Do you want to take a break
when it's green? They just
common with new food. Yeah.
They both places like that in
Philly. After Eddie Bravo, uh,
fought and metamorris or has grappling
match and Metamorris we went to a Fogo de
Chao and uh,
near the Beverly Center.
Brian and I have eaten it about
most of them. Most of them across the
country. There's anyone in San Diego.
Yeah, I know. I noticed. I noticed when
I was down in American comedy company,
when we would show up
town and we found a Fogo, we'd go,
ah, we get alongside and we go there.
That's delicious. And Joey Diaz would
look at you like you're an asshole.
If you go anywhere near that salad bar,
why you fucking want that salad bar dog?
Listen, sit down here. He had no danger.
You're in no danger. Bring it over.
Bring it all. We've got,
what do we got when we got,
he started talking in Spanish
to the fucking guy. The skewers,
they speak Portuguese.
He's talking to them in Spanish
trying to find some middle ground.
I recently went and they, they hide that
Kanye now they, that guy's hard to find.
You ask it to different people and you
get so much chicken sausage and bacon
stuff and you're like,
just give me the Pecan.
I think it's a matter of
how many people are there.
Like some things like are more popular,
right?
Uh, last time we were there,
they kept coming with it.
They had the big Kanya and the garlic
beef or be is like top sirloin.
What they do is they have like a,
an open fire. It's like a wood fire.
It's like real and they have these skewers
that they lean over the fire and the
skewer spin around and when
when they deem that it's ready,
then they bring it over your table,
slice pieces off the outside and then
they put it right back on the five salted.
Yeah,
the result it and put like I have a
basting thing if they do and so this is a
big piece of meat and they put it over
this fire and they just slowly cooked the
outside and then they put it back in
and slowly cooked the outside and I'm
getting hungry. There's a place near
here you want to eat after this?
Yeah. Fuck yeah. By the way,
Joe, our green mountain grill,
they have a new app now that you could
use the app to tell when your food's done.
They sent me the info.
I got to hook it up though.
You got to get a guy to come to your
house though and plug it in sensor thing
and yeah, it's not easy to do, but that
green mountain grills ma. Awesome. Yeah.
That's a pellet grill. If you don't
know what that is, it's a smoker.
It's smokes your, your
food like, like an oven.
That's the hot smoke of uh, this burning
firewood or this burning a hardwood.
They take hardwood.
And when you like,
say if you bought a table like
this table's made out of Oak,
well someone who cut this would you
leave a lot of saw dust and they buy the
hardwood saw dust and they
compress it into these pellets,
which with the natural sugars of the wood,
there's no additives.
It's just the wood itself. And then
you pour these pellets. It looks like,
almost like you ever seen that pine
kitty litter to use that stuff.
The best stuff
cuts the smell back the most.
Yeah.
But you take these pellets and
you pour it into this like hopper.
It's like this box close the lid on
it and he set the temperature and it
automatically keeps the fire
going. It's like this got this, um,
what is it called?
An element that that heats it up and
it spins it and like this gear and the
pellets automatically get introduced and
the fire has the exact right amount of
temperature and you can keep it at like,
you know,
like for two 50 or three 50 or trying
to cook something. Whoa. So amazing.
It's so easy. Like I used to have another
kind of smoker used to have to add,
would do it all the time.
It was a nightmare.
This thing does it all itself and
it tastes like all those guys.
Like have you ever watched
those barbecue competitions?
You ever watch those things and like
the food channel, a lot of those guys,
they use those pellet grills now. The
pellet grills are like a big, a big deal.
Hey, you put the meat on, you know,
earlier in the afternoon and it's
just falling off the bone. No,
it's pretty bad ass. It's pretty bad ass.
I'm a big fan. I've got a big, big fan.
Tom, I ran right back at you. Joe's big
fan. I love cooking men. Cooking is fun.
It's especially fun when you're cooking
something that you killed yourself.
When you cut it up yourself and
you slap that bitch on the grill.
It's very exciting though. Never
killed anything. What'd you be willing?
I'm thinking about doing a hunting show.
This is the idea of the hunting show.
The idea of the hunting show is I go
out with people that have never been
hunting before, whether
it's comedians like Hannibal
Burress, he said he would go,
um,
a lot of guys are interested in going,
I would go to the flash star
hotel closest to where goes,
it goes go home and he wouldn't hunt.
No.
What if we took you out in a pickup truck
and you can just roll down the window
and fire it out the window? Yes,
definitely. What'd you do that?
That's my style.
You can do that in some places in Texas,
there's a ranch that Aubrey hunted at
where you literally shoot your rifle from
the front seat of the truck. Oh, I love
the, the fucking truck has no windshield.
So you drive around on this truck.
You know,
I don't know if it's like a jeep
or if it's actual pickup truck.
They knocked the windshield out,
but you drive around in this truck and
then they get close to these herds of
animals and then a fucking set your
rifle up right there through the window.
Boom. He shoot it. Then you get
out of the truck, you get it,
you take a photo with it. Oh, I got to
get out of the truck. You don't have to.
Okay, I'll bring it to you. I'm still in.
I'll bring it to you and you can wave.
Instead of taking a picture
with the animal you kill,
you just wave from the window. This is
dumb. This is dom to deer and you uh,
and then they take care
of everything else.
It's like the laziest way to hunt ever.
I would like that.
What I was,
we were in the mid Sophie,
we're in Hawaii and she was
snorkeling and I finished. She's only,
you are so fucking lazy.
Could find a way to snorkel
without even going under water.
I got one of those riffs
that you see through,
put my head on the snorkeled with a raft.
Oh, that's hilarious. I snorkeled for the
first time. Last time I was in Hawaii.
It was awesome. It's really
fun. Yeah. Swimming around
a reef. We're around a reef.
You're seeing all these fish moving
around in their little world. You know,
it was a little, uh, I
stepped on a CNN enemy though.
This fucker went right
into my foot. Really? Yeah.
They had a poor vinegar all over my foot.
You're supposed to do it.
If you've got to go near a reef,
like reefs are really sure.
He's supposed to do it with those a scuba
shoes because that was his barefoot.
But you,
uh,
you step down in the wrong spot and he
see an enemy like black spines went deep
into my foot. Oh yeah. Fuck me up.
I never go in the ocean without shoes on.
I just don't want to step on anything
gross. Like what? Condoms dead.
I stepped on dead. Jellyfish wants I'm,
it's just disgusting. And just, you know,
there's a lot of great stuff
she can fuck you up. Especially
Australia. Oh yeah. If you were to,
uh, Australia, there's um,
certain species of jellyfish
that kill people every year.
Yeah. I was just there a
couple months ago in Perth.
They have the helicopters going
over, you know, to spot the sharks.
They have that in Adelaide to really,
yeah. Cause they have, well they see them,
they warn people. Fuck that big
white, great white sharks. Yeah.
Yeah. That's a, that's a scary spot.
Apparently the most scary spot
for sharks in South Africa.
Australia is pretty bad. Is it van? Yeah.
That's also a place where a lot of people
surf too, right? Yeah. Did you ever surf?
Yeah. Really observed you surf,
but you, what was it like?
I was a pretty good athlete then. I
was, I got up a couple times, you know,
I did it a few times.
It's the thing about it,
you have to be a strong swimmer to really
get out there, to have them enjoy it.
Can't just like go 20 feet and
expect to ride something in.
You got it. Right. And you've got to climb
on it at just the right time to write.
Yeah, it's probably difficult.
It's, yeah, it's very difficult.
A place in Abu Dhabi,
I think it's Abu Dhabi or Dubai.
I've seen that they created an
indoor surfing. That's pretty wild.
It's ridiculous.
So we're most ridiculous thing ever.
Like isn't the whole idea is that you're
out there in the ocean with nature and
these guys will learn in the middle of
the does it, we're in a pool, in a mall.
Sometimes.
You've got to settle.
Brennan did comedy there back in, was
it Neil that you used to say? He did.
He tries. I'm kidding. No, he does.
Eddie have just had a Kickstarter.
He created his own. Um,
he created his own like
mobile podcast van,
like a van to go drive
around and do podcasts.
We talked about doing that on the podcast,
like getting a stream
one of those streamers,
whether it's called streamline
streamline's those silver ones. Yeah,
they'll silver things. Is that
called streamline? Yeah. Why?
I feel like it's called something else.
Streamline trailer. It's the silver one.
Yeah. Well that thing, the cool
looking retro looking one Gulf Stream.
Jimmy Buffet had one stream.
I was actually thinking about recently.
You just sell it because I have my second
card and selling it and try to and get
one of those and we've
death squad into that.
It's not a bad idea dude.
I thought about doing it too and like
that we could do them like on the road.
You could do it like you show up an hour
early for a Gig, do a Gig, you know,
doing the parking lot. But the fun, the
friendship flashed on the dust squad.
There was no one knows. No one
initiation fees is two on your backstage.
Lower back. The lower back
two dolphins game. Why were
you like to come? But there,
yeah, this one, this is,
there's a company that makes like a high
end version of these things where the
inside of it is like air stream. There it
is. I know you fucked it up. Streamline.
What'd I say? Streamline. Yup.
But there is a streamline,
see this is a streamline
trailer. Uh, so there's some,
some of them are streamlined. They just
ripped off the air stream game. Yeah,
look at that.
It makes it look that sexy thing.
How much are these fucking expensive?
They're not cheap because they're really
made well be says there's a place up in
big Sur where you will you rent them?
They have a,
they have them set up on this
property and that's how he camp.
They have like a like a
little grill out there.
Like Dunkin was up there for like a
week. He loved it. He said big surfaces.
Favorite place on the planet.
It's beautiful.
I know there's one in Joshua tree where
a lot of la comics all they rent out a
trailer.
They have,
I went to [inaudible] where they had
this big circle of trailers in each one's
decorated like a different,
like the 70s you know the retro on the
Star Trek one you have any interest in
doing like going to burning man?
No.
Next year we should podcasts from
burning man. If we're in a trailer, yes,
but if we, oh yeah dude, we're going
to be a trail. That's what I mean.
I will go there if there's a trailer,
but it's burning man.
It's a ridiculous festival out in the
middle of the desert where everyone gets
together and they all like dance
around and do drugs. They don't shower.
It's an excuse to be stinky.
It's like it's a like a
psychedelic sort of a festival.
And these people, they all get
together. Look at this one Brian.
They have one that's like a truck.
They have a,
they have like a coach and
you could drive it around.
They call them interstate Ext.
So look at this. Oh Wow. Yeah.
So you could drive it. So you'd have like
your, your kitty cat on the side of it.
It gets someone to paint it or get
one of those uh, uh, wrap. Yeah.
And you take one of these
things around if you develop,
like if you really developed a
plan and like set forth like a,
uh, like a, a real like legitimate
plan to get one of these things.
You could do it in a couple of years.
Here's,
will Smith at burning man this
year on segways. Will Smith,
was there no for real
or is it a Smith Mask?
Which ones will Smith just wonder here.
Other dancing together.
What are they doing? Filming something.
They're getting jiggy with it.
They're getting genuine. Um, desk Mckenna.
He are not a dentist. We can have Graham
Hancock rather. He goes there every year.
I think you just got back it,
it just happened, right? Yeah,
it was last week and actually the first
day or two was canceled because of rain.
The, they have the crane and it closed,
flooded. All the roads going into it.
They even have like these
really small ones. Look,
they just attach to the back of your
trailer and then you can just leave it at
home if he went to, yeah, there's
some good ones. Um, w rain.
Where is it? Uh, uh, Arizona.
Where does Bernie man type place?
I think it's one of the thing.
It was California. And what did I think
it was California done many death valley,
California and the land to go to burning
man thumb. No desire at all. Jews.
We're doing a podcast
down there next year.
Would you be willing to stay for one day?
We'll lemme you when you come out.
You do the pockets with you out.
You're in Arizona. That's great.
Heard it here first in to the
broadcast. We drink, we eat well.
We've been talking about taking
this bitch mobile, doing some uh,
podcasts in New York, doing some
podcasts and other places where I can't,
you know, I get, can't get certain guests
to come here, so I want to go to them.
I like it here. Do you like
it? Here is a good spot. Yeah.
Very good. But you, you're,
you, you know, still with
the Werewolf starting out.
They're trapped by the pool table.
I gotta fuck toy miss up.
You're not paying attention. She is black.
Rock desert is worked. Burning man is,
where's that? Arizona. Nevada. Hmm.
Didn't they try to enforce
laws there this year?
The same like the catch people with
drugs are gonna arrest him and some shit.
Check your car for weapons.
All that. Leave people alone.
Fucking drugs. She's, hey,
he's got a, they got to make money somehow
by my era. That's exactly what it is.
I keep all those people in uniform. Who
gives a fuck? What do people even care?
Old People, conservatives, people
who want tax dollar business,
that's not their business.
That's the point.
That's what makes young people so angry.
It's almost like they know that they're,
they're controlled.
They have is fleeting and they know that
there's kind of a new age in the air
like what was going on in
the 60s is going on now,
but to a much larger extent and to
a much more broad extent, like the,
the understanding of how
corrupt our system is.
The understanding of like how
flaw did all is piece together.
Even by the people that are in it.
They're involved in it.
It's like they're all admitting the
whole thing is a disaster. Well,
there's the financial system, the
political system, and then on top of that,
like marijuana is becoming legal. Whether
people like it or not. It's spreading.
Colorado was making so much
fucking tax money. It's incredible.
It's also happening in Washington state.
Unprecedented number two,
Superbowl teams.
We're both from states that it was legal
cars highest fuck come up with good
ideas. Excellent strategies.
I, Joe, I don't even, you know,
I smoked pot four times in my life
and I always go for number five. No,
it's one hit.
Just a little bit of one hit the switch
to all these stores that will be a
heroin addict and a week and make you
feel good. It's not a gateway drug.
Just the Partnership for drug
free America trying to trick you.
I'm totally convinced that
it's not a gateway drug, by
the way. I'm totally good.
I know. I don't know anybody from that
went from pot to heroin. Well, you could,
but you could also go from
toothpaste to heroin. You know,
it doesn't mean that it's a gateway. Like
everybody drinks water. Who does heroin,
by the way, Karen would, should
be legal, by the way. I do too.
I think everything should be legal,
but I think there should be consequences
to selling people things that are bad
for them. So I think that if
you, if heroin is legal, but
if you're selling heroin,
I think that should be massive
consequences. I think you should be.
If people die of overdoses,
I think you should be held responsible.
Just like you should be held
responsible. Say if you come up with, uh,
you come up with some new medication,
you know, he caught up with,
if you're a pharmaceutical company and
you come up with a new medication and
deals with Migraines,
but it also winds up killing a
certain percentage of people.
They should be held
financially responsible. You
should be able to be sued.
He's got a joint for you.
He's the devil. Look at him.
That's what the devil looks like.
Everybody thinks the devil looks mean.
Likes cuddly devil.
Looks like a big sweetie.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. He
doesn't stop being a pusher.
What were we talking
about before the devil?
Just the legality of drugs
and how ridiculous. Uh,
and you were saying that people who
sell, excuse me, this is the point,
sells drugs to people she'll be held.
That's why it's being responsible for
the repercussions of what happens to
people when they use it.
If people die of heroin overdoses,
if that's possible from
something that you sell,
you should be held financially responsible
up to a point because you know,
you could die from Shell, from
salt, you could die like get me a,
if you'd give a Guy Bacon
every day for breakfast,
it's going to be dangerous if
you eat nuts, not banded bank.
And believe it or not is not bad for
you. Bacon. Yep. Not Bad for you.
It's delicious thing I've ever had
in my life. It's not bad for you.
You know what's bad for you being
fat enough that bacon is bad for you.
That's what's valued to say it like that.
I'm not saying any foul.
You said it with like a,
you like go,
you projected it to you because you
like the audience of my delivery.
But I mean you,
I'm at Ralphie may I met someone larger.
That's not me. I love Ralphie
by the way. This is just jokes.
They're talking about me. I
right here. Yeah, he's right
there. Um, but when you're,
when you're so fat that
Bacon's doing un well,
some people have naturally
high cholesterol too.
That's another thing to
take into consideration.
There's some people that are genetically
have high cholesterol and they have to
watch it. Yeah. And they have,
you also have to balance out your good
cholesterol and your bad cholesterol.
A lot of people think the cholesterol is
all bad. You know there's Ldl and Hdl,
there's, there's good cholesterol
and then this cholesterol that is,
it's not not good for you but is good.
But if you have like low
cholesterol like pho,
there's certain cholesterol that's
actually good for brain function. Yeah,
I think I've just heard that though.
Uh,
cholesterol,
the hipster coalesced good. I'm
going to write cholesterol. Good.
Okay. Good versus bad cholesterol from
the American heart association. Okay,
so this is not bullshit at all.
HDL and LDL triglycerides.
What's the difference in Ldl?
Cholesterol is considered
the bad cholesterol because
it contributes to plaque,
which is a thick, hard deposit
that can clog arteries and make
them less flexible. So are still our, our,
our theory or old sclerosis.
Arterial Sclerosis is what comes from
the bad cholesterol and those narrowed
arteries or give people heart attacks.
HDL cholesterol is considered good
cholesterol because it helps remove LDL
cholesterol from the arteries, which is
interesting. So expert Cresta does that,
is that that a a pill? Yeah,
and Lipitor too, right?
It's that same same kind of stuff.
Experts believe that HDL
acts as a scavenger carrying
LDL cholesterol away from
the arteries and back to the liver where
it is broken down and passed from the
body.
One fourth to one third of blood
cholesterol is carried by HDL.
A healthy level of HDL cholesterol may
also protect against heart attack and
stroke while low levels of HDL cholesterol
have been shown to increase the
reduced risk of heart attacks.
Um,
Dr. Mark Gordon explained this to me
when I had my, um, my blood work done.
And when he was telling me is that
there's a lot of issues like where people
think they have high cholesterol
and then, you know, they say,
oh my cholesterol count is this. And
he'd say, okay, what does that mean?
Is it your HDL or Ldl?
And then most people don't even know,
like they used to not know.
And if you're dealing with a physician
that doesn't understand the difference
between the two, if they're not
an expert in it, like thinking,
give you bad advice and get you on
medication that you don't even need.
Like you just said, you have
high HDL, you have high, uh,
you have high healthy
cholesterol, you can, you know,
you really want to balance
allegedly coming from me.
I'm a little doctor to
steal one of your bits.
I'm not a doctor that I had no idea.
But um, so my point is big
and not bad. Not Bad for you.
Did he went to burning man this year and
changed as supposedly changed his life
forever. Like look at his picture
of him at burning man and then like,
look at this.
He was at burning man with
his own little umbrella.
You didn't even have a guy
holding it for him. That's crazy.
ADDS up pink. Who's that? PDT. Oh,
and supposedly it changed his life once.
CanNot explain.
I'll never be the same.
Same
Bacon is loaded with fats,
but they're good fats.
The fats and bacon or
about 50% monounsaturated.
And a large part of those is a lyric acid.
This is the same fatty acid that olive
oil is praise for it and is generally
considered heart-healthy.
40% of it is saturated fat,
accompanied by a decent
amount of cholesterol.
But we now know that the saturated fat
isn't harmful and cholesterol in the diet
doesn't affect cholesterol and the blood.
Fascinating.
But that's the greatest thing was I had
all day to Bacon, Bacon and jogging.
Go get some Bacon said when two of
them together. Do you, so you, you,
you're going to the gym though, right? You
work out? Yeah. Where do you work out? No,
don't tell people they'll fuck it.
Stock you.
They'll stock in a steal your underwear,
breaking your locker and shit in it.
You know the this place shirt.
Correct. Oh, that place. Okay. Yeah.
So you get a good workout there.
Yeah, I've got an, excuse me.
I got a torn rotator cuff,
partially torn.
So it's been tough to lift the weights
and then you get flabby right away at
this age. It's funny, I
was in Perth and I opened,
the elevator was closed during a fire
alarm about but pulled this thing.
Whoa. Unbelievable timing. I'm in Chicago,
fucking totally in pain. The guy comes
up to me after he goes, you know,
I'm an orthopedic surgeon.
Uh, I got 20 doctors here.
A couple of us were talking about you,
you have a partially torn rotator cuff.
I said, uh, why you can tell by looking at
me. He goes, absolutely. He said he could.
He could see the way he was raised in my
hand. He says, come in tomorrow, Pro Bono,
I'll take care of you. Wow. I says, you
know, I got insurance. It's not, no,
you made me laugh for 25 years.
I'll take care of it.
So I think it's going to be me,
him and a needle.
It's like a whole group of doctors and you
know, he's trying to be funny. He goes,
is that the hand you come with? Oh, he
said, is that the hand you jerk off?
And I said, well, I jerk with
that hand, but I offered the sand
and uh, anyway, so I'm up there and he
gives me a needle in the shoulder. I said,
well, why am I paying my hip
hurts too because I look at that,
the x Ray that give me another
fucking shot. It was great.
So the parsley turned rotator
cuff, does it need surgery? No, no,
it's 85%.
I mean it's only 15% tour
so it just needs exercise.
So you have to stabilize it. Is
that what it is? They have to,
you have to always be moving.
It does it fuck with you right
now if you're moving around like,
like sometimes like this,
like moving and like that.
I can't let that goes like this.
I can't do,
I've never had like real
soldier shoulder problems,
but I had some of their recently
where I shot too many arrows. I uh,
I got overzealous with my bow and now I
have a 90 pound bow and an 80 pound bow
and I shot the 90 pound ball like 150
times a day. It was just way too much.
My shoulder just got worn out and it was,
it was hurting for like a couple of
months. But thankfully it wasn't torn.
It was just like tendonitis, like all
very mild form of irritated tendons.
But now it's 100%. Took like
five weeks, five or six weeks.
I never had done anything like it.
I've loves,
luckily it was my right hand cause
I'm lefthanded so yeah, it's not good.
Shoulders are a weird joint cause
shoulders move. Very calculated,
very strange ways as
opposed to like knees,
which just been like a hinge and a
shoulder goes bad. It's bad for fighters.
It's a real issue for fighters.
Like um,
they have to get surgery and they don't
fight for a year. It's a long time out.
It's a career ender for baseball
players per pitchers. Yeah. Yeah.
I would imagine you have to be really
smooth fucking weapon that arm back.
Like it's,
it's really,
can they fix that now or it's
still not that they could fix it,
but now it's not a career ender anymore.
Well it can be. It's all going to,
how still can bail, you know,
just like the elbow. Wow man,
that's it.
It's weird when you find out there's
parts of your body did they can't fix.
Like one of the things that I've found
out when I started to have back issues as
they want to start cutting things,
they want to start getting in there
and fucking Yank and shit out.
But there's certain things
that they just can't fix.
Like they've started to
give you artificial discs.
They started giving those to people
like they have, um, they have spacers.
Were these a plastic things that they
screw in, in the place where you're,
you're Mushi disc used to be.
And then now they have these titanium
rotating disks that they put in your neck
and yeah, pretty crazy.
And some people, um,
in other countries they do that and
they don't do it yet. In America,
I don't believe so.
Some people who get injured in America
go to other countries to get your fucking
neck cut open. Like Germany does it. And
England does it to put a little fake
disc and it moves around screws and shit.
Which is how you get hit,
like what your break and like Bo Jackson,
remember Bo Jackson, great baseball
and football player. He had a knee,
a hip injury. It was the end
of his career. That was it.
It's just playing baseball for
a little while and tried. Yeah,
he was the first one that ever
played with an artificial hip,
but I mean it was never the same.
He had so much power.
He was able to hit home runs without even
over whatever and torrent turning over.
You didn't even totally rotate what
halfway rotate and he would get pissed.
He would break a bat on his leg and
how fucking hard that is. The dude,
he's a super athlete.
That guy,
Bo Jackson could have done anything
if he wanted to go into MMA,
he would have been all checked guy.
He was a such a super athlete and
they said he barely worked out.
Barely lift awake. Yeah, just,
just was naturally super strong
and just a great athlete will.
Chamberlain was supposed to be like
that cause I'm from Philly and we always
read about him. Oh, imagine,
look at the size of the guy.
But he was the fastest to,
that's the fastest guy on his
team. He wasn't, you know,
well you remember when Jordan was in
his prime and he would literally fly
through the air.
Yeah.
He would fly like nobody had
seen anything like that before.
Julia serving sort of the
sky hook. Right, right. No,
that was the hook was a Abdul Jabbar.
Oh.
But Julia serving was the
first one that did the, uh,
from the foul line and the dunk contest.
Whoa.
Really from the foul line,
a dunk so crazy that someone can do so
fucking big Joe that he could palm a
record album to imagine that.
Like you could be putting my God,
that's insane. That's insane. Yeah.
Imagine if Michael Jordan got into MMA
was just flying across the fucking Kaeser
punching people live
because there's levels of athleticism,
you know, it's like this, the average
guy and then the z above average guy,
and there's the guy who was above the
above average guy and then there's a super
athlete and then there's a Michael
Jordan who makes the super athletes,
like he's on another level. If Ron
James does same thing, right? Yeah.
You know, an old buddy of mine is
Charles Barkley. Uh, you know, he is,
he, uh, was telling me, he goes,
look at me. He says, I got my,
my size of 32 inches. He goes, I got a
definite advantage. He goes, look at that.
A little white guy, Scotty Brooks
could barely touch the net. Yeah.
There's certain physical advantages
that are undeniable. Oh yeah.
The idea that all men are created
equal is fucking preposterous.
You could say that the human soul is equal
or that you should be equal under the
eyes of the law. Yeah. But now
they're not an equal. Yeah.
You could take all the steroids you want.
You never have been able to do it.
Michael Jordan did naturally and
you can't practice being six 10.
That's also a weird thing,
isn't it? Where like, uh,
where people talk about like performance
enhancing drugs should be illegal.
They definitely should.
But if they are,
that means like the super athletes
are always going to have an advantage.
Just a natural,
undeniable advantage in speed and
power and the ability to move well,
racial differences make a difference.
I mean Jimmy, the Greek over here,
no they do, but I mean physically,
you know, it's incredible.
There has not been a
weight cornerback in the,
in the NFL that I remember
in the last 2025 years.
What position? That's discrimination.
That's why they're quicker. No,
they're trying to keep the
white men down. Dom, you know,
you come on this podcast,
he started spreading black propaganda.
It's the same thing every time.
But I hate all minorities. Joe.
Even white people. Yes. When
why people would come minority.
Maybe everybody relaxed.
Also minority talk.
It's sort of,
it's funny the thing he said about race
because on a serious level these guys
can't say anything like that's what's
so funny about Barkley cause he's black.
He can say stuff, right. He says
that, I know you can't say it,
but I'm going to say it.
Whatever it is, you know? Yeah.
There's a lot of fucking like things
that they used to say like on a regular
basis now they can't even say.
So they've had to adjust over
the last just few years. Yeah.
Well everything's so politically
correct now and now it's Sam,
that Guy Sam got picked up by the cowboys
to get got it came out of it and say
that he was getting, yeah, so
here, that leads with a team so,
well I heard that he was,
according to Jamie, that he's a,
the reason why they picked him up is
that the cowboy is the guy who runs the
cowboys is into publicity. Oh yeah,
totally. That's exactly it. Yeah. He's,
he's a moneymaking machine.
This guy,
the cowboys had been a 500 team
for the last 10 years. Probably.
They haven't won a Superbowl
in 20 years and the the most,
they're most valuable per franchise
in America. That's incredible. Yeah.
That's hard to believe. They
have to make any sense. Thanks.
Three point $2 billion. Why?
How come they don't have to,
when they don't have to win
because of publicity. First of all,
they're called America's team. You know
who named them that? The owner themselves.
Yeah, the owner. It's that guy named
t text gram, but America's team,
they got the star and the glitter and the
fucking weight is a Dallas cowboys and
the dude's names tex.
Yeah, he went tech Graham.
He wins. Yeah. But I
mean he's, he's dead now.
But he was the one that
created that image.
Whatever happened in that show
used to do for comedy central.
That was a funny show. You used to
do like a show with football players.
It was called off sides. Well, what
happened to it was the timing was bad.
You know, if comedy central
was as big as they are now,
they could have afforded more.
But NFL films is so fucking
expensive that they just had to lift.
And we had good ratings, but it just
wasn't, you know, they, they're,
they're footage costs
so much for us to get,
and I had so much fun with the players
because they knew I wasn't a journalist,
so they were like, I get, uh,
you know, Brett Farve is okay.
So Reggie White was their
star, their team, and he said,
he recognized me because man,
I saw you on Oprah. And I said,
I can't picture you sitting
there with a Kleenex box going,
I can't believe he's two sisters never
met before. They were 21, you know,
you know. So, uh, Reggie one
that to do with thing with me,
he liked doing impressions so far of
was was the second biggest star on the
team. And he comes up to me, he
goes, what are you doing? I said,
we're doing it football show for comedy
central. You want to do it? He says, well,
what do I gotta do? I said, just, you
know, fuck you, fuck around. You know,
I'm not a journalist, but would just have
fun so I could see him. He was a little,
had some trepidations about it. I thought
I was going to maybe lay into him.
I said them so I'm fucking
this girl in the ass, right?
I mean I'm holding it down and fucked
him. Banging a no rubber, no nothing.
I aint no pussy. And he starts
laughing. He goes, are you
allowed to say this? I go,
we're not on satellite.
Then I'm just trying to make you laugh.
And then he got loose and then it,
then we had a great interview. When w
when you did that, like was the NFL
in the same position that's at now?
Was it just as popular still?
Nfls never dwindled, right?
No, it's gotten bigger and
bigger but it's bigger now.
It was the football is by far the most,
I mean I dunno about Nascar,
but the regular like athletic sports,
football is,
football is so fucking big, high school
football, college football. Know.
I think Nascar is the biggest
spectator sport, right, isn't it?
I think don't they have places like
boarded up 200,000 people or something
absurd?
Well, you know what
happens. Yeah, there's that.
But you know what also happens is
that like when you go down south,
everybody knows about Nascar.
I was on the radio once in Atlanta and
they just started talking to me about
going to Kyle all draw up and Neil
Day and this guy, I'm a home hand.
It did bring it up.
All these names.
I never even heard of this guy won
the Talladega wrong. I literally,
I go, so what are you talking about? And
they're like, we're talking about NASCAR.
You don't follow Nascar.
This guy does not follow Nascar.
Like it was so alien to them that I didn't
know who any of those guys where it's
heard about Dale Earnhardt. What about
Dale Earnhardt? So he's still doing it.
You know like you hear certain names
like escape from that world and
I mean,
I only know Tony Stewart because he was
the guy that accidentally apparently
killed that driver that got out of the
car. He said, yeah, that was fucked.
It was crazy. What the fuck was he
thinking to get? The driver got,
well Tony Stewart apparently clipped
him with his car and spun him out and he
was only 20 he's a hothead,
20 year old, you know. Jeez.
Amazing. Tony Stewart is going to race
again. It did. That's, that's nuts.
He raised again and when he came in
like 41st it came real slow, Huh?
Yeah. He can't be a dick
after won somebody over.
Imagine if you just fucking balls
to the wall clip and everybody now
or would it be just very safe driver
now he's like giving proper turn single
that he's like,
I'm going to the racetrack.
Is that a normal position for
him to be in 40th please? Oh no,
he's usually up there at the top. I
mean, I don't know that much about it,
but I bet he did try to take it slow.
Probably. It's probably a real mind.
Fuck man. I feel like
mom, it's like boom, boom.
May have seen the after he killed Duke.
Who? Kim, you know, like I, you know,
the guy should have been frightened but
Raymond was never the same after that.
No, no it wasn't. It's one
of those things, man, it's,
it's hard for guys. It's,
it's hard to also, you know, for a boxer,
you're dealing with your own
mortality too. You know, that's, uh,
that's, that's the fight that changed
fighting from 15 rounds to 12 did it,
he died in the 13th. I
believe. He, you know,
he had a bleeding on his brain
before he got hit. Got in the ring.
How do they know that? That's
what I read. I don't know.
They said that they had whatever,
that he shouldn't have been
fighting the guy, you know. Well,
I know that he was cutting
weight and that was also,
I think back when they would
weigh in the day of the fight.
But now they know more about
weight cutting. Cause man
senior was a lightweight.
So that was 135 pounds.
And I think that, uh,
I think that fight took place as
a lightweight fight. I believe.
Fought Livingstone bramble he found
a lot of great fighters. SARC whale.
He came to see me at the
Improv one night and uh,
we went out to talk and
his wife and his kid,
we're watching a show and some guy comes
up and it goes boom, boom and seen.
He goes, can I ask you something
when you hit me? Right. And,
and I said to the guy, I
said, look, you know, I said,
they can't hit you Moravians. Really
Nice Guy. Do you ever meet him?
I'm said hi to him. Real conversation
with them. You know, Youngstown, Ohio,
like real cool guy and did it
all for his father. Great Story.
And I said, look man, he can't hit you.
You know, like Raymond's like he's,
and they said, well, can I hit you
then to, to rape me? I said, no,
you can't fucking hate him. What are
you crazy kind of hit you when he said,
he said, I always wanted to see what like
a professional punch felt like, Oh God,
like the fuck I look,
I like to give them an amateur punch.
Well now he that dummy,
the guy's got a his fucking hands and
then put gloves on and then punch you.
Either you could break his hands course
with the forest that they hit. Yeah.
You could easily break your
hand on someone's forehead.
He's lucky he didn't say
it at the Vinny Corto.
Vinnie would have probably punched him.
Oh God.
I did a great thing of any one
time. Every tennis what? I Dunno,
I brought them up.
Okay.
We had this crazy fucking nut cocaine
head lived upstairs and they will fund to
doing this. Yeah, they would fuck.
And then you hear the shower and it was
like five in the morning and I stay up
late. But after a while, like I said,
too much gay turned the music down just
a little. That's all nice. You know,
next day Kim's window was broken in a car.
I knew he fucking did it.
So I go get Vinny. Vinny
looked like fucking, you know,
incredibly fucking gorilla.
Just cave man 100%.
And I get, I get a kick out of him. And
I liked the I personally, but, uh, he,
he did me a favor, come, we go up and
was like, good guy, bad guy thing.
And he kicked the door and the
kid goes, what? And I go, hey man,
I just want to ask. And he sees Vinny and
then he changed completely and he goes,
uh, you know, uh, uh, my cup,
I just wanted to tell you that somebody
broke a window. And as your neighbor,
I want to warn you that
there's somebody around here.
So just look out for yourself. And I'm
totally not really me. And Vinnie goes,
my fucking cousin, he goes, I
love him like a brother. He goes,
if anybody does fucks with dom,
I get these fucking headaches.
I don't even know what I'm doing. And
the kids go on and the guy goes, no, no,
no ma'am, I certainly didn't do it. I
go, holy fuck accused you of doing it.
Why would you say that? And,
and it goes, Vinny said,
I sleep on his couch and the afternoon,
make sure there's no fucking noise.
I'll go fucking great. And that was
it. You know, stop. The noise stopped.
Everything, stopped everything
that he'd see him at the gym.
See Vinny pressing 500 pounds at the gym.
Yeah. How you doing? How's your cousin?
That's a problem with
living in apartments. Yeah.
I had a guy that lived
below me that asked me not,
I had a pool table in my living room.
I bought this pool table us and I rented
this apartment specifically because it
had a place for the pool table. This is
the place that I lived in. Uh, when I,
when I had to stay in la though, the
first place I moved in North Hollywood,
he signed the lease. I signed the
lease and that's what made me stay.
And that's the reason why I got all
everything, News, radio, everything.
But I got this,
he was a,
it was a loft and it had this big
living room and I was like, I get doubt.
Like I measured it out. I can definitely
get a pool table in here. I'll take it.
I tell the guy this, the fucking
landlord is, shows it to me.
I'm looking for a place, that pool table,
he was below me, so, and Lord Yo, yeah,
that would the, not the landlord, but
the superintendent or whatever it is,
the guy, the guy who showed me the
place wasn't the actual landlord,
what do they call superintendents?
And so he's this,
this gay guys, really flamboyant
gay guy with his boyfriend. And um,
he co I, after I put the pool table in,
he knocks on the door and he goes, uh,
we're having an issue with
you walking around. I go,
you're having an issue with me
walking, just walking. He goes, well,
the floor creaks. I hear you walking.
What are you supposed to do? I go, okay,
well what do you want me
to do? And he goes, well,
between the hours of 5:00 PM and 10:00 PM,
you just not
not do that. I go, see, you're asking
me not to walk in the living room.
I'm not even doing anything. I'm just
walking. And he goes, he goes, oh.
So I see the game, we're gonna play here.
I go of the game, we're gonna play. I go,
well,
you're telling me is the structural
integrity of the apartment that you rented
me is not good enough for
me to actually be walking.
Just walking in the living room between
a five hour window every night when you
get home to when you go to bed, that's
what you want. He goes, yeah, I go,
is the fuck is this? I thought that's just
crazy. You can't say don't walk like a,
what if I just walk around my
pool table but I don't play.
I just walk in delivery. Like if I have
people over and they want to walk around,
look out someone. You just have to roll
or scoop. How about I put a Webcam.
You can tell when I'm walking and
when I'm just, when I'm playing pool,
so you can't get mad at me. That's
fucking apartments. That was just,
settlers kept playing pool.
Fuck him.
I had a guy wouldn't let me do the
treadmill. I, I told them, I said,
I'll do it anytime that you're
not there just to a compromise.
Anything I moved to for him,
killing me. You're killing my wife.
I said, who the fuck a buy in this
country? Go back to wherever it came, Tom,
I can't believe you took it there.
Well yeah. Well it's, I hated the guy.
Why did you have to have to
go to the immigrant place
punchy this country get the fuck back.
Who made guy,
the guy like when he said to me like,
oh I see the game we're playing.
I was like, okay, there's
no negotiating with you.
You're a ridiculous person.
I probably thought about it like probably
didn't play as much in but it takes
the fun out of it. They ain't got to
worry about some fucking nut downstairs.
It wasn't, it's the crazy
thing was it wasn't loud. It
wasn't like I moved around.
I heard
I didn't hear anything when I was walking.
I didn't hear shit.
I've been in that situation where you
hear every single footstep and they had to
end up putting carpet just to fix it.
Why had a carpet already?
It was already carpeted.
It's just a shitty building.
Cause the lady next door to me,
super nice lady,
but she would be on her phone and I to
hear every fucking word she said like I
was listening. I May. It was like,
there's no insulation in California.
That's the difference between apartments
on the east coast and department of the
West Coast is those,
those fiberglass insulation or the stuff
that they pump into the walls to keep
retain heat. They don't need that
out here, so you got wallboard Stud,
wallboard.
You basically got a fucking notebook
between you and some person who's talking
like some pretty intimate shit.
Every time she would get a phone call,
I would hear her voice,
her answering machine go on and I
would hear friends leave her messages.
That's not good. That was ridiculous.
I always think about that.
If I'm watching porn and they hear
it explore, turn it up really loud
when the guy comes,
I stopped caring.
There'd be there.
There is this too many times where I'm
just masturbating my and we look over,
notice
my windows openers to people
fencing in my backyard. I'm like,
oh you guys fencing? Yeah.
They just fence all day.
Who fences and your
name would be neighbors?
My neighbors dress up as pirates
and golf people and plants.
Burbank, man. Fucking
white people in Burbank.
They're fencing in your backyard.
They make their own costumes though.
It's pretty bad ass. But they do.
Yeah, they're mean, but very glamorous.
Like they're kings and stuff,
but pirates. What? I don't know.
So do they do like a part
of a festival or something?
I think they must work at
universal or something. Oh,
so they're practicing their trade maybe.
Hmm.
But they also have those sewing things
on like are those like things where you
so on in their windows,
like when you walk by there,
just like it looked like people
were just standing there. Oh,
the mannequins like yeah, those
snowing. Yeah. That's wow.
I guess they bake a lot of clothes.
Yeah.
When are you going to play
dress up and make your own shit?
It's probably more satisfying.
It's probably what we were talking about.
Eating the food that you kill.
Extra satisfying when you're out there
at fucking comic con Alpha that you
created yourself. We were in
Sacramento this past weekend. I did a,
the punchline you have do the
punchline Sacramento go. Oh,
what a great fucking club.
Oh, I love it. Perfect club.
Perfect size bar in the back.
Low ceiling. Tight seated. Ah,
we had so much fun there
but a while we were in town,
it was there for the UFC and there
was some sort of an anime convention,
like some sort of address up.
Dork fest was hilarious.
Just what's up layer layer.
What is that? The convention.
What's layer? What is that?
The thing that I was watching
in Sacramento. How do you know?
Are you just making shit up? That's
not what they were doing. You're wrong.
100% they were dressing like anime
characters. You Fuck? He's just this.
Jamie's into it. He's like
Qt, prudential. Norman to who?
Both this but how about
renaissance, right? We're not
talking about renaissance.
Fair of Jamie Layer.
This must be it the fuck out of here.
There's 100 million of those things.
I love it though. It's cool
because dorks getting opportunity,
they get an opportunity to hang
out with other doors, get outside,
get a little vitamin D, renaissance
faire, any of these things? Well,
this is an anime thing because people
were dressed up like superheroes and some
people were dressed up like furries.
There was like a lot of weirdness going
on that came out of Japan, right? Furries,
uh, yeah. Enemies. Just pretty much
Japan animation in their style.
Do you ever perform in Japan, dom,
that your people know he's the Escobar?
It's not funny. It's a the Moo.
My eyes were opened. I knew you back in
the day. I got a picture of Joey Diaz.
I'm going to put on Instagram later today.
I got his headshot that
I found in my office,
so he used to have on the wall is from,
he was walking 220210220 pounds.
Crazy.
I can't believe it's the
same guy. We'll see ways is
three, depends on how high he is.
When you ask him
wasn't dog.
He used to go on stage and he would
talk on stage. He goes, listen dog,
I'm 45 years old. I got no time for this
bullshit. I'm 50 years old. I got no time.
And again, the same set, we'll give
you three or four different ages.
Went through the fat blob.
He's like, don't talk about it.
It's just my little thing.
It's just a little fat bomb thing that
he had to get removed from his like
shoulder head. So it was weird.
He told me, he just said,
I love that guy. I fucking love that
guy. Love him to death. He's so much fun.
There's no more fun guy to be around.
Like, like when you bring him to shows,
like everybody's funnier
to the show's funnier.
The comics on the show or funny
or you're funny, you're backstage.
Everybody is funnier. I love him
too. And where's the CO headline?
A couple of times. What a blessed, so
much fun. I told you what he said to me,
right? What? I said, Joe, I don't
care who goes on first or second,
whatever you want. It goes
dumber. Ever tell you what,
why don't you close the first
shows and I'll close the second.
So you don't have to follow a fucking
pig lake me and then you could do it and
then you can do it at the laugh
factor if you want. I said,
so you're not only do me a
favor, you threaten, you get
me spots and other clubs.
He said he's a great dude. He is.
His podcast is doing fantastic too.
And that's one of the things that I
really love about the Internet, that um,
you know, a guy like Joey
could be Joey. He would never,
no one would ever understand him unless
he saw him in the uncensored form,
like on this pilot and I never understand.
Or his podcast dose in that kid that
still does that. You'd give him
mushrooms yet it gives him stuff.
He doesn't tell him who Joey to what
kid is it little friend that always
hanging, what is his name?
Lee. Yeah, he doses him. Yeah.
It keeps those to them like fucking like
roofie in him while he's not fucking
him. I don't have a problem with
that. If you're around Joey. No,
not to eat any of the shit. He
toast Burke. Chrysler's Dad.
I know Keith Burke crisis dad edible weed,
and it bursts like,
what are you doing? And He's
like, his dad was like, oh,
I'm just eating some candy that
Joe gave. He goes, that's how I can
listen. Cock sucker. You
Dad's gotta live gotta live.
He's Tom Ziglar has a fucking hilarious
story about the same thing that I said
about getting high with Joey
on the plane where he's,
he just throwing down these Chiba Chews.
That's Joe Joey in the middle of a panic
attack, like eight another cheap shoes.
He doesn't give a fuck man. He goes deep.
He's one of the funniest people I know.
He's bad comedy store. Yeah, he said
that it's been a good challenge that,
that he forgot how, how that room
was. You know, when you're on stage,
well they don't know you that you don't,
they don't know your comment
there for Jelly. Yeah. Yeah.
It's a different kind of a group.
You know,
you've got to develop material that like,
you set it up differently.
You got to introduce it
differently because they're
not expecting you to be that
this raucous, crazy, you know,
giant Cuban guys done a ton of coke
in his life, you know what I mean?
They don't know what to what,
what he's doing.
They just see a guy on stage and then
they have to slowly but surely be
introduced to his ideas.
What's going on there,
whether it's they're trying to stop
people from smoking weed where at the
college.
Is that true?
There's a rumor that uh,
that, that might be true,
but not the management. Like, you
know, what are you going to stop,
go hide in the back?
That sounds like the dumbest idea ever.
That's like telling football players
and stopped doing steroids. Yeah.
That's so stupid. Yeah. What do
you think keyless, the comedy star,
what are you gonna do to
stop him from drinking too?
Well, it's just one person that wants
to do it and then he's not, I mean,
that's ridiculous.
He have power that one person.
No, I doubt it. I have no idea.
His name rhymes with Pauly shore.
I Dunno. I don't go there anymore. I'm
just talking about in my ass. Yeah,
that going to go now? I don't think
so. I can't. I talk to Scotty,
Scotty shores, my buddy, I talked to him
when I was down in San Diego. I was like,
just say I just too much of a
bad feeling about that place.
I love when you come in for breaking
balls. I love doing your show,
your show the laugh back.
See the laugh factory doesn't have any
negative feeling to me. Especially now,
you know. Now it seems like there's
like a whole new crew there.
It's a kind of a different, yeah,
different sort of a vibe there.
But you,
if you go to the comedy store ever,
especially everyone that you've met
through desk while like Justin Martindale,
Tony Jeremiah, they're just everywhere
now and there. It's all positive.
It's like a huge family and when
somebody from the outside comes in,
it's like a whole family
looking at that person. Yeah,
but the person that comes in doesn't
want you smoking weed and I'm going to
smoke weed. If I go to the comedy
store, we all do it. What if,
what if you get banned from smoking weed?
I have a license.
No,
you can't just can't say I
have a lifestyle that the
liquid smoke in your house.
Well you know we were upstairs
when we, when, when it's private.
Just the acts really let
you smoke inside upstairs.
Oh Hey this isn't blowing it down.
All those people get the show better
as glass nail in between. So
yeah, that's a great thing.
He's got it set up up there.
That's a sweet thing.
Other than when they're in between shows
like Friday and Saturday with the two
shows. It's, it's basically a
club for the acts. We can relax.
I don't mind going there. I, you know, I,
I like the laugh factor when I do it
with you. It's got a good vibe, you know?
Oh I love it. I love that
shit with you. Thanks.
I always fun with the interview.
Yeah.
If you ever seen breaking balls
with dom Irrera he does a show,
he fucks around with the audience,
does material that brings up a comic
and then fucks around with the comic
inbetween and then brings up the next
comic relief. Yeah, it's fun. It's fun.
It's fun because you know,
Don, you're, you're at your
best. Well I wouldn't say it.
You're at your best. You're always, I
mean, you're always funny on stage, but I,
I love the particular type of funny
when you just fucking around. That's,
that's what I liked.
Yeah. Like when we did
the, uh, kill Tony shared with the ice
house. Yeah. We were crying and lift. Oh,
so fun. It was so fun. That was,
that was really, really, really fun.
And for those comics to get a guy like
you fucking with them and you know,
talking about their material.
I mean, a lot of those guys,
it was the first time they ever
went onstage. That's amazing.
Imagine that the first time you ever go
on stage and you get a guy who's been
doing comedy forever, it's been
on HBO, a legend in comedy,
and he's critiquing your act. That's,
that's, he's busting your balls.
It's as good as you could ever hope for.
I mean that's a beautiful moment.
The idea killed Tony is a great idea.
That should be a comedy central show.
She's totally sell. That shit is
on the schedule. It's a great idea.
Comics do a minute, you know it's,
and it's especially fun.
We did it at the Ice House because the
ice house has such a good feeling to it
and then the room is perfect.
Yeah, this is totally rooms good.
Just like the belly room. Yeah, about
the same size amount of seats. Right.
Belly rooms, like a
hundred seats, 90 seats,
so it was that room with the Ice House
has an annex. They have a big room,
which is not a big room.
Anyway,
the big room was only like
190180190 something like that.
And then they have the smaller room,
which is only about 80 or
90 and it's fucking amazing.
Yeah.
I liked that main room.
I think that's my favorite room cause
that's barely ever used. It was,
and it used to be such a famous room.
Started there three, three
Saturday night shows out. Yeah.
But the main room late at night when
there's only like 10 people in the room,
like it's fucking sad.
Yeah, no, no. Unless it's like
Brody Stevens or something.
I prefer those where it's just him.
I was in the main room once back in
the Joey Diaz days with Joey Diaz had,
uh,
Jeff,
you know Jeff the piano man [inaudible]
he had Jeff play Ozzy Osborne and he got
on stage and took his shirt
off and he's singing war pigs.
He's singing at Joey
Diaz is singing on stage.
And it was fucking one of the greatest
things I've ever seen in my life because
he's completely committed to it. He
had no shirt on. And the audiences,
maybe there was for audience members
and the rest of the audience was,
all comics were all just hanging out.
And Joey deals is onstage and they're
fucking with the lights. No, it wasn't.
It wasn't Jeff. It was the other guy
who did the, the main room. Mike. Fuck,
is that his name? Mike. The guy with
the glasses? Yeah. Yes. Great Dude.
Who was in a band? Another guy. He
didn't have classes. He was in a band.
You remember that guy? I was like, what's
up dude? Hey Dude. Yeah, he's still there.
What's his name? Uh, Shit. Do
you know what I'm talking about?
I think I got the wrong guy.
I was talking about Mike who is the
manager of playing piano. No, no, no, no.
I know you're talking about the guy
who handled the sound and the shit.
Now it's not Jeb, Danny,
Danny, Danny, Danny, Danny.
Danny is playing a war.
Pigs, you know, and uh,
and Joey Diaz is on stage
screaming the lyrics too,
along with the sound that's coming over
the loudspeaker, which is, you know, Ozzie
and they're doing like the different
color lights, like Joey's on stage.
And I just sat back and
we were all barbecued.
We're all completely
baked out of her mind.
Sat back and laughed and we
were all just clapping and just,
it was such a pure performance.
It's great cause he wasn't
trying to impress anybody.
There was no one there to see him.
There was no audience.
It was just us having fun and like,
like I said,
maybe four people in the crowd maybe.
Yeah.
That's some shit that only takes
place at the comedy store. I,
that's why I love it. It feels like
you're just hanging out with your friends,
getting wasted, you know, and having fun
and getting, it's just playing around in,
you know,
doing silly shit.
And you would think because it's the
comedy store that it would be packed all
the time. It's the gut is getting
in. Let her location. No you can't.
It's got this name. You
know, like when I was a, uh,
an open miker we'd heard about the
comedy store. It was like Mecca.
It was like I would always wanted
to be at the comedy store, you know,
to me like getting,
becoming a paid regular at the comedy
store was more important that getting my
first television show. It's
interesting. Yeah. Cause it was, it was,
that was the spot that was her Kinison
came from. That was what prior came from.
They all started the comedy store.
So when I was there and you would,
I would show up the first time I was
there, it wasn't even half full. I was,
I was there at the, in the or and
like some terrible actors on stage,
some fucking singing,
nothing. Some was blue.
It was dog shit. And I remember
going, this is the common, he's like,
what the fuck is going on?
But this is this place.
I would expect it to be like when
you see live in the sunset strip,
like a line around the block,
the WHO's who of Hollywood's,
they're the greatest comics in the world
are all going up. Nope. It was like
when I first went out, what year was
that? 85. It was like that was it.
Like that was the Kinison
days, right? Yeah. Yeah.
Well I first went there and uh, he used
to go on right before Sam at the end.
Wow. Um, we became friends, a lot
of, a lot of laughs. A lot of,
a lot of fucking lips to blow with them.
What's that?
Did you ever do blow with him? No. I
thought he said, did you ever blow?
Did he ever offer it to, you know, he knew
me. He knew I wasn't, I see
the thing about Sam and I,
we were, it could be friends,
but I'm not a follower and I
don't want to be a leader either,
but I just rather just paying
and you know, I was, I like,
I would never be part of his entourage.
Yeah. He had a whole cult of following.
Right. And the outlaws. Yeah. And, but
we had a lot of fun together. I mean,
we had a lot of laughs.
I was always glad when he was there.
I passed the first time I auditioned
there and then she forgot me.
So then I had to audition again,
you know?
But yeah, it was fun. It was amazing.
You know, cause I remember him,
Roseanne couldn't get on in the
main room and couldn't get on.
She couldn't get a spot in the main
room. When was this? In 85 she couldn't.
I thought she was already huge in 85 no,
this was probably later than 85 yeah,
I always heard that. Right when she moved
here. She got to show the same day. Yeah,
she means she was giant.
Oh No. Oh God. Look,
I remember working in Vegas with her and
she couldn't get on that. She was good.
She, she all she wanted, there was
a spot in the first show. Main Room.
Why that was the money spots cause that's
when we would all make four or $500,
which was a lot then, you know, write,
write, write town. I used to make,
well I started out at the
comedy store in Hawaii. I went,
I had a very circuitous route
to the comedy store in Hawaii.
I did the Hawaii with Barry Sobel
and carry snow. Then I went to,
uh, I went to a la Jolla, did well there,
went to Vegas and that went well.
And then I went that.
And so I didn't really start doing the
common story until I had done like the
tour. Wow. That weird. They
had a Westwood one too, right?
That was a little before my time.
Westwood.
It was on West Wood Avenue in the Westwood
one was where Kennison really like
started out.
That's where you're really like develop.
Apparently I took a friend
of mine who's a priest,
is the reason I went in to see the,
the room and Sam was on and my
friend's hair was back. I said,
it's not always like this.
It's, especially back then,
nobody knew who Sam was. Nobody saw that
coming. Oh, it was fucking incredible.
Incredible energy. Yeah. That, um,
the comedy store had a whole like series
of clumps and now they're down to how
many were there and they were all
consumed. People owned them. Well,
there was a dog. Mitzi. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
not the same people. Same One person.
All right. Yeah. Let's see. You still
make a lot of money in Vegas, man. Yeah.
Why don't they out? Well, obviously
now it's a mass, but so what,
think the comedy store in Vegas
would be a no brainer. You know,
what happened to the original one?
They should, they should have.
They raised it because, uh,
the Bellagio bought it out.
That's where the Bellagio is
now. I would think that, um,
that would be a no
brainer for a franchise.
I mean Improv's are all over the country.
It's amazing that the comedy store never,
yeah,
the impact is really
knew how to franchise it.
And Jamie and Jamie's doing it too. Yeah.
Yeah. With Chicago and Vegas. Right.
You were just in the laugh
factory back in Chicago with me.
I'm going there in October by the,
I give you a $2 to do a full weekend,
but you'll be at laff factory.
It's a lot of money for a of factory.
He really off for your shit.
Money.
I usually air allegedly
and we're on the air.
Allegedly. He got a pair of deal
allegedly now they fixed it. I have no,
I have no tech. Nope.
That's what makes you funny.
If you had tacked, we'd get in the
way of a lot of good jokes. Thank you.
Joseph would right? Yeah. Tact with
the fucking shitty old for you.
Hey Dominic,
smoothing out your mess and
how you got a know mess.
I didn't know herpes couldn't move to
the, but I, from talking about earlier
herpes, you could shut the
fuck up. I think that um,
Mitzi like had an issue with like the
idea of franchising because they had to be
comedy store comics and if you had
franchise a certain point in time,
you seen it down, the more we
need 365 days a year, you know,
she would have a seven night a week show
at 365 days a year of good comics and
you're flying him out to
Louisville, Kentucky. Good luck.
There's no one's going to do a week.
No. I mean this is Vegas clubs.
Like they used to do that at the Riv.
Right. You would do Monday through Sunday.
You'd do the whole week.
Yeah. Yeah. You'd have to,
you'd have to stay for seven days. I
go and get calls from buddies. Yeah.
They didn't make me do that.
I did Thursday through Sunday.
I just did Friday and Saturday.
I did the late night shows because I
couldn't do the regular show at the river.
I could only do remember that extreme,
extreme extreme. You and Slayton. Yeah.
Thank God I would, I
couldn't do it. I can't,
I can't do Vegas from more
than a couple of days.
I Love Vegas for a couple of days.
It was killing me.
How many days you do this past one. Uh,
for, but I went in early and it came,
came back late and so Wednesday through
Monday or something like that. Yeah. That,
that's when I, cause I didn't want to fly
in the heat. Right. Like go to the floor.
I can't fucking take that.
I didn't intend to Greece.
I'm very delicate artists. What's
your favorite place to work in Vegas?
Yeah.
Uh Oh God. That's what
Beth to see. That's,
that's a bad question is a bad question.
Why? Because you just worked for Jamie.
You don't want to tell the truth.
Well you know it was for act
like to tell you it was fun.
It was a fucking great job.
Was I opened for Cher for years in the
early nineties when we did the Mirage.
The Mirage is great.
They used to call me easy money cause I
would be at the sports book and this is
when I could still fucking jump.
I'd hop over to fucking rail just a minute
to eight because everything starts on
time there. Boom. I fucking slide
across the stage, do my stew,
25 minutes and then I go in the
back of the crew fucking with me.
They'd have a chair and a towel and
water. You'll KZ money. All right guys.
Almost a 26 tonight.
I went crazy.
That was a fun game. You say hop over
the sports book. We betting. Yeah.
So you'd gamble up until the moment you're
supposed to go on stage and he'd run.
It was a big gambler, but
yeah, I would bet on games
and stuff. I like to watch it.
I like it to stretch out.
I don't want to put everything on
black and then leave a fucking loser.
Well if you,
especially like if you're a sports fan,
it makes the game more exciting, right?
Oh yeah. Well that makes everything,
I mean that's what I love
about Benton football. Like,
like with the pro football starting
tomorrow night. I fucking love it.
I love the over under the over under is,
yeah,
I loved that because especially if you're,
I'm pretty over because you rooting
for everybody. It's all positive.
Like the unders,
all negative.
Don't drop that tear drop that peers
can get that motherfucker. I was like,
but the overall is fun. Yeah. Positive
beddings by the negative Bennett. Yeah.
There's a cheer sometimes in Vegas.
If you watch a boxing match,
they'll have an over
under on how many rounds?
The bet that and then it'll hit
the fifth round. Everybody goes
like there's a roar in the crowd.
Yeah.
Like I think it was Larry Merchant that
actually brought it up once during a
broadcast.
Yeah.
The reason why these people were cheering
because cause they gambled won it.
Yeah. There's a lot of
proposition bets like that.
Like you could bet a
bunch of fights parlay.
Put them all together if you get them all
right. It's sane amount of money. Never.
Aubrey is a big gambler.
He always Campbell's in Vegas.
He's never hit that shit yet. He's gotten
close though. It's always one shit.
Judge's decision fucks you up. I
can't get into it. Gambling on fights,
gambling on anything. Why not even
slot machines and all that stuff.
It's just for fun. It's not right. Like
I'm addicted to it or cards. Nothing.
Bedding. It's probably good. Yeah, it's
probably good that you don't do that.
I just don't know shit.
It just hit me.
I realized my favorite club
to work in Vegas. Bread,
carrots club cause it working there
in October. I can't believe it.
It just hit me. Use Club
was a Tropicana, but now
I didn't just hit up a memory. Lost
it for real. A real memory loss.
You always talk about Brad Garret's.
I was waiting for you to bring it up.
I was wondering why. I thought you were
out of reverence to Jamie. Well, it's,
it gets my bread. I was, I
worked for dad out of body,
but the Mike Collab is bad.
You got to see his club with
these fucking chicks there.
Switch one that Brad Carrow.
I'm like, God, they got,
did you ever since you book a
weekend when I'm there for UFC,
I would love to MGM. Right? How often? Uh,
yeah, downstairs. The Mgm, it looks Nice.
I pass by it. I've never
performed there. We did that once.
I remember we had a couple of times I
was there for your uh, your fights. Yeah,
but I never got to see
you at Brad Garrett. Um,
there's a bunch of UFC is coming up.
So how often do you go to, to Vegas?
How often you do it? Three. Three or
four times a year. What about January?
You got anything booked in January?
The weekend of January 2nd.
That's the weekend. The UFC is going
to be in Vegas like great fights too.
It's like I could do that. Let's do it
doable and you can come during the day.
You can see the fight started for so
you could watch the fights from like,
what's the first show at eight?
There's only one show. What time is it?
I don't know if you'd get them
to do it at 10. That's the shit.
But dumb. Get them. Do it a 10.
You can see all the fisticuffs then get
over there with ample time and then eat
mushrooms at 11 what is it?
It's, it's at the MGM sometimes.
Sometimes at Mandalay bay.
Sometimes MGM.
Those are the only two places
I was at the palm one time.
They used to do it at the palm. They don't
do it at the palm anymore. Dana White,
uh, he gambles too much and he
broke them. Smash the palm. Yeah.
Did he really? Yeah, he smashed him.
They banned them when they banned them.
He pulled the UFC out and they started
doing the smaller events at the hard rock.
He was winning. Oh yeah. Wow. He
wins. He wins. Big Man. He Bent,
he loses big money, but he
gambles big money. He gets crazy.
You like $1 million a night. Wow.
Oh my God. Yeah. I don't get it.
I don't know how you could do that.
It's like keep a pulse and not fucking
scares me. Sweat all your blood out.
It seems like, it just seems like I
would if I lost $1 million in a night,
I was totally quit. But he's won like
five or six months, not really gambling.
You know what gambling is?
If you have a plot,
a guy who's better equal to you and
pull and you play pool, that's gambling.
Right?
But you're not,
you know these fuck casinos wouldn't
have crystal chandelier is that people
really gambling?
The odds are set against them.
They definitely are set against you.
But if you're good at certain
games like blackjack, yeah,
there's a more of a level field. I mean
certain things are fucking ridiculous.
Slot machines. Desert ridiculous.
Yeah. They post the rigged.
It's not even like it's a machine.
Like they set them,
they can set them to easier or harder.
Like they can decide whether or
not you're going to win or lose.
Like they could set it.
So it's one person wins a month,
you know video poker to you. Yeah,
because you sit there, you get the drinks.
What ain't nobody you'd under
no anybody like blackjack toys.
Like keep your hands off the
table, sir. Not like that. Crazy.
People get pissed at you.
I've heard people say that like if you,
if you're playing
blackjack at a bad table,
when someone doesn't know what
they're doing, they fuck up the hand.
How could they fuck? I mean,
I see what they're saying,
but that's a weird way of looking
at it that they fuck up your hand.
Like what kind of a whack ass game
are you playing with someone else?
Making shitty decisions affects you.
They affect the card count. Yeah.
They make the, you know,
whenever I'm craps too,
I don't even understand that fucking
name, that deck games. Ridiculous.
You've got to know too much.
Yeah. Richard. Jenny used
to have a bit about crabs.
It's fucking funny. Bit
Too. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
About how he doesn't like a
certain games because like he,
he, he liked games where nobody
knows what the fuck is going on.
That's what this whole thing about craps.
So funny bit man,
that he did that bit like on the
tonight show, I think. I never saw that.
I used to love his ref bit.
Let's see if we can find it. See,
see if you can find Richard
Jenny on craps and we'll,
we'll end with this at a respect for
our late friend Mitch, the Jenny.
He's a guy we've talked about a hundred
times on the, on the podcast that, uh,
he doesn't get enough respect.
Fucking great. Stand the,
Oh yeah, man. When he was,
when he was the best,
when he like in the late eighties ish,
somewhere around there like
88 89 he was one of the best,
one of the best in the country.
Just did,
but didn't get that sort of like
the same respect like Kennesaw.
I think rich is brilliant.
I don't think he had the charisma.
That's my x that are not
as good as him or put,
get bigger than him because you know,
is this a Brian?
No, no. Richard. Jeni craps on
craps. Just written no, but on crap.
That's why it, cause that's
it. This came up as the second.
Okay,
let's give her a shot.
Okay.
We're stressor.
He dressed like a guy who
he's on a boat.
Oh, always can always in a
good mood around holidays.
I had a great thanksgiving boy. I was
so thankful. Thankful on Thanksgiving.
Yeah. Look at that Turkey
and I'm thinking, Hey,
life is tough and you have problems,
but nobody ever cuts a hole in your
ass and filled you with mushrooms. Wow.
Bravo.
Jay Leno was edging.
Imagine problems without bringing
up that model of self restraint.
President Bill Clinton won a guy.
Gotta give him credit.
You gotta give the Guy I can't get my
girlfriend. The smoke, the Gar. Backtrack.
I guess the thing that annoys people is,
you know,
you kind of want the president to be
a hero when it turns out, you know,
Clinton is just like every other stupid
guy. He can't turn down oral sex.
He can't. You get no Guy Dad, because
I couldn't buy in to do activities.
No guy ever gets tired up one sec to not
moving at all so big they can't believe
it's happening. At the same time, there's
been able to remote in exam, which going,
those are the big Joe.
I'm not moving.
I'm with my girl can talk.
What's better than,
I don't know if this is the cramps bit.
Hopefully this is really one at a time,
Huh? No. You know,
I think she'd be president. You
hear me out here? Jack Kevorkian.
You know why he doesn't lie.
This guy has nerve [inaudible] himself
and 60 minutes ending a guy's life so you
can get arrested on purpose
and if he's going to fix it,
he's going to starve himself in jail
as a protest. Now that is courage.
That's commitment. That's the
guy standing up and saying, hey,
I don't want to live. If it means
I can kill other people. Nerve
nerve. I mean think about
it. Think of a comparison.
You Know Bill Clinton commits adultery
live and squirmed and would've been if it
was single person Jack and warhead commit
first degree murder and broadcast on
national television. He is not
the type of guy with Jay. No,
I didn't do it.
Not Him.
He'd be on the White House lawn having
sex with an intern and doing bong hits
out of the death machine.
How much time is listening to us?
Okay,
did give it a little bump and
it has been to make the segue.
Well, I'm happy if it's
doing its job. Mean
it was depressing out gravy was pointed
right at his crotch and he goes, Dave,
nope.
Anyway.
Jessa isn't that weird?
That sort of tonight's show type comedy
where you have like seven minutes,
five minutes. Yeah. Sort of rushing that
every bit I hate. Right in those sets. I,
last time I did it was a Jimmy Fallon
and I had fun because I liked Jimmy and
then you know the band,
but it's like they're still fucking when
he was doing his show or the TV show,
his show. Yeah. It's hard. It's
hard. It's not real comedy.
It's a uh,
like a clue.
It's like the difference between a
preview to a movie and the actual movie
itself. Yeah, I think that's a
good way of putting it. I mean,
there's no soul to it. Yeah,
he can't, he can't get deep.
Everybody knows it's only going to last
five minutes and you have a few minutes
and you just wrap it up and that's over.
I've seen a couple of guys,
I mean Silento was perfect
for that. Well, Richard,
Jenny was really good at it too, cause
they look real good joke writer out of it.
He was rich.
W was he flushed out bits so well that
the tick took away from that part of him.
You know what I mean? Yeah. That was his,
that was his number one thing that
he was really good at and that's,
I learned that from him actually.
I've talked about it before about how
to really like get the most out of a big
thing out of his subject. What is it?
A card table. Dating card table. No,
I don't think that's it on craps
playing craps. Maybe playing craps.
It was an old bit.
So the,
all those looked like there were
two too recent for it to be him.
No worries. It's over folks.
Fucking podcasts over dot.
Merera I love you to death too,
Joe. Thanks for having me on buddy.
Thanks anytime my friend and we'll uh,
do your show breaking balls at the
laugh factory soon and I'll uh,
I'll put it down to come
and do my podcast again.
Can you keep Jamie Masada out of the room
again, room. We did it one more time.
One more time. Keep him out of the
room. By the way, I love your Joe.
Why are you so mean to me, Joe? I
love Jamie too. That's a good guy.
And uh, he promises to pay Brian
more money than the opiates.
Hey,
this podcast is brought to you by 10.
Go to rogan.ting.com enter in the code
word nothing cause I already said it.
rogan.ting.com save yourself 25 bucks.
You're flux.
And we're also brought to you by audible.
Go to audible.com forward slash Joe,
get your free audio book. We recommend
Burt Chryslers, the life of the party.
Get your free audio book and uh,
up to one free month of audible service,
the number one provider for
audio content on the Internet,
audible.com forward slash
Joe for a free book.
And we're also brought to you last but not
least by on at.com. That is o n N. I t.
Use the codeword Rogan and save 10%
off any and all supplements. Uh,
it's 72 hour sale,
has one day,
18 hours and 10 minutes.
Uh, if you're, uh,
right now it's five 51 on September 3rd.
So if you get that,
use the code words CEP,
Sep 72 and save 15% off anything.
All right,
we love the fuck out of you.
And we will react to mar desk,
squad.tv shop squad.tv for all of
Brian's original artwork and tee shirts,
all of it done by Brian packaged by Brian,
sent by Brian all through
stamps.com and have a sponsor. Um,
we'll be back tomorrow with a,
the young and dangerous
Tony Hinchcliffe until none.
Be Cool with each other and spread love
and give kisses. Mock. There's
one for you. See you soon. Bye.