Four three,
two,
one,
boom.
So I took a four and a half hour ride
down to San Diego because my friend
Brendan was felony to showtime.
Special.
Yeah.
And it was run the jewels the entire way
down and back.
It was awesome.
Thank you.
Whew.
I wish I could work out as hard as
people work out.
Tried music.
Well,
I've lost 31 pounds,
but I'd be 90 pounds out easy now.
That was one of the things that I was
saying.
This is workout music.
Yeah,
it is.
It is an elder and I are Chubby is too
fat,
but,
well,
you were saying you lost 31 pounds.
31 may be picked up three over the
holidays.
But I'm,
I'm,
I'm on my path.
I really am.
Shouts out to Al Clayborne,
um,
who's from out here?
Who's a hell of a trainer?
If I had his discipline,
I'd already be a hundred pounds down,
but the gold is a hundred and the next
18 months you can do it.
Yeah.
I'm not 100% just eat bad and got lazy.
But you know what,
man,
you could turn her.
It's one of those things where you just,
if you could stick with it for 90 days,
it will become a part of your life.
Well that's the goal.
That's the goal.
You know what I mean?
And,
and,
and I'm,
I'm about it.
Like,
cause I like meat so I still get to eat
me and I like green stuff and I don't
like salad dressing.
So I think it's going to be relatively
easy for me.
Yeah.
Like olive oil and vinegar does not
taste bad bro.
I don't even use that.
Like when I have a salad,
one wife make salad,
she literally will make the salad.
She may add a little goat cheese or not.
She'll,
she'll throw some chicken or some steak
on there.
But if it's fruit in the salad,
I don't need any salad dressing.
Just throw some strawberries and apples
or stuff to salting to just give me that
strive juicing.
And I'm good.
If I could figure out during that three
to four times a day versus the one meal
and with my wife and then he didn't like
trash in the studio.
I'll be,
that's the problems from the temptation
rules.
And you see burgers and fries.
Yeah.
Fuck it.
You see a Coca Cola?
Yeah.
That,
that really is it for me.
I had to quit sodas because the worst,
which is,
which brings me to cripple cola.
Yeah.
So what is critical to bottles of it?
But I wanted to keep it in the
frigerator.
I wanted to join it and it's perfect
temperature,
Coca Cola,
Pepsi Cola,
rse color,
anything with Cola.
Right.
Has probably killed more Americans than
anything else in the world.
Right?
So anything that's color,
cause Coca Cola was provided tons of
jobs in my hometown.
I won't want to diss them.
They might promote a concert,
am I right?
But we know that sugary drinks aren't
good for you.
Right?
Yet we don't have an aversion to,
we don't criminalize sugar.
And my doctor Larry told me,
Michael,
sugar is poison,
right?
I want you to work it out of your diet.
But these kids that are members of these
little punk ass street fraternity's
essentially gangs we criminalize and
villainize a bunch of teenagers who
simply don't have anything to do.
They don't have jobs,
they don't have skills,
they don't have organization,
they don't have police athletic league
like they used to.
They don't have people engaging them in
academics or sports where they used to.
So they just kind of,
you know,
mess off,
fuck off.
Sometimes fuck up in violence happens,
right?
If you could take those same kids with
the entrepreneurial spirit that will
sell your water on the side of a highway
and you add it to something to public
already wants anyway,
Cola,
you create something like Cripple Colin
[inaudible] and essentially what you're
doing is creating the same sugary shit
that we all go buy and drink and we
should.
And now we're given the structure of say
a hell's angels to say,
yeah,
you could say were criminal
organization,
but we still can sell your fucking tee
shirt because we are now paying our
taxes.
We're now employing people and we're
were now doing what we're supposed to
do.
And that's what I wanted to give the
gift of my friends who are hurt,
who are members of street fraternities.
And we actually pulled it off at the
show.
These guys actually managed to bring
something in microcosm to the market in
Atlanta.
It did well enough for us to keep
continue doing it.
And I want to see how far I can go.
And what's in it?
Sugar,
water,
artificial for artificial arm.
Uh,
what is it?
Food,
color and flavor.
And that's it.
And I think it's six ingredients.
Total wheels,
does it,
have you ever,
do you know what Zevia is even fuck with
cvs?
I mean the fake sugar and stuff you use,
it's no,
Zvm has a soft drinks that are made with
Stevia.
Yeah.
But the thing is like,
you know,
what I found out when me was sugar is
either just do it or don't.
Like for me it's easy to do things that
are actually a real,
just sugar,
like a Mexican coke or just have,
you know,
some carbonated water and lemons in it.
I don't do well with irritation.
This cadillac in the hand job.
I want the whole thing.
I know what you're saying,
but this stuff is good.
It's,
it's different.
[inaudible] who has adjusted Bieber?
He's did it.
It's just I am such an addict as shut
the real thing.
Yeah.
So it doesn't make sense for me
sometimes to tempt myself.
I'll do is trump water.
I just,
I do a lot of water now,
a lot more water now and I do a lot of
club soda with lime,
which I used to talk shit to lp about.
I'm a chicken white guy,
drinks and now it's l is ordering a
fucking,
you know,
he's ordering a drink,
drink and I'm just like,
yeah,
I'll take a club soda in La.
That's good man.
If you could stick on that path.
Shouts out to my man Bariloche.
Um,
who is a friend and mentor.
A lot of times you might see a guy with
me.
Um,
does security bear introduce me to
Shaolin Kung Fu?
You mean basically kicking and punching
and moving around.
And he also introduced me to a lot of
the guests that are on your show.
Um,
including,
you know,
guests that talk about intermittent
fasting,
the talks about getting rid of the
sugars and stuff,
and he just loves me like a big brother.
So he keeps me in tune with what's going
on.
[inaudible] actually introduced me to
Stevia.
Always good to know God like that.
It's got its finger on the pulse.
I liked getting to know people.
They're smarter than me,
so I don't have to learn as much.
I can just go to them with questions.
Yeah.
That's the move.
I don't,
I don't like being the smartest guy.
No,
Nah.
Well,
I don't have that choice.
That's,
that option's not possible.
You need to get another rule of your
smart as fuck that.
Yeah.
I mean,
talking to Ilan Musk on the show about
that when he was,
I'm talking to me about the thoughts
that are bouncing,
bouncing around inside of his head that
he can't control,
and then he's like,
it's always been his whole life.
Like you wouldn't want to be me.
I was like,
Jesus Christ.
I'm just thinking about it.
I thought I did something to cool
smoking with mar and that was definitely
cool.
But you get an elan musk to fucking
smoke is classic stoner history in the
making right there.
Yeah.
I didn't even see,
the thing about it is if I had any idea
that
people would react to it that way.
I mean I would just do that on a normal
show.
That's normal.
Yeah,
California.
It's legal or smoke weed.
It's no big deal.
It's fun.
It's a slick,
a comradery thing.
Everybody thinks,
oh,
everybody's sharing space together.
It's a piece by week.
Absolutely.
It's one of the only things that you sip
off that another man's lips touched.
Like everybody does it right.
I will.
Women too,
but we just don't admit to ourselves
that there's another guy.
That's true.
But that's like it's been washed.
Yeah.
Joint to joint.
The person,
they'll be like,
oh no,
wash.
Like if someone wanted to give you a
haul off of their cigar,
try this.
He'd be like,
get the fuck out of here.
I've actually had,
I asked,
Noriega did that to me.
Manwell nory Noriega the rapper.
Oh,
evictor Santiago Maldef,
smoking cigars out of smoke cigars and
Don Koch,
and I'm not a cocaine user,
but I would have definitely,
you know,
my wife talked about going to Columbia
and I said,
honey,
I've never said this to you.
She said,
what?
I said,
if we're going to Columbia,
we're going to do cocaine.
I said,
of all the places in the world,
no to cocaine everywhere from Dubai to
Denver,
but in Colombia I say,
fuck it.
We're here with the source.
Yeah.
When you're in Hawaii,
you eat poi.
Yeah.
You know,
you go to a Luau.
I would try for sure.
Those leaves the chewing of the Columbia
and Peru when you,
as you ascend up the mountain of shots
out there,
mortal technique.
My Peruvian raw rap friends.
I love that too.
Yeah,
I do too.
I stayed,
man,
he's been on a couple of times.
He's a great guy and a great human
being,
man.
Dude,
that guy brought me a plate of his
grandma's food to the podcast studio.
That's how down home that dude is.
He's one of the best movies,
a plate of food.
He's a great human man.
Like he's a great,
he like,
that's more of the stuff I'm saying
people need to do instead of arguing
ideas and extreme do you need to get
with people who don't look like you are
not culturally a light and you need to
allow them to do things like that
because that creates friendships,
empathy and builds bridges instead of
burning.
Well,
he's just a real dude.
He is.
He's a real dude.
Like who he is.
I mean that is who he is.
He's got very strict ethics in his mind.
He's essentially smart.
He's like a soldier in terms of he how
he thinks and operates and takes care of
his people and moves.
You know,
he took me on my first tour with rap
music as what?
Rap Music before me and Ella went out
together.
I went out with him,
you know what I mean?
And we ran through the south together
and I just,
he was just pro all the way and we
became friends and I just love him to
death now.
And I go to war with them any day.
Yeah.
He's a great dude.
I've hung out with him a few times,
like him a lot.
He came to my mother's funeral.
God bless his soul,
Teddy.
Really?
Yeah.
I believe that.
That sounds like him.
Yeah.
It's a,
there's good people out there,
man.
Even in show business,
wacky ass show business people.
Yeah.
There are good people who shelby is none
of the people in the officer's you can
trust,
but the talent,
we're okay.
Yeah.
Well the officer's,
there's some folks out there,
there's some good agents and good
pieces.
They get a bad rap.
You know what it is,
man,
it's just fucking hard.
QMAP imagine how hard it is and you know
how hard it is to make it in,
in entertainment as a performer.
Yeah.
Right.
You know your path.
Oh,
it's fucking difficult for everybody.
Now imagine you have to rely on other
people performing and you have to pick
the winners.
You've got to figure out who's the,
who's going to work for you.
A bunch of addicts and emos like in
terms of the tablet,
like we're,
we're,
I know,
I give my managers headaches three,
four days a week.
God bless your soul.
You know what I mean?
I know I do.
I really like my friend today,
he was with me.
Um,
he's a promoter,
a he,
right Eric Mail House.
So when I met him,
we were doing a show,
we were booked to do a show,
um,
me and another artist,
well,
the other artists' contract didn't say
pay regardless,
mindset pay regardless.
So after the show and I wish my fucking
money and everyone's like,
what?
What are,
what are you talking about?
You don't get paid.
I was like,
no,
I was my fucking money or I think it may
have been before,
like I'm not going on.
And he ends up snatching me in another
office.
Like,
look,
I want to fucking pay you don't tell the
other fucking guy.
Oh Jesus.
It.
And that's how we became friends.
I took my mind,
acted like I didn't get paid,
talk shit about them in front of the
other guy.
And they call them later like,
man,
I don't know what the fuck made you hold
cold,
but thank you.
And we've been friends.
And so when he called me and said,
you're going to Joe Rogan's experience,
I'm like,
you're coming with me.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
I'm those sketchy gigs.
We not sure if you're going to get paid.
I know it's the Chitlin circuit,
you know,
it's like me and T.
I play in Montgomery,
Alabama in 2003.
Wow.
It Chitlin circuit.
It's fun.
The Chitlin circuit is fun.
I will advise anyone who,
who likes,
like,
you know,
you're like street rap to get to the
south and get to one of those small
clubs with anybody's accepted and just
go watch those kids as they grow up.
You're going to see some hellified
shows.
Now,
how does a manager find a rapper?
How does like an agent find a rapper?
How does that work?
It works a lot of the local shows.
Yeah.
Local shows.
I will say like in Atlanta,
um,
meech and Ke Hu,
both management,
their management for 21 savage,
they've been on the Atlanta scene for
years.
Cultivating young talent,
whether it was grip plies,
rest in peace.
Um,
um,
two,
nine,
which was another group out of Atlanta
and all these kids were dope.
You know,
some worked out,
some didn't on group dot grip died of
cancer.
Unfortunately.
Um,
to nine members went their separate
ways.
We still are making dope music,
but then they found the kid in 21 that
they managed to help get to the next by
toy and congrats to 21.
He had a number one album a couple of
weeks,
but management usually comes from a
group of people who care and just just
want to see someone they're a fan of be
treated well in the industry.
So I really applaud music managers
because like you say,
placing your,
your own fate in your own hands.
It's one thing placing in the fate of an
emotional addict,
which a lot of times the act can be
including myself.
Oh Shit.
That's the roller coaster ride.
That's a hard job.
This distress of other people performing
is brutal.
Yeah.
My,
I mean I've,
my publicist,
God bless her soul.
I thought,
I thought I killed her a couple times
this year.
You know,
she might have come from am I conserve
one of,
I have two publicists,
white woman and Katherine who's done a
lot of music publishing.
And then when I started talking about
topics,
have a black woman in Jennifer Farmer
who's a great publicist,
but she's also a publicist for like
former senator of Ohio,
Nina,
Nina Turner in Mega Church pastors.
So she knows she's helping me keep my
image clean.
But you know,
she didn't want me getting on
television,
talking about doing cocaine and smoking
joints and I don't do cocaine,
but it's just like if I go to club,
yeah.
Do coat and she's just,
you could just see her face sake.
[inaudible] oh my God.
And you know,
churches are calling,
they're like,
Scott supports Ar 15 so I thank you,
Jennifer for you,
for tolerating me.
She put,
she's got to understand that that's also
a part of why people like you.
Yeah,
she does it,
you know?
It's just,
it's just something to deal with their
work.
I get it.
I wouldn't want to be here,
but you have to do what you do.
Like that's part of what makes you fun.
Absolutely.
You know,
cabs know what they're going to get,
what it is.
No filter.
Yeah,
you got it,
man.
You got somebody has to,
somebody has to shake the box a little
bit.
Somebody has to be the kid that's
willing to poke the Hornet's nest just
to see how many of flowers,
my two of my greatest heroes,
when black people usually talk about
heroes,
right?
We talk about Martin,
Malcolm [inaudible],
Elijah Muhammad,
Mario,
Marcus Garvey it.
But two of my biggest heroes coming up,
we're Luther Campbell and Larry Flynt,
right?
Because in my lifetime I saw Luther
Campbell and Larry Flynt fight the
government on behalf of the American
people's right to say whatever they want
it to say.
So at the same time,
in my formative years,
I was learning to love the bill of
rights,
the preamble,
and you had to say its constitution,
constitution.
I got a chance to see people fight for
my right and I couldn't wait to be a
rapper,
just soccer curse and by my own titty
books.
You know what I mean?
And those people have shaped my life in
terms of love,
of freedom and liberties as much as the
Thurgood Marshall,
you know,
as,
as much as,
as much as a Barbara Jordan,
as much as a,
as a Shirley Chisholm.
So for me,
who I am is needed,
you know,
it's,
it's an,
I remember one of my friends saying,
Mike,
I like the fact you're talking on social
issues.
Um,
but why do you always feel necessarily
talk about smoking Weed and Strip clubs?
I say,
because that's what I really do.
And I never want someone to be able to,
from the other side to say,
don't like this guy because he smokes
marijuana.
Go to strip clubs.
I want whoever they say that to to say,
yeah.
And he goes with his wife and they
smoked together.
I don't want it to be some secret I
keep,
I want people to understand that when I
want you to be free,
I don't want you to be free to agree to
see the world the way I do.
I want you to be free to live as you
would like to live.
So long as it doesn't infringe on me and
others.
That's supposed to be what this is all
about.
Yeah.
It's supposed to.
What this country's all about.
That's what Ms. Ellis,
he told them.
Yeah.
In high school.
Well,
the Luther Campbell thing was so strange
because it was at one area in Florida,
right,
where they had very strict brass
blasphemy laws.
Yeah.
They've tried porn stars there before.
They tried some male porn star was doing
really fucked up videos.
They tried him down there for,
for obscenity,
and they had him locked up.
They,
they,
you know,
it's very conservative and they just
decided that the two live crew was just
too much.
They were like,
they were drawn a line in the sand.
Huge.
But it's a crazy thing to do and
something's very popular.
You're like,
yeah,
but you know,
they also make examples out of the
popular,
yeah,
I just found out what the what the,
the mucky on a stick thing,
man.
What apparently monkeys in India while
out.
So farmers will kill unlucky and put his
head on six while the markets and all,
hey,
this is dangerous to do.
Right.
So essentially famous people,
I mean me,
you Luther Campbell,
Lenny Bruce,
you know Rodney Dangerfield,
uh,
Andrew Dice,
clay,
Richard Pryor,
anymore.
What you become is something to
symbolize what will happen if you dare
step out of line of social order.
So you,
your head on a stick is,
isn't less about actually charging you
for crimes and more about keeping the
rest of the public and fierce and
lynching.
Yeah.
And a lot of times we don't want to say
that,
but it really is,
you know what I mean?
So do you think they see something like
two live crew come up?
They never had a rap band,
like a nanny kind of band,
like two live crew right there.
Word what's next?
So he's got the shit in the bud that
snippet into butter.
Put the head in the stick,
put the head on a stick right there in
the yard and,
and thank our luke fought,
I can remember channel two or five abc
or CBS and they were,
they were,
they were getting off the plane in my
town.
I'm a kid watching this one up 1213
years old and the news reporters just
went tmz style,
just put it in her face.
And I can remember brother mark,
he's just pulling up a playboy magazine
and the titties,
I mean right there on the screen.
I'm like,
yes,
because it's lot of tea and the report,
I was dropped the camera,
you know,
trying to get it out.
But that's where,
that's what made me love the United
States constitution when in matters of
freedom of speech because I got a chance
to see it fought for an exercised right
there before me as I was learning about
it.
This isn't an interesting that really
what we're concerned with too is
visuals.
We're not concerned with what people
write down,
what we're concerned with,
what people say.
But we're not like,
you could write that in a book and no
one what?
You could write his lyrics in a book and
no one would get mad at up at that book.
It's something about them singing it and
people singing along to it.
Yeah.
People were like,
this is it.
We gotta we gotta stop the civilizations
falling apart.
We've got to stop this.
Yeah.
Well,
I mean,
you know,
songs,
vibrations,
humming,
you know,
meditation,
Your Hump,
you know that rhythm changes things.
It opens your mind.
It clears you.
You know what I mean?
Had it not,
you know,
had it not been for an artist like
little Kim,
would you have feminism in a way you
have now?
Would you have women gladly celebrating
their sexuality and bodies if it wasn't
for her?
She never gets the credit.
Do you think people know how extravagant
she was and her time?
I think she doesn't get the credit she
deserves.
I think women know that it became safe
for them to be sexually aggressive and
free because of her.
The women that you know were coming of
age in our time,
but I don't think in retrospect,
because wraps young,
it's only 45 46 years old.
I don't think that,
I just think it's getting to the point
where we appreciate what we've,
what we've accomplished.
So a little Kim is going to become more
celebrated as the years go on her.
Trina,
you know,
Kaia choice it.
The boss,
like so many hip hop has been a very
fair game.
The women are very long time.
You know,
whether people want to know it or not,
you know,
you have,
you've always had to call her response
records in hip hop.
I get on there and the baddest
motherfucker in the world and in a girl
pops up behind you.
Nah Mother Fucker,
I'm bad.
Or you know what I mean?
Those records have been around forever.
So they've,
we've always promoted equality within
because it made money.
It made sense.
And women were the audience too.
It's pretty amazing that hip hop is
really only 40 something years old when
you really stop and think about that.
It's one of the primary sources of music
in the world.
Yeah.
I mean if you think about how many songs
are being published,
how many songs people are listening to
and enjoying right now,
how many of those are rap?
It's a fucking giant number,
Matt.
If you could look at the whole country
right now and just a little light goes
off when it's a rap song is playing like
woof.
And if you listen to wheeler walker jr
willow Arkan says the rest of the
country music is just biting rap and,
and acting like they are so,
well I think it was a little bit of
that,
but I think at one point in time it was
a little that a lot of rappers would
look at guys like waylon jennings and
Johnny Cash and old school gangster
country guys,
outlaw country is way different from
them.
I love outlaw country.
You can't tell me Waylon Jennings,
Kris Kristofferson,
Willie Nelson,
Johnny Cash are kicking it.
Like that's what the fuck is that?
Right?
But that's,
and that's not the same as you
allocating and Nellie beat to your songs
and talking about cowboy boots.
And said air force ones not the same.
There's something about the almond
brothers midnight rider and you know,
whipping pulse that's radically
different than you just singing about
your Ford and,
and you know,
and rafting on dates with your chick.
Yeah.
I don't think people even understand
tied to the whipping posts.
You can't fake that song.
When they came at me about the NRA
interview last year,
every day I smoked a joint,
woke up and laughed and listened to that
record like every single day.
I just wanted you guys to know it didn't
bother me any.
My wife just told me to shut up talking
to you all.
We went shooting a lot more and we play
almond brothers whipping posts every
morning because I had to remind myself
that this is normal,
that you are being done like this
publicly because you are disagreeing
with the system that people have agreed
to that you don't agree to.
And it's okay not to agree.
So the harmon brothers really got me
through that segment and stopped me from
punching a lot of bourgeoisie black
people in the face.
Well,
you're a proponent of your,
your right to carry a gun.
Yeah.
And I'm a lover of 19 states
constitution as a whole of,
of,
of all our rights in amendments,
but in particular,
you know,
the first and second amendment rights
matter to me as an African American,
as an and as an American first foremost
as an African American,
I've only been free 55 years.
My parents were born and apartheid.
And as an American we are,
we are a country that broke off from
what we felt like with the tyranny of
the monarchy.
And we did that because farmers and guns
dare to wage guerrilla warfare against,
at that time when the largest armies and
navies in the world.
So I honor that by continuing to be in
the spirit of the host farmers,
you know,
in the,
in the continuance of crispus attucks,
the first person to die in American
revolution was a black man.
You know?
So for me,
I would dishonor those patriots who
started this country and Christmas
attics.
I would dishonor the lineage is an
African American who was only 55 years
in the freedom by giving government more
gun patch.
I just not something I believe in
government is people pro.
Part of the problem with giving
government anything is that they're just
people.
They're not something special.
Absolutely not flawless.
Absolutely give People Power over you in
theirs.
They will,
I mean this is not saying we should
stockpile guns and point them at the
government,
but if people have guns it's way harder
to just take over.
Sees a little.
Absolutely.
That shit happens all the time.
And other countries APP does happen.
Absolutely.
People get occupied and governments turn
on them and governments changed the
rules and put places that were
democracies are no longer so absolutely.
That's real and we're never far from it.
Is it safe as you feel?
You're never far from it,
but I think what we need more of is
people like you that are,
that are a reasonable,
very educated in the matter of very
articulate person who comes from a place
where they don't expect that argument
come from.
Yeah,
I understand.
You know,
like you think about left wing people
are Democratic People,
progressive people.
You'll always think,
you know,
you think about democratic people
overwhelmingly being appreciated by the
black community and you always associate
them with being anti gun.
Yeah.
That's a common thing.
So when a guy like you steps out and
says,
no,
I think it's a disservice to take this
right away.
Absolutely.
If I didn't support it and fight for it,
I've been,
I've been an African American 40 40
something years now.
Right.
I have known democrats primarily my
entire life.
I'm from the south in particular in
Southeast Alabama,
Georgia,
Florida.
I have never known a black male Democrat
that was working class that did not own
a weapon.
Not that.
So I'm going to follow the examples of
my grandfather.
I'm not going to listen to the National
Party and their rhetoric about the arm
in the population.
I think obviously we could agree that we
would all love it if we never needed
guns.
Yeah,
of course.
Right.
Of course.
Who wouldn't?
I rather not need it than be prepared
though and not be prepared.
Sure.
Right.
Better to have it not to need it than
they did not to have it and re part of
the country I'm from.
And what you do often.
Like I'm from a part of the country,
I grew up fishing,
hunting and growing food.
My sister grows food,
don't get to as regularly now.
Still fish occasionally shouts out to
Greg Street when our biggest tjx down
there and so great fisherman,
right?
But this is this normal in my part of
the country as not having straws and
being able to smoke in public in places
like La is it,
it just,
it's not that big of a deal.
You know,
you,
you know,
in my,
in my mind state a household should have
five guns,
right?
You should have a revolver,
a semiautomatic for a few and your wife
carrying out,
you know,
in public you have a shot gun,
just go.
This is a great all around going to
have,
whether it's burglars or vermin,
you know,
and you should have bolt action rifles,
some course case.
Got To kill your meat.
You'd have a semiautomatic rifle meant
to,
you know,
defend against here and there just to
fuck off on Sundays and show your
homeboys who was Dick Baker.
But what should,
what you should not do is give up your
right to own weapons or use them on
people.
That's the thing about using them on
people is that it's so rare,
but so horrific and so,
so common for something that's so
horrific and everybody's against it.
But I don't,
I don't understand how you would ever
buy taking guns.
I mean,
you'd have to take all the guns away to
stop that from happening,
but how are you going to do,
how are you going to do that?
Criminals are going to give him,
of course.
Huh?
So was no way they'll,
right.
Regular people should probably not do
that again.
Yeah,
that's,
that's where it gets squirrely.
It's like,
how are you going to get those guns from
the criminals?
You're not,
you're not going to,
you're not going to joke.
Well we can do though.
And I will say as an owner,
you get lazy.
Sometimes you don't train enough.
We should try.
And more.
And that doesn't mean,
you know,
go try to be the quickest draw and you
practice it,
you know?
But what you want to do is make sure you
know what you're doing with your weapon.
Make sure you know how to clean your
weapon,
make sure you're not a story,
a weapon.
And I took my son and my nephew and I'm
shooting,
I'm about to start taking my 11 year old
girl Michael shooting because I want
them to know what they do if they see a
gun.
So we've already went through,
what do you do if you're somewhere you
see a gun,
how do,
how do you get out of that situation and
get other kids out of that situation and
let an adult know all that comes with
it.
You know?
And you know,
the strange thing to me is that my
mother,
when she was in high school,
was actually taught how to shoot a
rifle,
right?
Because the NRA,
which is now vilified and hate it for
four reasons,
some deservedly sell,
some not.
They used to have big programs in public
schools to make sure that children new
firearms safety,
so my mother's school and other schools
benefited from that.
I don't care if it was just that sheet
of paper that tells you the gun safety
before you went and age.
That was just a piece of propaganda they
did.
It was better for the overall public.
So I tend to say as Americans,
we've gotten away from stuff like traits
in school.
We've gotten away from different options
beside funneling our kids in the college
debt and we've also gotten away from
basic training such as balancing a
checkbook,
a basic home economics,
or how do you,
you'd make a Lasagna at home by herself
and stuff like gun gun,
gun shooting and archery.
I think that if those things return to
public school,
you get a safer,
more confident student body.
You get a reduction on things like
bullying and in bullshit and you get an
increase on self-propel interest of
children and you start to meet to grow
it scholars than excel.
But do you do,
do you really,
how was it going to stop bullying?
Just by knowing that more kids know how
to use guns.
Guns don't stop bullying.
No boxing class stops bullying pimps.
He said that no one wants to fight
somebody gonna fight back.
I think you're right.
I think for sure martial arts,
uh,
I know wrestling does it.
Yeah.
One thing you can do though is make
people more aggressive.
Initially you had a lot of people just
getting into it and learn how to fight a
lot to get that far.
It's like blue belt mentality.
That's why you get with your homies
though.
You go with your homey.
So you and your homies are just beating
the shit out of each other and you're
not picking on a kid at lunch.
You know what I mean?
Like me,
Willie Spearman.
I remember six credit.
The thing is though,
man,
you'd get hurt each other.
It was a horrible video.
Uh,
did you see I'm the one that,
um,
are uh,
who put it up.
Um,
what was it?
It was a one of those fight breakdown
videos.
Robin black.
Yes,
it was robin black to Steve's.
They get in a fight.
One Steve Chaos.
The other,
Steve,
it's fucked up.
Two dudes have boxing gloves on their
friends and one of them knew how to
fight a little bit and the other one
didn't know how to fight it all and he
knocks him out.
Don't do that to your whole head.
Bounces off the floor.
Yeah.
I think a martial arts in general is
great for kids to stop bullying because
you don't,
you don't have to worry.
And we look at this,
watch this shit,
but this kid in the blue has no idea
he's doing.
That Guy Leans in with a jab.
We'll get this plat.
Oh,
that's so fucked up.
It's so obvious that Tommy to sleep,
he knows how to fight.
Yeah.
Like even when he threw a jab,
he like leaned in on that Jab.
That was,
unless that guy is a real asshole that
really needed that punch.
That's a fucked up thing to do to your
buddy.
Aw Man.
Like we got this kid leans in,
look at that kid knows how to Jab.
That's a real jab.
Here comes awful.
Next snap lights were about to go off.
That's bad for you kids.
And boom.
Blap good timing there too.
Kid drops it and,
oh,
did you see what I put up on my
instagram today?
Not when was a kid who looked like he
was more of a boxer then a Kung Fu guy.
Um,
it looks like the,
yeah,
I kicked him in the job.
It wasn't joe was a chest.
It felt like he hit chest to Kava.
Teach them.
I have to go look it like,
yeah,
but he could have been got them in the
look at this.
I thought he got him in the neck area.
Yeah.
I think it's a little bit of high chest.
Yeah,
but,
but humble the shit out of him.
And then he smiled and patted him on his
back front leg side kick yet why he did
it smooth.
That's one of my favorite moves.
There's a big guy,
people never see,
uh,
just a great kick to the gut coming and
getting the fuck out of doing this.
Let me get out of here.
That's how you get out of those Chitlin
circuit clubs when the whole club is
trying to kill you.
How many of those situations ever been
in a good three,
two or two?
It was our fault.
Me and my crew really,
and two,
we were just in the middle of some
bullshit.
We know what's going on.
We had to get out of that club,
you know what I mean?
But yeah,
that,
that song,
that's,
that's the only thing about the Chitlin
circuit.
Fun Times,
great groupies bags of money,
but you could die.
Now how do you guys start out?
You start out like is there a like a
open mic night or something?
If a guy wants to become a rapper,
how do you get going?
Like to get on stage?
It's like I'm from the underground rap
scene and that I liked these cults rap.
I like battle rap,
that type stuff coming up.
So I was more out of the open mic scene.
I got to hang around the older guys in
the cool guys and the drug dealers
because I can rap about treat stuff
right.
Where's your and you take like a t.
Ah,
he was always interested,
loved music and stuff.
But tip was a trap rapper from the
start.
You know,
he,
he was entertaining for the streets so
he didn't,
he didn't need to go to fucking open
mic.
He just needed to be opened up on a mic
and then allowed the greater public.
The hearing I'm saying,
excuse me,
I talk about him and I mean big boy
cause there are two of my best friends.
So I know I got poetic license to talk
about those guys where I don't really,
you know,
tread lightly with other rappers.
You never know whose feelings get hurt.
But so it was no need for him to do open
mics as much as just find someone who
believed in him.
And that was um,
kp La Reid,
Dj toomp and gave him platform to create
the genre.
Now known as trap music.
Me,
I came up more of how to battle rap
scene and out of the,
you know,
go show your wares,
kind of like a comic.
You get up in front of everybody,
do your shit,
see what works,
go home,
readjust,
come back next week.
So when you do like a battle rap thing,
we sign up.
How,
how,
how would that work those days?
She just threw you in the pit.
I mean it was like,
was like fine first time.
Yeah.
You show up.
Um,
I got my name,
my name,
my nickname Scott.
Right.
My nickname was Scott or my family
called me Michael.
Um,
my friends were the unruly scholars and
those guys were like just east coast
rap.
One was from Connecticut and from South
Carolina.
It was family from New York.
They could wrap their ass off.
They were like Rakim and big daddy came
and sang group.
They defeated a lot of guys may better
records and then one day there was this
thing called green lights where people
will play their music and then they'd be
battle each other.
My homies income and man,
you could just,
everybody who you thought was the
homies.
Homies was just shitting on them.
And I'm like,
what the fuck?
I says my homies and my manager,
Rod,
gg Mcgee,
who I had just seen like a couple of
weeks ago,
he was the person that kind of pulled me
out of knocking around in a trap trying
to be a petty drug dealer into a studio.
And he was the first person to say,
Yo,
this kid could really wrap.
Like,
you know,
fuck that shit.
I know he steals cars and you know what
I mean?
And he rides around,
do a hood rat shit with his ratchet
friends,
but he can really wrap,
let's get him in.
So he was the guy that started bringing
me in.
So it offended me.
They were talking about my friend like
that.
So I just start fucking off with their
heads paddle wrapping them.
And a man named double dee called me,
killed her that night.
He said his kids are killer.
Mike's a killer.
And that's how I got the name killer
Mike.
Ah,
what a great story.
So the battle rap scene,
you would just get tossed into a pit and
how much time would you get?
This is in the nine is this isn't like
formal battle rap now.
Like battle rap has evolved like boxing
now.
Like what I'm talking about is
essentially cockfighting so,
but like when you would battle up,
there would be no,
no time limit.
No time.
You just went,
you just went until you won the crowd or
the other guy shut the fuck up and
walked away with his hand down.
What was a long battle rap man died that
night.
Those guys were still,
I literally took out four and five and
six and those guys were still trying to
come at me before d who was fucking
built like you when?
When?
When we were children.
You know what if it was like I was dean,
knock you the fuck out.
Just told everybody,
shut the fuck up.
This kid one.
So,
and it was decided.
All right,
these spoken,
you know what I'm saying?
Dj Double d gave me,
my mom gave me my rabbinate.
It gets heated man.
I've watched a bunch of them online with
dudes getting each other's face,
man.
My,
um,
my um,
my deep,
my Dj,
Dj track star keeps me up with the
paddle scene and I couldn't do it like
as an older
man,
I'm just saying to myself like,
Yo,
I was just how to fight somebody,
right?
Like straight the fuck up like you by
Dae Dae man.
It's,
the disrespect is amazing but amazing.
It's a martial art of sorts.
You know,
it's a mental martial art.
The ability to stay self disciplined
enough not to wile out the ability to
give it and take it.
You know what I'm saying is,
I mean it's an art there.
If you've ever seen roast battle,
no roast battles.
What they're doing,
standup stand up comics with the same
principle.
They go,
well they prepare for it like sometimes
like weeks out and they tell them who
they're going to be battling against and
they write a bunch of jokes about each
other and just shit all over each other.
Ruthless joke writing.
It's on comedy central rickles worthy
shit.
Ruthless Shit.
That's ruthless.
That's what comedy should be.
It is that it's a rare place.
That one spot where they're doing it
like that.
That roast battle is a rare place cause
it's like pure joke writing and fucking
meanness.
I got to check that.
That's called a,
what we call [inaudible] in the south.
Joe [inaudible].
Yeah.
Hey,
I made you all in the shit out of you.
Like that's when you're just,
you're just,
it's roofless.
Are you saying Jaw Lynn?
Like w Joning Joan to John Chowning.
Joning John The lady.
Oh Yeah,
yeah,
like Joan,
but it's,
I think it's spelled j o n e j o.
AN like John Jones.
Yeah.
So yeah,
and they call it John.
I and there's parts like,
I think they call it that in dc too,
but I'm in cap and some other places.
What's called Joan and in the sound man
number,
what they dove that Joanie just talking
bad about each other.
Yeah.
With comics it's a,
it really is a,
a martial art because you've got to keep
it together.
Whether this person just ruthlessly
shitting on your appearance and your
life and x relationships and divorces
and mean people are rules such as life.
Man,
life is real.
Yeah.
I gotta give props out to my friend
who's a comic little deval number one
record with that smile bitch record.
Lil Duval is one of those guys where
man,
he's going to say some shit to you,
man.
He's going to test you in nuts.
He goes,
you know,
he gonna hit you.
You know what I mean?
He,
he's real.
He's about this high,
but it's fucking ego is this big and
he's really good at talking shit.
So I've heard him destroy some rooms.
He um,
style bender who's like one of the best
fighters in the UFC.
Yeah.
Came out to that,
came out to that song loud smile bitch.
That's a great fun.
I'm very proud of my friend man.
It's a great fucking song.
Any Song Snoop jumps on
and style bender as he's getting ready
to go into the octagon.
He was dancing,
he was dancing to the song and when he
got inside he was dancing,
having a good time.
And then once the fight started that,
I don't know if you ever seen him fight.
He's in the Matrix.
He's on another level,
like spectacular stryker,
his kid,
I got to see him.
I haven't lightening fast and credible
timing.
He's got creativity.
He's loose in there.
He gives you looks,
you don't know what the fuck has
happened and Blam you get head kicked.
He's phenomenal.
He's like one of the best in the world
right now.
Up and coming.
But he came down.
Yeah,
I gotta check them out.
Israel at his Sanya Israel Allisanya one
of the best.
He's fucking,
if you love technique,
you love that guy.
Shout them out.
I liked silver for that reason.
Yeah.
Well Anderson Silva and him are
fighting.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
It's a sort of a passive,
he's 40 years old,
I believe.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
It's probably one of his last fights.
I was about to say.
How old do you think I should be before
they,
they stop.
Well,
you know,
Anderson is not a guy who,
uh,
engaged in trench warfare.
He always fought very smart.
He did.
He didn't really take the kind of
beatings that maybe a lot of guys that
fought as long as him took.
He's very technical,
very good at avoiding getting hit.
I mean,
he's been hit,
it's unavoidable.
He's finding the best in the world
continually.
He got hit,
he got dropped by a couple of people.
But um,
it's not like most guys,
but most guys that get to his amount of
time in,
they're going to get hit way more.
He doesn't,
I mean his face looks exactly the same.
It looks perfect.
He doesn't have a messed up face at all.
You think about that guy,
the fact that he fought the best of the
best forever and his fate.
I go,
thank you.
His face isn't fucked up.
I mean,
that's all you need to know.
This is what it is.
Face Floyd's copy without about floyd.
Like people,
people hate to get mad with flood.
I'm just like,
Yo man,
you know,
defense is a part of voxer to man.
The ability not to get hit as a talent.
Not a lot of people have,
dude.
It's,
it's a part of everything.
Yeah,
it's part of life,
but it's,
it's a part of a Jujitsu.
It's giant.
Hixon Gracie is number one principle.
He's like,
first I'd defend,
I'm always safe no matter what.
Always safe.
Always say oh ways he can't do shit with
him.
There's certain guys that allow you
Hickson one of them.
He would allow black belts to take his
back and put in a full rear naked choke
with the hooks in and they would start
from there.
Start from the closing sequence.
You're at [inaudible] you're going to
sleep.
Exactly.
And he would get out.
That's amazing.
And dudes can tap them from the NASA.
Yo shout out to Wiz Wiz.
Wiz Khalifa.
Cousin Bri.
Yeah.
Shouts out the breeze.
Breeze got into Jujitsu and is brought
whizz into it and it's now shamed me
into going to,
so at some point I want to pop up in a
gym.
I've got to get you and Joey Diaz and a
Jujitsu class would be the greatest
thing I to get this done,
the shelter,
I've got to finish rehabbing carrot.
It's going to clear me when I don't know
what your shoulder's rotator cuff
surgery on both shoulders.
Jesus.
Yeah,
but I can do this again now.
Okay.
Yeah,
I can grab,
but again,
they got you doing those elastic bands
exercises,
those in the room,
those this morning.
Wiz put on a ton of muscle.
There's a photo of him pre and post and
it's truly impressed.
Sure.
I would not want to follow Wiz Khalifa
Ryan.
Now he's not just a thin,
tall kid rapping can shred.
Is he good?
ABS are ridiculous.
Give you kicks and take your bitch at
this point.
Have you seen his abs there would kill
us.
There's huge too.
Like look at that,
look at it.
They're not just,
they're not just ripped.
I'm going to stop slobbering soon.
They're not just rip their big like look
how much power.
The advantage of going from skinny to
big though versus me.
Why it's times a muscle under here but
got to lose a lot of Chubby to see it
baby,
your legs carrying around all that
weight.
I've always thought if someone could
lose weight once they're really heavy,
they would have an advantage of their
legs.
Calves are still good,
but the legs are constantly used to
moving around with much more weight.
Now all of a sudden they don't have that
way.
It's like he'd been backpack training.
Like what are the difference?
Well that's,
that's not as good at difference.
It's hard to tell them.
No big difference.
Still a difference there for sure.
Which is those a great human being.
He goes to that a place in um,
in Hollywood,
um,
Jay's place
performance.
Uh,
what is it called?
Unbreakable.
The places the shit.
Supposedly it's like a semi private
place and be going there like chuck
Liddell's working out.
And that makes sense cause we,
this is like really rich.
Yeah.
Like the black community,
he's like white people rich as well.
We call it white.
He's on,
he's on a very high level right now.
God bless.
Yeah.
I like with,
well if you did that to your body,
that dude works hard while I'm doing it,
I'm doing it slower.
I need to pick up the pace and go a full
90 days like you say,
but I feel a lot better.
I just did a fucking sap.
I was running commercial.
I felt like the king of the world.
Did you?
Yeah.
I mean I've been working out.
Miss shouts out to Al Clay,
barred from Clay Morphett effects.
Now,
former professional bodybuilder.
Just teach me kind count how to retrain
my brain and when I'm not being lazy and
really on it.
Feel great sweat today so you don't
regret the day.
The good thing about it too is with a
guy like you,
if you continue and you continue to lose
weight and get healthier,
you're going to inspire other people to
do the same thing.
People that are your fans that go,
fuck man,
now I want to get my shit together.
Yeah,
cause what you don't want to do is get
rich dad.
Have some young Wiz Khalifa like I
fucking on your wife.
That's my daily mantra.
That's a good,
I got a hot red hair wife and I don't
want to die all my money.
Go to some young steadman like God
fucking honor.
Yeah man.
You want to have more energy?
Fuck it.
You can do it.
Yeah.
No,
no doubt.
No doubt.
But yeah,
what you said is true.
Get off the sugars,
go out the flowers,
eat,
eats meat and grain shit tree on it.
That's it.
Keep moving as much as he ever use one
of those fitbit's or any of those
things.
And now I gotta do I gotta Watch man,
man,
my man from Nike gave me a watch it,
I gotta like I was a good,
it was real good.
They,
they'll,
it gives you a number.
So you look at the numbers and you get
the metric of how hard you're working.
Yeah.
I like that one that we were doing.
What the fuck was it called again?
The one that we did for the uh,
fitness.
Yeah.
I'm trying to by zones,
trying to convince my wife that having
threesomes enforce them.
It's like circuit training.
It is.
She hasn't went for it yet.
It was definitely a hormonal buildup.
Yeah.
Well,
I'm going,
I'm going for it.
I'm trying.
It's trying to,
I think next season,
all the trigger warning,
that's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to try to start a polygamous
compound based on cross fit.
Man.
That never goes right.
Is anybody ever pulled off a compound?
Yeah.
A few people.
Quiet,
quiet.
People pull it off.
When you start to realize that your
uncle and your aunt and her best friend
aren't uncle,
aunt best friend,
like,
Oh shit,
I don't had two wives.
You know what I mean?
Yeah,
but,
but if you're getting loud about it,
it's,
I just want to go back
because people know about it.
By the time they know about it,
it's already gone bad.
Right.
So there might be a lot of them laughing
at us right now.
We know how to do it.
Yeah,
exactly.
We just keep our shit together.
Don't tell everybody to just stay low.
Did you see wild,
wild country?
I did not see.
Wow.
All countries,
they bought a town.
They put,
they took over a town,
a whole cult.
They just started just importing people.
They brought him in on buses.
Shut the fuck up.
Do they took over a town?
Yeah.
These,
uh,
what was his name?
I forget the guy's name.
I forgot a,
was it an east Indian guys?
Say it again.
Into the mic.
Raj knee.
Yeah.
He had another name though.
Did it?
What are they making?
Like textiles or something up there.
I think I may have seen part of this
high three in the morning.
I don't remember what the fuck they were
doing for jobs.
I was just paying attention to how they
got these people in there.
They took homeless people and they
shipped him out there on buses so they
could vote from the town.
That gave them jobs and identities and
these people were extremely happy.
That was what?
It was crazy.
It's like a,
I'm sure up.
Some of them were troubled,
but for a lot of them they finally had a
sense of purpose.
They just been taken into this place as
family.
So they made Utah,
they basically made a town in Utah.
I've always suspected that.
What I did see part of this movie geek
at three in the morning like,
oh,
why is it that white hippie like people
trust Brown people with beards so much?
Well,
they want to believe in enlightenment
and in all the media portrayals of
enlightenment and all of,
you know,
when people talk about mystical
experiences at an India,
it's always that part of the world that
emphasizes spirituality.
And the idea that the Hindu religion is
a,
is a more ancient,
more compstats be ritual religion as
this all goes to the Indian yogi figure
is the white Jesus figure of white
people 100% so for white people who
don't know white Jesus in the black
community is a mythical creature that
has enormous power,
right?
It's insane for anyone to believe in a
deity that doesn't look like them,
right?
So,
but in the black community were just in
love with renaissance paintings and
Jesus is white as fuck.
All right,
so we have the same infatuation that
you're weird hippy art has with Indian
men with long beards and their Mr
System.
We have that white jeans.
So that you've just helped me understand
why,
because I've always wanted to like what
the fuck is it up?
Well,
white people and east Indian people that
cause Vikrum who directed trigger
warning also has a documentary where he
creates a fake religion and convinces,
you know,
white middle class people to follow.
That is a crazy one.
The white Jesus one,
right?
I why Jesus is a motherfucker Bro,
like late man,
I'm going to get me a shirt that says
white people.
One stay woke and and what I mean by
that is Western civilization,
it,
this is the latest phase.
Like people have to understand there
have been many empires and
civilizations.
That was a time where molly and Africa
and Kim in in Africa what the biggest
civilizations and colonizers on earth
later.
Persia,
biggest cock like you've had systems and
right now the West has just for the last
thousand or so has been kicking and
dominating ass.
A lot of what we see on the news between
the West and what we call the Middle
East now,
what it was wanting,
western perjury at western Asia,
this is thousands of years war,
you know,
you're hearing Islam versus
Christianity,
but it's really two ideologies that have
been fighting for thousands of years
over how to glove should be governed.
So with,
with that Shit,
man,
it's like there's no,
there's no stopping this shit and it
split white.
Jesus springs out of that and kind of
goes everywhere in colonizes everything.
So you know,
the Church pops up with candy for kids
bibles for you.
And by the way,
we're going to be gone a while,
but we're going to leave this guy here
on the wall.
So you know what the ideal,
what God's son look like.
So if God's son looks like a dooby
brother and still does God,
God looks like Jim Morris,
Jim Morrison with a full beard.
Straight the fuck.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's really,
Jesus would probably a Tan guy with dark
hair and curly curly hair and Brown eyes
that was saying shit that the government
and the church didn't like.
So they knocked him the fuck off.
Yeah.
Why do you think that each race looks
for someone of another race to be their
advisor?
Because I don't think people trust the
divinity in themselves.
You know,
I think,
I think that once you understand that as
human beings,
we really only looked different because
of subtle differences in atmosphere and
change and you know who you mix with
win.
But I think that all those books that
are moms paid oprah to sell us of self
help and inward looking.
Reverend Ike had told my grandmother's
generation had in the seventies you know
what I mean?
And I think that we're scared to turn
off the lights and at some point see
something divine within ourselves.
Because once you do that,
that requires you act differently.
And I think that people need to be told
what to do.
Not that they actually need it,
but they want to be instructed,
you know,
versus knowing or going on a gut feeling
or experiment and getting something
wrong.
You know,
my grandfather was one of the most kind
moral men I've ever met.
He was always gentle with children.
He only put a belt on my butt twice in
my life and shit.
I think he cried harder than that same
man at 14 years old.
Shot a man in church for kicking this
bike down.
You know,
he grew up in between 14 and 54 when I
was born.
And he had experiences that he had
learned to regret and he had dealt with
that and he had become something that by
the time I was a child and he was
raising me,
my grandfather was divided in my eyes
almost.
You know what I mean?
Not because he was perfect because he
was genuinely good and moral.
But as a 14 year old boy who had grown
up fatherless,
who dropped out of school in the third
grade and who had,
who understood it,
that I must protect my mothers and
sisters.
He refused to people that buy anyone,
even in adult to the point of putting a
bullet in him.
You know what I mean?
So I think that a lot of times we're
afraid to see the divinity in ourselves
also.
Because then you have to acknowledge the
darkness and you'd have to deal with
that.
And it's easier to get instructed by
someone else.
And it's easier to see the evil outside
too.
It's easier to see the ad.
It's tough to know I can't control it
just happens.
Versus,
um,
I'm,
I'm complying and I'm complicit in it.
You know,
that's a,
it's also a consequence of,
you know,
one of the things that bothers me the
most when people talk about people that
commit crimes or think about people that
commit crimes.
So much of who a person is as a
consequence of things that had nothing
to do with them.
Absolutely.
They get had been born in a terrible
neighborhood to horrible parents,
been abused sexually and physically.
And,
and by the time you get to them,
they broke their life is already a mess.
It's a shambles row.
And for you to try to,
to think that they are going to look at
life and just figure it out with no
assistance whatsoever,
it's crazy.
It doesn't work like that occur.
One of the weirdest things about our
culture is that we haven't put more of
an emphasis in finding the spots that
are there,
the ghettos and the terrible
neighborhoods in this country.
And figuring out a way to build them up
and just make it even,
we know you're out a way.
We know unequivocably where jobs and
commerce are present and economic
opportunity and prosperity occur,
Dessa,
dramatic reduction and elimination and
gang violence.
Yet we do not put resources into
building institutions that will create
entrepreneurs' or work on a soft skill
so the kids can be working at and around
production houses to the owls.
We put that money into prisons.
Yeah.
And then we use prison labor to undercut
things like call centers.
Um,
things like that,
that the jobs,
I mean,
it factories may need and we,
we're doing a disservice by doing that.
We,
and I always say we,
because we looked how our quote unquote
leaders and blamed him when so many
times we allow it,
you know,
we allow this to happen by not paying
attention and not voting.
We allow it to happen by not raising our
voice,
even though we know someone in prison
and saying this is wrong.
You know,
the last people,
I don't,
I don't believe just for the record,
I don't believe in the big three.
The Abrahamic religions,
I'm not into them,
but the books I've read and they're
amazing graphic novels,
I cannot read them.
Like I can look like a graphic novel of
sorts.
Right.
And when you look at the people who
Christ died with,
right?
It was,
he was,
uh,
he was up there thieves.
The last person he saved before he got
hired here,
it was a thief.
I was like,
what's a confessed?
Steve was dying right next to him and he
was like,
you know,
we going to go on this together.
That sets an amazing thing.
So as you're serving your savior or your
messiah,
you need to be thinking about who he
spent his time with.
You know,
he was with liars and thieves,
he was in the streets.
He was what people were alleged to be
prostitutes.
And I think that if we start to turn our
attention to those places and we put our
intentions and good there,
we do produce on the out on the other
side better.
But as long as we look at religion as
something that makes us holy,
makes us clean,
washed us of our sins,
and we become pious that I think
religion will something be something
that's forever kind of harmful.
It helped to create that.
And I think that that,
that believing that some people are good
at evil doesn't allow us to say,
well,
what could we do to fix those ghettos,
fix all depressed areas.
Because for every ghetto where I'm from,
for every get all this in a city,
in the south,
I can show you a mountainous region what
a trailer park dishes is bad for sure.
And those and those.
And those kids deserve a life better
than oxycontin addiction and in turmoil
and pain to your right.
100%.
And I feel like there's money to be made
doing it too.
I mean,
it feels like these jobs,
I feel like.
Yes,
it's an ignored resource.
Yes.
Yes ma'am.
I follow kidney turbo cheeses.
Follow kitten.
A turbo.
Jesus in Alabama,
man.
Oh,
anybody named turbo.
Jim's names turbo.
Jesus K.
Listen man,
he's amazing man.
I believe he's,
I don't,
I'm not a big confederate flag.
Just doesn't bother me as much.
All right.
Not saying that you had to pass.
Just it's,
I've lived with it so long.
It's kind of like,
all right.
Did you,
were you shocked at all of a sudden it
became a bad thing?
Like with the Dukes of Hazzard and all
that?
Not while I was at Duke because it has,
I have pictures of me.
And what's the General Leon a shirt.
Right.
Um,
I'm not surprised because you know it,
my thing with the competitor of faggots
that side loss,
right?
So you're flying a loser's flag.
So I just never really bothered me.
But as I got older to drama,
the drama that's been placed around it
has been amazing because if I'm not
going to change Robert E.
Lee,
the school's name,
we're not going to really be able to
change places.
It's going to be here.
You know,
it's a southern,
you just kind of that it's going to be
there.
But Turbo Jesus as a kid,
I saw following.
So my natural assumption is typical
redneck kid,
right?
Hella talent.
He can fix anything with a motor on it.
He makes these amazing Katana like
swartz out of riches,
right?
He's just an amazing kid.
But I see him rallying against kids that
uphold that flag and upholding,
you know,
anything that feels like racism and
nationals and he just wanted a more most
morally good kids I've ever seen running
around.
And he's an ally and he doesn't look
like stereotypically anything you would
expect.
But that's the great part of this.
To me,
the great part of all of this country he
is,
you know,
as as polar opposites is people try to
make say a you and I,
here we are together as equals,
you know,
here we are together engaging one
another as equals and we don't look like
one another and not from the same
places.
And I think that's just a whole bunch of
opportunity in that.
You know,
I think that there's money to be made in
promoting that versus promoting division
in fear.
And so absolutely you should be,
there is money in helping children be
better there.
There is in there and if we're going to
live in a capitalist system,
be a compassionate capitalists and be
the best you possibly can because we
need more of you.
But just seems like something like an in
terms of something that we think about
as a civilization,
we don't think about neighborhood
rebuilding.
No,
it's not a primary concern even though
one of the biggest problems we have is
with crime and violence.
If you ask people what's the two biggest
things you're afraid of?
It's crime and violence.
Next be car accidents and cancer and but
crime and violence,
you could severely mitigate.
Yeah.
Can if she had all these community
programs.
If you think about the amount of,
if they've,
I bet if they calculate it out probably
a wash,
the amount of money you'd spend spent
fix things versus the amount of money
you would save by not having as much
crime.
I agree.
Roxanne Shawntay
I saw her and I don't know shit,
so I'm just guessing.
I eight south eighth anything is better
than what we're doing.
More prisons what we're doing it.
Yeah.
Well that's the scariest shit we got
going on.
The idea that someone's profiting off of
putting people in cages and that they
also lobby to make sure that there's
more laws in the books.
I told Larry King early today that I'd
rather stop arguing over the second
amendment with people that I should be
arguing for amendment of the 13th
amendment.
We should stop arguing over guns and we
should start to say,
why does that 13th amendment have a
loophole that allows for slavery that
says slavery is illegal except for yeah,
to people.
People have no idea how much prisoners
get paid to work when they were working
on the fires.
Yes.
What was,
I think it was $2 or something.
Some fucking insane amount of money.
They pay them and when they get out of
prison,
they are not allowed to be firemen.
Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Is that real?
Yeah.
It's real
like because you're a felon.
Every crime it for everyone,
but,
but I any felony,
you can't be a fireman.
I can't say any,
but a lot of the guys I've known that
have gotten out of prison have not been
allowed to apply for five.
It's right.
There's,
there's felonies where violent felonies,
drug selling California is paying
inmates $1 an hour.
Holy Shit.
Not even $2 your life is worth 99
Pitney's plus one.
Just stop and think about fighting fires
for 10 hours.
You make $10 that's insane.
That is that.
Not only is that slavery,
that might be worse than slavery because
$10 an hour isn't even going to buy you
food.
That's what I said.
Walmart pays.
It's,
it's less money to work all day.
Then you could feed yourself.
Yeah.
Yup.
This is the white guy thing.
That's,
that's what I try to tell people.
People Talk Shit when I was coming on
here.
All right.
I was like,
Yo man,
these are the guys in ally.
I appreciate you saying that because
that's true and it's not just black guys
is poor white people.
I almost wish I could have a convention
with to say we got to say masters.
They're saying this right here.
More than 2000 volunteer inmate
firefighters and they volunteered,
including 58 youth offenders are
battling wildfire flames through
California.
Inmate firefighters serve a vital role
clearing thick brush down to bare soil
to stop the fire.
Spread a wonder.
Um,
do they get better service for that?
Do they they get out earlier?
Nope.
They don't think nothing.
I don't think so.
I would hope they do,
but if we're paying them a dollar out,
what do we care?
But we're,
we're like,
we are,
the public should be up in arms about
it.
Yeah.
Well,
they're obviously trusted those guys to
not run too,
because when you're,
when you're chopping down bushes out
there,
when there's a fire going on,
but where are you?
Where are you going to go with it?
Nobody knows what the fuck is happening.
It's chaos.
So where are you going to go?
Where are you going to go?
Yeah.
And then when they get you shit dollar
an hour,
just how insane is that one?
You know something else we do in our
prisoners that's cruel and brutal.
We put people in a box of 23 hours a
day.
Yeah.
A lot of math for an hour to walk in the
space.
Yeah.
You driving him crazy.
She doing.
Yeah.
You're fucking with their sensors to the
point where they're going crazy.
Absolutely.
They get solitary.
I,
I have friends that have been in
solitary,
they talked to you about,
and they're just there for themselves
with your own mind day after day after
day.
I remember going to in school
suspension,
not being able to talk about to go
fucking nuts after three hours,
you know?
So imagine being in Georgia state
corrections when you're a little kid.
You can't shut the fuck up for anything.
Coach dollar used to tell him,
you know,
he used to be honest,
like shut the fuck Cameron dollar one
1995 ucla.
He played um,
play point guard for them when they won
national championship.
His Dad was the culture of high school.
His Dad was the basketball coach and
he'd softer in school and I stayed in,
in school.
Oh Man.
I knew his dad like a fucking player.
I couldn't play any basketball.
I'd just be sitting there quiet.
He'd be reading the paper just like,
I can't wait to get the fuck outta here,
man.
Coach [inaudible] home at and say Shit.
That's how I knew I didn't want to go to
prison.
Thank you coach dollar shouts out the
camp not talking to anybody for just a
couple of days.
It would be enough to drive you crazy.
And I imagine some people that had been
locked in the hole for like eight
months.
Yeah,
they do that to people.
they do.
They break down.
I mean that doesn't,
isn't that what they did to Chelsea
manning?
Yeah,
didn't they?
Yes,
that's exactly what they did.
I think
I forgot what her original name was.
I as Dua,
I forgot.
No,
it's not what you might change.
You might get like Chelsea else going to
say,
you might say piece of shit.
It's always been Chelsea,
but yeah,
she um,
I think they locked her in the hole for
like 10 months.
Damn.
Yeah.
No talking.
No.
Nobody.
Just by yourself.
Fuck you by yourself.
That's crazy.
I mean,
you could break someone's brain is tired
of people's brain gets broken on a good
edible.
As I watch first 48 I see.
Mother fuckers rang it broken 15 minutes
to cigarettes at a honeypot.
Yeah.
That's another reason I tell kids don't
commit crime or with your homies,
man.
Watch first 48 you're going to see
everything go bad man.
For a newport.
Yeah.
Just so many fucking crimes.
So many laws that don't,
don't need to exist.
Poverty.
We end poverty.
We fixed crime when that's a fuck load
of it,
that's for sure.
Then I'd still be sociopaths and greedy
people that are going to have that,
but far less than crimes of opportunity
like Robin Moms,
if their persons that gas stations car
jackings you're not going to see stolen
cars.
You're not going to see burglaries.
You're not going to see that.
If you start to have an influx of,
you know,
we'd need to bring a lot of stuff back
to America.
We need to start making shit again and
he'd start buying shit.
We make again.
We need to,
we need to start refocusing on what we
could be doing in house.
I think,
you know,
I think that would certainly help us and
I don't know what we could do,
uh,
to sort of promote that idea of,
um,
I mean,
why doesn't it,
it's nothing that ever gets discussed
in any political discussion.
Like when,
whenever there's some debates going on
or whenever there's,
cause we're being given an agenda,
but nobody ever thinks of that one
aspect of our culture,
the weakest aspect of our culture
economically.
If we don't really consider it,
you just look at it as a source of
crime.
It's a statistic we sitters as though
it's something that just is just has to
be,
but it doesn't have to be like that.
Well,
especially if we know history and to
tell them he shuts all.
I'm really trying to say like there are
other alternatives,
other ways to try this and,
and we could,
yeah,
you can't,
you can try to fix homelessness without
criminalizing being homeless.
Right?
We know that most men that are homeless,
um,
have some types of mental illnesses,
schizophrenia.
So that means that we've broken down and
we're not taking care of the mentally
ill in a way that we should be a could
be.
So if you start to fix that,
you start to fix that kind of
homelessness.
We know that women and children,
we know why they're on the street and we
know that if they're subsidized into
these types of affordable housing,
apartments in the city,
the kids have the opportunity to go to
better schools,
to become better parts of society in
terms of having to networks and
resources.
We know the mothers are closer to work,
can be home,
but we don't do that.
We build cities.
Like right now we're developing Atlanta
and we've been promised a certain amount
of,
um,
of workspace in the city for working
class people,
for poor people.
Some of the developers aren't doing what
they say they do.
And because you do that,
you start to increase the,
the things that are blights on us.
You know,
we just have to be really committed to
it and do it.
And that's it.
And once we do it,
it's done,
you know.
But if we,
if we keep acting like it's not
happening and complaining about poverty
and crime in war and not doing anything,
it's just the cycle never stops nasty on
the insanity.
I really don't understand yet.
Well everybody feels like it's somebody
else's job.
Everybody feels like work like,
yeah.
And everybody feels like,
well you just got to get out of that
neighborhood.
Nah,
that doesn't work.
That's what I was his work.
Roxanne Shawntay talked about reentry
vacation.
She said,
you know,
she,
she doesn't want to hear people come,
keep complaining about gentrification
when the kids that are leaving these
neighborhoods,
whether they'd sing dance,
rap or not,
or just cokie could jobs and colby
decent human beings.
You should be reentering your
neighborhood.
You should be buying houses or pieces of
land near.
One of the most impressive things,
one of my favorite players are John
Stockton,
and I'll know if it's true or not,
but I read a story that he actually
bought a house right on the street he
grew up in.
So in the Aussie that he go back
essentially home with his kids.
So they'd had some type of normalization
to their life.
We,
we should be doing it,
you know,
um,
Tiana,
I have bought properties together in the
same neighborhoods we grew up in,
were developing things like restaurants
and stuff.
I like to see more athletes and rappers
become the merchant and business class,
net weight.
And I like to see people who grew up in
neighborhoods move back to those
neighborhoods they grew up in like,
like the typical iconic American dream.
You know you can build a,
you know,
another eight square feet in the back of
the a frame house if you want to,
but you shouldn't be going to 54 60
minutes outside the city in there
complaining about the blight of the city
because you took yourself away,
you took the talent and the resources
away.
Do you think that everyone should feel
that way though?
Or is it,
I mean,
do you feel like you have to be
committed to the city that you grew up
in or couldn't you want to just get the
fuck out of there and go somewhere
different difference?
Nothing wrong with getting the fuck out,
but you just think you should go back
and support it.
Yeah.
It's like I tell kids,
you know,
in college and they say,
Mike,
you know,
what can we do?
You know,
kids in college gets,
when you go speak at college and say,
well,
what could we do?
Kids want to affect the world very easy.
Fanned a kid in high school,
tutored at Kit and make sure they
replace you at this university or
another.
I said,
you're just used replanting a scene.
If you grow food,
you know you don't grow the same way and
you have to year after year some you'd
have to give that land a break.
Retail it,
you know what I'm saying?
It was kind of like the neighborhood.
So you don't have to stay in the same
neighborhood your whole life.
You don't have to feel like I never win
anything or escaped anywhere.
But you do have to,
don't sell your mother's house,
you know,
rent it to your cousin,
let you get my assistant but don't,
don't sell your mother.
That piece of land was worked for the
blood to toil the soil.
It means something and it should.
And,
and for working class people especially,
it keeps your neighborhood and
communities more like the ones that made
you be a good human being,
you know?
So I think that there is something,
most people don't leave the town,
they grow up in and moved to the other
side or they moved to the suburbs for
most people or most people marry
somebody they knew.
You know what I'm saying?
My thing is make the best of it.
Don't let it keep becoming a worse.
A man named Mr John,
my wife and I own barbershops or people
don't know Yom distincts called the Shea
washing room shops.
We have one at state farm arena that
when the Atlanta Hawks play,
we have our flagship store on age would
ave edgewood avenue was once an Auburn
Avenue.
When wants to centers of black Atlanta
in terms of commerce and retail and
money,
Atlanta life insurance company with
their,
you guys google.
Some of this stuff's,
it's big time shit.
You know,
this isn't the old narrative of we've
never had nothing cause that's not the
truth.
And Landon was a very rich city for
African Americans.
Still is on this street,
used to be owned by African Americans.
The storefronts in there,
their children after these people.
Dot off solar buildings off and sold it
for cheap.
And I know this because many,
Mr John who runs the grocery store,
they stopped me one day.
He said,
you know Michael [inaudible] after we're
gone and this neighborhood's been
gentrified and everything's different,
they're going to come along and say that
white people stole this from us.
And he said,
that's not true.
He say the children or the people that
were here left and they never came back
because they didn't think what they
parents bill was good enough.
Oh man to kill me because that is not
just black people,
less Americans period.
We have gotten to a point where we are
unappreciative,
we are entitled and we don't think what
happened before us was good enough so we
don't treasure it.
We don't honor it.
We don't reinvest in it.
That could be a farm in Milledgeville
that could be a house in Adamsville,
but we have to do a better job of
appreciating ourselves,
appreciating our community and in Capri,
Shane,
our greater community and you have to
reenter,
you have to reenter fi day.
You have to be a part of whatever
gentrification happens to make sure that
your stake is still there and net what
you care about from a moral and civil
perspective represented there.
My uncle,
my uncle John Blackman,
who was a huge influence on me dad and
had a five car garage where,
where he did transmissions and stuff and
I begged my aunt to sell it,
please,
I don't want you.
I know they're going to come.
The beltline's coming.
I was cooked,
but please sell it to me.
I didn't want my uncle's building,
you know,
for to go to strangers and become,
an apartment complex or something.
And I walked in your building I senior
building and I said,
wow,
I know what I'm gonna do with it now.
I've had it for like three years now.
It's just,
I just had it,
but I didn't never knew what I wanted to
do.
But you were like,
Yo,
you need somewhere to go every day
you're building is impressive.
I'm like,
Yo,
I'm just going to just make my bit,
my uncle's building.
My office is right.
And I figured out a way to make a lot of
money off of it.
I mean,
I've already made a lot of money,
which is what leaving me to buy it.
But it's important to me that as his
neighborhood turns into hipster land,
because it's definitely going to be,
she's going to be black hips going to be
like chocolate,
hipster and land.
I just wanted to make sure that's,
there's still some chocolate working
class in there and sometimes they're
going to go buy coffee and there's going
to be a loud ass muscle car and lots of
marijuana smoke point out of it so
they'll know that you know,
my uncle's nephew still in town.
Well,
you've got a,
a great combination of a work ethic,
a sense of community,
and you had a business perspective.
I don't have a business perspective.
I'm doing shit.
My wife,
my wife,
your wife is doing it all while she
taught Campbell.
You seem to know what the fuck you're
talking about.
If you've got a pretty good roadmap,
Eh,
you know I've zero that zero business
perspective,
you have the discipline to go to the gym
every day though.
I do have that.
That's what I got it.
But I'm crazy that I'm going to the gym
to try to silence demons forever.
I had man failing was the best thing
that ever happened to me for.
I think for everybody fail.
Not because some people get stuck at
they failure and they become bitter and
they become envious.
They become hateful.
At least how to mock.
Yeah.
But failure can be one of the best
things that ever happened to failing and
having to learn to become a business
person.
I'm very thankful for removed from the
failure.
Now don't you think dad about your rap
career as well?
Like that's what I was talking.
Oh,
from business perspective as well.
From hailed at rat first I was a good
rapper,
but outcast tacoma and I records math.
My first record that went gold at a time
where we read other record was going 10
million.
It was a fee.
It didn't work.
Right.
It didn't work for me.
So I had to go to Texas and people like
chameleon,
Aaron Paul Wall Bunbee zero,
slim thug,
trey to truth,
right?
Um,
people like flip and hump.
These people taught me how to press up
my own cds,
put them in the marketplace,
sell them at profit,
reinvest themselves.
They taught me that and selling drugs.
You know what,
they taught me to rudimentary
fundamentals of business and when I met
my wife,
I can remember dating two,
three,
four,
five little hot chicks and her just
mentally being,
you know,
our wife caught her,
right?
Right.
Freshman Year of college.
But just mentally she was light years
ahead of everyone because the
grandmother had raised her in that way.
Grandmother had a shot house running
around or like a Chitlin circuit you
want go get a shot for $2 on Sundays
because the south is,
you know,
it's a weird place.
We didn't use to sell alcohol on Sunday.
So my wife I recognize,
have a sharper mind and me for business.
What I had was good ideas for what was
sale and what would be well in the
marketplace and what she had was a
discipline to Oregon.
Have any failures in your business
practice or the jam.
And first few years I had a barbershop I
wanted to kill every Barbara.
Barbara's are like independent rappers.
You know,
everyone wants to be more famous than
they need to be an artist.
Barbara's going to be famous.
Yeah.
Partner's life via famous.
I mean there are local fixers.
Yeah.
The artists.
Absolutely.
And they should be,
you know what I mean?
But um,
with the essay,
it,
man,
it can be frustrating.
You know,
when Barbara comes in one day,
like I want to wear a glitter Cape
today.
The next part was coming of like,
yeah,
I want,
if I want to cut hair in the nude,
I want to use your shop to do it.
And you're like,
Bro,
it doesn't,
it doesn't work like that.
Like,
like this is the right.
But I had to learn for us that the booth
rent model,
like you pay in booth renting us not
making any more profit that they're
knit.
So we had to kind of say,
well,
what is supercuts do?
What does great clips do?
What?
Oh,
you want it by commission and then you
split.
That means they have to beat her and her
weight.
And that's how we kinda learned business
when we got an offer from the hawks to
put our place in the space of the arena.
And we want to be a more arenas.
We started to understand,
okay,
this is how you do business business.
You know,
this is not just how you,
you know,
make two to $4,000 extra a month and
that's just some good income for your
wife to be able to enjoy it.
But this is how you start to say,
you know,
more than the bright a barbershop.
This is a lifestyle and retail brand and
we happened to Barbara.
But if you're a guy,
I don't like going to the beauty shops
or beauty stores to buy my brushes or by
my combs or you know,
if you want to get a little gray out of
your beard,
you know,
you don't want to be in the rx section
of your local walmart or you're was
like,
hey,
where do I get the grade from my beer
cause I want to go get hot young chicks.
You know,
you want to go shop.
And so we develop products,
we have cool stuff.
You can just buy it right there.
And we've learning to be business people
and hopefully I would like to become the
chick filet of barbershops.
I'd like for people to want to want to
have us in their towns and pay us a lot
of money to come.
Well it's a man's hangout too.
I mean,
you can say anything you want and no one
judges,
you can tall,
you can watch the Joe Rogan Talk Shit,
you know?
Yeah.
Barbershops are uniquely masculine.
They are like beauty shops are for
girls.
Girls can go into a beauty shop and get
their nails done and no,
there's not going to be any men there.
They can talk all kinds of crazy shit.
Yeah.
That's one of the reasons why they like
it.
Yep.
And,
and the women that do come to
barbershops are some of the best shit
talkers.
So even they fit in,
right?
Yeah.
That's
what,
you know,
barbershop is exciting as one that has
those two or three women customers data,
just prime shit.
Talkers.
How much,
if any,
are you paying attention to things like
crypto currencies?
Um,
Dj Vlad has taught me a lot about
stocks.
So much to the point that I bought my
wife thousands of dollars in stocks for
Christmas.
She cried,
she cried when I,
when I showed it a wedding band that I
bought,
cause I never really got her winning
band and say,
I really want to show you.
I'm dedicating myself to you.
And this is,
this is never coming off at if Soviet,
beginning of Christmas,
she cried when she saw my wedding band.
And at the end she cried when I say,
I never want you to be fully dependent
upon me or feel that way.
So here's a lot of stock.
And she cried like a baby.
I called flat like this shit works.
Bronco Friesen,
Bro.
But I'm so I'm learning about,
and I just put lots of money into the s
and p 500,
but I don't know a lot about crypto
currency and stuff.
I'm learning how to have money.
I'm fascinated by them.
Uh,
d the idea of a decentralized economy,
you know,
cause we're always,
the whole thing has always been about
the,
the amount of money that banks control.
If you just stop and think about what's
going,
what goes on with the Federal Reserve
and what goes on with all the money and
how much a dollar is worth overseas and
balance of it all.
If there was something that we can all
rely on that wasn't controlled by any
gigantic group of people that have a
vested interest in profiting off of this
pile of money.
If it was some sort of a bitcoin like
thing,
it'd be a really different world.
Yeah.
Really,
really different.
Eh,
it,
it would,
it'd be different if the world was money
list.
It'd be different if there was a gold
standard.
Again,
it'd be a lot of differences.
But the question becomes,
is the banking mafia of source ever
going to let that happen?
And what happened?
How could they stop it?
Well,
it's like stopping the Internet at this
point.
So you think it's calming,
you think we're going to get the
cryptocurrency?
I think it's eventually going to be,
what are we going to throw the chicken
coops?
It's kind of,
they're going to,
yeah,
let's be big.
That's a question correctly,
right?
You can't throw coins and clubs.
It's true.
Yeah.
What can you,
yeah,
we,
yeah.
Pieces of paper that tells you how
change on your way and cash and no ass
bro.
Bitcoin will become like dollar bills
that'll represent bitcoin mccarthy black
tower built with a goal,
like a shiny gold lettering to make a
shit ton of money.
We'd be going,
no,
some,
we made some of it for her fight for the
forgotten charity.
They build wells for the pygmies in the
Congo.
My friend Justin wren,
he lives in the Congo for six months out
of the year building wells.
And so fight for the forgotten we,
we raised,
we raised a bunch of money through this
thing called the cash app.
Every time someone,
someone's actually $5 goes to fight for
the forgotten.
Gotcha.
And we got some big coin that we raised
that went to them too.
So wells got built because of that.
He's built.
I don't know how many,
well these are like 18 wells they built
for the pygmies and they're constantly
building new ones because the big
museum.
Freshwater.
Yeah.
He's a fighter.
He fights for Bell Tory.
He's one of their top heavyweights stove
shit.
And uh,
goes over to Africa and lives in the
Congo with the pygmies ass fucking,
yeah man.
He lives there in the village for,
you know,
months.
He's gotten malaria three times.
Almost died from it.
Yes.
The dedication.
He's one of the nicest people that's
ever walked the face of the planet.
That's fucking nuts.
So did he do to malaria shaft and shit
and it's still catchman area.
I do not do a first trip to Africa next
year.
So,
you know,
as a black guy,
I feel it's important or y'all want to
catch malaria?
That's him back there.
Wow.
Yeah.
They call them the big pig.
Me.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
Nicest guy that's ever lived.
Those are,
wow.
Yeah.
I mean the guy goes there for six months
a year.
It's amazing people in the picture with
them look like they were related to me.
Yeah.
It's pretty cool,
man.
He's got some great videos on fight for
the forgotten.
That's beautiful.
Uh,
where you could see the,
um,
the wells being built and the water
coming out.
I got to check that out.
You can send me the link.
Yeah,
for sure.
Dope for sure.
Um,
what were we talking about?
How do we get up to this
corporate donors we raised,
we raised some money for him through a
bitcoin as well,
but I think that it's,
um,
give me some advice.
I don't know enough about it.
I'm an idiot.
I just thought anything on anything
money related.
Cause you have an icon jeep,
so I know you have more money.
I just work a lot that just,
you know what,
we'll such grandfatherly that's true.
That's the shit.
My grandfather,
I'm not a big,
I'm not a big investor.
I'm not very smart.
I got you.
I have people handling that kind of
stuff,
which,
you know,
work a lot,
but I don't pay attention to anything.
I paid attention.
Guilty now.
Yeah.
I do too many things myself to the place
where I know exactly what I have to pay
attention to them.
What I don't,
I don't have to pay attention to is just
gone shot.
Robert Paul laid my accountant has made
it pretty easy for me.
He is literally a graph.
This is a dollar you make.
This is what goes into savings.
This is what goes into investment.
This is what you and Shay weren't
invested in real estate.
This is for retirement.
So now everything that comes in and I
already know.
So it's like when they call us until
like,
hey you guys,
you guys got a $500,000 a day.
I just know that I'm not going home with
two 50 because asset management
conditions,
my wife and my accounting already chop
that shit up.
So I'm just like,
I got enough money to buy a Camaro.
Yeah,
I don't like to think about that.
I had just to think about now,
because you know I'm black and you know,
shit,
I ain't been too good if you like,
but he got money.
If you pour a black,
if you pour America's fucked up,
yeah,
if you pour and black Americans fuck
that with a deal during ass.
So you know,
my whole shit is,
let,
let me take care of my money because my
Grandpa,
you know,
my grandmother,
her family owned land,
they started as sharecroppers but
because they all land she could,
because she could become educated
because they could sell the stuff.
They grew to stores and produce markets
and stuff.
So she named were methodist.
So she got to go to school.
My grandfather,
some mother old no land.
So grandfather had
to work in a bread factory in cotton
meals and shit.
So I knew did difference between
ownership and you know,
the advantages of having something in
it.
So it's something I can have obsessed on
because I don't want my children to
endure poverty.
And I,
and I grew up working class,
you know,
my wife,
she jokes but she says it a lot.
You know,
she was from housing projects in
Savannah and her grandmother and her
mother worked.
They were out of there.
But you know,
she says to me,
me all the time,
you were spoiled.
You know,
you're a little rich.
Kids were like,
what are you talking about?
She's like,
you had a fucking rv.
I'm like,
I lived in an a frame house.
She's like,
I don't care.
Your Grandpa,
your grandparents couldn't afford the
RV.
You guys went on vacation.
You were spoiled.
So I understand money means a lot and it
doesn't mean everything to me,
but it helps to afford me to be able to
take care of her,
my children.
I completely understand it,
but I don't really give a shit knock on
a daily basis.
I'm more like you do.
But you think about businesses,
you think about starting businesses and
forming businesses.
How do you have the time to do that and
write and perform and all the other shit
that you do?
Because it enabled what the business has
enabled me to enjoy writing and
performing.
When I had to wrap,
when there was no choice,
um,
it,
it wasn't as fun anymore because the
pressure was,
am I going to chart,
can I make this much?
Will the record versus,
you know,
if I have a couple of streams of revenue
coming in,
you know,
it makes it a little more relaxed and my
art is freer that way,
you know?
Ooh,
I like that answer.
That's a great answer.
That makes sense.
That makes a lot of sense actually.
Yeah.
To free yourself up creatively so that
all you have to think about when you're
doing that,
you're just doing what you want to do.
Yeah,
that's it.
Yeah man.
That's ideal.
That's wise.
That's the goal.
Yeah.
If I'm a,
you know,
a lot of people talk a lot of shit about
billionaires they like and they want to
be,
and then daryl,
there are tons of billionaires from the
nerdy sexy or Bill Gates or the wild
dope,
eccentric,
sexy of Eli Musk to the ogs of Warren
Buffett and shit.
I like Ted Turner,
Ted Turner as well.
Ted was the guy who got nine and got
snookered out of six,
ended up with one or two and it's like,
man,
I'm living in my fucking life.
Growing Bison eaten good meat.
Where the fuck the cowboy hat when my
funky mustache,
he's,
he was such a good owner of teams and
our city,
when he owned the teams,
he was a great man with tbs and he did a
lot of good.
He's,
if,
if a billion is the new style,
I want to be a billionaire,
but of having a lot of money's a
standard,
I'd like to be the quirky eccentric guy.
Like Ted,
he always seemed free to me.
Yeah.
Especially once he got rid of Jane
Fonda.
Ava shouts out to this and when he
married Jane Fonda the south where we
literally thought it was,
we all made,
it was like the city of Atlanta had went
back to gone with the wind.
It was just amazing.
Again,
it was,
people were strutting around that,
you know,
Jane Fonda's virtual,
our first lady,
you know,
if he will start to,
but I choose a nice lady to the city.
David Justice and highly barry were
interesting to
not interested
in is 10 some bastard.
He was handsome.
One motherfucker world.
Was it?
What's the,
um,
what's the yachting if anyone,
I don't know.
The Yada he who's,
he got into the yachting Outta Nowhere
Cause Cup America.
That was the America's Cup was it?
Was that right?
Yeah.
Ted Turner lived a life that Ralph
Lauren puts on tee shirts.
Yeah,
he looks like a,
like a billionaire and a movie too.
He does great gatsby type.
He does.
He does some guy who is a wise
billionaire.
It brings you into this study and you
have a scotch with him on ice.
Exactly.
Explain Shit to you and you're like,
what in the fuck shouts out to tay it
man.
I know you don't get your love like a
lot of the other guys who love the cut.
He does the fucking my tannic ground
bison,
he's out there chilling man.
We bound it.
The population of Bison so he could cook
them and eat them.
It's like get the fuck outta here.
That's bad ass man.
Look at those overalls.
Respect.
That's how my fucking grandfather
dressed with the same mustache.
That's what I want to be like when I
think about making 21 million and
escaping the game and shit.
This is me like maybe overalls and a
braves cap,
but this is it.
Now let me ask you this,
how far away from him or dudes with
machine guns at all times,
but he's in fucking Montana,
but so what?
I can drive to my tenants to kill Ted
Turner.
Who wants to come in?
No one wants to kill Ted Turner.
He kept somebody,
Bro.
No one wants to kill.
I would imagine he has two snipers.
He probably has a,
yeah,
he probably has two snipers
say east and west and he has one guy
within a few feet of him,
but very relaxed.
I don't think teds walking around like
Qaddafi.
Did you think you get to assert didn't
work out well for Khadafi know and do
more kind of long for him.
He was hanging around with the wrong
dude's.
Damn.
The last video of Kadafi dead is one of
the most disturbing videos and all of
human history to see him realize that
they got his over and then that guy
strip shops at knife up his ass and he's
barely even reacting to him.
He's just,
he's in a state of shock.
If you have understand people who have
not of a certain age man,
these were the villains when we were
young man,
Gorbachev Kadafi cashed all like when
you start dating,
and I'm not saying I agree or don't
agree,
I'm just saying they were gave get to
give it to us as doug villains.
I never thought if he could go out and
the way you went out bad,
we saw a couple guys go out like that,
but that was the craziest one because
that was him getting caught by rebels
executing him on the spot.
They didn't even wait.
They didn't even wait until like,
fuck this.
Fuck this trial.
I'm going to kill this guy right now.
They threw his body on the hood of the
car.
Driving around with a fucking deer.
Yeah,
like a fucking deer.
Exactly.
Then
I had researched and beat the shit out
of him.
It is,
it's a horrible,
and his dad job is showing,
you can see it's gray hairs.
Ah,
y'all said a little bit and then temple.
Yeah,
that's a well but Ted Turner's the
billionaire.
I want to be,
if I could pick one of the most
disturbing videos,
was Hillary Clinton laughing about him
dying over?
You see that video?
No Bro.
She's doing an interview and she,
they're talking about Kadafi and she
goes,
we came,
we saw he died
and she starts laughing cause I guess
they have genuine
throngs worthy.
That's sir.
It was a surgery as a queen
and we all want it.
My friend called me this year.
Oh cassie Jaye swift.
My wife tells me I need a husband more
than,
than we,
the world needs a martyr that,
and my friend called me saying,
you know what man,
really,
I just don't want nobody to kill my
friend.
That and that really made me push it in
perspective.
Like maybe I should keep saying it.
A dance.
Maybe you shouldn't try to braveheart
this thing.
Yeah,
people definitely still do.
Get shot.
Yeah.
Straight up.
Fuck what anybody says.
Eh.
There was a dude who was an Enron
whistleblower who?
Enron whistleblower who shot himself in
the head twice.
Yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
That kind of shit.
That doesn't,
what in the fuck are you talking about?
Did you ever read the strange death of
Vince Foster?
I have not.
It's a great book.
Okay.
It's about Vince foster who was in
cahoots with the Clintons,
shot himself.
They,
when they found his body,
the gun was still in his hand,
which never happens.
Guns fly out of here.
Then there was less blood at the scene
of the crime then was missing from his
body.
So the idea is that someone moved him.
Someone put him there.
Yeah,
right down on his shit.
Fake Donovan Shit.
They did it for sure they did it,
but before there was an internet.
Oh,
you to do is grease the right amount of
people and have a plan in place and it's
done.
It's done.
He
did it forever.
They did it through the Roman era.
They did great.
They did it from the beginning of time.
People who've been whacking people this
era.
A lot of people act as though those
were,
again,
like I said,
he's empires that were under having
thousands of years.
Like a corporation will change his name,
you know,
and,
and go forward.
There's something else.
I honestly,
I'm going to at some point get a,
what was it?
What's her brother's name?
Romulus and I forget the other brother,
but who were circled by the wolves that
was like to start to fit the fairytale
started wrong.
I'm going to get that as a peer.
As a pendant.
Ooh.
Yeah.
It's going to be some,
I like artsy rap shit.
So I have like the winged victory of
some [inaudible] is my,
is um,
is a piece,
have another piece that's based on it.
Get that.
I'm getting that on appendage Jesus,
yet it wasn't Romulus.
And what's the other brother's name is
Raymond [inaudible].
Raymond's and Robin and sell.
Apparently our society that we live in
under now was the legend is Jamie said,
well you see we started by two brothers
who were nursed after,
after bay being abandoned where nurse by
a wolf.
So Western society is built on that
concept and you're gonna ask me to give
up my fucking guns.
The Fuck Outta here.
Fuck.
Gotta Yo man.
Wolf Tooth,
Wolf Scott chain mail around its neck
exam.
I'm going to get that on a fucking
pendant.
It's going to be like this rapper.
Big Shit.
That's a war wolf thing.
Look at that.
That's got to do vitals protected.
That's crazy.
Yeah,
that's what,
that's what we're sitting in the middle
of teas.
Every geist Erica babies from wolves.
From wolves.
So what do you think the mentality of
people who run a us?
Jesus Christ.
I saw this,
I saw it in the loo.
Me and my wife was stoned as fuck.
That's incredible.
Walking through the loom and I was just
like,
this is amazing.
I stared at what a freaky looking wolf
too hungry and shit.
Looks like a fucking Hyena actually.
Yeah,
it does.
It doesn't look like it's got wolf hair.
Cause waves are beautiful like that.
That's an,
that will faint.
But it's weird to decide to make a bald
wolf.
That's a bald wall.
Yeah,
it's like shaved.
Yeah.
There's no hair on it anyway.
Doesn't show any hair.
Who knows what the fuck wolves looked
like?
[inaudible] that's a good point.
Yeah.
Shaved the hair into the rock.
Yeah,
that's true too.
Yeah.
It'd be hard to shave it,
but still what a freaky idea.
Eh,
so that's what suckled off of wolves.
They think about it and that's,
that's,
that's the mentality.
And arrested out of the rep in the room.
Have you ever been,
have not been in the room with me.
I went a couple of years ago for the
first time.
It's amazing.
Really stunning.
Stunning antiquity.
Is that what they call it?
When you go to the Vatican man,
you walk around and you realize how much
these motherfuckers stole.
There is billions of dollars where the
art there and you're like,
where did you get this funny?
You're not out there selling sneakers.
Fuck is candy and bibles and we're going
to take all of this art that she has.
It's crazy.
You know,
it's interesting.
You know when you see Roman guys with
little Dicks,
the little thing,
they,
they big dicks were discussed like big
dicks.
Were there were two savage and not
civilized.
They had little dicks and these little
statues.
If you look at these beautiful,
perfect bodies,
I'll a little dicks and that was because
they felt like big dicks were gross.
Oh Wow.
How crazy is that?
That's what the guy,
at least the professor that was guiding
us to load zig,
dude,
you're in the wrong century.
Yeah.
You just,
you are almost there.
The thing is though,
they want something that doesn't exist.
Right?
Because a guy who's built like that,
it's going to have a hog on them.
You know
those guys,
those guys are bad.
They're fucking a diocese.
Right?
That's beautiful.
You see Anthony Joshua step into the
ring.
You go,
that guy's got to have a gigantic day.
He has to look it up and he's a fucking
specimen.
There's no way he has a burger.
With that said,
if you look at bodybuilding,
yeah,
but that's a different animal there.
They're breaking their body's ability to
perform,
to stop testosterone.
They're nuts.
A shrinking fucked up.
Yeah.
It looks bad.
I got a picture of Ronnie Coleman that I
send to my friends every now and then
just as like a wake up call.
I save it on my phone.
I sent it.
I just want you to know that this is how
big people can get,
so why while you're lifting weights,
just keep everything in perspective and
always know
possible.
One of them,
Ronnie me show you the one that I got on
my phone,
Jamie,
he just had back surgery,
game prayers up to run.
I heard there's a documentary about him
that's on Netflix.
I'll watch it.
It was just sad and not sad,
but like you feel bad,
just like first of all,
it's amazing.
He had that type of discipline.
He was eating 10,000 calories a day.
He was training for one hour a day doing
full,
full training,
top to bottom because he was a cop at
the same time and he was just a bull
about it.
Here it is,
but with that said it.
Oh my God,
there's that picture.
Yeah,
that's not good.
I can't.
That's insane.
This one jet,
that's a CV.
You find that one?
It's insane.
Yeah.
And,
and now,
here's his back.
Is,
is savagely just betraying them.
Yeah.
Well,
he,
he apparently would lift so much weight,
you know,
he's a much smaller now.
He would live so much weight and worked
out so much harder than anybody.
Wow.
What a look at his last.
I want to send this so people can get
the one that we're looking at,
cause it's so fucking forget cycle.
You see the picture of that bull.
Exactly.
You a all time.
Yeah.
They have,
um,
something wrong with,
what does that Myostatin and Myostatin
inhibitors,
Myostatin is something that apparently
it regulates the muscle growth.
And,
uh,
when these myostatin inhibitors,
when they do,
they either happen accidentally on dogs
called whippets on.
Have you ever seen a window?
Whippet whippets get,
uh,
they have,
an anomaly that occurs pretty,
pretty rarely where they growed like
double the muscle.
They fucking look super jacked.
You know,
we've gotta look like trash it up.
Yeah.
Pull up one of those,
uh,
Myostatin whippets
okay.
So here's a,
here's,
sure.
There's the Ronnie Coleman picture.
So everybody could see it.
That's the one we're looking at.
Like what in the fuck Jesus.
Those pictures were as you're a fag.
I walked into a gym,
do more to dishearten knew that
anything.
Exactly like what the fuck am I not
getting?
I ass not happening.
You would have to be on everything that
science has ever twice did to put that
kind of mass on mass and you have to
have perfect genetics.
You have to have everything.
You have to have a warm Jesus Christ.
See if you can find those whippets.
The myostatin whippet crazy looking.
It doesn't even look like a real dog.
It looks like someone Cgi,
like someone's fucking with it.
I just made a real dog just,
they just have a weird anomaly,
a genetic anomaly that makes them super
fucking jacked.
Like how does that work though?
In terms of like,
I'm not,
I come,
I like pit bulls like I like,
there it is.
So that's really how we thought that was
fate.
No,
that's real.
Wow.
It's real.
There's a bunch of them.
It happens in this community for some
reason.
I've read something about what it is
about breeding that somehow or another,
this gene is trait has is more common in
whippets than most other animals as
crazy.
I'd like the traditional style pit bull
like Pete from little rascals,
right?
Yeah.
The,
the new pit Bul.
The ones that are lower if bulkier,
almost like the lowest as an English
bulldog or over muscle.
I always wonder how useful are they?
Well,
if they get ahold of you,
you're fucked.
Damn sure.
Power is just insane.
The power that those things have is
insane,
but it's bad.
It's really when
you get an answer like this,
and I have a hard time breathing,
it's not good for,
yeah,
it's supposed to have longer legs so it
can move.
Good pit bulls were bred for a couple
reasons.
They were bred for purposes of fighting
and purposes of bringing down bulldogs.
You know,
they run alongside the bull,
grab the,
grab the nose,
ring trop their wait flip essentially
football ball.
So I'm just thinking myself as we liked
the aesthetics of what they look like.
Like,
what are we really doing to these little
guys where they're fucking,
they're buffed to shit,
but they're shorter shit.
It's hard to get up,
prepare steps for them.
You know they have such amazing
qualities because the fact they're game
bread because the,
the,
the ones that are,
that responded negatively to people that
would growl at people or show aggression
to people.
They called them.
So the ones that are real game dogs,
let's a little 35 pound males.
Those are the best dogs on the planet
earth,
man.
I've been trying to convince shaffer
like they're so nice.
I'm like,
I just,
Shit,
I'm sorry.
I can't do like these other rappers and
get a fucking a girl dog and act like
that.
You already make me hold your fucking
Paris.
I'm not
straight the fuck up.
Like I buy these things your thousands
of fucking dollars.
I shouldn't be having to call the
coordinate because you want to fucking
walk around,
you know,
hold my purse.
I have to go to phoenix sky.
That's one of her favorite stories.
I'm wanting to phoenix sky.
Hold my fucking purse.
I'm like taller.
Hold versus up.
You're hilarious.
Checkmate moved that girls put on her
gun is in there though.
So I feel a little manly,
but it's still a fucking Louis Vuitton
purse,
you know.
But if I had,
if I had a pit,
yeah,
great,
great pit,
then I'd be,
I,
you know,
I'm just like,
I can't get a girl dog.
I got to get a paypal.
You could get a little pit bull and
people won't even know it's a pitbull.
Yeah.
And they're nice.
I told her about,
my oldest daughter is 21 now Naya.
And we had,
we had,
uh,
we had a pit named coca.
I,
if for some reason didn't not like
sleeping in her bed or laying down a
[inaudible],
we would have to,
and this is when I'm working,
like I'm getting up,
going to work at the fucking advanced
auto parts.
Her mom is in school and beauty school.
It's like we're tired.
We're young,
too young to have baby.
We're beat the fuck up a night.
Would only sleep in her little rocker.
This dog was sleep directly under her.
And if you are not mere her mother,
you were not walking up there touching
this child.
Well and when my daughter was awake,
she was her best friend.
She could ride it like a horse.
You could tell him to sit,
stand,
move.
She'd do anything but to in her eyes to
her purpose in life was to make sure
that this child is say that's a man.
That was other pit bulls.
I know big boy on pitfall Kennels,
his brother he and changed.
They have one.
They,
they have amazing dog.
Yeah.
There's a lot of those out there.
There's a lot of great pit bulls out
there.
The only problem with pit bulls is they
have an aggression towards other dogs.
They do.
Absolutely.
Do you have another dog around?
There's likely going to be a scrap and
it got to be exhausting for me.
I understand that.
Well I'm,
I'm,
I'm pro one or two like my thing is I
only have,
you should only have one or two pitch.
You should have one that's dedicated to
you and the family we should have two
pits.
Got are part of the family and they
understand,
you know,
who's the dominant and who's the Alpha
News?
A Beta.
I had
one pair that I got from the pound and
she had been the pound for like five
months.
Yeah.
She was in the Ellie animal shelter.
She was only 11 months old.
She was a prison dog.
Basically.
She just,
most of her life had been locked up in
this little cage and that dog,
if anybody else wanted to get pet,
she would get up to them and go get the
fuck outta here.
She would show her teeth and ground him.
She want anybody getting pet by her.
She would,
any other dogs tried to move in?
She would growl at him,
box him out.
She box him out.
Like check them.
Like if you're trying to pet one of the
other dogs like no,
no,
no.
She'd get right up in there.
You know what I found with them?
They are like children in that they
throw tantrums.
Yeah.
So if they get lonely and they get
lonely without you,
they miss you.
Yeah.
They'll do shit.
Like,
just tap the fucking cell or the house
or to the laundry.
And then you'll get there.
You'll call them,
you're looking for them and they're
like,
oh shit,
I fucked up.
And they're hiding in her room and shit.
Like they,
they,
um,
they're brilliant little fuckers.
You know what?
My man,
my man Cielo had had a bunch of great
pitch back in the day.
So I want to get a pit bull.
I'm declaring that today.
Shane and kate.
Tell me what to do.
Wow.
That's happening.
As long as you're responsible owner,
train it.
Well,
make sure it doesn't get loose.
Yup.
And I don't believe in fighting dogs no.
Now to fight.
No.
Fuck that.
Um,
they're,
uh,
they're escape artists too.
You gotta be careful though.
You fuckers can climb a fence.
They can climb a fence.
They're smart enough to open the gate.
Yeah,
I've seen him run up a tree.
My oldest daughter has a tiny little dog
and a,
it's one of the smartest dogs I've ever
seen because it's a,
it's part Chihuahua and part a
Australian shepherd dog,
I think.
But it's the only dog I've ever had
where it's Paul got caught on the leash
and it lifted his leg up and put it
behind the behind the leash.
Oh Wow.
I've never seen a dog do that.
Dogs get that one arm and then fuck
this dog looked at that one.
Oh,
this is easy.
Oh Shit.
My bad.
And I looked at them like,
you let a motherfucker,
there's smart little dude.
My wife had an Australian shepherd when
I met her Mfi.
Yeah.
That,
that smart fucking dogs.
Chihuahuas are smart making dog.
Oh yeah.
They can be me.
Yeah.
Surprisingly.
What's the weirdest thing is that all
those came from wolves.
Everything came from a wolf.
Yeah.
All of them.
That's nuts.
Every dog.
Something key that we took it back and I
say this,
some people in my community,
but in humans evolved from monkeys.
Ooh.
He's saying kind of Asheville get,
so that was the words of killer Mike.
If you're just listening.
Yeah.
We definitely didn't pop up just like we
are.
I don't believe that.
Anyway.
What do you think happened?
I don't know.
I don't know what happened,
but my wife says,
joking,
you got to know my wife.
She's,
she's very cool,
very down to earth.
She's my best friend.
She speaks in his thick creole.
He like accent and she'll just say
things blindly out of nowhere there.
It's fucking hilarious.
And she'll,
we're watching planting today and she
says,
you know,
people get mad about it,
but shit,
when you look at them,
human beings do look like monkeys.
I mean,
we probably were swinging the fuck
around a few thousand and I'm just
thinking of myself.
You do realize in the black community,
that's an insult to even call us.
And she's just,
because she's black,
of course,
she's just like a man.
She pointed at the screen.
I was just like,
yeah,
we probably a fault.
You know,
and,
and you know,
it,
people can have whatever debates they
want to file it.
But,
you know,
I think that we act a lot just like,
I think human beings are arrogant
because we think we can communicate and
we can use tools to build shit.
But basically we're hairless apes and
you know,
just cause we can communicate doesn't
mean we're communicating the right
things.
Animals live in harmony with nature and
a very different way.
You know what I mean?
They kill for hunger,
you know what I mean?
AIDS can't kill for reasons that are non
hunger related and things of that
nature.
So we know that's a part of us.
But I,
I honestly think,
yeah,
I think we evolved from something that
didn't necessarily look like us.
Yeah.
If that may have swing from a tree where
the most advanced of the primates,
but we exhibit characteristics so we can
see in the lower primates and if you pay
attention to all the top scientists who
have spent studying human evolution,
they're all pretty much in agreement
that there was something that we were
all similar too.
And they all branched off at a bunch of
different ways.
It's amazing.
They keep finding new forms of people
too.
Yeah,
I saw why they just stopped destined.
Noveon or something like that.
That's what it's called.
Not another,
the one from Russia.
So do you think yellow do you take alien
has really popped down.
Fuck the monkey and we popped out nine
months later.
Here we go.
Oh look,
that would be the most fun.
Yeah,
I think so.
I think if a pit stop happened and what
was the movie that was really crappy and
not as good as it should have been?
That was the aliens like precursor
something showed essentially where can
atheists atheist,
right.
They should have been very good at
theory.
But yeah,
I think,
I think that that that's the
possibility.
Aliens were chick hanging out at the
moon,
said,
Yo,
look at the blue plans to fucking go see
with and say Yo [inaudible] he looks
great.
Fuck the shit out of it.
Got Out of there.
And the next thing you know you have war
and pestilence and violence and poverty
and MMA.
Mm and joints.
But one monkey that accelerated stop
past way past all the other ones.
Like one invention,
the invent,
the ability to communicate and the
ability to having opposable thumbs,
the ability to communicate.
And then it started advancing.
As soon as it started talking,
started figuring out ways to express
itself to each other,
and then they started making things and
they're off to the races and the next
thing you know,
a couple hundred thousand years later,
the world's different Pune.
It's like this thing erupts and then
just covers the world,
which is shit.
Yeah,
and that's us.
How do you subscribe to the theory that
we just may be a virus and the earth may
be getting rid of us?
Well,
no one would like to think that.
Right,
but the reason you call a virus or
something,
it's just an a,
a word that's been assigned to a living
organism and a system.
By biomedical science,
I mean,
we all know what a viruses,
it's a real thing.
It's amazing that these brilliant people
have discovered it and come up with
vaccines to stop and prevent them,
but it's a some sort of a life form
really.
Essentially.
Yeah.
Now,
if we looked at the earth as being a
living organism and so we should we,
it's certainly you can make an argument
that it's a kind of a life form that
it's a host of massive amounts of life
of all the life.
Yeah.
Um,
you would think that maybe some of those
things would not be in harmony.
Just like some of those things in a
human body aren't in harmony,
right?
Your gut bacteria is off or you got a
cold because there's bacteria in your
body that you picked up from a fucking
bathroom somewhere.
Whatever you're saying,
all that stuff could easily apply to how
human beings interact with the earth.
Are we the virus though?
Like,
cause when you got to look at it at some
point the earth is,
or you or the theory is it's a living,
breathing organism.
Here's what I can say for sure.
Okay.
We are the virus to the ocean because we
don't even live in it and think about
it.
That's life.
Before we were monkeys,
we were something that crawled out of
the ocean.
Right,
right.
Imagine if the earth,
the ocean was,
I mean,
I don't know what it was like.
We are getting a hundred really stone.
This is what our fans were.
Stone is,
fuck,
I don't know what the ocean was like a
couple of hundred thousand years ago
before people really became what we are
tool to using.
You know,
people that figured out how to get out
into the ocean and capture fish.
But imagine if you could see it,
imagine if you could see an image of how
many fucking fish were out there 200,000
years ago versus how many are now.
It's like they lived next to a vampire
that just keeps sucking the life.
Avid.
I bet we've killed 50% of all life in
the ocean.
That's what I'm saying.
Felt like we have to think of ourselves
at some point.
You gotta say maybe the best thing human
beings could do for the earth is,
is to aid humanity.
Maybe.
But maybe viruses are there for a reason
to maybe that it all needs to exist.
There needs to be some sort of a
balance.
Where are we trying to eliminate bad
things.
Maybe they do serve some sort of weird
fucking purpose.
So even even in that we find purpose as
is,
that's the talent of humans.
The ability to adjust and make logic out
of us being here.
Yeah.
Well and to keep moving and make more of
us.
This China make it to the moon.
They grew cotton on the moon apparently
already.
Right.
How they grew something in the moon,
but it died.
Yeah,
it died quickly.
I was happy that it was that cotton
because seeing as how they're their
biggest investor in Africa and China was
growing cotton that didn't go well for
black people 500 years ago.
So I was just like,
please don't let cotton grown in the
moon.
I was like,
I don't want to transmit Atlantic slave
trade.
I have to learn Mandarin.
This shit.
So do you think they actually set up
shop before us or as American steel
number one cause they feels like,
I feel like we lost that day.
We went,
China landed on the moon.
Yeah.
I feel like,
oh shit.
You know,
I've grown up being,
you know,
like I'm black,
I'm American,
but I like I come here,
a lot of people I'm saying I like
America.
Like America.
Yeah,
exactly.
I feel like we're a bad like Frederick
Douglass when asked what he leave was I
answered,
you know,
like what the fuck am I going to leave
for when I see something like the moon
landing the China,
the growing the plants and landing
there,
there what,
what,
what was it?
Was it,
uh,
what,
what was the kind of ship that they
landed on the moon?
I'm not,
I put one on the moment.
Apparently landing on the dark side
though.
Right on the side that we didn't make it
to all or just went and told me that
video of it was a drone.
Right.
Is that what it was?
Some sort of a drone?
I think of that.
I honestly think about that as a win for
science and for innovation.
I don't think about it in terms of like
nations cause I feel like that is done
by scientists.
That's done by the wizards.
And so are you saying we're going to
steal the scientists because when
Kennedy gave the fucking speech,
Kennedy made it seem like the moon
landing was going to make us the
preeminent nation.
And I think that's the propaganda
China's going to run it.
You don't think,
well,
I think they have some fucking amazing
technology and to deny that would be
ridiculous.
But I also think that it's important
that everybody,
everybody be competitive in this.
Like if they,
if you really want to make things
better,
you're not gonna,
you're not gonna do that in a vacuum.
What helps the technological innovation
and one of the reasons why it's so
accelerated as there's so many people
working on it,
it's not just a few people trying to
make cell phones better.
I got fucking so many geniuses out
there,
so when I see something like this,
like they landed on the moon,
I go did geniuses.
One you just gave me hope.
Yeah,
they're Chinese people,
but they're just people.
We're all just people.
Absolutely.
You know,
and the idea that they're going to all
get those people on that side to think
the same way is what we're worried
about.
Right.
That we're,
it'd be US versus them and their
technology is going to impact our lives
the way we frame it as a country.
Yeah,
we always worry about that.
But you have to admit that that's what,
that's the way we frame it.
But if you look at the history of the
world that's been,
that happens so many times.
I think it makes sense to be worried
about the rest of the world.
I get it.
You know,
I'm on it and I'm on this side of the
fence so you know,
no problem with that.
But you know,
just,
you know,
I'm an American,
so that's what we want to know.
If,
if,
if red October is going to happen
tomorrow.
Fuck man,
I think Russians don't hate us.
I don't think anybody has a quarrel with
anybody over there.
It's the government.
That's what's the hustle is that the
real interaction is between a very small
amount of people that involves all,
these are the people that are with them.
For some strange reason,
I think they should just be thrown
essentially in a stadium to fight to
their death.
Gluten would be the king of the world.
Fuck everybody up.
Him and that other dude that runs the
other little country next door.
That was unreal.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That guy is a huge supporter of MMA.
Fucking bad ass was bad.
There's some bees over there.
You and how bad Putin would fuck up
trump.
Oh Christ.
You can't a fight to the death with
Putin.
I would actually probably bit pooed
versus Obama too.
Yeah,
for sure.
Look,
Obama is probably better than a debate.
Yeah.
Pooh who is a real,
exactly.
That's what I'm saying.
Like a lot of real real can we,
you'd have to go all the way.
Bush one I think was bad ass.
Maybe as a younger man that need you to
leave the CIA,
you gotta have some killer in.
Yes.
You know,
he was a tough guy,
but I probably have to get all the way
back to Kennedy in terms of physical
prowess and his back was bad.
I think you've got to go to Abraham
Lincoln when Lincoln.
Yeah,
he was wiring.
He wasn't that farmer bill farmer
strength.
He did wiring those old dudes back then.
We had to carry everything true.
They didn't,
you know,
farm work was real work just carried
everything everywhere.
All those dudes are just wiring as fuck.
He was a wrestler too.
Yeah.
Are,
yeah,
so he's,
he's,
he's beloved in my community.
We like them a lot.
No,
I get it.
Yeah.
He wrote this little thing called
emancipation proclamation.
Did you see that stupid fucking movie
where they had him as a vampire slayer?
Did you ever see that?
Nah,
I saw the trailer and decided maybe
that's not the one for me.
That was one of the ones you happier
kids don't ask you to go see.
Yeah.
Did Jamie,
didn't you say it was based on a graphic
novel?
Yeah.
So it was like a fun comic book that
somebody made and then they turned it
into a movie as a movie.
It was like so weird as a graphic and I
will probably work better.
Yeah.
There's some things that work that just
stay in their world.
Right?
Like there's some realize that movie
though.
Who said the question?
That's it.
There's a fun movie.
I mean it was dumb and fun,
but I'm just saying that's perfect.
I liked it.
Yeah,
but who gets it?
Who gets that movie?
Who?
Who what?
The pitch?
Yeah.
So Abraham Lincoln,
he can to kill vampires.
Vampires,
but an ax.
What?
Yeah.
They probably said another president
first and they said,
Ooh.
And then they say,
Hey Bradley,
what's up?
Tim Burton?
So,
oh,
I love that dude.
He's wacky though.
He doesn't get wacky stuff.
Yeah.
It was a beetle juice or something to
what was,
who else was tim burns.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Tim.
And he's so can we get a John Woo film?
So can we get another hard boiled or as
a killer could we get,
yeah.
When was the last man?
It's been a long time and it's American
movies,
although good.
We're nothing like,
well,
nothing like the foreign films.
Yeah.
Hyper violent stylistically beautiful.
Slow motion was use crazy.
Him or Tarantino.
I just love to drop a movie this year.
Yeah.
I think his style heavily influenced
John Wick.
I will.
Yes.
100% right.
Hey one bro.
Hell yeah.
Damn.
Sorry Kathy.
Get the pound.
Yeah.
I was wondering why the Fuck I love John
Wayne moved.
That's hyper violent.
Hyper violence.
Beautiful old school cars too.
When you're on the guns,
the magic of the slow moving Su and the
lead characters.
Kiano reads as bad ass man dresses
impeccably to go assassinate people.
Absolutely perfect.
Perfect attire hit me.
Come on,
man.
Drive around a 70 Chevelle ss as a male
mach one.
Come on,
come on.
True.
That's a,
that.
That movie is amazing.
That is really the second one I liked.
I love the first and I think I'm going
to let love the third.
I'm hoping.
Please.
I didn't see any cars though.
I saw the previews.
I didn't see cars.
I saw a motorcycle.
Just got to give him a car.
I always called him motorcycle.
Fuck.
He got to give him a car.
People don't understand.
Men want to go to see that car.
Motorcycles bring out the teenage boy.
So yeah,
that's true.
I remember ordering cycle.
We're on,
I even have a motorcycle and my mom's
like,
you're going to get a magazine issue.
Has a cycle world.
That's true.
Right muscle causing for old men.
Teenage boys want Ninja bikes.
Let me tell you something and I want to
share the secret with it where a lot of
people don't know is all white guys and
young black men has the same interest.
They both like young black women.
They both like muscle cars.
They both like slightly gaudy jewelry,
you know,
not working and money,
you know what I'm saying?
But muscle car to crowd.
If you go to Amica him auction,
you're going to see like you know young
black guys who,
oh I guys talking,
you know,
talking to one another.
This is one of the most beautiful sites
I've ever seen.
That's Larry.
Just after Mike and old guy,
I met at a meekum cow coming from and
become auction.
There's a bunch of those auctions,
right?
Like is Barrett Jackson Meek is unique.
It's a working man's Barrett Jackson.
Oh,
what's the difference?
You can actually afford the cars that
she said.
You know,
bear Jackson is beautiful cars,
but you know you're going,
you know I'm spending money and they got
cards you can get for,
but bear bear.
But with that said,
they say the inspection processes better
and Mika,
Mika,
Mr Guys,
a blue collar guy might've retired,
but he wants to go to the oxen.
He goes,
he gets a great car,
but he's probably going to know
something about cars and look it over
and sell.
Yeah,
man.
There's something about the comradery of
a fellow muscle car enthusiasts.
Yes.
You know when you could find a dude
who's also just as stupid as you about
to pour money in,
something that's never going to fully
make you Haffi as you want to be.
There's some guys that I'm friends with,
it's like this.
There's an extra bond because they're
just a stupid about cars.
Is I am man.
Shouts out to my man Ryan Ball.
Um,
you've given more.
Shouts out than anyone in here because
this is what you're supposed to do here.
He shouts out to Ron Paul and Mike Musto
muscle.
Yup.
Mike has my 96 impala,
which I got from Shauna.
Donald Topia shouts out to Shaun.
Got It from him,
got the 96 impala with under,
with under 1100 miles on it at the time.
Um,
ron did some slight adjustment.
He works over at Ford.
Yaddo does make the car even beautiful.
Just tweaked it,
Lord it a little bit,
did some cool stuff and mike featured
it,
so that's nice.
Yeah.
I have different people that are pockets
in my life that love you.
So as I'm shutting people out,
I appreciate you letting me do a bit,
you know,
I know they'll appreciate it.
You know what?
That's awesome.
Joe fucking Rogan.
Thank you.
Your killer fucking month.
It's a big deal.
I'm here.
Mike.
Mike Tyson was here.
I know.
He was all right.
Back to Mike.
My stuff shocking about how weird it was
to meet Mike Tyson.
It's so strange to hang out and talk to
them like party.
He was so iconic that whenever you're
around him park there's like 10% of you
that has to go holy shit.
It's Mike Tyson's,
no matter what else you're saying,
10% of your brain is going.
Holy Shit.
That's Mike Tyson.
When you showed the clip of the 51 year
old Mike Tyson and hitting the bag,
I remember it as a child.
He was the first person I see.
I have two dads,
I have a non bio on the Bio Dad and I,
he was the first person I had seen in my
life where I say this guy could probably
beat my dad.
You know,
like everybody else.
You Know My,
cause my dad's pretty tough guy,
had been a policeman,
was pretty good with his hands.
My bio day.
I mean my non biofire was a six foot
seven,
you know,
he played offensive tackle on same high
school teams,
Richard Dick.
So I got some pretty,
you know,
bad as dad's not there acting tough.
They just,
you feel protected as a child.
I remember just seeing Mike Tyson,
just slight,
whoa.
It's got,
could probably fucking kill everything
you say.
He hit with such vicious and evil
intent.
It was amazing.
He could still do it.
Yeah.
So when I saw him,
he was hitting the bag like he's still
terrifying.
Yeah.
If he was a young contender coming up,
you would look at him and go,
wow,
this guy can punch.
Yeah.
He doesn't have nearly the hand speed
that he had when he was young.
Look at that man.
Yeah,
that was the peak.
He is an amazing story though,
man.
Listening to him describe his childhood
and how custom motto had hypnotized him.
Yeah,
that was amazing because I'd never heard
him talk about that before and that's
what people need to understand.
Like who he was.
He people want to say,
oh he was,
he was hyper aggressive and he did
terrible things and he was violent in
this.
Think of how this kid grew up.
How's it forfeit?
Yes.
Literally or taken in by this one guy,
the first time in his life where
anything is positive and it's all about
fighting and being a destroyer.
And he gets hypnotized by this guy to be
a destroyer and he's a physical
specimen.
He really is.
You put your hand,
you grab his,
just his hand,
like his whole body's like carved out
above a large block of rock.
He's a tank of a man.
Wow.
You know,
still to this day he's a tank and when
he was young,
they saw that right away,
Teddy Alison on this podcast that when
Mike was 1,390 pounds and they didn't
believe he was 13 they thought we were
sandbagging.
They they,
they put them in at 16 he's like,
yeah,
okay,
say 16 nobody would believe he's 13 and
they would come on,
you're shutting these fucking kids.
They did want to believe it and he just
let him have it.
Okay,
okay.
You don't have to,
but because he said people were always
lying about how many fights people had,
they would always say,
he's only had 10 fights,
and you see the guy move immediately.
I'm like,
Oh my God,
this guy's at 50 fights watching him.
And Teddy was saying that that was
always the hustle,
that everybody always lied a little bit
about someone's record and when they saw
Mike Tyson at 13 wait 190 pounds just
fucking specimen.
There's some people that are just built
perfect for certain things.
He was built to be this perfect for
bobbing and weaving and tight and he was
so fucking fast.
His Hook and uppercut boldness,
I,
what's fighter has that upper cut like
the likes.
Louis had a tremendous upper cut,
eh?
Yeah,
there's,
there's some fighters today.
Joshua was a tremendous upper ha
uppercut.
Yeah,
there's some,
you know,
amazing talent today,
but it's like what Mike had done was
revitalize the entire country's image of
the heavyweight division because
characters and got mad at me for a while
and no disrespect,
but there was guys that just like pink
Olan Thomas who's a champion and Tony
tubs.
They weren't the kind of guy that you
like
look forward to seeing as being the
champion of the world.
You didn't believe it.
You're like,
I don't believe that's the toughest guy
in the world.
It might be a tough guy.
I'm sure he's a tough guy.
He's a professional boxer,
but I don't think that's the best guy.
And then Tyson came along very is
perfect name.
He had the perfect look.
He had the perfect body,
the perfect image,
and he came at the perfect time.
Yup.
Mike,
when you look at hip hop and where it
was and where Mike was at the time,
it was a perfect synergy for him to
become a hero.
Mike Tyson,
Mike Jordan,
like these people became icon.
It's at a time where the United States,
like in the 80s after getting opaque
kicking ass and the debt crisis fucking
up the 70s our ranch shit at the end of
the seventies early eighties I steal.
I remember my grandfather worked at hall
steel,
remember steal my other grandfather
steel leaving America.
I remember like it just kind of being
like it wasn't as proud and he was one
of those things that may you feel bad
ass and the Times feel dangerous and he
was black and those little boxes and you
didn't wear the boots.
He wasn't flashy.
Like he was a perfect villain at a time
where Villainy Nwa,
you know what I'm saying was was
celebrated danger.
I think he was perfect for the time and
I think he's perfectly now like what
Mike is when I hear him interview and I
really talk and people make fun of his
list,
but whatever.
And I think that gets in the way of you
hearing the real wisdom.
He's saying a lot of times,
like Mike is repeatedly talked about
change and about growth and about how he
doesn't see things the same.
And I think if we actually listened to
that,
it kind of challenged us to do the same
shit that we really don't want to do.
Yeah.
He's a,
one of the rare guys that you'll talk to
that accomplished an insane amount,
literally became one of the most famous
boxers in the history of the sport.
And you talk about him now and all he
wants to do is dismiss that past life.
He went to,
he like I was,
I was silly.
Look,
look at me.
I'm a silly person.
He's a real warrior.
Like he's,
he's,
he is like in a class that come
fulfilled.
He's the reluctant teacher almost.
You know,
he's,
you know,
you do,
you,
you know,
you do a,
you do a movie.
Mike is the guy who used a student go to
beg to teach you to fight and you want
one.
You want to know why he won't teach you
in.
It's because you find out later your
teacher killed someone,
you know,
in the ring or some shit like he is,
he is really that character.
He is a,
he's,
you can tell even with the pigeons back
in the days that there's kindness and
love in there somewhere and now he gets
to express it to human beings.
You just see he's a happier person.
You know what I mean?
Until you bring up don king's name.
Yeah.
Don't do that.
And then,
then you get scared.
Like he's going to fucking beat me up.
And my dad too.
He,
the crazy thing about him selling weed
now is that he,
they chart,
what did they charge him?
$300,000 I think for he tested positive
for the Andrew Gelada fight for weed.
So they find him $300,000 they just
stole money from him cause he had weed
in the system.
Wow.
Now he sells weed.
Ain't going to nfl guys.
So should let everybody smoke
it.
It's good for your brain if you're,
if you're,
especially if you're doing something
like slamming into each other,
running 30 miles an hour.
Yeah.
It's probably good to give them
something to calm them down or release
some of the inflammation.
The,
I mean,
grown adults telling you you can or
can't do it.
It's just what's ridiculous about it.
The end of the day,
a grown adult telling you they can't.
The ones who say you shouldn't smoke
weed.
They don't do it.
They don't know what they're talking.
Haven't ever done it.
The ones who do or don't,
or the ones who have and like,
I don't do it anymore.
I don't like to get high anymore.
Those guys,
you're like,
oh,
okay.
I get it.
Used to you don't like to do it.
Fucks with your productivity,
whatever.
I get it,
but if you never done it and you're
talking shit about it,
you don't even know the benefits.
You really just want to be like,
shut up.
There's benefits to it.
There's definitely some people get
fucked up by everything,
whether it's weed or alcohol or speed.
People get fucked up.
Some people just fucked up.
I been a drill,
yes,
but I can,
I can honestly tell you that I read an
article in huff or something years ago
that talked about parents who smoked and
stoners actually being more engaged with
their children.
So that doesn't mean you get up and you
get fried the first thing in the
morning,
you take your kid to school,
but it does mean that were drinkers or
smokers would come home and almost avoid
the child to smoke or drink or do
something else or had other things going
on.
Stoner with literally pop up may take a
hit or two of the joint and the focus
would be more on just being the child
parenting,
kind of kicking it,
cooling it.
Yeah.
You're way more curious when you're
high.
So if you're just a little bit high and
you're around kids,
you're,
you would be thinking more the way
they're thinking or trying to be a
little calmer with them and a little bit
more,
a little bit more patient.
It makes you more relaxed person.
Absolutely.
Because the anxiety is given to you.
She asked out the shower writing to God
was shook one that's talked about and he
talked very openly about anxiety in
that.
And he's wanting,
yeah,
these are the people I like to see you
bring up too is a great,
I got that on tape too.
I got that one in audio.
It's not as it was listened to it.
I was running.
Yeah.
Like man there who cause he,
he reads it.
Yeah.
We don't acknowledge that.
Like in the African American community
kidney disease,
it's something that plays and not just
diet carrying around stress and all that
anxiety is bad for your kidneys.
They,
that's where you're fearing stressed
beats up the most.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
it's very important for all of us to be
honest about how we feel.
It doesn't make you weak.
It just makes,
it makes you brave enough to be able to
express honestly what everybody is
probably feeling.
But it scared to bring up cause they
don't want to be thought of as weak.
Yeah.
They don't want to be a whiny bitch.
So I didn't want to tell you what's
going on that's wrong.
But especially something like anxiety,
man did the,
the delicate balance of chemicals that
exist in the human mind and how much it
can be affected by stress and
relationships and life in general and
your diet and all these other factors
and then there's genetic issues and
some,
some people just have problems.
Yeah,
a wound tight and you can get help if
you can get help.
I'll get help through cognitive therapy.
You can get help through medication.
There's a lot of people that believe
that ecstasy should help people,
that they should be able to do MTMA
therapy for a lot people with stress.
It's a lot of talk of that now and now.
That thing,
your body,
you making the decision on what to put
in it.
Yes.
It's more in line with right than wrong.
Well especially if there's science
behind it.
Yeah,
like if they,
if they allowed it to be legal,
then you would,
you would allow it to be regulated,
which means you would allow it to be
like you would know exactly how many
milligrams of this is in this and how
much you should take.
If you weigh 112 pounds versus you weigh
212 pounds,
that all those things should be taken in
consideration by science.
And if we had that,
if we just had freedom,
I can see that.
Yeah.
I think they're hub,
they're having a lot of studies are a
lot of success rather with um,
veterans and treating veterans with MDA
and maps,
you know,
maps the psychedelic organization,
no heard of them.
They're an organization that is working
to try to um,
make psychedelics legal.
And uh,
one of the things that are pushing
initially is this mtma study that
they've done with veterans and they're
showing a significant benefit and
reduction of PTSD and stress from
veterans to come home.
And they've seen a lot of shit over
there and they're just,
you know,
fucked up from it.
And it seems to be one of the best
things I've ever found and discovered
for alleviating.
The other thing that they've used it on
is a,
I think John Hopkins had one they did
with Siliciden,
same sort of result,
give people psychedelics under
controlled situations and they have a
big alleviation of stress from the past.
They can let things go.
I got introduced to mushrooms.
Oh Wow.
Okay.
As Dj.
So if,
and that was a beautiful experience.
I introduced my wife to him because of
that,
so I can,
I can definitely see that.
Yeah.
There's something to them.
Yeah,
for sure.
There is me and l do me and l enjoy
mushrooms while we make music?
Do you really?
Yeah.
Mushrooms.
We and whiskeys.
He and drink whiskey,
drink some Tequila or what do you call
the others?
Tequila and mezcal is it?
Yeah.
He,
he drinks a mass cal.
I drink whiskey and shrooms in a week,
but usually we had drunk ants in here
from yesterday.
Apparently Richard Rawlings brought this
cinnamon Tequila and some of it had
spilled on the table and the answered
found it pop up everywhere,
brushing them along.
They were everywhere.
They were drunk,
they were just drinking Tequila and it
was just all giant line of,
I'm like,
they found the fucking bar in the middle
of space and got added.
Yeah,
they found it and when we got here it
was covered with ants,
shrunk aunts.
My wife made me hang out at a bar all
night last night with her and her
friend.
They got shit faced drunk,
threw up in an uber.
Nice.
Run it through the hallway in our
underwear back at the hotel.
That sounds like good night.
Throwing up an uber,
like how many times does that happen to
those poor bastards?
I forever,
I tipped the God damn near $100 I was
like,
when,
oh sorry.
Row.
You know how much puke a large amount,
not ge,
but enough to be aggravated because she
had a bag.
So you know,
you'd think that the bad catches,
but it wasn't plastic.
You know,
I thought it it,
it,
it gave a little leak.
It's hard to get that smell out,
that smell.
It's caused about 150 bucks to get it
together.
Piecemeal out.
Really that shit is in your body.
Like imagine if you turn yourself inside
out.
Probably Smell
pubes first far to the morning.
But puke smelled is something in the
need.
That's why I don't like Yoga.
Hot Yoga,
rather regular yoga I can endure.
Why don't you like it?
Because Yogurt,
no fart.
Like Yo man moms her farting,
you know,
straight up you go to hot yoga,
hot yoga.
You ever had a hot chick convince you to
do that shit.
It's like my wife's side,
so she could talk me in the most dumb
shit.
Right.
So all,
yeah,
we're going to fucking hot yoga.
Yeah.
Hi.
Mavs tits acids.
Yo,
this shit you gotta block for me to say.
And then it's like,
Ooh,
pitch to too far.
Yeah.
Like I know my wife are,
that's not my wife Fart.
And then you say fuck it.
You start farting.
Oh No.
Yeah.
Like then,
and you know that shit.
Yeah.
So I don't,
I don't fuck with hot yoga.
I,
I'd rather just do regular yoga and then
just sign of that shit out.
Like you,
yeah.
Um,
I like how yoga
and tell the truth.
I don't,
I do it fasted.
Okay.
But first thing in the morning,
respect.
No one farts though.
Oh,
people far for sure.
April fart if you go to the early
classes.
Okay.
All right.
So the pros.
Yeah.
All right.
This is a couple different places that I
go to,
but I let go into the early classes.
Do your side of the same day you hot
yoga?
Sometimes.
Most of the time,
no.
no double door.
I have,
if I have an injury,
if I have something that's fucking with
me,
but uh,
if I do that,
I almost consider it like a sauna
because you get so God damn hot.
Like the room might only be 104 degrees,
but when you're working out hard doing
yoga,
your body is poor and sweat.
You must be heated up as warm as you get
in a sauna.
It feels the same way to me.
Gotcha.
It feels like almost like I'm trying to
work out in the sauna.
Gotcha.
This doing some study now at Harvard
about it,
about a heat shock proteins and hot
yoga,
and you know how much inflammation it
reduces and how beneficial is to you.
I forget what scientists were involved
in it,
but a bunch of people were talking about
it the other day.
I know it definitely gets gas at your
ass.
It definitely does so well.
If you have something that you shouldn't
beat and like eat a hot dog with
sauerkraut and a coke and then two hours
later tried to go to yoga class,
you're a criminal,
you're a terrible person.
Fucking Mofo.
And there's nowhere for that far to go
either.
It's stuck in the hot day.
Yeah,
that's the thing.
It stays there that you get the real
earthy chicks,
they burn sage and then that starts to
suffocate you and you gotta leave the
real earthy chicks.
Yeah.
Do you know sage?
Someone told me this check and see if
this is right.
I think we might've talked about this
before.
A Salvia is sage.
Salvia divinorum someone said is like
the same shit as sage.
Really?
Yeah.
Psychedelic Shay and says she uses sage
burning first.
I couldn't really,
didn't really like the way it smelled.
And now it's almost addictive.
Like it's a beautiful smell.
It's a weird smell.
It is weird.
Someone said it's like related to to
Salvia divinorum like there's so close
he related,
they think that that might've been why
they call it sage stoned off stage.
You get a little buzz or something and
they're saying [inaudible] smell.
I've never really,
I've never caught a sage buzz.
Yeah,
I mean,
but it does calm you.
He's like,
if I,
like if I walk in the room and I smell
it now,
I instantly feel just like,
yeah,
the sages,
the common stages.
Official name is Salvia office and
novelists or something.
So it's a cousin.
The salvia divinorum sort of like genius
believe is solid.
We never know if I could say Janice or
Jenice.
I was panic on that one.
I believe it's Chino.
Uh,
so that's uh,
I wonder if that's where the name sage
came from.
Cause the sage is a wide per a wise
person.
It came from the use of some trippy
plants.
Could be.
It might be or might just have some
other strange,
what did you find out?
Like what's the origin of the,
the,
the word sage.
Oh,
it's in the mint family.
So that makes sense.
Why is it called sage?
Sage was once considered a medicinal
cure.
All sage is an herb that has a sweet yet
savory flavor.
Sage botanical.
He known as Salvia efficient.
Novelis is native to the Mediterranean
regions.
Sage.
Sage is botanical name comes from the
Latin word salver,
which means to be saved.
Ah,
interesting.
So why do they call it sage then?
So someone calls it Salvia and Salvia,
whatever the fuck it is.
And then we call it sage.
Why do we change the name?
It still doesn't,
doesn't say why we changed the name.
Right.
The botanical name makes sense.
It comes from the word salver,
meaning to be saved.
That makes sense.
But why sage?
You mean like we like an English?
Yeah.
Why don't we say shop at it from however
they were using it back in the
Mediterranean region.
Whatever word they use is probably very
close.
But they always like treat you like
you're stupid.
Like you have to have a botanical name.
Like bitch,
just tell me the name.
What's the name?
Why does it have two names?
What is it?
Is it sage or is it foster?
Mitis eyelid ptosis.
Hominin he sage.
Definitely easy to say.
It's crazy ass names.
You guys want to give them at least
scientists.
They're all like,
look up,
we'll,
we'll tell you.
Let me look.
Let you make your own little name for
it.
There you go.
What do you want?
Little people,
people that don't understand science it,
let's just call it sage.
That's right.
Sage.
You can't pronounce that.
Salvage Salvia.
Norum cat do it.
Have you ever experienced that stuff?
Salvia?
No.
That's what that was one of the ones
that slipped through the 1970s,
uh,
psychedelic Dac data sweeping act that
made a bunch of things illegal,
including apparently some of the things
they made illegal aren't even
psychoactive.
They just to make everything illegal,
but they missed Salvia.
So it used to be able to buy it.
You see have to go to a gas station and
buy Salvia and trip your fucking balls
or what's,
what's the Salvia trip line?
It's,
I only did it once and it was really
weird.
It was like,
I don't think I did enough because Ari
Shaffir had a entire life he lived for
three months in one Salvia trip that
took 10 minutes.
We talked to him about is the craziest
fucking story.
He had relationships and breakups and
jobs and,
and he lived a different life and then
woke up on the couch in 10 minutes
underwater.
Yeah,
he lived underwater,
right?
Yeah.
Dude.
Just wrapping balls on this stuff that
you could buy from the gas station.
Ssi.
It was Chrism.
I try,
I try to stay in very dense and to
cause,
so there are times where I a very
dissident in the mushrooms kind of take
me on the trip.
He ride.
Yeah.
But I,
I don't,
I don't know how far I want to go.
That's a scary,
there's already right there.
That's him tripping.
They got it all on video.
Oh Shit.
Him and this is some stuff that you,
I don't know if it's legal anymore.
I think they've made it illegal,
but you used to be able to buy it
virtually anywhere.
Head shops,
they all,
they all carried it and it's so much
more potent than weed but yet legal and
has a long history of people using it to
char repin.
So when I did it,
I didn't get any of that,
but I did get a third.
I wouldn't want you to be that trip and
you're a strong guy.
You know your,
your,
your stocks.
Yeah.
You don't want it.
You don't want to have to be the homie
to save the homie from itself and the
homies to physically fit.
It's like fun.
Right.
You have Hershel Walker's tripping bad
mom partial than the other room.
Kit has all names,
you know what I mean?
You call the police [inaudible] who was
kicking his old ass,
save us,
you know,
send Ronnie Coleman.
You would literally have to have cost
asides or Ronnie Coleman and they still
can fucked.
They would still be fuck.
You'd be fucked.
Yeah.
I saw myself from like outside my body,
like it,
like it would pulsate in my body and
outside of my body,
in my body and outside my body from like
over here looking down at myself.
Very.
My mom,
when she had me,
she died on the table for a few seconds.
Jesus and she said she saw herself.
I wonder what that is cause that's the
same thing that everybody says.
I mean regardless of your religious
beliefs,
to stop for a second and try to figure
out why so many people see themselves
from above their body see themselves
outside their body.
Like what is that?
Well,
we know one.
I mean,
I mean all,
all people and even science kind of
agree at this point through the body is
just a vehicle of sorts.
So machine of sorts that whatever energy
or solve the spirit,
what are people trying to identify this?
It's within it,
but it's,
it does disconnect out.
Imagine,
I'm hoping that they figured out how to
put myself in a computer before I die.
I'd like to live a couple hundred more
years.
Fuck off.
So what if it sucks though?
Yeah.
What if I like to try to be alive?
Dude,
if you're,
if you're in a computer,
you can't die.
No,
I'm saying if you're 89 and you're about
to get the fuck outta here,
you got the opportunity to upload right
into 29 again for the next 29 years.
Like Yo,
fuck that.
I might try that before I decided to
click on out of there.
You know,
I think they're going to be able to
reverse aging and I think they're going
to be able to do that before they're
going to figure out a way to get you
into a machine.
We'll see.
I think the real problem,
it'd be a guy like trump putting himself
in like a million machines.
Just not one.
Not One.
Like someone who has like a Ted Turner
Bankroll says I like about a million
texts in this town.
Starts Breeding Ted's.
Yeah,
but the butthead robot,
but trump ain't got ted money now.
He might not have it,
but he's got money for a few robots.
Yeah,
yeah,
no.
And those monies,
those robots to go out and make more
money.
Are Robots going to destroy us?
That's a very good question and that's
something that Elon Musk is actually
scared of.
Really?
Yeah.
He's a little deval says it's going to
happen.
He's a very intelligent guy to just,
besides making a good record,
he talks about us essentially replacing
each other with robots soon.
It's entirely possible.
The Way Ilan Musk looks at it is that
he's,
he was trying to warn people,
but they weren't listening and that
there's no telling how powerful they
could get once they become sentient,
once they start taking control of their
own destiny and creating new robots and,
and just deciding whether or not we live
or die and how they're going to run
things,
they're essentially,
they're going to become a life form and
artificial life form that's way fucking
smarter than us.
Yeah,
and he's saying,
do you think it's smart to arm these
things?
They've seen,
it's smart to make this,
like he's looking at it in terms of he's
the tip of the spear.
Right.
And it comes to technology and an
implementation of it.
I mean,
think about who this guy is,
right?
If he's the one who's telling you
everybody's kind of slow the fuck down.
This is dangerous.
Like you literally might be making a
terminator movie here.
Yeah.
He's literally might be making a
terminator movie.
Yeah,
we have to worry because we,
when were you were saying that you think
we evolved from monkeys?
We evolve from some lower thing.
Well,
the idea is that we got to keep going.
if we might hit a biological bottleneck,
and that might be the whole convergence
of humans and technology,
that might be what it's all about.
Like biologically this system doesn't
move fast enough,
but if we can transcend this and move
into some sort of a digital life,
that life,
we can accelerate all of the innovation,
all of the improvements in insane
numbers like years traveled through
time,
change the fucking,
the nature of life itself.
That's going to probably be one of the
stages of our future.
Whether it's a thousand years from now
or a hundred thousand years from now.
It seems to me like with this adoption
of science and into our daily lives in
terms of like the technologies that
we're all addicted to,
phones and tablets and all these
different things going to say.
He says that we're a Cyborg is already
your extension.
Niesr this is just a rudimentary way.
Yeah,
he's ready for sure.
Right.
You already living people already living
through this.
Yeah,
yeah.
Yeah and he's also coming out with
something called neuro link.
I don't exactly know what it was.
He was very vague about it,
but he was saying he was going to change
the bandwidth to change your,
your like your ability to access
information and people are going to wear
it.
You know where this thing on your head,
it's going to literally charge up your
fucking brain.
Some strange,
strange days because he couldn't,
he couldn't explain too much about it,
but he was saying it was going to come
out in a few months.
I'm like,
what?
No fuck man.
Were we were,
you know,
30 or 40 years away from being
unrecognizable.
That's what I think.
I think we're 30 or 40 years away from
being a living in la at the time,
living in a virtual world,
half the time,
live in an augmented world.
I think people are going to exist in
these weird worlds where it feels real
and isn't.
I think they're going to come out with
programs that are fun at first,
but then become life consuming where you
put on these fucking goggles and this
suit and you go into this world and you
live with these people in it and
interact.
We touch each other,
but no one's there physically,
but you feel like you are and it's
magical.
You're like you're living in Avatar,
you're on Pandora.
You're hanging out with the blue people.
Gotcha.
Yeah.
You with the Navi,
that shit could happen.
You could literally get to a point where
you believe you were there or we could
be there now.
We could be there.
Yeah.
That's a sneaky,
sneaky argument.
Right,
but that that's,
that's the truth of it all.
It is a truth.
Right?
It could be there.
We could be there.
We could be a part of a simulation.
Yeah.
That's another thing that you learned.
Most sad.
I'm like,
God damn it.
You're supposed to say no.
It's impossible.
It could all be fake.
Deja.
Volcker peaches.
A glitch.
Yeah,
sure.
So I just try to live like my grandpa's
age.
She has enjoyed a regular shit as much
as you can.
You know?
Maybe I won't upload,
maybe I just don't want to go earlier
than the fun stops.
But I think that there's a beauty in,
now that I'm getting older,
I guess I see a beauty in and in the
life death cycle.
I don't want to die now.
I don't want to die tomorrow.
You know what?
I guess what I'm telling myself.
I'm fucking treadmill,
God dammit.
But my grandparents were always adamant
about not going an old folks home.
And I used to think it was about they
didn't want to be treated bad and he
thought we forget about themselves and
they never want it to stop living.
So my grandmother died in my arms
walking up a hill to my granddaughter,
took him to her great grand daughters.
My daughters are pre k graduation and my
grandfather died fishing,
which was his greatest love and next to
my grandmother.
You know what I mean?
And they realized that their life never
stops if they literally died living.
So I guess that's,
that's,
that's maybe ultimately what the real
thing you should think about is whether
we're in the machine and outside of it,
you know,
live the best possible life.
You shouldn't be trying to escape your
life with goggles or even the phone.
You know,
this shit has to be lived.
I agree.
Unless this is the goggles.
Yeah.
Putting goggles on inside the goggles,
like mirrors looking at mirrors.
Could be,
and then we figured out who we really
are.
It could be,
could be,
that would be the ultimate mind.
Fuck.
If you put on the goggles one day and
you realized you gotta get Outta here,
man.
No I do not.
I'm just,
you made me think of something.
I'm just stoned and I forgot,
I forgot the fucking name of the
exhibit.
There's an exhibit at the High Museum.
I'm on the board of the High Museum.
Right.
And there's an exhibit there about
artists and it involves debt.
It is the Infinity Mirror.
His ticket.
So is um,
Yay your way.
You Sama,
it's up.
You got it.
Yeah.
So when you weigh Kusama yeah,
yeah.
I'm not,
I'm not good at,
I'm not good at that one.
But in Fidelis,
I'm taking my daughter,
I'm taking Mikey Mikey's in an 11 year
old.
Exactly.
And I'm going to,
I'm going to,
I'm going to probably hit a joint a
couple times uber down and I'm going to
walk through this museum that she
usually doesn't like going with me
because people kind of,
sometimes he'll recognize me and it
bothers her if she's really trying to
hang out with dad,
you know what I mean?
But I'm going to get a chance to walk
through there with just me and her kick
his Solo Dolo and just experience that
with her.
Just that you see the goggles and Gospel
and mirrors on mirrors.
So I'm looking forward to having like a
Glen Stope.
That looks amazing.
Yeah.
Fuck,
that's incredible.
I'm on the board.
I mean,
I got asked,
I'm a rapper.
When was this museum?
This is the high museum in Atlanta.
We have one of the most premium
beautiful modernist museums in the
country.
We hit,
it's greatly supported.
I'm on the board,
our,
the greater communities.
How do you have the time to do all this
shit?
You're making me feel lazy.
How do you,
it's time to do all this man.
I just,
I stopped doing as much dumb shit.
Just decided to be a responsible husband
and dad and go to strip club couple of
times a week.
Sell every day.
He was sleepy.
Shouts out to sleep.
You,
I miss you bro.
But they asked me for high mood for Hamu
um,
doctors Rahamo Pico and I know what I'm
saying.
His last name wrong is an artist who my
wife owns his piece.
He did the rap music cover and my wife
has a piece on loan to the Carlos Museum
at emory university.
Um,
he's one of,
he's just,
he's going to be a basket like artists
in terms of how he's talked about and
more.
He's an amazing human being.
An artist.
We're lucky enough to own some of his
works.
He's on the board.
And he suggested that me and a guy named
king and he worked over at interscope be
um,
Pete Pete brought to,
and they met us and they accept us in
it.
And I'm like,
you gotta understand I grew up about
four or five miles from this place.
And for most kids this place was an
impossibility to go to because their
imagination wouldn't let them do it.
Right.
So you were in the,
there's a lot of times you have very
poor or working class areas that are
right next to things that are inspiring,
but kids are not brave enough to break
to filter and go because they're never
encouraged to Ted Turner and the high
museum and things like that have always
made it very accessible.
So when Ted Turner on the praise and the
hawks,
if you've got b's and a's,
you got tickets to the game,
right?
So you could see baseball party reason
baseball died in inner cities.
This cause the stadium's moved out and
you couldn't see it.
Right.
The high museum and the Woodridge found
that woodruff foundation,
which is a coke charity,
gave me and two other kids a scholarship
to go train on Saturdays to draw and
paint,
stuff like that.
So this museum has been in my life since
I was a kid.
So being asked to get on the board was
just a huge honor.
And especially having an 11 year old now
that probably is going to want to be an
artist,
man,
it makes me the coolest dad in her life.
So yeah.
Plus like what a thing on the resume.
Yeah.
You just look so sophisticated.
I know,
right.
I get to go buy a jacket and slippers.
One of them jackets with the leather
patches on the elbows.
Thank one of those scholarly gentleman.
Perhaps even have a pipe and some
tobacco.
Yeah,
I got class man.
man.
For sure.
That's cool.
That's cool that you're involved in all
those different things.
Yeah,
it's very inspiring.
You know,
you're doing a lot of shit.
You obviously have a mind for it,
you know,
it's like,
have you always been entrepreneurial
like that?
Have you always been?
I never,
I just didn't want to be poor.
I just put the world treats poor people
bad.
But I didn't grow up poor.
I grew up working class.
So you're taught to work,
that's what you do.
Yeah.
And I didn't like working.
I knew I was,
I knew I was lazy by nature,
so he got to figure out.
But it's cool that you applied that as
well as you still artistic.
You know,
you're still very creative.
You know your wraps or get your fucking
flow is great.
Thank you.
Your wraps are great.
Eh,
I got,
I um,
if I was a fighter,
I probably your multistyle fighter.
I have,
I have the ability to get on the tracks
and wrap next to Tia and big boy,
you know,
next to bumpy and you know,
project pat and next to lp and be
something totally different.
Every track.
I've been blessed with some talent,
you know what I mean?
And um,
I'm glad that I got with Elle because
Elle is,
l is like the Freddie Roach of producing
and rapping.
Right?
He's a great fight coach for me.
When I first heard his beats,
I was just like,
no one in the world,
last federal is be sent me.
Um,
I'm supposed to be rapping over his
beats.
So he was only supposed to do three
beats on my first album on rap music.
But I went into a fucking campaign to
make him do the album.
So I started calling him like,
this is how we became friends.
Like Yo,
so you know what man?
The records of toe,
we got to finish them up.
Yeah.
Like yeah man,
I'm working on my album.
Yeah man,
I'm stoked when we,
I remember I got to get your song for
that.
Yeah,
you gotta make sure,
but so what sub domain you need to do
the whole album,
bro.
I don't have time.
I can't do it.
I called back a couple of days.
So you thought about it,
thought about what we talked about.
We've talked about,
about you doing my whole album,
you know,
I told you know now you didn't mean that
Bro.
We eat
until he finally just to calm the copy
property called and say here's some more
money.
He was just like,
Yo bucket and we became friends and man,
I truly believe that like,
you know,
he is,
he's my gusto model in terms of being
able to put me in focus and training
like Freddie Roach,
how you see Freddie Roach bring things
out of fighters that you know are in
them but no one knows how to bring out
and l does l does that.
So the discipline,
you know,
I,
I've,
I've written,
gotten with him,
it's a great,
that's the great thing about partnering,
you know,
your weaknesses or Canada,
you can identify and fix them,
you know,
because you have someone training there
which are right there.
Right.
You feel inspired by your partner.
Absolutely.
And I love him for it.
Yeah.
When two people really enjoy each
other's company and benefit from each
other's presence and get inspired by
each other,
the to become bigger than just one bus.
One.
Absolutely.
That's why,
you know,
I make sure when I,
when I'm introduced,
you know,
out of a sudden you have shell Rawlins,
people know him,
Michael Render Kilo Mike.
But I want a place,
I always say,
you know,
first and foremost on Michael Render,
cause this is my mom named me killer.
Mike's a character that I love.
I enjoy playing.
You know,
and I'm,
I'm Shay's husband,
want half a run the jewels.
These things are more than just who I
am.
They make significant,
you know,
change in my life if I,
if I live up to the honor in those
titles and you know,
I'm a better person.
So Ales,
my relationship is a very important one.
Second may be only to my wife.
Yeah.
And your way of discussing this too.
It's a sincere,
a fun guy and you're,
you're an inspirational guy in terms of
your work ethic and all the things that
you've achieved.
When you say things like that and you
talk about your word and you talk about
who you are,
that's very powerful to young people
coming up.
Cause they'll hear that.
They'll hear how smart you are and how
well read you are and how much you
understand about the business and in
life in general.
And then they hear how your thought
process works and it'll help them mature
their own thought process.
Gravitate towards positive things.
It's very beneficial.
Thank you,
man.
I been,
I mean,
I learned a lot listening to you check,
checking out the guests you bring on.
Just pick it up from Arizona.
I just believe in picking up whatever
you can tell.
That's all I'm doing,
man.
I'm just picking up with,
uh,
an antenna that spreads it out.
Yeah.
Do a hell of a job.
Thank you.
Can you go ahead?
Weird Gig.
Yeah,
I know.
But you do like your,
your main job is making people laugh and
you're fucking side hustle was making,
keep making people think that's,
that's an amazing side hustle,
bro.
It's overwhelming though sometimes.
So sometimes I do so many of them and I
do some of them on subjects where I'm
not even well read.
I don't,
I don't exactly know if this guest is
being honest or if they're,
you know,
but you're learning,
right?
Yeah.
But that's how you feel too.
That's how you,
that's how you counter,
you fall into shit.
You don't,
you don't like,
you don't,
you don't wake up and know.
Yeah,
you wicked wake up curious and you can
search and you're honest.
You have an honest and integrity with
your audience where you say,
I was wrong about this or I've learned
to pick up more of this.
I think that's what it's really about.
You know what I mean?
I don't think it's about being right or
knowing all the time.
You,
you,
your forum is very dope because it's
conversational and not contrived it,
it really is me having the ability to
ask.
We were talking,
you know,
Google research have these notes.
I don't know if you know,
well,
of course you don't take correctly.
Sure.
An amazing comic when an amazing reason
why we know about the Zapruder film.
It's exactly,
yeah.
Dick Gregory brought it to Geraldo
Rivera.
I knew this man his last three years of
life.
Um,
first of all,
first meeting him,
he cursed me and Tia out is though we'd
stolen the tires off his car.
Right.
Why would he say,
well me and t I just kinda got on like
too Hokey wrappers that kind of saw
them.
You know,
it,
it's,
you know,
we're,
we've embraced the fact that our
community looks at us as leaders,
right?
We're not trying to be doctor Caner
Macklin,
but we're businessmen were rappers.
We have accountability and
responsibility
in our community.
So we accept some of what comes with
that and we're willing to do things.
So in considering protesting,
considering,
you know,
talking to politicians on the behalf,
tweet it,
you have to consult with elders.
So we get on the phone with them like,
you know,
so what,
what do we do?
Like kids are getting shot.
How,
what should we be engaged and should we
wait?
Should we mark it?
March,
nick,
Nigga,
what the fuck you go mom.
It's fun.
They don't think it'll be march 50 years
ago.
You know,
they don't open a street up.
Let you mark tell you clothe itself and
then shoot your ass if you,
you
just like,
oh shit.
Like I never actually,
I never thought of that.
And this is more serious than we're
showing up and were angry.
This is confronting government.
And once government has shane,
you do something a few times you have to
practice guerrilla warfare or you're
just doing what the British did that
lost him.
America,
you're stepping up in a formation,
shooting your shot,
falling back,
stepping up for it.
You're just playing a fucking game where
they're dancing first is doing things
that really disrupted system and things
that really progress the move.
And I was like,
Oh shit,
you know,
this is radically,
this guys is more than just a funny man
and he's more just think he's really
sacrificing lady that shit down.
So yeah,
we got cursed out by Dick Gregory tip
hung up.
Why you didn't call me back later life
man,
you know like,
hey my phone messed up,
dog tilt talk.
Cool.
It's my phone hung up dog.
I don't know how to say Nigga,
you Haga he say,
well what'd he say?
Oh,
you know,
and then,
but,
but around that,
you know,
tip and I have have been able to be a
better benefit to our community,
you know?
And then when I say our community,
I don't mean some imaginary mythical
rapper place.
I mean the five,
10 mile radius we grew up in,
you know,
we've made some some,
some change.
You know what I mean?
And for the better,
we're going to bring some jobs and shit
like that and I think that that's cool.
You know what I mean?
That's very cool.
It sounds cool too.
It sounds like your,
your you,
you think in a very positive,
in a progressive way of of helping
community in a real sense.
Yeah.
That's nice to hear man.
I hope,
I hope I helped some people for I get
outta here.
I also young people say,
you know,
and your music is fun as fuck.
Straight up.
Kick you in your Dick Punching your face
music.
It's fun man.
It's really good shit.
Like you,
I got a great job.
You know what I mean?
The secondary job of doing the TV show,
you just go,
but I got a great job.
You're a great stand up man.
Thank you.
I mean in the line of like Carlin and
Hicks,
like you really push buttons and make,
make mother fuckers twitch like Oh shit
and think and go home.
That's,
that's rare.
It's easy to do,
you know,
Kinda Shucky Shit.
But you,
I like your shit.
Thanks for,
I appreciate you like my music.
Thanks man.
Yeah,
I love your music.
no,
I appreciate it.
It's a,
I think we both are in tricky
businesses.
Yeah.
I get a lot out of music,
man.
I get a lot of fun and energy out of
listening to music.
I don't have any musical talent at all,
but when I hear good music,
I get excited,
man.
It fires me up.
Like,
I mean it's,
I,
it's one of the most important
things in our culture in terms of like
our ability to generate energy and
motivation.
It's a vibration.
Yeah,
it really is.
I W with me,
man,
I think you guys are,
I think right now stand up comedy is the
last vestige of freedom of speech in
this country and you guys are to be
protected at all costs.
And I think if people don't protect your
law,
costs is going to be at,
at the,
um,
for the,
for the worst of us all.
I definitely think there's something to
that,
that there's very few people that are as
free with what they're allowed to say.
Uh,
like standup comedians.
He goes,
we're saying this crazy shit under the
guise of it being funny.
Yeah.
So you can get away with saying a lot of
things that won't be criticized as long
as people laugh at them and you have a
good point.
If you're just making the points without
the joke,
people wouldn't,
they wouldn't,
they don't want to hear it.
They get mad at you.
But something about delivering a point
with a joke.
That's why trigger warning works.
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
It's one of the last ways you can
deliver a message that maybe people
don't agree with,
but if you can make them laugh at some
shit they don't even really agree with
and the laughing hard,
they'll see a little bit of your point.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
When you,
uh,
set out to do trigger warning,
what did,
what was the,
what was the initial premise and how
much of it did it change until,
what,
once you got to production and what you
started filming you,
one of the only people who have asked
that question.
You can,
you can do business bro.
Straight up bro.
Oh,
you know,
yeah.
Brown originally we shot it with fx and
we over we over did it.
It looked really good,
but it looked really TV.
Uh,
and um,
it could have been dealt,
but it would have been a parity of a
very real thing I was attempting to do.
And right now I'm talking about crypto.
Nicola,
what it turned out,
uh,
turned into at Netflix was a real
mmm.
In your face.
Simple and plainly shot
documentation of the possibilities of
barbershop arguments,
right?
So in a barbershop argument,
you get to say,
you know,
the only thing that separates Alka palm
from Joe Kennedy is Al Capone got caught
and eventually died in prison and Joe
Kennedy went on to produce precedence,
but they both had been bootleg.
Or you know,
people say Shit like there's barbershop
talk and you need,
you got to go home and be asking
yourself like,
well well damn,
if Papa Joe did it was a bootlegger.
Like technically it could have went
fucked up for him and we never would
have had an American dynasty versus owl
catch Sibley's in shit and it not going
so well.
But him being the preeminent marketing
campaign in face of any compound,
like then you want to sell cigars to a
restaurant,
right?
So it got it.
I got a chance to say,
you know,
Shit,
what if I could do this for my guys?
And again,
giving it a shot and giving it a try.
I thought of that shit at 15 years old,
I started trying to figure out how to do
it 10 years ago.
Daniel and I got it done eight,
nine years later.
And now you have this.
And,
and I say that just to say that I read
Brian Koppelman,
the creator of billions,
um,
is a brilliant
writer to me and he's a phrase of friend
also.
But Brian has been putting up lately
these just encouraging things,
telling writers to write,
even if your stuff is getting body even
if you don't think is good to write,
to to push yourself to push the idea
forward.
And I've been taking a lot of
inspiration for that because Daniel
Daniel Weinfeld and I wanted a co writer
who's in cocreators.
Daniel and I have been talking and
developing this over 10 years now.
I know how to do it,
how to go in a room,
how to get it,
you know,
it won't take me 10 years for the next
one,
but it was worth the struggle,
you know,
it was worth doing that.
It was worth tweaking my ideals worth
critiquing my idea to be like the first
time around like nine.
It's not,
it's not what it should be because I was
nervous as shit the night before it came
out about everything in it.
You know the,
the,
what scenes were shot,
how did it look,
the production value and now seeing
people get it and unlike a lot of other
artists not have to call yourself a
genius.
Let me tell people,
like every artist thinks is a changes.
Every comedian thinks they're fucking
Richard Pryor and some part of your
mind,
you have to think you're great or why I
do it.
You have to believe there's greatness in
you.
Right.
But I never wanted to be the guy.
I'm a fucking genius.
You know what I mean?
I just never want it.
But to see it,
because I always thought the idea was
genius.
Like fuck that shit.
You remember real people that used to
come on in the seventies eighties I
remember watching that show as a kid
looking at motherfuckers like,
wow,
these motherfuckers exist in it,
in it,
and he's off far off places like Iowa
and Kansas and I wanted to approach it.
I want it to approach people in a very,
I'm here right in front of you kind of
way.
Not Above you,
not celebrity Michael Morris,
but people normal wrapper.
And it gave me that opportunity and
people can say is genius and I'm going
to say I'm humbled and honored,
but you're fucking right.
And it's genius because I'm engaging
people at a regular human level,
not at the level of celebrity or power
to used to be an engaged but one it
allows them to fully open up.
I haven't seen it on TV sets some shit
like real people or no,
I haven't seen revolutionary tv like the
Jeffersons or you know,
all in the family or mod and I think
that the world is getting scary and
pussy to be honest.
You know,
not to,
not to disrespect pussies because
policies are tough,
but I think that something needs to be
dangerous.
The best compliment I got on this press
run has been like and brochures,
Ambrosia for headset.
How's it feel to have some [inaudible]
show on TV?
And it's dangerous because it unites
people,
does it separate people?
It gives you alternative answers in the
ones you thought you had and it forces
you to think it doesn't solve all the
problems or wrap it up pretty at the
end.
Gives you some options to do and some
shit to think about us.
And it's funny as fuck.
And so first of in dark and I like it.
I got an imagine netflix give you plenty
of room.
Yeah.
Hell they weren't tripping man.
They don't trip.
They don't trust go.
You know what you're doing.
Go ahead.
Yeah,
exactly.
And then you walk on the room like how
the fuck I'm doing.
But
they're smart enough to let people
create their own
shit.
Like for standup.
Comedy is no one better in terms of like
interacting with them about a special,
you don't have to give many any notes on
the material.
They,
they know that you're going to do your
best.
I felt.
Yeah,
they don't tell.
They can't help you.
Like no one can help you as a comic.
There's not a another person like an
executive is gonna help you do your
best.
You gotta you gotta be looking at it
yourself ruthlessly and you'll figure it
out.
And so they trust you.
Yeah.
So I would assume they did the same
thing with you.
Yeah.
Perfect.
Beautiful.
What a world.
Yeah.
The forever the,
it was the opposite.
There was 50 fucking cooks in the
kitchen.
Everybody's pulling you this way.
What neighbor to shit?
He need a fucking theme song.
You got,
you need a thing you say every week,
which you talk about Willis,
you need to hook.
Everybody needed a hook.
Oh Shit.
Oh my God.
Shouts outs.
Different strokes.
Yeah.
What a weird change in that short amount
of time from different strokes it today
in the world.
Yeah.
That's the weirdest thing.
I'm older than you,
but uh,
not so much older.
We grew up in similar times.
I'm 51 yeah.
You know,
when we were children for both of us,
the world was a way different place than
it is for children today.
Yeah.
These kids are being forced to turbo
charge their evolution and their
education.
They're getting every kid over the age
of like 13 has a phone.
Basically.
The parents hanging there as long as
they can.
That's filming the kids 13 here's the
whole world.
You little fuck adage is true.
Good luck and and and,
and the whole world at a push of a
button where my grandmother,
we get encyclopedias every four years
and I couldn't wait to get the new set
cause you got to read and learn new
information and now that information is
right there.
But if they aren't genuinely curious and
interested,
it'll die right there.
Well there's also a lot of things other
than that information.
It's not just an information device.
These fucking apps and these kids are
using back and forth with each other and
games and are so addictive.
Yeah.
We used to have this place called
outside too.
That was amazing.
Yeah.
Outdoors man.
I'd go and I'd just,
I'd be gone for hours and how it return
dirty as fuck.
Having one on hand,
an adventure.
That was that.
That was amazing.
Now he,
now even outdoors is regulated to some
also you worry about child molesters
creeps and you worry about shit.
We've almost like heard too much about
what's possible.
And then the fact that there are,
there are really still child molesters
out there.
They do exist and we also send them to
church with them so they know.
Some of our worries are,
are exasperated.
Yes.
Yeah,
for sure.
For sure.
Yeah.
That's one of the weirdest things ever.
Like more than likely to chime.
Let's say she was going to happen at a
place that's really,
maybe we should be getting outside
again.
You know,
I started,
I started at Man,
I said my man,
tell my wife,
you know,
get Michael a leaf blower to start going
back outside.
So I started looking for leaf blowers
but to jess and I started taking,
instead of having my nephew do
it because I'm running around on twitter
and shit,
just when I'm home taking my own trash
up and down and spending some time
fucking around on my yard watching
around and stuff.
I just,
I realized being a rapper and living on
a tour bus,
how much I had stopped going outside,
you know,
meanwhile my cousins are fucking Haga
and his Georgia,
you know,
they got,
and I'm just like,
if it went down tomorrow,
like I'd be fuck.
Like I've,
you know,
I'm,
I'm rusty as a nail in the rain right
now,
so I just,
I,
I definitely think there's something to
be said for introducing your kids to
maybe a little more of what it was like
2030 years or 30 40 years ago.
You know,
just imagine that human beings lived
before houses.
Yeah.
There was humans and then they figured
out shelter,
you know,
the,
or it's some kind of rather some kind of
primate and then that primate figured
out shelter and eventually became a
human is a better way to describe it.
But
something like us lived and it hadn't
even figured out roofs yet.
Yeah.
I mean,
I love the wash shows,
those videos or youtube where it's
usually they in these people are there,
they're dark and they're age,
so it has to be the India or Southeast
Asia or somewhere.
But they,
they,
you'll see two dudes and they'll just
make a fucking a hut or something out of
mud.
They'll make a pool.
They're just,
but you get to see the ingenuity and you
understand if they're,
if they're quote unquote primitive
culture never does that.
We never get to skyscrapers like Jack
Fresco talks about that.
Like there's no nothing new.
Everything you see is a,
is an a is an improvement or some
variation of something they've seen
before.
So that those,
you know,
just the curiosity to do that or the
necessity to build that shelter,
you know,
now now gives you a trump tower.
So that's where the dark side of it
comes from.
Dark side for me is that with,
with this innovation that it happens
almost unchecked in terms of our
ability,
our ability to think about what are the
consequences,
like what are the consequences if we
keep making things better and better
computers.
And artificial life and artificial
intelligence and what w what are the
consequences?
The consequences of there's no more,
this thing is no more weird pink monkey
thing.
Yeah.
That that thing goes away because we
don't need it anymore.
Now we've got a new life form.
They new life form is digital life.
Yeah.
I mean that's the real real concern is
that just like we are an evolution of
those lower primates,
it's going to be an evolution.
I think that's going to happen.
I don't think I,
you know,
I,
there may not be any avoiding it by
diet.
Again,
we're the virus,
you know,
and this is just one of my thoughts is
that me saying unequivocably that we put
virus.
Yes.
Yeah.
The thing is I like people like the
other side of it,
people are cool dounreay that aliens go
ahead and attack this motherfucker.
So white people or black people or cut
the bullshit and finally have to do
night like one great movie of Red
October.
I think we're going to get our asses
kicked every saying we're not at least
at least for one time humanity.
All the empires would have to unite.
Like that's what I'm saying.
Remember that Reagan's speech?
No,
you never heard it.
Reagan actually said that in a,
he was,
I forget who he was addressing.
Maybe the first person to ask besides
him putting in the civil right that I
mean the cane day you might give me.
The only other thing I like about Ronald
Reagan was a very strict,
one of the things that was really
strange about it was that it's,
it's shut off this gigantic wave of
conspiracy theorists who were thinking
that they're going to tell us something
about alien contact.
Check this out,
listen to this
outside universal thread.
I occasionally think how quickly our
differences worldwide would vanish if we
were facing an alien threat from outside
this word dude and yes,
I asked you is not an alien force
already among us.
What could be more alien to the
universal aspirations of our peoples
than war and the threat of
tell you what to Ronald Reagan knocked
it out of the fucking park right there.
Straight up.
I have a song called Reagan.
Many of you know wasn't the biggest fan
of him or many of us presidents cause I
rapped about more than him in there,
but that definitely is going to make it
on a killer Mike Song.
Really that,
that,
that to you.
Got It.
You got this killer Mike and LP.
We definitely,
if anybody think aliens are going to
come kill us all one day,
so I'm going to maybe suggest to ail.
Hopefully we'll use it,
but if not fucking I'm gonna do it.
Dad.
Shit is amazing.
Yeah.
What do you,
do you think that it is possible that
aliens came down and manipulated the
genetics of lower primates and creative
people?
I'm willing based on all the theology,
I'm willing to accept it.
That's a possibility because I don't
think that we're alone.
Right.
I just don't.
I,
there's nothing,
even if there is some divine thing that
woke up and decided to make us and we're
a special children and we on our to the
boot plant,
there had to have been some other things
made her play with.
Right.
I don't think that I think is very
arrogant as a human being to think that
it's just us.
Right,
and I think that the possibility that
something made it here and something
happened exist.
Absolutely.
Because if we're experimenting on
animals and things,
we got like my daughter's army,
their temperament is mean.
They're curiosity is me.
Like I see,
I'm looking at Michael and I'm looking
at a night and I'm like arguing with
tonight.
It's like arguing with myself.
She doesn't know why she acts like that.
I don't know.
Now if I can look at my pit bull and
say,
well,
her mother acted like this and this is
why I know she's coded this way.
I know her father was his.
Then I have to look at my daughter and
save on a genetic basis,
23 and my chromosomes.
I know our temperament.
It's like that.
I know why Michael is not going to argue
she's a smart kid.
She's an art student,
but the minute you put her in danger,
she's going to punch you.
You know what I mean?
That's what,
that's what it's going to be and it's
not going to be anything else because
she is going to protect her.
And so it's like,
I have to think that my curiosity,
if nothing else,
my drive to do this.
So if you take the primate side,
you say,
well you know you,
you know that I have to live in mark
since I got to survive as wolves,
as Lions,
tigers,
bears out here,
I have to go high,
I have to create shelf.
There's something else with was a very
small input could have dropped here,
landed here.
And what's crazy,
if you look into nation of Islam
philosophy of sorts,
they have a Ufo type philosophy.
Something here in and by their amount of
scientists created,
you know,
all of,
of when a Shrek rain kind of created the
different races.
But something could have come here in it
and it gets here and it says Bonet with
I do this and this and I create this.
And then we set upon evolution and we
ended up here.
Or that's just could be,
you know,
me stone having watched too many south
five movies.
But it's possible.
It is.
It is possible.
There's zero evidence for it,
but it's certainly possible that if we
could go to another planet,
we knew how in life that it's possible
if we found some lower primates that we
would manipulate them.
It's very possible for a full survey of
another planet we got there and like,
okay,
here's the good news,
good news.
A lot of life.
The bad news is the most intelligent
thing is basically a chimp,
but we've got some ideas and a we're
going to do is we're going to plant some
seeds of our genetics in some of these
chimps.
They're going to be smarter than the
other chimps.
And then we're gonna believe mushrooms
everywhere.
Leave the mushrooms everywhere.
Let the chimps,
he'd mushrooms.
Maybe we're in a fishbowl maybe.
Yeah.
Cause again,
we're at,
we very arrogantly think of ourselves is
as top choice,
but maybe,
maybe we're just a virus on this living
thing.
Maybe something maybe,
you know,
we say,
but we could go a state of virus,
amass virus could kill us all.
Yup,
sure.
That's what we're constantly fighting.
The earth wouldn't stop,
but they'll think about viruses like get
viruses wholly negative in our eyes.
I don't think we're wholly negative to
each other.
I don't think a virus thinks his
holiness.
So what I'm saying is that eating you
up,
you're having a good party.
When you get the flow,
they're like,
dude,
it's probably up if this thing is really
a living thing.
If the earth is really living thing,
we are possibly the worst thing.
Sore it.
Oh,
for sure.
Last.
Shouldn't it get rid of us other than
meteors?
Yeah.
We're the worst thing for not just the
biological life,
but the particulates in the atmosphere
and now we're creating technology that's
going to eventually kill us and get rid
of us that may be able to live in
harmony with biology maybe.
So.
Yeah,
maybe.
Maybe it's over for us in a few thousand
years.
It could be.
But you know,
the thing that makes us fun is the thing
that's totally unnecessary.
It's the thing that got us to the dance.
It's the thing that made us want to
breed and there's the animal side.
I got to Piss so bad I can get it.
The animal side,
you have to embrace your primal.
There is,
it's there,
it's a part of you.
Yeah.
You've existed in this state for a long
time.
Fucking,
and the people that came before that
were savage are still,
you know,
yeah.
I always think that to myself when I
hear people say,
why did he throw it all away?
It just stick to yourself.
Cause that bitch was hot.
Yeah.
Fight Nature.
Nature's a crazy gene.
Crazy fun.
And that's the reason why there's 7
billion of us.
This,
it's insane.
Drive this computer code that's in the
back of your head is constantly running.
They had a species must survive.
It must,
that's really all we put here to do is
reproduce.
Well,
we're doing that.
Where
I've been,
the way I've been describing it is that
I feel like we're some sort of,
uh,
electronic caterpillar that's making a
cocoon.
We don't even know what the fuck we're
doing and we're about to become a
butterfly or just megan is cocoon and we
just completely engulfed in it.
We're not thinking about it,
but everyone does it.
They all do it.
That's how I felt.
Like when I,
when I,
when I see all this stuff getting better
and better and more invasive in your
life and the technology becoming more
and more advanced and everybody obsessed
with it,
that's the thing I think is like,
this is eventually going to be
everything.
It's going to be way better than this
physical life.
They're gonna offer you a life that
exists just like the Matrix.
The Matrix sounded like such horse Shit,
Fun,
fun movie,
great movie and Shit.
But like that can never happen now.
I think for sure it could happen 100%.
It could happen.
I see that there's no question.
If they could make a world that's better
than this and all you had to do is plug
the back of your head.
Let's see.
I think that's,
and um,
and again,
if I'm 89,
I might say fuck in and plug in for
another 80,
89.
Yeah.
And maybe if they keep your flesh alive,
they'll figure out some way to reverse
everything.
Maybe.
Uh,
maybe you think,
I mean,
but then Dan,
you got to decide who gets to live,
who gets a dye.
Yup.
You go into it and we get some classes
he thinks most and then you gotta you
gotta you gotta go to kill your master's
mode.
And that's what I think happens.
Ultimately,
that's the thing they say is that as
people get more affluent,
they have less children in the
population decreases as the world's
economy evens out and so that we reached
like a point where we can maintain a
sustainable population.
How does that has still happened without
mass genocide or mass sterilization?
That's a good question.
I don't think they're saying that.
I think what they're saying is that as
people become more educated and more
affluent and more successful,
as more urbanization takes place,
people work more and have less children
and when they have less children,
the population actually slightly
decreases.
This is this argument,
but I don't mind fuck more people who
fuck more,
have more children night.
That just,
that's one of those stats where I'm be
like,
they might do,
they might just be talking about a
particular class of people.
They're still sell 7 billion people.
Yeah,
there's still 7 billion people live
mostly for under 22,000 a year.
Yeah.
And it usually every time development
comms at exploits them.
Yes.
So like where does the balance out of
affluence coming?
Like I know there's one country now
that's doing a universal pay for people.
So are we going to talk about going,
because when you go to like is does that
happen?
Is that,
is that it?
We're going to universal pay.
Well universal paid would be fine if it
was universal effort.
If everybody did it,
put it out the same amount of effort.
I would agree with everyone getting to
say no.
I'm not saying I'm for or against that.
I'm just saying how do you maintain,
how does it,
how does it happen that everybody all of
a sudden it's affluent without mass
genocide of sterilization.
But think the idea is that as urban,
and listen,
this is not my theory for sure,
but I've read it.
The idea is as the world becomes more
urbanized and more educated and more
wealthy as as city spread out,
what happens is less.
Those people have kids and they have
less kids.
This is just a,
and it doesn't work that well.
I don't know if it works or not,
but I know that this is an actual study.
Right.
See if you could find that he pulled her
vein is fuck,
some people are,
yeah,
most people are,
but the overall humans,
once people have serious careers,
like the man and the woman have a
serious career,
they,
both of them are like really invested in
the career.
They generally tend to have less kids.
And when the,
this is the idea is that as this people,
I don't know,
it's a solution.
I don't think it's a good solution.
I've made people become obsessed with
work.
That's one of the things,
but the rest of the world's just not,
that sounds like I'm still talking about
America.
Like I poor people are fucking man.
So again,
I just called back to me like I hear it
all studies show,
but you gotta say to yourself,
how,
how do you handle the other 4 billion
people?
I think the argument is,
and this is not my argument today,
they go,
they keep,
they keep expanding is that these cities
and these urban areas,
uh,
that as the society sort of evens out
globally,
whether it takes a thousand years or a
hundred years as things start to even
out people will be more like Los Angeles
and less like less like poor place at
Calcutta.
Yeah.
Potass site.
But what I'm saying,
it's like poor in Calcutta.
You got a bunch of people walking.
It's pumped in this noise.
It could be a Los Angeles.
She got small,
you've got traffic,
you've got Trisha,
anything.
My death.
There's Delta two different extremes
that that just seem weird.
Like I'm just saying,
you know,
sometimes I just feel like maybe we are
at the point,
it ain't no turning around then we might
be just cause we got 7 billion people.
We might be,
but we also might not be.
And I think it's not a bad time to be
optimistic because as people look for
better and better solutions,
but,
but like jock fresco and the Venus
project talking about moneyless society
to rather radical change of what a
political states and things of that
nature chompsky talks about,
you know,
essentially all all countries
essentially now no matter western or
eastern oligarchies and shit.
So like what's the radical departure
from this and that saves it all in your
mind.
Like with the Joe Rogan,
United Nations speech,
I think people are more aware of the
flaws of the system than they ever have
been any generation previous.
Okay.
I think when you look at kids from the
seventies and eighties I don't think
there were nearly as educated as to how
truly fucked up this country is and but
also yet truly amazing in terms of like
the history of the world,
but has plenty to printing to improve
on.
But probably will.
I think people are getting better at
life to getting better at all,
all of the things and government will
come along with it.
I think we're going to get better at
things.
We understand each other better.
We communicate better is I'm optimistic
and I think with all these incredibly
intelligent people that are looking at
the problems in the world in terms of
carbon,
in the atmosphere or pollution in the
ocean,
people are already starting to work on
solutions.
I got,
I'm really optimistic that,
that it's,
there's at least a potential for someone
to figure out some to some of these
problems.
Overpopulation is always going to be a
weird one because you don't have the
right to tell people how many kids they
can have cars who,
like if you meet somebody who's got 10
kids and the most fucking amazing family
ever,
what,
what?
What are you gonna say?
It's bad.
They have 10 amazing kids.
Everybody's great.
You go over the house,
it's all love.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
Why is that bad?
You tell me.
So.
So people are good,
but only a certain amount.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's where it gets weird,
but,
but it's not a cut and dry issue.
It's not a one or a zero.
It's like,
yeah,
there are too many people and yeah,
you probably shouldn't have 10 kids,
but you gotta fucking awesome family,
so hey,
have a good nightmare.
Yeah.
What the fuck to do?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You know,
it just speaking as you know,
just has a lot of their brow people.
Just this scenario,
this is never went well for us.
I'm always,
always,
always check it out.
You can't tell him what to do.
He just always watching you.
You know what I'm saying?
This das scenario usually doesn't go
good telling people how many kids are
gonna have kit though.
Fuck at that.
But it happens like it happens.
You think about,
you think about countries where refugees
are pointing to now,
just just put up illegal sterilization
and you start to see,
you start to see where countries are
still alive and refugees that are coming
in.
It's crazy and it's scary.
It was terrifying.
And I don't want my country to become
that.
Like I remember what countries have
sterilized people as they've come in.
I've read a story about it once that
they did that to some refugee somewhere,
but I can't remember where it was.
Hey,
I can't remember either.
I'm squishing.
Probably know so,
yeah,
but I a country accused of sterilizing
refugees.
Maybe that was just a rumor.
Maybe it's what the snow is.
Not all of them.
I could imagine that happening here.
Not Saying,
not saying with some people if they had
their way.
Yeah,
and that's scary to think about it.
These are the people we put in power.
Like you know what was cool to me about
what Ms. Ellis and taught me,
she was,
she was a teacher.
She had one leg,
right?
She and she wore like a curly met Larry
and mold three stooges.
She wore the,
the like the little mushroom hairstyle
curling up.
And she was mean as shit,
man.
Like God damn,
she was mean.
But this lady talked to fucking,
she taught civics and when she taught
about how,
even if your parents weren't
naturalizing weren't citizens,
if you were just born on us soil,
you got shot.
You know you were a citizen.
Yeah.
I'll just like,
damn,
that's amazing.
Because when you think about,
at that time we had learned about,
I think in history of the Irish and
their plight to be here and things of
that nature.
Just like,
man,
this country gives you a fucking shot.
And this is like when America was
rattled,
this is in the middle of public enemy
Erin Shit.
But there was something to be admired in
it.
Like James Baldwin had an adoration for
American,
had many people didn't even know he
ended up dying.
You know,
as he's living in France.
I think the expectation that dream,
that American sales you manage shit is
amazing.
Eric can be,
and to know that that was a possibility
then and now my kids don't think like
that and my kids are dead in the middle
of keeping people out as shit.
It's fucking weird.
So
in my lifetime,
I'm scared to death something I'm I see
happening in this country.
That's how afraid I am right now with
shit going fucked up.
That's what I mean when I say when you
say,
well,
we'll have a government or a world one
day where people will be a more fluent,
well in capitalism,
even though I'm a capitalist,
you know,
I try to practice compassionate
capitalism and capitalism.
Capitalism requires someone get
snuckered does it really the way we
practice it,
absolutely ideal that you shouldn't be
to be more like Milton Friedman and the
free market.
Right?
And what Thomas all talk about.
But we as in you and I know,
but we,
you and I engage in capitalism.
Yeah.
You and I occasionally capitalism has a
lot more fair than what countries are
doing with one another large scale sit
and stuff.
That's why I say the current system of
capitalist,
there's nothing wrong with you being
able to buy that beautiful jeep outside
based on the work you've done.
Your work ethic will determine your
worth is written in the window of my
barbershop.
And I really mean it,
right?
You're work ethic is gonna determine
with you or even if there was no such
thing as money,
if you plow your fields,
you going to be more bountiful.
So long it's been [inaudible] me ask you
this.
You think it's the system of capitalism
itself that has the flaws in it or is it
human nature as desire to exploit
things?
I think it's human nature unchecked in
that system.
Okay.
You know,
I think that allowing marijuana to
become legal should not have allowed.
The type of taxation that's been allowed
in California.
Colorado was at one point in time was
39% yeah.
What does it in California,
I don't know,
but it's high enough that I seen the
house.
So we'd go from about $150 to 320 bucks.
I think that's terrible.
But I would like it if all that money
went to a good purpose,
but we know it's not.
Yeah,
that's right.
Counting Shit.
You know what I'm saying?
[inaudible] it never lands where it
should.
It never does what it's supposed to do.
That's what I'm,
that's,
that's what I'm getting.
That's why I said when,
when Stereo,
when I say,
you know,
I want to be that guy,
but usually I go,
but for bribery,
just because you just like God fucking
damn.
Like,
why isn't good happening in the
immediate cause so much money is pushed
into the immediate,
well,
if we does become legal worldwide,
it's in Thai.
I mean countrywide,
it's entirely possible that it's going
to stimulate economies and a lot of very
poor places.
It's going to have some real positive
benefit.
I agree,
but,
but what,
what I'm saying about capitalism is why
are we not ensuring that the people who
have suffered since 1937 have a fair
shot?
Right.
We've allowed so many laws to come in
with marijuana legalization,
get it does not allow for the spa
business man to have the type of
ingenuity is set up,
got a small liquor store had at the end
of prohibition or bar.
You know,
Jamie was telling me that in Ohio they
were setting it up.
So they were trying to make it legal,
but only two guys can grow it to
enormous corporations.
That was the bill,
right?
Is that how it worked?
Jamie,
I believe might've been four
or something like that.
Wasn't a lot,
some small amount of people.
They were the only ones who could.
I'm saying,
Bro,
we know,
we know that's fucked up.
That's so crazy.
That wouldn't even ask for them.
We notice fucked up when it should just
be your lab to grow it with a,
with $100 state,
federal tax,
state tax stamp,
you gotta stay tax to have 100 bucks.
You can grow up to three acres of
marijuana.
Bam.
Love it,
love it,
perfect love you do your shit.
And then the growers have to buy from
you.
So if a farmer wants to make a
collective with,
for the farmers,
they are making that collective,
but we shouldn't be able to to,
to allow that type of domination because
essentially then you're just giving
people,
you know,
monopolies of sorts.
So it's,
it's like I just,
I don't trust us to,
to be on our shit enough with the people
we leave in charge.
Right.
Well it also,
it wouldn't make sense in any other
relationship.
And then the of the relationship are,
all someone is saying is if I let you
sell something,
you give me a certain percentage because
you're basically saying that all of the,
the frameworks of our government and the
the city's roads that you drive on and
all that stuff takes money to maintain.
So we're just going to take a little
piece now they'd take it 39% that's so
much.
But if that 39% went all to public
schools and paying teachers more money
and paying cops and paying firemen and
community centers,
but beyond just pain,
good son of a former cop,
cousin of current cops,
policemen should be from areas that
they're policing or areas like those.
They should be offered no interest loans
to live at and around those communities,
teachers should be also,
and the fire department,
they should almost hold a special place
because of the nobility of those jobs
and how important they are.
We all should do stuff like tax freeze
is once you retire,
whatever your taxes are,
once you retire at 65 years old,
we should knock baby 10 20% off.
And that's what you pay until you die.
You know what I mean?
We should do everything we can to make
the the class of people you're saying
about affluence possible and we're not
doing it like that's,
I guess that's the only button I'm
pushing when I seen,
cause I'm a very optimistic person,
but my pessimism,
my pessimism comes more from the lack of
what I've seen us be willing to do to
make sure that one another treated
fairly then I have seen for.
Right.
You know what I'm saying?
Like I refuse to disavow.
You know what I mean?
Tuesday tends just an attitude though.
And that people evolve that attitude.
No.
We realize how important cooperation
really is a dewey though without being
attacked by all of us.
Some of us do.
You do?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And I do.
If there's,
there's people that do,
and it takes a hard,
it's a hard knock into your head to,
to really let it sink in.
Yeah.
But once you do let it sink in and you
live your life that way,
reciprocity and friendship for all and
camaraderie.
I'm so richer life,
it's a better life.
Absolutely.
The problem is people aren't taught,
they're not taught in enough.
They're not taught it in.
Men are taught to to face each other,
to hate each other and the hate on each
other and not look at each other in a
with a a famine mentality or a
mentality.
The lamest shit alive that is life.
The opposite is beautiful.
The obstacle.
You're uplifting people and like you,
you've give out 35 shoutouts.
Yeah,
positive dude.
That's what it's all about,
man.
That makes me feel better that it's
people like you out there.
It makes people feel better when they
listen to your music and they enjoy it.
That you're this guy behind it that's
not taking any of this for granted and
you're running with this shit.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I appreciate it.
Beautiful Man.
I love it.
Did we just did three hours?
It felt like three a good.
Three to
30 or 20 minutes.
It was incredible.
I was hanging in there tight.
Well,
listen man,
I'm a big fan.
I'm honored that you came down here and
did this.
It was beautiful for me.
I enjoyed it very much and I love you
shit.
I learned much to tell you a tell people
how to get you online.
I've just killer Mike Online,
k,
I.L ,
instagram,
twitter,
all that shit.
I don't go to my facebook.
That's one of my kids running that shit.
Okay,
so don't send to any page.
Thank you brother.
Appreciate it,
man.
Pc.