Hello Ladies and gentlemen,
this episode of the podcast is brought
to you by draft kings draftkings.com,
America's favorite one week fantasy
football site where you can win enormous
cash prizes every week.
You've already researched the plays for
your season long fantasy team,
especially if you're like Jamie and you
are a serious dork about it.
Turn that knowledge into
instantCash@draftkings.com
last year.
These are real numbers.
One player turned $11 into 4,000
in one weekend.
Another player won 100 grand his first
time ever playing and another player won
a million dollars in one day.
Just playing fantasy football.
I used to think fantasy football was
ridiculous,
but now I'm starting to understand it.
It's like when I found out how much
poker players made,
I went,
Whoa,
wait a minute.
I say poker when they're playing cards,
like a bunch of little kids.
No,
no.
They're making stupid amounts of money
playing fantasy football.
That's real.
I can't believe it.
Like men,
like men.
Yeah,
keep you season long league where it is,
but also play one week
fantasy@draftkings.com
to win huge cash this weekend.
Hurry,
get your entry into the millionaire
maker event were first place.
Takes home a million dollars.
That's a million American real dollars.
Not like Mcdonald's books or fucking
chucky cheese dollars or some shit.
Head over.
Is there a McDonald's dollar?
I'm going to made that up.
Head over to draft kings.com
now and enter the Promo Code Rogan to
play for free to become a millionaire.
Imagine if you win a million bucks by
entering the Promo Code
Rogan@draftkings.com
for a free.
That would be ridiculous.
Draftkings.com.
Bigger events,
bigger winnings,
bigger millionaires,
and to Rogan for free entry
now@draftkings.com.
That is draft kings.com.
Oh,
she sent me another one to me.
Undies one,
which I'm wearing me undies right now,
by the way.
Not that you needed to know,
but there's a new.
There's a new underwear sponsor.
Where's the fucking Mandy's thing?
Man,
see,
that's why I hate when people,
when she sends me separate ones.
Hold on a second,
let me find it.
Me.
They're the best underwear I've ever
had.
I can give you one without any,
any preparation,
but I'll tell you what.
I didn't think anything of it.
I used to buy cheap underwear.
I used to buy underwear and like a
package.
Those little plastic packages that you
get at like Walmart or something like
that,
just throw it in the cart and keep
moving.
But when they started sending me these
Mondays I was like,
what is it just underwear like what's
the big deal?
Well,
this is one big deal.
P,
the average man doesn't change his
underwear more often than every seven
years.
That's ridiculous.
Like the average male buys a pair of
underwear and keep that rotten but
filter for seven years.
That's terrible.
And they're not that comfortable.
They,
they also that weird hole in the front
that no one understands that shit was
made during the depression when people
didn't understand how to really pay out
of your own music.
What is that whole?
Nobody uses that guy down the hall.
Okay.
Do you use that whole shut up anyway?
Me undies.com
is seriously the most comfortable
underwear you have ever tried on you.
We'll try these on and you will say,
oh,
they actually wick moisture away from
your body.
They feel perfect.
They don't ride up on you.
They pull moisture away from your skin
so that your cool all day long.
I have them right now.
I wear them everyday now.
See only underwear I wear.
Now,
I know it sounds ridiculous,
but if you try me undies.com,
just give it a shot.
Listen to me try it.
And uh,
you will see that there are underwear
that are better than.
So like everything else,
like someone came along and they figured
out,
they figured out the better mouse trap.
They figured out how to make underwear
better.
Go to [inaudible] dot com forward slash
rogen and get 20 percent off of your
first order.
That's 20 percent off your first order
when you go to [inaudible] dot com
forward slash rogen.
And you'll even get free shipping in the
United States and our friends to the
north in Canada.
Free shipping up there as well.
I guarantee you're going to be happy
with them.
The best underwear.
Seriously I've ever bought.
Go to get that 20 percent off.
Go to [inaudible] dot com forward slash
rogen it.
Last but not least,
we are brought to you by ting.
If you go to Rogan.ting.com,
you can save 25 bucks off of any of the
new team devices that they sell at tank
with.
Ting is,
it's a mobile site that is a mobile
service that uses a sprint backbone and
they buy time on the network on the
sprint network.
So if you are,
if you were on Ting,
you're actually on the sprint network,
but you do it by tings.
Rules and tings.
Rules will save you money.
My,
my bill last month was 18 bucks.
Excuse me.
Now I don't do a lot of phone calls.
I mostly text,
but that's fucking ridiculous.
Cheap.
18 bucks.
And I go online all the time with it.
A $21 is the average monthly bill per
device for 10 customers.
Four hundred and $40 is the average
annual savings for per device,
uh,
for a business with one to 20 employees.
That's a pretty interesting.
What's interesting to me is that
companies are starting to.
It's actually 11 to 20 employees a
business with 11 to 20 employees.
Four hundred $40 is the average annual
savings.
Um,
what they've,
what they've done is they've figured out
a way to make you feel better about your
relationship with your cell phone
provider.
Like for a lot of people sell cell phone
providers,
just this big company and they have
their rules and if you don't,
if you go over your cost,
you money,
if you,
you know,
there's a bunch of weird shit that goes
on.
Like if you want to cancel,
you have to pay some sort of an early
termination fee.
Tings removed,
all that.
No early termination fees,
no cancellation fees,
just cancel.
That's it.
If you don't want to be a part of them
anymore,
you're gone.
You don't have contracts,
you don't have any of that stuff.
You use what you use and that's what you
pay for it.
You don't have like x amount of minutes
per month.
It used to be that you would buy a
certain amount of minutes a month,
like 100 minutes a month,
and if you only use 70 of those minutes,
you never got credited for those other
30 minutes.
So Ting,
they did it first.
The first way they did it was the credit
people.
They decided to give people the money
back and credit their next bill and then
they decided like,
why are we charging them for stuff
they're not using anyway?
What's.
Let's just set it up so that we charge
people for what they use and in doing so
you will most certainly save money and
it's the most logical and reasonable way
to provide cell phone service.
In my opinion.
I don't see why anybody would not want
to just do it that way.
The only reason is it benefits the cell
phone providers to charge you a fixed
rate.
Then when you go over that fixed rate,
they hit you with the overage charge and
if you go under that fixed rate,
it's to their benefit.
So 10 cut all that stuff out and they
they provide you with an awesome service
with a great company using the sprint
backbone and they do it completely
ethically and I just,
I like doing business with them.
They're the official cell phone provider
for this podcast.
The phone that we use when I coordinate
guests and make calls and stuff,
all that stuff is all through Tang.
If you go to Rogan.ting.com,
you will save 25 bucks off of any of
their devices and they have all the
finest android devices in stock.
Like the one that I have is the Samsung
Galaxy s five,
which is pretty awesome and it has a lot
of features that like even with the new
iphones that are coming out,
it doesn't have like it's water
resistant,
which I don't understand why these
people are making electronic devices
that aren't water resistant.
When they can make ones that are water
resistant.
It just seems logical.
If you go to Rogan.ting.com,
you can find all the various devices and
if you're a cheap person or frugal or or
you just.
One of those people that realize is
most,
most of the time you don't really need
the latest and greatest and all this
shit.
It's just a.
it's a fetish and a lot of ways and if
you're a Weirdo and you're like flip
phones,
they have those two.
You could buy one of those Samsung,
m for hundreds for 72 bucks.
You can buy one of the older iphones.
You get an iphone four for 100,
12 bucks.
You or you can get an iphone five.
They have iphone five.
Iphone five,
s has come in.
They have a the galaxy note three,
the htc one,
m eight,
which is an awesome phone as well.
Anyway.
Rogan.ting.com.
Go there.
Saved money,
be happy.
All right.
Graham Hancock is here.
Why fuck around young Jamie Cube's
music.
Joe Rogan podcast,
my friend Graham Hancock.
I'll take these offices.
You're not wearing them.
Good to see you,
buddy.
Nice to see you.
Joe.
Good to be back.
Good to see you.
Returning from floating.
I saw your tweet
showed a picture of a look like someone
was in space.
That's how it felt to me.
Now I have to thank you for this because
you are the guy who turned me onto
floating.
I never did it before.
You spoke to me about it last year.
I was so harassed and so rushed.
I never got.
I never got a chance to do it.
I thought I'd do it when I got back to
England.
It didn't happen,
so I got in touch with your friend crash
few weeks before I came out here and he
very kindly fitted me in and I think his
place is called float lab technologies
and they're in the field.
They're there in Venice beach,
so it's a totally new experience for me.
And what made the experience even more
surreal and special because I had asked
for an appointment fairly late in the
day.
Was that.
I mean he needed more notice.
He's constantly booked up.
What he could give me was the two rooms,
one for myself,
one for my wife Santha at midnight at
midnight,
two nights in a row,
and actually there's something about
floating at midnight,
which I think is really.
It's really special.
I don't do any floating during the day.
Right,
right.
It's a really good time.
It's a really good time to do it.
So we went along to Venice beach and
park the car and crash came out and took
us in.
And first of all he showed us his
collection of African masks and he has
got the most amazing,
slightly fearsome collection of African
masks up there.
There's really incredible.
Actually it is a deep guy.
He's,
he's a,
he's a trip thinking about a lot of,
a lot of stuff.
And I've been,
I've spent a lot of time in Africa.
I've never seen a collection like that.
It's just just amazing dog on,
you know,
some of the really fascinating peoples
and their,
and their mass.
Then he takes us down.
He talks us through what it is.
So,
you know,
you go into this room and in it I've
seen in some places they have like a pod
where you close,
you close a lit of.
But that's not what he's got.
He's got a bigger room than that.
And there's a big full size.
Feels like a huge metal safe.
Um,
if you have trust issues,
you know,
it's a little bit,
you've got to,
you're going to close yourself up in a
huge metal,
safe in the darkness.
It takes a little bit,
you know,
a little bit of courage is,
I would say is required to do that at
midnight on Venice beach.
But we did it.
And,
and you know,
we got in there at certain warnings.
You don't want to get the salty water in
your eyes.
If you do,
it's a big distraction.
You don't want to get it in your ears
because it's got a block.
So you wear ear plugs.
It doesn't bother me.
I just go in with my ears.
I don't worry.
I would prefer to because because the
feeling of being completely deaf was
slightly slightly alarming for me.
Although I realize a sensory deprivation
is part of the deal.
Um,
and,
and uh,
so you close the door,
there's a towel hanging off the back of
the door in case you do get salty water
in your eyes.
And then you just lie down in this,
I guess body temperature,
say line solution in which it's in,
which is impossible to sink and there
you are in the darkness completely
without,
without sensation,
totally by yourself.
The first time in
a way ever.
I mean this is what sometimes we're
alone,
but to be completely alone in total
darkness suspended in that amniotic
fluid,
that strange say line,
say line solution with no sensations
coming in,
no sounds,
no light.
It's an extraordinary opportunity to
meditate,
to reflect,
to just drift away into another place
and not theirs.
The only danger I would say it happened
to it,
I kept,
I find it difficult to shut down my
mind.
My mind is always running and,
and a few times it when I was just
wanting to let everything go everyday
concerns and worries came back in and
started and started annoying me.
But most of the time I was able to let
go and it felt like I was.
I was weightless and I was floating,
floating in space.
That's why I posted that picture on
facebook today because that's what it
felt like.
And sometimes I didn't know whether I
was horizontal or vertical.
I felt like I felt sometimes like I was
vertically floating vertically.
It was a very odd sensation.
Um,
I wouldn't say that I got into deeply
trippy space,
but I did have fundamental visions.
Patterns.
Lights started to,
started to generate purple.
Purple Strips of light started to
appear,
which certainly would not there in the,
in the darkness with me.
And that was,
that was interesting.
But most of all was just very relaxing,
just very relaxing to let go,
be completely supported by this soft,
gentle water drift,
drift away into the realms of the mind.
It was,
it was a wonderful experience and I felt
much better about it the second day.
Then I did the first.
The first day was some unfamiliarity.
The second,
the second night last night was just
amazing.
Yeah,
that's what it's all about.
It's all about getting used to the
experience.
And the more you get used to the
experience,
the easier it is to slip into the deeper
and deeper states.
Yes,
it's the first time.
It's very alien,
is so odd and is also kind of bump
against the sides and you have to
crashes.
African mosques.
Well yeah.
You probably shouldn't show you those
before you go into total darkness in a
meat locker.
Exactly.
But you.
Yeah,
yeah.
The second day,
the second day so much better and so
much so it's made me think maybe I
should get myself a flute thing.
Oh,
you definitely should.
It's huge.
I love having one.
I love knowing that anytime I want to go
in there I could just go in there how
they loads and loads of money or are
they okay?
Yeah,
there are loads and loads of money.
Thousands and thousands of dollars.
Especially the flash ones.
The crash ones rather the um,
the original one that I got which was a
Samadhi tank,
I think that was like six or $7,000,
but crashes are more like 30.
Okay.
Because his car.
Yeah.
It's like it's like buying,
it's like buying a car and it's also,
it has these incredible filters.
It's set up through like he has it set
up like the one that I have in my house,
I'm the only one that goes in it,
but if it's a commercial grade
filtration system,
like he filters things through ozone.
There's all these different various
steps that it takes.
He's written like an entire,
like multi,
I don't know how many pages.
Probably like 50 or 60 page.
A booklet on the necessity for different
types of filtration and you know what
he.
I mean he's an obsessive guy and his
obsession with tanks has made.
He's.
There's a guy in Austin that has some
really amazing tanks to that does it a
little bit differently.
He,
he does it through a company that makes
boats and his are really excellent too,
but crash is like the leader of the
pack.
He's the master of the game.
There was nothing like his stuff when
this stuff came out.
Now there's guys like the guy in Atlanta
in a,
in Austin rather that is elevating his.
I,
I spent some time there and checked out
his facility.
It's beautiful.
He's friends with my friend Aubrey.
But the um,
what,
what crash did was,
there was no innovation going on in the
United States when it came to float
technology.
There was like the standard somebody
tank,
which is really great.
I mean,
it's cool.
You could definitely get a cool
experience in it.
And then there's some,
some,
uh,
home models that a few people had,
but what he did is he just took
everything to the next level and made
everything,
these steel modular boxes that it fits
together perfectly.
More sound deadening,
more insulation,
better filtration system,
stronger reinforced sides because if
somebody wants,
would kind of go out on the sides a
little bit from the water and sometimes
they would rot and like you had to get
things replaced.
He fixed everything he fixed.
There was an issue with the,
the linings would burn out sometimes
because of the heat pads.
He pads with short out it would burn
through the linings and then would leak
water everywhere.
He fixed that by,
first of all,
by setting like this redundant system.
And having to heat pads too,
so if one burns out you have a second
one ready to go.
And then secondly he put these thick
pond filters.
He doesn't use like the same kind of
filters that a lot of people do.
Not filters rather liners.
His liners are very thick.
They're for like Koi ponds.
So he's done a lot of innovation.
He's really figured out a lot of
different things.
It's the place to go if you're lucky
enough to live in la.
Well it's also if you're lucky enough to
be able to get in now because now he's
booked way in advance.
That's what I found.
I mean I read it to him.
I wrote to him at least four weeks ago
and there were just no slots available
during the day.
He,
that's why he gave me the two midnight
slot.
So that actually I'm really glad he gave
me the midnight slot.
That's the way to do it late at night.
So the way to dentist.
And he's opening a new unit in Westwood.
Yes.
Where there'll be seven.
Yeah.
That's not enough.
No.
Even seven's not enough.
I mean there's not.
There's,
you could open up one somewhere that has
50 and that soccer would be filled all
day.
It will be 20 million people in la,
so there's not so many other doing this
in La right now.
There's a few,
you know,
um,
I think people are starting to become
aware of it now and it's growing.
Sweet.
We'll amazing experience what one
question I have and wonder about.
What about if you have a joint before
you get in or take some psilocybin,
what would that do?
I don't know what it's like to not do
that before you go in and do that.
Every soil,
not suicide been,
but I have,
but the um,
the pot is,
the edibles are the way to go for about
an hour before a terrifying supply of
edibles.
Terrifying dose.
Originally.
What do I do?
And then I get in there.
That's what I like to do.
Okay.
That's what,
that's what I'd like to do as well if I
hadn't given up many years ago.
It makes me very humble.
There's something about getting in
there.
It's just a.
and because I've done it so many times,
but you know,
because I have the tank in my house,
I'm super comfortable,
I can,
I can get relaxed with floating.
It's a normal thing to me.
So when you're on the edibles to,
it just takes you to these really,
really,
really bizarre places.
No moments of paranoia or fear,
you're just calm there.
I wouldn't say that I'm,
I'm pretty good with that though.
I mean if I had real problems with
paranoia and fear,
I wouldn't be able to do everything I do
for a living.
Sure.
You know what I mean?
Everything I do this live,
you know,
everything I do when I do commentary for
the UFC that's live.
Very Edgy.
Yeah.
All these things are all live and
they're all depend on maintaining your
sanity under sometimes pretty intense
pressure.
But um,
so I,
I don't,
I don't have those,
those paranoia or fear issues.
But I certainly feel the,
the,
the thoughts,
I just don't indulge them and I feel the
thoughts,
but it's like a lot of ways not indulge
them.
Yeah.
It's like a lot of psychedelic
experiences.
It's a matter of controlling the
mindset.
I kind of equate it to just the ability
to communicate on the Internet and the
ability to access information on the
Internet is led us to this weird place
where if you want it to,
your day could be filled with horror.
You could just go everyday to the worst
possible websites and see the most
horrific videos and the most horrific
photographs and see the world in the
worst possible light.
If you chose to just immerse yourself.
You know,
just watch the news.
I mean,
even worse the news.
if you really wanted to really change
the way you saw the world when you could
live on a beautiful treeline street with
the nicest neighbors and you know,
the,
the cutest little dogs bark in and the
life looks beautiful,
but through the portal that is the
Internet,
you can immerse yourself in twisted
sadistic minds and,
and it's like you have this decision to
not do that.
And that's in,
in,
in sort of reinforcing that decision and
in and um,
you know,
making those choices.
You build up your resistance to doing
things that are negative,
you build up your resistance to
indulging in negative thoughts and in
that sense I think it's good,
like one of the weirdest things is have
you ever seen someone who's never been
in any sort of a conflict type
situation,
but they get thrown into one and they
have a panic attack and they
hyperventilate and they don't know what
to do?
It's very weird.
I've seen it happen many times and then
I've seen other people that are in panic
situations or or rather high stress
situations a lot and they know how to
stay calm and keep cool and I think
sometimes your life can depend on it.
Sure.
Very much so.
As a killer scuba diving,
which I did a lot of panic.
Panic will kill you.
I would imagine.
I'm terrified of scuba diving.
I've never done it,
but I would imagine that being a 100
feet down in the ocean where the winds
are moving occurrence.
Yeah.
Banging you against rocks and stuff.
That's got to be your lays it down there
and you really gone.
Yeah.
That's a.
that's a whole nother world.
I did some snorkeling recently with
dolphins.
I was in Hawaii and uh,
I actually did it with my four year old
to.
I took her with me into the water and
you know,
she had the mask on and everything and
she's like looking down and seeing the
dolphins swimming under us.
It was amazing,
really incredibly rewarding.
Did they come and scan,
you know,
they didn't,
they just swam underneath us,
you know,
they really didn't give a shit about us.
Really kind of one of those weird
looking things up there.
They just,
you know,
it's kind of a,
it's an eyeopener,
like how little of a shit dolphins care.
They don't care about you man,
as long as you're not trying to capture
them,
the more people,
whatever.
Avoid the boat,
you know,
they came near the boat.
I've,
I've been around them though when
they're very playful too,
like we're fishing once and they were
jumping by the boat and being really
playful with us.
This was a totally different experience.
This was,
they just pretty much indifferent but so
beautiful.
Like just being around them,
hundreds of dolphins and you're looking
at him swimming underneath you.
But yeah,
I could imagine that panic in that world
when something goes wrong,
you know,
adapt than an occurrence.
If you panic,
you literally are dad because that's
what you have to stay steady and that's,
that's the power of the mind.
You have to.
It's mind over matter.
You have to impose your mind on that,
on that,
on that situation.
Because I don't know why actually if we
have all this evolution,
why we Pattanaik I would've thought
billions of years of evolution would
have got rid of that terrible dangerous
thinking,
but actually it's there though.
So necessary.
It sharpens your,
your reflexes.
It's one of the things about fighters is
that a fighter going into a fight and
not being nervous can be incredibly
dangerous.
Yes,
and when I was competing,
there were moments that I was too
confident and I went in and I couldn't
compete.
Right.
I didn't,
I couldn't.
And I also couldn't snap myself out of
it.
Like there's a level that you achieve
when you're really nervous and you're
not sure of what the outcome is going to
be there.
Like our,
a level of reaction and of intensity
that you achieve when you go into the,
into a competition where you're scared,
where you perform so much better.
Right?
Right.
And then there's like,
when you're super confident,
you feel there's something that happens
where you're not nervous at all,
you can't get up for it.
It's a weird thing that happens.
So that adrenaline is,
I think it's a necessary component.
It gives you that extra charge.
It's just about managing that and
managing very difficult was interesting.
I watched a told you a few months ago,
I watched this Hixon Gracie,
a movie choke choke and that's one of
the things that he said quite early on
in the movie.
He said,
actually,
he's always afraid.
He doesn't say I'm a field person that
he says,
I'm always afraid.
Yeah.
And,
and yeah,
it's managing,
it's managing that.
What a formidable fighter.
That guy,
he's an amazing guy to,
uh,
we had on the podcast recently,
him and my friend Eddie Bravo together.
It was just a huge treat for me as a
martial arts,
lifelong martial arts practitioner and
fan because he's a real master.
Fascinating,
fascinating.
The guy that documentary.
I recommend that to everybody.
Even people that don't do martial arts
like yourself.
You wait,
how'd you hear about it?
Okay.
Well,
my son in law,
Jason Sarris does mixed martial arts.
He does particularly Brazilian Jujitsu
at a place called Ama clinic in London
and he does it three,
four times a week.
He's very,
very,
very devoted to it.
And he's,
he's been talking me through a lot of
these issues over the last year and,
uh,
I,
I get it.
I get,
I get why he loves it and I think it's
been.
I think it's been a really great thing
for him and I think it's a really,
it's a really great thing for him to be.
There was a time in my life when I did
do a martial art.
I did,
I quito.
Uh,
I got to Brown belt,
uh,
in my very early twenties and then I
quit.
I'm not quite sure why I traveled.
I went away,
I lost the practice,
and then in my forties I went back to it
and I worked my way back up to,
to greenbelt.
But I.
Quito is a different thing from,
from this,
this real grappling.
I mean,
this Brazilian Jujitsu,
what I see is to,
to people who are into locked and
they're sent the sensing each other,
each other's movements all the time is
that you can't,
you can't predict what's going to happen
next in any,
in any way.
And,
and I understand that it's a kind of
meditative thing also that,
that if,
if you actually start thinking,
I imagine because I don't do it,
but this is what my son had low tells
me.
If you start thinking while you're in
there in that grapple with that other
very strong,
very dangerous person,
I don't think that's really good.
I think you have to not,
you have to not be thinking.
You have to be acting somehow on muscle
memory,
on,
on instinct,
on experience.
You're not really thinking through your
next move or are you,
I don't know,
sometimes you're thinking,
but
a lot of times you are reacting on,
in,
uh,
in what you try to do is achieve sort of
a zen state of flow state and when
you're at your best,
you're in that flow state where
sometimes you'll be in a position where
you don't even realize how you achieved
the position.
You just,
you just instinctively did it.
And it's instinctive based on thousands
of repetitions,
many,
many hours of mat time.
Matt,
Matt Time's very important.
Matt time being the actual sparring
itself because the rolling,
the grappling,
sparring,
you understand like the language of,
of human interaction.
Like there's a,
there's an interaction between a person
attacking,
a person defending and there's just like
this thing that goes on.
We kind of figure out,
yes,
this is something that in daily life,
in a modern technological society,
most people have no experience.
So the tool and they never in a,
in a fight situation,
never ever having to having to deal with
that.
So if they suddenly find themselves in a
situation of danger attacked on the
street,
they're not going to have the faintest
idea what to do.
No,
well hopefully that never comes up
anywhere else.
But the benefits extend outside of that,
in my opinion,
the benefits are it's,
it's,
it prepares you for like the drama of
regular life pales in comparison to the
real drama of training and have of
competing inside the gymnasium.
Because essentially every time someone
does Jujitsu,
they're competing.
Every time you spar,
even if you spar with a very good
friend,
he's still competing.
You know,
you get used to this struggle and that's
something that most people don't.
They don't have in their life.
And in,
in having that struggle and in this
competition,
it makes the regular stress that people
go through the stress of bills and have
relationships and it,
it,
it alleviates,
mitigates a lot of the issues that
people have because the life or death
struggle.
If someone trying to choke you and you
battling it out and you're tired,
you're exhausted and you've tried to
remain calm and catch your breath and
defend and trying to stay cool and
trying to figure out what's the proper
defense for this situation and how to
turn this around and how to get back to
a better spot.
Uh,
it's,
it's so harrowing and it's so.
It's so stressful,
but in a good way.
So you're totally in the moment.
Yes.
Oh yeah.
Totally.
In the moment you're thinking about all
the other shit girl you dated when
you're in high school where she now
you're not thinking about that,
you know,
the bills you've got to pay or no,
no,
you're not thinking about any of those
things.
And in that sense it is very meditative.
It alleviates a lot of the stress of
life.
And then when it's over,
you just kind of,
you feel very relaxed because you spent
all this excess energy that I believe
people.
I mean,
this is not a scientific way of looking
at the body,
but I think of the human body and a lot
of ways as sort of like a battery and a
lot of people's batteries are
overflowing with Jews because you don't
use them.
You sit down and sedentary state in
front of a computer all day,
which is pretty bad for your back and
you stare at a screen and you do your
work and then you sit in your car or on
the train or whatever to get home and
then you sit in front of the television.
That's.
That's a lot of people's lives.
Absolutely.
That's not normal for a body.
The body is supposed to be moving while
you're young and alive and why you have
energy.
You're supposed to be.
Your body wants to be involved in
activities.
Your body wants to go hiking and do
things and if he doesn't,
it atrophies and shrivels up and it
stops being functional and when you can
get all that energy out,
I'm in a training session.
It does a couple things.
One,
it strengthens your body,
so if you ever do have to use it for
something,
even just something as simple as like
picking things up or just strength to
help move something you have that,
but to you you alleviate all the excess
energy,
you drain the battery a bit and by
draining the battery you put more juice
in the battery for the future.
Like the battery has like a higher
threshold and then you also like,
you can deal with stuff easier.
Like when I don't train,
if I don't exercise,
if I don't do some sort of rigorous,
rigorous physical exercise,
like at least a few days a week,
I will react differently to stress.
Right.
You start getting snappish and.
Yeah,
well I get more irritated than I should.
I affects me more than it should,
but when,
when I train,
like if I train a lot,
it's everything is pretty easy.
Yeah.
I've seen this effect on my son in law
is a couple of years now of doing this.
He's been,
it's really transformed him.
It's really,
really great thing and they will benefit
from it.
I mean,
I'm 64 years old.
I don't know.
I don't think I can go and do that stuff
now.
I don't know if you found another 64
year old.
Yeah.
Okay.
Or I could work with one with one
personal,
one personal teacher,
you know,
to,
to who would understand my level.
I see it.
I see huge advantages in doing it.
I think it's,
I've got more and more interested in it
over the last couple of years.
It's really fascinating thing.
And also tell me about this.
I mean,
in a way you're being a warrior in there
in a way,
in a way.
It's a warrior thing.
I mean,
this is a contentious issue.
The human race.
We've been around it anatomically modern
form for the last 200,000
years for a lot of time.
Our young men,
um,
in many societies have been,
have been called to warfare in one form
or another.
I would say that it's gone on long
enough for it to be a fundamental part
of the human experience actually,
um,
in our society today,
a lot has a lot,
has worked to move that aside and
probably that's a,
that's a very good thing.
Although we still do have war of course,
but it's done at a distance.
Largely it's done.
It's not.
I mean I'm writing,
I'm writing novels about the Spanish
conquest of Mexico at the moment I am
dealing with,
I'm getting inside the heads of warriors
and those guys are on the battlefield
hand to hand with edged weapons.
That kind of experience of battle and
warfare doesn't happen.
I think much in modern warfare today.
It's,
you know,
it's more that guy remotely part think
piloting a drone and shooting people,
shooting people from it from a distance,
but maybe there is.
Maybe there is a warrior need in us
which,
which can be met in a harmless and
positive way on the mat in something
like mixed martial arts.
That's what I'm coming to.
Which you agree with.
It's very possible that there's
something to that.
I think it's very possible that there's
something to the idea that we have
ingrained in us a certain amount of
experiences based on the genetics of all
the people that have lived before us and
that whatever fight or flight is inside
of us,
whatever mean throughout history like w.
I've been discussing this with friends
like how fascinating this time is
because throughout history,
in the past,
if a boat of stranger showed up,
it was very dangerous.
Yeah.
A boat showed up and you're like,
Holy Shit,
it's gonna.
Get crazy.
A bunch of men climb off the boat.
You gotta hide women and children and
now when a boat shows up,
it's tourism and everybody gets excited
like,
oh,
we need their money.
Come on.
Come to this island.
Come to this place,
bring your family.
It's a completely different world that
we live in.
It is,
and those,
those experiences that led us to,
that led the human race in 2014.
These experiences of people pirates
showing up and Viking showing up and all
those dangerous people showing up in
these different places.
You know,
people coming over the hill on armies
coming.
That was just a part of being a human
being for the longest time for a very
long time.
Have you seen this new thing that was
going on about the,
uh,
the autopsy of a witch King of England
second or we should the third.
Yeah.
They found his bones,
which is really amazing,
man.
They found his bones like they found it
under a,
like a parking lot or parking lot.
Yeah.
Crazy man.
I don't know.
It's him.
I think that there's,
there's a long tradition regarding him
and the battle that he was killed in and
there's a famous,
these even a shakespeare play where he's
at the end of the battle saying famously
my horse,
a horse,
my kingdom for a horse so that he can
flee.
But it seems that he died in face to
face combat was hacked to pieces as far
as like one of the last of the,
the,
the kings to die like that too.
To die in combat.
Yeah,
it would.
We're in those sort of late 14 hundreds
there.
I would say I would say so.
I mean,
combat went on the period I'm writing
about fifth,
early 15.
Hundreds was brutal and bloody brutal
and bloody period at man like hernand.
Cortez is a leader,
but he's a killer.
He's a coldblooded.
He's a cold killer.
I,
I
think that,
that kind of,
that kind of experience is Israel today.
Does it freak you out when you read
stuff about like these these days and
realize that that,
that all could happen today.
We just,
we need the wrong set of events to take
place to where we're not far removed as
a species from that time in terms of the
actual history,
like gets the blink of an eye between
then and now a blink of an eye.
We are the same people.
Nothing's changed.
Um,
there's been some,
there's been some social changes,
but look,
we're still slaughtering people on a
large scale in large scale levels.
It's just that it's just that,
that hand tan face to face thing.
Technology has intervened a little bit
in that.
Um,
if our society were to go into a radical
collapse,
people could find themselves facing
those contingencies very quickly,
very,
very rapidly.
And it is in fact in a radical collapse
and other parts of the world.
I've been talking,
I've been talking about this on stage a
lot lately because there's a lot of
these.
This is duck dynasty guy.
That's hilarious.
It's duck dynasty,
ridiculous American reality show.
But one of the main guys on duck
dynasty,
um,
he gave this speech and it's video
speech where he was talking about the
impending apocalypse and what they call
the rapture.
We Christians think that Jesus is going
to come and he's going to take away
everybody that's Christian and bring
them to heaven and everybody else is
going to be stuck on earth.
I believe that is a very elite group.
We're going to go 144,000
of them are going to be floated with the
idea with the rupture.
And he told people that they should
watch this Nicholas cage movie that's
about to come out and called left
behind.
That's based on this very famous series
of books amongst the Christians have
left behind like these these people
have.
He doesn't use somebody who doesn't get
raptured.
Is that.
Is that the.
I guess?
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's so fucking stupid.
It's so stupid.
It's.
It hurts my brain to talk about it,
but what's fascinating is that they're
all worried about.
Everyone's worried about the apocalypse,
apocalypse,
the end,
but the apocalypse,
if you go to certain parts of the world,
it's there.
It's there.
It's in Liberia right now.
It's in Somalia right now.
Right now.
Listen,
back in the 19 seventies,
I lived in Mogadishu.
I lived in Somalia.
I lived in that,
that failed state.
It was fine place then back then it was
fine.
Yeah,
it was fine.
Why was it fine?
I mean,
this is not politically correct,
but it was run by a dictator and he kept
things come.
You know,
if that has been the case in many
unfortunate scenarios.
I mean,
that's what's argued about Iraq.
And,
uh,
if you look at Iraq before the US
invasion,
it was largely superior to what it is
now,
a vastly superior to what it is now.
Again,
I mean,
we're not,
you know,
kind of not supposed to say these
things,
but honestly,
for the average Iraqi living in Iraq,
things were a whole lot better under
Hussein.
It was peaceful.
It was,
there were,
there was not a lot of interreligious
conflict.
When was the secular state?
It was a secular state.
They in fact,
quite tolerant and,
and all you had to do was not getting
the face of Saddam Hussein.
That was the simple.
That was the simple rule of life.
Just don't get in the face of Saddam
Hussein.
And that was a simple rule of life in
Somalia in the 19 seventies.
Don't get in the face of Siad Barre.
If you do,
I'll tell you a story.
See [inaudible] Muhammad Siad Barre,
who was the president of Somalia when I,
when I went there in 1975,
um,
he,
he did a number of interesting things.
For example,
there's Somali language was not written.
This was a nomadic society,
70 percent nomadic.
He introduced a written script for this
amount of language based on the Latin
alphabet.
This had not been possible before
because religious leaders had said they
had to have it in the Arabic script
because they were Muslims.
He just forced that through.
Then he introduced a family law which
allowed women to divorce their husbands.
At that point,
11 religious leaders,
11 shakes,
mobilize the public and said they had to
rebel against Siad Barre.
Well,
what he did,
he hold those guys out of the mosque the
very same day and shot them all and that
was the.
That was the end of that argument and
suddenly women,
women could divorce their husbands and
the society was very free and very open.
One can't imagine today from the scenes
of horror that we see from Mogadishu
actually how peaceful it was.
So you know,
it may be the case that in some,
in some situations,
and Iraq is definitely another example.
You know,
we in the West are constantly saying,
we must have democracy.
Democracy is a great thing.
Well,
maybe it is a great thing.
At a certain point,
at a certain level,
when you're in a society that's very
sectarian,
very divided into tribal interests,
very divided into different religious
groups.
Maybe it's actually more comfortable if
you have a dictator.
Well,
there's a power vacuum issue that I
think the issue is we civilizations
largely operate on momentum and when
things have been set up in the way that
they have been in Iraq or the way they
have been obviously in Somalia where
there's one guy who's calling all the
shots and they've Kinda got this whole
thing established when that guy's not
there anymore and then everyone's
scrambling to be the new guy.
Everyone's scrambling creates chaos,
absolute hell,
and it creates this intense violence
amongst the people like they are our
Iraq.
The people that are in that civil war
state that they're at now where various
sections of their population are vying
for control of this failed state.
It's horrific.
You have this hideous death cult called
the Islamic state,
which may or may not have been initially
funded and set setup by the United
States of America and it's allies who
knows who.
Who knows,
but it's a death cult and it's just
horrible.
Give it.
Frankly,
I would rather have Saddam Hussein a
then the Islamic state.
Crazy thing to say,
right.
The one evil is better than the other
evil.
These obviously we're.
We're only talking in objective reality
terms here.
We're not.
We're not saying,
hey,
it's okay
to be addicted.
No,
not at all.
It's evil to be a dictator.
Clearly it's the same as a terrible,
so evil and wrong and we don't.
Ideally we moved to a state where a
situation where we have no governments
and where people run their own lives and
peacefully negotiate with one another,
but that isn't the way it's going down
in Iraq and it's not the way it's gone
down in the southern part of Somalia.
Yeah,
that would be ideal,
right?
But it's really hard to run a bunch of
people,
like the idea of a society.
The idea of taking a million people,
500 million people,
whatever the number is,
and having a group of people that adhere
to the best interest of all the folks
that are in that society.
One of the.
Their,
their,
their needs are so varied,
their resources are so varied there.
The fortune in what situation they find
themselves born into is so very.
And then you have the people that are
fortunate,
sons and daughters that are trying to
keep the unfortunate from getting into
their gated community of life.
So much crazy.
And then you can be sure that dictators,
sons and daughters are all very well
looked after in a dictatorship that
always happens.
Like sometimes kids like kids,
it's,
it always the case,
you know,
that they are.
And that then generates feelings of
anger and fury that that is,
that,
that is happening.
But a situation where just bullets are
flying down the street constantly and
you're live.
You live in permanent fear of your life.
Uh,
that's not good either.
Yeah.
The arguments that United States is
funded isis in order to build up support
for an invasion of Saudi Arabia or
Syria,
or rather a really terrifying and more
terrifying because I don't want to look
into it because I don't want to know.
It's a horrible thought.
I don't even want to know.
I know that that kind of shit has
happened before,
so when you see that it's happening now,
you're like,
oh fuck.
Is this really going on?
Is that really what's causing all this
profoundly depressing and the product?
The problem is that we can't really
believe anything that our political
leaders and the west side,
I mean they are.
They have been proven to be a absolute
crooks.
Thieves and liars.
They lie by instinct all the time and
that probably problem with constant
lying at the top levels of politics is
that it pollutes the debate completely.
You suddenly can't believe anything
that's said and that leads to suspicion
of all of all kinds of horrendous
possibilities including the funding and
setting in motion of this isis horror
and it doesn't help when someone like
Julian assange comes along and exposes
all these things that a lot of people
disagree with and what do they do?
They try to get them locked up on some
trumped up charges and export them as if
they were really trying to export him
from,
you know,
to to Sweden and eventually to the
United States because of some sexual
thing that wasn't even seems so violent.
He wasn't even rape.
It was consensual.
Some weird sexual charge.
Like I think they call it surprised sex
or something like that.
It's not.
They're not even calling it rape.
Right.
There's one thing that like if there was
a woman who was saying,
Hey Julian Assan,
she's a piece of shit.
He drugged me,
raped me,
okay,
yeah,
send that guy to Sweden,
but they're not even saying
that if this isn't a charge that makes
any sense.
And the fact that this guy has been
locked up in the embassy in London for
all these years,
it's crazy.
It's crazy.
It was a very crazy situation.
It's really weird to see,
man,
it's really weird to see him on
television doing these skype interviews
and knowing that he's in this embassy
and then the moment he steps out of
that,
they're going to snatch him up.
It's like he's just being protected by
some weird loophole.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well,
you could take,
take,
take sanctuary in an embassy.
At some it's an old.
It's an old law.
You can't leave,
like he's going to have to dig a hole
underneath that motherfucker oil out of
the street and then pop out of a manhole
and a scoop them up in a car and take
them to Costa Rica or somewhere where
they're gonna honor that we live in a
time when they're just that.
Just constant conspiracy theories.
I mean there's even conspiracy theories
about him,
you know,
he is,
that he is part of the problem rather
than part of the course.
All of that,
all of that happens.
Nothing is,
nothing is believed anymore and that the
problem that comes from,
uh,
the proven fact that our political
leaders are actually liars.
The upside to us again and again,
and,
and how can we,
how can we trust them?
How can we entrust ourselves to them
when they,
when they behave in that way,
what's needed is,
is transparency.
What's needed is open.
Do you think the transparency is going
to be an eventuality because of the
Internet?
I think it is right.
I think gets blown wide open.
It's very difficult to keep secrets and
it also erodes faith in the leadership
when like,
is this a democracy?
Is this a representative government or
is it some sort of a weird dictatorship
because of it is a democracy.
Hello?
Fuck,
are you keeping that guy locked up?
How?
How is Julian assange still locked up?
Because I need to know.
Please tell me what exactly he did that
you need to export him to the United
States.
Oh,
he released some information,
which is our information to citizens
that this is not,
you know,
information that should be kept secret
from a king.
It's,
it's,
it's information that someone who was
being paid with tax payer dollars.
I did a bunch of shit that the United
States doesn't agree with.
Everyone was upset by the information
that was released.
Everyone was upset by that video,
that collateral murder video.
Everyone was obsessed by this massive
amount of data that showed there was a
lot of coercion,
a lot of lies.
A lot,
a lot of stuff that we don't agree with
and because of that,
this guy is like public enemy number
one.
Yeah,
that's,
that's so anti what we think of as the
United States.
Completely contrary to everything in the
United States stands for complainant on
that.
And so in answer to your question,
I would say yes,
it is some kind of weird dictatorship
posturing and posing as a,
as a democracy,
because for,
for democracy to be real,
you have to have complete openness of
information.
People must be told the truth,
then they can vote and make decisions on
the basis of facts.
What we actually
have in our society is the continual,
very clever massaging and management of
information,
uh,
this so,
so it ceases to be democracy.
When the voting,
when the voting public are fed,
lies on the basis of which they make
their decisions and vote that,
that isn't democracy anymore.
That is in a way democracies are the
worst kind of dictatorship because they
have this appearance of freedom.
They have this illusion of freedom.
And everybody can say,
well,
it's great because I live in a,
in a democracy,
at least if you live in a dictatorship,
you know you live in a dictatorship and
there are certain parameters that you
have to work your way around.
But when you live in a dictatorship that
is posing as a democracy,
it's more complicated and there were a
lot of people truly believe and act as
if it is a democracy.
But at the very top there's fuckery and
manipulation and coercion and money and
corporate greed and interests and the
military industrial complex that it's
funding all of these maneuvers and it's
people profiting wildly and not to
forget all the big corporations,
big,
big pharmaceutical corporations.
All of this about management of
management of information that we,
that we are given.
So what the Internet offers is the
opportunity for,
for ordinary people who are not part of
the power structure and not running a
big corporation to take power back to
themselves.
And that is,
that is happening and it's happening in
a big way.
And it's very disturbing to the powers
that be.
Yeah,
people want like an instant change.
But it is almost instant the,
the,
the amount of time that we've actually
spent having the Internet has been
pretty brief.
Nineteen 93 ish forest is when I gave
birth yesterday and then like 2014 where
we're at now.
It's really only been around in this
forum for the last decade,
like 2004,
2005 and then social media allowing
people to exchange information and the
heat of political crisis.
And they were,
they've been able to expose things that
are happening in real time that
ordinarily would be protected by the
media.
They would shelter and filter the
information.
Now it's all just coming out and they
can't.
So they have to shut down the whole
fucking internet and some of these
countries which,
which uh,
which is a very difficult,
very difficult thing to do.
Now I've seen the huge shift in power
that this has.
This has introduced.
There was a time as a,
as just my own,
my own small level as an author where I
would have depended on the goodwill of
the big media in order to get my ideas
out there.
And since my ideas of sometimes being
radical and contradictory to the
established order of things,
it was very difficult to do that.
Well,
I don't need the big media anymore.
Right?
Absolutely.
Don't need them.
They're not required at all.
They're redundant as far as I'm
concerned.
What does.
What is?
What is important is the community of
likeminded people that I am.
I am reaching through social social
media through facebook,
through my,
through my website.
Not to say that facebook perfect because
facebook is very problematic and is
itself a large corporation which is
filtering and controlling inflammation,
but at least it's there.
It's something.
There's some excellent things with
facebook though.
One of the excellent things that
everyone is themselves like that is your
facebook account.
This is when you're posting,
this is who you are.
For the most part.
I mean obviously there's some frauds out
there.
Sure.
There are a lot of.
When people are commenting,
they're commenting using their facebook
indeed identity.
Yeah.
So like that's a real person as opposed
to twitter or a lot of message boards
where you getting trolls and lot of
assholes that are posting under fake
names and they just,
there's a lot of people out there that
it's like a sport to them to like to be
Shittier,
to rile people up.
Like that always puzzles me that I kind,
I come across,
I get relatively little of it on my
facebook pages.
I have an author facebook page,
I have a personal facebook page.
I run them both parallel at the same
stuff in both of them.
There's one or two people who kind of
haunt me there and just always want to
say,
just always want to say negative and
unpleasant things.
And my view is go for it guy.
You know,
say those things if you want to,
but you're always going to get that if
you are in the public eye.
And the thing to be aware of is that
it's a tremendous waste of it.
Unless you're actually doing something
evil and someone's trying to expose
something which you're clearly not.
But if you were,
then that kind of makes sense,
like these people are crusaders,
but it,
a lot of them are just what,
what you call haters in the United
States.
And the thing about haters is they're
all losers.
Yes.
There's no one that lives a fulfilled,
successful life with an awesome family,
a great relationship.
They're doing what they want to do for a
living.
They're happy and at peace.
And they also go online and a very
hateful things and shit on people.
You know,
they,
they're,
it's a mess of wasted energy.
Yeah.
Like they're,
you know,
and some people are really good at it
and it's like damn,
if you put that energy into something
productive instead of stocking Graham
Hancock and fucking with them all day,
you could get a lot of shit done.
You exactly.
Probably be a happier person.
Exactly.
So the only answer at the receiving end
of that is not to feed it.
Yeah.
No,
it's not to nourish it with angry or,
or hurting or her responses.
Well,
that's what they're trying to do.
Someone searches shit,
you're fucking books.
I wipe my ass with your book trying to
fuck with you.
Absolutely.
The answer is the answer is some.
Somehow what I try to do sometimes is to
just respond with love,
you know,
just as it's nice if it's true,
if it's real and I tried to do the same
if I can.
Um,
sometimes it's really hard.
It's hard,
but you do also agree.
I,
I definitely feel this about myself,
that some of the,
some of the criticism that I've
received,
even a extreme criticism,
even if it's unbalanced,
I've benefited from.
Oh,
is yes.
Useful?
Yes.
It's useful.
The,
the,
there's,
there's something to learn from that.
It's not that that was saying,
you know,
what doesn't kill you,
makes you stronger.
I mean,
you have to let,
you have to learn from this.
It's out there.
We have to engage in some,
in some way with criticism.
I've received an enormous amount of
criticism from,
from my work and for the suggestion that
was a lost civilization and the work
that I've done on psychedelics and
altered states of consciousness.
Just endless.
It's not,
it's nonstop.
And My,
my view is,
thank you,
thank you for criticizing me.
I appreciate it.
If there are holes in what I'm saying,
if my argument is weak in a particular
area and you're helping me to see that
the right response is gratitude to them,
they really are in a sense working for
you in some way because I mean there's
spin unwarranted criticism that you've
received that have made me rethink a lot
of things I do.
Even if it's unwarranted,
they've made me rethink like what is
the,
what is causing this reaction?
Like what's.
Is there anything that I could have done
differently that could have avoided
that?
Or is this an necessary evil that just
comes with the business and it makes you
think about things in a more complex
way.
And although that might be
uncomfortable,
I think there's some great benefit of
it.
There's some great benefits from it.
And once again it's putting us,
it's putting us into a real social
social situation.
As you say,
these people are real,
you know,
it's like being back in the village in
the old days where where you might be
directly criticized by one or other of
your fellow villages.
Well now our villages,
the whole world and it crosses all
national boundaries and all religious
interest.
It's.
It can be anybody anywhere who who's
taking an interest in us and I'm.
I'm constantly receiving information,
some of it critical,
some of it positive through facebook in
particular through facebook,
which is,
which is very helpful to me and I
really.
I really appreciate it and I tried the
best I can.
I try as much as I can do.
It would be.
I don't,
I don't want to spend my entire day,
morning to night on facebook,
but I try to engage with that.
I try to respond because I realized that
people are giving me that time.
Somebody sends me a link to a story I
haven't ever seen before.
It's really important for my research.
Thank you.
That's really great.
Twitter's giant for that for me.
Just absolutely gigantic.
I've gotten more information from
twitter,
more interesting websites that people
have sent me to,
more interesting articles that people
have sent me to.
Then any other resources that I've ever
been in contact with and it's just
directly because of interacting with
people and when they send me interesting
things,
I retweet them and then you know,
those retweets gets seen by a large
number of people so that people see that
I do that and so they send me more
interesting.
It's really cool in that way.
I like that it's like a establishing a
network in that sense.
It's really a whole new situation which
we've not faced before,
done on a done on a gigantic scale and
and what it means is that information
which used to be strictly controlled and
in the hands of elites is now changing
the power structure of information is
changing entirely and that's a very
potentially a very exciting new time to
live in and great things are coming out
of it and it's easy to say this,
but I think a new consciousness is
dawning in the world.
Actually.
I don't think it's very big yet.
I think the old way of doing things is
still extremely strong,
but people are waking up to that power
and saying,
you know,
I am not simply a to be pushed around
and told what to do by an expert or a
government official or a corporation.
And that's great.
That's great.
I,
I believe you're correct and I think
that it's hard to see while you're in
the middle of it.
Yeah,
because it's all happening while we're,
you know,
we're participating in it.
We are living in a time of extraordinary
rapid,
unbelievable change and when the history
of this time maybe things will settle
down,
maybe they won't,
I don't know,
but when the history of this time comes
to be written,
they'll have to be some perspective on a
200,
300 years from now.
It will be seen as one of the most
extraordinary moments in the whole human
story.
Mr My friend Amber Lyon has an
interesting way of talking about certain
events and one of the things that she
talks about when it comes to a corporate
control of information and like things
on the lines of like the Juliana songs
situation.
She talks about being on the wrong side
of history and I think that's a very
good point that they're the people that
are trying to suppress inflammation in
that way and the information that would
directly affect the lives and not just
but the consciousness of the entire
culture that that's the wrong side of
history and all things are said and
done.
People trying to act in their best
interest currently.
They don't realize like the fucking Jig
is up,
man.
You might be able to hang on and keep
treading water for another three or four
years,
but the Jig is up.
Yeah.
It's like the inquisition was on the
wrong side of history.
You know when it made it made Galileo's
say that actually the sun did revolve
around the earth even though he knew
that the earth moved there.
It's clear that the Galileo was on the
right side of history.
We know that now we've got perspective
on it.
We can look back with hindsight and and
it's the same.
It's the same thing that's happening
today in different ways.
Yeah,
it really is.
It's just,
it's just more.
It's more intense because it's happening
worldwide and it's all happening at the
same time and we're seeing positive and
negative repercussions of it.
Like these failed states that come about
because of Arab spring.
Like everybody says,
let's get rid of the dictator and then
you know,
mark,
Pandora's box is filled and now Libya is
like this and how world hell world.
Syria as a helloworld,
Iraq's a hell world in every case.
Pandora's box has been,
has been opened and the immediate result
has been the things got way worse than
worse than they were before.
And then,
you know,
if we,
if we're talking about the dark side,
the negative side of things as well,
there is this,
this horrible problem of bigoted
religious fundamentalism which is,
which is not confined to the Islamic
world by any means.
I mean,
there are,
there are many Christian bigots as well.
There's a tendency for people cling on
to old and devalued ideas and to have
her have an almost religious for
fanatical commitment to them and be
willing,
I mean,
what idea is worth killing another
fellow human being for because they
don't share your idea of.
I mean,
this is demonic.
It's a horrendous,
horrendous situation that this happened.
I followed a few guys on twitter that
are a part of that whole Islamic state.
There was an article about this guy who
was a rapper who is suspected a rapper
from London suspected of being one of
the guys that beheaded one of the
American journalist.
And um,
I was following his twitter feed.
It's just like his band,
his twitter account,
but it was,
you know,
it was just,
it was so strange to see what's going
on.
And also strange to see his.
There was this thing that was going on
with his interaction with the other,
the other people.
There was this intense camaraderie,
this intense comradery with his other
Islamic warriors.
You know,
that they all looked at it.
Everyone was brothers.
And sisters and everyone was,
you know,
it was all great intensity to all of the
decisions that were being made and great
intensity to the bonds they all had,
you know,
fighting against what they thought was
the evil United States.
And unfortunately there was also some
things that he said that,
you know,
they were talking about.
Everybody's freaking out that one head
got cut off,
one body part got cut off of this one
guy.
But what about the thousands of people
that are blown to bits by these drones
that no one's talking about?
And that's undeniable.
That is undeniable,
that is a,
that is absolutely true.
Two wrongs never make a right,
so they do not.
The fact that the fight that that
happens does not excuse the,
the cold blooded slicing off of fellow
human beings head.
But nevertheless it happens.
It should not.
We should not condemn the one without
condemning the other as well.
Absolutely.
And in fact,
the one you know,
you're talking about one individual as
opposed to thousands of people that have
been killed by drones that are innocent
but completely innocent people who are
so called collateral damage just ripped
upon by,
by our high tech weapons,
you know,
which,
which will be had a person in an,
in an instance slice buddy parts off,
just completely destroy that if you're
lucky,
if you're lucky,
they only break off a few things and
then you have to suffer for the rest of
your life and agonizing pain.
So we have to own this,
we have to take that,
we have to accept that this is,
this is something we do.
We in the West are not innocent of this
barbarity.
We're also part of it is it we,
you know,
that's the real thing.
Well that's the real thing because then
you come back to the question of the
manipulation of public opinion by very
small interest groups who have,
who have a very unbalanced a control of
inflammation,
right?
And then who,
what,
what is,
what is we mean?
If it's not you and it's not.
I mean,
do we take responsibility for people we
don't even know,
doing things that are under the orders
of people we also don't know and under
the influence of corporations,
we're not really exactly sure who's
pulling the strings or how it's getting
done or what politicians are moving,
what pieces into place and the whole
thing is when we take responsibility for
standing by and letting bad shit happen
and not think about it somehow or other,
it didn't fail to fail to act.
When when we know that something really
wrong is being done in our name,
that is.
That is as bad as doing it ourselves.
Have you ever seen the interview?
There's an interview that's out there.
One of the guys that say who was a drone
pilot and he was responsible for don't
know a large number of deaths,
but he would describe what it was like
to be a drone pilot and what it's like
to,
you know,
to to operate these death machines and
fly to the sky and just launched rockets
and how crazy it was and this.
This is a new thing that didn't exist
decades ago.
Didn't exist during the first Gulf War.
There was no drones.
I mean it's this idea of precision
attacks by automated machines that fly
around the Air Launch Hellfire missiles.
I mean,
what a fucking crazy name.
Call them hell fire.
Yeah.
And,
and it becomes like a computer game.
Oh No,
you're looking at it on a screen and
completely detached,
completely,
completely detached from the Mass Med or
that you are in fact inflicting what a
dark world we live in.
We live in a dark.
We live in a dark time and the only,
you know,
the only thing is that there is this
light which is growing.
There is,
there is the capacity for love human
beings.
We are,
we are capable of love it.
It involves detaching ourselves from
controlling orders and actually thinking
as human beings thinking for ourselves.
Very difficult to do.
But it is.
I think it's happening.
I also think that that conflict,
the conflict of battling against the
negative builds up the positive.
Some strange way.
I mean the,
the antiwar movement was really a big
part of what made the hippie movement of
the sixties.
Like that was a lot of it was in
response to the Vietnam War,
this war that people knew to be unjust
and so this flower power,
love,
power movement,
Lsd and marijuana and all that came out
of that.
That very resistance to killing people
that didn't do anything bad to us,
produce this very positive thing,
but then of course that was a then a
counter reaction to them,
which we call the war on drugs,
which slapped down on that and shut it.
Shut it all down again.
I mean,
I know you're not big into supernatural
issues,
but when I look at all of this,
I have to say the gnostics who you know
too.
If I simplify the.
The idea gnostic ideas,
the knowledge we know about gnostic
ideas because a batch of texts were
found buried at a place called not
commodity and Upper Egypt in the air.
The temple of Dendur in Upper Egypt and
they'd been married for 1000,
600 years and they were founded in 1945
and they can contain a complete corpus
of ideas of people who call themselves
the gnostics and they see a dark force
at work in the universe which is which
is seeking to snuff out the divine spark
in humanity and it's a supernatural
force and what they say is that the
entity who we've been taught for the
last 2000 plus years to believe is God.
Doesn't the entered the Abraham,
the god of Abraham who may be called
Yahweh or who may be called Allah,
that that from the gnostic point of
view,
that's not a god at all.
That's a.
that's a demon.
That's a lower level supernatural who's
got this huge inflated ego who wants to
be praised and worshiped,
who's constantly urging his followers
onto acts of violence and war.
And I think it's.
I,
we cannot say there are any facts in
this area.
Maybe it's just the dark side of the
human psyche and maybe it's all
generated by our brains or maybe there
is a supernatural realm,
but I think it's.
I think it's A.
I think gnosticism is a very useful tool
to look at.
The society we live in today,
they believed that there were entities
called Arkansans who are evil angels who
disguise themselves as human beings and
mingle with us to drive us into all
manner of crimes and behavior that is
hostile to the nature of the soul and
that's what I see happening everywhere,
but they believed fundamentally we are
good and that we have this light within
us and that that the way to reveal that
light is through.
It's through knowledge.
That's why the serpent in the garden of
Eden is the good guy in the gnostic
frame of reference.
That's very bizarre.
The serpent being a good guy.
He's the good guy because he's saying to
Adam and eve,
you have to know the difference between
good and evil.
You can't just be these thoughtless meet
creatures you know who are wandering
around in a happy days in the garden.
If you're going to grow and develop,
you have to make choices between good
and evil and it's the tree of knowledge
of good and evil that the serpent
introduces Adam and Eve to and says you
need to eat from that.
And,
and,
and actually I,
I would say this is true.
You do need to.
We are defined by our choices.
It's through our choices that we grow
and if we're ignorant of the context,
how can we help to grow?
Yeah.
And this,
I mean,
the stories of like Adam and eve and
the,
I mean,
all that stuff.
It's,
it's allegorical,
right?
I mean,
it's supposed to be there.
There's,
there's an allegory to certainly an
allegory.
There's.
So there's certainly an,
an allegory that's real serpent,
you know,
I don't read it as a real,
a real apple.
I mean actually for the Gnostics,
it very clearly and definitely it was a
psychedelic mushroom when the gnostics
portray the tree of life and the God
that.
Sorry,
the tree of knowledge of good and evil
in the garden.
It is,
I'm an eater Mascaro.
It's the flag agric.
It is,
it is.
Sometimes there's a Psilocybin,
it is a visionary substance,
which they were say depicting that in a
way from the gnostic point of view
is a necessary part of the liberation of
the spirit that we.
That it.
It's,
it's an an agent for awakening.
That's what the serpent was giving.
Now I know that all the fundamentalist
Christians out there are going to say
hancock is a devil worshiper because
he's saying that the serpent is the good
guy,
but that's what the gnostics said and
there was a deep and ancient study of
the mystery of life and the mystery of
reality.
I've read somewhere,
I don't remember the source,
but I read somewhere where they were
talking about the interpretations of
ancient languages and the translations
from ancient Hebrew,
Aramaic,
all to Greek Latin.
That a lot of things got lost along the
way in the confusion and that one of the
confusions was that the word apple could
could be interpreted also as red and
then it wasn't an apple,
but that it was a red and that red being
the color of the and area that that was.
Why?
Absolutely.
I mean there's folks have to understand
if they,
they've never tried to pay attention to
how people translate ancient languages
and then try to translate them several
times,
not just into,
you know,
from ancient Hebrew to Latin,
but also from Latin degree,
from Greek to English.
There's so much that gets weirded out
along the way.
Like if you've ever taken a phrase from
like a Russian,
a website where you don't know what
they're saying and then put it into like
Google translate and you see the English
version of what they're saying.
Oh my God.
It's so convoluted and confusing because
of the way the structure of their
language is very different.
The grammar that they use is very
different and that it's nothing in
comparison to how different it was in
ancient time.
Yeah.
A lot get lost in translation and the
translator imposes his or her idea of
how things should.
Of course on the,
on the material and many of the texts
that come down to us are highly edited
artifacts which are,
which are actually representing a
particular point of view.
That's why these hidden gnostic texts,
which just lay buried for 1600 years
until they were found in the 19 forties,
are extremely,
extremely interesting.
And,
and actually we don't need to rely on
translations there.
They're worse.
Most of the gnostics were wiped out by
Christianity when Christianity pooled on
the Jackboot of Rome and became the
state religion of the most powerful,
militaristic empire of the ancient
world.
Uh,
it's set about destroying all
competitors and amongst those that
destroyed were the Gnostics,
but certainly they were burnt at the
stake from a very early date,
but some gnostic sects survived and they
have left us images and there are a
number of gnostic churches these guys
saw themselves as Christians.
There are a number of gnostic churches
where they painted the tree of knowledge
of good and evil,
quite specifically as I'm one to
Mascaro.
Yeah.
And,
um,
even in French frescoes,
what does that fresco from like,
uh,
it was,
I don't remember the year,
but it was an Adam and eve portrayal
that showed several different types of
types of mushrooms.
I know that.
And it's Adam and eve clearly standing.
Absolutely.
And it makes you wonder like,
this was in not modern times,
but not 5,000
years ago.
This was like 1200,
eight days,
just like say 800 years ago,
something,
something like that.
We were at the tail end of the last
surviving Gnostics,
the cathars in the southwest of France,
or an example of a,
of a gnostic,
a sect who survived through until the
Catholic church wipe them out with the
so called Albert Jensen Crusades,
a truly horrendous act of ethnic murder
that took place in the 12 hundreds.
So we're actually not that long ago and
things have,
have survived from that time.
And uh,
it's very interesting that,
that they are clearly indicating that
the psychedelic experience is of crucial
importance.
That it's a liberating experience that
allows us to wake up to the true nature
of things.
Now,
of course,
they would do it right.
They would do it in a sacred context.
They would work very hard on the setting
to create the place and the space where
this experience unfolded.
Because that's part of the experience.
The substance on its own is only part of
the story is anybody who's worked with
psychedelics knows the context in which
the experience unfolds is at least as
important and the intent with which you
go into it and what we're seeing now,
again,
history has been obscured from us,
but recent research is showing,
for example,
the famous Eleusinian mysteries in
Greece 2000 years at the temple of
abuses.
It pilgrims came from all over Greece
once a year to undergo and experience
and that experience involve drinking a
brew.
We can now say with absolute certainty
that that was a brew closely.
There were elements in it closely
related to Lsd and that this,
do we know that with absolute,
because the work has been,
the work has been done by Hoffman,
by Gordon Wasson and others.
Um,
there's a,
there's a very detailed study of what
was in that brew.
It was called the Chi on and growing on
the barley that was used in the brew
was,
it was an Erg,
got a,
a form of got a which contained Lsd,
a Mites,
and which was soluble in water.
They've really done the science and
great in great depth and when you read
the accounts,
you know of of great figures from the
ancient world,
people like plato or socrates who went
and had the experience at the earliest
one,
mysteries,
they drink this.
They enter a darkened series of
corridors and passageways and chambers
in this huge,
this huge template and this is light
appears and they start seeing visions.
It's pretty obvious what's going on.
Yeah,
pretty obvious that they were tripping
in some way,
shape or form,
and they saw it as nurturing.
They saw it as nurturing.
They felt that there were several of the
ancients who had this experience and who
said that after having had this
experience,
they lost their fear of death,
that they.
That they understood that it was not,
that it was not the end.
Now we could argue about that,
but that was the experience that they.
That they had.
Yeah.
That's the experience that a lot of
people have when they take asset of the
things that Larry Hagman
said,
who is popular American actor.
He did this interview when he was on CNN
and they were talking to him about death
and he said that lsd completely took
away his fear of death and he just
didn't.
It didn't mean what it meant before.
Just because you realize you're part of
something,
be part of something that's the,
you know,
it is important to have a sense of self
because it's important to brush your
teeth.
It's important to pay attention when
you're driving.
It's important to take care of your
health while you're alive or you'll
suffer some ill consequences,
but it's also important to recognize
that a lot of your need to take care of
yourself can be,
can overwhelm your greater perspective.
The greater perspective of being a part
of everything in that it's not just
about you and the worst cases of of
human beings are the ego's run a muck
like the dictator,
like Saddam Hussein or the anyone who
control.
It's all of them.
It's all about them and you know,
huge insane,
and they cut people down and smash and
destroy and kill and leave horrible,
horrible lives in the wake of their
ridiculous detachment.
From these universal ideas that we are a
part of a giant collective consciousness
and that's,
it's almost impossible to get to that
without something,
whether it's yoga,
whether it's Dmt,
whether it's something that you ingest
that gets you to that understanding that
that understanding is very difficult to
realize with our normal conditioning
than their normal alpha male primate
behavior.
That
the problem solving state of
consciousness,
that's that state of consciousness is
not our friend when it comes to
understanding our place in the wider
scheme of things.
It is a friend in many ways and it's a
good state of consciousness.
But there are so many other states of
consciousness that are,
that are a volume and the need to be so
tough.
Now,
some people are very lucky and they can,
they can get into deeply altered states
of consciousness and,
and see reality in a different way,
uh,
without needing to take any substance.
It's fine,
you know,
or they can get there through meditation
or they can get there through floating
in a flotation tank.
But,
but for a lot of people,
a very powerful vehicle for changing our
perspective on the nature of reality has
been for thousands of years the
psychedelic experience and it's time
that we rehabilitated that and,
and,
and gave it a place in our society.
Well,
I think as you were talking about
earlier that this is a time of great
change.
I think this is a time of great
awakening when it comes to psychedelics.
I was listening to this Guy Sturgill
Simpson.
I tweeted it today.
He's just a country music singer who
sings about dmt.
Oh really?
I hadn't come across some men as country
music,
like old school,
Waylon Jennings style country music if
you're into that.
And I am.
I liked that kind of music.
I've been really into that of the last
couple of years I've gotten.
And I've always been a Johnny Cash fan.
I've always liked dwight yoakam and some
country singers,
but I've gotten into a bunch of other
stuff recently.
But this guy sturgill simpson is like a
big part of what he's saying about
psychedelics and in a country song,
I mean,
incredible stuff.
Yeah.
And I think that that to me just sort of
highlights that this is spreading
through a bunch of different genres,
different art forms.
You see a lot of psychedelic art now,
not just Alex Gray who's the master,
but you see others that are coming
along,
a lot of psychedelic art work.
I see it all the time when I go and
speak at events,
at conferences,
people come to me with their aunt and
I'm seeing.
I'm seeing this trip to huge explosion
of,
of a visionary creativity,
uh,
taking,
taking place.
And I'm constantly meeting people whose
lives have been transformed,
uh,
by,
by these experiences.
And I think a lot of people are getting
informed by guys like you who have
written books on these experiences from
supernatural to your own discussions,
including the one that got banned from
Ted,
ted thing has kind of been exposed as
being this really bizarre,
almost cultish thing that it's done a
lot of.
Great.
Good.
I'm a big fan of a lot of the speakers
that have come on Ted,
but I had Eddie Wong on the show where
he talked about his experience and Ted
where they kicked him out because he
left there to do my podcast.
They wanted them to be a part of this
whole thing all day where you didn't
hang out.
He had to stay in a hotel room with
someone else like they made him.
He's like,
can I get my own hotel room that know
the Ted Experience?
You have to shack up with some fucking
random dude who's talking about physics
or whatever it is.
We want everybody to be together.
It's very difficult.
Scientology,
well,
it's also become intensely profitable
and when things become intensely
profitable and they come to this giant
business,
that's.
That's part of why your talk got banned
from Ted.
Instead of having an open discourse
about agreeing or disagreeing about what
you're saying.
There's nothing wrong with that,
but your ted talk got banned because of
pressure from a bunch of people there
were saying that you start using the
word pseudoscience.
Pseudoscience stop the pseudo science.
Yeah.
There's almost a cult of people that are
afraid of debating ideas that are very
controversial and very difficult to nail
down,
especially when you're talking about the
emergence of consciousness in early man.
Okay.
No one knows how the fuck people got
from hunting things to drawing on cave
walls to experiencing visionary,
a psychedelic states.
But we do know that happened.
It happened.
It happened,
and it's worth talking about it.
Yeah,
we're not.
It's not like 1940,
whatever the fuck it was when people
figured out Iowasca whatever year it
was.
What year was it?
Goes back a very long.
No,
but I mean Western world.
When they.
When Mckenna talked about how they
first,
when they harming,
they wanted to call it telepathy
telepathy,
but they realized that it had already
been been scientifically defined as
harming.
Yeah.
So that was.
What year was that?
That would probably be in 1930.
Somewhere $30 or 40.
Twenty to 20.
And then Watson.
Gordon Wasson was in like the fifties.
It was $50 goes down to Mexico
encounters.
Maria Sabina has a mushroom experience
and that's the beginning of the mushroom
story.
In the West actually,
so that's like modern western culture
and civilization.
This is our introduction to it,
but this shit had been going on for
thousands and thousands and thousands of
years.
So for us to assume that these you,
especially you and I who have had these
psychedelic experiences,
I've never had an Iowaska experience,
but I've had many a dozen dmt trips and
mushroom trips.
Yeah,
there's something there.
There's something there that's
unbelievably intense and to deny that
that had an effect on consciousness of
emerging people crazy.
It's ridiculous.
It's just crazy in my opinion,
very anti scientific.
It's extremely anti scientific.
It is like the modern inquisition,
but it's a weird thing where people are
ignoring that aspect and concentrating
on all the other potential aspects,
which I think probably worked in some
sort of a symbiotic fashion.
Yeah.
The introduction of meat into the Diet,
the,
um,
the experimenting with different food
sources because of the changing of the
climate.
There was a lot of factors that came
into play that made lower hominids human
beings a lot of every evolutionary
factors,
a lot of environmental factors,
a lot of experimental factors.
Um,
a lot of things happened where there was
some benefits to certain types of
behavior and those people survived and
then things evolved and changed.
And then boom,
we have Graham Hancock here at 2014
sitting in front of his apple laptop.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean,
there was a lot of things had to take
place a lot.
It was a,
it was a very complicated process,
but I'm absolutely sure that
psychedelics were a key word,
a key part of it.
Everyone who's taken psychedelics is
pretty sure that it was a key part.
You know,
why?
Because you've had the experience and
everyone who doesn't.
If you haven't had a psychedelic
experience and you're talking about
psychedelic experiences being not a
factor,
a noneffective,
you're crazy.
Yeah.
You'd be better to shut up.
Well,
it's just nonsense because they have
people who have not had the,
had the experience at all.
I just don't even in my view,
need to come to the table because
they've got nothing to bring to the
discussion.
I don't mind if they come to the table,
but I find their arguments to be almost
hilarious.
Yeah,
it's like I have a very good friend
who's a very intelligent guy and he's
never taken any drugs and his take on it
is,
and he's a brilliant guy,
loved talking to him,
but his take on it is simply a,
all the work's been done.
There's no,
I'm not going to learn anything new from
that.
And I'm like,
well that's so crazy.
Yeah,
I'll just say his name,
Penn Jillette Rice.
I love that guy,
but it was the same,
but he doesn't do any drugs.
It doesn't do anything.
Right,
and he feels that there is no need for
him to say it's all been figured out
with all the work's been done.
I'm like,
Oh God,
dude,
let me get you high on Dmt last 15
minutes and you tell me what work's been
done.
See,
that's,
that's what's so I think what's so
special about dmt in particular is that
there is that there is no negotiation
with the experience.
There are very few people who can resist
it.
Once you hit the hit the threshold
because it dose and it's going to take
you where it where it takes you a.
Then you are confronted by one of the
most intense and extraordinary
experiences that it is possible for any
human being to have.
Yes,
we can jump out of an airplane at 10,000
feet.
Yes,
we can scale a sheer cliff.
That's also very intense and very,
very extraordinary.
Yes,
we can go scuba diving to the depths,
but if we look at the whole range of
human experiences and say what is one of
the most intense and potentially most
transformative experiences as possible
to have,
I would say dmt done with the right
intention and the right context is right
up there with anything else.
It's the most intense thing I've ever
experienced.
Me Too.
I mean,
I haven't experienced everything.
Obviously.
I've never been scuba diving.
I've never been skydiving and it doesn't
mean that those things aren't intense as
well,
but to deny the impact of those things,
it seems silly and the people that are
arguing against the,
the,
the efficacy of these experiences or
against the influence of these
experiences to have those people
actually have never haven't had taken
these experiences arguing against them.
It seems so silly.
It's crazy.
It's crazy that they're scared of them,
but it's those people are who are
running the rules in our society still.
Yeah.
Well if they,
if they weren't there would be really
terrifying.
If our society was wrong in the way it
is now by a bunch of people doing dmt,
you'd be like,
what the fuck?
Yeah,
but that,
that's one thing we can be quite sure if
our society was run by a bunch of people
doing dmt.
It wouldn't be running the way that it's
run.
No,
it wasn't.
Well,
you know,
Makenna found out about dmt by a friend
who is a scientist to work with the army
research lab and they had like a barrel
of the stuff,
they had a fucking barrel of emt.
And if anyone,
if you've,
DMT is,
it's very small doses,
they're tiny,
transformative.
These tiny little doses that you smoke
take you into these incredible realm.
So the idea of a barrel.
Yes,
or Lsd,
I mean the Mckenna described Lsd and the
best way I've ever heard is that the
amount of Lsd you need for it to be
effective is like an ant that can break
down the empire state building in 30
minutes,
like exact,
literally that little.
He was a great genius.
And it's um,
it's very fortunate.
Again,
we have the Internet and the Terence
Mckenna is his passed in the year 2000.
He's still,
he's still with us and his and he is
having this liberating effect on people
all around the world.
And he had the gift.
He had the gift of language.
He spoke in a such a compelling way.
I love listening to parents.
I do too.
Bill Hicks,
you know,
the two of them together,
just amazed,
and Hicks was a huge fan of Mckenna and
became,
I found out about Mckenna because of him
because there was a joke where I'm Hicks
said,
uh,
something about leaving mushrooms under
the,
um,
under the table of all these people,
take it and it he said what Terence
Mckenna would describe as a heroic dose.
I don't remember saying who the fuck is
Terence Mckenna?
And so then I wasn't even a google back
then.
I searched Terence Mckenna because of
hearing about it on Bill Hicks.
And then I got ahold of some of the,
um,
the uh,
audio recordings and then you listened
to the guy's voice.
It's like,
wow,
what a weird guy,
you know,
weird,
interesting,
compelling way of communicating credible
use of language a which just makes you
think all the,
all the time.
That's the service he's providing for
all of us still.
Yeah.
I mean,
he missed the mark on that December 21st
2012 showed everybody did at.
Everybody's got to miss the mark.
Guy Used to get high a lot and come up
with the cool theories and things to
think about and when you're postulating
and thinking about the future.
Here's the thing about thinking about
the future.
No one's ever got it right.
No,
no one has ever figured out the future.
There's not a single fucking person ever
sat down anybody to get it right.
Nobody got it right.
The future is.
The future is indeterminate.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
I mean,
talking about psychedelics,
the what's happening with cannabis in
the United States right now is,
is very,
is very interesting to me coming from
coming from Britain where you know,
nobody has ever even willing to
contemplate the legalization or the
direct striction of cannabis,
but in America state by state,
people are voting with their feet and
the barriers of being,
uh,
being broken down.
I mean,
America has been the huge dark force
behind the war on drugs all over the
world for the last 40 or 50 years.
So many countries around the world have
just blindly followed the American lead.
That's the American government.
That's the American power structure.
But the American people are saying,
no,
the American people are saying,
actually we want to smoke cannabis and
we find it positive and nurturing for us
and state by state,
either it's being decriminalized or
medical Mariajuana is available or it's
actually being legalized in a number of
cases.
This is a big change.
Again,
there's all kinds of conspiracy theories
like how Monsanto's going to take it
over and so on and so forth,
but I see it as a really good thing that
these barriers in the heartland of the
war of drugs are being broken down by
the American people themselves and I say
Kudos to the American people for getting
on and making that happen because it's
going to be a benefit to the whole
world.
Yeah.
Warren Buffet is starting to get into
the marijuana trade.
Oh yeah.
That's when things are going to get
freaky because then you got a guy who's
worth $90,
million dollars or whatever the hell
he's worth.
That's when things can get very
interesting.
Well,
sure.
I mean people are going to.
People are going to make commercial
advantage of this,
but at the end of the day I just come
back to,
this is something that I've said again
and again,
as the years have gone have gone by,
for me,
the fundamental issue is the right of
the adult
to make sovereign decisions about their
own consciousness and one of those
sovereign decisions has to be the right
to use cannabis or not to use it,
but one must be free to make that
decision and not and not controlled by
society and once that is recognized,
once all the scare stories about
cannabis go away and we find that in
fact state by state,
it's a.
it's a positive rather than a harmful
thing.
I think that the question marks are
going to begin to arise over the
psychedelics to and and we're going to.
We're going to see all those barriers
breaking down in the years to come.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
I think the bringing up Warren Buffett
and Warren Buffet's company specifically
what's happening is he's a part of this
company.
He says its subsidiary,
subsidiary,
subsidiary of Berkshire hathaway has
this company called cubic designs and
they sell the maximize usable floor
space in warehouses and they sent a
thousand flyers to weed dispensary's in
recent weeks and these flyers,
they show these medical marijuana grow
ops and it's like double your users
growing.
This is fucking like,
this is intense stuff because it's
companies that are real estate holders
that have giant amounts of,
um,
of,
of money invested in this that are
saying,
you know,
what we're going to dip our feet into
this is growing marijuana industry.
And.
Exactly.
I have a friend who works at a
dispensary in Colorado and the
dispensary is five acres indoor.
Wow.
Five acres.
That's great.
That's an enormous building and it's all
pot.
It's just millions of dollars in
marijuana and there's people that are
there.
This has only been less than a year.
I mean it was made legal last January
and here we are.
We're talking right now.
It is September of 2014.
This is a crazy thing.
I just did my comedy special in Denver
and I hadn't been at Denver and while
the places changed and it's like
marijuana is a huge part of the culture
now.
People are moving,
there's marijuana tourism,
people are moving there for marijuana.
They're moving there to be a part of the
marijuana business because you can get
really fucking rich right now because
there's a lot of people that are not
sure what's gonna Happen federally
because it's still illegal federally,
so they're not sure whether or not they
want to dive into it yet,
but the people that are bold that are
willing to take a risk or making insane
profits a chance of making a sheehan
from it and the government is making a
lot of money to 39 percent of the
profits go to taxes.
Wow.
So every marijuana joint that's gets
sold 39.
If it's sold for a dollar thirty nine
cents,
no one's selling for a dollar,
but if it's sold for $100,
$39 is going to the government.
So they're making over $100,000,000
this year in taxes just in Colorado.
Yeah.
State government.
Yes,
and so they're looking at this by the
federal government is not reaping the
revenues.
It's no
because it's illegal,
it's illegal,
but they're finally allowing the people
to put their money in banks,
which was a long time.
They had to do this weird shit where
they had to like put it in safe deposit
boxes or they had to buy,
take the cash and then use it to buy
bank notes and the like by bank checks,
it's very strange.
They weren't allowing them to use credit
cards or any of the normal ways that
people do business that keep them from
being robbed at gunpoint by criminals,
untrackable bills,
so they had these kids that were driving
around with stacks of cash is really
dangerous and scary,
very dangerous and scary,
but it's very.
It's very good that the goal of this is
changing and I can only see it as a good
thing.
I don't see any.
I don't see any downside in it.
It's a really,
really positive development that's
taking this taking place.
I agree,
and I think it's also a part of this
whole movement that you and I were
talking about where the world is
changing,
information is out there,
people are just not prepared to put up
with that fucking shit and he longer and
not prepared to put up with it,
to be told what to think,
to be told what to do with their own,
with their own consciousness,
and it's great that that it's Americans
who are leading the way in this and that
and the rest of the world is watching
and all the lies we've been told about
cannabis,
they're going to just drift away and be
wrecked and destroyed forever by what's
happening in America.
So it's a great service that's being,
that's being done to the world.
As you know,
I had my own longterm relationship with
cannabis.
I smoked cannabis for 24 years.
I overindulged.
I undoubtedly abused my relationship
with cannabis.
I don't blame the cannabis for that.
It was me.
I was.
I was crazy.
A little crazy.
I mean,
it's very crazy to,
to smoke it from nine in the morning
until 2:00
the next morning,
seven days a week of rather vaporize it
as I as I did,
and I reached a point thanks to a series
of Iowasca journeys in October 2011
where I made the decision that I
wouldn't smoke cannabis and it's three
years have come since then,
but I want to live in a society where I
and fellow adults are free to choose
either to use cannabis or not to use it
without any state agent sticking their
nose in our private business.
This is,
this is our private business,
what we do with our own consciousness
and,
and it's incredibly encouraging to see
that the Americans are taking that power
back and showing the rest of the world
how to do it.
And also,
um,
antipop doctors are being exposed.
It's really fascinating.
All these doctors that are paid off by
pharmaceutical companies.
There was an article recently about pot
doctors being paid off and all of the
leading pot,
like antipop doctors,
all of them taking it.
Oh yeah.
All of them.
Why am I not surprised?
Well,
it's interesting that guys like Sanjay
Gupta who used to do that,
we used to be on board with that now has
come out,
come out in a huge way and he's also
starting to address psychedelics
starting to address what's going on with
psilocybin
and there's the new study that's shown,
these people that took psilocybin and
quit smoking six months later,
80 percent of them,
some,
some large number,
70 or 80 percent quit smoking and didn't
go back to it.
Yeah.
Because of just the clarity of those
visions where you kind of understand
like what am I doing to get that
perspective on your,
on yourself here and that's,
that's the,
that's the big news.
You know that these,
that these things are positive and
beneficial and the way forward for
society is to create a positive social
environment and positive spaces in which
in which we can explore these
experiences and the result for society
as a whole will be very positive and
very convinced of that.
Vice Dot com is the guy who broke the
story.
It's incredible and it's all these
different doctors that have like,
here's one Dr Herbert Keebler of a club
or clever of Columbia University.
He's been impeccable.
Academic credentials has been quoted in
the press and academic publications
warning against the use of marijuana,
which he stresses may cause wide ranging
addiction.
That's my favorite wide ranging
addiction and public health issues when
he's writing his antipop opinion pieces
for CBS News.
CBS News are being quoted by NBR and
CNBC.
What's left unsaid is that clever has
served as a paid consultant to leading
prescription drug companies,
including purdue Pharma,
the maker of Oxycontin,
Reckitt Bank bank,
Kaiser,
the producer of painkiller called
neurofen and out comers Alker Mez the
producer of a powerful new opiod called
Z o h,
why dro?
How do you say that?
Zohydro Zohydro,
I guess I can't count.
And what you say is what?
What,
what,
what?
He's,
what he's been hiding and covering up is
that all this stuff he's pushing.
That's the real addictive drugs will pay
10,000
deaths a year.
It's a multi billion dollar business
that causes 16 deaths a year.
Just in this,
this sixteen thousand sixteen thousand
deaths a year stunning and a doctors are
on the take to keep promoting that and
to stop us exercising our free choice as
adults to manage our pain in other ways.
For example,
with cannabis,
and even if it did,
it was just 16 desk.
Obviously.
I agree.
Sixteen thousand 16 desks that 16 more
than cannabis causing zero.
Cannabis doesn't kill any.
That's the most ridiculous thing ever.
Like you could die from aspirin.
A lot of people die every year from
aspirin and a lot of people die every
year from salt.
Too much salt and they die absolutely
drink too.
We have a painkiller,
I think you'd call it a set,
a set to a fan.
He said,
America,
we call it paracetamol in in England and
had reflux.
You liver.
Oh,
it's really,
really dangerous.
Dangerous thing and,
and,
and once it reaches a certain level,
there is no recovery from it and it
kills thousands.
Thousands of people.
A year while I was reading this thing
about bodybuilder or watching a video
rather about bodybuilding and this guy
was being interviewed who used to be
this big competitive bodybuilder and
they're talking to all the drugs that
you have to take to get so big,
but one of the things you were talking
about was that what really kills these
guys is not the steroids.
It's painkillers,
right?
They all get hooked on painkillers
because they're in pain all the time
because they're lifting all this crazy
weight and fuck fucking up their body
while they're doing it and they take
Acetaminophen.
All these different values,
percosets and that stuff.
It just destroys their kidneys.
Destroys your liver.
Kidneys.
Yeah.
It's withdrawal symptom from stopping.
Taking the painkiller is huge amount of
pain,
so you then go and take more,
more painkillers.
These are highly,
highly addictive,
highly,
highly dangerous drugs.
Yeah,
and state sanctioned.
Taken out.
Totally,
totally state show.
So I'm wondering now,
three years after I gave up cannabis,
whether back in dip my toes back in the
water in there in a respectful way,
not,
not do it every day,
have some sacred moments.
I value the sensual side of it.
I don't know.
I'm,
I'm the next time I have an eyewash
station I'm going to,
I'm going to ask a Iowasca is going to
be my intent because that was Iowasca
that really interrupted by cannabis
habit.
I'm going to ask,
is there a way I can do this?
I don't know.
Maybe that's weak of me.
I've wondered this.
You know,
I was talking with a friend last night
and he said there is a true addict
speaking.
You know,
I said this because it sounds a bit.
It sounds a bit like that,
but I,
I did volume cannabis.
It was,
it was an extraordinary positive thing
for me in many,
many ways.
And I,
I.
What I feel is that I got out of balance
with it and if I could,
if I could find that balance again and
use it rarely at special times,
then I think it would be okay.
But I'm,
I'm,
I'm a little afraid to go back there.
Well,
you should be afraid,
right?
You know,
because you've had personal experience
with addiction.
And I think that addiction is purely
mental.
It's purely metal because it was very
easy to stop.
Once Iowasca gave me the message and I
really got that.
I,
I had a severe kicking first of all,
a DMT trip.
Then immediately afterwards,
five Iowasca sessions I was,
I was psychologically beaten up and the
message of that beating was you have to
stop smoking cannabis and,
and uh,
and,
and I did.
And looking back on it,
it's absurd to,
this is a very,
very powerful a plant agent.
And here I am,
you know,
vaporizing it 16 hours a day,
seven days a week.
You went deep.
I went deep.
I went,
I went very deep.
And,
and,
but,
and it got to the point where I wasn't
enjoying it anymore where I just felt
that I couldn't live my life without it,
but I discovered I easily could live my
life without it.
When I stopped,
it wasn't a huge chore,
a problem to stop.
It wasn't actually difficult and then
that sense I would definitely was not
physically addicted to it.
Yeah.
That's the thing is that I think there's
some people that do get physically
addicted.
I'm not,
you know,
I used to say marijuana is not addictive
and I don't think it is with most
people,
but I think biological diversity of
biodiversity in human beings is such
that there's certain folks that have
weird reactions to all kinds of shows
and things.
Cats,
some people around cats like my friend
Gary,
he can't even come over my house because
I have two cats.
If he walks in the door he was
targeting,
gets as wheezing.
You can't breathe.
Like he has to get out of there.
They kill him with a room of cats.
But then I got my friend Joey Diaz who
has,
what is y'all 11?
I think he has 11 cats,
so motherfucker has 11 credits.
Yeah,
but if you.
If my friend Gary went over my friend
show his house,
he would.
He would die.
Yeah,
but Joey's having a party over there.
He's got cats on his lap.
He's pet numb.
They're sitting on his shoulders.
We're all.
We're all different than what works for
one person,
doesn't,
doesn't work for another,
and that's again,
why,
why this issue of adult sovereignty of
us having the right to make our choices
about our own bodies is fundamental and
and actually with the psychedelics and
the cannabis issue,
that's just the tip of the iceberg of
the whole issue of health and personal
health and how our society is working to
take away our choices over our personal
health and to turn us into robots who
consume the products that are pumped at
us by the big pharmaceutical companies
or who are inventing every year this
unholy alliance with psychiatrists and
venting every year.
New mental conditions for which new
pills will be.
Will be dosed out.
Yeah.
In England,
you guys don't have those commercials
either.
Those commercials are so fucking
insidious.
Ask Your doctor about this drug that
might cause you to shit yourself all day
long.
Commit suicide,
suicide.
The big untold story about
antidepressants,
the antidepressants caused people to
kill themselves.
How about antidepressants that
supplement the antidepressing
antidepressants like there's certain
antidepressant,
I forget what it was called.
It had insane side effects that they
were promoting as a supplement to your
regular antidepressant.
Regular antidepressants isn't doing it
until you sit up with this one,
but this one could cause fucking kidney
failure.
Your Dick might fly across the room like
a mocking bird.
We didn't think anything could happen to
you,
but you might not be depressed or you
might just take our pills.
These other doctors,
drug dealers,
these are the true matthew of drugs.
Well,
it's also the idea of commercials.
Commercials are influential and the
influence of commercials is very
insidious because there's one thing if a
commercial is influencing you to buy a
particular vacuum cleaner,
but that doesn't bother me man.
This is the best it look.
If you're,
if you're too much of a knucklehead to
go and consumer reports or you know,
go to read reviews online by independent
people that tell you this vacuum cleaner
is great,
this vacuum cleaner sucks.
If you're too much of a knucklehead to
do that,
I don't feel bad for the executive,
but when it comes to consciousness,
when it comes to pills,
especially when it comes to happiness,
man,
because that's the big one.
Antidepressants,
they should we call them happy pills.
You know,
I wrote an article a long time ago from
my blog about happy pills.
I called it happy pills and it was about
this,
uh,
this girl who was taking these,
these antidepressants.
And I think that the selling of
happiness in pill form is the ultimate
ridiculous American notion.
It's horrible.
Uh,
it,
it's,
it's suggesting that the onset does not
lie within that,
that it can be bought,
that happiness can be bold.
But I think that the ultimate delusion
also what's insidious about it is
selling it on television like that does
a huge disservice to the actual people
that could use antidepressants because
they have a real mental imbalance.
Sure,
there's people that do do that.
So like you're selling it as an antidote
for a shit life where there's other
folks that might have a real issue.
They have an imbalanced huge chemical
imbalance in the brain and that can be
adjusted and adjusted and make their
life wonderful.
People that have a miserable life,
they can make their life wonderful,
but instead were people will trivialize
it because you see a commercial or a
chicken running around a field of wheat
and spinning around with her baby and
then someone says,
I want to live like that.
And then they called her a fucking
doctor and next thing you know,
you're on a pill that you didn't need.
If you just start eating vegetables and
going jogging every day,
you'd be way happier person than you
were on that pill.
And again,
let me,
let me say right,
I outright that the psychedelics are
very effective antidepressants.
Psilocybin being trial tested in humans,
communities for thousands and thousands
of years,
Iowaska and the Amazon,
at least 4,000
years of use,
and anybody who's worked with psilocybin
or or IOWASCA enough,
we'll know that,
that they do help with mood,
they do,
they do help you take a more positive
outlook on outlook,
on life and and whether that's to do
with altering the chemical balance in
the brain because they do work on the
serotonin system in the brain chemically
or whether it's to do with the
revelation that one has,
that life is an incredible gift and
incredible joy and a privilege to be to
be alive.
This is,
this is what we forget,
immersed in the cares and woes of daily
life,
constantly struggling to meet the next,
to pay the bills,
to to get on in,
in work would relentlessly driven to
produce and consume and we forget that
it's a magical,
enchanted,
gorgeous,
glorious universe that we live in and we
have this amazing bodies and we should
just celebrate every minute of it.
Psychedelics help with that too.
Yeah,
it's hard.
It's hard to keep a balanced
perspective,
but it's.
I think it's also important to realize
that perspective shifting consciousness,
shifting experiences can also change the
way you look at the world and when you
change the way you look at the world,
it can adjust the way your brain
functions and that it's not an either or
situation.
It's a Kombucha Tory situation.
Sure,
they might affect your brain in a very
chemical way,
but also just the altering of a
perspective could enhance your mood and
it can enhance the way your body and
brain function because the mind is what
we are.
We are our minds.
The mind is the most powerful,
the most powerful thing,
and that's where all healing,
I believe resides.
It resides.
It resides in the mind.
If you can kick in the body's ability to
heal itself through right mental
attitude,
no,
no medicine will do that for you,
and that's why placebos actually work.
You know?
That's why they worked better than than
the prescription drugs that had been
tested.
Again,
they don't work better than prescription
drugs,
but occasionally they do do just the
fact that they work at all.
The placebo effect is not nearly as
effective as medicine,
right,
in most cases,
but just the fact that it does work at
all,
that there's a way that you can tell
your body to make itself better and the
way is by tricking it to thinking as
taking medicine.
Look,
you're going to be better.
I'm going to be better.
The alleviation of stress and
anticipation of this horrible demise
that your impending doom that you can
escape with a sugar pill.
That's incredible.
It's incredible.
It says something about the mind set and
it's something really worth looking at
that further that is enhanced in
psychedelic experiences.
Perspective enhancing aspects of that I
do believe can change your overall
health or change overall consciousness,
which can change your overall health.
Yeah.
There's a lot going on man,
and I think these conversations are
super important for people that are
uninitiated and that haven't.
They don't understand what the.
What's the Hoopla about?
Why is everybody got down with that
Rogan's going on about drugs again,
I know I.
I have.
I have a constituency of my readers and
people who follow me on facebook who are
constantly throwing handcuffs or a
druggie and pass at me,
and I just feel this is really
important.
It's a really important conversation to
have and fundamentally get right down to
the bottom of what it's about.
It's about this whole issue of us taking
back power over ourselves.
That's what it's really about and the
and it needs to be seen in that,
in that context,
to make decisions about our own lives,
right or wrong,
and to learn from our mistakes and to
grow and develop as a result.
I think it's also super important that
you discussed your relationship with
cannabis in an abusive way too,
that there's a balance to be achieved.
There's a balance to be achieved for all
of us.
Sort of a strange.
That's what.
That's what I've.
That's what I've learned in a way I.
I had to deny myself this wonderful
sense you'll plant,
which helped me to enjoy food and music
and many other essential plays.
Sax.
Absolutely.
You've never had socks on pot.
You know what I mean?
What you're talking about.
I don't even know what led Zepplin
sounds like.
Exactly.
It's a beautiful sense.
You will ally,
and I've had to deny myself.
That sends you an ally for the last
three years because I abused it because
I might spark up a joint right now.
Want
to dive in right now?
Of course the jail.
You're like,
you're like the,
the garden of didn't sure you want.
Yes.
You sure?
Why not?
I don't want to force you into anything.
You're not.
You're not forcing me.
It's an interesting expand now.
Now.
No,
no,
no.
Not that.
I'm going to go.
I'm going to go live on Joe Rogan.
Is that bad?
No,
that's not bad.
That's the way to do it.
If you want to dive in,
we'll go a little baby.
Hit little baby.
Little Baby.
My first baby hit in three years.
Nothing crazy.
Nobody has to get hurt here.
Okay.
You were showing some images from
Lebanon before the POC.
What have you gotten into?
Well,
not by the time I smoked this little
baby hit.
I'll,
I'll probably have forgotten.
But um,
so what I was getting into was,
um,
this,
this fella here,
American shit too.
That's not that crappy getting England
that's made by American scientists and
botanists.
They all drive muscle cars and they do
steroids.
So familiar.
That's such a nice feeling.
That's,
that's back.
Can we,
are we seeing on the screen?
That is.
You're going in for another baby hit.
She's a little tiny.
That's it.
Stop right there.
Right you to get confused on the way
back.
We will see.
So here it is.
Lebanon.
This is the um,
this is what is called the stone of the
pregnant woman.
Whoa.
I fall back.
That's the level on top of that is me on
top of that can be a power point
demonstration.
So we see it.
But this,
this little,
this little tiny dark up here on top of
that.
That's me in Lebanon.
And is this a recent in July?
Yes.
I was there and I was there in July.
People say that Lebanon is very
dangerous and this place is right on the
Syrian border.
But I didn't see any danger there at
all.
I had a,
I had a magical experience in Lebanon.
It was great.
It was exciting.
It was for you,
it must be incredible because that's a
sight of so many ancient,
huge monolithic structures that are
unexplained as far as our construction
methods are.
So the temple of Jupiter at Baalbek in
Temple of Jupiter,
this is what they call it.
It's a rough.
There's undoubtedly a Roman temple.
They're okay.
And that Roman temple dates from the
known historical periods some two,
300 years after Christ.
It's the Roman temple of Jupiter and
it's very extraordinary,
but it stands on these huge foundations.
There's a group of stones called three
stones called the tree lithium,
which are,
um,
each weighing 840 tons,
840 tons.
What the fuck?
And they are lifted to 20 feet above the
ground and built into a wall of sat on
top of one of those stones.
I've been done underneath it and looked
up at it to 840 ton stones.
This is this gigantic achievement.
Now the Orthodox view is that the Romans
did everything that they,
they built those foundations and they,
the temple I think,
and many researchers who have studied
them in this field would agree with me
on this,
that actually the Romans found a much
more ancient site and they,
which was just extraordinarily
megalithic gigantic stones and they
built their temple on top of it and
later historians have simply given the
whole thing to the Romans without
considering,
uh,
what was,
what was going on there?
And part of the reason I think that is
because of these stones that are still
in the quarry,
which I was trying to.
I don't know if it showed up on the
screen.
I was trying.
I got it.
You got it.
I'm trying to show it,
you know,
I'm trying to show it just now.
These stones stood in the quarry.
Okay.
Now,
so what the historians say is that the
Romans.
Okay.
They found they could move the 840 ton
stones.
That's 1 million.
Six hundred and 80,000
pounds for people who don't like the
word ton.
You've got your calculator going back
to.
Because it didn't make sense.
I was trying to double it,
but it's not double.
It's two pounds,
2000 pounds.
It's a number.
Whatever it is.
It's just a CSM number is 6,000
pounds for every ton.
So I was going eight to 2000 for each.
What?
Eight hundred 40 times 2000.
Is that real?
And then that's where it is.
That's what it is.
Now a million.
So here's the thing,
those are the 840 ton blocks in the
walls in the foundation of the temple.
Then we go to the quarry and we find
this humongous thing which weighs over
1000 tons.
And there's another one on the other
side of the road which was 1,200
tubs.
One thousand two,
one thousand two hundred thousand to 2
million.
Four hundred thousand pounds.
Yeah.
So here's a fuck.
So here's the theory.
Okay.
The Romans,
the Romans found they could move the 840
ton blocks and they did.
This is the orthodox theory and then
they built their temple on top of it,
but they found they couldn't move these
thousand or 1,200
plus ton blocks,
and by the way,
this one is completely separated from
the bedrock of which has been caught.
They couldn't move them so they left
them in the quarry.
I think that actually proves that the
Romans didn't create the 840 ton
megaliths because if the Romans had
known that these gigantic blocks in the.
If they had cut the blocks,
okay,
if they had cut them themselves,
which we must say they did.
If we are saying that the Romans were
responsible for these mega list,
if the Romans had cut these blocks
themselves,
they knew they were there and the very
first thing they would have used for the
smaller blocks that they put into place
in the temple of Jupiter was these large
blocks.
They would have sliced them up like a
loaf of bread into smaller blocks and
move those over to the temples.
The fact that these huge megaliths still
standing in the quarry suggest to me
that they were buried when the Romans
came to that site because otherwise it
would have been the very first thing
they would have used for quarrying
smaller blocks that they were buried and
that the Romans found an existing
prehistoric megalithic platform.
And on top of it they built their temple
of Jupiter.
That's fascinating theory.
Um,
it's,
it seems like open to interpretation to
me.
Sure.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Because you're looking at.
But we'll either,
you know,
regardless of why they built the one.
What is it?
1,000,000?
Jesus Christ.
2 million.
400,000.
It freaky when you done in pounds.
That's insane.
Yeah.
When you do it in tons,
it's abstract.
Twelve hundred tons.
Okay.
What does that mean?
You know,
it's hard for my head.
Well,
let's consider,
bless.
Consider an average vehicle which might.
Wait,
let's,
let's push in pounds.
So it's about two tons,
right?
Is that about the weight of an average
vehicle?
So two tons divide a thousand by that.
So you're looking at 500 family sized
cars under a thousand,
10,000
tons.
Oh my God,
it's just the imagining a 2 million
pound rock and a bunch of dudes are
moving it and we know that someone at
some time in history they built that.
They moved those stones.
I mean it wasn't that one,
right?
It wasn't.
It was.
What was the first calculation that we
had?
What did we say?
It was 640 times is that there's three
blocks of 800,
84.
I joined so closely that you can't slip
a sheet of paper between them.
I mean they've not been just roughly
leave it into place.
They'd been set down with perfect with
perfect precision.
So someone did that.
We know that.
What did that?
And there are plenty of people arguing
that the Romans did it.
I feel along along with other
researchers have approached this a bit.
I feel I want to look at alternative
possibilities for,
for what these mega lists are all about
and that's.
And that's one of the things I'd been
doing for the last year,
is traveling around the world looking.
I feel so lucky to have the opportunity
to do this and just amazing,
amazing archeological sites and one of
the countries that I visited and I want
to really mention this is Armenia,
um,
where I have seen incredible stone
circles,
just wonderful dwarfs stonehenge make,
make us just standing all and look at
the way that these huge megalithic
stones in what is called the moonstone
circle.
They have certain holes drilled in them
to align up with particular areas of the
sky at an Armenian Akio.
Astronomer from that kind of data
believes that the place called
[inaudible],
not just two or 3000 years old,
as most historians believe,
but well over 12,000
years old.
Why did you believe that?
Because of the astronomical alignments
that the positions of the stars in the
sky change very slowly down the ages.
That the alignment to the solstices
changes because there's a slow nod on
the axis of the earth,
very,
very slow over tens of thousands of
years.
Which means that if the sun rises at a
certain point on the horizon,
on the summer solstice today in two or
three or 5,000
years' time,
that point on the horizon will have
changed.
You wouldn't notice it in a lifetime.
You wouldn't notice it in 10 lifetimes,
but if you stay long enough,
you'll note that actually the sun isn't
rising in the place on the horizon
anymore.
When did we?
That's called the procession of the
equinox.
Well,
actually no,
that's the second.
That's the second.
That's a difference.
That's the changing tilt of the Earth's
axis,
which which kind of is a wobble and nods
back if there's a wobble and there's a
tilt and then there's actually a tilt
within the tilt.
No,
well,
yeah.
This is the.
This is the view,
but the effect is because the earth is
the viewing platform from which we
observed the stars in which we observed
the other celestial bodies such as the
moon and the sun.
The earth is our viewing platform.
If you change the orientation in space
of that viewing platform,
then the rising points of stars,
the moon,
the sun change,
and the positions of the stars in the
sky change and it becomes a kind of
language.
Once you understand this,
that it is universally available to us,
the calculations can be done.
We can do it.
Anybody can buy a computer software
today which will show you the ancient
skies over at any point on the earth's
surface at anytime in the last 30,000
years.
That's amazing.
These and what's involved in those
computer simulations is simply
calculations that had been done in
previous centuries by it,
by astronomers,
and we understand these,
these processes.
We can measure them and set them up,
but there you have a regularity of
changing patterns in the sky.
If you tie that into architecture on the
ground,
then actually you have a way free of all
language,
of dating,
of actually speaking.
You can use this universal language of
the stars and architecture to make a
statement to the future.
You can say that this particular time
was very important to me,
to our culture.
It mattered to us,
it mattered to us so much that we've
created this huge monument to freeze the
skies over a particular point.
I wonder why those particular
constellations,
if at all,
were important to them.
That's where things get really strange
and if I wanted to play devil's
advocate,
I would say,
well,
these holes,
they're pointing up towards the sky.
Here's a lot of fucking stars on the
show.
How do we know?
Just because they line up with this and
a thousand years ago,
it doesn't mean you weren't looking.
It's very complicated.
So what you want is multiple locks.
I mean take the pyramids of Giza and
here I cite the work of my close friend
and colleague,
Robert Robert Duvall in particular in
his book,
the Orion mystery.
You,
you take the three great pyramids of
Giza and you look at the heavens
overhead and you also look at the
religious system of the ancient
Egyptians.
What was important to them?
What did they.
What did they believe?
You pretty soon discovered that stars
were incredibly important to them.
Stars cover the inside of the ceilings
of,
of all tombs,
of the pharaohs tombs,
for,
for example,
a monuments are lined up to particular
places on the horizon.
Whereas star,
perhaps it's serious who's counterpart
amongst the gods was the goddess Isis.
Perhaps it's a Ryan who's counterpart
amongst the gods who was the goddess
Cyrus.
Uh,
this is the thing.
You have a mythology that speaks of
entities who have,
who are clearly stated to be connected
to particular asterisks,
particular,
particular constellations.
That's the first thing.
Are The constellations that are being
said to have a reflection upon the
ground and architecture,
were they significant to the culture
concerned?
Well,
yes,
absolutely.
The constellation of Orion was of
enormous significance to the ancient
Egyptians.
Therefore,
it has to be a matter of interest that
the three pyramids on the ground are
laid out in a pattern that is temptingly
similar to the pattern of the three
belts,
stars of the Constellation of Orion.
That's fascinating.
Temptingly similar,
but there's something else.
Then you have shafts which run through
the body of the Great Pyramid you have.
There's a place called the king's
chamber high up in the Great Pyramid.
It has a shaft and it's north and south
wall,
which are about eight inches high and
eight inches wide,
and those shafts cut all the way through
the body of the pyramid and they come
out on the south and north sides of the
pyramid.
You can actually,
and it's been done in the past,
you can drop a cannonball in,
at the outside entrance to those shafts
and they appear and that cannonball
moments later will appear in the king's
chamber,
the shelter about 200 feet long.
Okay.
In the Queens Chamber down below,
there are also two shafts.
Uh,
these shafts do not exit on the outside
of the pyramid,
which creates a mystery of its own,
of great interest.
What is it?
The other end of those shots,
but they do have very definite
alignments.
And what Robert was really the first to
show some archeo astronomers were,
we're onto this as well in the case of
some of the stars,
but what Robert was really the first to
show is that in 2,500
BC,
the epoch in which Egyptologists say the
pyramids were built,
all of those foreshafts that shoot up
out of the king's chamber and the Queen
Chamber all targeted very significant
stars in the sky at that time.
Like for example,
the southern shaft of the Queens Chamber
targeted the star Sirius at exactly the
moment that the star crosses the
Meridian.
That's the north south line that divides
the sky above our heads at exactly the
moment that the star crosses that line.
The shaft targets it and you could,
you could fire a laser beam up and you'd
hit that.
In theory,
you'd hit that,
start the,
the,
the alignment is that great.
So they locking the pyramid in in the
epoch of 2,500
BC,
two four significant stars in the sky.
Another one of those stars is the lowest
star of the belt of Orion.
That tells us that this is a dating
mechanism of some kind and it it can't
be an accident that that's the case and
once you understand procession,
you understand that these alignments
will change,
so therefore it becomes very interesting
to discover that the orientation of the
pyramids on the ground is that which
Robert argues are the terrestrial
reflection of the three stars of the
belt of Orion,
that the orientation of the pyramids on
the ground because of procession shifts
very slowly down the ages.
And if you,
and you can see this clearly on any good
sky map program as you go back in time,
you find that the constellation of Orion
at the moment it crosses the Meridian.
The same place that was targeting the
star Sirius at the moment.
It crosses the Meridian.
That the perfect alignment between the
belt stars for Ryan and the three Great
Pyramids of Giza is not in 2,500
BC,
but in 10,500
8,000
years earlier.
So we have a very interesting problem
here.
Either it's all coincidence or the
pyramids are monuments that speak both
to the age of the ancient Egyptians,
2,500
BC and to a much earlier time,
wasn't it?
Also the same time where the Sphinx was
pointing towards the Constellation Leo?
Well,
that's the again,
the third part of the lock,
and Robert and I looked at this in depth
together in our book called the message
of the Sphinx,
and so we have the Giza plateau.
We have the three pyramids laid out on
the ground in the pattern of the belt of
Orion in 10,500
BC.
That's looking south.
Now let's look east.
Let's look Julie's east east of course,
where the sunrises,
but people who don't observe the sun
don't realize that the sun tracks back
and forth along the horizon during the
solar year reaches its most northern
most point on the summer solstice 21st
of June,
and it's southern most point on the
winter solstice 20,
20,
first of December.
On the equinox.
The day that night and day are of equal
length.
The sunrises directly,
perfectly due east.
That's actually how you define an
equinox because the sun is rising
perfectly Jewish and looking at it is
the sphinx aligned gazing directly
perfectly at the point of sunrise.
Now we have to consider what's behind
the sun.
Then what is the constellation of the
Zodiac that the sun is rising in because
that's what the Zodiac is.
It's A.
It's a group of constellations that by
chance that the son passes through
during the course of the year,
but that the constellation that the sun
rises against,
the background of it is also affected by
precession,
the wobble on the axis of the earth,
and that changes.
You have roughly 2,160
years in each house of the Zodiac for
the last 2000,
160 years.
We've been in Pisces and as I often say,
it's not an accident that the the early
Christians use the fish as their symbol.
Before that it was the constellation of
areas.
The Ram Ram's were incredibly important
in the year from 2000 down to the time
of Christ.
Just look at the biblical stories.
Anyway,
to cut a long story short,
the Great Sphinx is a lion,
admittedly with a human head,
but that head is rather small and we
think that the head almost certainly was
recovered in a later time.
Probably the whole statute was
originally Elian crouching there on the
horizon,
gazing Julie East at the rising sun on
the equinox and at the Constellation
pint the sun,
and that constellation is in 10,500
BC,
the constellation of Leo as above.
So below Leo speaking to the Sphinx,
uh,
Ryan speaking to the pyramids,
locking in to a date that is far before
any civilization began.
And I,
I know I'm on a long wrap here,
but just at that,
at,
at that point when the egyptologist
well,
it's impossible for there to be any
thing like a civilization at Giza 12 and
a half thousand years ago.
Just when they're very happy saying
that,
and they're telling us that no other
monument can be found anywhere in the
world,
which is 12 and a half thousand years
old on this scale.
Lo and behold,
up pops go directly to Epi in Turkey.
Go back to in the area of Turkey that by
the way was once historic Armenia go,
Beckley tempe pops up.
It's dated by the German archeological
institute.
They discovered that this huge complex
of stone circles has been deliberately
buried 10,000
years ago and the carbon dating,
because you can't date stones,
you have to date organic materials.
The carbon dating of organic materials
found with those stone circles puts
their age back to 12,000
years.
I'm more for you.
That must have been like Christmas.
It was Christmas.
It was like.
It was like a gift.
I,
you know,
I don't,
I don't want to.
I have to confess.
I mean,
we all have egos.
Of course.
I have to confess that,
that it was a nice moment for me when
the New Scientist magazine in Britain,
which years ago,
back in the nineties when I published
fingerprints of the gods,
was amongst the magazines that tact my
work as quote unquote pseudoscientific
and all of the.
I don't know how my work can be pseudo
scientific because I don't claim to be a
scientist.
I'm a fucking journalist.
You know?
I'm not,
I'm not a scientist,
how can I be a pseudo scientists,
but here's a guy who's got an obsessed
with an idea.
I kind of,
and I'm a little weed,
like that's actually New Scientist
magazine back in the 19 nineties was
saying that I was wrong,
where the basic message of fingerprints
of the gods is history as much older and
much more mysterious than we'd been
told,
so it was great in October 2013 when
you.
This magazine came out with a headline
saying history is much older and more
mysterious than we thought.
It's funny.
The Hancock was right.
Title showed up in my next.
Sorry Dude.
In my next life we were fucking with
you,
but there was,
there was happy and that's what changes
everything.
Yeah,
they're really done.
By the way.
I'll just say I guess we may be running
out of time,
but I'll just say,
are we good?
I just say also Indonesia,
which is the other place that my wife
Santha and I've done a lot of research
in the last six or seven months,
has been found.
What was thought to be a 2,500
year old site on top of the hill.
I'm a site made of blocks of columnar
basalt,
which forms naturally but which can be
used as a construction medium.
Okay.
It's called Gunung Padang.
And on the top of the hill in a series
of terraces is a rather extraordinary
monument,
thought to be about 2,500
years old,
made of these blocks of columnar
battled.
Um,
no really thorough research has ever
done by archeologists.
A little bit of trenching down to about
half of half a meter in depth was done
and some carbon was brought up and
dated,
but really the site,
it was just kind of taken for granted
that it was two and a half thousand
years old.
Along comes Danny Natoya ggn,
who is a caltech trained phd geologist,
a working out of the city of Bandung in
a government agency of the Indonesian
government.
In fact,
he particularly focuses on earthquakes.
Earthquakes are his thing.
Um,
he comes along and he's intrigued by
Gunung Padang first of all,
that there's old traditions about it
being a sacred place.
It's go back at,
it seemed to go back a very,
very,
very long way and he starts to look at
it as a geologist and what he realized
is suddenly it comes to him.
He's not looking at a natural hill.
He's looking at a pyramid on top of
which is this relatively recent
monument,
but somebody built a pyramid there,
so he begins work on this,
so it's covered in dirt.
It looks like a grown,
but it's inside.
It's a.
it's a manmade structure.
That was Danny's intuition,
but then he had to prove it,
so he put together a team and they did a
huge amount of remote sensing work and
some core drilling down to depths of
about 15 meters into the top of the hill
and what they.
What they discovered was incredibly
tempting it,
it supports Dan,
his intuition that we are looking at a
manmade pyramid here.
It has produces dates that go back as
much as 26,000
years right into the last ice age and
the remote sensing equipment shows
rather regular cavities inside the
monument,
which looked like chambers of some kind.
Well,
naturally Danny and his team were
stopped working for quite a long while
by the archeological establishment in
Indonesia who said,
we know that this structure is two and a
half thousand years old and there's no
need for any further research on it and
it just disturbs the local villages and
um,
uh,
you know,
go away.
And so they lobbied and they had him
stopped.
Uh,
but donny took it to the highest level.
He got the support of the Indonesian
government and two and a half weeks ago
they started work excavating,
thoroughly excavating.
And so far the results look very
interesting to see a building 26,000,
26,000
years old.
And again,
you know,
we can't,
I can't summon up a map magically,
but if I were to do so,
consider Indonesia,
which is a long string of islands today.
But if you go back 12 and a half
thousand years ago,
that long strip of art,
string of islands is joined to a
gigantic mainland,
huge,
you know,
ice age continent because sea level is
hundreds of feet lower.
And therefore,
Indonesia becomes actually quite a
plausible play place for some sort of
whole of records,
some sort of time capsule because
Rebecca is also a time capsule that's so
absolutely incredible.
I can't say fascinating anymore because
people started giving me shit about it.
Last few podcasts I see.
I don't know when things are
fascinating.
I would camp come up with any.
You know me.
It was my way of going,
whoa.
There's interesting stuff happening
happening in the world.
I've been lucky to spend some time
exploring this.
I am writing a sequel to my best known
book and undoubtedly his fingerprints of
the gods,
the evidence for earth lost
civilization.
There was that 1995,
1995,
and now you know,
after being scorned and put down by the
archeological establishment,
there is enough new evidence out there
for me to produce a whole other book.
There's a whole other story to tell.
Not An update of fingerprints of the
gods would with a new book which looks
at all of this information.
What's going on in Stonehenge?
This most recent monuments,
they discovered bigger than the rest of
Stonehenge stonehedge.
They.
That's the thing,
you see this why archeologist need to be
a little more humble because the next
turn of the spade can change everything
completely alter the story and we should
always remain,
remain open to just a one discovery like
that one farmer finding this stone and
go back with on earth.
This incredible structure that rewrites
history literally turn to the space.
That piece of stone is seen by American
archeologists in the 19 fifties really,
and they decide not to look at it
because it's so finely done that they
think it belongs to the Ottoman period
within the last four or 500 years.
Actually it turns out to be 12,000
years old.
What's good that they didn't fuck with
it?
It's cool that it happens this way.
Got The German archeological institute
later.
Unfortunately they've stuck a hideous
roof over the top of the top.
Now they have.
Oh,
it's trying to keep it from decaying or
something.
Look,
it was 19 years.
It was exposed to.
The Sun was out there.
It was being.
They began the excavations in 1996 and
it's fine.
Fine,
and now that they finished the
excavations,
they decided that in that particular
area,
they're excavating other areas,
they decide to stick this horrendous
roof over it,
which cuts out the light,
makes it impossible to see the stump is
the roof is badly built,
so it there are platforms built inside
it on which huge heaps of stones have
been part of.
That's to keep the roof on if there's
any high winds,
so suddenly so suddenly the possibility
of any kind of magical experience at the
world's most intriguing and mysterious
ancient site is completely written off
by this hideous piece of soco protective
architecture,
which in my view is just the worst kind
of vandalism.
I've really offended by it.
I went back to.
I was in Tibet in 2013.
I went back again this year and I am.
I was just horrified.
It made me feel physically sick to see
what had been,
what have been done to it.
That's so bizarre.
The desire to.
Is it because to sell tickets so people
have to pay to get in there?
I think.
I think it's a kind of.
In this case,
I think it's a kind of possession.
This is ours.
We've seen it with the experts,
with the authorities.
Nobody else.
We're really get to form an opinion
about it because we're going to damage
it's appearance so much in protecting it
that it'll,
that it'll lose its essential mystery.
Well,
it just seems bizarre that they're
trying to protect stone.
That doesn't make any sense.
It's like,
imagine if someone decided to put a
giant canopy over the sphinx and be
like,
what are you talking about?
Big Bear forever.
This is being done at archeological
sites around the world has been done at
dre and I go him in,
in Malta,
which have profound,
astronomical alignments.
You stick a fucking great dome over the
top of it,
you know,
um,
it's being done at Rosslyn Chapel in
Edinburgh.
Everything and the worst of the worst
vandals or often the authorities,
those who,
those who are in control.
Well,
that's how we asked guys in the pokey
now,
right now,
he's not,
didn't get arrest him.
He did,
but all the challenges.
Withdrawal.
Oh,
he came up with some shackles situation.
He said he's a big front man for Egypt,
still running everything over there.
No,
he's not running everything,
but he's got an official position in
relation to the promotion of tourism and
so bizarre when you see those guys so
vehemently opposed to new information,
which is essentially what the idea is
being proposed are there's new
information.
Yeah.
There's certain pieces of new
information that in my mind or just
undeniable the Robert Schoch stuff.
I mean,
I'm trying to.
I my first trip to go back to Tempe,
Robert Shuck and I traveled together.
You guys made a video,
right?
There was some filming yet,
but we were.
We were at Rebecca tappy in December.
Uh,
sorry,
not go back to tempe at Gunung Padang in
Indonesia.
Shock and I were were there in December
2013 and then I went back again with,
what was his impression of it?
His impression was very much that this
is an intriguing site.
He looked at the,
you as a geologist,
he can understand what remote scanning
paperwork looks like and he looked at
what Danny's team had produced and said,
this is absolutely fascinating.
It really deserves further research and
that's now what it's getting fortunate.
Well,
it's just amazing when they uncover
these things like I love the ones that
they find in Mexico when they're like
building something and then they stumble
upon some ancient Aztec temple.
Not many people who go to Chichen Itza
and see the temple of cookware can
there.
The pyramidical con,
which is the famous monument petition
eater.
Not many people realize that there's
another pyramid inside it which is
inside it.
There's a little door at the bottom of
the stairway and I don't think it can be
done now.
The place has been so tightly
controlled.
I don't think people even allowed to
climb the pyramid of cuckold con.
When did they stop that?
I believe that stopped in the last two
or three years.
I was bare.
I know it may be a little longer.
I was in the last time I was there was
in 2010 and then it was stopped with
Roseann by people's feet.
I don't know,
maybe maybe all kinds of arguments,
but.
But the fact is it was possible to
climate.
Yeah.
I used to back in the nineties anyway,
inside it is a whole second pyramid.
The pyramid that we see has been built
on top of an earlier one and there's a
passageway leads up to the top of it and
there's an altar and there's a figure of
a Puma or a Jaguar.
Inside is very spooky place.
Wow.
Yeah.
That whole.
The whole complex is so incredible.
It's so amazing to think that,
you know,
I know you scuba dive.
You ever done those tunnels that they
found in the Senate?
No,
no.
Those are terrifying.
These people scuba dive and they go.
There's is mind tunnels that they had
found that are underwater.
Yeah.
So you have to,
but the people that are treasure hunters
have gone into these things and you
found these incredible artifacts.
Yeah,
but you gotta be willing to swim
underwater.
Scuba gear in a dark tunnel for a long
time.
They're long.
Like you can get a mile in
that.
Temporary takes.
Tremendous courage also takes,
it takes very special equipment.
Um,
you know,
you're having to having to carry a lot
more air with you and it would be a very
complex mixture of gases.
Sometimes they have narrow pastures.
Do you have to squeeze through one of
the most cave?
Cave diving is one of the most dangerous
things you know,
because.
Because I'll tell you why,
because the entrance passage can be long
and winding.
There can be several alternative routes
through it and it's often heavily laden
with silt with sediment.
If the dry,
if the diver is not very experienced or
if the diver panics and starts thrashing
around,
that silt,
silt gets thrown up into the water and
completely fills the water so that you
can't see your hand in front of your
face and suddenly your mile in 100 feet
deep and blind.
Oh fuck.
That was one of the most legitimate
freak out you've ever had on a podcast
right there.
You're saying that me thinking that was
just a tremendous freak out.
Yeah,
just the idea of being,
knowing that it's going to run out of
air before it settles to.
Yes.
Oh yes.
You're done for.
Unless unless you can find your way,
unless by some miracle you can find your
way through that fog where the very
first thing,
if you're going to do that,
that you have to do is you have to calm
your mind.
You're freaking me out,
man.
Yeah,
yeah.
Well,
let's talk about my novels then.
listen,
those people are just brave as far.
It's amazing that people are willing to
do that.
It's guts.
It's courage.
Courage of the warrior in a way.
So is this.
How many novels have you written there?
So I've written three.
Just the third.
Well,
I've written an entangled,
which is a whole other story.
And then I've written volume one and
volume two of war.
God,
the first volume was war God,
knights of the,
which it was published in 2013.
There was a big support and take up from
your audience,
which has beautiful,
really grateful for.
I heard a lot of positive reviews to
people.
Enjoyed it.
Thank you.
And I made A.
I made an offer at that time on your
show where I said that if people wrote
to me at a particular address,
which is war God dedications@gmail.com,
and sent me their own address and showed
me that they've pre ordered the book,
I would send them assigned dedicated
bookplate.
In other words,
I would sign a label.
I would dedicate it to them.
I would send it to them.
Little did I know that nearly 5,000
people would ask for those signed
dedicated book plates.
It became a massive labor of love for
myself and my wife Santha.
She's doing the envelope thing.
I'm dealing with the correspondents
putting the signing,
signing the book plates.
We go to the post office were spending
thousands of pounds on postage and that.
But it was great.
It was a fantastic thing and it gave and
it.
And it helped the book to get noticed.
Um,
because there was great skepticism about
buying a second volume from my
publishers unless the first volume
worked.
And the first volume worked enough for
me to to be commissioned to write volume
two of what God,
which is called war God,
returned to the prelim serpent and that
is published on the ninth of October.
And I'm making the same special offer.
Very Limited.
Don't do to you,
but it's going to be a bit different.
First Time.
First off the,
if you go to my website,
go to www.grahamhancock.com
and go to the war God page.
It's very easy to get there.
I'm right.
Scroll down at the bottom of the page
that shows the covers of all the
additions and you will find a statement
there.
And that is that if people write to me,
if people preorder,
first of all,
they have to preorder either order
volume one or preorder volume to Amazon.
Don't take your money until they
actually send the book.
And I've got the links to Amazon.com.
They're a,
I will when I finished my travels and
I'm going to be on the road until the
27th of October.
Uh,
but during November I will send out
those book plates again.
But what I can't do this time is I can't
get into personal correspondence with
people.
It was very interesting.
It was very touching and heart and heart
warming thing that so many people wrote
to me and so many of them I wanted to
speak back to them.
It's very cold,
you know,
to receive a letter and not to reply.
So.
So I did,
but I.
The problem this year is that I've got
to write the sequel to fingerprints of
the gods and I really need to start that
during November because my research
travels will be over at that point.
I've got to write that and I can't spend
two months or three months corresponding
in detail.
So my,
my offer is right to me.
Show me that you've bought the book or
preordered volume to a and above all,
please give me your postal address
because you can't imagine how many times
people write to me asking for the book
flights and don't get me their postal
address.
Please give me your postal address and
when I get back from my travels,
I will sign the book plates.
I will send you a signed book plate,
which is simply a label that you can
stick inside your copy of the book and
that if,
if,
if that results in a bit more uptake for
war God too,
it'll be good for me because it's very
difficult to start a new career as a
novelist at the age of 64.
Uh,
and we really enjoy it.
I love it.
I love writing novels and I love
getting.
This is why I was talking about warriors
earlier.
I love getting into the spirit of the
warrior.
I don't know why it's fascinating.
It's just,
it's just absolutely fascinating what
would drive a man like Cortez to take
490 men and,
and face them against the might of the
Aztec Empire,
hundreds of thousands of men under arms
who will kill you in the most awful way
if they,
if they catch you,
what kind of will does it take to do
that?
And,
and it was,
it's been interesting for me to get
inside the heads of these people and
also to consider because I'm interested
in them supernatural elements where they
being misled by demonic forces in some
way.
That's something that,
that exam.
So I love doing it,
but it's,
I'm known as a nonfiction author and
that's mainly what I do.
Uh,
people by nonfiction because they're
interested in the subject.
Very often people buy a novelist because
they trust that novelist and know that
his next book will be good leadership.
Your fascination with demons.
What's your fascination with
supernatural influences and the concept
of demons?
For a long time,
I didn't believe in any spiritual
element to life.
I was,
I didn't see any of that at all.
It was only really when I send,
and this is where my credit is,
we'll say,
well,
handcuffs gone nuts.
You know,
it was only really when I started
drinking Iowasca in 2003,
I suppose for a decade before that,
I'd been immersed in the ancient
Egyptian texts.
And the ancient Egyptians are all about
the quest for immortal life.
They're all,
they're all about how you live this life
to continue on as a,
as a spirit and ultimately to live the
life of millions of years,
and they very clearly indicate that dark
forces are at work in the universe which
can mislead us as well as there are
light and positive forces that we can
choose to follow,
which will lead us into very nurturing
and worthwhile and excellent directions.
All those influences are there.
So that's there in ancient Egypt.
Then I start drinking.
I asked her in 2003 and I encounter,
um,
seamlessly convincing parallel realms,
inhabited by intelligent beings,
some of whom a seem very dark and
dangerous and some have,
and some of whom are filled with light
and joy and,
and exercise the power of healing.
Now,
I absolutely accept that all of this
could be a projection or a creation of
my own mind,
that there is no exterior reality to it
whatsoever.
It's just,
that's all there is.
Um,
but I don't think it's that way.
I think.
I think that what happens in a deeply
altered state of consciousness is that
we've reached in the receiver wavelength
of the brain and and counter other
levels of reality that are normally
closed off to our senses.
And the first thing I would say to any.
I know that a number of people who've
worked with psychedelics in depth
haven't come to that conclusion.
I know that,
but the conclusion that I come to my,
the little offering that I bring to the
table and that many others have brought
is that there is a separate freestanding
reality of some kind which we don't
fully understand yet.
And that in altered states of
consciousness we can encounter,
interact with that reality.
That's the.
That's the view that I have now.
In that reality are spiritual forces.
Some of which seem to eat fear in energy
and,
and dark energy.
They thrive on.
They think they seem to thrive on
anything that's miserable or wicked or,
or,
or cruel or thoughtless of viral about
humanity.
And at the other side of it are entities
that glow with light and love and that
and that seek to show us how we may
bring to light that divine spark within
us to go back to the GNOSTIC,
gnostic idea,
those you encounter in a very direct way
in the Iowaska journey,
um,
because unlike,
you do encounter them in the DMT,
Jenny too,
they're not quite the same.
But unlike DMT I asked,
it allows time for really processing and
thinking through what you're
experiencing.
It's,
it's unfolding over four hours,
not four or five minutes.
And that,
you know,
that is,
is a huge effect and it had a huge
effect on me and I,
I'm,
I'm not adamant about this.
I accept.
I could be fantasizing it all.
It's interesting.
The other people encounter pretty much
the same beings and,
and the same sort of drive to do
something better than they've done
before.
It's interesting that there's that
transpersonal side of it.
I choose to believe that there are
freestanding parallel dimensions and
that we are encountering them in altered
states of consciousness.
And therefore there's interesting
scientific work to be done because in
theory we could actually begin the
targeted exploration of those dimensions
by using volunteers on psychedelics.
I choose to believe that that's what's
going on.
I could be completely wrong.
It could just be the majesty of the
human mind and we just invent all these
worlds.
That's what I was going to ask you.
What's the most compelling argument
against it?
Like what's the most compelling art
article?
A argument rather from a neurological
standpoint like has anybody ever
explained to you like what's going on?
There isn't a compelling argument.
I don't know.
There's a reference frame and the
reference frame,
and this is again where where I got
myself into so much trouble with Ted,
the reference frame is the reference
frame of materialist science and that
reference frame says that all
consciousness is a kind of accidental
epi phenomenon of brain activity.
There's actually no reality to
consciousness.
That is not something that's been proven
scientifically and experimentally.
It is just the way that a large and
influential group of scientists see the
world that everything can be reduced to
material causes.
So the changes in brain activity that
accompany visions,
you can measure,
you can observe those changes on MRI
scanner,
those changes in brain activity are the
experience you're having according to
this reference frame.
Your,
the,
your experience can be reduced to that
and there's nothing else to it,
but that's not a fact.
That is a,
that is a philosophical view about how
reality works.
We don't know for sure.
It could easily be the other way round,
um,
that,
that the brain activity is simply
necessary in order for us to see
something that was always there,
but it was normally closed off to our
senses.
So the,
the,
the compelling argument as far as like,
what's happening when you're having
these extreme visual experiences,
what's,
what does the argument.
Has anybody ever tried to explain it?
Is it just some supposed to be some
chemical reaction with your cerebral
cortex?
That's the.
Yes,
that is the,
that is the materialist reductionist
view,
but it's just that and nothing more.
But there's a whole other view on it.
Rick Strassman at the University of New
Mexico,
you're very familiar with his weight
because you presented the spirit
molecule.
Yes,
Rick's Rick Strassman does entertain the
possibility that what is going on is not
merely in and of our brains but does
represent stable,
freestanding dimensions of reality.
We have no facts in but we have an
incredibly
intriguing area to inquire into,
you know,
and it's also one of those things where
I feel like when you've experienced it
yourself,
you get a really better frame of
reference as to why this is compelling
it all because it sounds preposterous to
someone who has no experience.
I know it really does.
You know,
because.
And I'm going to have loads of people
saying handcuffs at Draghi of course too
late,
but there's that thing that people want
when you want to define certain aspects
of,
of whatever the psychedelic experiences
where they seem to be almost impossible
to define for people who have actually
experienced it.
Yes.
The real problem is when someone who
hasn't experienced it tries to define it
and it's like,
man,
you can come up with a bunch of really
compelling arguments from a medical
standpoint.
It's to like what is,
what's the effect on the cerebral
cortex?
What's the effect on the visual aspects
of,
you know,
the,
your interpretation of this thing is
because of this chemical interacting
with that.
That's all fascinating,
amazing stuff.
But the science is bad science to
present it as fact when it isn't.
I have many times given this very simple
analogy of the telescope,
um,
which I think explains the logical
problem in the materialist view.
If you want to look at a distant star
with your telescope,
you're going to point it at the right
area of the sky first of all,
and then you're going to focus it.
And as you focus it,
physical changes will take place in the
relationship between the lenses inside
the barrel of the telescope.
Yeah,
right.
Okay.
Eventually the star will come into view
and you can see it clearly.
You'd be completely wrong to say that
the star is the physical changes inside
the barrel of the telescope.
Those physical changes have simply
allowed you to see the star with my
fucking mind,
and that's the same idea with Dmt,
that it's that it's changing brain
function to allow you to see something
that you couldn't.
It's refocusing the brain in other
words.
Wow,
that's very possible.
It's an interesting inquiry.
I'd never thought about it that way.
I don't think.
Not Entirely and and interesting
experiments could be done to test that
with human volunteers.
You could.
You could begin to investigate if there
is a freestanding reality,
then we ought to be able to get certain
information out of it that they should
be possibilities.
So you know,
we always had just started as a chemical
gateway.
Yeah,
but I think this is a way better way of
explaining it.
The idea of a telescope having to focus
in to see something and then the
chemicals focusing you in that a
chemical,
your own brain makes your brain makes it
focusing Ulan and perhaps for some very
good reason.
Wow,
that's amazing.
I never thought about that way before,
but whatever it is,
it's pretty fucking profound and for
someone to comment on it,
that hasn't taken.
It seems kind of silly,
especially because it's only 15 minutes
is disrespectful to speak of.
It too is it's fine to speak of it,
but it's disrespectful to put it down
without having had the guts actually to
have the experience yourself.
Don't you think it's becoming more and
more accepted though?
Because I think for a long time
academics resisted taking it or if they
did take it,
talking about it because they didn't
want to be labeled because there's a lot
of people have that will label you.
If you talk about psychedelic recently,
it's been considered a career relenting
move and I can talk very recently,
even though they all knew the news,
it'll knew the positive side of this,
but this is again gradually changing and
again,
I think the the American role,
the role of the American people in
changing the legal status of cannabis
state by state is also going to feed
into this and allow us to have a more
rational dialogue regarding
psychedelics,
which can be.
Of course,
I'm not saying to people yet go out and
take psychedelics.
What I'm saying is that these are very
powerful agents and that they can be
extremely healing used in the right way
and they can change our whole view of
reality.
Why should we be forbidden to explore
that if as responsible adults we choose
to do so?
Yeah,
it's,
it's the argument is stupid and I think
the argument is eventually going away
and I think it will be replaced by a new
argument and then the new argument is
what the fuck is really happening?
Yeah,
and your.
Is it your question about it or your
proposal is vast,
very fascinating one,
but whatever it is,
those things are there and you can
benefit from them or not.
It's up to you,
but yeah,
it's the fact that we live in a world
where those are illegal is is,
is crazy,
it's gone,
and if people are having very bad
experiences from time to time with
psychedelics,
part of the reason for that is the world
we've created where these are illegal
and where it's impossible for people to
get good advice that they can trust them
with as this atmosphere of danger and
threat that surrounds it.
Take all that away and this very
powerful instrument can be managed much
more effectively.
No,
no,
no doubt,
and I equate it a lot of ways.
This,
this idea of it being bad and negative,
acquainted a lot of ways to vaccinations
and here's why there's this vaccination
is anti vaccination movement in this
country.
A lot of people feel like vaccinations
are unnecessary and they may have some
good arguments.
They may have some good arguments,
especially about some certain
vaccinations for things that are
sexually transmitted,
diseases and things along those lines
like hepatitis shots and shit.
You're given a little kid,
so there's a real good argument against
that and there's a little.
There's definitely an argument that
there's a lot of medication the kids are
taking and is it the right amount,
but there's no argument that
vaccinations haven't saved a fuck ton of
lives because they have.
They've stopped a lot of diseases.
Data and attract.
Absolutely,
but they also,
much like we talked about,
some people are allergic to cats,
some people are very different
biological reactions to all sorts of
different chemicals and there's going to
be some adverse reactions.
Something in your body that I absolutely
agree that the vaccination is incredibly
effective medical tool in many ways,
but there also is a kind of vaccination
mafia because they are the ultimate mass
medication and people are making money.
There's no doubt there's whenever
there's profits,
there's fuckery.
There's no getting around it.
Just the way he even being side by side.
So the.
Yeah,
it's.
It's one of those scenarios very much
like psychedelics in a way that the are
going to be some rare cases.
If we make psychedelics legal across the
board,
there's going to be some rare cases of a
person in a bad state of mind or a bad
mental makeup or what have you.
Pad psychological makeup,
you can fill in the blanks where they
take it and it's detrimental to them.
It's going to happen and that'll be
highly publicized and used as an
argument to stop all of these freedoms
and building access is ridiculous.
Have the very best answer to that as I'm
sure as I'm sure you remember,
you know the,
the,
the lunatic who leaps out of the window
and he can fly on Lsd.
Why didn't the fucker try and take off
from the ground?
He goes,
we lost a moron.
The world got lighter.
Exactly.
World got lighters.
One of my favorite lines.
Beautiful.
But that's,
um,
that is,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's just a strange argument to keep
people from doing it because,
especially like this doctor that we were
talking about earlier that's talking
about cannabis in the addictive
properties of cannabis,
and this isn't even talking to someone
who was addicted to cannabis and you,
it's still,
it's a silly,
I like,
there's a lot going on when someone's
addicted.
It's not all necessarily chemical and
the ones that are chemical you're
getting paid for,
so that doesn't even make any sense.
The ones that chemically make you
addicted as the ones you're getting
money from,
people are fed up with all of this shit
because it's so corrupt and it's so
wrong and it's time that is time that a
new direction was taken.
And there are people who are on the
wrong side of history on this and the
will be.
But we are moving forward.
I think we are as well.
I think it's,
uh,
it's,
it's pretty cool to see too.
Yeah.
But,
you know,
I think it's also important that a guy
like you who smoked pot from 9:00
AM to 2:00
AM every day,
seven days a week,
365 days a week,
going to enormous length to be able to
obtain it.
When I was traveling,
I was that of sources that it is,
it is.
Um,
I,
I do know what I'm talking about.
I had a long relationship with it.
And um,
I understand how,
how do you feel now having good dip back
in the water?
A little bit.
I feel good,
but I don't feel any urge to become that
guy again.
My clarity,
I've,
I,
I was able to write with cannabis,
but since I stopped smoking cannabis,
I've been clear.
My mind has been a clarity.
So there's a certain fog was lifted.
That fog wouldn't have been there if I'd
had one joint at the weekend and that
was all but it since I was smoking all
day long.
That's why it was there.
It's nice not to have that felt.
Yeah,
go to bed.
I feel more productive.
I write my novels.
I can write 5,000
words a day,
sometimes I'd get sucked the zone,
so into the flow.
Um,
you know,
that all that is good and I feel I feel
good about it.
And I think field probably in the long
run,
my right choice would not be have a big,
have a big relationship with cannabis.
I think I've done that.
Been there,
done that.
Know I've got the t shirt.
For me,
it's a tool.
I don't use the same tool every day is
that sometimes I'll use any tools,
need it,
but it has a pretty profound effect a
lot of ways.
You know,
one of my favorite things to do is at
night get high and go down to the beach
and stare at the ocean.
I used to love doing that.
Oh my God,
I think freaks me out when I'm high.
When you're,
when you're this,
it's a goddess.
It's a monster.
It's a living thing almost.
It's a force.
It's a nature force that doesn't give a
fuck about you.
I think there's one reason why like
people that live by the beach or so
mellow.
Yeah.
The beach communities are notoriously
mellow.
That's true,
and I think one of the reasons why
they're notoriously Melo is because
they're faced with overwhelming evidence
that day ain't shit.
Yes.
You're sitting there looking out at the
greatest like natural force that you
could imagine.
It's an entire different world.
You're out there.
Literally.
It's like if we had explained it in a
galactic term,
it would be like your parking yourself
next to the membrane between dimensions.
I mean you are literally in this world
over here and right next to your face is
a whole nother world.
Like we couldn't even imagine that,
but that the fuck exactly what it is.
Have you go.
Like if you go to Santa Monica and you
go over by where that peer as and you
just walk along that sand and just start
walking out into that water.
You're in another world in like 20
steps.
You're and you're over your head and
you're in another dimension that you
can't survive in.
But to get the fuck back,
it doesn't feel like you went to another
planet,
but you might as well have gone to
another planet.
Definitely.
And it's right there.
One of
my strongest experiences of diving was
just to tell a little story,
was dieting it off a tenor reef in the,
in the Canary Islands.
And I was down at a good 20 meters under
water,
let's say 70 feet.
But there was a storm that day and the
huge swell on the surface was so
powerful that it was smashing me against
the bottom of the sea.
Oh my God,
Bang,
Bang.
And I just,
that moment I realized I am.
I'm in the hands of a gigantic force,
but I can do absolutely nothing about.
There's nothing you can do the sea,
the sea for me is a goddess.
Fortunately I got over a lip and down
into deeper water and it was okay for
water.
Yeah.
Another 10 feet is what the fuck man.
How long did you have to wait it out?
That was another story.
Um,
we stayed down for about 20,
25 minutes.
We then had to have to come up.
We'd been working quite hard at depth
that you get through,
you get through your Ehr.
But what we hadn't done was recky the
exit point and when we surfaced in this
heavy swell,
it was extremely difficult to get out of
the sea.
The rocks came down quite steep and we
discussed this before you.
You came up at a different spot and it
was bad.
But anyway,
here I am,
I will tell the tale and
an older and wiser man.
Greg Fitzsimmons is a terrifying.
He's a good buddy of mine.
Very funny.
Standup comedian has a terrifying story.
He was on vacation.
He saw a woman drowning and he went out
to save her and he realized that was
hanging onto this woman's swim in back
while his kids and his wife and everyone
was on the shore.
And he was like,
Holy Shit.
Like I'm trying to save someone hear
sometimes when people try to say people,
they get drowned.
I know happens often.
It happens often.
Yeah,
that's it.
He said that the tide was a little bit
too strong.
Who's really spooky.
Rip Tide.
The sea is something to respect.
Fuck yeah.
Something.
Something fast I had is that's a
terrifying thing,
but that's my favorite thing to one of
my favorite things to do at the beach
late at night by myself.
Smoke a spliff.
Just stand out there and stare it by
myself.
Puts everything in perspective.
It's just.
It's like the ultimate.
It's very psych,
not just like a duck,
but it's very isolation tank.
Ask in a way.
It's an overwhelming amount of
information,
but there's solitude and the sound and
the noise that sort of drowns out the
rest of the world doesn't totally drown
it out like an isolation tank does,
but it has a partial effect because you
get.
It's a moving but semi static image
because it's these water waves that are
coming at you and they're very similar,
so get in this very similar thing over
and over again with very little
variation and then there's the
overwhelming number,
the gallons of water that's just so in
front of you so you can't see past this
fucking thing and it's dark.
So then there's the unknown,
the unknown,
which is the big freaker.
Know you're looking out this black
monster and sometimes when it's this
black monster,
you get a better sense of it than when
it's this beautiful blue thing during
the day when the sun's hitting it.
It's reflecting because you need to give
all this visual stuff that's distracting
you from the fact that south Florida
water giant fuck load of water.
It's right there.
And he could just go,
which,
yeah,
just come in like this and you're gone
and everything's gone like a thousand
fucking feet high waves.
That's happened before.
As
has happened before.
That's also part of the new research
that I'm doing and I'm about to do a
trip with randall cardinal crosses being
on your show.
Love Him.
Um,
you know,
randall was so far ahead of the curve in
recognizing that the gigantic flooding
that came off the North American ice cap
wasn't just caused by what I used to
think it was caused by,
which is that lakes of meltwater develop
on the surface of the ice cap.
And finally,
the dam,
the dam breaks and the melt water pours
out randomly pointing out for years
that,
uh,
that the water flows were much too
radical for that,
something much bigger.
I had to be had to be involved.
So he was well ahead of the evidence
when scientists began to realize that
the North American ice cap had been hit
by a comet 12,980
years ago.
It was set in motion,
the epoch,
the geologist called the younger dryas.
So run.
And so randall is a great expert in
this,
in this area.
My wife's sent this traveling with us as
well,
and a friend of Randall's who's worked
with him for many years called Bradley.
And we're going to do a road trip from
Portland,
Oregon,
all the way to Minneapolis,
uh,
following the,
it's about 2000 miles,
I believe,
following the southern edge of the
former ice cap.
And Randall's going to show us the scars
and tears on the landscape of what
happened when that ice cap was instantly
liquidized by a comet impact and huge
tidal waves of water roared down,
off it,
across the land.
Lord,
going to see that,
uh,
in,
in detail with Randall Real,
looking forward to doing that.
Also the first time I've ever crossed.
Well,
most of America by road.
Um,
I've always wanted to do that.
Certain spots shouldn't stop.
If you feel like you're in danger,
you're in danger.
Get in the car.
I hit the gas.
Yeah.
And if you do you know what country
music is.
You've got to listen to some of that.
Gets a hold of some country.
You got to fit in,
you got to blend in.
Can you fake southern accent?
Because if they think you're from the
England,
I can do my best.
But from the angland they won't like him
and they want to get very upset if you
go down better knows what are you dr
who.
The funny thing is in England,
I often get mistaken for an American.
Do you really?
It's weird.
You here nobody.
Nobody's in any doubt once I am,
but in England I'm officer American.
Yeah.
Or sometimes Canadian.
Well,
Canada has a bit of that.
There's like a certain amount of English
it sounds like in there,
the way they talk about things in a
certain,
uh,
clear variation between them and us.
If there is definitely I even,
I can hear that and I've got a 10 year.
Can I,
can.
I can hear that too?
Yeah.
I can totally telecommute Canadian after
awhile,
but.
So similar.
Yeah,
very similar.
Very similar.
That's hilarious that anybody would ever
think you're American.
I know,
I know.
Anyway,
it's going to be great.
I'm really looking forward to this.
Boy.
That sounds fantastic.
It's going to take loads and loads of
pictures and we're going to go up in an
airplane a few times and look at the
look at the land underneath us and is
going to be a great,
exciting research trip and it's the last
research trip for this cul that I'm
writing to fingerprints.
I'm sure you've seen this most recent
discovery about micro diamonds.
Yeah,
that's exactly it.
That's precisely.
That is the,
that has finally settled it.
Any scientists who were attempting to
argue that there wasn't a comedy impact.
Now,
with all the evidence that's come in
over the last five or six years is just
settled by the nano diamonds scattered
in a huge swathe all over the world,
which are assure,
a chemical imprint of a massive comet
impact,
and they know a lot about it.
Now.
It's really very,
very clear,
and this was an episode that changed the
world,
uh,
it killed off the many of the megafauna
that we've all heard of,
the mammoth,
the woody rhinos and so on and so forth,
and it got rid of what was called the
clovis culture.
A hunter gather a culture in the United
States.
And I think it got rid of a whole
civilization that we've only remembered
in myth and memory.
At least that's the line that I'm
investigating.
It's a fascinating line,
especially when,
as each visit that you come back to the
podcast,
there's new information.
Last time it was the nuclear glass that
they discovered when they were doing
core samples again,
which is about 12,000
years ago.
Right?
And then the new one is this micro
diamonds.
It seems like over and over again,
this is not.
It becomes not a possibility,
but a reality that there was some sort
of an impact,
something gigantic happened,
but all over the world and right.
It wasn't just all over the world.
It was massive in America,
but it was the effect was everywhere.
Both impacts because this comment broke
up into fragments like she would make a
levy nine,
both impacts,
but also very important,
the gigantic cloud of dust that's thrown
up into the upper atmosphere,
which then so you have this immediate
reaction of flooding as the comment
liquidiser as part of the North American
ice cap.
And then a huge dust plume is up in the
air all over the world.
And the whole earth is shrouded in dust
as cool and cool because it's reflecting
back the sun's rays.
So we go into this 1,300,
1000,
400 year period called the younger
Dryas,
uh,
where the earth gets incredibly cold
even though previously it had been
coming out of the,
out of the ice is truly are gigantic
event.
And then weirdly,
all our history,
everything we think of as our past
begins at the end of the younger dryas
around it kicks in 12,000,
980 years ago,
ends 11,000,
600 years ago.
The Earth begins to want,
begins to warm up again and everything
we know about ourselves or can claim we
know unfolds in that last 11,000,
600 years and the period before the
younger dryas,
we really blank on so much of it.
It's so fascinating.
I send it again.
Shit.
It's amazing that all this information
keeps coming up to support this.
And it's amazing.
If we do consider the possibility that
it is true,
that everything can be essentially shut
back down to zero with some rocks from
the sky and that that's something that
we really need to get in our head that
could happen there.
There is a very distinct possibility
that we could be hit by something.
The NASA photographs of the,
I think they call it the black diamond,
the earth at night.
Okay.
What you see is certain areas of the
world a brightly lit up Europe,
North America for example,
on the other hand,
Africa and large parts of South America
are dark because there's no
electrification in those areas and those
photographs are often taken to say to
speak of our achievement,
look how we can light up the planet like
a,
like a Christmas tree,
so that it can be viewed from viewed
from space.
But I would say it also says another
thing that if we had,
if we were to confront again the same
sort of cataclysm that hit the earth
12,000,
980 years ago,
then the people who would survive and
carry the human story forward would be
those very people who live in the dark
areas,
the areas that aren't electrified.
And we who live in the glowing lights
that show up on those NASA photographs
who've become so specialized,
who most of us are unable even to know
how to plant a vegetable or,
or,
or hunt an animal.
We're the ones who would,
uh,
who would be gone and the whole order of
the world would be reversed.
Whoa.
So the world would become like an Arrow
Oscar culture.
You'd have all these fucking people from
the Amazon.
That would be fine because they're fed,
they're fine,
they'd be absolutely fine.
They know how to survive,
you know,
they know,
they know how
to do it.
So again,
I think the message of this is we
shouldn't be arrogant and complacent in
the achievements of our civilization.
We have done wonderful and amazing
things as well as terrible things,
but we shouldn't be arrogant or
complacent about it.
We should recognize it's all very
fragile.
It can be taken away from us at anytime.
We can take it away from ourselves
without a doubt.
The information is something to
consider.
Just the information about these,
these impacts.
It's something to consider and it's also
something to consider that if that's
correct,
for what a magical time it must have
been back when they had developed some
sort of technology that was enabling
them to make structures like go Beckley
tap is why I'm magicians of the gods
because there's something magical.
Something about it that we would,
we would call magic perhaps was just
another another form of science.
Well,
yeah,
whatever they were able to do.
I mean,
it's amazing that we haven't figured it
out yet,
but we're so arrogant in our assumptions
that it had to be all the ways that
we've already figured out.
He's so silly,
like isn't there some shit we haven't
figured out exactly like this new,
this new ability to.
They've just found out that they've
taken people and they've used the
internet to send information for more
person's mind or another person saying
that 5,000
miles away.
It's incredible,
but nobody else did that before that and
so we didn't really think that that was.
We thought maybe it'd be a possibility,
but now we know it's possibility.
Whatever the fuck they did to make these
pyramids like just because we haven't
figured it out yet,
it doesn't mean that we're using wooden
rollers,
like they could have had some really
incredible technology that we don't have
a trace of it anymore.
We're looking at a full of technology
that we don't recognize as exactly
because we're.
We're programmed thinking about entirely
on our own terms and it's almost like
the universe is giving us a puzzle that
so incredibly in your face with its most
obvious results and because because we
have these preconceived notions that
we're not willing to accept that as a
possibility.
Like when people look at the pyramids,
they go,
well,
you know,
the thing is they build ramps and they
use stone rowers and like there's a
whole faction who will look for the most
boring,
meaningless might've,
but they might've done it,
but they might've done that.
But the fact that that there are large
groups of people whose mission is to
look for the most boring rather than the
most extraordinary possibility.
It's good.
That's how we have bonds in our society.
We do need to look.
We do need to look with a skeptical eye
and say that there could be mundane
explanations for this,
but we also need to keep a tiny fraction
of our research effort.
Perhaps a very small fraction indeed to
exploring alternative alternative ideas.
Because every night if they do come out
right,
they change everything in the way that
the mundane things don't and it's really
worthwhile and the only thing I'm
understand why I've been subjected to so
much criticism and I welcome it,
I've I've learnt a great deal from that
criticism,
but is it wise for us to live in a
society which is hostile to the
exploration of extraordinary
possibilities?
Shouldn't we actually protect
that and make that something which,
which we encourage those who wish to do
so in our society to do just on the off
chance that they might come up with
something utterly world changing,
especially if it's done with careful
consideration like you've done or
especially like with Randall Crawson's
done with asteroidal impacts is
absolutely stunning and fascinating.
I mean,
and what he's done is done with very
careful consideration.
Absolutely rattles real.
He's a real scholar,
real thorough researcher and
investigator and he was awesome.
And the podcasts wasn't one of my all
time favorites.
Right?
Yet these,
these ideas are fascinating,
but what I was gonna say was that it's
almost like the number is so large,
like 2 million,
300,000
stones in the Great Pyramid,
which is so bizarre.
The numbers in tons.
Yeah.
The number of 50 to 70 tons roofing.
The king's chamber elevated to heights
of 300 feet above the ground.
It's almost perfectly aligned to true
north,
south,
east and West within a fraction of a
single degree.
You know,
so crazy that the like if they could
come back from,
from the past and if they come to our
time today and go,
wait a minute,
how did you guys think we did that?
You think we use slaves?
Oh my God.
That's so funny.
Yeah,
yeah.
You've got to come over here,
man.
Tell him,
tell him how you think we made the
pyramids.
Slaves on would get the fuck out of
here.
Yeah,
exactly.
Like laughing like you guys haven't
invented this magneto thing yet and it's
something that allows you to turn to you
turn things with staff with sound.
Yeah.
You don't know how to manifest things
out of the air.
I don't know how to exercise the
majestic and incredible power of your
mind just running out of time.
We are unfortunately running out of
time.
Can I say it again?
Yes,
please.
Because I am a big playlist.
Please,
please,
if anybody out there we'd like to take
me up on this offer.
Just go to Graham Hancock.com.
Go to the war God page,
which you'll find easily.
Scroll down and see what to write to me,
but I have to repeat again.
I will send you the book plates,
but I can't correspond.
Correspond and it will be November
before I'm in a position to send the
book plates because I'm on the road
continuously until the 27th Graham
Hancock Dot Com.
Graham Hancock Dotcom.
I.
My goal is to make this so successful
that you never make another offer ever
again.
I wanna I wanna ruin you.
You can't sign all these things.
Too many coming in and you're like,
what the fuck am I doing?
Why Am I.
I can't do this.
This is my whole life now,
so now it's.
This would be the last one.
I think it'll probably be the last one.
By the way,
this.
There's chapters to read free online on
the [inaudible] page as well,
so I'm not asking people to buy sight
unseen.
They can have a look beautiful and your
book,
fingerprints of the Gods.
I've said it before when you've been on
the podcast for changed my single
handedly changed my ideas about history,
changed my ideas,
not just not in any way discounting the
amazing work that traditional
traditional historians have done,
but just that these things exist that
defy explanation and that I didn't know.
Just the fact that there is a guy from
Boston University named Robert Shaw
who's a prominent geologists who said
this is clear erosion and there was last
time there was rosie was 9,000
BC,
like you're talking about.
An insane amount of time has passed
since there was thousands of years of
that rain fall.
By the way,
you needed thousands of years to do what
we see on this.
This isn't wind like this is some crazy
shit and that's what I try to do.
Fingerprints was to bring together
people like John Anthony West who
brought Robert show up to this fixate,
Robert Duvall,
like random rose,
phlegm,
math,
a lot of researchers who were working in
the field and coming out with
extraordinary information and part of
what I did in that book was was to bring
all that information together into a
kind of synthesis.
I suppose
it's such an interesting theory and it's
such an interesting subject and now that
it seeps getting substantiated by places
like go Beckley,
tappy or these micro meteors that sort
of piece the puzzle together.
Slowly but surely,
I think as time goes on,
we're going to find there's going to be
a bunch of civilizations that we uncover
those ones that are finding in Mexico,
and then of course there's ones that
they're finding in the Amazon with a
thing just like we were talking about
the other.
They find a hill and they think it's a
hill,
and then someone realized.
I was like,
Holy Shit,
this is a.
This is a building guys.
Huge earthworks in the Amazon stone
circles.
You know?
That's another place to look for a lost
civilization.
We're out of time.
That's it,
right?
Or we're dying.
We're dying.
How much time we have.
It's counting down.
How much time give me seconds.
Less than a man.
Alright.
Thank you.
Thank you Graham.
Hancock sponsors.
Thanks to me undies.
Thanks to Tim and uh,
thanks to draft kings.com.
Go there and do that and use those codes
that were all earlier.
Send them earlier.
Just fucking rewind that.
Uh,
but thank you also to everybody tuning
into this podcast and thanks for all the
positive feedback and everything.
Go to Graham Hancock.com,
Graham Hancock Dot com and order the
book.
Thank you sir.
Appreciate it.
Thanks Joe.
It's been fun.
Say Bye.
Good bye everybody.