Rogan experience,
how did it humble you?
Like in what way?
Because I realized that
when we were.
Let's see when,
when I'm,
when I film a documentary and I'm soften
men,
I film a documentary called when they
grow in.
I'm in Cape Verde two years ago.
Negro?
Yeah.
Iguana.
Does that mean black water events in
Portuguese and then we were there for
about five weeks,
five or six weeks and then the living
conditions were really bad
and there was no grocery stores around
and we had to catch my own food and it
was really a self sufficient type of
chip.
In the first week I remember the only
thing I could focus on was,
oh God,
this is.
This is terrible.
The we don't have a shower.
There's no hot water and bathrooms are
disgusting.
I'm starving is nothing around.
And then all you can thing is like how
you comfort is gone and after a week
that's the.
The focus changed on the good things I
we're seeing around us and why having
nothing all of a sudden then I was like,
oh,
I actually now for the first time in my
life can take the time to realize what's
good around me and then how we were
having fires with the neighbors and then
how we were offering and fish and we
were like,
oh,
you know,
if I give this guy to fish is going to
eat one today and then one tomorrow.
But no,
the inviting neighbors to share when
they make sure that it was like a whole,
like community sends to all of it and I
was like,
wow,
I've been living in London for six
years.
I don't even know the name of the
neighbor.
And it's,
it's,
it's bad.
It's just not a way of living that I
want.
It's not focusing in a right thing is.
And it's,
it was that,
that's in that way,
you know,
it's realized how much of how much of an
asshole we actually became and I just
didn't want to do that.
The moment the cameras went off,
muscle walkie twists that a spoon and
started getting it to twist.
The producer had a complete mental
breakdown.
Now,
up to this point,
I'm just thinking this is tricks,
right?
It's not,
it's not that big of a deal.
He starts screaming,
yelling that rain,
he's evil,
should never have listened to randy.
He woulda got this on tape.
If it wasn't for Randy and he looks down
and he's got a wet spot on the front of
his pants and he looks down and he says,
I just had a demonic ejaculation,
like literally,
and he's having a mental breakdown.
I go and I have to spend the night,
which was not a bad thing.
She was quite pleasant,
um,
to look at his,
his assistant.
I had to spend the night with her in her
room because randy was calling her.
I'm not randy.
I mean,
uh,
Tony editable calling her.
The producer was calling her
consistently screaming and yelling about
randy and this scared the fuck up.
You can't just gloss over the fact that
guy just noted in his pants and he was
yelling,
you're just to.
He had a mental.
It's a mental breakdown.
Orgasm in your pants during a mental
breakdown.
I didn't it.
He did it.
You should document that.
That's more impressive than spending a
spoon.
I should've said,
yeah,
that's my psychic ability working right
there.
I mean,
that doesn't make any sense.
So he,
he tells you this as an ejaculation
pants.
He in front of everybody.
He says it's a demonic ejaculation.
East straight up says I.
The Arctic ejaculation seems like a
together guy with definitely got a head
on his shoulders.
He was a producer for,
I think it was BBC,
if I'm not mistaken.
He was doing a documentary for them,
so yeah.
Well,
he's fucking crazy.
Huh?
He finished.
He finished a documentary,
so.
Oh,
well.
Yeah,
definitely.
It wasn't crazy though.
As long as he finished.
He.
Well,
he believed in psychic phenomena.
He also believed that a demon made them
come in his pants.
That is true.
How are we going to do this?
Cowboy?
What are we going to do short RBC up?
When I run out of air,
I'm now thinking in my mind,
how am I going to die?
Gel,
right?
Tell my wife telling my kid I'm not
fucking.
I'm coming home now.
I got to fucking realize how am I going
to die.
I have a notepad that you carry in your
pocket to draw and write on.
I'm thinking,
what?
What?
What are you going to say?
What's your.
What's your letter going to be?
Your writing fucking death later.
You're awake.
You're a fighter.
We figure this out.
Don't fucking find a way to quit.
You fucking bitches the conversation.
I'm having one result while I'm in
fucking complete panic mode in complete
darkness thinking that there's no.
This is how people die.
What the fuck are you doing?
You're going to write a letter to your
fucking kid and tell her how you.
How you fucked up.
I'm sorry.
Daddy's not coming home.
So I'm fucking thinking.
I'm not going to drown.
I'm not going to breathe my last breath,
so I'm going to breathe this BC that
just fill up with air and I'm a fucking
breathe it until the oxygen level no
longer happens.
I just pass out.
That's,
that's my.
That's where I've come to realize how
I'm going to die.
I'm going to fucking just slip away and
pass out.
Keep breathing the same air until
I go away and I started thinking,
you fucking piece of shit.
You're giving up like the year having
legitimate conversations with myself
while fucking complete panic.
Like you're,
you're going to quit that.
You're writing a letter and you're gonna
fucking breathe your last leg.
You pass out,
you fucking pussy.
You're a fighter.
Figured the fuck out.
So I'm upside down.
Growing on the ceiling.
I remember when I came in,
came in the big cave.
It was like a huge fucking crack that
runs along the top turn.
Both my watch is off now at this point
because they're giving off light and I
kill my light and I said that cracked
gonna fucking lead to the surface.
That cracks going to fucking give us
something.
So I just called start panicking,
me panicking you again because I'm
panicking.
I don't know what to do.
I'm sucking air and I'm fucking
breathing hard and I'm hyperventilating
and crying and crying on the ceiling,
looking for this fucking cracking.
Goddammit.
I found it.
I found the crack and I followed the
crack and the crack got bigger and all
of a sudden I see fucking glow.
Like green glow.
Crawl on Cron.
Cron.
Find it.
Try to get up.
My tags are too big.
I can't fucking get out of the little
hole.
Can't get out of the hole.
I'm fucking big B.
Big,
big fucking hitting.
Screaming,
freaking out.
Calm down.
Calm down,
Kelly.
This is the way.
Calm the fuck down.
Reel it in.
We're here.
We made it.
Grab control.
Follow the cracks more.
Opens up out.
Boom.
There's the K fucking I'm out.
Made it.
You're coming home.
You aren't doug about
that was the feeling.
Meanwhile,
my guys out there,
I can't be mad at him because he
panicked.
He grabbed the line,
he fucking ran out the whole.
He looks at me and he says,
um,
so we're not diving together ever again.
I said,
no,
that was it.
That was it.
And I texted my girl,
I love you baby.
And uh,
there was a fucking scary moment,
but daddy's coming home.
What is it like to have Jordan Peterson
as a dad?
Is it weird?
Do you have to check yourself
constantly?
Make sure you're on,
on steady ground?
And I'd say anything ridiculous.
No,
not at all.
Not at all.
I didn't realize it was weird until I
went away to university and then kind of
style.
I was away for awhile and then when I
came back to the house,
especially because the house was full of
like paintings and masks and statues and
like 32 different paint colors and they
came back and was like,
oh,
maybe he's a bit eccentric.
No,
he's definitely eccentric.
Um,
we were talking off air about what it
was like to watch your dad become famous
and become famous in his fifties,
right?
Like,
yeah,
54,
55.
That's when it became famous before that
relatively unknown,
respected professor.
One issue with this one transgender bill
or the the,
the preferred pronouns bill,
and then boom off to the races.
Yeah,
that's strange.
It was.
Yeah.
It was super weird.
Especially how the media was portraying
him and how what was actually happening
at the events wasn't what was being
portrayed in the media,
so that was weird to watch and then
people recognizing him on the street is
strange.
It's.
Yes,
it's.
When you say what,
what happened in real life was not what
was being portrayed like what was
different.
Mostly what he was saying.
So most of what he said is on film
anyway,
so you can go to youtube and see what
he's been saying like not there's not
like some secret that's going around,
but what's been portrayed has been so
much more negative than what he's
actually said.
Or they'll take like sound bites and
just weave a story that isn't quite
true.
Which I didn't read it for some reason.
I now it looks silly,
but for some reason I just thought that
what the media was portraying was
honest.
Always.
Yeah.
Me Too.
And it's not.
They're trapped in there and they can't
write,
get out.
They.
They didn't have an
option to say,
I don't want to see them.
It's really interesting.
All the different spins though.
All the different women's spins in w.
One one really bizarre spin that I saw
was this one was saying that this is
indicative of the problem of all comedy
clubs and aggressive male audience and
women sitting there feeling threatened,
not being able to use their voice.
I'm like user voice.
Like what are you gonna heckle?
You were saying like you like you would
be more empowered if there were more
women so you could heckle is.
That's not cool.
Like you're not supposed to do that at a
comedy club.
Have you.
Don't like someone just don't laugh,
but like one's,
here's the thing.
It's not your job or it's not your place
to say that you don't like someone when
the other people do like it.
You know if you're right,
if you're going to get up and walk out.
Yeah.
Just like you're going to see a movie.
Like you're an audience member,
right?
The deal is you're not there to perform,
the audience is there to just sit there
and laugh or not laugh,
but don't be rude to the other people
that are enjoying it.
So as soon as you break your
sensibilities above,
the rest of the audience will.
You are a problem,
right?
You've made.
If you decide like,
hey,
I didn't like this,
I'm going to go home and write about it.
That's totally your prerogative.
That's fine.
Get up and walk out.
Go somewhere else and talk about it on
stage yourself.
Nothing wrong with any of those things,
but this,
this one woman's take was like,
women don't feel like they have a.
They can.
They have the ability to speak out about
it.
I'm like,
speak out like so you're saying like to
heckle,
Hey,
I don't want you on stage.
I know everything about you and your
story.
I want you to perform in front of me.
Even those other people laughing,
right?
And that these aggressive men were
yelling.
Good to see you back.
Louis aggressive men like,
okay,
that's like there's a framing of this
and this is one of its becomes this male
versus female framing that sort of
represents aggressive men,
sexual men doing things to women they
don't want.
The women are sitting there in silence.
They don't want to be there and they
don't have a voice because they feel
overwhelmed and out overpopulated or a
outnumbered.