Zealot. Yeah. Did you start, did you
launch that was the mail. Guess what?
No sponsors. Just fucking cue the music
and it give you a dollar at least. Yes.
Give me a book. All right, cool. Hit it.
Experience you podcast my night.
All Day.
Yeah, we have music. It's ridiculous,
but it makes me feel like
something's actually happening.
[inaudible] Sam Harris.
Ladies and gentlemen, thanks for
joining me, man. This is really cool.
It's an excellent opportunity.
The internets or a buzz.
I've gotten more response for this as far
as like questions for you then I think
any, any guests we've ever had.
Great. Well I'm very happy to be here.
I'm happy here too, man. I've
watched a lot of your videos online.
I've enjoyed every one of them and I like
in some of those debates that you get
into with those old
Gracie in action videos.
Have you ever seen those
old Gracie in action videos?
I'm not entirely sure though.
I know the ones you're talking about.
I've seen a lot of Gracie material.
Yeah,
well the Gracie in action videos were
really the first videos that Horian Gracie
Horian. Gracie, a WHO's a hit,
Leo's son, voices brothers,
a brilliant businessman,
and he realized that all he needed to do
was put together a series of real life
encounters between a train
Jujitsu practitioner and
some guy who thinks he knows
how to fight.
He's,
he's sure he knows how to fight and
then he just gets mangled every time,
every single foot. This wasn't
the Gracie challenge at all? Well,
they've got a bunch of them.
I mean there's Gracies Gracie and
action one and two. There's essentially,
it's just,
it's,
it's basically just compilations of
home videos that they have of really for
martial artists, really brilliant
stuff to watch because you know,
until the Gracies came along,
nobody really knew that there was one
guy out there that could just sort of
manhandle people like that and
just strangle them and children.
If there was one martial art that was
so superior when it came to grappling
situation that you would watch those
and you'd almost feel bad for the guy
getting strangled,
but not really.
That's how I feel when I watch a lot
of your debates. That's very high
praise.
I can tell you it's not as satisfying
in a debate format as it is on the mat.
Oh I'm sure cause it cause no
one ever taps. It's like you're,
it's like you're fighting,
you know,
an army of zombies that
they've lost but they, they,
they can't be forced to
admit that they've lost
it.
Says it's must be a very bizarre thing
for you because as far as like people who
have spent like hours and hours debating
publicly debating the merits or the
idea of religion, you might be like, you
know, like top 10 on youtube of all the,
the, the different
information that's available.
Have you ever seen anybody in all these
different debates you've been where you,
you've knocked something into their
head and you see like a light go off.
Like Holy Shit, what if you,
right. Do you ever get that?
Well it's hard to see in real time.
People are pretty good about not having
epiphany's in real time in front of you.
You know, so, so yeah,
you can see people get uncomfortable and
you can see them want to make a lateral
move to a new subject. Cause there's,
there's a lot of, uh, I mean,
one of the great strategies or,
or the one of the,
the less noble but effective
strategies of debate is too,
if you've lost a point, you just
don't, you don't concede it,
you just kind of move on to something
else and hope no one notices. And if,
and in, in a formal debate, a format,
there's often no mechanism by which to
sort of for your opponent to score that
as,
as conquered ground because you like,
you can't address each
other in real time. So, so,
so it's like I talked for 10 minutes,
someone else talks for 10 minutes.
The moderator doesn't
necessarily interrupt us and we,
the two discussions can't
actually address one another.
So a formal debates are actually,
um,
ironically the kind of the worst
format to actually prove who's right,
because it's like fighting someone, you
know, vert you're, so you're separated by,
it's, it's like, it's like boxing, you
know, it's like the clinic, you get a,
you get a clinch and the
ref separates you. Um,
and so you can't really test every tool,
uh,
in that context. And so, um,
you can just kind of talk past each
other and not address the thing that was
brought up 10 minutes ago and it never
really gets scored. So it's, it's, it's,
um,
it's amazingly unsatisfying even when
you feel like you have said exactly what
you should have said and you, because
they just won't buy it. It's just like,
just like fighting with fog, you know,
no one never, no one ever falls down and,
and it's occasionally you, you, you
score, you score below that, you know,
the audience has noticed. But even
then the audience is partitioned into,
you know, the, the, the, your side and
the other side. And it's amazing how, um,
in vulnerable people's prejudices
and biases are to two argument.
So it'd be an also becomes a team, you
know, become something that defines,
you know, a lot of people
are defined by their ideas,
especially when it comes to their
religion or their politics. You know,
they're defined by them to
the point where they like,
act within certain parameters because
they think that's what you're supposed to
do if you're on this team, people like
that. For somebody. I mean, it's a weird,
creepy desire that we
have to become part of a,
of a team and defend that team. And
I think that happens when, when,
when it gets into religious arguments,
it's like you're,
you're not just attacking an idea that
someone planted in their head and you're,
you're, you're attacking how they
define themselves. Yeah. It is. It's,
it's people's extended identity.
I'm a windows user. Yeah.
It's like I'm, I'm a Christian, I'm
a Catholic. And it becomes, you know,
it really becomes a big part of how they
view and if you want to take that away
from them, it's like, you know, yeah.
So you can see that when
you're having the discussion,
it's especially obvious in a debate
format because they basically,
nobody has any hope that that either
side is going to change their mind in the
context of the debate.
I mean,
they've come there to represent their
views and they've got so much invested in
doing as well as as they can that they're
not, even if they're mine was changed,
they're not going to admit it. It. So
it's not really an honest discussion.
But when you are having
an honest discussion,
let's say we know one on one with
somebody of deep conviction about faith,
you can,
you can see the kind of the emotional
hijacking of the conversation on their
side very quickly.
It's like,
it's basically like debating whether
they're their wife is attractive or
something.
I mean,
it's just like a goes to something at
the core and it's no longer about the
ideas or evidence or, or, um,
and so that it's one skill,
which admittedly I,
I don't have a such a firm grasp on,
but one skill to acquire just as a
person is to figure out how to have these
conversations where you're, where
you're, you're being as rational and,
and intellectually honest as possible,
but you're actually kind of making the
right Jujitsu moves around people's
emotional response because it's just
too with comedy. Well, yeah, I that,
that's what's brilliant about comedy.
Yeah. You do it with comedy. Well,
I've seen you do it, you know, compared
to Elvis being alive, you know,
and knowing that Elvis is alive,
feeling that he's alive. Yeah.
It was really very funny how you did it.
And it was the perfect way
to do it because you did
it very politely. You know,
there was no name calling. You didn't
get all shouty. Yeah, yeah. But that,
that is what is brilliant about
pure comedy because if you,
if you make someone
laugh at themselves or,
or the idea that they
would otherwise defend, um,
you know, you've, that that actually
is a visible sign that you have,
you have made contact, you know,
cause it's, and, and you don't get,
you don't get that when you,
when you're playing it totally straight.
And so comedy is very powerful.
Yeah.
Also,
obviously you're restricted
in the language that you
can use and these things,
right. It's, um, it is a,
a fascinating sort of a,
and an exchange. It's a, it's fascinating
to watch the psychological. We'll spin,
you know, when, when people
really get behind an idea,
whether it's religion or
whatever the fuck it is, when,
when they really get behind it
to the point where, you know,
they're not budging at all.
They're not thinking at all.
They're attached and married to it. It's
very dangerous. Right. I mean, isn't it?
Oh, well, yeah,
insofar as someone really
believes something and the
beliefs have any point of
contact with behavior and the rest
of physical reality, I think it's,
it's, it's the most consequential thing.
I think what people believe is, yeah,
that is the,
the lever that moves most things in
our world. You know, it's politics,
it's public policy, it's the laws
we write in the law as we choose to,
to truly defend and,
and they're all just ideas that are,
that have a certain number of subscribers.
Is it
possible that religion in its form is
useful for some people because they're
just what a,
whether it's psychologically they need,
they need some scaffolding,
whether it's, you know,
Eh, to use it as a tool, not
to use it to control anyone,
but to use it as like a personal growth
tool. Do you ever look at it like that?
Well,
in so far as it can be taken out
of the belief space where it says,
so there's, there's the, the, the
doctrinal belief based part of religion,
which is where people are making
claims about reality on bad evidence.
And that I,
that's just a problem.
I mean so far as your pretending to be
certain about something you shouldn't be
certain about and then
teaching your kids to do that.
That's just a problem for our,
for our conversation with one another.
As human beings,
there's,
there's all this other stuff that people
are attached to that isn't inherently
problematic. So they liked the music,
they liked the buildings, they like the,
the style, you know, they like
the artwork. They like the, um,
they like to think about certain historic
figures who they have this sort of
emotional bonding widths or GNC.
They love the stories about Jesus
in the New Testament. And, um,
all of that is, uh, some of that
could be intrinsically good. I mean,
if you get the right,
you get beautiful buildings and beautiful
music and a reason to come together
and holidays and Mso.
So I think we actually want something
very much like that in secular culture.
And we,
and we,
I think are suffering from the fact that
we don't have an obvious alternative,
a secular, reasonable, reasonable
alternative to that, um,
that we can just point religious
people to and say, no way, no,
how come you're not doing
that? You know, this,
this has everything you want without the
bullshit. That's very important. And,
you know, if someone tried to form
some sort of a secular group like that,
it would quickly devolve into
being a cult, most likely. Yeah.
Depending on who become someone
trying to fuck everybody's wife. Well,
we had some other top that comes when
someone's at the top who has the eternal
wisdom, uh, and it is important to you.
And part of that process of
dispensation is to fuck your wife.
Uh, that there's actually a story. I,
I think I had told in an end note at
the end of faith, I knew some guys who,
who brought out a guru from India
who they just thought was just the,
quite literally the Messiah who's,
he was a story.
They kind of naked yoga and the yoga who
just for this little little, uh, um, uh,
almost a speedo track a speedo. Yeah.
Like a and long Jetta, you know,
long dreadlocks and he's kind of this
kind of gorgeous 25 year old Indian Sato
who was silent,
so he wouldn't even never speak.
So though the only wisdom is very
kind of low bandwidth teaching,
the only wisdom you're going to get from
him is what he could write out on a,
on a, like an eight by 10 chalkboard.
So he'd write these, you know,
just gnomic little sentences in
response to your, your questions.
And he was a really good drummer.
So he would leave these curtains,
these devotional chanting, uh, uh,
sessions where he would drum and people
would get a quote quite out of their
minds and happy. And so they were just
worshiping this guy. They brought him out.
Um,
and at a certain point he can be,
I don't know how,
he must have communicated
this on his chalkboard.
He said he needed to start sleeping
with the various, you know, um, uh, as,
as luck would have it, the, the most
beautiful wives of his devotees. Um,
and so he was doing that and, but
the breaking point came when, uh, uh,
the one guy who was his host whose
wife was sleeping with him, um,
gave him Haagen Daz this Saudi wanted to,
to eat Haagen Daz Vanilla ice cream with
cashews for breakfast. So that was like,
he, someone gave him Haagen
Daas and it blew his mind.
And so he needed this for
breakfast. Uh, so the,
so he was Wa this guy was
walking through the, you know,
like the Ralph's a
freezer aisle at, at, uh,
in the morning getting us a
resupply of vanilla ice cream.
And that was the moment that was the,
that was the,
the final Straw where he realized,
okay, this guy is, is just,
we're just guys tool. And they just send
them back in India, you know, he's like,
you put the ice cream back on the shelf.
That's hilarious. Hacker bags. Yeah. No,
it wasn't, it wasn't the wife.
It was the, it was the hug.
That's ridiculous.
So what did the Haagen daas
just represents something
so silly that it couldn't
be,
it was just, it was just too obviously
carnal. You know? Like there's no Tantra.
You might,
you might be doing tantra with my wife,
but you're not doing top drawer with the
Haagen daas for breakfast Muesli Card
or ice cream.
That's very funny. Yeah, man.
I mean, I think it's just a,
the primate instinct when any man is
in any position where he's got ultimate
power over a group of people.
It's a terrible idea. Yeah.
That's why everybody's afraid of what's
going on right now was in terms of,
you know, government and new laws are
being passed every day. It's, it's good.
It gets kind of spooky.
It's like how much control do you
really need over people? Is this is,
I understand that you know,
we're in trouble some times.
I understand that we're at war,
but do you really? How much,
how much control does the
government really deserve
over people? I mean do, do we,
do we really need to be in this
situation we're in right now?
I, I, I'm, for the most part,
I'm kind of libertarian on
this subject. I mean, I'm not,
I get a lot of flack from Libertarians
based on, on the, you know,
the 5% where I depart from, you
know, classic libertarianism,
but like actual defense authorization,
you know, I just think ea,
the principle is that peaceful,
honest peoples have the right to be
left alone. You know, if someone,
if you're not harming other people and
you're not stealing from them and you're
not yet, and you're honoring
your contracts, you know,
maybe we can define what all that means.
But if you are not an infringing on
other people's happiness, then you have,
you should have the
right to be left alone.
And what that means is we as a society
shouldn't want the police to kick in the
door of a peaceful,
honest person to stop him from doing,
from what whatever it is he's doing,
smoking pot or you know, you know,
whatever victimless crime
is currently illegal.
And if you draw the line there,
I think get a very sane,
a response or very sane idea of
the limits of, of state power.
Um, and, and it's, um, yeah, it's, it's,
it's all about mitigating harm
and keeping people safe. Now,
now obviously we can't,
we can only,
there's a trade off between freedom and,
and risk.
So, you know, there's a
tension between let's say, um,
the, the right to privacy and
finding actual terrorists,
you know, so it's like if we,
if we, if we wanted to maximize,
we're going to find everyone who's a
terrorist, well then we would just,
there'd be no such
thing as privacy and we,
every day the government could read
all our email and looking our windows,
et cetera. So there's, there's
a tension there and we,
and we have to keep finding the, the,
um, the sweet spot, but it's, it's a,
it's a tension that
everyone should recognize.
So do you think that these new laws
are being passed, like the Nda,
do you think that that's the idea
is that as the population increases,
as is crime going to keep up or pick up
to a point where they're going to need
something like this? I mean, when,
when you think of someone being able to
detain people without warrants and not
even have to inform their family and that,
that could be an American citizen,
I mean, at what point in
time would that be effective?
You know? Yeah, I don't see, and again,
this is not really my area to have a
very strong opinion. So, uh, you know,
I would be open to any counter argument
on this, but I've never seen the, the, um,
the wisdom or necessity of
infringing on our existing laws to,
to fight the war on terror. So the idea
that, you know, the people at Guantanamo,
I'm,
I understand that there,
there were different things apply on
a battlefield and, and, uh, you know,
in a crime fighting scenario
in, in, you know, in the states.
But I mean,
why,
why people don't have the right to
counsel or the right to see the evidence
against them. I just, it seems like
it's crazy if they're guilty, you know,
they'll let let the, the truth
shine on the, on the data.
Well what do we hurt is that
we were always, you know,
growing up there was always a problem
with Russia and there was always this idea
that we could go to war with Russia,
but there wasn't like a really strong
belief amongst people that we were the
good guys and then we did all
good guys stuff. Only you know,
that America was making sure the rest of
the world didn't start speaking German
or Japanese or any case. But it doesn't
feel like that anymore, you know?
Now it seems like as the
age of information has
gotten us to this 2012 date,
like where we're at right now,
it's so easy to get information that
people are just so much more cynical about
their intentions.
So if you see laws like this,
like what's the motivation to
crack down more on civil liberties?
He said just to make it easier
for them. I mean, is it to,
to create bigger government? What,
when, what is the motivation for that?
Well,
it's,
it is fear and some perception
of necessity of, of,
of, of taking the friction
out of, of the system,
the system that that would keep us safe
or respond to an attack or detect an
attack.
Um,
and it's understandable when you think
about what the President's daily briefing
must look like. You know, it's like,
it's gotta be absolutely terrifying. And,
and the,
the reality of the prospect of nuclear
terrorism is like once you actually just
put those goggles on and say,
yes,
the nuclear non proliferation
proliferation is more
or less a lost cause.
I mean, the, the technology is
spreading, the material is spreading.
He got a 30,000 out of work scientists
in the former Soviet Union who have
every, who are not
taking care of, you know,
who have every economic incentive
to not be entirely ethical. Um,
so if you feel as many people do this,
just a matter of time,
that new,
a nuke in some form gets into the
hands of terrorists and we have a,
a massively porous border.
The joke is if you want to get nukes
into the the U s you just hide it,
hide it in a bale of marijuana.
I mean, it's like we can't,
we can't fight the war on drugs. So the
idea that we can keep everything out is,
is pretty much a pipe dream.
So,
so when you start thinking about the idea
of a new going off in a major American
city and forget about the loss of life,
just what would that do to
the world economy? It's,
it's easy to see how the paranoia get
ramps up. So I, you know, I don't,
it's a hard, these are obviously
hard calls to make for,
for anyone and um,
you're going to look,
just imagine the day after
and an act of terrorism,
orders of magnitude bigger
than September 11th, what?
W two to have to talk about the reasons
why we didn't do all these things that
we could have done to keep, to
keep us safe. So I'm very much,
I mean I share your concerns about
infringing on civil liberties, but, uh,
it's just the way you
look. Scary. It's scary.
Or on the other side it scared
the threat is scarier. The fire,
I think the threat of,
of nuclear terrorism is
quite real. And, and, and,
and anyone who thinks that it's not,
or that's just fearmongering.
Um, I just think it's not,
it's not reading, reading the,
the books or papers of,
of experts who, who,
whose job it is to actually worry about
this. Uh, it's just, it's just not a,
uh, it's a real, it's a real problem. Uh,
so, uh, the question is in the
face of that, what do you do? Uh,
and you know,
I'm as annoyed as the thing you don't
do is force everyone to take their shoes
off in airports until the end of time.
I mean,
so like we're so inefficient
in how we filter.
We filter and, and uh,
so yeah, I mean it's a,
it's, it's a big problem.
That's a problem. Actually.
I don't know that much about,
I mean, my file on what we should do
is, it's pretty thin, but it's, it's,
it's pretty clear that,
you know,
every time I'm in an airport and I see
some old Norwegian lady who obviously is
not a terrorist,
uh,
submitting to the same search as a
somebody who looks like Osama bin Ladin.
Um, I, it seems like a
misallocation of attentional
resources. So yeah, it
seems ridiculous. Yeah.
It's just the idea behind it. So, and,
you know, what else freaks me out.
I was all the fucking radiation.
How much radiation of those
big body scanners is that?
Um, I don't know. I, I, but I,
I would be concerned that
the manufacturers are not
entirely candid about,
uh, or even cognizant of, of the health
effects of them. So I, I don't know.
I mean, I, I haven't seen
the data on them, but yeah,
you want to minimize the
amount of x rays you get,
but every time you want to play and you
get, you're getting dosed. So it's not,
I don't know how it compares
to the actual plane flight.
How much time are you day do you
think about nuclear terrorism?
Because if I was as you are, you know,
it's not a, it's not even every day. It's,
I put it out in my mind like,
like anyone else. Yeah. Well,
no, it's just, it's, it's,
um, the truth is, I,
I believe you asked me rationally how,
how big a risk do I think it is.
I think it's, it's a, it's a big risk.
It's not a one in a hundred risk, I think.
I think it's, well, that's what, you know,
experts like Graham Allison think in
this next decade that he wrote his book
about five years ago,
but he thought like next 10 or
20 year period, the chance of a,
a new going off in a major
American city was like 50, 50, not,
not wanting a hundred. And, and so, and,
and no one really criticized him for that.
I mean it's the people kind of a panel
of experts I think came up with 30%.
Right. So it's, but again, you're not,
you're not hearing the people say no,
it's one in a thousand, um, 30%
terrifying. It's terrifying. And,
and yet I don't feel that I have,
I don't really live with that piece of
software humming on the hard drive very
much. I haven't integrated that
into my sense of, of daily risk.
Uh, so it's, it's not entirely,
I haven't responded entirely
rational link to that information.
But with all the different books that
you've written about religion and all the
different debates that you've gotten
into with people about it, I mean,
you can't have a rosy view of
how this is going to turn out.
Do you,
do you think it's possible to,
the human race can pull out of this
[inaudible] right now to move to the next
level? Yeah, for sure. Well, I just don't,
the truth is I actually don't think in
terms of optimism and pessimism very much.
I think I'm by default,
I slightly pessimistic,
but, um, you got to
live life and you want,
we all are just sort of trying to find
our way toward the high points of, of,
of wellbeing and,
and
um, I think, uh,
I think, uh, I think culture can change
quickly. You know, that's, that's, it's,
it's easy to,
to deny how risky are our situation is.
And I think that we shouldn't do that,
but it's also easy to overlook how
quickly we can get our act together.
And so when you look at just how, I mean,
the example for me is, is the change in,
in, in views of race in the United States.
I mean, when you roll back the clock,
even 70 years,
there was just a level of racism
in this country. It was just,
it was just unrecognizable.
It's having,
it's not that racism isn't
still a problem, but people
were being lynched and,
and there would,
you know,
senators would come out and get their
photo taken in front of the dangling body.
I mean, it was, it was just insanity.
MMM.
It's amazing. When you think of
how little time has passed. Yeah,
it is a very good point. Yeah. We will.
Racism probably is the one thing that
we've made the biggest amount of progress.
Yeah. Yeah. As far as culturally. Yeah.
And it's, it's, it's undeniable
progress. It's, it's,
and it's progress of a sword that it's
very hard to pick or what would cause us
to sort of roll that back. I mean, I, it
feels like those are gains kind of just,
just gains in terms of standing
that we can't, can't lose.
I don't think we've fully felt the
impact of the Internet on culture either
because the first couple of generations
who grew up exclusively with the full
access to information like that,
they haven't really reached adulthood yet.
And once,
you know,
once these kids that grew up with the
internet their entire life and constantly
having access to new ideas that aren't,
you know,
not regional people that they have to
talk to people in their neighborhood,
people in their state.
But instead of being able to talk to
people all over the world and get,
watch a lot of your shit
online, why don't you, you know,
watch a lot of different lectures online.
I mean that kind of,
there was nothing like that when we were
kids. The impact of that generation,
I think that's going to
be pretty substantial when
the case is now re I think
that's going to be the next
big leap of cultural evolution.
The Internet kids when they become
adults and start running shit. I think,
I think it's just the attitude online.
It does not mirror the attitude that
that's expressed in, in, in laws.
And the idea is that people have
about about, uh, about our society.
Yeah. Yeah. I,
I'm a little war. I think it, it
goes, it can go either way there.
I think the Internet enables two very
different and antagonistic processes.
On the one hand, it, it
does, it, it allows you to,
uh,
Hansel bad ideas very
quickly. It's like, it's hard.
It's very hard to lie about yourself
or about anything given access to
information. So that's, that's very good.
And it connects and people can see
how other people live. And so it's a,
all of that breaks down
barriers between people,
but it also let it out also amplify a
certain voices too in a way that never
would have happened before. And these
are, they're just terrible voices.
So for instance, Global Jihad, uh,
the phenomenon of exporting al Qaeda
style Islam to the rest of the world more
or less without friction is
entirely an internet phenomenon.
It's very hard to see that happening the
way it has in the last 10 years without
the Internet. Um, and just
just, hey, we have these,
any crazy person with his crazy idea
can create a little subculture on the
Internet and you have this walled garden
where people can just talk endlessly,
uh, in a very self confirming
way. Um, whether it's,
whether it's a certain conspiracy
theories or, or just, you know, racist,
racist subgroups, whatever.
And they, you just,
you just get in there and you never get
out and you find enough people who are
echoing back your bad ideas that you
and you never the other problems,
you never meet these people. And
then, and then also the, the, the,
the role of anonymity online. I think
it's pretty destructive. I mean,
if you've ever read a youtube comment
thread, which I'm sure you have,
it's just the most poisonous
Lucy's. Yeah. It's amazing. It's a,
if you ran into people like that in real
life, you'd want to have a sword. Yeah.
Be Hacking through them everywhere you
went. Yeah. I don't, I, I see your point.
It makes, it makes a big, uh, the,
the anonymity makes a big
difference in having a lack of any,
any sort of repercussions
for shitty behavior. Yeah.
That's not natural for humans.
It's not natural for humans to be
able to affect each other with ideas,
without social cues, without, you know,
feeling the emotions of someone whose
feelings you're hurting or you know,
to be able to do it. Like this is
just so, so cunty is what it is.
And even it's not even just inner internet
comment threads or even an amazing, I,
I find it with email, it's
like everyone's, this is,
this is now a trivial to point out,
but everyone has sent the email
that they shouldn't have sent, uh,
and watched this even a very
good relationship unravel
based on the fact that
there's, you're not being modulated
by facial cues when you're,
when you're saying,
when you're dropping these bombs on
your friend or your brother or whatever,
and it just, it's just
escalates. Oh, the other hand,
it's a good way to tell someone they're
fucking, that's what happened actually,
to get all the information
in one place. Yeah. I'd
be in the room with them and you know,
have them argue with you about it,
you know, and that sense. Right? Yeah.
So when,
when you look at the possibility of
nuclear terrorism and, uh, you know,
you're, you're a fairly
young guy, you know,
and you look at all this is
insanity and chaos in the world.
What way do you think is going to be the
way out of this? Is it a technological,
I mean,
what's,
what's going to elevate people or make
people's ideas evolve to the point where
they realize that this idea
is a completely ridiculous
nuclear wars? Absolutely.
A kid can't even be on the table. It can't
be an option for anyone in the world.
What's going to get us to that?
Well, it's a, it's a big
question. I think one, uh,
one piece of it is so accurate. It's
connects back with something you said,
this idea that we are the good guys and
that our enemies are aren't and there's,
there's not actually moral parody between
the two sides and in these conflicts.
I think that's still true.
You know, Guantanamo Bay,
it can be make it as bad as you want it.
It's still true that we're the good guys
in, in this particular conflict. And,
um,
now I wish we were better than we are and
there's obviously some bad guys on our
side and in any given moment, but, um,
I think the one thing we
have to get past is this,
the kind of moral relativism that you,
you tend to hear from the left. Um,
and I'm, I'm very much on the left in
almost every respect, but, uh, this,
this disempowering idea that we,
uh,
so for instance, to talk
about nuclear bombs, you know,
we should [inaudible] what gives us the
right to have nuclear bombs. If, if we,
if we are going to have them,
Iran should have them. You know,
we have no argument to keep Iran a
nuclear free if we keep oms ourselves.
Well, we're a very different from Iran
at this moment. We're not, you know,
our president doesn't get in front of
the microphone and say that he's going to
wipe out a turned turn a
country into a lake of fire. Um,
and he's not waiting for the Messiah to
come back and, and, and rapture everybody.
Now,
if we had a sufficiently crazy president,
well then all of a sudden we
would have a similar liability,
but we're not using,
we're,
we're not prone to use nuclear bombs
in a flagrantly crazy apocalyptic way.
And we don't know from
everything. Iran says, uh,
they certainly seem capable of being just
as crazy as as we could fear. And so,
um, that's, that's a difference that,
that we have to just acknowledge.
And so it matters who gets
the bombs. And if, if,
if people who are quite
zealous to die, uh, who,
you know, people who are literally happy
to set off the bomb in their laps, uh,
just for the pleasure of setting it off,
uh,
that's a very different kind of
mind to be engaged with. And,
and it, it raises the stakes. It's not a
rat there. These people are not rational.
I'm not saying the entire Muslim
world fits this description, but,
but there are people who are not rational
actors based on their ideology. I mean,
they want to get to paradise.
You know,
they think you win if you blow the
place up at the right moment. Um,
and the moment take on board that
certain people actually believe that,
then you have to play a different game
with respect to the risk that they pose a
so it, so what we should do, I
think we, I think we need to one,
acknowledge that they're
very different moments of,
of tension in this world.
Those where we're dealing with rational
actors and those where we're dealing
with, with, uh,
either completely irrational actors or
actors where they have an ideology that's
motivating them to do things
that should be unthinkable. Well,
completely agree with you that we have
to be aware of a religious zealots and we
have to be aware of a crazy people
willing to blow themselves up.
But you got to wonder why they're
mad at us in the first place.
And I agree that for the
most part, I mean, I,
I think our idea still sort of holds
that we're the good guy in comparison to
the rest of the world.
Does that mean you have to be a
certain amount of evil just to keep up,
you know, just to compete? I mean,
is that what's fucked up
with our foreign policy?
Is that why we go into places like Iraq
with false information about weapons of
mass destruction, where it was, there's a
clear motivation to get in there. Right.
Well, I think you're
right. I mean, I'm not,
I'm not going to defend a rock that I
think was, was a stupid war to fight.
That's going into Afghanistan that
just ended, you know what I'm saying?
I mean that's what we're looking at.
Afghanistan is the clearer
case because we really,
I think had to go in and
after September 11th.
And so you think we had to go in tits
control al Qaeda cause well it was,
it was rational to go in and try to kill
Osama bin Ladin and, and the rest of,
of, uh, the people who brought
us September 11th. And, um,
and it was,
and we were,
we at September 11th to some degree was
a price paid for never having dealt with
these people in the first
place. I mean, they, they,
that when you listen to the chatter on
their side about how we were a paper
tiger, that, you know, they
could blow up the coal,
they could blow up embassies in Kenya.
They could, they could, you know,
w w w we got bombed in Lebanon
and we just left. I mean,
so we were scared of conflict
after Vietnam and, um,
that was noticeable to everyone on
their side. And, um, so we were,
so, to some degree, this problem was just
getting bigger and bigger and bigger.
And when you ask him,
it's possible September 11th happened
because we didn't invade Iraq earlier
cause we didn't go in Afghanistan earlier.
Well, no, we didn't deal with the
threat of, of Jihadi terrorism earlier.
Weren't they upset in the
first place because we're, we,
we have troops on their land.
Well,
you gotta be precise about exactly why
that's offensive when you look at why
Osama bin Ladin and the rest of, of, uh,
Okaydo were upset.
It was because it was not because it
was not a nationalistic concern of,
you know, we're proud Saudis and
our holy land, right. It was,
this was a theological
grievance. I mean, they were,
Osama bin Laden was
already out of sorts with,
with the Saudi government at
that point. And He's, um, uh,
a Sama and anyone else enamored of this
whole notion of global jihad want a
global caliphate. I mean this, this
is the idea that, that, that is,
that we're living in a perverse
time where Islam has been,
has been delegated and subjugated
and has a, has not yet triumph.
And the, and it has a mandate
to triumph in this world. And,
and so if you really believe that,
if you have to believe,
if you believe that you have to
fight to spread the true faith, um,
for the glory of God in this
life and win the game, you know,
Gangas con style or more relevantly
Muhammad style in this life that is,
that dictates a certain kind of
grandiosity and arrogance and,
and expansionism and people like
Osama bin Laden a really believe that.
And, and, but he was free to live a very
different life than he, than he lived.
You know, he said he didn't have to
spend his time in caves scheming to, uh,
to defeat the Great Satan. He could've
just been chilling in Paris. I mean,
he had a lot of money
and a lot of opportunity.
Do you buy the official story how they
killed him and threw him in the ocean?
Um,
I haven't thought about what might
not be true in it, but it seemed,
I basically, I buy the, I buy the official
story that we went in and killed him.
And what happened to his body?
I am or why? I'm not sure.
I think we didn't,
uh,
I think it would be amazing if he was
dead a long time ago and they just
concocted a, a crazy hero rescue story.
Jessica Lynch thing. That would be,
I think, I think the, uh, no, I mean,
cause it would have been so many other,
if you will, if you were going to fake
something like that, first of all,
it's just so hard to fake anything and
we couldn't fake Jessica Lynch. You know,
it's like,
it's like you get people's,
this is what's wrong with most it with
helicopters, right? Yeah. And it's,
it's, there's just too, eh, these things,
operations like that go wrong
spectacularly and everyone
knows about it and they
go right sometimes.
And it's very difficult to fake at the
Pakistanis aren't acting like we faked it,
you know, they're just pissed that we
actually successfully got in there.
Seal team six style and,
and, and got out. Um,
so,
but the problem with,
with any conspiracy of that sort,
and especially a bigger one,
like a nine 11 truth style conspiracy
is that it's just takes so much perfect
collaboration to bring it off.
And we know that people are so bad at
that we know that interests don't align so
perfectly.
We know that there's always somebody
who just wants to sell their story to a
tabloid or it feels guilty about their,
the part they played or are they getting
divorced and they just can't stop
talking. And it, Bill Clinton
couldn't keep a semen stain,
dress out off of the news. You
know, it's like, it's like,
that's the simplest thing.
You know,
he's just like the present United States
with a terrified intern and this is
going to wreck his presidency.
And he still couldn't keep the dress.
Uh, see, I see. Well he
couldn't keep that dress,
but how many freaks he think
he banged my head as president.
That guy was just whipping out
his dick left and right. And
that's probably why he isn't talking
about it once. You're a freak,
you're a freak. And when you're
a freak of the highest order,
where you want to be the king
of the world and you know,
you're whipping your dick out in meetings.
Like he would meet with women and just
whip his dick out and would run out of
the room screaming that I did that shit
a lot, but he couldn't. But, but again,
we have to know about that. We know about
one September 11th every other month.
Yeah. But you read, um, well they know he
did get a few girls. He got mad at him,
hitch wrote a great book.
No one left a lie to the triangulations
of William Jefferson Clinton. Really?
He just took him down hard hitch.
Christopher Hitchens. Yeah. Yeah.
For about short book. It's like
150 pages really brutal. And I,
and I don't, you know, I just, it's,
you'll never quite think about
Clinton the same way. I mean, it just,
it just puts a fine point on everything
you just said. And it's, it's, yeah,
it's pretty brutal.
He has a tinge of ego that when he talks,
it always makes me wonder what he's
really like. You know, and I'll say thing,
you know, they have these
big political speeches. They
didn't do this. We did this.
When will the Democrats, we did
this, we did that. And you know,
sort of bragging about stuff.
It's like, it's very unleashed.
Or like at this stage of the game when
you go and look into his past dealings,
like I read the strange death of Vince
Foster, that's a creepy goddamn book.
I'd like to go back and reread that.
He's a guy who was somehow involved in
that crazy real estate deal that they
were with and they found him.
He shot himself,
but there was no blood at the scene.
So it was clear that his body had
been moved. Yeah, yeah. That, I mean,
that's the kind of, again, I'm not saying
no one has ever murder,
no one ever spire is,
but it's just so easy to manufacture
details like that that are then impossible
to debunk. Like, so how do we know
there was no blood at the scene? I,
how do we know that some
18 year old didn't just say
that on his website and now
that's the meme that gets spread and now
you have it in your head that there was
no blood at the scene.
But it's so, so much.
So many conspiracies seem to be engineered
by that kind of chatter. And then,
but if you and I wanted to say,
okay,
we're going to devote the next month of
our lives to just knocking down each one
of those points. How would
we do it? Let me see.
What were you going to
go to have to travel to,
to find out whether there was blood at
the scene and talk to people wouldn't
know.
And it's just an endless sinkhole of
energy and yet it just takes a second to
set that fire. And that's what
actually had happened in debate too.
There are certain people who you debate
on the subject or religion who know that
they can start many small
fires and they're given,
you know, the eight minutes
for their side and they can,
they can set 30 small fires.
We get a half trues,
untruths stuff that, you know, you
really should respond because it's just,
it's just false. Um, but it
takes you so long to put it,
put the fires out that you just,
you can basically put half of them out
and then you haven't said any of what you
came to say and then they
just come back and say, well,
he didn't put out fires
three, four, eight, nine. And
so he's clearly conceited,
my points. And, and it's just a
gate. It's a debating game, right?
Dinesh D'souza is and egregious, uh,
uh, example of that in technique.
It's just if you ever see, he did
a debate with, um, Daniel Dennett,
uh, which was, you know,
really didn't serve, uh,
Dan very well because he,
it was just,
it was a technique that was
quite effective. He just,
it's a fast talker and he,
he can just,
uh,
make a mess and it would take you an
hour and a half to clean it up. But
I, I'm, I'm absolutely a agree
with you on everything you said.
But do you think that there
are real conspiracies?
Do you think that every one of
these things is bullshit? I mean,
people clearly do conspire,
right and wrong was clearly a conspiracy.
It might've been a conspiracy that we
entered into the Iraq war under false
pretenses. I mean, it
might've been a conspiracy,
the Gulf of Tonkin incident and Vietnam.
That might've been a big conspiracy.
Yeah. There's no question that,
that from time to time, you know,
powerful people get into some star
chamber and twirl their mustaches and,
and conspire. I think that probably
happens, but it's just hard.
It's hard to bring it off.
And you should never assume
that's the case. And,
and I mean this is,
there's an adage on this,
on this subject that you did never ascribe
to conspiracy what can be explained
by incompetence or something like
that. And, and it's just so obvious.
The incompetence factor in many of these
situations is so high and so obvious
and as it is almost everywhere. Yeah.
And especially in government and with,
with September 11th, it's just, it's
just, I mean, the, the, it's just a,
just the crushing variable that it's
just, you know, we were just not,
we're not prepared to deal with that
kind of problem. And, um, you know,
anyone who thinks this was a,
a conspiracy thinks
that at least hundreds,
probably thousands of people woke up
one day. It's perfectly normal. People,
people, the FAA, people in
the military, people, uh,
in government woke up perfect
psychopaths willing without,
with a clear conscience to murder 3000 of
their innocent neighbors. And not just,
you know, not, this wasn't Tuskegee,
this wasn't the poor and disenfranchised.
And you know, of a race that you're
not so fond of. This is, you know,
these are some of those powerful
people in our society just,
just blown up one day.
And all of this was perfectly tuned
to leave the person at the top of the
conspiracy.
Presumably George Bush sitting,
reading my pet goat when the whole
thing kicked off. I mean, it's just,
it's ridiculous. It's, it's like a, and
then as a pretext to go into Iraq. If,
uh,
first of all,
it would have been so much easier to think
of a pretext to go into Iraq, but why,
why make it look like the w we got bombed
or attacked by Saudis and Yemenis and
Egyptians, which in fact is, oh, it looks
so you're saying as a motivation to, yeah,
I mean the,
the general idea did it on purpose so
that we could go to war with Iraq. Yeah.
If you're,
if you're thinking about that sort of
the false flag operation thesis that we
wanted to go to Iraq and steal their oil,
but then we,
and we're perfectly evil and
perfectly machiavellian and,
and it could bring this whole thing off
without any leaks to this day, you know,
10 years hence,
no one has come forward and said,
this is the part I played in it
and I feel terrible about it. Um,
and yet we botched it in these,
in these huge ways where we had to go to
Afghanistan before Iraq and we'd really
didn't want to go to Afghanistan.
No one suggests.
We actually wanted it to be running around
Tora Bora, um, fighting the Taliban.
And we go to Iraq. That worked out well.
I mean the idea that that was the easiest
way to get their oil. Uh, it's crazy.
It would have been far cheaper to buy it.
Um,
but based on the arguments shape
of wanting to control Iraq,
I mean that we wanted to take
over and control their oil,
which we kind of do now.
Right.
But we want it so if we
just wanted to go into Iraq,
that that took create a let,
let, let's buy the, the,
the idea that people can spire and
that actually certain people in our
government are willing to,
to run a false flag operation so
that we can go into Iraq. Okay.
What would you have done?
You would have, you know,
you would have shot down one
of our planes over Iraq and,
and which we wouldn't even have needed
that because Saddam was shooting and our
planes, we had a no fly zone and force
for 10 years. And Saddam was, he,
the war wasn't over as far
as he was concerned. He just
kept shooting at planes.
He didn't hit any,
but let's let him hit one hit
and then we then we would go in.
But it just, that killing 3000
people in downtown Manhattan,
uh, people who are well connected, who,
who and sending are the global
economy into a tailspin.
It just doesn't have
the right shape of it.
I completely agree with you that it
would take way too many people to plan it
out most likely.
And when I look at it,
I just see it's someone's
going to tell theirs.
There's just too many things that have
to be coordinated to many people are
going to start talking.
Just,
I agree with you that it's
much more likely in competence,
but there was definitely a
motivation to go into Iraq.
They wanted to go into our rack already.
Then it's something they had been planning
on even before September 11th like
looking for motivation.
So it's possible, right,
that this incompetent government allowed
this attack to take place and then they
capitalized on it.
But why was,
what was their motivation to
go to Iraq in the first place?
If they weren't going over
there to try to control the oil,
then why were they so
desperate to go to Iraq?
Because it was pretty clear that
they wanted to? Well, I think, um,
and again, to some degree, I'm talking
out of my depth here because I'm not,
you know,
I'm not really like a policy guy,
but the argument which was
made publicly at the time by,
by many so-called
neo-cons is that our rack,
because it was the perfect
test case for two to create a,
a vibrant democracy in the
heart of the Arab world. I mean,
this is basically educated population.
Um,
the week completely underestimated
the level of sectarianism there. Um,
but again, that's easily ascribed
to incompetence. I mean, we just,
we were sending in 23 year old,
you know,
friends of Bush with no expertise at
all just because they were the nephew of
somebody who had donated to the campaign.
And all of a sudden these people are
in charge of some major piece of the
machine of how to create a democracy.
In Iraq. I mean, the level of,
to read any of those books about what we
did in Iraq is to just above everything
else, just to come face to face with,
with a shocking degree of incompetence.
So we're, the good guys were just in
competent. Well, let me look who is,
look who he had in the Oval
Office at that moment. You know,
there's a lot of words come to mind when
you think about Bush and confidence is
not, well, you know, bushes
of strange case, you know,
I mean obviously it's not a,
not the smartest guy in the world,
but when you look at like the
policies that he put into place,
it's really similar to what Obama was
doing. It's not much difference at all.
Right. But that, I mean they're, I think
they're crucial differences, but, but
one,
two important things.
One is that Obama has inherited
the world that Bush helped make.
So, so no, but Obama has got the hardest
job on planet earth at the moment.
You blame Bush for the whole
Iraq mess. Do you? Brilliant.
Or his administration at least. Yeah.
Well, we didn't have to go into Iraq and,
and it was, uh, we could have
arguably we had to go into
Afghanistan. I mean, I think, I think,
I think our approach to fight
in the war on terror is, is, um,
fundamentally ill conceived.
I don't,
I don't see why we need to be fighting
wars and taking credit for fighting wars.
I mean, this, this should, from my
point of view would be all covert,
all JB seals and stuff. Yeah. I mean,
in so far as all of his fascination,
there may be situations
where that's not possible,
but I don't see why we need to be a w we,
we should fight the war on terror as a,
um,
as a crime, as an international
crime problem. Uh,
and that has occasional
military solutions.
But from my point of view,
our people, you know,
jihadis in al Qaeda should just have
been disappearing and no one takes credit
for it. So why should we ever say we
did it? We know. Yes, we did it. And,
and now there's a possible
blow back to that. And I mean,
the reality is, you know,
whenever you put navy seals on the ground
and let them shoot they oral or drop
bombs from, you know, Predator drones,
you're going to be killing some number
of innocent people. And that's terrible.
And the terrible truth is there
is no alternative to that. I mean,
unless you're going to be a pacifist
that you're gonna run the risk of killing
innocent people when you have to fight
certain conflicts. And, and so that's,
I just don't see any, it's, do you ever
look at it from their point of view?
Do you ever low? Yeah. You try to look
at it from the [inaudible] point of view,
the Taliban's point of view,
the point of view of someone who is
watching this giant military and machine
coming in and raping their
country's national resources. No,
but that's really minerals and okay,
but what's going on in Afghanistan?
I think about Afghanistan for a moment.
What is the point?
What's the point of view of a woman
in a Burka and Afghanistan? Now?
From my point of view, her,
it's very likely whether sheet,
whether she knows it or not, there is a
much better life. She could be living.
You know, the, the,
the average life expectancy in
Afghanistan for women is 44 years.
It's got the highest,
almost the highest maternal mortality
and infant mortality in the world. Um,
it's, it's, uh, you know, most
women are illiterate. It's just,
it's a terrible life for women.
So one of the real, real,
when we think of having
to leave Afghanistan,
one of the real ethical problems from my
point of view is we're just abandoning
them to, the Taliban were abandoning the
women to the, to the Taliban. And, and if,
if there was a way to actually help them,
we would have a moral obligation to do it.
The problem is it's so costly to do,
it's so intrusive to do and so many people
shoot at you or blow themselves up a
while you do it, that there's, it's,
it's completely impractical to do so.
I think we have a real problem ethically
till just abandoned women to getting
their noses cut off because
they decided not to marry the,
the octogenarian that their father,
uh, sold them too. Well, you know,
obviously I don't agree with any of
that stuff or any of those social
restrictions they put on,
but do you really think that we should
have troops overseas to try to reinforce
our moral standards on this, this
country? That's a mess. I mean,
should we really do that? I think we
that, is that what we're doing? No. No,
but I think we need, well, we are
attempting to do that, but it's just,
it's just not doable. I do really
think that's our motivation though.
And went to degree.
But what about the amount of money
that's they're pulling out of there?
What about the amount of
money that they're making just
in minerals? Well, let me,
let me sidestep that
for a second and just,
just talk about what I
think the end game is.
The end game is to have a global
civilization that actually works.
And what, what would
that look like? It would,
it would look like more or less
what it looks like in any country.
And now whether you have a world
government that achieves this or some,
some federation of states that works
better than, than certainly than the UN,
you need to have, you know, if, if,
if w w girls were getting, you know,
their, their noses cut off a and B and
being forced to live in Burkas in Florida,
it would be a crime problem and
we would send it, we have it,
we would send in police to, to, uh,
force people to treat their daughters
better or treat their wives better. And,
and that's, that's necessary
and appropriate. It's just,
there's no mechanism that allows us to
do that as a matter of international law.
And,
and so we clearly have to get to a time
where when you have a hostage crisis
where an entire country is
held hostage by some lunatic,
a or a group of lunatics
in the government, uh,
is the matter of national
sovereignty is not an it, I mean,
who cares about the national
sovereignty of North Korea? That's a,
that's a hostage situation.
Well,
that's a really interesting point because
we negotiate with North Korea and we
give them money and we're not even
thinking about going over there.
We give them money out of
compassion to alleviate starvation.
We going over there because they have
nudes cause that what it is and they have
so much artillery pointed
at South Korea and the,
and the distance is so small that
they're nukes aside, they would just be,
it would be a disaster as it,
but it, but again, that's just,
that's an argument for not
letting these, these uh, um,
failed states and,
uh,
deranged states get too strong.
I mean, that's so, I mean we, we,
we need a way to,
to,
we need a way to convince the
entire civilized world of, of, uh,
of functional democracies to apply quasi
global pressure to any one of these
regions demanding that they
get their act together.
And Afghanistan is definitely,
definitely a place that, that, um,
where it would be compassionate
if we could come in, you
know, if we could get, if,
if every,
if,
if Russia and China and everyone else
could get on the same page with us and we
could all agree, all right, the women of
Afghanistan, we actually need to help you.
So how are we going to do
this? We're going to it. The,
the first pass we're
going to, we're, you know,
any guy who's throwing a battery acid in
the face of little girls because they,
they want to go to school.
Okay.
That we're going to deal with that
guy a as the sociopath that he is.
Um, and if it just so happens that there's
a culture of those guys and they call
themselves, the Taliban were going to deal
with the Taliban as a, as a, you know,
a gang of, of, of
sociopaths. Um, but again,
this is just,
it's,
so we tried it on her own more or less
on our own and the results have been
terrible. And, and the results
have been terrible because of the,
largely because of the role that religious
thinking plays there. I mean, we,
you know, you, you burn a curry,
a Koran by accident and basically the
war's almost over and well last because,
um, everyone takes to the streets and
begins killing people, uh, uh, you know,
there's nothing more inflammatory than
then trespassing on their religious
sensitivities. And, and you know,
if you accidentally bomb a
wedding and kill 50 children,
you don't get the response we recently
got with this current incident.
And so it's, it's just, it's not,
we're not dealing with a
culture that can have a,
a sane discussion about,
uh,
the proper goals of human life and how
to, how to safeguard human happiness. And
so in your mind,
we need to be the police of the world.
We're the only ones who know what's right.
We're the only ones who are going
to enforce it, where the good guys.
And so we need to go over there.
America,
just the military industrial complex
that runs America. I mean, what is it?
No. [inaudible] who's
we? We is, um, well just,
just look at again,
take,
take one piece that you agreed on
are the gains we've made socially and
culturally and moral a around, uh, racism.
So we have,
we're at least seeing the daylight on
the subject of race in this country.
Now we have the benefit of a kind of a
running start ahead of South Africa and
we see they've got their apartheid
thing going on. Uh, and we begin,
it takes us a while, but we begin to apply
pressure to them, you know, boycott in,
uh, uh, uh, trade with South Africa
and, or, or, or blocking trade.
And that has an effect now that's,
um,
if you could get the entire world on the
same page on each of these questions.
I mean, so the treatment of women is
even a bigger variable than, than, uh,
notions of race because you're here,
you're talking about fully
half of the human population.
So wherever they're
treating women terribly,
uh,
that's a, um, and systematically,
and not just, not by accident,
but because of some ideology that women
can be treated terribly. That's a, um,
that's a human rights problem that every,
every society that has a robust conception
of human rights can figure out how to
apply pressure to.
Now s
stopping trade may not be enough.
Uh, and, and then you, you,
you have all of these other secondary
effects of when you apply sanctions to a
country, then the women and everyone
in kids and everyone else suffer. Um,
and so it's, it's, it's such a
blunt instrument we don't have,
we don't have good tools to deal with.
Yeah.
Problems.
I could see it as a justification one of
many as to why a part of the world was
run by bad people with bad ideas.
But I don't think that's
the motivation to go there.
I don't think that's the main
motivation to go there. I just,
I don't believe that the
army would act that way.
That they would spend so much money
to go somewhere to save some women.
I don't buy it.
Well,
I'm not saying that's the only motivation,
but it's one that you think is
one primary one. Well, it's, well,
again,
I just would have to focus on any specific
conflict we're talking about. But so,
but when you,
when you ask yourself why
they're there, so they're,
they're soldiers who've done
multiple tours of duty in,
in Afghanistan and feel committed to the
project and feel reasonably good about
what they've done. Why do they feel
that way? Why are they, why don't they,
why don't they get up every morning
feeling like they're completely wasting
their life and taking massive risks
for no reason at all? Well, you know,
I'd have to interview each individual one
to find out what their motivation was,
but I look at, Afghanistan has
a giant moneymaking effort.
I look at how much money they're making
and minerals and I don't think they send
tanks and it's for save women. I
don't, I don't believe it's not, it's,
it's not a money.
It's,
it's the most co these to Afghanistan
and Iraq have been the most costly things
we've [inaudible] we've made in people
but aren't huge military companies like,
like, uh, uh, how Burton and,
and people that rebuild these places
and people that are contractors.
There's a lot of money being
spent, right? Well, yeah,
they're their companies
make money in times of war.
Yeah.
I mean,
so the people that do make bullets make
money when they get to sell bullets.
But in terms of the, um, the,
the cost to our economy in
general and the cost to, and,
and, and, and the cost to,
in the lives of the men and women
are military serving over there said,
so everyone who ha,
who none of the soldiers are extracting
wealth from the ground in Afghanistan or
of course directing acting oil for.
And yet when you hear them talk
about their experience, you,
what you don't hear is a litany of,
we never should have done that.
That was a complete waste of time.
I can't believe that our
government is not true at all.
I think there are a lot of
people online that are soldiers,
former soldiers that have a lot of those
stories. No, no, no. There's some of that.
I mean, it, you can't say, you never
hear, no, no, no, no. I'm not saying, but,
but, but the, it's not
all of what you hear.
What you also hear is an experience of,
of really trying to,
you know,
building schools or building know to
build infrastructure and really trying to
help a democracy grow in,
in these places.
Now it is such a thankless
job. And again, I'm not,
don't,
don't mistake me for being optimistic or
it all sanguine about what's happening
in Iraq and Afghanistan. I think
it's been a disaster. And, um,
but you think ultimately it's a good
idea? No, I, I, well, Iraq, no. Um,
Afghanistan, I think it was
absolutely essential that we,
we do something now. We clearly, we,
we did it badly from day
one who committing far too
few troops and our proxies
do it for us and do it badly.
And Osama bin Ladin got away.
But you see it as a war of culture.
You see,
I get bad people out of control,
a country that they could
potentially be dangerous to us.
It was worth the preemptive
strike. Well, again,
let's just start talking about the big
picture. If you're, if you're a pacifist,
you think we should never do anything like
this. You as you never pull out a gun.
And start shooting or threatened to shoot
because nothing is worth killing for
now.
I'm not a pacifist.
I think if we all took a Gandhi and
response to these problems and just,
you know, got on our Facebook
page and made a lot of noise, um,
that there are certain enemies we could
have and do have who will just inherit
the earth. I mean, so the thugs
will win. In that case, um, Gandhi,
Gandhi's nonviolence worked against the
British because the British were the
British and they had enough of a
conscience not to just kill everybody.
It wouldn't have worked against Hitler.
Um, and uh, and Gandhi actually knew that.
So, um, so the,
if you're not going to be a pacifist,
then we're just,
then the question is just when
do you pull out the guns? Uh,
and we can then have an intelligent
discussion about whether it made any sense
to pull out the guns,
these of Iraq or Afghanistan and um,
and you know, then, then it's
just a pragmatic question of, of,
of when you do it and how, how
you, how it's best to do it.
I can agree with Don.
I can agree that we need guns because
they're bad people in the world.
We need an army. We need
a military because they're
are bad people in the world.
But then when you look about
our actions that define what,
what our purposes with this army,
look at our two main campaigns,
Iraq and Afghanistan,
you've admitted they're both
complete fuckups and disaster.
So if that's the case, how do you think
the rest of the world will look at us?
Why wouldn't they be upset with us?
It seems to me that these campaigns have
done far more to hurt the way the rest
of the world wants to treat us. The name
thing else we could've ever done. Gone.
Going to these places and blowing up
buildings and killing whom and how many
hundreds of thousands of
innocent people died in Iraq.
And how many people are dying
every day in Afghanistan?
W do you think about the numbers that
have been piled up just to the actual raw
statistics as,
as motivation
for these people? Well, I think it's
had paradoxically has had both effects.
It has. Um, because look at,
if we didn't go in to certain situations,
so it's like a,
when Libya was kicking off the,
the resistance was desperate for us
to come in. And we looked at that,
the kind of the,
the mealy mouth,
the approach we took just sort of
letting our allies to take the lead. Um,
that looked a little
bit like cowardice and,
and we got a lot of grief for not
actually being active enough to help,
help prop up the, you know, the, the
Libyan, uh, that's a pretty case.
You've got a guy's been a
dictator forever. And the people
literally,
it was the same case.
People were not riding in the streets
because he was a better dictator. I mean,
it's like we, it was worse,
arguably worse in Iraq. Uh,
there were more reasons to
go in. The people were, um,
there was every expectation
that the people, uh,
enough of the people were
ready to be rid of Saddam,
that we could have been
graded as friends. And, um,
and yeah,
it was a disaster because for mainly B,
because we underestimate the level
of sectarian violence that was,
was going to begin the moment
we took the lid off. And, um,
I mean, again, that's just, it just
incompetence but it's not, it's like,
so when you,
when you have Sunni Muslims
who are going to blow up a,
she a mosque, people who didn't even know
about that before they went into the,
well,
a lot of people didn't know you know it,
but we didn't even know the difference
between Sunni and Shia. Yeah.
I mean that we hate you had, you had,
you know, there's, you know, bloopers of,
of our, uh, you know, White
House press conferences where,
where they're getting people's affiliation
wrong and not even thinking they're
interchangeable.
Do you think that these debates,
if you've had with all these
like fiercely religious people,
have they given you more of a
pessimistic thought or idea on how,
how we need to handle people in other
parts of the world where their entire
cultures are run by religion?
I mean, does it, do you use,
do you like lose a bit of hope for
rational conversations to the point where
you're like, you know what,
you have to engage militarily,
there's no other option,
so you're never going
to get by with debate.
You're never going to get
by with rational thought.
You never going to get by with reason.
You're talking about cultures that want
to murder you for burning some pages
accidentally.
You're talking about culture that wants
a murder you for drawing their guy,
right?
Yeah. Well I think it's not, it doesn't,
it's not partitions so easily by state,
but I think I view it as kind of
concentric circles. So it's, so again,
we're talking about Islam
here for the moment.
You have this sort of the center
of the Bullseye of doctrinal,
crazy global jihadist Islam
where yeah, I think, you know,
al Qaeda and al Qaeda,
like thinking that's just a deal breaker.
I mean it was a word war with that
subset of the Muslim world and the,
and they are not our idea
that we're at war with them.
They're at war with us. They'd answer.
We're talking about it. We're innocent.
We've done nothing.
We've done, we have done,
they are running a very
different game in their heads.
It's not about land.
It's not about the Palestinian does not
about it is they're living. They've got,
they've got these seventh century or
14th century goggles that they've, uh,
looking at the world
through. And you know, if we,
if we pipe bay watch over on
the satellite dish, that's a,
you an offense that they're willing
to die for. I mean we w w w it's a,
it's a very different game
they're playing there.
You got to imagine what it's like to
really believe in paradise. You know,
to really want to get there,
to know that,
that if you blow yourself
up killing infidels,
you're going to get there and you're
going to get everyone you love there.
And then there's just this velvet rope
in front of Paradise and you're going to
walk right past cause the angel's
going to lift it up for you.
And the way to get there is to be a
jihadi. You know, it's, it's like a,
it's a, it's the ultimate.
It's like being James Bond,
who's going to get 72 virgins
in paradise and you end,
you have got no other problems in life.
You need to worry about,
you don't have to worry about getting
education or getting a job or making it
work in this world are
building a civil society.
You just have to play
your side of the game,
right and die in the right circumstances.
But how many of those are there?
How many? I think, I think there are
enough. Well, I think there are, I mean,
there are tens of thousands of people who
went to training camps in Afghanistan.
Um, so again, so, so concentric circles.
So the center of the bull's eye,
let's say that's just,
let's say that's half of a
percent of the Muslim world.
Okay. Which is the timing.
So when that, whenever you,
half a percent is a, you know,
a 1% of humanity is schizophrenia.
I mean, so half a percent.
It's a tiny segment of any, any
population. Th there's, there's,
there's no idea. So crazy that only half
a percent of Americans believe in it.
If you ask people. Yeah. Yeah. So you're
going to get more than half a percent.
It's just it. So, but
even half a percent. Um,
what does that, it's like,
you know, it's millions of,
of of people who are just the die hard
of the die hard now as 1.4 billion
Muslims. Um, so,
so you think it's possible that half
a percent of them? Oh No, I believe.
I think so. I think it's for vogue
is worse because it's all, let's say,
so let's say there's,
there's potentially,
let's say there's potentially
a million jihadis, right?
I think it's probably worse than that,
but let's say, yeah, let's just see.
Let's say it's you, but when you
see, just be defined it, you,
you mean guys who are willing to become
suicide bombers more than a million?
Well, I think that that wouldn't
be a crazy guest. I mean, I have,
I have no way of knowing, apart
from the fact that, that you're,
there's like in any and every
Muslim country, it's 10, 15,
20, 30, 40, 50, depending
on the country, up to 70%.
Who thinks suicide bombing is a good
thing. Wow. Right? So it's not the,
these are when you, when you run
the poll in, in, in, you know,
which has been done by Pew
and other organizations and
you started asking people,
do you think you know, uh, uh,
suicide bombing in defense
of Islam is ever justifiable.
And, and then it's, you
know, yes, sometimes,
rarely and never are the
possible responses. The, the,
the number of yeses and sometimes
gives it gives you a, a,
if not a majority, a significant minority
of, of every Muslim country. Even in,
even in the UK, you would get
something like, you know, 20, 25% of,
of,
of young Muslims thinking that it's
justifiable and you'd get that immediately
after the suicide bombings
in London. These polls had
been run, you know, do you,
do you want to live under Sharia law?
You get like 30% in the UK among Muslims,
18 to 24 now. So, so one question is,
do people actually believe what
they say they believe when,
when you are taking a poll and,
and what does it actually
mean to say yes to that?
How does that inform your life?
So let's just style it all the
way down to half a percent. Okay.
Everyone else's just bluffing, half a
percent is still with the spread of, uh,
of weapons of, uh, of,
uh, high yield. You know,
whether it's nuclear weapons
or biological weapons,
um,
half a percent of any popular,
any significant population, it can do
a lot of damage. And so we, we just,
it's something that we have to win a
war of ideas ultimately. And we have to,
we have to discredit these ideas so that
the next generation doesn't find it so
easy to believe these things.
But,
but how did they accept us?
How do they accept anything,
any real solution coming from us
when they know what we did in Iraq,
when they know what we did in Afghanistan,
when they know what a fuckery
we've made out of the whole thing,
when they know how much
rampant corruption there is,
missing money there is,
how do they ever look at this as
anything other than a money grab?
How do they ever look at it as like,
oh,
these are the Americans are
going to teach us how to live.
How could anybody except that? Well,
it's not, but when you look at, again,
it's just necessary.
It doesn't matter how the accepted,
we just have to do it anyway. When
you're talking about the center of the
Bullseye, uh, these people
are truly on persuadable.
It says there was nothing we were going
to do that was going to get Osama bin
Ladin to say, you know, I had
you guys all wrong. This is,
you know, the eye. This is,
we're friends now and, and uh, um,
so I think a certain percentage of
people are on persuadable and they're the
force or the threat of force
is the only game to play.
And then what we have to do is win a war
of ideas around that first circle where
they become marginalized,
sufficiently marginalized and, and,
and not supported within
their society. So, so,
and that arguably that has
happened to some degree,
even with how chaotic
Afghanistan and Iraq,
uh,
look.
Well,
there's certainly been more penetration
than there was like 50 or 60 years ago,
but the majority of the population is
still like really deep into their culture.
I mean,
they have a weird setup.
They only have one city cobbles
the only real city. Right.
And Afghanistan has just filled with
like tribes, right? Essentially.
Uh, yeah. Yeah. I mean, I, I haven't
been there, so I'm, again speaking,
I've only read third hand,
but a bunch of, yeah.
Mccain talk about it. Where he, I think,
believe one of his quotes was that
it's run the same way as it was when
Alexander the Great was around.
Right. Just at the end,
some of that tribalism isn't
strictly a religious problem.
It's a, I mean, the toes,
tribalism is a problem and
religious tribalism is a
problem. And, and these are,
you know,
these are
mmm.
Any ideology that fundamentally divides
one group from another and prevents them
from recognizing their
common humanity as a problem.
And so not all of that's religious.
Some of its racist, some of it's tribal.
Um,
but
the role that religion plays
in confounding this, uh, our,
our, our best intentions. Even so,
even, even if our, even if are,
we only had our best intentions and
they were not mingled with our worst
intentions,
even if it was not about if,
even if we would just go
into Rwanda to help people,
even though they don't have oil and
we got no national security interests,
but they take out the machetes and start
killing their neighbors and we just,
we're going to put our lives on
the line to just stop the violence.
Okay.
It's the, the problem is, it's just this,
there's no elegant way to do it.
You wind up killing us and
people you wind up, uh,
you can't, you can't commit enough
resources to build a civil society.
You can't,
it takes too long to,
to teach people what they should
want. You know? It's, it's just, it's,
um,
so you sort of reconcile our problem. You
sort of reconcile our military actions.
You reconcile the corruption,
all the fuck.
I'd be saying all the
fuck ups that they are,
what they are and there's
nothing we can do about them now.
But what's important is we keep these
crazy people from developing nuclear bombs
and from attacking us cause they're,
they're very real possibility of,
of nuclear terrorism to you is far more
important than whatever mistakes or
corruption has been, you know,
has, has that we've put out as a,
as a country that have gotten,
gotten these people to have
this sort of a perception of us.
I think what, well, I can't, yeah,
I can't sign on to all of that because I
think our screw ups have been huge and,
and I think we,
we have a huge moral debt to all the
people we have accidentally blown up.
I mean obvious obviously collateral
damage is a huge problem. And,
and I think we are.
MMM.
And it's been a problem in every
war we've ever fought. I mean,
one of the things we, we've now,
which is an advantage on the one hand,
but also disadvantages that
there's so much more transparency.
We know so much more
about the bad stuff we do.
Whether inadvertent or not,
that if we didn't know this in World
War II and more bombing Dresden and
incinerating hundreds of
thousands of people, um,
got an innocent bystanders for, for, for
the most part, um, and not, you know,
nonmilitary targets.
And we could know,
arguably we should never have done that,
but we've arguably couldn't do
that now given how much info given,
given what the images would do to
us on the nightly news. And so, um,
and I think that's all to the good.
I think we should,
I think we should understand the cost
of war more than we do and we should
understand how horrible collateral
damages more than we do. Um, how,
how'd you feel about wikileaks?
Well, I think, I think,
uh, a song has just, it'd be
he's a cult of personality.
He's a creepy bastard. So it, so it's
hard. It's hard to, I mean, I, I'm,
I like transparency, I think, I think the,
the journalistic aspect of it
to some degree was legitimate,
but I think it's also, if
you're going to release, uh,
certain secrets shouldn't be released.
So there are certain secrets are there
because they're keeping people safe.
And to release those secrets,
uh,
irresponsibly is to put people in
harm's way. And so it, so I, it was a,
it's a very mixed,
hey,
do you feel about the initial video
that he released collateral murder,
the one that showed the guys and the
helicopters shooting the people on the
ground? Yeah. Well, children
and them saying, well,
I shouldn't have brought their
kids. Right, right. Well,
the thing that's horrible
about that is the, the, um,
horrible but,
but maybe inevitable is
that we're just not wired to
okay.
And understand the consequences of our
actions once we can fight war remotely.
You know, I mean, you have a, if we were
just fighting every, if it was all just,
you know, bayonets, there's a,
there's the kind of the, in a,
in escape ability of the horror of war.
But the moment you can fly something,
you're sitting in your,
in your office park and outside of Las
Vegas and you're flying a Predator drone,
or if 13,000 miles away, um, it's, uh, I,
I'm,
I'm not this,
I'm not suggesting those guys don't
have a hard time sleeping at night,
some of them, but it's a very
different kind of violence. And,
and one of the scariest things about
technology is it uncouples us from our,
our emotions, from, um,
the reality of the consequences of our
actions so that the most harmful things
aren't actually the most disturbing
things, you know, so, so,
so if you miss an example,
actually I used in, um,
I think the end of faith know,
if you hear that your grandfather fought
in World War II and he dropped bombs.
He was a fight. He was a, he was a bomber
pilot. He dropped bombs over Dresden.
That's one kind of level of abstraction
of a, of his actions that it's,
it doesn't really disturb you about him.
And it needed to have disturbed him.
And he's, he's at 30,000 feet dropping
bombs, not really getting what he's doing.
But if you hear grandad killed a
woman and her kids with a shovel,
all of a sudden he is the
scariest guy who ever heard of.
And probably he's couldn't sleep for
the rest of his life either because it
takes a very different
kind of person to do that.
But the guy dropping bombs killed farm
any more women and children than the guy
with a shovel. And, and,
and so, so that, that um,
it's fascinating isn't it? And then
now we're moving into drones. Yeah.
And she'll lose even more.
So we need,
the burden is to figure out how to have
an appropriate emotional response to
reality and to be guided by, it's not
to say that our emotions are always the,
the, um, uh, perfect
guide. I mean there, there,
there may be ways in which we are wired
to have a strong response to something
that we should just get over.
And,
and we're not wired to have
an appropriately emotional
response to something
that really is, is a massive danger. And,
and so our perception of risk and our
perception of harm is not what it needs to
be for us to, to, to make intelligent
decisions and compassionate decisions in,
in these kinds of conflicts.
Did you agree with the video being
released? Did you think it was a bad idea?
Um,
for morale for,
it's hard to separate that from
everything else that that has happened.
But as far as wikileaks you mean? Yeah.
Yeah. So, I mean, I think wikileaks,
I truth is, I don't even know the ultimate
consequences of wikileaks. I, you know,
it's, it would just, it would just
matter what the consequences are.
There isn't transparency. Good.
Yeah. But to a certain point,
but do I think Obama should be forced at
his next press conference to just share
his White House briefing with
the world? No, I think he,
I think he,
there are certain things that I understand
that he and people like him need to
know that I don't need to know. And
if, if I knew and blogged about it,
I would be harming our national
security. Um, so, so yeah, no,
I'm not for the just unlimited
distribution of secrets. Yeah.
Yeah.
So you allow them to have certain
secrets just for national security. Well,
it's just a clearly we absolutely
need that. We would be paralyzed.
I agree with that. To what your sure.
Absolutely. Right. If there's bad guys,
but to what level? Like at what point,
how do you know that's where it's weird.
How do you make the distinction? How
do you decide that, uh, you know,
they shouldn't be able to have,
you know,
a certain secrets that may in fact be
damaging to American civilians or meet,
we might disagree with it.
It might change the way we feel
about a president or our policy.
It's probably not that
complicated. I don't think so. No.
It's probably pretty basic.
It's probably like, all right,
we should definitely not
tell him about our, uh,
where nuclear warheads
throughout the United States
are located everywhere. Yeah.
You would think so. But I think there's
a lot more complicated than that.
Yeah. Well, again,
there are trade offs between some of
these things where it's just there,
it's hard to really be satisfied that
you've hit the right answer because it's,
it's the cell,
for instance,
going through security and in the
airport there's this issue of fairness,
you know, and there's this
issue of intelligent uses,
use of attentional resources. So the
fairness would say, yes. Fris Frisk,
the 75 year old woman who looks like she
just got out of her evangelical church
just as much as you frisk the guy who,
who just prayed on his knees to Mecca,
um,
before passing through security.
It's only fair to be blind to those,
uh,
otherwise salient
differences between them. Um,
but it's stupid to when you know that the
person who is going to blow himself up
on the plane is a jihadi and not a,
an ordinary looking old woman.
Um,
so again,
you see what are the consequences
of being starkly unfair? You know,
where you just profile nakedly and say
yes without apology. We profile if you,
if you're Muslim,
we are going to subject you to a heroin
search at the airport because we're
worried about your brothers. Um, we, we,
we have to find a balance.
We're struggling to find a balance
between those two things. And, um,
I think we,
we're in the current environment.
I think we're wise to err on
the side of being fair. And,
and I mean, I think, and I
think you would, you would,
you would want us to err in that direction
to be fair and to be transparent and
to be, but that's what's so scary
about something like nuclear terrorism.
One thing has to happen
and all of a sudden are,
we'll all be desperate for a level of
security that will radically transform our
lives. And it's so, and it will be, again,
it could be completely out of scale with
the actual damage. So you know, if you,
if a new queen off in Los Angeles
and killed 100,000 people,
right? So a small nuke until 100,000
people and rendered, you know,
some area uninhabitable for Awhile.
That would be such a,
a rattling event that it w we would all
be demanding huge changes and we would
be forfeit in our civil liberties.
Happily it with both hands as was
clearly evident after nine, 11,
after nine 11.
Right?
This would be orders of magnitude worse
and yet it would be rational to say,
well listen, you know, 400,000 people
died of heart disease last year, you know,
no one is forfeit in their civil
liberties are going nuts over that figure.
We're talking about a hundred thousand
people, uh, who, who, you know, what,
what is the real risk we're talking about?
Well,
there's this sudden death over
[inaudible] self administered death.
Even if that would be
okay,
even if we, uh, I'm not saying
that's the right way to look at it,
but even if you could show a commensurate
body count from [inaudible] from some
other source, um, actually bill morrow
wants made this point where, um,
I think he was talking about Hurricane
Katrina. I say, well, look at,
look at what happened with Hurricane
Katrina and the billions of dollars in,
in cost and a thousand lives lost.
If a terrorist had done this,
we would, we would completely freak out
as a nation because it's the weather.
We basically can't get our act together
and, and don't really worry about it.
Um,
okay.
That difference in response is uh,
okay,
well something we have to be cognizant of.
And so one reason,
one rational reason to Pete to,
to want to protect against certain,
especially salient events like
nuclear terrorism is because
okay,
we are guaranteed to overreact
in such a way that it,
the consequences will be a horrendous,
I mean,
just economically consequences.
That's a very good point.
So your point is cut back
on civil liberties so that
we don't have to cut back
on in the future when the shit hits the
fan to some degree. That's an argument.
You're not, yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, but, but cut back on them.
And again, I wouldn't phrase it in terms
of cutting back on civil liberties, but,
but I,
yeah,
it comes back to, to, to moments
like airport security. For me,
it's like how much security do I
want when I get on an airplane?
I want intelligence security
now intelligent. I want,
I also want fairness, but,
and I'm willing to put up with
a certain level of, of, um,
inconvenience to, to, to, to know
that basically this is being done.
Sanely now do I want huge inconvenience?
Do I want to be bombarded with
rays? Do I want to, you know,
I'd want to have take my clothes off
every time I got on a plane. No, but, um,
it's just, you just, we
have, as a society, we, eh,
there's something very corrosive
about the, the signs that,
okay,
these efforts are ineffectual and
not being done intelligently. I mean,
if we could all just see,
uh,
an airport security protocol
that just looked right, you know,
where it's just,
you know,
then I think everyone would
understand why we had to do it,
but it looks so wrong and
it feels so wrong. Uh, and
okay.
It doesn't feel like it's improving.
It's just like there's figuring out the
system better and this is an easier way
to do it. Less intrusive.
There's no easier way to do it.
And I'm not even putting myself, it's
like I'm not, you know, fine. You know,
I don't actually, look, I don't think I
look like I'm al Qaeda, but, but I don't,
look, I, I'm not as benign a, I mean,
I once saw a little girl when
this, when we first got the, the,
the shoe bomber effect and a, we were
all having to take off our shoes. Um,
I saw, you know, I saw a three year
old girl in her, you know, whatever,
whatever those,
I'm one of those black and white shoes
that little girls were called jellies,
bugs. I don't know. There's some
little older school name. Anyway,
she was like holding up a line. Her, she
was being forced to take her shoes off.
She was terrified. It's like
a first flight, you know,
and like the parents were being
traumatized and it was just,
it was just the most insane, insane,
misapplication of, of human resources.
Um,
and meanwhile that was a flight where
I had accidentally taken, uh, a,
a bag that I used to keep a gun in
and I went through security with,
with a double hand, a handful of
bullets just inadvertently. Right. So I,
so I'm getting through with bullets
and they're looking at, at this girl,
like she's, you know,
the, uh, she's Okaydo.
So of course Al Gore got frisked.
Do you remember that? No,
but Al Gore made a big deal out of it
cause he was flying commercial and right
on, I'm one of these flights and he got,
he got frisked. I was like, what does,
that's not symbolic
demonstration of fairness. Yeah.
Yeah. It is. I guess at a certain
point in time that you got to come on,
you think the ex president,
the x vice president is going to
become a suicide bomber was really,
is that what we're looking
at here? Yeah. Yeah.
So that it's that kind of thing that I
think is, is corrosive. And, and, uh, the,
the,
the missteps and failures we've had
at the level of foreign policy and in
fighting wars have been
corrosive for the same reason.
It's just the ineptitude and the,
and the,
the [inaudible] acknowledged and
unanticipated costs and it's all just,
um, yeah, it's,
it's very hard to be idealistic or feel
like anything is being done right. But
again,
think of just what Obama's got to deal
with when he drinks his first cup of
coffee in the morning and he's got,
he,
they're getting information
from a world of intelligence,
which is, is, is struggling
to quantify certain risks.
And there is no question that there
are people who are desperate to blow up
whole cities in this country because not
because they have said they have a long
list of rational grievances
against our foreign policy,
but because they're fighting a cosmic war.
And that's just,
that's just something we have to
absorb as bizarre fact s as it is.
So you think for most people it's almost
impossible to sort of understand their
mindset,
to really put yourself into their shoes.
It's virtually impossible to really have
that kind of a crazed, I don't, well,
I didn't mind it actually. I feel like
I can put myself in their shoes. I,
you know, if I read the Koran and I read
the Hud eighth and I read what, what, um,
people like Osama bin Ladin
say about their intentions,
what and why they're doing what
they're doing. You Watch enough,
you watch a few suicide
videos, um, you know,
last testament videos of,
of suicide bombers.
You just have to imagine what it would
be like if you really believed that this
was the structure of the universe
where this human life that we,
that people like us
really value is just this,
uh, irredeemable fallen, uh,
uh,
really revolting circumstance of,
of separation from God.
And it's just this anti room
to the better place that,
that you get into if you live this
way and die at the, in the right way,
at the right time.
And
eternity awaits Aternity where all the
good people get get to be happy forever.
Wait, now why would you
want to stick around here?
I have to talk about this more,
but I also have to pee.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm going to put
my headphones down and I'm going to ask
you about question when we
get back though. How the
fuck does anything get fixed?
How do we fix this? If you were the
grand social engineer of the universe,
think about that. I
will follow you. So now,
but now what do we do while you Pete.
Okay.
Hey, how's it going? Sorry,
I'm just readjusting everything.
Okay.
Um, so is this something that
you fell into? Like did you, uh,
like think like this growing up or did
you have somebody that inspired your,
your, your beliefs in the way that you,
that you think and like your, your,
I guess your stance on
everything, you know, or did,
have you always been interested in it or,
well, I've always been,
I've been interested in, um,
okay.
Religious experience, right? I mean, why,
just what it means for people personally.
And just what the possibilities are. You
as a, as a teenager, I just, you know,
I was as interested in just what is,
you know,
what are the limits of reality as
anyone else. And so to some degree,
my research there has been scientific
and now increasingly scientific.
But early on I just, I was interested
in religion as a possible account of,
of what's true. And, um,
I was also interested in the kinds
of experiences that the founders of,
of the world's religions have
had or seemed to have had.
So I'm interested in the
kind of experience that
would get Jesus talking like
Jesus or Buddha talking like Buddha and,
and I,
I've sought those experiences with
drugs and meditation and, and um,
it's very,
it's clear,
absolutely clear to me that there is a
range of experience there that is hugely
motivating and real and accessible and
has been traditionally described only in
religious language and seems to
cash out the crazy claims of,
of the various religions.
So like, so if you're,
if you're a devout Muslim and you start
having the kinds of experiences that
we've had on acid or the that that
people have had intensive meditation
retreats,
um,
they get framed in very
much in doc trinal ways.
So it seems to justify your
infatuation with this one revelation,
a revelation which is
intrinsically divisive,
which argues that you should hate
everyone who's not in the fold.
Um,
so clearly we need a way of talking about
these kinds of experiences and valuing
them that is,
which is,
which is just as generalizable
and scalable as uh, the, the,
the larger conversation of,
of reason and science based thinking
about the nature of reality and is not in
print and therefore it's
not in principle divisive.
One of the things that Mckenna always
said in describing the difference between
religion and a psychedelic experiences
that the psychedelic experience,
you don't have to believe
anything to go on it and you'll,
you're going to experience it
whether you like it or not,
you're going to get hit by it.
How you interpret it and how you
disseminate it inside your own head.
It's one thing,
but it's not like a religious experience
in that you don't have to believe.
Oh yeah. Which is probably the
beauty of it because you know,
the ego wants you to hold back to all in.
You can retain all control of your
faculties at any given time. And you know,
you don't want to relinquish control
to some sort of a foreign substance,
some sort of a drug,
some sort of a thing that you know you're
going to give up your whole body and
your mind for three hours.
Fuck that. That's too long.
And that if that freaks people out,
yeah,
it freaks me out. It freaks people
out with good reason because there is,
there is a chaos factor to psychedelics,
which you don't get doing yoga now.
I mean that's, that's, that's their power
and their, their peril. Because the,
I mean, the other thing that Mckenna
said, um, which is obviously quite true,
which is that if you teach someone to
meditate or you're teaching them to do
yoga,
or you teach them to,
you tell them to do whatever spiritual
discipline you think is so potent
based on their talents are
based on their happenstance or,
or nothing might happen. I mean they,
they, they just might get bored. They,
it doesn't matter if they
do it for an hour or a week,
it's not necessarily gonna move them.
But if you give them a
hundred micrograms of LSD or,
or a sufficient dose of
anything in that family, um,
there is just no question
something's going to happen. Now,
it could be very pleasant. It could
be very unpleasant. It could be mixed,
but there is,
there's going to be a break with their
ordinary consensus trance of egoity and
um, so it's a short cute,
so it's a huge shortcut.
But the problem is it does just
sort of just puts you in a,
and you're not quite sure where
it's pointed and then you're, it's,
you're going there.
So it's a method.
But you think that a meditation
is probably an equally
effective method if you,
if you really follow it
through. I mean, I think,
I think of meditation the same way I
think of martial arts. You know, I could,
I could teach you a spinning wheel kick,
I could show you it and you might
not ever be able to do it right. You,
you might not have the flexibility,
the coordination,
whether it's mental flexibility might
not be able to focus on it enough or be
intense enough or spending,
you'd be disciplined enough to stretch
yourself enough to pull something off.
But you can't say that another
person can't pull it off.
It is possible to pull it off.
It's possible to be an expert at it.
But now to all the people
that you teach this, you know,
like couldn't Bellini or some intense
form of meditation where you achieve
altered states of consciousness, how
many people are going to have the focus,
the drive,
the discipline,
how many people are going to put in the
time and the numbers to actually pull
off an altered state?
I have never done it.
Well,
uh,
I completely agree with that,
except there's one caveat,
which is I think that the center of the
Bullseye of altered states of meditation
is not so altered. It's
not, it's actually the, the,
the thing that you want to realize from a,
from a contemporary point of view
is not actually the same as the full
kaleidoscope of effects you get from
psychedelics. It's not just, and this
is a distinction I made, I think, again,
in the end of faith between, um, uh,
the content of consciousness and realizing
a specific property of the nature of
consciousness. And there's
no question that, that,
that cause for ordinary waking
consciousness, like the content,
the spectrum of content is, is trimmed
down. I mean, we have, you know,
there's just a kind of a feeling of it's
because it's all solid and it's just me
here in my body, I'm kind of locked
in my head and see you over there.
And now there's no, the, the, the,
the energy of the situation is,
is, is quite, um, limited. Uh, yeah. And,
and they're not too many surprises.
I mean,
we have all kind of been
taught neurologically to
just perceive or ourselves in
the world. You give someone
LSD or psilocybin or Mescalin,
and that begins to change radically.
And it changes for everyone.
And it can be terrifying.
It can be incredibly blissful. Um, eh,
but what happens is people are flooded
with new content and new feelings of
meaning a new field and new, uh, um,
just the energetics change.
So will they tell you,
put your hand on a tree and
you feel like the buzz of,
of kind of living in contact with a tree
and which you have never felt in your
life.
Okay.
All of that kind of,
the more aspect that you get with
psychedelics isn't what isn't the point of
meditation.
And it comes with meditation.
So if you go on a three month retreat
where you're just meditating 18 hours a
day, and every time your
mind gets lost in thought,
you'd come back to the practice,
whether it's, you know, mindfulness,
you're like the Pos and the
meditation or whatever it is.
It could be yoga that,
you know,
being in a pressure cooker of intensive
retreat can give you that some
experience of more,
I've never quite had it.
Like what you get in a psychedelic
experience, how close we've become.
MMM.
Well it's not, it's not the, um,
you can certainly get what you get with
MDM may, I mean the like the full blown,
empathic, unconditional love
real thing happened. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Yeah. Wow. Um, and they're
actually practicing within Buddhism.
There are practices that
are just tuned to that.
So the practice of loving
kindness called Metta in Pali,
it's just, you're just, you're just
trying to stoke that emotion and it,
you're just, you're just thinking, it's,
it's, it's a very simple practice you,
you bring to mind, people you love.
You're not, not romantic love,
but just people who you just,
you know, your best friend say,
and you just meditate on that person
and you just think, Eh, you know,
thoughts of well wishing for them
to see it as you. May you be happy.
May you be free from
suffering May and just,
and just connect with your wish
for that person's happiness.
And you just train that up. The crucial
piece is once you get concentrated,
once your mind is no longer
wandering into the, into the, um,
into the chatter of just distraction
and you can actually focus,
you get the feeling going and you
can focus on the actual practice,
then you can do it. Then it would just
be, it gets kindled and then you're,
you're feeling very much
what you, you feel, uh, uh,
on ecstasy where there's just this,
mmm,
it'd be it, it becomes, it becomes like,
like ecstasy the moment you move it off
because you start with someone who's
very easy to love, like your
best friend. Um, and then,
then the,
the practice evolves and then you move
it to a neutral person and then you even
move into an enemy. Um, and so,
and then so then you get it.
Then it's just broad spectrum.
You know, three 60, I love,
I wish everyone happiness. That's the
goal of the practice and, and but,
but wishing with a totally focused
mine that is not lost in thought.
Uh,
it,
I mean the truth is just
having a concentrated mind
that's not getting lost in
thought is just intrinsically pleasurable.
It's intrinsically blissful.
It's sort of, it's like the,
the emotional base note of
all the good drug experiences.
It's like, it's sort of kind of the, the,
the opiate happy feeling
comes just with concentration.
It doesn't even matter what
you're concentrated on.
If you're just concentrated on a,
my Buddhists do practices where they'll
just focus on a colored disk and they,
they reach levels of concentration was,
so you're just focusing on a
piece of a swatch of red and
you're, you're, you're,
you're reaching states of consciousness
that are just extraordinarily blissful
and, and, but again, that's
not, that's not the ultimate,
it's not the ultimate point of meditation
and constant concentration is just a
tool to use to actually glimpse something
about the nature of consciousness.
And so that, this comes back to
what I was saying before, that the,
that the actual goal,
and this is,
this is a difference between
just getting more content and,
and getting the kind of the
wisdom that comes with, with, um,
recognizing something about consciousness.
The goal is to recognize that ordinary
consciousness without anything getting
psychedelic is a circumstance
of genuine freedom.
That the,
that the,
the sense of being a neurotic
self locked in the head,
uh,
worried about what other people are
thinking that can be cut through fully so
that it's, it's just gone. I mean,
so that you can recognize the intrinsic
selflessness of consciousness and that
can happen without any of the
pyrotechnics. It can happen without the,
the rush of energy in the body.
It can happen without the colors changing.
It can happen.
It happened without any luminosity of
any kind of says you don't feel like
you've taken a drug. You're,
you're, you're, you're,
you're awareness is crystal
clear. It's, it's, it's,
it's compatible with ordinary
behavior. You can drive a car. You can,
if someone says, can you pass the salt?
You don't, you're not this dazzled,
stoned person who can't find the salt you,
you're,
you're fully here and integrated and
yet the center has dropped out of
experience and you can just,
only the world remains in some sense
and you're no longer on this side of it.
Look,
assessing personally or even just
even that the sense of subject,
object perception and even just, it's
like there's, there's a way of looking at,
you take any object and there's a way of
looking at it as an object where I feel
like I'm over here looking at it and then
there's also a way of still seeing it.
But Lou scene,
it's so clearly that you're no longer,
you're no longer the sear,
you're no longer the law on the outside
or the on the inside looking out.
There's just seen, there's
just a totality. If this is
some karate kid type shit,
you're like become the cap. That's
what, no, no, it's not becoming the cab.
It's just become, the world becomes
come. Whatever you focus on,
yet it becomes become the church become
re most of us feel like we are having an
experience. Like there's,
there's our experience,
there's the world of our experience,
and then there's us over here
having the experience, you know,
like we're on the outside looking in or
we're looking over our own shoulder. Uh,
there's a distance,
there's a subject,
and then there's all the objects and
it's possible to collapse that distance.
You know,
in a way that is,
doesn't require any psychedelic explosion.
And that is the, from a meditational
point of view, that that is,
that's the center of the
bolt side that you want to,
you want to find that intrinsic
property of consciousness.
And then you meditate on
that and then you just,
you drop your distraction and you fall,
you fall back into that space
of just being open and aware.
And then it doesn't
matter what happens then.
It doesn't matter whether you
feel blessed or you don't,
you're not waiting for the
meditation and get good.
You're not trying to have an experience
that you had yesterday that you know
that you lost and you're
trying to get back to it.
I mean that's also all of the seeking,
the tends to come and people's spiritual
lives where they're just trying to get
some place. That's the
irony is you know, the,
the seeking is your problem,
you know,
see you trying to become happy trying
to positing a goal and then seeking it.
Uh, from a, from a contemplative point of
view, is the trap that you want to avoid?
You mean as far as like behavior is
concerned? I mean, as far as, I mean,
you don't mean that as far as like
goal setting in life, right? No, no.
I mean there's,
there's certainly a place for goal setting
and how do you have this attitude and
still write your book? No, no, I mean it
was it possible. Yeah. No, no I'm not,
I'm not, I'm not nullifying all
purpose based behavior obviously, but,
but from a contemplative point of view,
like,
so the question is what is available to
realize now in the present moment that
is liberating. It's like what?
So, so it's just, just me.
Neurotic may unhappy me,
me who's disappointed with yesterday.
What can I do right now to be free?
Is that even possible? Does that he,
does that question even make any sense?
Now some people would say,
well, that doesn't make any
sense. You know, there is no,
there isn't.
You are just a monkey or you're just an
ape with various needs and desires and,
and you can be as happy as you can be,
but there's just,
there's nothing really profound to be
realized about the nature of consciousness
in the present.
There's just you think believing in
certain things, wanting certain things,
etc. And that's just not true.
Now it's completely rational that many
people think it's true because they
haven't had certain kinds of
experiences. But, but the truth is that,
and this,
this is a truth that that inconveniently
for our sake is only really ever
acknowledged in the context of religion.
The truth is there actually is something
more profound to realize about the
present moment and you get one look
at that truth through the psychedelic
experience because it's just you being
neurotic and someone hands you a tab of
acid and all of a sudden you are
a wash in an ocean of new content.
That is, is completely
profound. And, and I mean,
you've had no idea. Life
could be so rich, rich.
Now if you have a bad experience,
you have,
but you have a bad experience and that's,
that's something else.
But if you have a good psychedelic
experience where you feel like Jesus
that proves to you that
is possible to be much,
much deeper and happier and fulfilled
than you, then you realized.
I read that you had had a very similar
experience, uh, to me, uh, when you,
the first time you did a
Mtma [inaudible] and, um,
that was a real behavior
changing experience for me.
And I remember the, when I
did it, I really couldn't,
couldn't stop thinking after it was over.
Like,
why can't people be
like that all the time?
What an incredible world it would be if
people thought like that all the time.
It would, anything ever get done,
I don't know. But, you know, boy,
human interaction would
be blissful all the time.
Yeah, no, I mean, and again,
I keep feeling just a
civic responsibility to,
to bracket all of my um,
uh,
enthusiasm for psychedelics with
the warning that I think they're,
some of them are more just biochemically,
more risky,
are riskier than others and some are
just psychologically risky and it's
possible to have a bad experience and
to really regret taking any of these
frozen.
Well if you have a hard time with reality,
I say stay the fuck
away from psychedelics,
but he, but even if you don't, or even if
you've had nothing but good experiences,
you can suddenly start having
bad experiences. I mean,
that was my course I took,
I took em to Mtma a few times.
I took silicide been a few
times. I took acid, you know,
a dozen times or so.
And I had for the most part,
just especially with with Lsd,
I had 10 perfect experiences
where afterwards it was just,
it was unthinkable to me that
anyone ever had a bad trip.
I didn't even know what that couldn't
even see the direction you would head to
have a bad trip.
Did anything change in your life
before you had the bad trip?
I don't, I don't, I don't know what
the approximate, cause it's insecure,
but it's just,
but then I think this is,
I don't know,
I don't have any science to go on here,
but anecdotally I think
this is a reasonably common
experience where once you've
had a bad trip, then the door is
slightly ajar there and you can,
you can, you know, you see, you can find
your way there in a way, kind of reliably.
Um, so I, I approach psychedelics
with more caution now and I,
you know, it's been years since
I've, I've done anything. Um,
but it's not that I wouldn't,
it's not that I wouldn't do it again.
I probably would, but I would just, I
would pick my moment wisely because I,
you know, as good as the good trips
were, the bad trips were just as bad.
And, and it's, um,
so the legal situation is very
unfortunate because if it was legal,
then we can have people that were experts
on it that were professionals and they
could distribute it and they could do
it properly into the right environment.
And we'd have, you know,
protocol and, and, and the,
the correct things to do if someone is
having a bad trip and they're in the,
you know,
the safety and comfort of professionals
and people that can let them know that
everything's gonna be fine and sort of
steer it in one way or another. You know,
that's all something, the, the, the
potential growth experiences, we're,
we're all missing out on those
because of the illegality of it.
But I agree with you that you should
be really careful, but anything you do,
especially, I know people
that they just, you know,
they get on Xanax and they
lose their mind. You know,
I know people that just things that
seem to be mild and acceptable.
I know people can't drink.
You know, that every,
everyone's mind is very
different biochemically,
the way it reacts to two
different substances. You
know, some people can't smile.
I've,
we were talking about this before.
I know people that have given them pot
and they swear there's something in it.
They, well this is not pot. This
is, you're drugging me. And so, no,
it's just pot man. It's just, you're,
you're, you're set ups different.
There's a certain amount of immunity
that I've developed that you,
you don't have tolerance
rather. Right. Um,
I think it's really unfortunate though
that we can't experiment with these
things if they aren't like, uh, you know,
at a university level. But this isn't like
normal people are quietly doing research
on basically everything now I think.
I think,
uh,
I don't know if there's anything that
you can't do research with at the moment,
but it all is pretty quiet. But they're
doing an MDA research. And actually the,
um,
I'd,
that I was at Ted and someone
who's somewhat close to
this research told me that
the,
they've been having such success with
two sessions of Mtma therapy for PTSD,
that the,
that the military is now looking
at it using MDA for Mgma for,
um, yeah, I'd heard about the two or
like two or three sessions protocol,
which sort of,
I think the jury is still out on the,
the neuro toxicity of Mtma. I
think it's, I mean, this, there,
there've been studies
on, on, on both sides,
but if it's just two sessions and you
get some huge response rate for PTSD,
um,
and that,
that's where it gets around the neuro
toxicity questioned because it's not,
it's not so toxic that you can't do it a
few times or even a few more times than
that. Um, but yeah, so, so anyway, I,
I'm not a
psychedelics or we're truly indispensable
for me at a certain time in my life in
terms of just,
I was so I was a hard enough case and
skeptical enough that there was anything
worth realizing through introspection
that it took just getting hurled over the
wall for me to realize that there was any,
any more to the world. And, and, and so,
and, and then that gave me a basis
from which to practice meditation and,
and kind of look into these things.
What do you think is happening
in the psychedelic experience?
I've heard the broad spectrum of,
you know,
you're just changing the brain chemistry.
You're adding in and add a different
element that creates hallucinations.
And because those hallucinations,
you know,
you get these profound feelings and you
can learn and grow from those feelings
too. It's a radio and you're tuning into
another life form that only communicates
with you through eating it.
It's from another planet.
And that's why there's a logos.
That's why when you take especially
high doses of mushrooms there,
you'll have people, community,
you'll have a language,
whether it's internal or not, you don't
really know. I mean, it could all be,
you know, how much of w if you
can see any of that stuff. I mean,
how much of that is just firing against
the different parts of your brain that
causes, uh, causes visions? I mean,
what do you think is happening
in a psychedelic experience?
Well, let's say, so I blogged
about this. I wrote an article, a
drug, drugs in the
meaning of life. And, um,
and so I, I'm in a footnote,
I differentiated those two
kinds of psychedelic experience
because there is this,
there is the one experience
which is, um, again,
personal,
even if it's even if it's trans personal,
it doesn't put you in dialogue
with anything else or it
doesn't seem to put you
in dialogue with anything else. Um,
and that's the only kind I've ever had.
I've never had the
experience where you're, um,
the Terence Mckenna style on now in
the presence of the other talking and
receiving information that,
that I couldn't have had it
any other way or it could,
don't think I could have
had any other way. So the,
so for people who have had that
experience, it seems rational to say that,
that it's putting you in touch with and
other, in some sense, it's not just you,
it's not just an expanded you or just
the universe without you be without your
ego involved.
It's actually
putting somebody else's attention on you
and now you're in dialog. Now that's,
cause that's an experience I haven't had.
And so I can't really that,
but the thing is that the test of
the validity of that experience,
it's pretty straight
forward. I mean, if you're,
if you're getting information that
you couldn't have any other way,
that should be provable. And one of
the things, one of the, the, the, um,
the fishy things about
Terence has account of,
of these states is that at many
moment he claimed to be getting,
he really did claim to have a compelling
experience of being in dialogue with
kind of omniscient other, you
know, so he would, there was,
I don't know if you read his book
true hallucinations. So He's,
he's in the Amazon and he's walking
around and he's, he's had more, um,
mushrooms than, than any
person in human history. And,
and he is in dialogue with,
with,
um, it's a very, very readable book,
very fun read. Um, some very, uh,
out there ideas in there. And,
and so I'm going to summarize,
I'm going to,
I'm going to falsify by summarizing what
he was claiming to be in dialogue with,
but he's in dialogue with
some Omnish and other, um,
and it's just so he's pointing to a
species of plant that he doesn't know the
name of his cube. Terrence was very, had
a lot of botanical knowledge, but he,
his point,
his point of plants that he doesn't know
the name of and he claimed he's just
getting the Latin name in his head
beam to him by the other right now.
That would be a, he, he,
it's been a little while since
I looked at the book. But
if you're of a scientific frame of mind,
you actually want to establish whether
this is more than just your experience.
That's the kind of thing that you, it's
very testable. I mean, you could say,
listen, I had, you know,
I didn't know any of these plants and I've
never taken a course in botany or get,
I'm going to give the same dose to someone
who I really does know what I really
know.
It doesn't know a damn thing about botany.
And we're going to see how many of
these species of plants he can name. Um,
and that's just, I mean
that would be, it's, it's a,
it's as easy as testing psychic
phenomenon and an ordinary sense.
And if you could attach it
is scientifically, if you
could just get information,
one unique experience though. I mean, but,
but it's just a member of
any of those names. He, yeah,
he didn't so, so Tara,
Tara's was so smart. Um,
but he,
you know,
he was not the most rigorous,
uh,
at the margins of his rap on
what is real, you know, he was,
he was more poet than
scientists when he would,
when he would get to some of
these crucial moments. And so, um,
yeah,
I haven't seen in his work any
effort to be really rigorous and say,
okay,
I had this experience where I was getting
information that I know was not my own
content. It was not based
on prior learning and it was
not just merely imagined.
It was real information.
And here is how I went about
trying to authenticate that, that,
that it was real information because he
talks about just being able to close his
eyes and see, not, I
mean alien civilizations,
obviously that's hard to authenticate,
but you know,
see historical periods and see,
um, he said, yeah, yeah, no. Yeah.
So he was, he would, you know,
because Evan, it wasn't some of his,
some of his talks. Oh, he's probably high
as fuck. Yeah. So, so obviously it's,
it's possible to be completely stoned
and have these wild experiences that are
basically just dreams right
now or hypnogogic images and,
um, unless you can bring back those
Latin names. Yeah. If you can't,
if you can't bring back something
that's clearly information,
then my feeling is there's no
reason to claim that it is.
You can claim that this is the one thing
that what's indisputable is that people,
people can have a range of experience
that is incredibly beautiful and life
changing.
And then
a certain percentage of people feel the
need to tell a metaphysical story about
the significance of those experiences.
And,
and religion is in the
business of enshrining specific
metaphysical stories as
the ultimate truth.
Um,
we know they can't all be true because
they're all mutually canceling. Um,
which is to say of Christianity's
true Islam is false and vice versa.
Uh,
but
the psychedelic experience falls into the
same, uh, under the same rubric. I mean,
you can have all of these experiences
and not know what they mean and be very
humble about what they,
you know,
what you don't know and still value
the experiences or you can say, oh no,
I,
I'm in contact with the pleiadians and
they live in a star system and they're
sending messages, blah,
blah, blah. And then you,
then you're just part of the cacophony
of new age, uh, claims that are,
that are unsubstantiated. So, uh, I didn't
know that he had claimed that, that said,
it's really pretty funny.
But one of the things that he did claim
was that he was high on mushrooms and
they were communicating with him,
telling him to create a map
of time out of the Ching.
And it's something the whole time wave.
That's another thing
that just, you know, he,
he played some mathematical game
with the, the end date, right? Uh,
the king when sequence and the itching
and uh, I don't, I don't think he did it.
I don't think he was alone for this.
I think he found some mathematically
talented or crazy grad student to help him
with this game. But he got
some pattern of, of um,
what, you know, but again, you
mean how you define novelty?
It's so sketchy and yeah,
I never wanted to go down that
particular rabbit hole with him.
Um, but yeah, if the world ends
in eight months or whatever it is,
uh,
as he predicted or the same dictating the
singularity happened or something huge
that he,
what he predicted is the,
the asam tonic achievement
of novelty on December 21st,
2012. Um, uh, whatever that means,
it's going to be the most novel day
and the history of the universe and,
and nothing, nothing be the same. Um,
so if December 22nd dawns and basically
what we've just had another news cycle
and, and it's just Fox
News versus CNN, um,
we'll know that that novelty
theory was, was wrong. Um,
and then there'll be the percentage of
devotees who just think it's kind of time
shifted in some, you
know, well there's a way.
Hello.
Cause he was such an entertaining
speaker and I think that was really a big
problem. The problem was that he was so
entertaining and engaging that, you know,
he sort of was a prisoner to his gift
and his gift was to tell these compelling
stories and if the story
wasn't so compelling,
well you move things around and make
it compelling. And unfortunately,
I really found out recently because
of people in my message board kind of
eliminated this to me.
He changed the end date is December 21st,
2012 end date that he always said was
that he magically arrived at with his
mathematical program,
which was to the day,
the same end date of the long count of
the Mayan calendar. Right. He, Brian,
you gotta throw that fucking stupid
clock away, man. That shit's annoying.
Ridiculous. Meow cock.
You're a grown man. Um,
but apparently it was really a November.
It wasn't, uh, his, his original,
his original calculations
were in November. Well,
and then when he found out about
the end date of the Mayan calendar,
then he just shifted it a month.
No, which is so convenient. Right?
But this is ridiculous because
he used to say to the day,
so he was a great speaker. It was,
I mean, really, really cool ideas.
A lot of fun to follow.
But when you do that much,
you know, reality must become
like a slippery fish in
your hand, you know, really,
really difficult to
constantly have control of.
Yeah. Yeah. No,
that is a bit of a liability when you
say it so well you can get carried away
with just the, the, the experience
of, of saying it that well and to,
and to some degree is true with
writing. I mean, you can have,
I think Freud's influence
is how is outside influence.
It's outsize influence, which is, um,
kind of inexplicably given how
crazy some of his ideas were, um,
is born of just the quality
of his writing. And he was,
Freud was a great writer
and, and uh, it's just,
um, I mean the whole mythology he
created for what's going on in our head.
Fascinating. Fascinating. But it, so it's
like a, you know, it's so much of it is,
is cocaine base should
have been obviously bogus,
but he was a damn good writer.
Yeah. Well to this day, people, you
know, talk about 40 and slips, you know,
that there's somehow knows deck
going on in the back of your mind.
Well, it's not, the thing is,
I mean mother and there are,
there's a lot of unconscious
processing going on. And I mean,
this is actually the subject of my
current book, very short book on free.
Freewill is, speaks to
that. That it's just
the sense that we have
of being the kind of,
the conscious authors of our thoughts
and actions we know is false. Now.
It's not false in the Freudian sense that
we've got the ID and the superego and
the, and the ego, uh, uh, at war.
And it's all being driven from behind
by a kind of intelligence that's
consciously editing, uh, what we can
consciously know. But there's just that,
there's most of our PR what of what's
going on in the brain is unconscious and
most of it's not even
potentially conscious. And,
and that actually explains a lot of the
change you get with psychedelics because
what you change the biochemistry enough.
Okay
you,
you are,
you're playing with the margin of
what's conscious and what's potentially
conscious.
And we are potentially conscious of
a lot of things we don't tend to be
conscious of and that it
completely transforms our, our,
our experience.
But there's a lot that we're not just
potentially conscious of that the brain is
doing.
And it is,
it is everything we are conscious of
is dependent upon all of that work.
So for instance,
the fact that you are hearing my words
as words right now because you speak
English and I'm speaking in
English and you're parsing the,
so I'm making sounds and you're just,
you're not making any special effort to
hear words. You're just hearing words.
In fact, you couldn't not hear
word if you tried and it just,
the words are coming and
you're understanding them.
And I'm going to get to the end of
this sentence sometime and we'll both
recognize that it was more or less
grammatically correct. All of that.
Okay.
It's happening unconsciously
and you're not. And, and
okay,
you're just conscious of understanding
what I'm saying or not based on whether
I'm following the rules of English
grammar or not, but I'm not a,
I'm not aware of what's allowing me to
follow the rules. You're not aware of, of,
of what's allowing you
to detect my errors. Um,
and the truth is from a
conscious perspective,
I don't know how I get to
the end of the sentence.
And this has really like all of this,
this experience of talking is riding a
top of machinery that I can't inspect.
And when it fails, it's a, it's a
surprise and I don't know why it failed.
And so that's,
that's just talking about parsing speech.
But all of our,
all of our thinking and behaving
and wanting and doing all of our,
our inner life is made
of, of, of
unconscious processing of that sort.
And so their experiments where
you can show that people,
people, when you think you have
consciously decided to do something,
your brain is actually committed to
doing it half a second or some seconds
before your, before you, why you still
think you're making up your mind.
So this really nullifies a conventional
notion of free will because you're,
you know, if you say, if
you give me two buttons,
push and I can push either one I want
and I can push them when I want and you
just tell me to make up my mind and I
go back and forth and back and forth and
say I'm going to push the left one.
Which completely free choice. I did it.
No one forced me to do it.
Okay.
The truth is if you were recording
from my scalp with EEG or,
or looking with Fmr,
I at at a brain function,
you could detect that
before I thought I was committed cause I,
cause in these experiments subjects
watch a clock and they, and they,
and so I'm like watching the hands of a
clock or watching random numbers appear
on a screen.
And I looked and I,
my only goal is to just look at when
I've decided when I'm committed, I go,
I go back and forth between
left and right, left and
right, and then I say, okay,
that's the hand to the six.
I'm going to go left.
All the experiments show
that that for some decisions,
several seconds before we could
tell from the brain what whether,
whether the subject was
going to go left or right.
So your subjective sense of being truly
upstream of your decision making process
is, is a false one. The only problem
I have with that is two fold.
One is that if you're going
to study something like
that and you, you, you know,
you, you, you make it
clear study where you're,
there's a red and a green and you have
to make a choice as to which one and you
monitor the subject's brain. Is that
real? Is that real life? I mean,
it's a fucking test, you know? I mean,
how do we know what's going
on in a real life scenario?
How do we know that there's not a lot of
overthinking going on? How are we now?
There's not a lot of shit going
on behind the scenes like in,
in this sort of a situation because you're
a, you're, you're setting up this test,
right? To can, can,
could psychedelics change free will if
a psychedelic experience changes your
whole tune? Could it, could
it literally change what,
what decisions you would
automatically make? I mean,
if there is no freewill of freewill is
just your mind for whatever reason goes
left or right based on morals or ethics
or what feels right or what feels wrong
in that sense, wouldn't psychedelics
be able to change free will? Well,
I think freewill is, is a
truly incoherent, crazy words.
It just doesn't make a placeholder.
We have,
we have causality and,
and no one has ever described a way in
which mental or physical events can arise
that make sense of this idea of freewill
or of being the true locus of the
causes of your thoughts and
actions. And, and this is,
most people think that we have this,
the,
it's a mystery here that we have this
subjective experience of freewill,
but we can't map it on to a notion
of physical cause and effect.
But I think if you've looked closely,
you realize you don't even have this
objective experience of free will.
So if I ask you, you
know, think of a, a, a,
an MMA fighter. Okay. Okay.
So did you get one? Yes. Okay.
Who'd you think of [inaudible]
Saint Pierre. Okay.
So now why didn't you think
of Matt Hughes? Uh, okay. Now,
until now, whatever story you're gonna
tell him about his menial, right?
So the truth is you're not in a position
to know why you thought of George St
Pierre. Right? And so, so, okay,
there are all these MMA
fighters whose names you know,
and you know them as well as, you
know, George Saint Pierre, his name,
you could have thought of Overeem or,
I mean there's a hundred you
could have thought of, right?
Yeah.
You,
let's say you thought of a few and then
you settled on one to tell it for the
purposes of telling me what you thought
of since he got Hughes and you got over
him, you guys Saint Pierre and then
I said, well who was it? And you say,
well Saint Pierre,
right?
You can't explain why you fixated on
him as opposed to Hughes or whoever the
other candidates were in your mind.
All of that's being driven from behind
unconsciously and there's no way to ever,
even if it wasn't even if there was
no time lag, even if we knew that the,
the neurophysiology and the, and the
conscious thought were truly simultaneous.
So there was no part of your brain that
was going George Saint Pierre before you
are aware of it, right? It's still a
mystery as to why it is what it is.
Right?
But that's sort of a,
an answer to a question
with no consequence when
it comes to something with
consequences and their freewill. Then
when someone contemplates the, you know,
the results of their actions.
And I mean is,
isn't that what we really truly
consider to be free wills?
You look at something and you so should
have hit this old lady with my car. No,
I should not because I have free will.
I mean, even if there was, you know,
some sort of a decision that had, you
know, green lit in your brain, you know,
seconds earlier than that, no, we're
not going to run over this old lady.
Sort of that's freewill,
right? I mean, what, what leads
someone to murder someone?
Is every murderer innocent
because they don't have freewill?
Are they a accumulation of their past
histories and our emotional responses to
various stimuli, good or bad
in their environment that's
led them down this road.
And here they are in this moment in time
and this physical altercation and they
murder somebody. Do they not have free
will? Right. Yeah. So all good concerns.
Um,
okay.
Clearly there's a,
there's a difference between
voluntary and involuntary action and,
and so we can talk about that difference
without ever invoking freewill.
So they're,
they're the things I choose to do and
I'm reaching for the water because I want
to pick it up. And that's different from
me accidentally knocking it over or,
or so, so, and, and
those differences matter.
So if you intentionally shot me,
that's one thing.
You're a murder and attempted
murder. Um, if your,
if you accidentally shot maybe
cause you were cleaning your gun,
there was no intent and that says a lot.
You're a very different
person in the world.
You're not the person who
intentionally shot me. Um,
so we don't have to worry about
you in the same way. Um, so for,
for the purposes of our legal system,
the difference between intent and, and,
and lack of intent is huge.
But it's huge because it says a lot
about what someone's likely to do in the
future.
Yeah.
That the payoff is that,
yeah,
there are
one,
I think understanding that,
that the incoherence of freewill
does subtly change your,
your morality and would
change our legal system in,
in small but crucial ways because
okay.
Changes your morality because
you have to acknowledge that
there's a huge role.
For luck in this world that,
that that is morally relevant that
we don't acknowledge. So, I mean,
you are not responsible for the
fact that you have your genes,
that you were born to this, this society
that you've had your life experience,
that you're brave. You,
you didn't make your brain,
your brain isn't exactly the
state it's in based on Noah. You,
it's not an accomplishment of
yours. Right. You and Andy,
you can't take credit for the
fact that you're not a psychopath.
You are lucky that you're not a
psychopath. On some basic level,
you would be unlucky to have the genes
and the life experience that would make
you want to get up tomorrow morning and
kill kids. Do you think that cycle, that,
that sort of a pathology
is inherently genetic,
do you think that know better mental,
whether it's combination.
So it's a combination. It's,
it's significantly genetic,
but so was a combination of environment,
but you didn't pick your environment.
Right?
Right.
But it's not something that someone
can avoid based on a bunch of different
circumstances. Yeah. So,
so I'm not negating the role of human
effort and human intention and we can
change ourselves. We can, we can get in
shape, we can learn new skills, we can,
we can improve relationships.
This is everything about what people
want to want to do with their lives,
um,
can be conserved.
But the truth is some people are
much luckier than others. I mean,
it's like, and, and, but,
and no one can take credit for
the fact that they're intelligent,
that they're good looking that there,
I mean, it's, it's like, so say this,
but what about the
secret, correct? Yes. Yes.
That talk about the dangerous nonsense.
Did that drive you crazy when that was,
you know, was, was all coming
out that was a oh yeah, it was,
that was the most irresponsible thing
in the world from Oprah's Oprah, Oprah,
Oprah is boosting of
that book. Was, was, uh,
journalistically irresponsible in
the way that, that, that few things,
it's amazing watching
people run with it though.
People that were convinced that all of
a sudden they were going to create their
life with their imagination.
Right. But sort of,
there is some sort of an impact that
your thoughts in mind have on the real
world. Oh No. It's positive
energy. Psychic energy.
There's something there.
Yeah.
If you're a nice person and you're
thinking nice thoughts about people,
they're going to notice that.
And like you, and that's,
that becomes a self fulfilling
loop. I mean, you were like, if you,
if you are an angry person who's always
noticing what's wrong with the people
around you, that that's, that's very
hard to keep to yourself. Right?
And people began to treat you a
certain way and it becomes self.
So you think it's an entirely
social pointers of a thought?
Well, I, there is not,
I wouldn't attribute any
spooky level to it. It's all,
it's all understandable. Um, you've,
you ever seen like mass prayers where they
work on a certain, you know, thing and,
uh, you know, everybody together try
to pull up their energy that, well,
that's, it would be so it would
be so easy to demonstrate and,
and there's been so much prayer.
MMM.
That Ha. I mean, it's just, it's,
I mean, this is what the great, um,
the website. Why, why does God hate
amputees? I mean it's it because it's so,
so you have all these people who
believe they've been healed through
intercessory prayer of their cancer and
all these other diseases that are self
limiting.
You'd never hear somebody up here.
If somebody who's prayed to grow back
and arm and said, look, you know,
here's a picture of me without an arm.
And now they're both back on the,
on like the human salamander.
You, if prayer worked,
you'd be able to pray for
lost arms that you say that.
But what a prayer only works
a really tiny bit and you go,
you have a lot of people involved.
There's boosts your immune system. No,
I mean it's just not, it's not
perfect. It's not magic. Is there,
is there power in thought, but
it is billed as magic. Yes,
it is billed as magic, but every once,
okay, God, if we're talking about God,
I'm talking about groups of people
praying for things I'm talking about using
their energy of their thoughts.
I'm not really talking about invoking
a higher power, I'm just stopping up.
But no, but they think they are. Maybe
it was just making it a with art bell,
you remember that child? Our
Bell? Yeah. Coast to coast.
Werewolves at three o'clock in the
morning when you're driving on am radio.
I believe he did some sort
of a chest where he tried to,
they tried to influence something,
whether it's weather or something with,
you know, a gigantic MindMeld off. But
it wasn't, it wasn't a religious thing.
I think the idea was it can you get
a bunch of people to concentrate on
something and do we have like the most
minute ability to influence things and
together we could do something measurable.
But I dunno if anybody ever do anything.
A lot of people who have done research
of that kind and what they claim is just
that these,
these micro departures,
these micro effects that when
you aggregate them over many,
many trials represent huge statistical
departures from chance and met.
Most people in the skeptic community
find that completely unpersuasive because
you looked into it at all
like random number generator.
And I've just, I haven't,
apart from just reading a couple of
books like Dean Raven's book on the
conscious universe, um,
it's what you come down to.
There are just Meta analyses of
someone's statistics and the,
the concern on the part of
skeptics that, you know, there,
there are frauds involved or there's just
a file drawer effect where people are
not reporting their failures and
they are reporting the, the, the, um,
the positive results. And so,
um, there's just what you want,
what you should be able to find
is if these are, if these are,
if these are real abilities that that
really matter in terms of, you know,
tangible results tend to,
you should find someone who can come
into the lab and demonstrate telepathy or
clairvoyance or whatever the thing
is you're interested in. And so,
so that it's really,
it should survive the presence
of a skeptic like James Randy,
who's a professional magician who knows
how to fake these mentalist games. Um,
you should be able to test it in.
So I actually have short,
I spoke to Rupert Sheldrake about this
one's cause you do, you know, sure.
Residence.
I said he's a big advocate of the
scientific testing of these phenomenon,
but he's very, um, he's a
believer. He's a, he's a,
he's a, he's a real
believer and you know, he's,
he's published essays or,
or articles on,
you know,
pets that know when their
owners are going to come home.
And so he's got the camera on the dog and
the owners headed home and he's got it
them times sinkton showing the effect
of the dog getting up at the right time.
And he's very into the idea
of democratizing science
where you can get thousands
of people doing these tests on
their own and, and, and, and,
and showing some effect.
Uh,
but what he hasn't wanted to do is
just actually submit to James Randy's
challenge of showing up and doing
an experiment that will survive the,
the,
the scrutiny of professional magicians.
And I'll just allow this
thing to be, and, and I,
it's just,
you know,
people find James Randy's
skepticism so unpleasant that they,
that they think that that would
nullify the experiment or somehow,
or they're not going to submit
to it. But I mean, James,
Randy has put up $1 million to anyone
who can show some positive result.
Um, now I no doubt he's not the easiest
guy to deal with. If you actually,
you know, if you are a, a,
a committed to the reality of psychic
phenomenon and you have to go in and meet
with James, Randy and, and
design an experiment, um,
I'm sure he's gonna he's,
uh,
he's going to make you jump through hoops
that you feel like you don't have to
jump jump through. But yeah, it would,
it would be trivially easy
to design a valid experiment.
They could demonstrate these, these
effects. And so I'm open minded that,
that this stuff is
possible, but it's, it's,
it's fishy that he hasn't,
it just had taken the people
should just come forward and, and,
and demonstrate the effect. Well, what is
rel Rupert's claims? I mean, is it, is it,
you know, that every single time Rupert
Rupert's claim was that, that, um,
he doesn't think science should be decided
by contest. Essentially. It's like,
it's, it's not, that's not how you
do science. You don't do science.
To answer $1 million challenge
put up by a magician.
And that's a okay.
I,
the kind of the his aesthetic objection.
Or is interpersonal objection to working
with, with a cranky person like Randy,
but I'm cranky, not in the, in the flaky
sense, but cranky just in the, you know,
he's a, he's a confrontation.
Yeah. He's confrontational. Um,
but given how the whole field of
Paris psychology and you know,
cy studies is treated like intellectual
pornography given how discredited it is
in the, in the view of,
of mainstream science.
If there's an effect there and you've
got a protocol that has demonstrated it,
just come forward and do it.
Do it in every context where you
can shine light on it and, and,
and just prove it. Um, and Sheldrick
has never done this, not well,
not to anyone's
satisfaction that, that, um,
that, that can move the conversation
forward. And he says he, you know,
there's many people who
say they've done it,
but when you actually look at what they,
what hasn't happened is you haven't,
you haven't discovered people with,
with where there's a really strong effect
where you get one person who's like,
you know, the tiger woods of,
of mind rating, where you were,
where they can actually show
a departure from, from chance.
That is huge in, uh, in their own trial.
What you get is if you get 6,000 people
staring at a random number generator
trying to make it depart to the high
side as opposed to the low side,
you get people saying that
there was this tiny effect.
So it should have been 50,
50.
It was actually 51% over all those trials.
And that when you do the stats on it is a,
you know,
you would expect a one in
10 billion due to chance.
That's just,
um,
that's subject to many kind of
experimenter, uh, problems that, that,
that people are right to worry about,
which is one you didn't, I mean,
people have been caught not reporting
their failed experiments. I mean there's,
so there's a kind of a true believer
syndrome that happens even in certain
things. I mean there's, there's a,
there's a phenomenon of
scientific fraud across science,
which is a problem we guard against.
But, um, it's also been true of,
of pair of psychology as well.
Do you think it's possible that people
have these certain senses that have not
evolved yet? And that that's why
like sometimes you know, you know,
someone's going to call you and you pick
up the phone and it's them. You know,
there's weird non duplicate
a bowl that's on a word.
There's weird experiences that you can't
duplicate. You know, there's, there's,
there's random weird things that can't
be controlled, but sometimes the,
the right frequency kicks in and you
catch a radio station from San Diego when
you're in San Francisco and
it doesn't make any sense.
And it only lasts for a little while. Is
it, is it possible? Do you believe? Like,
have you ever had personal
experiences where you know,
you knew someone was staring
at you and you looked
and they were, you knew the phone
was gonna ring and a dead. Oh yeah.
It's all bullshit. Well,
no, it's not bullshit, but
a huge component.
And perhaps the component that explains
all of those experiences is what's
called sampling bias.
Where are you?
You notice all the hits and you
don't notice that the non hits,
you don't notice all the time you pick
up the phone and you had no idea who was
calling you, which is most
of the time. Right. Um,
and this was before caller id.
Obviously caller ID has, has, has,
has ruled out the psychic phenomenon.
Um,
but so we're not, we're just,
we know, we don't keep track.
We w one w w the hits are salient to
us and the, and the failures aren't,
and so,
and religious people do this all the time.
God always gets credit for
the good things he does,
but he doesn't get scored for all the,
the disaster as he fails to prevent. So,
you know,
a bus crashes and everyone's dead except
one little girl and it's a miracle.
It's God's miracle that,
you know, she walked away.
But what about all the dead people?
So of course, um, and so the,
the non hits always out weigh the hits
and if you actually do, so the, and the,
the classic demonstration of this, which
is still shocking to people is, is the,
um, it's called the, the,
the hot hand fallacy and basketball,
the idea that people get on a shooting
streak, you know, Michael Jordan,
he would shoot two outside jumpers and
when, when he goes up for his third,
there's this sense both in him and in
the audience that he's actually more
likely to make that third shot.
Having made those pro prior to
because he's, he's just on a roll.
So that whole feeling of being on a role
in basketball has been studied because,
uh, what's amazing about professional
sports like basketball is,
is these statistics are like every
single game that has ever been played.
It's completely broken down. And that we
know what we know every shot and every,
every, you know, uh, a basket
and every rebound. And so,
so statisticians could
just sit down and analyze,
is there such a thing as the hot hand?
Is it actually true that if a guy
has made three jumpers in a row,
he's more likely to make the fourth
or as the fourth truly independent of
everything that's gone before.
And they just,
they found that despite the personal
experience of being on a roll and despite
the fact that we feel like we've
all seen someone on a role,
there's really no such thing as
being on a role in basketball. Now,
there may be other sports where
it's different, but there's so much,
there's so much chaos and
so much uncertainty in once
that ball leaves your hand,
uh, it's, it's, it's a,
it's a low percentage enough phenomenon
that it is actually insensitive to
statistical analysis. No,
it's, it's insensitive,
insensitive to the fact that you feel
great and everything's going well for you
and you just sank two baskets
and you go up to sink a third.
That third is you're no more likely
to sink that third. Then you were a,
if it was your first one and you're, or
you would just, or you just failed to, to,
to you, you just missed two and
then you go up for the third.
So do you completely discount the
players comfort like when they feel like
during the zone that doesn't exist?
I mean,
what is the zone state of mine
that created having an experience?
So what's amazing about this is this
is no one's ever more likely to make a
basket.
Is that what you're saying?
A quarter now they're confident and they
make the basket knowing that they're
going to make the basket.
Statistically you say that that doesn't,
there is no sign of a, and this, again,
this research is probably, it's probably
10 years old or so. So you know,
maybe something's happened
in the last decade,
buddy land just fucked up the whole
thing. Right, exactly. But my,
my understanding is there
is zero evidence of,
of what's called the hot hand in
basketball. So that it literally, it is a,
it is a subjective error that
everyone feels powerfully.
And so given that,
and it says,
just map that on to all of our psychic
so-called psychic experiences where you
feel like you knew someone was going
to call or we're just just luck it.
Yeah. It's just, it's just there's
gonna be some, how do you know though?
How do you know it's just luck?
How do you know it's not either or?
How do you know it's not well, cause
I'm ty was tested a brief buddy. Yeah.
It shouldn't be just testing it.
You're by caught by placing
the experiment on anything,
don't you automatically
alter the results of it?
Especially we talking about something.
So a theory is an idea of
a friend and then boom,
there's an email in your box.
You haven't talked to them in years.
I'm just playing devil's advocate here
because I don't believe in it. Listen,
I've had to, I had, I don't know that
I don't believe in either. So here's a,
here's a, here's one weird experience
like that that I've had, which, uh,
may statistically it seems a
completely beyond the pale,
but it's,
again,
there are going to be low probability
events that happen every day. And, and,
and so, you know, I, I know
a guy who went, for instance,
his college girlfriend,
uh,
when broke up with him and went to Europe
and he was convinced the relationship
wasn't over and he decided he was going
to go to Europe to find her. Right?
So He's 18, right? Not a crazy
guy, just really romantic guy.
And it was not a scary breakup. So Anyway,
nice story. They got back together.
But um, what happened is, so
he goes to, so it's just the,
the only an 18 year old could
get it into his head to do this.
He gets on a plane and he doesn't
even know which country she went to.
So he just goes to Europe,
right.
He goes to Spain because he
speaks Spanish and starts asking.
He's like 10 days into his trip and so
he's in Barcelona and some tourists,
I hand him other tourists,
hand him a camera and said,
will you take our picture?
And he picks up the camera and he's taking
their picture in interframe walks his
ex girlfriend.
Right.
So he's like within 10
days he just found her in.
So what are the chances of that
happening? Well, it's pretty fucked.
Pretty is pretty small,
right? Um, but that kind of,
that stuff happens to people.
It would be,
it would be a miracle if high low
probability events never happened.
You know, it's like if, if it
will be a miracle, if no one,
no one in human history ever had a
story like that to tell, you know,
we're in a system where it's,
it's balanced.
There's bound to be very
low probability events or
it's just not fully evolved.
And this kid went on his instincts and
he tapped into the information in the
universe and he knew instinctively
where to go and he met his sweetheart,
God Damn Sandra Bullock movie.
If, if it's a, if it's an ability
that anyone should care about,
it should be testable.
It should be strong enough
tested.
But how can you test something when it's
an unique event that very rarely takes
place completely uncontrollable,
and it's something that's just a,
almost like a natural phenomenon
that rarely occurs. I mean,
how are you going to put something in a
testing environment in the environment
of a laboratory? Oh No. See if it really
does make sense that you think about,
I think it might be Sheldrake who's
doing this. Hey, there's a test of the,
of the phone call
phenomenon where you get,
people can subscribe to get there.
They get a call at the,
they enlist like their five closest
people in their lives and to call them at
random intervals,
you know,
I guess they did it disable
their caller id or whatever.
And you can just set
this up so that you know,
still not a true moment because they're,
they're acting on a, an experiment.
But then instead,
do you know that someone calling you
might not just be calling you because they
tapped into this idea of loving you and
they I this idea of missing you and that
is the tune that breaks through all the
way to you and causes you to look at
your phone right when
they turned in. That's not
replicatable. Replicatable. Yeah.
That's what goes for replicable.
Replicable. Yes. It's not, I mean,
you know what I'm saying?
I mean it's,
the idea of unique events isn't
disproven by experimenting with it.
Look, I've, I don't know that it's
true that sometimes, you know,
when someone is calling the,
but I've,
I've had the experience myself
but I haven't had in years.
It's been years and years since
I knew who was going to call me.
And I looked at it.
But I do remember it having,
having it happened in my life several
times would if it's something that just,
you know, want to fucking summer
solstice, the planets are aligned,
your own biology, you have
a certain amount of water in
your system and boom, the,
there's a certain amount of love and the
thought gets through. Is that possible?
Well, well sure it's possible. But
the question is what even though,
even if it's true,
given this description doesn't really seem
to matter because then they're all so,
so it's,
cause it's not fascinating would know,
but it doesn't mean it doesn't count.
It's like it's not,
it's not a matter of just,
it's not a sign of how connected you are
with the person because sometimes you
know, it's somebody you
don't even like. Right.
It's not a measure of how crucial it
is that they reach you at that moment
because sometimes it's completely trivial.
And then other times when someone really
had get ahold of you because you're,
you know,
dad was sick,
they couldn't find you and you are just
blissfully ignorant of the fact that the
closest person in your life is having
a medical emergency. Right. Well,
no one's saying that it works all the
time and that because it works on a blue
moon that it can't, you know, but
that, but then that's not working well,
it's not that it's not working,
it just doesn't work all the time.
It's a rare event. Is it? Is, are there,
is it possible that there are rare
events like that or do you think it's all
just, well, no, but they're
much more likely scientifically
to be as much as well,
given this,
given what we're talking about now,
this is all much more likely
to be coincidence. I mean,
it's just, it's just, it's,
it's quite you. You don't have that many
people in your life. You think about,
you think about them. You don't have that
many people in your life who call you.
I mean, we just were actually run
the numbers on this one problem.
Is that we have very bad
intuitions of probability.
So if you heard of the the
birthday party problem, no.
So if I got a room,
if it puts you in a room of
just random strangers, right?
How many would I have to have in the
room for you to be confident that two
people in the room had the same birthday?
She's so that you'd be willing to bet.
I'll bet you they would have
to be thousands for me. Okay.
And that would just be gas.
Okay. So that's, so that's
basically everyone's guests.
That is just,
there's 365 days in the year.
We've got to get two people on the same
day. That's going to be a lot of people,
right?
The truth is,
and this is just the fact that
if you get 23 people in the room,
you have crossed the 50% threshold so
that it's more likely than not that two of
them have the same birthday.
That's amazing. 23 people. Now,
the reason now what's
crucial to understand is that
it's, it's the crucial piece.
And this actually goes to this deflate.
So many conspiracy theories and other
bad ideas is that it's absolutely crucial
that we didn't specify which birthday,
right? So it's any two birthdays,
any single birthday, any
two people, and any single
birthday, 23. And that makes it,
that makes it, that changes the
game entirely. But if I said,
how many people do I need in a
room to find one with my birthday,
that changes it. Right? Um,
but at any two people on any
given birthday, it's, yeah,
if you go with just your birthday,
that's thousands though.
I don't offhand know what that would
be, but anyway, that's a so, so anyway,
our intuitions, our
intuitions are bad, uh,
about probability. And so, um,
and so when you look at
like nine 11 truth stuff,
it's so much about finding these
little anomalies that strike people as
intuitively highly unlikely and
in desperate need of explanation.
Whereas you can always
look at, at, at any,
anything you look at after the
fact can be described as a miracle.
So like I could say to you,
what are the chances that all of the
wires and objects on this desk would be
exactly in this position on this doesn't
amount of creationists argument for the,
the evolution of the eyeball. Like
how's it, yeah, so a bit, but at least,
so there's actually more to
talk about there. I mean,
it is kind of inscrutable how this,
this stuff happens
through um, uh, genetic,
uh,
mutation and, and environmental pressure.
But we can tell that story, but that,
but this is just a post
hoc after the fact.
I say this is just inexplicably that the
wires are tangled and exactly this way.
If you were going to kind
of randomly do this again,
you'd never get them in this position.
Um,
but of course it's completely meaningless.
There's not it,
the wires have to be some way.
They just happened to be this way.
And I'm putting a,
a morale completely gratuitous burden
on you to explain the fact that they're
just this way. Right?
And so in any situations,
certainly any situation is complicated.
As September 11th,
you're going to see all these anomalies.
So you see, you know, the fact that,
how do you explain the fact that
mmm.
You know,
on that day we,
the navy was running a fighter jet test
and the F and we had f six teens that
were out over the ocean or whatever,
whatever the thing is, you know,
they only run that test,
you know,
two days a year and they were running
at that day, right. You could,
if it wasn't that anomaly, you'd find
some other anomaly. You can always,
if as long as you're
picking after the fact,
you can always find something weird that
is in desperate need of explanation,
have their bins to stay statistical.
Have there been studies that have
proven statistics on people knowing that
people are watching them?
I've heard there's been studies people
say if you had Rupert Sheldrake on here,
he would say yes, but you
would say, no. I, I would,
I'm not close enough to the research
to have any sense to some degree.
Some substantiated though. Well, you just
have to take people at their word. So,
so like I've talked to Rupert,
I don't think Rupert is,
I don't think he's a conscious fraud.
I think he's a smart guy.
He's a very earnest guy.
Is he lying about what he thinks he
knows or has he self deceived or is he,
has he been deceived by
unscrupulous people or is
there a Shim bias? Yeah, yeah,
exactly. So it's just the, the,
the problem is that it's so fringe and
so many people want to believe it's true
that it's easy to worry that
it hasn't really been fully,
um,
you know,
the bushes haven't been beaten hard enough
to find all the errors and the biases
and the frauds.
But if there's a real phenomenon there,
it should be testable and it shouldn't
be vulnerable to the slightest quirk of
Oh,
that,
that experiment or had a bad vibe or it
was too skeptical and therefore killed
the effect. Um, it just, uh,
especially when you're talking about
people who actually wheel, if, if, if,
is it possible that someone
could be the experiment there?
Could I have a bad vibe and beast too
skeptical set up and they got him a
negative energy. You could, you
could set up an experiment where I'm,
the experimenter was 5,000 miles
away or had really good vibes.
You could put the true believers
in, you know, kind of the coach.
You can put a completely friendly coach
who was, you know, Sylvia Brown, you know,
crazy, fraudulent psychic, Sylvia Brown.
She could be there working
her magic, you know, and,
and just, just helping
everybody. You could, you could,
you could surround them with only true
believers if you wanted to. You could,
you could design the experiment
in such a way. Uh, um,
so you can make the vibes
as nice as you want.
It's just that that's anyone who's,
there's a,
there's a fundamentally unscientific
attitude you get from many,
many people in this area of the
human conversation, which is,
science has reductionistic.
It's, it's, uh,
hypercritical. It's life destroying. It's,
there's this whole area of truth that
science and principal can't touch.
And that's just not true. It's like
if it, if it's a real phenomenon,
science is the best way to touch it.
There's certain things that it's hard
to figure out how you would do the
experiments.
Harder to figure out how to get it in
the lab and how to get it to where the
person who's doing the experiments not
being influenced by the fact you're,
you're experimenting on them.
Yes, exactly. So there are
certain, so you know, the,
the scientific research I've done is with
functional magnetic resonance imaging
where you have to put people in an MRI
scanner and it's hugely limits what you
can study because there's the peep people
can't move. You know, if you move you,
you destroy the image.
So you got to lie in a clattering machine,
uh,
motionless and do some cognitive task
that you can do looking at computer
goggles or, you know,
looking at a mirror, um,
and across your feet out into the
room. It's a, it limits you. So, so,
so a brain scanning
experiment is hugely limited.
You can't put somebody on their
bike and have them, you know,
ride off into the distance,
uh, while scanning their brain.
But though those things aside,
you can,
and here we're not talking
about experiments with
those kinds of limitations.
You can,
if people have an ability to know
who's calling on the phone, uh,
if there's even one guy on planet
earth who knows who has this ability,
it should be, we could easily design an
experiment that would demonstrate that.
And the people who claim they're there
are people who really claimed these
abilities. The claimant a repeatable
basis. Yeah. Yeah. There are people who,
well, there they're the sort of kind
of shyster western new age psychics
who,
uh,
I'm not sure, but I, I, I imagine they
just never submit to being tested, um,
for obvious reasons.
And then there are there,
then there's the kind of Buddhist Hindu,
Yogi,
contemplative world where people imagine
that great meditators have developed
these abilities. And even some
of the meditators will, you know,
wink wink suggests that they probably
have these abilities but are just too
humble to demonstrate them.
But,
and there's sort of a kind of religious
taboo against demonstrating them or, or,
or challenging them or are submitting
them to test. But in, yeah, in the,
in the, in the contemplative
world among Buddhists and,
and an Indian Yogis,
there's actually a straightforward
path to developing these skills.
I mean there's, there's a recipe
you could go into your, you know,
you can go ask the Dalai Lama,
how could I learn to read people's minds?
He has an answer to that question.
I mean it's not like, well it's,
it's just a matter of whether you're
gifted or not. Now there's actually,
this is like you can get,
you can basically get a phd
and reading people's minds in,
among Buddhists and Hindus.
So the people who've done that,
why don't they get tested?
It's not cause it,
cause what they're claiming is not
an ability to make a random number.
Generator jumped slightly.
If they've got 5,000 people sitting
next to them also doing it, they,
they,
they claim just huge abilities are
possible for meditators who have reached
certain levels of concentration.
I mean there are people who,
who
the stories are as crazy as anything
you've heard about like remote viewing.
That's probably the craziest shit
of all time, right? Is that Beverly?
It is proven. That's never
been proven. Just vague enough.
Well first of all there are,
there are magicians like um,
so the British magician Derren brown.
I gotta pee again.
I forgot to drink in this gigantic.
I'm so,
I'm so well let's do non psychic that I
forgot I had to pay as how in touch I am
with with the physical reality.
This has been a really
fascinating conversation man.
We could go on for hours and hours. How
long was this again? Almost three hours.
Oh really? Yeah. Yeah. Well yeah
we're five minutes away from three ls.
Hope we didn't kill our audience. People
love this shit. Look, I think your,
your,
your devotion to the scientific method
and exploring everything is very
admirable.
It's very interesting and unique and
we've never had anybody on the show that
breaks things down in that way before.
It's really, really been really cool. Um,
follow him on Twitter,
Sam Harris Org,
and check out all of his books from
letter to a Christian nation was the first
one that I ever read to a end of faith.
And what is the most recent one?
The moral landscape and freewill is the
most recent. And Freewill is the PDF.
It's a downloadable small,
no,
that's a line was a short essay that
that's why a book on the ethics of line is
it Sam Harris. Dot. Org is at the best
I used to go to for everything. Yup.
We got to do this again man.
We didn't even touch a real pleasure.
We didn't talk about martial arts.
Who got all up in Jihad and a little
bit of drugs. It was great man. Awesome,
awesome time. We do this over and over
again. So Ladies and gentlemen, that's it.
Follow him by stuff. Sam Harris is
the fucking man and the show's over.
Thanks everybody. See you
soon. See you this week.
We got a lot of people coming up.
Who the fuck did we got? Brian? Uh,
at the Ice House? Yeah, we got
Joey Diaz podcasts on Friday.
Felicia Mason Silva's coming
back on Tuesday. I'm Aubrey.
Marcus is coming back next week.
We got, we got a lot of people too.
We've got a lot of people. All
right. We love you bitches. Thanks.
Thanks for everything. Bye. Bye.
Okay.