Four,
three,
two,
all the way from Tucson,
Arizona.
Dr.
Weil,
how are you sir?
I am good.
Thanks for doing this man.
I appreciate it.
Pleasure.
You come highly recommended by many
human beings that I know well.
I'm glad to hear it.
How do you.
How do you get such a fine reputation?
Well,
I've been doing the same things for a
long time.
Just putting one foot ahead of the other
and saying what I know to be true and
push and Macho Macho.
Who doesn't like Matcha tea?
This is your stuff.
Yeah,
but you know,
a lot of people know,
have only tasted really bad much
enlighten me what's know?
It's powdered tea and it's very,
very finely powdered and it's very labor
intensive to prepare and it's got such a
huge surface area that it oxidizes very
quickly.
So if it's not properly packed and
stored,
it loses its brilliant green color.
It turns yellow,
green or gray green.
It gets bitter and loses its taste.
And I got to say,
most of the macho that I see served in
this country is of that sort.
And many people have never had the good
stuff.
What's the benefits of Macho?
I know there's.
First of all it's been.
It's beautiful.
I mean I've never seen a green color
like that.
It's just amazing.
And the flavors are amazing,
but it's the only preparation of tea in
which the whole leaf is consumed and it.
It's grown under special conditions.
The leaves are shaded a deep shade for
the last three weeks before harvest.
So the in response to that,
the leaves produce more chlorophyll,
more antioxidants,
more the good stuff.
So it's got a much more of the things
that you want.
And this has like a pop top,
like pringles.
Yeah.
Is that so the marches and it's got to
stay fresh and fun and you want to keep
it in the freezer and freezer and you
can sift it so it doesn't form lumps.
And then you whisk it with that
traditional bamboo whisk or you buy a
little electric whisker and you can
whisk it in hot water or cold water.
And it's very yummy.
And w what,
what does it do for you?
Like,
what's the good.
Well you've got,
it's got caffeine of course,
so you get stimulated by it,
but it's also got [inaudible],
which is this relax and compound that
modifies the effect of caffeine and
produces a state of relaxed alertness so
it doesn't have the jangling effective
coffee.
And uh,
you're getting all of these antioxidant
benefits that are well documented in
tea.
Anyway.
I love it.
It's a great thing.
Anytime you get one of these little
whisks,
it's cool.
It's like a real bamboo made from one
piece of bamboo.
It's a miracle of a Japanese
craftsmanship.
It's beautiful and it's beautiful.
So,
um,
how often do you drink this stuff?
I have a bowl of it every morning and
yeah.
And sometimes I have a glass of iced
macho later in the day,
especially in warm weather.
You just so much a fiend.
I love it.
It's a good thing.
I first tasted it when I was 17.
I was an exchange student in Japan.
Uh,
19,
59.
I lived with a family outside of Tokyo.
We had no language and come and on the
second night I was there,
the mother took me next door to her
neighbors who practice tea ceremony and
they did this thing for me and I was
fascinated by that whisk and the color
of the Macho and I thought it was great.
You know,
I never thought I'd be able to get it
over here.
Yeah.
Well,
so you,
you import this stuff yourself.
Was that.
I started a company called Mochi,
Kaare.
We've got the URL [inaudible] dot com
and I went to Japan to Eg,
which is a little town outside of Kyoto,
which is the center of the best tea
production in Japan.
And I sourced really good macho,
you know,
there are many grades and launch of the
most,
the highest are too expensive to use for
everyday use.
They're really phenomenal.
Alex,
like truffles are really expensive so
I've tried to find the best Macia that
is affordable and make it available to
people here.
So like the highest level stuff.
How much would it cost for a cup of tea?
Hard to estimate for a cop,
you know,
it possibly.
There's a preparation called thick tea
in Japan where they use three times the
amount of powder and probably one bowl
of that stuff,
which is shared by several people.
I don't know.
It could be a $100 a bowl.
Whoa.
Really?
Yeah.
Why,
why did it catch on in Japan like that?
It's always been,
you know,
it has been in Japan for a very long
time.
And,
and uh,
this powdered tea preparation was
originally taken up by Zen monks,
uh,
to help them stay awake during long
hours in meditation.
It was also associated with a Samurai
and became the tea ceremony developed
around that.
Is there anything that is similar to it
is like your Vermont Tay or Guarana or
any other time?
These are all,
they're all caffeine plants,
but in my experience,
t I think,
and it's primarily because of that Elle
fanning content of the effect is
mellower of caffeine.
So you get stimulated,
you get alert,
but it doesn't have the jangling
effective a lot of these other caffeine
beverages.
Do you drink regular coffee as well?
No,
I've never drunk coffee.
Wow.
I think I was turned off because my
parents,
when I was growing up,
drank really strong black coffee with no
sugar cream and I couldn't imagine why
people would savages and those people.
There were different people.
Did you grow up in a northern climate?
I grew up in Philadelphia.
When it's cold outside people they drink
that black coffee makes you angry.
Yeah.
Dark black,
burnt coffee.
I like bright green,
shining Russia.
Isn't it interesting that things that
are good for you?
Many things that are good for you,
like bell peppers or something like
that.
They have a beautiful color to,
well,
you know,
all these,
uh,
the health benefits of fruits and
vegetables.
A lot of them have to do with these
pigments and the pigments the plants
produce,
they're part of their own defensive
system and they do good things in us.
And one piece of advice that I often
give people is you should try to eat
across the color spectrum and every day
about what did you eat today that was
red?
What was purple,
what was green,
what was right.
All of these have different benefits.
Is that a scientific perspective?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
These are categories of phytochemicals
are protective,
phyto nutrients and a lot of them are
these pigments that give a fruits and
vegetables that are bright colors.
Do you think that people
should very those colors and in a given
day or.
I think as as much as you can across any
day,
try to eat across the color spectrum.
That's a good thing to aim for.
Okay.
So just just get as many of them as in
as you can.
Yeah.
So do you take this approach with
fruits,
with all sorts of different things?
Yeah,
brightly colored stuff is good.
Do you eat meat or fish and vegetables?
Just fish and vegetables now when you
did.
One of the things I'm super concerned
with and I've been more concerned with
the more pay attention to it as
sustainability when it comes to fish.
Absolutely.
It seems like especially ocean fish,
we're human beings are just terrible
monsters.
You know,
there's a famous oceanographer in this
country,
Sylvia Earl,
who was the woman that held a record for
the deep dive and she came up to me at a
meeting once and pleaded with me not to
recommend that people eat fish.
He said there just aren't going to be
any in the future and that's probably
true.
Probably the future is going to be
farmed fish and that can be done in a
responsible way.
You can get the good guides,
one is put out by the Monterey Aquarium.
You can get a wallet card that lists
that lists fish and shellfish and rates
them both by toxicity and
sustainability.
And that's a good guide to follow.
Yeah.
Um,
mollusks mollusks I eat,
I eat,
I like oysters and scallops.
I eat them.
What is,
what has led you to not eat chicken or
fish or beef?
It's been a long time.
And uh,
let's see.
I was,
I think 28 and I was interested in Yoga
and people that I knew who were doing
yoga had become vegetarian and I saw
friends of mine that had become
vegetarian.
I thought,
well,
I'll just try it for a little while and
it agreed with me,
I didn't eat fish for a number of years
and I found that made the international
travel very difficult,
especially to Japan.
And,
and then I was reading about all the
research on good stuff and fishing.
I started eating fish and that way of
eating Greens with me real well.
Yeah.
Um,
it is a thing that agree with you thing,
right?
It really dependent upon the person's
very individually.
So,
you know,
it's hard to give blanket rules except I
have no problem telling people to stay
away from refined,
processed and manufactured food.
That's the bad stuff.
Yeah.
That's a really good,
clear thing that everybody can kind of
apply in their life.
But as far as like,
what is gonna work for you,
there's a lot of trial and error
involved isn't absolutely.
You got to do experiments,
pay attention,
see what works for you.
Yeah.
Now you practice.
What would you,
how would you call it?
Integrative,
integrative medicine?
How would you define that?
Well,
it's medicine of the future and uh,
you know,
the short answer and the future short
answer is that's the intelligent
combination of conventional and
alternative medicine,
but really it's,
it's a system that focuses on the body's
ability to heal itself that looks at
people as whole persons,
not just physical bodies,
uh,
that takes account of all aspects of
lifestyle and understanding health and
illness,
a values the practitioner,
patient relationship and makes use of
all therapies no matter where they come
from that show,
reasonable evidence of efficacy and are
not going to hurt people.
So I am absolutely convinced this is the
way out of the healthcare crisis.
I've been training doctors and other
health professionals in it for many
years now.
Now,
when you say the body's ability to heal
itself,
how would you accentuate that with this
to me is the thing that's most missing
from medical education?
Uh,
I,
I think the only time I heard the word
healing used in medical school was in
the,
in wound healing,
which in my first year course in
histology,
to me the most marvelous thing about our
bodies is that they have the capacity to
heal themselves.
You'd get a cut,
you can watch it heal,
and that happens throughout the body.
Knew the DNA molecule.
This is just a big molecule on the
border of life and non life.
It has within it the ability to know in
quotes when it's been injured,
have a cosmic ray,
knocks a part of it out.
Instantly it begins to manufacture,
repair enzymes that,
that duplicate the missing piece and
paste it in and you can see that same
thing at any level of biological
organization.
And to me,
that's where good medicine should start,
that the body has within them the
ability to maintain equilibrium,
heal itself.
Now knowing that the body has disability
of what?
What do you do to accentuate that?
Well,
if I,
when I listened to a patient and hear
their story at the back of my mind,
I'm thinking,
why is healing not happening here,
but what can I do from outside that can
facilitate that?
I can't put it into somebody,
but I can help it along by either
supplying energy,
missing materials,
remove obstacles to it.
You know,
like you have a wound that doesn't heal.
Maybe there's a foreign body in it.
You remove that heals now.
Um,
when you have people that come to that
have issues like saved,
someone comes to and they have a back
issue.
Yeah.
Got a little bit of lower back pain.
Do you approach that from a,
in terms of like how they're eating,
how they're living their lifestyle?
First I would question them about
lifestyle for sure.
But,
uh,
you know,
I'm a great follower of a,
a man who died recently named John Sarno
who isn't,
you know,
veterans work.
Sure.
Uh,
he has some great books,
mind over back pain,
healing back pain.
And his main belief,
which I totally agree with,
is that the vast majority of back pain
is muscle spasm,
which originates in the mind and it may
localize that an area of physical
injury,
but the injury is not the cause of it.
You can live with a slipped disc and
have no pain.
Uh,
you look at x rays it defined slip
though.
What does that mean,
bulging or herniated?
That does not necessarily close pain.
Uh,
and unless there's associated
neurological symptoms,
you don't want to do anything about
that.
It's unless it's pressing on.
Exactly right now I'm John Sarno.
His idea was that it's a lot of stress
and anxiety and a lot of different
psychological factors that I'm sure he
was some kind of incredible healer.
He required the people who came to him
come to to evening lectures that he
gave.
That's all many people who did that lost
their back pain forever,
just listening to him.
So other people have had that happen.
Just reading his book,
I've read a little bit of it's,
you know,
I've had like legitimate injuries.
So whenever I hear someone say,
Oh,
it's all in your head,
it's not all in your head,
it's in your head and your mind,
your box in your head and your muscles,
and then the problem of muscle spasm,
which shuts off blood supply and it's a
vicious cycle that that'll localize at
an area you've had physical injury,
but the pain is not coming from the
injury.
It's coming from muscle spasm and that's
controlled by a greatly influenced by
the mind.
So when you,
when your back is like seizes up,
that is a muscle spasm and it's
incredibly painful and it's located in
the area of the injury.
So it doesn't confuse you into thinking
it's the injury that's causing you pain.
What leads people into getting physical
interventions that may not be necessary?
Yeah,
I'm a big believer in waiting,
especially with spinal stuff.
Solutely absolutely always want to fuse
you and cut you.
And if you look at.
Here's another interesting thing.
You can look at x rays of people's
spines that looks so horrible.
You can't imagine that they can move and
they have no nothing,
no symptoms.
And you can look at other x-rays that
looked perfect and people are disabled
by pain.
So there's a very low correlation
between physical findings and subjective
experience.
Now,
what is Sarno recommend?
I never really recommends going about
your business.
Go nobody even ignoring it,
going about your business and if
possible,
try to figure out what,
what message you know,
your mind descending down there.
But basically it's a reassurance that
it'll go away on its own.
So when he does these lectures and he
has people cures him of it is just,
he just reassuring them that
everything's going to in this process of
how he calls the tension Myositis
Syndrome.
And he explains the mechanism of how it
works.
One friend of mine,
he was in his late twenties,
uh,
played basketball,
had a very serious herniated discs.
He was within hours of having the real
logical surgery,
spinal surgery.
And I yelled at him to read this book
and CSR News in New York.
And he said,
I don't believe any of.
That's all bullshit.
And I said,
go,
go see him.
So he went the same.
Oh,
it went through the evening lectures.
Thought this was nonsense,
uh,
went home,
was having dinner and realized his back
pain was gone,
never had surgery.
She's really know Scott to be something
to that,
right?
There's,
there's something to the placebo effect.
So if there,
if,
if that is a real thing,
if you can convince your body that it's
got the medicine that it needs and it
starts to heal even though there's no
medicine,
there's got to be something that is
working against you as well with the
wrong mindset.
It's funny to me to hear people
rediscovering the placebo effect.
Now,
I wrote a book in 1983 called health and
healing and had two chapters in there.
One Placebos.
And what I wrote is that the greatest
problem is that we know when we talk
about placebos,
it's in phrases like,
how do you know that's not just a
placebo effect.
The most interesting word there is just,
or we have to rule out the placebo
effect.
We shouldn't be rolling it in,
man.
That's the meat of medicine.
That's pure healing from within mediated
by belief on mixed up with the direct
effects of treatment.
That's what you want to make happen more
the time.
It just is a mind fuck for a lot of
people because they're like,
how am I trick myself into getting
better?
Why can't I just do it?
Because that must have something to do
with the structure of the brain that the
part of the brain in which our will is
isn't,
doesn't connect directly to the
machinery of the body to the autonomic
nervous system.
So you have to find some way of getting
around that.
One way is to project belief onto
something external and then let it work
for you.
Yeah,
but that's so strange that the mind
works that way.
It would seem like,
wouldn't it be an evolutionary
advantage?
Just have it at access,
you know,
like.
Sure.
That'd be nice,
but that's the same thing.
You know,
it's a similar problem to why can't you
just get high without taking a drug the
highest in your brain,
not in the drug.
The drug is a trigger that releases it.
Why can't we just sit down and say,
well,
I'm going to be high for the next 10
minutes.
So the same thing,
we don't have access to those controls
to.
It just seems like that one though.
Healing getting better.
That one seems like it's something that
we should as a culture concentrate on.
Yeah,
for sure.
What we really concentrate on is actual
medicine,
but one way to concentrate that is by
giving people greater confidence in
their body's ability to do that.
And doctors have great power to do that
because patients project a lot of belief
on them.
I've had many patients over the years
who said that the most important thing I
did for them was that I was the only
doctor who told them they could get
better.
I mean,
astonishing.
Yeah.
Is it because doctors had just seen too
many patients and they're overwhelmed
and they got legal bills and they have.
I think some.
I've thought about this a lot and
there's also the negative side of this.
I've seen what a,
there's something called medical hexing
in which Dr say things that actually
interfere with healing or caused people
to get worse.
And I think a lot of this is done
unconsciously.
Uh,
so here's one of my thoughts in their
training.
Um,
Dr,
see a very skewed sample of sick people.
They see very sick people in hospitals
and in that group,
healing is less likely to happen,
but if you look at the total spectrum of
illness,
the vast majority of things get better
on their own.
So I think observing in yourself for
wound healing is a good one to start
with,
to get greater confidence in your body's
ability to do things that's really
valuable.
So this obviously you're not talking
about catastrophic injuries,
you just talking about general wellness.
I think even in the case of a
catastrophic injury,
this stuff operates.
I worked a lot with hypnotherapists over
the years and one of the,
one of my colleagues,
uh,
did a lot of work in training paramedics
to be really careful about what you say
around unconscious people who've been
massively injured.
Uh,
you know,
when the,
if a,
if a paramedic takes an automobile
accident victim and they're putting them
in,
says this one's a corner.
That is a bad thing.
You know the unconscious mind on and on
the other hand you say something
opposite to a person.
You can see cases where you can stop
bleeding in unconscious people severely
injured just by giving them suggestions.
Whoa.
Yeah.
So when you're saying someone's a goner,
you trigger stress.
Are you trigger helplessness?
Like what happened?
A medically trained person tell you that
you're not going to live.
That's a.
that's a curse.
Yeah.
That's saying well hex.
How strange is it that sometimes your
life is hanging on the border of you
believing you're going to be okay and
you believe in you're not going to be.
Oh,
so you want to be very careful about,
you know whose hands you place yourself
in.
Yes.
Never want to stay in treatment with a
doctor who thinks she can't get better.
A negative doctor.
Well,
doctors are just like every other
occupation.
There's people that are really good at
it and it really concentrated and
focused and there's people that are half
ass.
Well the ones I trained through our
University of Arizona Center for
Integrative Medicine get it.
You know,
we're putting out.
We've graduated about 1600 physicians
now from very intensive training there
in practice all over the country.
Teaching other people's is a good thing
now.
When you say integrative medicine,
when they're in practice,
are they essentially general
practitioners?
We've trained people from all
specialties and specialty you can name.
We've trained them,
so orthopedic surgeons and neurologists,
dermatologists,
anything you could ever do and so you
try to tend to look at them.
We teach them all the things they didn't
get in medical school,
nutrition,
mind,
body interactions,
strengths and weaknesses of alternative
medicine,
herbal medicine,
all that like say someone comes to you
and maybe they have a bad case of
psoriasis,
autoimmune issue like that.
Prime prime target for mind body
medicine for traditional Chinese
medicine,
which often works well and in that
dietary change,
but people on an anti inflammatory diet,
use of natural products that reduce
inflammation,
so there's a wide range of things to
choose from and this does not reject
conventional treatment.
You know,
we may use conventional medication,
but if you do,
I recommend using the lowest dose of the
least potent agent.
Start off with that and you can ramp up
if you need to.
Well,
a lot of people and me,
I'm definitely guilty of this.
They hear terms like holistic or eastern
medicine or Chinese medicine to go
bullshit.
Right?
Well I have a good bullshit detector too
and so I'm really careful about what I,
you know,
accept and what I know.
Um,
what,
what do you not buy into?
Like when you see your bullshit
detector,
like what were you.
I'll give you an example.
I've,
you know,
I'm not,
I can't see any basis for crystal
healing.
Crystal my pocket right now.
Exactly.
Alright.
Well,
too bad.
How about the colonic irrigation people
tell you,
tell you that they see a watermelon
seeds coming out and you haven't eaten a
watermelon in months.
That's bullshit.
The,
the lining of the Gi track sloughed off
and is regenerated every 24 hours.
There's no way that things can get
encrusted there.
Yeah,
that's a weird one.
The colonic thing,
because your body has all this natural
bacteria that you're supposed to keep in
there.
Right?
Not only keeping there,
we're finding out that that's like more
and more really important determinant of
everything,
of general health,
of mental health to.
Fascinating.
Yeah.
Whose idea was it to start doing those
colonics?
That muscular way back.
That's kind of like a wacky idea.
Pumps water up there.
See what's up.
Yeah.
And you have to stand there when it gets
it.
It's addictive too.
I see people get addicted to this.
Yes.
Yeah.
So out of all the things I won't go
further into.
My wife had it done once and she was
describing it to me.
I'm like,
yeah,
I'm going to pass some lady's looking at
the two and telling you what's going on
in their life.
At some point the is like looking at
your shit.
Right?
It started as early as 1500 BC evers,
pop piracy in ancient Egyptian medical
document described the many benefits of
colon cleansing in ancient times.
The practice of cleansing the colon was
administered in a river by using a
hollow reed to induce water to flow into
the rectum.
We don't want to drink downstream of
that.
Yeah.
And,
and,
uh,
you know,
there's no need to do this.
What you want to do is make sure that
things are going through in the right
direction regularly and it cleans
itself.
That's how it's supposed to do it,
right?
Yeah.
Another big one.
I hear all these people that talk about
detox,
detoxification and sell all these
products.
The body has many natural methods of
purifying itself and getting rid of
things with.
The other one is through sweating.
A one is through breathing,
one is through urination,
one is through colonic elimination.
Uh,
the liver has an incredible capacity to
detoxify.
It can take,
you know,
you put something into your body,
the liver within seconds of seeing a
compound that has never seen before can
begin making a specific enzyme to take
that apart and get rid of it.
Wow.
And you can amputate half of the liver
and it can regenerate within 36 hours.
What's?
Yes,
livers amazing.
Thirty six hours.
Yeah.
So I thought when you gave someone like
half your liver,
if there was like a liver transplant
issue that took a long time.
I know liberty can regenerate really
quickly and there's sand.
There's a natural product that you can
take that most doctors don't learn
about.
Cold milk thistle,
you've probably heard of that.
That revs up liver metabolism,
so you know these are all simple ways to
increase,
but the first rule of detoxification,
I'm sure you can guess you stopped
putting toxic things in,
cut it off at the pass and let it let
the body get purifies all.
Yeah,
well,
what do you do when someone's a
cigarette smoker?
You tell them to set a date.
The quit set a date.
That's the most important thing because
each attempt,
it doesn't matter if you succeed,
it's making the attempt to quit,
goes into a reservoir of motivation.
That one day will be fallen off.
That it's easy,
and this by the way,
happens with heroin.
Addicts,
happens with cigarette
addicts.
I've seen many people,
lifelong cigarette addict struggled,
gave it up,
came back one day they wake up and they
look at stain fingers or a dirty ash
tray and they don't want to do it
anymore and it's an easy.
There's no struggle.
Same thing with heroin addicts,
so it has to do with motivation.
You can't put that into another person
in.
All you can do is arrange circumstances
that maybe it'll happen.
So the most important thing is to help
you to set a date to quit and it doesn't
matter if they how long they stick,
but you're saying there's actually some
strength to be gained from failed
attempts.
Yes.
It's making the attempt that you get
credit for really interesting.
Yeah.
So the more like say if you're a drunk
and you keep falling off the wagon,
if you just keep making these attempts.
Yes.
No really.
So there's something ramps up in your
mind that makes it more feasible for you
to quit.
Yes.
And when it,
when it happens,
there's no struggle.
It's not,
it's not an issue,
it just,
you don't want to do it anymore.
Now what do you do when people come to
you and they're on antidepressants?
Well,
I have a book called spontaneous
happiness,
which is about emotional wellness,
is a lot there about antidepressants.
First of all,
they don't work so well.
You know that sometimes they work.
Sometimes it's hard to distinguish them
from placebos,
you know,
the popular ones,
the Ssri,
and now because they don't work so well,
you know,
what doctors do,
they added one psychotic drug.
Horrifying.
These are for major mental illness.
They're not things you just add on to
make the antidepressant work better.
We've talked about that one ad nauseum
on this podcast because it turned out to
be the most prescribed drug in America
that I can't believe that.
That's just astounding.
Well,
the word is that 25 percent of women
between 40 and 50 are on antidepressants
in 10 percent of adults in the country.
All right.
Now here's another.
That's a crazy number.
Well,
first of all,
the pharmaceutical companies have done a
great job of convincing people that
ordinary states of sadness are problems
of brain biochemistry,
that you have to be treated with the
drug.
We're not supposed to be happier with
them.
Secondly,
there's a big problem with a lot of the
medications that we use in
antidepressants are a good example.
Most of the medications we use are
counteractive.
No,
they oppose some process in the body.
So when you do that,
the body pushes back against it,
that's called homeostasis.
You know,
an easy example you can relate to as if
you have a stuffed up nose,
you spray a drug in it that decongestant
you miraculous,
right?
You can breeze and depending on which
drug you use,
two hours,
four hours at lasts.
But when it wears off,
you have rebound congestion that's
worse.
If you use another dose of the drug,
then very easy to slide into a Jamie,
very easy to slide into a state of
dependence on it.
Same thing happens with many of these
drugs,
antidepressants,
they raise serotonin levels,
neuro junction,
neural junctions.
So what is the body going to do?
If you force an increase in Serotonin,
it's going to make less serotonin and
drop serotonin
receptors.
So if you stay on one of these for any
length of time when you get off,
you're gonna be in worse shape than you
were to begin with.
And this is now has a medical name.
It's called tardive dysphoria,
meaning lingering bad mood due to the
drug.
So the drug actually prolongs or
intensifies the depression,
you know,
maybe.
Okay,
for very short term use of very severe
depression,
but these are not things you want to go
on and stay on for a length of time.
What's fascinating to me is when I
talked to people that are on them that
want to talk to you,
like they're on some cancer medication
or they're on something that cures
polio,
like they make it seem like you're
insensitive to the possibility that
there's other solutions and there are
many other solutions.
We have really good evidence for the
antidepressant effect of physical
activity.
Yes.
Both to prevent and treat.
We have very good evidence for
supplemental fish oil for omega three
fatty acids to prevent and cbds well and
the microbiome looks like it's involved
in our mental states as well.
So you know,
there's so many different ways of cbd
for sure.
So again,
gets back to inflammation and it gets
back to in an integrative approach and
not just relying on a single thing like
a pharmaceutical treatment.
Yeah.
I've talked to intelligent people that
are on Ssri in one form or another and
even ones that have struggled were on
one for awhile and then it stopped
working and then they tried another one
and they're combining ones and they're
on this weird sort of chemical
rollercoaster and they reject any
possible notion that there's other
alternatives,
especially when you bring up the
exercise one,
I bring up the exercise one,
they go,
oh,
this fucking meathead exercise.
We just stopped and I'm like,
I'm telling you.
We did this thing with my friends called
sober October and what we did is we no
alcohol,
no anything for the month of October,
but also we did this fitness challenge
and we got really carried away and we're
all competing against each other with
this heart rate APP,
so we're working out three hours,
four hours a day.
It was crazy,
but what was interesting about it to me
was not just that your body sort of
adapts when you force it to work out
that many hours,
but that your mood is phenomenal.
I've felt so good.
Yeah,
and I was telling everybody if you could
take what I like,
I don't feel that good right now.
I mean I felt great,
but I don't feel as good as I did during
October because I was working out four
hours a day.
It was if you could get that in pill
form,
you would take it every day if there was
no side effects because it literally
removed anxiety.
All the internal chatter,
all the negative chatter,
it was gone.
Everything seemed amazing.
True.
And there are side effects of physical
activity are great.
You know,
it revs up immune function,
improves the gesture and sleep,
all that you mentioned,
the anxiety,
the by far in a way,
the most effective treatment I found for
anxiety is simple,
a simple breathing technique,
regulating the breath.
I've seen this work for the most extreme
forms of panic disorder and the drugs
that we use for anxiety or the worst.
The benzodiazepines are highly
addictive.
Mess with your mind.
Yeah.
I have a good friend who has an issue
with anxiety medication and he takes it
all the time and when he does take it,
apparently it has that rebound effect.
Exactly right.
He gets horribly anxious.
Well,
these are handed out like candy and
nobody warns people how addictive they
are.
It's a worse addiction than an opiate.
Addiction.
It xanax real well.
I did not know that.
Harder to get off of opioids.
Wow.
Now how do you feel about psychedelic
interventions when it comes to
addiction?
It's like it seems that we're hearing
more and more about that.
I know you have a background in that as
well.
Well,
we're especially hearing about the Boga
and Ibogaine.
This is the African a psychedelic and
there are clinics and people using this.
The claim great success.
I don't have firsthand experience.
I only know what I've heard and what
I've talked to people,
but sounds good and I think that most of
the psychedelics are so nontoxic,
so safe and in the right hands.
I think there's many possibilities for
good outcomes.
Yeah.
They've also had some pretty good
results with cigarette cessation.
Yep.
With not just a Bogo,
but even with psilocybin.
Yep.
Apparently they had,
they did a study where they show the
difference between someone taking
psilocybin to try to quit smoking
cigarettes and some really large number
of people.
I think it was the neighborhood of 80
percent quit and then over the course of
x amount of years they were still at 60
percent.
So only 20 percent of those people would
come back.
That's great.
But with other methods that the number
was much smaller,
somewhere in the range of 20 or 15
percent after six years,
a lot of them just went back to it.
What do you make of the microdosing
phenomenon?
I mean,
this is pretty astounding to see this
actual pussies you scared to jump all
the way and get it all into one thing.
Scary man.
Why you want to medicate every day?
That's kind of how I feel.
No,
I'm just joking around.
Uh,
I think,
um,
I,
I know people who have experienced some
pretty severe benefits of it,
especially people that weren't doing so
good health wise and you know,
we're just really kind of feeling down
and depressed and all of a sudden
outlook radically changed.
Particularly psilocybin microdosing.
I know a lot of people who are doing
that.
Yeah,
same.
I have a lot of hope that Oregon becomes
the first state to.
Sounds like it's close to legalize
suicide.
I've been,
that'd be a big one.
It would be gigantic.
And I think once we realized that no
one's dying and a lot of people are
getting helped and a lot of people that
are terminal are having some really
amazing alleviation of anxiety and an
understanding that it's going to be
okay.
And just,
uh,
I think between friends and just the,
just the camaraderie,
it sort of when you have these group
experiences together,
like there's some incredible benefits to
that in terms of reinforcing
community and civilization the way we
feel about each other.
Now,
aside from the psychological and
emotional benefits,
I think you would be fascinated by some
of the things that I've observed and
written about of real physical benefits
of psychedelics.
And I'll just tell you a couple.
Uh,
I,
when I was in my late twenties,
I did a lot of experiments,
was in the seventies with lsd mostly
with lsd.
Um,
I had a lifelong allergy to cats.
If a cat got near me,
my eyes would itch,
my nose would run.
If a cat licked me,
I'd get highs were looking at me.
So I always avoided them and didn't let
him touch me.
So I took lsd with a group of friends on
a Spring Day because we get Virginia
fabulous,
you know,
I was outside running around having a
lot of fun.
And in the middle of this the cat jumped
into my lap and I had a moment of like
trying to defend myself.
And then I thought,
this is silly,
you know,
and I relaxed,
played with the cat,
had no allergic reaction and never did
ever after the disappearance of an
allergy that had been there all my life.
What would it be?
The physiological mechanism for some
time?
Well,
then clearly that's a very profound mind
body interaction.
Now we know that allergies are
influenced by that because you can show
a personal allergic to roses,
a plastic rose,
and they'll have an allergy.
So.
So there's a learned component to
allergy that can be unlearned,
but have an instant.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Now,
all right.
This is even more dramatic.
Maybe a year later,
same thing.
It was LSD in the spring.
I had also grown up with very fair skin
and was told I couldn't get tan and we
used to go down to the Jersey shore.
I can't remember.
I remember innumerable times,
you know,
gets getting second degree burns sheets
of skin peeling off knock Zima at night.
We didn't have sunscreen in those days.
Right?
So,
uh,
I just accepted that.
So it was,
you know,
I can't get 10.
So again,
high on LSD,
lying out naked in my great woods in my
home in Virginia and the sun was up
there and I thought this is ridiculous.
You know,
I should not be afraid of the sun.
The next day I got Tan and I have ever
since,
well that's a little more,
I'm not quite sure of the mechanism
there,
but it's pretty long.
Were you outside for though?
Because if you're going to get burned,
I was out in good time.
You know,
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't have normally have.
Yeah,
at least I would have had,
you know,
my usual reaction,
but then my skin got tan it never had in
my life.
So what are you suggesting happened
again?
You know,
there must be a way in which the nervous
system influences melana sites,
which are the,
the cell,
the pigment cells in the body that can
either extend their projections with
pigment granules.
So the nervous system controls that in
the mind connects the nervous system.
But what about someone who's like
ridiculously fair,
like what about someone who lives in
Scotland?
What I would do is when Dr Weil's
psychedelic clinic opens,
I would have an open,
well we'll see,
but there'll be an allergy program,
right?
You'd go in on the first day,
you take a full dose of something and
you're exposed to the allergen and magic
happens.
And then you come in for 10 sessions
with a
decreasing those and at some point
you're not getting,
you're just getting a placebo and you
don't know when that is.
And people are trained to lose their
allergies.
I think you can do the same thing with
suntanning.
Maybe not with people from Scotland
because they've got fewer pigment cells,
but I wouldn't rule it out.
I'll tell you one more also from this
period I told you I was playing with
Yoga.
There was one posture,
I couldn't do the plow where you lie on
your back and try to touch your toes
behind your head.
I got to where I could get my toes to a
foot from the floor and I had
excruciating pain in my neck and I.
As much as I tried that,
I made no progress.
So I was on the verge of giving up.
I thought I was too old.
He was 28.
So again,
when in an LSD state,
my body was feeling totally elastic.
I thought,
oh,
I'll try that.
So I'm lowering my feet.
I thought I had a foot to go and they
touch the ground.
I couldn't believe it.
I was raised it lowered.
Oh Wow.
Fantastic.
The next day I tried to do it.
I got within a foot of the ground and
had excruciating pain in my neck,
but now I knew it was possible before
that I didn't know was possible,
so knowing it was possible I was
motivated to keep at it and then a few
weeks I was able to do it.
If I had not had that experience,
I would've given.
So I think this is the magic of these
things.
They can show you possibilities.
They don't necessarily teach you how to,
how to maintain them,
but they can show you the things that
possible.
You'd never believe what didn't even
seem like it was just showing you a
possibility.
It was actually showing a capability.
You are capable of moving in a way that
you didn't think you were before and it
was because of your own tension and
worry.
Probably learned patterns of tension
that had built up all my life and maybe
some because of the conscious or the
psychedelic state rather.
There's some alleviation of tension.
My mind was out of the way.
Yeah,
hm.
Well you do,
you definitely sense that with
marijuana,
particularly edible marijuana,
you can really get good stretching in
with edible marijuana.
It's almost like you.
I mean,
I,
I hate to use certain terms to just
trigger people's bullshit alarms,
but there's a,
you can see,
you can feel more of the muscle,
you can see more of what's,
what it's doing,
right.
Whereas,
you know,
I'm,
I've been involved in martial arts and
athletics growing up my life,
so I have a good awareness of my body,
but it's way better when I,
yeah,
metal,
edible,
edible marijuana.
Like I feel,
I understand like I can practice moves
better,
like certain,
like kicking techniques.
I'm better if I'm more in tune with how
everything's working together.
Whereas sometimes I can do it if I'm
sober,
but it's,
I'm almost like there's a prophylactic
between me and my body.
There's a number next to it that gets
removed by edible marijuana.
One other I'm fascinated by,
this was with MDM,
a,
uh,
I was,
I lived in a ranch outside of Tucson and
I had pathways that had a sort of large
gravel and I could not walk on
that barefoot.
It really hurt my feet and if,
you know,
if I stood in them,
you could see Denson,
my feet on Mtma.
I was able to like dance on those
stones,
no pain.
But the interesting thing is there were
no marks on my feet.
So the pain is easy to figure out how
that happens.
But what's happening that you know,
you don't get a dent.
I mean,
it seems to me if your mind is out of
the way,
maybe little muscles there can,
are free to press back with just the
amount of force to neutralize the
pressure.
It's like if your mind is not
interfering,
I think the body has amazing
capabilities.
Well,
I definitely think you can mind fuck
yourself.
Right?
And you can definitely think,
ah,
Oh God,
this is.
You can start thinking it's worse than
it is.
Yeah.
And if you can relax a lot,
oftentimes there's many situations where
you relax and things aren't nearly as
bad as you are making them out to be.
So that could be some.
I'm with you on everything except the
tanning,
tanning.
I experienced it.
That's one of those things like big
foot,
like when you should just keep it to
yourself.
If you see the clip,
you're supposed to just go,
I'm not going to explain it.
I'm not going to keep that to myself
because I know when people tell me
things that I have no experience of,
I'm always willing to entertain the
possibility.
But then I got to experience it for
myself.
I'm willing to entertain it dependent
upon who I'm talking to.
Right?
Because there's some Kooky people out
there and you will entertain the
possibility after possibilities until
you die.
You realize you have one big Dr Seuss
book.
Some people are just crazy.
You know,
we have to accept that.
True.
Yeah.
There's no doubt about it.
But I,
I am absolutely aware that there's some
component.
There's something about the mind and the
way the mind interacts with matter and
with life that has a profound effect on
your body and it would be really nice if
we were all better at controlling that.
One of the insights that I've had in
psychedelic states is that everything is
conscious.
That consciousness permeates everything
that you know,
like I,
I feel whatever in me,
that my consciousness is also in rocks
and in plants and animals,
that there are some universal something
out there and it's.
There are two really different ways of
looking at reality.
One is the materialist one,
which is the consciousness is a product
of brain biochemistry and electricity
and that is dominant in science today.
The other is that the brain is a
receiving apparatus for consciousness
and that consciousness is primary maybe
existed before matter,
maybe organized matter into forms that
are more and we're able to experience
themselves.
I don't know,
I don't think there's a way to prove one
or the other.
It's just that for me,
the conscious is the primary one is more
fun and makes life more interesting.
I'm sure you're familiar with rupert
sheldrick.
Oh yeah.
He's good friend.
Very,
very interesting guy.
He has an idea that everything has
memory.
He believes that that
bill,
this would be like the reason I guess
why some people would not want to live
in a haunted house.
Right.
They would think that if someone was
murdered in the house that it would
retain some memory of these atrocities
and that you would somehow or another
interact with that if you were in that
house.
So like spaces like my dad is not a
very,
he's not a woo kind of guy,
but he went to Gettysburg and he was
telling me that when he was at
Gettysburg that it just,
he felt profound sadness.
He's like,
it just seems like it's just in the
ground,
like the whole area.
He goes,
I don't know how to describe it,
but I wanted to get the fuck out of
there.
Like just just being around this era
where this battle had taken place on so
many people that died.
I said,
you could feel it,
huh?
Yeah.
I don't know if I buy it.
I mean,
but he's not the Kinda guy that know.
Right.
But that's an example where somebody
tells you something that is experienced.
I'm willing to entertain it.
I have to experience it myself,
but it also could be,
you know,
like he um,
he got lucky and didn't get drafted
during Vietnam and that's probably in
his head that if he did get drafted,
he might've died over there.
And for what reason he wouldn't have
experienced this life know why,
what is the.
And then thinking about these young men
that died in the same fashion for some
war that didn't make any sense.
Like why the fuck are they even fighting
it?
Like who,
whose,
why,
why is this a.
and then having all these people die
together in this one horrible battle in
this one place.
And he could have been,
he was playing a game on his mind.
But now joe,
I want to talk to you about your
language.
Why the fuck do you swear so much?
I don't know.
Have you read anything about the science
of swearing?
No.
Do you know that there is a science of
swearing?
Escience?
Yes.
It's pretty interesting stuff.
Oh,
so the part of your brain that produces
swear words is not the part of the brain
that manages ordinary language.
Really interesting.
Uh,
you know,
we have two language centers and our
left frontal Cortex,
uh,
people that have strokes that damage
them often lose language completely,
but they can still swear.
So swearing is coming from somewhere
else.
It may be coming from the right
hemisphere,
but it's also coming from deeper centers
in the brain that connect to the limbic
system and the Amygdala.
And that connects to the involuntary
nervous system.
So here's a couple of interesting facts.
Swearing is associated with sweating,
increased sweating,
so you should be dripping with sweat
that much.
I'm a comedian also.
Interesting swearing,
a increases pain tolerance and there's
an interesting experiment.
Know the standard way they do paint
colors.
They have people stick their hand in a
bucket of ice and water and you see how
long they can keep it there.
That people who say fuck shit can keep
it there much longer than people who are
not allowed to swear.
What about noises?
What if they just go?
No,
it was swearing specifically,
so they've tried noises and swearing and
so it may be,
you know when you,
if you're hammering a nail,
hit your thumb.
Yeah,
you use one of those words.
That's a good strategy.
That's interesting because I almost
always do that.
If I heard something,
especially a finger slammed a car door
the other day,
I don't want to.
So that's what that is,
but that's.
Yeah,
and it's interesting.
It's coming.
There's a different part of the brain
that that manages that has different
emotional content.
Yeah.
It flavors language.
Yes.
I live them.
I'm a big fan of this.
Whereas I'll leave you some papers about
the science of swearing.
It's interesting.
It's very interesting now what it will.
What would happen if they were no longer
taboo with the St Louis area?
I think they lose their power.
Yeah,
right.
The same areas of the brain wouldn't
know.
I remember there was an episode of,
I don't remember what television show,
but it was on cbs and they had a line at
the end of the show and essentially they
were saying,
shit happens and it was a big deal.
I'll bet it was a big deal that they
wanted to be able to say shit happened
and apparently they pulled this off and
they got it through and it was like a
10:00
PM show,
so it was okay and it was 11:00
by the time they said Shit.
And I remember thinking like,
wow,
what a strange sort of like how many
people were involved in this sort of
dance.
Like how many lawyers and executives and
who.
It's very strange,
very strange that this one word would
treat everybody knows the word.
It's not even that kind of game.
We all,
yes,
but so,
but you're saying this game is
facilitated by one specific part of the
brain and so that because like,
I don't know,
words are taboo words,
taboo words and often associated with
things that we find offensive or with
bodily acts that freak people out.
So,
but so there's both,
there's a psychological social aspect to
it,
but there's also a neurological aspect
to it.
Now when the words like some some words
for some people,
like I remember when I was a kid,
I lived in Florida for a little bit and
I said Hell once and in Florida in the
19 seventies.
Hell was a swear.
Like,
yeah,
I don't know.
I mean I came from New Jersey and then I
was in San Francisco and then also in
Florida and I said Hell.
And they're like,
don't swear like that in this class.
I was like,
where the fuck are you people talking
about?
Like it didn't make any sense to me and
that I was like,
you guys have different swears now.
If you had a word that was not taboo to
you,
would it be,
would that same area of your brain?
I know this is,
there has not been a lot of research but
it hasn't been taken seriously,
but that's all interesting questions I
should have studied because some.
I mean if you're a really super
conservative person,
there's a lot of words that are off the
table.
Yeah.
But if you are a far more,
which is loose with your language,
you could shit this,
God damn it,
you know,
that would be nothing like God damn.
It would be just like,
aw shucks.
Yeah,
yeah.
But to someone,
God damn it would be like a really bad
deal.
Really big deal.
So what would be different parts of the
brain would be activated by that versus
if you said it,
it would be not that big a deal,
but if someone was like super
conservative and they said even more.
Wow.
Yeah.
Interesting.
What do you,
do you think that that is a universal.
I mean,
it seems to be,
seems to be universal.
It seems to be universal.
Another finding that came across is that
people who learn a second language that
swearing in the second language does not
have the same emotional impact that your
first language.
Does that make sense?
That's why they're so fun when you learn
Spanish.
Swears like you get a free ride.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Yeah.
And you can do them on television too,
right?
You can say a lot of Spanish,
whereas in English speaking TV and
everybody just pleads ignorance.
Do you.
So does every language has.
They all have swears.
Every language has words,
swear words.
It's universal.
That is really interested in Asian
languages,
European languages.
All of them,
Huh?
Wow.
Huh.
So that,
that would,
at least in my brain,
seemed to indicate that there's some use
for that.
Yes.
Well,
probably many users.
One is this thing of modulating pain.
What is a social bonding?
You know,
forming some community.
Yeah,
that's how I kind of use it.
I think when I swear in front of people,
I'm testing them out.
Like you freaking out.
If I say fuck you,
I can't talk to you like you too much
work,
you know,
you don't know exactly what if you're
talking to someone and every other word
like,
well I really wish you wouldn't use that
language is there's so much work to do
here.
I can't hold your hand dance through
this garden.
Right?
Yeah.
It's,
um,
it's to me also like I hang around with
a lot of people that swear a lot because
I hang around with professional
comedians and fighters and there's a lot
of swash swashbuckling,
freewill and type of individuals
involved in those pursuits and now
they're seeing that there's some study
suggesting that swearing is becoming
more frequent in our society because,
I don't know,
it's a trend.
I'm not sure anybody knows why,
but I mean somebody would have been on
the air like you are 20 years ago.
That's true.
Yeah.
Well that is specifically because of the
Internet because there were like,
yeah,
yeah.
But even that,
it's like,
it's resisted in a lot of ways,
like people are trying to figure out how
to modulate this and how to handle it
and they'll never handle it.
It's like the genie's out of the bottle.
Right,
exactly.
Yeah.
Um,
I think ultimately you find what you
enjoy and the best way to find with what
you enjoy is people actually doing what
they want to do and then you figure it
out.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I mean,
that seems to be what's happening in the
world of the Internet and podcasting and
stuff like that.
It's also the the access,
right?
Like a person like you,
you could just put together a podcast
and if people find it interesting,
if it resonates,
you could get a 100,000
downloads out of nowhere,
like 100,000.
If she have a radio show,
100,000
people listening.
That's a lot of damn people.
If they'd be excited and be like,
Hey Andrew,
we got the monthly in and you're doing
great.
You've got 100,000
people a day.
They'd be like,
Holy Shit,
this is a successful business,
but you could be doing that just from
your office.
Just put together with a laptop and a
microphone and no distribution
whatsoever in terms of like no string of
executives and gigantic corporation
behind you.
You don't have nobody telling you what
you can say.
Kansas.
Yeah.
Well that's one thing you get out of
today that you never got out of before
and you know,
this is.
I've been involved in show business for
many years,
but only this kind of stuff for nine
from doing this podcast and what I've
seen with this is like what's unusual.
I think what resonates with people is
that there isn't anybody else.
There's no group of people that saying,
Andrew,
could you stop saying this or let's,
let's concentrate on that and the polls
are showing that people like this and
you know,
you have breaks in between what the
commercials are playing and they come to
you with notes and they tell you all
that stuff too.
Seems to somehow or another ruin this
natural interaction that we have with
each other.
Yeah.
Now for a guy like you,
the Internet is.
I would think that with some of your
more controversial ideas like this is
the way you could really air them out in
long form because if you like a lot of
doctors,
they don't want to open their mind to
anything outside of what their,
what their practice.
Yeah.
I mean it's gonna be rough for you.
Right?
But I've never censored what I say.
I've always put it all out there.
Good for you.
Yeah,
I've done that all my life.
But do you,
don't you find that it's more not just
accepted,
but people are more interested in it now
because of the Internet?
Yeah,
for sure.
absolutely.
Because I've heard about you for many,
many years,
but it's sort of ramped up over the last
decade or so,
right?
Yeah.
Because of the Internet,
right?
Because people have this,
but you know,
I've been around.
It's funny when I look at this stuff
like,
you know,
all this stuff about pot and placebos.
I was saying this stuff in the 19
seventies,
you know,
my first book,
the natural mind was published in 1972.
It argued that everybody has an innate
drive to alter their consciousness.
You know,
drugs are one way of doing it.
Uh,
I did the first human experiments with
pot that we're ever done with a under
double blonde conditions,
but experiments.
Did you do.
I gave marijuana to people in a
laboratory in 1968.
And would you test them for?
Well,
we were just seeing people bet me you
couldn't do it.
Nobody had ever done this.
You know,
the oldest marijuana was becoming such a
big thing and nobody,
there were no experiments.
Like what,
what,
what kind of experience.
So we took the most basic stuff.
I just wanted to show that you could
give it to the human subjects in a lab
and get away with it because people
thought,
you know,
I mean,
in terms of the ftes,
in terms of law,
lawsuits,
everything.
And uh,
one of the things I wanted to give it to
people that never had it before to
speak.
So there'll be no expectations.
Everyone said this is terrible,
you know,
they're going to turn it to heroin
addicts from giving them stuff like
that.
Anyway,
I just wanted to see basic stuff like
does it dilate the pupils of the eyes
because cops were busting people,
you know,
they'd say their eyes are dilated,
must be high on marijuana and they'd
searched,
but marijuana doesn't,
it doesn't dilate the pupils of the
eyes.
I took chat,
tested blood sugar because people said
the reason people get hungry is because
blood sugar drops has no effect on blood
sugar.
Uh,
we showed that the people who had never
had marijuana before in a lab,
you could show slight decreases in
performance,
in motor function and cognitive
function,
but people who were regular users of it,
you couldn't show that,
that they added that too.
Yeah.
My take on that is that I think that
people that are not regular users are
freaking out.
Yeah.
And because their sensations and then
I'll do it and they just don't.
They don't know how to relax.
I mean that's the big one to me with a
physical movement because they want to
test drivers and all sorts of things.
For Marijuana.
I'm like,
this is not alcohol.
You're now in a completely different
thing.
If I had a choice of being a passenger
with these drivers,
I'll tell you which one I would take.
A person who had never used marijuana
had just smoked.
A person who was a user of marijuana and
it just smoked it.
It never driven high.
A person who was a user,
a regular user of marijuana and practice
driving high and a person with any
amount of alcohol in their system.
I take the third as the best,
best,
best.
Yeah.
That guy's a wizard at bet.
That guy drives high every day.
So He's used to it.
I'm not going to show any effect on his
performance.
The experiences,
a novel experience.
And if you're accustomed to it then it's
just like,
here we go.
This is my normal world.
And for many people you have to learn to
get high.
You have to learn to associate the
subtle physical cues with the altered
state.
That's a common thing.
People could feel nothing the first time
they try it.
Yeah,
you do hear that right?
But I don't think they know what the
fuck they're talking to.
Throw your eyes.
Fuck.
Now when you,
uh,
when you did these experiments,
what did you have to clear these with
the FPA?
What did you would not believe I have to
do?
I had to get permission from the FDA
which said that I couldn't do it unless
I first got permission from it was the
old Federal Bureau of narcotics,
which was the treasury guys.
The federal bureaucratic said,
we'll give you permission once the FDA
gives you permission.
So they played that off,
then I had to get permission from the
state of Massachusetts from two agencies
there and there were two universities
involved,
Harvard University and Boston
University.
So coordinating all this stuff was
unbelievable.
And then once the old the approvals came
in,
I had to get the pot and there was no
legal source of it.
So I,
I,
the Federal Bureau of narcotics
gave me confiscated pot that they had
confiscated case in Texas.
They brought it over.
They had delayed for so long.
I didn't even know her that time to do
the experiments because I was going to
graduate anyway.
They brought this stuff on a Friday
afternoon.
It was shit.
I mean it was brown dry,
it looked like even sitting in a
warehouse for years.
So the first thing I did was roll up a
joint and smoke it no effect,
whatever.
I called the,
the agent that I dealt with and I said,
this stuff is no good.
And he said,
how do you know you haven't had time to
run any experiments?
And I said,
I looked at it under the microscope and
there was no resonance on it,
so they grumbled and they gave me other
stuff which was passable.
But again,
confiscated stuff.
Yeah.
Because we always used to hear when we
were kids about government,
we'd the government lead was the good
weed.
Do you remember later?
That was later when that,
when research got going and the US
government started a pot farm in
Mississippi to provide proper research,
which was much better.
And there was only a handful of people
that were under these experiments.
So they made it so difficult to conduct
research as they have with psychedelics.
No,
that's slowly changing now.
Yeah.
Well,
um,
you know Rick Strassman?
Sure.
Yeah.
When he was doing that book,
Dmt,
the spirit molecule and he did all those
tests with those people.
That was really groundbreaking stuff
because,
you know,
doing it at the University of New Mexico
and doing my clinical conditions,
they were able to document the
similarities between all these people's
psychedelic experiences and do this with
government approval,
which I thought was really fascinating.
Fascinating.
Yeah.
And the fact that they did it and the
information's out and then there's been
very little movement in that direction.
It's Kinda just like,
okay,
now we know,
but look,
everybody's fine.
A lot of benefit do,
do we want to act on this?
Like,
you know,
it takes decades,
forever and flawless.
What research was done all along,
it was February to look for negative
effects.
Uh,
no.
Nobody who wanted to look for positive
effects.
Got Permission and funding.
That's interesting.
So you have to kind of frame the
proposal in a way that like,
were these kids are fucking themselves
up and we're gonna prove it sir.
So that's changing.
But you know,
the big stumbling block now we got to
get a cannabis out of that federal
schedule.
That's like causing a lot of problems.
Yeah.
There's been some noise about
decriminalizing decriminalizing it
federally,
which is like step one.
I guess that's a big stumbling block.
I'll give you one example.
I'm involved with a group called Maui
wellness group.
I'm the chief science officer now.
He Hawaii.
Yeah.
We got the first dispensary license and
growing operation over there.
Oh Nice.
Very good,
very good example in Hawaii for medical,
not for recreational,
like how sick you have to be where
they're getting a little you,
but they're specified conditions.
Hawaii's not is more uptight than a lot
of other states it's happening,
but uh,
our licenses for Maui County,
which includes Mallory Mold County,
Illinois,
so people from all the time and I
can come to Maui to buy product and our
dispensary,
but they can't take it back because the
waters between the island or federal,
they throw it still has to cross the
water.
Oh,
that's ridiculous.
You know,
that's federal,
that's a kind of as the kind of
ridiculous situation.
So better to be in Maui and not better
to run.
I got to go to Maui to get high.
That's great.
What if you're really sick?
Like what have you have cancer or
something like that?
Well,
on live,
on Lanai.
Yeah.
Well you got to violate the law,
but if you have it in Lanai,
you're okay.
So can you grow it a.
no,
you can only grow it if you have a
license.
And the only licenses for Jesus Christ,
we got to change this.
California was really ridiculous when
they were doing medical look.
You can just basically go in there and
go like,
I can't sleep.
Then go.
Okay.
Yeah.
It was nothing.
Like I had friends that had like long
elaborate excuses.
They have planned out like,
you know,
I was in a car accident while six and I
go to bed at night and I have these
horrible dreams.
The only thing that helps you is
marijuana and I'm just trying to feed my
family and that they would go,
stop,
stop.
Okay.
I'm read this script and just give it to
you.
There was no resistance.
If you.
My joke was that if you can't get a
license for marijuana,
you probably go to a hospital
immediately because you had a real
problem.
Like,
no man,
you need an actual doctor.
I'll tell you a story.
This is something that bothers me though
I'm not.
I'm not a user of pot.
And I was heavily in my earlier life.
A friend of mine,
Dr.
Colleagues in San Francisco sent me some
samples of stuff that had come from a
medical dispensary in San Francisco and
he wanted me to try them.
So one of them was a concentrated oil,
it came in a little syringe and an ad
had a very elaborate nicely printed
brochure with it that describe the use
of this pain and it said you should
start with an amount the size of half a
grain of rice,
uh,
take it orally.
So yeah,
my friends had taken at bedtime,
so this is a teeny amount and actually I
probably took somewhat less because I
was afraid of getting too high on it.
So I take it at bed time,
went to sleep,
woke up about an hour later in full
blown delirium.
I mean,
visual hallucinations as strong as I've
had on LSD.
I couldn't get out of bed.
I,
you know,
I was immobile.
Yeah.
I had burning thirst.
I couldn't get up to get a glass of
water.
I had a friends thing and a guest house
I couldn't call for help.
I laid there and it kept increasing.
Over four hours it got stronger and
stronger and when is it gonna end.
Anyway,
it lasted 12 hours and uh,
for about 24 hours after my equilibrium
was really long and this stuff is being.
And it said,
it said the direction said,
start with this amount and work up from
there.
People.
I'm thinking there's people driving on
the streets.
This stuff is out there.
That scares me.
Yeah.
There's people that support that whole
thing and their gullet right.
I'm sure you know.
So
No.
A lot of the edible world is a weird
world because of the,
the,
the response.
The body is so much different than the
smoking.
Different drug as a lot of the,
you know,
the long length of time it takes.
So you know,
it's like lighting the fireworks and the
fuse is down and you go back and try to
light it again.
And I'm sure you've heard the recording
of the police officers who stole the pot
from the kids and then ate it and then
called nine slash 11 on themselves.
No,
never heard it.
Oh,
that's wonderful.
I'll play it again because we played it
too many times in this podcast.
Okay.
I'll look it up.
But this poor cops,
they ate pot brownies and they're
calling nine slash 11 like I think.
I think we're dying times moving really
slowly.
I think we're dead so stupid.
So stupid.
It's,
it's good for kids to hear because you
realize like,
oh,
cops are just people.
Oh,
all right.
Okay.
It's just,
it sounds like my brother,
my brother got high.
You know,
it's crazy.
People that get high,
but the effect of the edible can be
pretty,
pretty fucking profound.
And this area in particular,
like Hollywood has some pre imposturous
thc level.
Imagine.
Yeah.
They're under different regulations now
that it's legal statewide instead of
just medical,
but when it was medical only,
you could get these insane concoctions.
Stars of death.
You ever heard of a startup that will
hit you with a star at death stars,
they're like 1200 milligrams.
They range anywhere from like 200 to
three,
400.
Each little star is hundreds of
milligrams and joey would eat like three
or four of them ate.
He would just throw them down.
He's a,
he's got an insane tolerance.
He just wanted these guys given all this
stuff.
However,
I am delighted to see our society
finally coming to better terms with this
plant me to cannabis.
You know,
the,
the word cannabis,
the same word as canvas.
All canvas sales and rope used to be
made from hemp.
Uh,
the and the species name Sativa means
useful.
It's useful.
It's really useful.
You know,
this is one plant that provides an
edible seed and edible oil of high
quality fiber,
uh,
medicine and an intoxicant that's a lot
of ways for a plant to be useful.
Uh,
we have been very stupid in our
relationship with that plant.
The cannabis,
it's the equivalent of the dog in the
plant world.
Dogs long ago made a decision to co
evolve with us.
They threw their evolutionary lot in
with humans.
Cannabis did the same thing.
You can't unravel the early botanical
history of cannabis because as far back
in history as we go,
it's always associated with human
settlements.
So that plant wants nothing other than
to be with us at the service.
And we have been so stupid,
we've led a billion dollar industry and
textiles go to China.
We've let a million dollar industry and
edible hemp products go to Canada and we
have ignored.
That's potential for medicine.
Well,
I'm really hoping that things are gonna
change in terms they will far
cultivation hemp,
you know,
I'm one of the owners of on it and we
sell hemp protein and one of the great.
We used to get our hemp protein from
Canada.
Yeah.
We used to have to get it from Canada.
We sell it in America.
We couldn't grow it here.
Stupid.
Well that's going to change.
I'm so hopeful.
It's good.
It does change.
It is.
It's fascinating also how well the
propaganda worked against it.
And how long even defiance of all the
facts.
Now I have to tell you,
when I did those pot explorers 1968,
I predicted that pop was going to be
legal in five years.
Boy,
was I wrong.
I mean,
I.
Oh,
I thought,
I thought it was just a matter of
getting the truthful information out
there.
Well,
it wasn't.
You know,
people believe what they want to believe
and they don't believe what they don't
want to believe in its root.
It's totally irrational.
Well,
it's also a really excellent example of
the contradictions in our society.
The difference between something that's
accurate and something that's perceived.
Yep.
And we have this perception of marrow
and,
and sometimes they have perceptions
based on experiences.
Like you might meet some really lazy,
fucked up people smoke pot all the time
and you go,
oh,
this is what pot does to you.
Also it was the associations of pot
because back then you know,
in the fifties,
sixties,
it was associated with Mexican migrant
workers with black jazz musicians in the
south and then with radicals and hippy,
so all scary people to mainstream,
you know,
middle class white society and of course
all accentuated by William Randolph
hearst and Harry anslinger and the
reefer madness films.
Those are great.
They're great.
Anybody hasn't seen those out there?
It's amazing how something that was
terrifying to someone back then is so
silly today when you watch the reefer
madness to.
It's really funny and at the same time
we're living with the two most dangerous
drugs that are out there with alcohol
and tobacco.
Well,
how about fentanyl?
That one's cute shit out of me to just
keep wrapping that one up and making it
more and more potent.
Yeah,
just the idea that opioids weren't
killing people quick enough that we
needed to make some ridiculously potent
versions of it and apparently now
there's they're approving something
that's even more powerful like,
but why would you do that?
But you know,
on a physiological level,
opioids are not that bad for your body.
The worst effect of being addicted to an
opioid overtime is chronic constipation.
I mean that's annoying,
but that's not like cirrhosis of the
liver degeneration of the nervous
system,
but overdoses,
overdoses,
of course,
that kills me by stopping your
respiration,
but there are many examples of people
who have been addicted to opioids who
have been able to get legal supplies and
he used them extensively.
They're healthy.
I've heard about that when in terms of
regular heroin use that I had a friend
who was a Longshoreman,
and this is like when I was a kid,
he was explaining to me how this guy
that he worked with would get a bag of
heroin every day at lunch
and he would shoot it in his car and he
would just sit in his car during lunch
hour and then when the time was up you'd
go back to work.
I was like,
what?
He said he would do that everyday.
I'm like,
she's going to be dead in a week.
No,
no.
He knows that if he knows the other take
care of himself.
Apparently he did.
Apparently he would do it all the time.
Right.
I guess find a new vein and figuring out
how to do it and not famous historical
example.
That's great.
There was a man named William holstead
who was a surgeon at Johns Hopkins
University in the early 19 hundreds.
He invented a local anesthesia and so
get a great guy.
He started using cocaine and injected
self-injected cocaine and not a good
thing,
and his,
you know,
his behavior got really bad,
not good,
so at some point his group of his
colleague kidnapped them and took them
on a yacht for several weeks and he came
back,
supposedly cured,
had a long life as a very successful
productive surgeon,
and only after his death was it revealed
that what had happened on that trip was
that they had gotten them off cocaine
and onto intravenous morphine for the
rest of his life.
He was an intravenous morphine user.
Did Not in any way interfere with his
health or productivity.
I would assume that if you're doing that
every day,
you're going to run into issues with
your veins.
Well,
yeah.
Presumably,
you know,
he knew how to rotate around that,
that I wouldn't want to do that,
but there it is.
Oh,
but the point is that it's a whole
different game from alcohol and tobacco.
Yeah,
a whole a whole different game,
but all problems,
it's the.
It's the social toxicity of it.
It's that it's that people are buying
illegal impure materials and overdosing
and so forth.
That's not the,
uh,
the nate pharmacological nature of the
drug.
What's been disturbing to me as a
person,
as an observer,
is watching people who get injured,
get hooked on it,
get it particularly pills yet it seems
that,
uh,
my,
my good friend Brendan,
he had his nose broken and he got his
nose fixed and they put him on pills and
before he knew it,
he was taking those pills everyday for
months and months and months.
And his friends eventually just took him
out of his medicine cabinet and they
just made an intervention.
So,
you know,
this is,
I think the,
uh,
the opioid crisis that we've got in this
country is a fabulous opportunity for
integrative medicine because the
realization is that you cannot manage
chronic pain solely with use of opioids.
So there has to be individualized
integrative treatment that use,
uses different modalities.
It could be everything from acupuncture,
yoga,
mind body stuff,
diet,
and that all has to be the state of
Oregon a couple of years ago passed an
integrative pain management initiative
saying that all pain,
chronic pain management had to be
integrated and they listed the different
modalities.
They left out mind body medicine,
which to me is one of the most
important.
Yeah.
Mind body medicine though on any sort of
report that seems like that's when like,
okay,
what kind of.
But look,
you know I studied.
I'm with you.
Yeah.
I studied hypnosis after I got out of my
medical training and one of the most
interesting courses I ever took.
There's a well known demonstration in,
in the literature on hypnosis.
You can take a person deeply hidden.
Pfizer's got good trans capacity,
touch them with a finger that you
represent to be a piece of hot metal and
they get a blister and you can take the
same person that touched him with a
piece of hot metal and tell them it's
cold and they don't get a blister.
Wait a minute.
Well,
yes.
Well known phenomenon.
This is actually if you ever seen this.
Yes.
Real life.
So someone's taken a hot piece of metal
and convince someone that did not going
to burn it.
Don't burn close too,
by the way.
That the Suntan stuff.
How long do you touch them with it for?
You know enough in an ordinary person
that up.
I call bullshit.
So we'll try it.
Let's try it.
I'll get you under cook your hand.
Yes.
It's like it's hot.
If it's hot,
it's gonna fuck you up now.
Well I think if it's held there long
enough so like,
like it's one of those things like the
walking on coals to.
Absolutely.
Which I've done a number of times I'm
sure,
but if it's cold,
you know this then that coles are not a
very good conductor of heat,
which is why you don't Cook Bullshit
because.
Yes.
I'll tell you what my experience was I.
The first time I tried it a,
I was with a group of maybe 40 people
and it was a standard length of the
firework was about 12 feet.
It was a hot fire was mosquito.
It was in my yard in Tucson and the guy
came in,
it was early in the days of firewalking
and he had this long for our thing to
get people ready.
Uh,
I was not in the right mental state when
I did it and my experience was it felt
fucking hot and then it got to the end
of it,
the condensed down to a number of points
that really burned.
And I had listeners the next day and
most people that have walked that night,
it looked like they were not in the
right mental state,
but I saw a few people who strolled
across it that looked.
They were in some interesting altered
state.
So I wanted to try it again next time I
did it,
I shouldn't have done it.
I was with a guy who was a real jerk who
thought of himself as a self styled grew
small group.
It was a shorter maybe eight foot cooler
bed of coals.
And I got significant burns from that.
So like an annoying guru.
So it's really annoying saying no idea
what he was like,
this guy's a jerk off and then you're
getting annoyed so you're out of your
mindset.
Right?
And I burned my feet so I said I'm not
going to do this again.
And then a friend of mine was doing some
intensive workshop with Tony Robbins and
Christ and it was going to end the last
day they were going to do try to set a
record for the longest firewalk done in
America.
So he wanted me to come up.
So I went up there,
I thought I'm going to watch,
I'm not going to do it.
So it was a 40 foot bed of coals and it
was really odd and he had like a troupe
of African drummers and people are
dancing and drumming.
It was like midnight and people were
getting in line to walk and I said,
I'm not going to do this.
Not going to be by family self going up
there.
And I was right there and he taps me on
the shoulder and says,
you're ready.
It felt like walking through crunchy
croutons.
There was no sensation of heat.
I walked slowly,
I kind of wiggled my feet in the things
and when I got to the end of it,
I felt so high.
It was like I want to ask that I had
energy rushes through my body.
I had nothing on my feet,
so on a much shorter,
cooler walk.
Those coals conducted just fine,
and then this one,
it's a mind body thing.
It's not about the conductivity of the
Tony Robbins hitting you with some for
gazy coals hot.
I mean you could barely get at the edge
of the thing.
Men,
the heat was amazing.
He know the Tony Robbins one.
It's what's really interesting is
recently they've developed this issue
with people trying to take selfies while
they're walking across the coals,
burning their feet.
It's become a significant issue because
it didn't happen till like within the
last night.
Never heard of that.
I think that would get you right out of
the proper state.
Yeah.
There was a big article about it.
Article about these people really
fucking their feet up well deserved.
You really think that you have the
ability to mitigate the amount of effect
that fire and Cole hot coals.
I don't have any proof of this is my
intuition.
I think what happens if your mind is out
of the way you can take,
you can absorb energy and let it flow
through your body rather than getting
blocked in the tissues where it causes
damage.
And I've seen this in other situations
as well and I think the problem is
ordinarily our mind is in the way of
that and does not let the body freely do
that.
And I think that applies to things like
getting hit really hard,
uh,
heat getting hit really hard.
How,
what do you mean?
Getting,
letting someone hit you as hard as they
can with something that would cause
damage and that doesn't.
Oh,
that's crazy.
No,
it's not.
I've experienced it.
Yeah,
I'm sure you have.
But are there other real scientific
studies that show that nobody's studied
it?
I'd love to study.
Nobody's studied firewalking,
you know,
the usual scientific explanations like
we probably shouldn't talk about this
until they do do studies because it
seems so simple to do these studies and
I'm not fighting for a second.
I think if I hit somebody,
they're going to fucking hurt.
Right?
If you get deontay wilder to punch you,
I don't give a fuck how much Tony
Robbins talks to you and common
experience.
A drunk involved in car accidents don't
get injured.
Okay,
but do you know why?
Because they're totally relaxed.
Yes,
but that has nothing to do at some
altered state of consciousness is not
allowing the injury to actually map out
of the way and their body is totally
relaxed,
so that's the tension of falling you.
You hurt yourself because you're
defending yourself.
You're right,
right you.
Your body is better off giving in to the
old saying it's the same thing with the
fire,
but it can't be.
That's a different thing because you're
not.
It's on the surface of your skin,
which is causing the heat tense in your
nervous system,
which is not letting not able to absorb
that thermal energy and Brown.
We're going to do studies.
Burn you anytime.
We'll try it,
buy it.
It just.
I think there's certainly you can
mitigate the sensation of pain.
I don't believe that you can do anything
about the actual physiological change to
a hot piece of metal interacting with
the tissue of your skin.
I just think that like the steak does
not know it's being cooked.
It's just getting cooked.
You're going to get cooked.
You are a meat.
I just don't.
I don't buy that.
I'll show you some of these studies on
hypnosis.
There's doctors right now going,
yes.
You tell them Joe Rogan.
This is nonsense.
Well,
I believe hypnosis.
I do believe that,
but I.
I absolutely believe you can achieve
different states of mind where you feel
things differently.
Your,
your concentration,
your relaxation is in a different state.
Your mind set is in a different state.
I do not believe that you can change the
physiological nature of your body's
ability to absorb punishment like a
punch or kick.
I do that same thing of absorbing the
sun.
Let's set some studies up.
Sorry.
How are we going to make these tests?
I don't know.
I'll have to figure it out.
We'll talk.
If they're doing this forever.
How do you not know?
This should be.
You should have these studies already
done.
I want to talk about these things to do.
I know,
but this is a significant icon rotation
point because if it's proven,
this is really huge and if you could
really take off hot metal rod that right
out of the fire and touch someone's
skin,
they're in the right state of mind.
You don't burn them.
That would be giant.
Yes.
I am coming here with you.
I'll send you some literature on
hypnosis that shows this kind of.
I'm sure that someone wrote some shit
down.
I'm sure I want to see actual real
studies.
I want to see and I want to.
I mean in this day and age,
there's no reason not videotape,
but it's true.
Come on.
All right,
so a lot of stuff to do.
This is a big one though because this is
something that will will people,
right healers and you know a lot a lot
of people like to bring up and when you
press them on it there's no evidence for
it and it's like,
well anecdotal evidence.
Well I've heard,
well I work with a healer and he tells
me like,
okay,
do you know what the literal meaning of
anecdote is?
No.
It means unpublished in Greek.
It does not mean stupid,
not worth paying attention to.
Anecdotal evidence is often actually so
and it.
And it inspires you to do the
experiments.
So will you go ahead and do that?
I'll report that hot piece of metal on
your report back.
Yeah.
And I'm going to go look at that burn.
I'll report back to you.
Yeah.
I mean I'm not saying that anecdotal
evidence is always inaccurate.
It's most certainly accurate many times.
Sometimes.
Yeah.
Just his likelihood that it's not that
it is,
but anecdotal enough is what gives you a
hypothesis test.
Sure.
But it's just not good enough to stay,
especially when something that doesn't
make sense chemically.
Physiologically.
Alright.
It doesn't make sense.
But I told you about my experience with
Sun Tan that.
Does that make sense?
It the Europe trip and your balls off
and.
Yeah.
And something happened in my body.
That would be interesting if that was
some sort of interchange and your body's
ability to produce melanin.
Yeah.
Or what is it?
Melancholy.
It's,
how do you say?
Atlanta,
Atlanta sites sites.
So your and they're controlled.
They're sites are related to neurons and
they're.
They're influenced by nerve connection.
So it seems to be perfectly possible
that mind through the nervous system
changes the behavior Mylanta sites.
Sort of like how your body can ramp up
adrenaline or anxiety or any also can
ramp up melana sites.
Yeah.
That doesn't seem like outside of the
realm of possibility.
That seems like obviously some people.
When I first told it to you,
you said it was outside the realm of
possibility.
Not outside,
but sounds crazy.
Definitely sounds crazy.
But I mean it seems like that would be
something also that would really warrant
study.
Absolutely,
especially those poor pastey ass
motherfuckers out there on the beach
turning bright red like,
come man,
you just got to think about it the right
way.
You imagine if you just told people it
was like a meditation and then you just
get a nice Tan.
Yeah,
good thing.
It would be a good thing.
Now when it comes to like we were
talking about autoimmune issues.
Like I,
I have video,
I go,
you see spots on my hands where I don't
get any pigment.
How do I fix that?
Fix that.
My brain,
you know,
all I can tell you is I would try to see
if you an influence through hypnosis or
through guided imagery to see if you can
change it in any way.
I don't know.
Hypnosis and guided imagery.
Yeah.
There are two mind body techniques.
I think it's worth trying.
I did read once that there was this,
I think it was a young man who had some
awful one of those awful war diseases
and there was one called theosis,
which is like the whole covered with
this callous,
tarred tissue and it went away.
Hit Moses.
Yes.
Yeah.
Over time I burned that case too.
They told him that like his arm,
that one arm was going to be cured and
it just like,
I remember that lately.
Eliminated all the warts on that one.
I remember that.
Yeah.
And they couldn't figure out how or why
and they couldn't recreate it.
So the ward stuff that's very well
documented and work cures.
There's so many different work.
Who are,
some of them are quite funny.
Yeah.
Uh,
you know,
you have to,
uh,
a particular plant under the full moon
and Robin and barry above the falls off
the next morning.
And when you compare that to the way we
deal with warts medically,
we burned them off,
freeze them off,
cut them off in most of the time when we
do that,
they grow back and multiple clusters
when they got,
when the mind gets rid of them through
this method,
they're gone.
So we want to find out how to make that
happen more than fun.
Yeah,
that's real,
right?
I mean this is,
this is actual real documented science.
That is what is so interesting to me
about the placebo effect is that it is a
real,
that your mind has this capability of
healing itself in this very,
very powerful way,
but we don't exactly know how to turn it
on or off.
Right?
And it can do the opposite too.
There's a phenomenon called Voodoo
death.
We're in societies where there which Dr
Sherman's a malevolent,
which Dr can curse a person and the
person goes home,
lies in bed,
stops eating,
and over days or weeks dies will.
So what more could you ask of in the way
of a mind body effect?
Uh,
he put a curse on what was the
basketball team.
They were talking shit about them.
Put a curse on them and they couldn't
win a Goddamn game in a few times.
Yeah,
he's put a curse on a few different to,
oh,
he's like a real,
how would you say?
Spiritual.
Very positive.
Mostly like real love oriented guy.
But occasionally I'll put a hex on a
dude and when he puts a hex on,
you got a real problem on your heart.
Apparently it's been very effective and
people freak out when Lil B Hex Ism
little b puts that hex on you,
like dammit.
And then he releases the Hex is lifted
them.
He lifts the Huh.
And when he lifts them,
everything goes back to normal.
All right.
This is weird,
man.
This is like a weird because everyone's
aware when he puts a curse on you and
when,
when he does,
people are gone.
No,
I can't believe this.
Like the idea of curses like a,
the,
the Voodoo curse or a gypsy curse on
you.
That is a.
well that's the negative side effects
that it has a name.
It's called the no cbo effect.
Noxious rather than pleasing.
Yeah.
That is um,
that's a documented thing as well,
right?
That people can believe that something
is wrong with them.
And then they start mine.
Yeah.
Fucking themselves into this terrible
state.
And then they start screwing things up.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Hot started.
Here it is.
Kevin Duran says,
I tried to listen to little b.
my mind wouldn't let me do it.
I can't believe this guy's relevant.
Was like,
okay bitch.
Kevin Durant will never win the title
after he said Lil B as a whack wrapper,
the base,
God's curse,
Hashtag the base.
God's curse on direct and then he always
signs his tweets will be funny,
but it works.
It works.
Kevin Doran is sitting at home right now
thinking of the millions that must have
cost is one now one now.
But he could have bought a house with
all that money lost those years.
A little be fucked over in a corner.
But that.
I mean,
I think the opposite is true too.
So somebody could put blessings on you.
Like there was a fighter that we had in
here the other day,
deontay wilder,
he's the WBC heavyweight champion of the
world.
And he said that from the time he was a
little boy,
his grandmother had him convinced that
he was like an anointed one,
that he was special and that she would
always say that to his parents like,
you know,
don't you hit him like this one's
special,
you know,
he's gonna,
raise everybody up.
And then he turned out to be like one of
the greatest heavyweight champions ever
in terms of like his record.
He's 40 now with 39 knockouts and he's a
phenomenally successful fighter and in
his mind he believes that he has some
like magic property or that there's
something to him.
He's a ridiculous knockout artist to me.
Obviously there's a lot of physiological
aspects of that and he's a big,
long,
tall guy with crazy knockout power.
You can't fake power.
You either have it or you don't,
but he's got it and he's got this weird
confidence too.
And you gotta wonder how much of them
actually is operating under this idea
that his grandmother was right about him
having some magical properties.
And so he goes through life that this
vision.
Yeah.
Powerful.
How you trick people into thinking that
way.
The whole nation full of a dlt while
there's a nation full of doctors are
afraid of the placebo effect because
they think it's tricking people,
keeping them.
And it's not.
It's like it's you know when,
when you present a treatment to a
patient,
your belief in the treatment as a,
as a practitioner catalyzes the patients
believe the best way I can do that as if
I give a patient something that I've
tried myself and I know from my own
experience that it works and then I can
present it in a way with my confidence
and that increases the patient's
confidence and increases the likelihood
of a favorable outcome.
Even controversial therapies.
Yes,
and even Wayne example,
something you see when you give a
pharmaceutical drug to a patient,
I think there's,
there's the direct effect of the drug
and then there's a halo of belief effect
and you know,
an interesting phenomenon is that
there's a famous saying in medicine that
you should use a new remedy as much as
possible before it loses the power to
heal.
And this is a common experience that
drugs work best near the time of their
introduction.
That's also the case with diets as well.
Absolutely,
and the longer they're around,
what I think what happens is people have
faith in new things,
so there's a big halo of placebo effect
over time that shrinks and it leaves the
stuff on its own which may not be very
impressive.
This is often the case when people take
on a radical diet like on opposite ends
of the spectrum,
whether it's a carnivore diet and aware
that a lot of people swear it fixed
Somalis Ales or Vegan Diet.
Very similar effects,
obviously very different diet.
Exactly,
so it's the mind.
The mind to mind is where it's at,
how do we,
how do we end?
The big problem in science and medicine
is that we don't believe in the mind.
No,
that's what I was saying earlier when
you were talking about mine.
It's not material.
It's not.
That's the problem when you're talking
about mind,
body interactions or work curious
placebo effects,
you're talking about a an nonmaterial
cause of a physical event and that is
not allowed in the materialistic
paradigm that science,
when we observed a change in the
physical system,
the dog is the cause has to be physical.
When you talk about a nonphysical causes
a physical event,
scientists to now,
well that's really unfortunate because
we know so much about how attitude does
shape the way your body reacts to
things.
Going back to the SAR,
no stuff,
you know that with back pain,
all that stuff.
It's like you know that to me that the.
You can't separate the mind and body.
There are two poles of the same thing.
Well,
if the placebo effect is real and it's
documented,
it's documented,
so obviously something is going on with
the way you feel about things and think
about things that it's having an actual
physiological effects.
There's something happening to your body
because the way you're thinking about
are happening to your body.
Now,
one of the things that has made this
suddenly have interest in the medical
world is that we now have these
techniques like functional Mris,
pet scans,
where we can observe living brains and
you can show that the placebo response
is associated with particular activity
in certain brain centers that has made
it real for people that otherwise didn't
believe in it.
Yes,
right?
Like there's a medically documented.
There's something they actually get a
hook into.
Yeah,
you can.
You can put it on a scale.
Yes,
exactly.
Yeah.
What part of the brain is responsible
for the placebo effect?
Well,
again,
it's probably some of these deep brain
centers that the same ones involved in
Sweden and wearing the same thing.
It's coming from centers that connect to
emotional read to emotion.
Yeah.
The ability to turn that on off
consciously and willingly.
This is tricky.
Yeah.
You know,
another thing I looked at over the years
was healing shrines in the world like
Lord the.
There's two interesting facts about
that.
Over the years,
the Catholic Church has accepted very
few healings as genuine that or have
full medical documentation and some of
them are quite spectacular,
like miraculous disappearance of widely
disseminated cancer.
No native of Lord has ever been cured
and the chances that a person that's
going to be healed there explained,
Lord,
this is a place as a place in France
where you know,
a,
you know,
a child saw visions of the Virgin Mary
and anyway,
growing up into a,
there's a grotto and you know,
it's now a major Catholic drawing and it
has a reputation for healing and
thousands and thousands of people over
the years of going there.
So as I said,
very,
you know,
there was relatively few reported
healings that had been docked,
fully document medically,
but no native of Lord has ever been
healed.
And the,
there's something called the Lord
phenomenon,
which is fascinating that the chances
that a person is going to be healed at
Lord or a place like that is directly
proportional to the length of the
journey traveled.
Yeah,
I have heard that.
So the length of the journey is,
is an investment of belief,
right?
So you're projecting belief onto the
plate place and then you get it back.
Yeah.
That that seems like that could
essentially work with any very,
very difficult absolution,
quest types of experience that you're
going on.
You're looking for something and you
have to earn it.
Yeah.
And you have to be fully invested.
There has to be something going on in
the mind that has you convinced this is
a real effect,
but the power is not in the place.
The powers in here and you're projecting
it onto that.
But man wouldn't be better if you didn't
have to go all the way.
That'd be great.
And how do you,
how do you get that going?
Like if someone said to you,
okay man,
I don't want to go to the Lord,
but uh,
what,
what should I do?
Well,
one is the acute.
Imagine you're going to Lord in.
That's taking advantage of this function
of visualization.
That's why these therapies like guided
imagery seem to work that you can
imagine something and have it become
real guided imagery.
Now is there a specific,
you know,
like there's like transcendental
medication.
There's boots,
a formal,
it's a formal system of therapy that
people are trained in.
Were you,
uh,
you know,
you sit with a practitioner and they
help you explore your mental imagery and
a May give you specific kinds of images
to work with depending on the condition
that you're dealing with.
I would think knowing the fact that we
were,
we have real evidence that placebo
effect works.
Why isn't there more study done to try
or more thought and more,
more people that are trying to emphasize
disability of the talent and we're up
against this problem that in the
dominant paradigm in science and
medicine,
we don't believe in nonphysical
causation of physical events,
but that doesn't jive with me because we
do believe in a placebo effect.
Like everybody says that,
oh,
it's just a placebo.
Right?
You said that earlier.
People always say that,
but it still works.
Right?
But,
but we're not using it.
Right.
We should be using.
It should be used.
It's the meat of medicine.
We want to make it happen more at the
time.
God Damn it.
It's just,
we're so flawed in our approach.
It's really interesting.
It's like the human body and the human
mind is such an incredibly complicated
biological entity,
right?
Our ability to consciously be aware of
our,
our life,
our position in the world,
our mortality,
the insignificance of us in the greater
scale.
All those things are like they are right
now all the time,
but you don't have any users manually.
Exactly.
We have this incredible machine that can
invent nuclear bombs and satellites and
there's no union users manual,
no user's manual for the mind or the
body,
especially not in how to manage the body
with the mind.
Nothing figured out,
bitch wide open on your own because few
people have got it.
You got to like find these masters.
Right?
So if you think about the 300 and
whatever million people we have in this
country,
how many of those people could guide you
towards a,
a proper integration of mind and body
and a positive way of interfacing with
reality that's beneficial to you
physically,
mentally,
spiritually,
not many.
Is there a dozen?
Not many.
Isn't it interesting with all these
human beings and essentially most of
them trying to improve in some way,
even people that fail on diets,
but they'd like to get skinny?
Even people that fail at school,
while I wish I was smart enough to
graduate,
I wish I had enough discipline people
people want to do better,
so there's this vast need for coaching
that would lead to improvement yet
almost mean nothing to speak of and
certainly not nothing large scale in any
city that has this approach where,
look,
we're going to teach you how to better
engage with the material world around
you and the better engage with reality
itself.
That's going to leave you a more
spiritually,
physically,
emotionally fulfilled like that.
It seems like that'll be a big business.
It would go.
One way to teach this stuff is by
example that if a person exemplifies,
you know,
good mind,
body functioning,
they can inspire that and another person
that seems like maybe the only way,
one strategy that I.
If I can do this,
if I have a patient,
if I can introduce that patient to
someone who's had their condition is now
better,
that is a very powerful way to up their
belief in the possibility of getting
better.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Which is why people love user
testimonials.
Right.
But,
but better if you actually meet the
person and show see for yourself,
but use your testimonials are so huge
for that.
Raise your right.
You know,
I was skeptical at first,
but then I tried it and boy he was
skeptical just like me.
It to me when I look at the giant number
of people that are unhappy and displaced
and just seem like they're left out of
society.
I was listening to.
Oh,
it was Johann Hari on Sam Harris'
podcast.
They were talking about the number of
people that are happy with what they do
for a living.
Happy with what they do every day.
And it was somewhere around 13 percent
and long.
Yeah.
And then the number of people that were
just like,
it's okay.
I just do it.
Like,
I don't hate it,
but I don't love it.
That was like in the 60 percent and then
the rest of the people fucking hated
what they did.
So the vast majority,
some ungodly number,
you know,
like 87 percent of people hate what
they're doing.
Oh,
how sad.
Or if don't hate it,
they don't want to be doing it and they
do it all the time.
Yeah.
That's crazy that,
that has to have a profound effect on
all aspects of your life.
Right.
I like what I do when you seem like you
do,
you have a twinkle in your eye when you
talk about it,
but I mean it's got to give you some
satisfaction for sure.
Right.
Yeah.
Help all these people.
Absolutely.
And also to see a lot of the things that
I've,
uh,
you know,
believed for so long,
becoming more mainstream.
It's good.
Yeah.
And much more so now than ever before.
More so now than ever before.
Yeah.
When you were doing those studies in the
19 sixties and you thought that
marijuana is going to be legal in five
years,
how could you have ever.
First of all,
how could you have ever thought of the
Internet?
Right.
That's the big thing.
The distortion of information.
Sure.
Yeah.
That's,
that's really the big one.
The decentralized APP distribution of
information,
and that's by the way in medicine has
really.
It's one of the things that's most
leveled the playing field between
doctors and patients sort of ended the
authoritarian,
paternalistic kind of medicine.
That was when I grew up.
Well,
it's,
it is a problem,
right?
A patient comes.
They think they know everything.
Yeah.
But I had seen,
I have seen many,
many patients who have gotten exactly
the information they needed and were
able to take it to the doctor who didn't
know about it.
I mean,
I think on the whole it's a really good
thing.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
No,
no,
for sure.
I'm saying just like I get how doctors
would be worn out by it all the time.
No less than I'm a,
I went to school.
This is what it is.
Well,
it's good for them to have to let go of
that.
Yeah.
Well,
there's no way you could know
everything.
True.
And especially doctors,
they must know that they have a
specialty for a reason because the human
body is so insanely complicated.
There's no way anybody is a general
specialist of every single aspect of
medicine,
but we need more generalists.
One of the problems that we've got too
many specialists and there's.
Yeah,
so someone like would you think of a
generalist as someone who sort of guides
you towards various specialists?
I'm a general practitioner and I'm very
proud of it.
There's good data showing that states
that have a higher number of prime of,
of,
of a primary care physicians,
family doctors have better medical
outcomes than patients with a high
percentage of specialists that the
problem,
some specialties pay more.
So we should be changing that.
We should be providing financial
incentives for people to go into general
medicine.
Yeah.
Would also make sense to that.
By the time you get to a specialist,
usually you're really messed up.
Right?
And if you're going to a back
specialist,
you might have like a real situation.
It's been bothering me for a long time.
Whereas you go into a general
practitioner for a checkup.
This is my biannual checkup.
He just kind of giving you the once over
making sure everything's okay.
How do you sleep and high eating,
drinking,
smoking cigarettes,
what's going on?
Just get a sense of you,
but they do they have enough.
Time is not a big issue.
Like what time do you spend when you,
when you're working with patients?
I take an hour and in our clinics we do
90 minutes on a first session.
That's gotta be nice.
Ninety minutes you can get to know
somebody,
but if you're getting in and out of that
office in 10 minutes he'd just,
here's a prescription.
Get out of here next.
You know the,
the has been studies on the amount of
time in a medical encounter when a
patient starts to talk,
how soon a doctor interrupts the
patient.
Do you have any guess what that is now?
Thirteen seconds.
You're right.
Really?
Yeah,
13 seconds.
I used the same number of people that
are happy with what they do.
Ha,
there you go.
That's pretty good.
Thirteen seconds.
Wow.
Well,
on my.
My foot hurts and I've been okay.
Here you go.
Shut the fuck up.
You didn't take this.
Take this opium.
Yeah.
Have you ever eaten in a true food
kitchen?
What does that mean?
It's a restaurant.
True food kitchen.
No,
I don't know what that is.
Well,
it's a restaurant that I started and
there's now 25 of them.
He got two and two and out in La and one
in Pasadena where I'm going to go after
the show and I'm in Pasedena tonight.
All right.
You want to go to a comedy club?
What time?
I'll be there for dinner if you want to
come over there.
True food kitchen.
Yeah,
it's great.
It's delicious.
Healthy food.
It's wonderful food that conforms.
The good nutritional principles.
It's anti inflammatory diet and there's
something for everyone.
There is like meat.
There's Vegan options,
vegetarian,
gluten free.
It's very delicious.
Food,
true food kitchen.
It's become an incredibly successful
restaurant concept.
Well,
that's a great idea to be able to serve
people.
Things that you know for a fact are
going to be healthy and nutritious.
Not just taste good,
but good for you.
Primarily.
It's food that looks great and tastes
great and happens to conform to good
nutritional science.
Yeah.
That is possible and that's a lot of
people think you have to eat fried
chicken and we'll come in there and try
it.
I would love to try it all right.
Definitely.
How do you eat for the most part?
You said you eat fish and you eat
through the full.
I try to grow a lot of my own food.
I love food,
fresh stuff out of the garden.
I like to cook and I invent recipes
which is,
you know,
a lot of the recipes and the restaurant
or mine a great.
So I,
I like simple,
simple,
quick preparations that are really good.
Do you fast at all?
I have been.
I've experimented with intermittent
fasting and I haven't found a regimen
that works exactly right for me,
but I'm fascinated by it.
I do a 18 or 16 and eight.
And how often do you do that?
I try to do it four days a week.
Sometimes it's difficult when I travel.
Yeah.
But uh,
even then I'm more accustomed to it than
ever before.
So if I eat dinner at 8:00
at night,
it's,
it's not hard to wait till she's back.
Okay.
Yeah,
it's not hard.
My body's just really used to it now.
How long have you been doing it?
About a year or so.
Maybe a little bit more than that.
Yeah.
I think that makes a lot of sense.
And uh,
continue to experiment with what I
haven't done that I really have been
thinking a lot about doing is doing a
multiple day fast.
Just a water fast.
I've done that for the longest.
I've done it for three days.
How was that?
The first day was difficult.
Um,
or actually the second day was difficult
the third day.
Fabulous.
You know,
I felt energized.
Hi.
My mind working very clear.
The problem that I have is how do you
come off it because it's very easy to
slide into eating pizza krispy Kreme to.
Exactly.
Yeah.
I think there's protocols in terms of
like small amounts of fruit,
right?
Like right when you're coming out of
blueberries,
which to me was.
The tricky part was transitioning off it
go too fast with the buzzer.
Rang schools out for summer.
Yeah,
I get it man.
I mean especially if you feel like you
earned it right,
you didn't eat for three days.
You want that pizza.
Right.
One of the things I found when I was
doing it,
having a bowl of March,
I,
I normally my my pattern is I want to
eat as soon as I get up so that those
morning hours are hard for me,
but if I have a,
have my macho that helps.
Do you exercise?
I do.
I swim mostly walk everyday.
I find that once my body got used to
fast to exercise,
it became much,
much easier and it just became like
before I would almost have anxiety
attached to it.
Like God,
I can't work out without food.
I have to eat.
And then when I started doing the
intermittent fast and then I started
doing fasted exercise,
I think it was.
I'm sure I pr if you probably measured
me in terms of like a.
He did a bunch of like weight lifting
exercises and measured my output.
I probably would be able to lift more
weights if I had some fruit first.
I'm pretty sure I'd have a little bit
more energy,
probably measurable,
but it's not difficult to have a
vigorous workout in the morning when
you're fasting.
You just kinda get used to it.
And I often do either hot yoga or run
first thing in the morning.
Weight lifting seems to be a bit of an
issue with weight lifting.
I don't like.
I like to eat something before I lift
weights.
Huh?
Yeah.
But swimming.
But you ever fasted swim?
It's fine.
No problem with it now.
Why don't you get off the pot?
You know,
it changed for me in,
in I,
I really used it regularly in my
twenties and thirties and when I first
started using it,
uh,
it was great.
I mean it was like hilarious highs,
laughing a lot of them.
Then it turned after several years more
introspective and,
and interesting.
I like creative writing for helping,
writing,
stuff like that and then gradually
transitioned into making me groggy and
not doing much for me.
And for,
you know,
it took me a while to separate myself
from it,
but in the last years of it it was
groggy and sedated that I think I
changed my body changed.
That's interesting.
Have you ever tried different strains?
I have.
First of all,
I don't like to smoke because I'm really
into breathing and I just kept put smoke
in the oil.
Right.
I've tried a vaping.
I don't,
I just don't like the effect of it these
days.
Aping,
I just don't like the effect,
you know,
I don't like oral feels,
it's too strong for me.
Yeah.
Well when you're talking about that half
of a half a grain of sand putting you on
Pluto for agreement sand that funny.
Imagine that at that would be like acid.
Yeah,
it was.
Felt like acid.
Yeah.
Well boy,
I'll tell you,
um,
for me,
the most profound and intense experience
I ever have in the sensory deprivation
tank or edible marijuana.
Edible marijuana in that tank.
That combination is just.
Whoa.
Huh.
A real strong dose because you.
Have you done the tank at all?
Yeah.
But not with.
Not with pot.
And psychedelics long time ago.
Yeah.
Well even sober you have some pretty
trippy experiences while you're in
there.
But there's something about the,
what I experienced with edible marijuana
is that,
uh,
when you close your eyes you get a lot
of really cool visuals.
Like I've had it before when I take pot
and then get on a plane,
like I'll,
I'll eat right.
Right when I parked my car at the
airport or when I'm leaving the house.
Then it kicks in when you're on the
plane.
Like closing your eyes,
Huh?
Something about closing your eyes.
The you have like really brightly
colored colored visuals oftentimes.
And I get that a lot inside the tank
with marijuana.
Huh?
I had that with that real strong stuff.
I definitely had a lot of visual stuff.
Yeah.
That's what's weird about it.
Right?
It's like it does become a psychedelic.
Yes.
Especially at high dose.
Why are they making that stuff so
strongly unnecessary when,
how many milligrams did they say it was?
I wasn't much because they've got these
damn Chiba Chews.
They're like 500 milligrams for one
little cake.
One little thing like that bank,
500 milligrams,
like why do you need that?
Because you started out with 10 and then
you worked your way up to $500.
I mean,
I guess there's a tolerance issue which
a lot of folks,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
Do you,
um,
do you regularly meditate or to do every
morning when I get up what kind of
meditation?
I first uh,
practices in and then I took some of the
positive training and now I get up,
I sit down,
I do my breathing routine and then I
just try to focus on body sensations and
the sounds in the room and when I'm
caught up in my thoughts I just bring my
attention back to my breathing.
But,
you know,
for me,
I think that the sitting sitting in
meditation,
that's fine.
But I think the goal is to be able to
carry that state and all of your
activities.
Uh,
so for me cooking is meditative,
chopping vegetables,
working with knives and uh,
that's very meditative for me.
So when do you think that when you're
having this meditation,
whether it's Zen or whatever,
that your,
you're resetting the way you're gonna go
through life for the rest of the day.
Hopefully that's the goal is to carry
that state throughout the day where you
kind of have a responsibility.
Don't you agree?
Like your guy who's teaching people how
to live a more productive,
healthier,
live.
You kind of have a responsibility to
live your own productive,
healthy,
live better.
Right.
I wouldn't feel right doing that if I
didn't practice it more slippery.
Right?
Yeah.
But I don't tell people to do things.
I don't do it myself.
When you have some thoughts about things
like something like a Boga,
would you be interested in trying it
yourself?
Sure.
Yeah.
I haven't had the opportunity to do it.
It's supposed to be ruthlessly
interspective [inaudible].
I've never done it either,
but I've had,
I've had friends who had a pill problems
who,
who did it and cured them,
but they said the ride is just 24 hours
of like,
what in the fuck am I doing?
And then once it's over,
you have zero desire the way that it's
used.
Traditionally in Africa,
the root,
it's these tribes that user that's
hunters take it and they remained
motionless for many hours on it.
The animals come close.
I mean,
that always fascinated me.
That is fascinating.
Yeah.
I wonder if,
uh,
taking it from the root.
I wonder if they have,
if it's,
they're getting the exact same
experiences they're getting in these
clinics.
I don't know.
It just to me in terms of efficacy,
if you look at the recidivism rates of
relapse rather,
they're mean they're sir rubbery high.
Yeah.
It's crazy,
right?
Yeah.
How successful that stuff yet.
And yet nobody wants to talk about that.
These are all these clinics,
like it's crazy how many rehab clinics
or are they?
We need you for six months.
Really?
Mexico says they kill it all in three
days.
I'd go down there and get into an in a
bogut clinic.
Yep.
I want to find out more about it.
That's on my list.
Well listen man,
thanks for being here.
Thanks.
Thanks for all the information that
you've shared over the years.
I want you to do studies.
I'm burning your site and getting
punched.
I will report back to me and tell people
how they can find out about you.
What is your website?
Social media.
My website is Dr [inaudible] dot com,
Dr w e I l.com,
and also check out the integrative
medicine dot Arizona Dot Edu,
which is my academic website.
See the range of that and match.com
for high quality macho and we have a
special offer for your fans.
If you go to [inaudible] dot com,
forward slash pages forward slash Joe
Rogan A.
Your listeners will get a special
discount code and marches m a t c h Kay.
Ladies and gentlemen.
All right.
Thank you sir.
Appreciate it.
If you could talk to you too.