And we're live Mr Maxwell.
How are you sir?
Mr Rogen.
Always say your brother and you brought
your bag of all your belongings.
All my goodies,
man.
Everything I own in this world.
I'll show it to you.
Yeah.
This always curious about this.
This always comes up with my wife.
Whenever I say Steve Maxwell is going to
be on the podcast.
That's that guy that lives out of the
bag.
Look at.
I'm pretty crazy.
This is everything I owned in as well.
That's insane.
Right in my back.
He has a um,
I mean that's not even a really large
backpack.
Like if you brought that elk hunting,
people would be upset with him.
And then a little little man purse.
Yeah.
So man,
purse backpack,
my chords and my ipad,
stuff like that.
And I travel all over the world.
Wow.
Pack really carefully.
As you can imagine.
Three petite shirts,
three pair of pants,
three pair of shorts,
a rain jacket too.
Lightweight hoodies,
long sleeve tee shirt.
I could pretty much recite.
I never felt more liberated than when I
got rid of all my stuff and I'm in a
different country every couple of weeks.
A lot of people say,
hey,
why not the roller bag,
Steve,
if you travel in any kind of third world
country down cobblestones.
Uh,
I actually had a roller bag,
but I ditched my first trip to London,
a change trains like four times going up
and down these damn stairs by the clunk,
clunk,
clunk back.
I said,
you know what,
this really sucks.
I'm going to carry it on my body.
So that's,
um,
I don't get any money from these guys.
But as the tom been fantastic travel
bags so well configured,
you wouldn't believe this stuff.
I get in there.
I even had my whole workout gym and that
thing,
man.
Really?
And what kind of stuff's in there that
you carry around with you everywhere
now,
this Tom Ben,
is this for hiking or is this just
primarily a trap?
Well,
there's a travel ban.
I want to take a serious hike with it.
But,
uh,
it looks like it's pretty sturdy,
very sturdy.
I use packing cubes.
There's different packing ways,
a good resource for your listeners that
travel full time,
go to one bag.com.
He has many recommendations for various
bags and uh,
where you can just basically one carry
on bag and travel anywhere in the world
for several weeks at a time
if you want to smell one bag.
A lot of this stuff is high tech.
I just washed my tee shirts out in the
sink,
you know,
very well if you,
if you were,
um,
one of the things that I've found from
hiking and camping for long periods of
times.
Wool wool is great.
There's a great company called First
Light First Lit II that I'm a buddy
minds part of my friend Ryan Callahan.
I'm out of Montana and actually catch my
dough him in Montana,
but they make will outer gear and inner
gear like,
um,
long johns stuff along those lines.
Fantastic.
A lot of hunting gear and you can wear
that stuff for days,
days,
and it doesn't smell stuff is this
stretch polya mine.
It's a little of that Hashtag a,
a nylon type material,
which real stretchy.
It's a silver impregnated sober,
uh,
help stop the bacteria from so you can
get like three or four days out of this
tee shirt.
Really?
Yeah.
And doesn't stay.
Maybe you could.
Well,
I stinky,
stinky,
Pervs my gym.
Check this out.
I can train a rubber band.
It nice and metrics.
I can do.
Good morning.
What is the amount of tension on that
railroad?
They just say heavy duty,
but remember the further you stretch it,
the smarter it gets.
It gets this old man.
Plenty of a stretch.
Maybe not.
You have a bowling ball bag that I
bought just so I could take on the road
with me so I could throw a 50 pound
kettlebell in it.
Yeah,
that works.
Although I try not to check,
but don't use it once.
This is a my cardio,
a little jump rope,
rope.
Anytime,
anyplace,
anywhere.
He can't run.
I like to do a little running.
Best self defense ever.
Right?
Sprint the hell away,
man.
Yeah.
If you could run further than the person
trying to kill you.
You know,
I,
I don't want to be.
I don't want to be like one of these old
guys that can't run,
so it comes in handy.
That's great.
And this is a little homemade,
a suspension device.
I can set this any length.
A suspension device.
I use a price and metrics.
Body weight rows,
Chin ups.
Basically.
Do you know your knots?
Not really.
I used to be a boy scout back in the
day.
I know a couple of fishing knots.
Low line,
right.
You just to cover that one pvc.
And then uh,
this is called a,
a,
a perisic not so I can slide this right
up and down the handle,
but if you would grab that handle and
put weight on it,
say it doesn't move obviously.
So it's instantly adjustable.
Huh?
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Pressing,
not.
It's a climber's.
Dispel that process per u.
s I k a.
If you go to an animated knots,
it's like a little app you can throw on
your iphone.
It shows you how to do the API called.
What is it?
Animated.
You can,
uh,
you shows you every kind of not.
So I can just throw this over a tree.
Do Chin ups,
body weight rows.
Oh Wow.
But if I want I can stand on it and I
can do isometrics.
I'm really indecisive metrics.
These.
Yeah.
You showed me a lot of those the last
time we worked out together and it was
really interesting what you're trying to
do now.
Isolation type movements.
I can do dead lifts.
Just absolutely incredible what it the
kind of work it can get like 15,
20 minutes.
Great for you.
You're on the road doing your comedy act
all the time.
Going to the UFC and Kettlebell.
It's good,
but it is a pain in the ass to lug
around and you can just in your hotel
room,
literally in 20 minutes,
your tongue will be hanging out.
Shockingly Metabolic,
uh,
amazing cardio at the same time.
You get every,
every muscle from your to your feet.
Good stuff.
I knew about isometrics back in the
sixties when,
uh,
as a young wrestler,
a coach use to use a lot of this stuff.
So anyway,
that's the workout gym.
Know Bruce Lee was really into
isometrics.
He was a,
he was into what they would call dynamic
tension,
which is essentially the same thing,
the Great Charles Atlas,
Charles Bronson,
the Charles Atlas,
those comic book ads of these to have in
the back like becoming a,
you were 98 pound weakling,
becoming like a big stud.
That was like what he was advertised a
lot of different dynamic tension
exercise for,
uh,
the father of modern,
ice metrics was the guy by the name of
Alexandra is asked who was a Russian
circus performer and he was traveling
around doing wrestling and bending steel
breaking chains over his chest.
He's just a little guy about my size and
he was captured by the Germans during
World War One and imprisoned and Zass,
uh,
in order to get a little extra food
because he's worried about losing his
physique.
He offered to train the comma dance dog
for extra food.
So meanwhile he's practicing his
isometrics on the cell bars every day.
And he eventually bent the bars and
escaped,
went back to the circus,
got recaptured this time they put him in
chains.
He bent the,
he broke the chains and bent the bars
and escaped.
Not just twice,
four times.
He escaped from the Germans bots.
It's all written in his biography.
I think it has anyone ever wikipedia
this gentleman.
Back then they couldn't,
couldn't verify my story,
but uh,
there's no doubt that this guy was
strong.
There's actually an old,
old,
old black and white youtube of him
breaking chains and stuff.
She's Alexandra is ass.
Another proponent of isometrics was the
fame.
Henry Wittenberg pull up,
pull up a picture of that guy.
Z Ass.
His biography is a big one.
Probably 100.
Sixty pounds under 65.
How the fuck did he been?
Chains?
Well,
he started as a kid in the forest.
He,
he actually went to some right there.
Yeah,
there we go.
When he was,
when he was a young boy,
he was really,
really,
uh,
I,
I'll tell you something,
I've lifted beams like that,
that,
that beam is really heavy.
He's got a beam wrapped around his neck
with his teeth.
Oh my God,
that's,
it's a tif lift.
He has a special math piece where he's
gripping it with his jaws and using his
neck.
Imagine how hard to beat to chuck that
guy out.
Yeah.
With that kind of net.
That's insane.
And uh,
he,
he would been saplings in the forest
because he couldn't afford steel
obviously.
And he would ben trees to get his
strength while these guys were the real
deal back in the day.
Man.
They were a pretty amazing.
And it's funny to know supplements,
you know,
no designer whey protein PCA's know
there was none of this like a dude.
I'm going in a ball like a catabolic.
It's
been 15 minutes after my workout,
you know,
they just eat good food and just
trained,
you know,
a lot of meat.
They're also closer to monkeys because
it was like,
it was a long time ago,
long time ago.
It hadn't evolved yet,
but these,
these people back then,
they also didn't really understand like
the modern principles of strength and
conditioning.
Like I don't even think they know.
I mean,
I'm not saying it in a bad way at all,
but I don't,
I don't think they necessarily had like
an understanding of all the mechanisms
involved.
They just knew you train hard classes,
you get stronger,
train heart gets stronger.
This guy knows what he's doing,
go visit them.
You can actually buy his book on Amazon.
Pretty interesting biography.
And I found a fence.
It was translated from Russian to
English.
It translates kind of funny.
One of the confusing things is it,
uh,
in Russia they use different names for
the same person.
So they keep.
Yeah,
I know.
It's weird man.
And how so?
Um,
he,
they just called them by four different
names.
It was like,
are they nicknames or nicknames like
Christie's a,
uh,
from the Ukrainian right.
Don't they use different names?
Yeah.
Unfortunately you're off camera.
So we're not going to be able to hear,
you know,
they uh,
they,
they use different names,
like little pet pet names.
And so as I'm reading,
I'm thinking who the hell they talking
about?
And then I'm reading back.
Oh,
they're talking about Alexander,
but they referred them with four
different names in the text and it said
it was just a kind of a weird
translation,
but Adley fascinating about his life.
That's so weird.
You know,
it's really interesting when you see
those old school strongman type
characters in because there was some
people that were doing things back in
the day like you want,
always want.
I always bring up the catch wrestling
pioneer,
a farmer,
Burns' farmer burns who used to do
these.
He used to hang himself by his neck.
I was like,
pull this up Jamie,
because there's.
There's actually photos of this guy.
This guy had a neck like my waist,
and he only weighed about 165 pounds and
he used to drop like a hangman's drop
and catch himself by his neck.
Look at him here and he was.
He was actually a baiting heavyweights
back in the day.
This is a.
This is a day where I wasn't just for
the pin,
but you could do submissions in order to
force it.
Got into the shoulders and people could
also tap.
And this is rough,
tough American martial art.
Yeah.
This is what,
what's now known as catch wrestling or
catch as catch can and when you would
get someone into submission to hold,
they would call it a catch and there
were a lot of submission holds that they
had back in those days that are still
super effective today.
And if you go back over the old rule
over old,
uh,
depictions and old images of submission
moves from farmer burns,
there's stuff that's still completely
applicable to.
This stuff is awesome,
man.
I actually had his original mail order
course back in the day when,
as a household or collecting stuff.
I actually had his original home
training course.
Wow.
That's amazing.
I had to keep it in plastic and stuff
like that.
Yeah.
Like,
look at this.
A neck crank he's got going on here.
He had a lot of the old order.
Nelson man.
There's a lot of moves that they had
that they used to use back then that are
absolutely effective today.
But just as Josh Barnett.
Yes.
I was just going to bring him out.
He really surprised deet and deeds a
hell of a black belt,
you know,
really well trained black out and I
think even he was surprised with that
headlock.
He caught them in a scarf hold two,
which is like about as old schools that
gets lost.
They get so some of these things are so
old.
They're new younger guys.
I mean when I was coming up the great
and Gracie Jujitsu,
there were so many different defenses
against a headlock.
We just basically just kinda gave up on
using it.
But if you don't practice that stuff,
you get some wrestler or catch wrestler,
judo guy,
some rough guy.
It gets you in one of those headlocks
unexpectedly.
Wow.
He can really hurt you.
Especially a really strong guy.
Like one of the things that's coming
into play a lot is that bulldog choke
you,
you rarely see.
You see,
like every couple years someone will get
one last one being Raquel Pennington.
Got It on Ashley,
Evan Smith and Ashley.
Evan Smith was kind of known as being
like the grappler in that match up with
Raquel Pennington was more of a striker,
but she caught her in that bull dog
choker and someone's like,
you got a school yard headlock.
Okay.
There are other needs or whatever.
Yeah,
right.
Right in front of him,
but the thing is when someone's head is
here and you get that form under the
choke and you clamp down,
man,
there's not a lot that guy can do.
There's not a lot when the head is here
and if you're a strong person and you're
fully locked in,
you're sitting on it.
There was not a lot.
There you go right there.
You see it right there.
We used to refer to that as the Rodeo
chuck because it's like a cowboy ticking
down a steer on most.
It's a good way to put it.
Yeah.
Actually,
you know,
rarely.
Really early was a bruce Lee choked out.
Kareem Abdul Jabbar in the same game of
death,
game of death.
One of my favorite movies.
He also had the first mma gloves in that
movie,
MMA gloves and enter the Dragon.
The Dragon.
That's right.
He did it a.
was it an opera or was it the,
uh,
it was a neck crack.
What do they call that?
There's a crucifix of course effects
there.
Yes,
that's right.
So he was pretty burly.
Oh,
he was,
you know,
I mean as far as like being open minded,
he was so far ahead of his time with
combining martial arts mean he truly was
the original mixed martial artist
because in the time,
like even when I was starting out in the
eighties,
the early eighties,
you really weren't supposed to train
anywhere else.
Like I would get the stink eye if I
would go to a boxing gym and try to
learn some boxing,
you know,
they would say.
And my truck window school,
you basically could learn everything you
want here.
You didn't need to go anywhere else and
he definitely didn't want to learn more
Thai or any of those other techniques.
You just would.
It's taking time away from your practice
here and this is what you really need to
do.
Well,
that's martial arts teachers trying to
protect their turf.
They,
you know,
they're worried about losing income.
If the students are going from this to
that to the other thing,
will you see it from even Jujitsu
instructors,
unfortunately with Jujitsu instructors
who only trained with the GE start
saying terrible things about people
train Nogi and the reason being is
because they have too many techniques
that rely upon handles on handles.
Yeah.
And as soon as they roll with a grappler
and they're,
they're,
they're going Nogi and they roll with
like a really good solid college
wrestler,
they're going to get smoked.
It's pretty tough.
They just can't.
They can't deal with someone who's just
really good at manipulating bodies that
are sweaty and with gable grips and
hooks and under hooks and their use of
those collars and they used to like
grabbing sleeves.
It's a whole different game and being a
former NCAA division one wrestler I
hated that gave for my first three years
or so.
And then finally as I started getting a
little old are getting close to my ffts,
I started loving it because it does slow
that game down and completely slows it
down.
So if you're a smaller and weaker you
can,
you can.
The gate definitely gives you a chance
to even the odds they're a little bit.
Well,
it allows you to control people.
And I think one of the things that's
really good about the key is people that
live in cold climates.
If you ever get in a self defense
situation with some war and a jacket,
like I had a conversation with a friend
of mine and I said,
if you are,
if you are in some sort of a street
fight with Jujitsu,
black belt and you have a leather jacket
on,
you might as well be a dead person
because if that guy just grabs your
collar,
I'll have to do is get inside your
grab a hold of the back of that collar
and you're gone.
You're gone.
He's going to just clamp on the other
side and he's going to choke you to
death.
Like you have a weapon or it actually
is.
Yeah.
People always think like,
I'm like in a straight fight,
you know,
you're going to be using all this fancy
stuff that you got to be the most basic
stuff you learn as a white belt at a
blue about to fall back on that stuff.
Most likely.
Yeah.
I mean,
you know,
you have to think,
like a person who you're fighting
probably is not a trained martial artist
know most likely a buddy of mine got in
a street fight with a train martial
artist once he told me that these two
guy,
he and this other guy was like yelling
at each other or something on the
highway and they decided to pull over.
So they pulled over to the side of the
road.
They got out and they started duking it
out and he threw a leg kick and the guy
checked it and the guy shot for a double
and he stuffed it and they're both
looking at it.
You're like,
oh shit.
Oh Shit.
And they said they went at it for like
10 minutes and then high fived each
other afterwards and got back in the car
that had a good outcome.
Well,
they've realized.
They're like,
oh,
okay.
We thought another train guy,
they thought they were good.
Each guy thought they were going to get
out and beat the shit out of some guy
who didn't know what he was doing.
And they both got out and then moving
around like,
oh,
look at this motherfucker.
And then after awhile they,
they thought it was funny.
That is.
Well I have,
I have used digital jobs in the fight
and the street straight back when I had
my school in Philadelphia.
Oh,
when crazy people would come into town
or something.
Well we had jim fights but a couple of
times even on the street,
you know,
just crazy stuff,
man.
Had a cab driver tried to run me over
one time and I was furious.
I was,
oh yeah.
I used to commute by bike quite a bit.
And um,
when I went by,
I was so mad I,
I hit this out of his cab and you know,
just gave him a couple of my express my
opinion.
And then the guy pulls over and jumps
out of the cat.
Yes,
there's coming at me and I,
you know,
I just used the inside control and just
laid him over the top of the cab and it
was over before it started.
He gave up and just got back in.
But thank God for basic standups.
Self defense also.
Thank God for him that you're a nice
guy.
Yeah.
Well sort of smash his face in nowadays,
man.
You smashed someone's face and you're
going to have all sorts of lawyers
knocking on the door.
And if there's a video of it,
because was always a video of it.
Now in the word disguises bro,
you got to go out of the house with like
a mascot.
That's.
How do you do it,
Joe?
It must be tough to wear mustaches and
shit.
Yeah,
I don't know.
Street self defense is like la obviously
last alternative,
like you would most likely never use any
of the techniques that you learn if
you're lucky you could live your whole
life and never used any martial arts if
you're lucky.
That's luck.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I always,
uh,
I,
I personally like to run,
not because I think running is such a
good workout.
I like to run for the skill of running
because if you don't run,
you're not good at running.
Most people don't like it.
I,
I do it more as a martial art because I
have a,
I want to run away.
But when you run,
do you know,
people can't run,
you know,
you see the way most people move.
I don't want to be one of those,
you know,
mid,
60,
70 year old guys that,
you know,
you can't run.
So I practice sprints at least once,
sometimes twice a week just for the
skill of being able to run fast.
Sprints are really good for your system
too,
right?
You're in,
it can be systemic was,
you know,
it was a real interesting study done in
running.
They found that people that run in the
zone that like do 10 ks,
five k,
you know,
competitive running marathons,
triathlons,
and such actually a shorter life
expectancy than people that don't run at
all.
When I was really surprised they claim
it's the oxidative stress.
My theory is people don't use the long
apparatus properly embraced properly.
They found that people that lived all of
them were the people that run real slow,
just nice measurably like zen running.
They they live longest.
They live longest.
Well,
if you ever heard of the theory that
there's only a certain amount of
heartbeats that you get in your life.
I have heard that.
Yeah,
I mean a kind of almost makes sense.
When you look at the age of professional
athletes,
like how they die young,
they burn,
they flame out in time pretty young.
Yeah.
No,
that's something that you have been
really a pioneer in avoiding like
keeping your body healthy like deep into
your sixties and seventies and I know
you have a whole program about that,
about with Brazilian Jujitsu.
He has.
I do a,
we call it just it for a lifetime.
We're actually going to do a,
uh,
a training camp this next spring in
April in Maui.
Hey,
how would you like to come?
I would love to have as my guest.
I would like to,
but I'm busy as fuck,
dude.
Man.
It's just hard.
It's hard for me.
Just just tell these guys,
hey,
I'm just taking a week off and gone to
Maui is hard.
I would have to,
you know,
it's like my time off is most of the
time if I actually have actual time off,
I spent it with my family.
Well,
bring your wife,
bring your wife and you're a young
diving.
Maybe they would love it.
They can take a paddleboard lessons
while you come up and paddle board
lessons.
I do,
man,
always nice.
But man,
every time I'm there somebody gets bit
by a shark.
Don't know what the fuck is going on
that have that big fear.
Ever since I saw that movie jaws,
it's like,
forget at bed while we're there and
we're watching TV.
And there was a newscast a about this
kid who got his leg mauled and uh,
my,
my kids were just in the pool or just in
the,
uh,
the ocean rather that day we were just
snorkeling.
And then we came back and we were
watching this thing about the surfer who
just got mangled and you know,
they had them all stitched up and he was
fucked up.
It's just such a primal fear.
I don't know what it is.
I know it's irrational because my chance
of being eaten by a shark is way less
than being an accident in a car.
And I,
you know,
I rent cars and drop.
People always say that,
but that doesn't make me feel any better
because the also,
the odds of you being eaten by a shark
when you're on the shore,
radically decreased.
That's true.
If you ever go to the ocean,
there's zero ads increase when you get
in the water.
So if you don't go in the water,
you won't get bit by a shark.
That's just a fact.
When I go to the,
what does,
this is a sunset beach,
I believe is what it's called,
which is just south of La.
Oh Christ.
What are you going to show me?
Reaches the water.
Seal it.
Oh No,
definitely not.
Going back right off a Huntington beach.
Oh my God.
This is insane.
That is one big ass shark.
That's got to be bigger than eight feet
because it just randomly caught it
because they were doing some other
stuff,
so he was filming something else and the
thing just breached the water.
Oh my God.
Show that again.
Could you imagine the fucking size of
that thing?
Dude,
that's a big shark.
That's not a seven foot shark.
Now imagine some kid on a surf board and
it just comes up underneath there and
that's how they stunned as seals.
If you've ever watched sharks hunt the
way they hit and knock it kind of
unconscious most.
And then did you ever see the film that
they put the that they got off of right
off of fisherman's wharf in San
Francisco.
Some tourists were out there and they
were just filming the water,
taking pictures of each other and seeing
all these people hanging around by the
water's edge and a great wife.
Fuck this seal up in front of everybody.
Ooh,
like right in front of everybody.
And we think it was probably two
different seals that are killed because
it killed one and there was just like
this big bloody puddle.
And then it like,
it got ahold of a second one.
It's hard to tell because you know,
you're just looking at the surface of
the water,
but massive red and I mean these people
are 30,
40 feet away from this thing as it's
tearing the Sila part.
It's really pretty crazy.
That is crazy.
There was an awesome picture of a,
a Orca hunting with his calf,
a great white.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
that's a great way to.
Yeah,
they,
it stunted and use Jujitsu.
Man.
It basically grabbed and turned it over.
And if sharks don't keep moving,
they basically dropped,
held it till it basically drowned.
And then at eight,
it's liver and the,
the,
uh,
the people that analyze the video,
felt that the mother a orco was teaching
the baby how to,
uh,
how to hunt.
How to kill a shark.
Yeah,
sure.
They're not nearly as agile as an Orca.
Nowhere near as smart.
I mean,
they're really dumb.
They have a tiny brain that just eat and
swim around.
But um,
the uh,
because when you see that video,
he,
when he flip it up upside down,
something about flipping a shark upside
down also kinda like knocks it out.
Yeah.
They just go passive.
I've seen people actually do it,
you know,
like in shows and stuff where they'll
just take and just flip it and rub.
It's bizarre.
That's pretty bizarre.
But there's a lot of weird like flaws in
God's early designs and it's almost like
the designs like that,
like the design of a shark.
It's like what?
It has to keep swimming.
It's just.
So here's,
here's that footage off of San Francisco
is though,
this is a different one.
Is it?
Well,
why is it so close?
This is a little bit later into.
As it got closer,
it starts off a little farther away.
Oh,
I see.
Okay.
Now let's go further with them because
the further away you get to see it back
it up from the beginning because you see
that this isn't the one though,
Jamie.
Really?
Yeah.
The other one.
It's from a distance and you actually
see the shark.
The rkv.
Well,
which one is this?
Jamie?
He's just a shark attack.
This is the shark eating seal.
This is right off of fisherman's wharf
where all the restaurants are.
People are walking around.
Yeah.
See,
okay.
So more than one.
Great white too,
but there's more than one footage of
this apparently.
Obviously this is a big deal and
everybody has a phone too,
but to be watching this.
I mean these look at that.
That's like,
what is that?
Thirty feet asked Brittany and chance,
man.
Yeah.
There's a better footage though,
a different angle,
which is a little bit further off where
you actually see the shark breach the
water with a seal and it's mouth.
It's like,
Eh,
I think I'll stay on shore.
No,
Nick Diaz,
he swam from Alcatraz five different
times,
five different times.
That guy swam from Alcatraz to shore,
but you know,
what am i.
One of my heroes,
Jacquelyn lane used to swim that while
pulling a boat full of people.
Wow.
Shackled.
Yeah,
and like as an annual birthday event.
What a man.
He's an animal.
I like the guy was still doing all sorts
of crazy exercises right up into his
nineties.
Yeah.
He was a crazy man who really a real
pioneer of health and fitness,
health wellness and juicing
and he got into Jersey.
You know,
I always tell these kids,
you know,
don't be listened to these trainers in
their twenties to thirties or even their
forties because they haven't been over
to the other side.
They don't know what sustainable.
They don't know.
You know,
they,
they just don't have that longterm
experience.
All my mentors were guys in the
eighties.
They're the guys I want to learn from
guys that went to the other side that
are super fit,
really healthy.
You know,
they're,
they're the guys I've been looking at,
you know,
to put my own program together.
I don't want to listen to these young
guys.
They have no fucking idea,
man.
I didn't.
I was a lot of the shit I did when I was
even in my forties and even early
fifties.
I look at him.
Yeah,
there were people he would tow,
not just a boat,
tow seven boats or something crazy.
I mean like 70 people.
He,
I think he told like a person for every
year of his life.
So here he's towing like a whole stream
of boats,
like how many boats were back there?
The guy was an amazing swimmer.
That water was cold and it doesn't look
to me like he has a wetsuit on it.
It looks like he may just have like a,
a singlet type.
It's hard to tell.
It looks like there's a wetsuit.
It's harder though,
but either way the savage.
That guy was amazing fitness guy.
There is and he's handcuffed.
Pretty amazing.
Yeah.
Here's a guy that stood the test of
time.
He had gone to his eighties and
nineties.
Another guy was a master,
Elliot Gracie.
I made that guy.
I actually had a Jujitsu with a lesson
with the guy,
you know,
when he was in his late eighties.
Wow.
And you know,
okay,
he's not going to beat anybody.
Right.
Doing competitive just.
But you wouldn't want to go up and mess
with that old guy.
He,
he would,
he would mess you up.
He had some thick ass hands,
big hands,
big forearms,
and he,
you know,
he,
he would just slap it on you.
I used to hate to be the guy that he
demonstrated stuff on because he would
just really put it on you.
I felt damn near injured,
you know?
Yeah.
Well he was a pioneer of no holds barred
fights like way back in the day.
I mean,
he was doing that in the 19 forties,
right?
Yeah.
And even before him,
his teacher,
he didn't learn directly for those guys.
Brothers did.
I was that guy a salt,
my Ada,
a little Japanese guy.
Uh,
he,
I had heard he won over 800.
No holds barred fight.
I don't know whether that's true or not.
Well,
it's like the Hicks and $400 dollars
number.
Exactly.
But made a,
he did,
he did a lot of no hold bar type type
deals and he was one of the guys that
really,
really developed that a guard because he
was finding that big American wrestlers
and football players,
uh,
we're putting them on his back and he
became deadly from the,
from,
from fighting from his bag.
He kind of specialized in that
particular position.
That's so fascinating because that was a
big part of [inaudible] game too with
keeping himself.
I mean he was like 140 plus
when he was competing and fighting
against much larger man,
much larger guys.
I lived with them for a month down in
his ranch and tears office and I used to
get daily lessons and his favorite thing
was to have you put himself into just a
really bad position,
like mad or whatever.
And they just basically defy you to do
anything to them.
And it's a,
it's a great game that you can play well
into advanced age.
You know,
you just let the kids work on you a
little bit and just play defense.
And there was nothing I could do.
I mean,
he just,
you know,
he basically knew everything I was going
to do before I did it,
you know,
he'd give his back,
let's let him out and you know,
he,
he basically,
his defense was just a superb.
You would have either had to use an
unusual amount of strength or do
anything or I made.
There was no full one.
It was,
but it may just put it that way.
Will Hixon you select guys start on his
back with a full rear naked choke,
fully locked in.
That's how he would start.
It's pretty amazing.
I mean,
but if you could develop that kind of
defense,
then if you're safe from there,
you say from everywhere,
like one of the big parts of Jujitsu,
I'm sure you'll agree,
is the ability to be safe in any
position and the ability to understand
what it takes to be safe in those
positions and the best way to do it.
Like Eddie Bravo did that when he was
training for or one of the big things
that he did was he had people start off
in bad positions.
He would have people start off mounting
them,
have people start off in side control.
He never started out just facing guy,
you know,
we're,
we're two equal neutral position.
Every position,
every role started with him on his back.
Every role started with him in a
compromised position is such a great way
to work if you're working with people
that don't have the same skill sets as
yourself.
For example,
Hickson was in America for years and
years and years and he only had white
bell blue about level guys to work with,
but this is the way he kept his sword
sharp.
He would put himself in these bad
positions,
partially closed triangles,
maybe a parsley closed Omoplata,
uh,
you know,
on the back with a maybe a partially
closed choke or whatever.
And then he just was just a genius as
getting out of those positions.
Yeah.
And if you can show your training
partners what to do,
you can actually make it more difficult
for yourself,
for you tell them what they're doing
wrong.
And I mean Hixon didn't just develop his
own Jiu Jitsu skills.
Obviously he had a lot of great students
as well,
a lot of great stuff.
And a black belt under Hixon to this
day,
it's one of the most prestigious black.
Seems a,
uh,
I would say probably the closest thing
you can get to Hickson is a so radio and
I'm out.
The guy's unbelievable training with
him.
And we were talking about law school
man.
Luis gave me my very first private
lesson,
uh,
add Hickson's old place on Pico.
That was before I didn't know that there
was a difference in the gracies,
you know,
when I was starting out and I was like,
oh,
this is Gracie Jujitsu.
Okay.
This is just like the UFC,
like who's Hixon Gracie?
Oh,
that's the brother didn't even know that
he was the man.
And so Carlson gracie school was closer.
It was off Hawthorne,
like right off sunset.
That was closer to where I lived by like
20 minutes and you know,
especially during traffic,
it was a nightmare to get down to pico.
So I was like,
oh,
I'll just go to this place instead.
So I fucked up and stopped training at
like the best place in the world,
like I didn't even know,
but that's how it was when I first
started.
Uh,
you know,
I didn't have a clue how well,
I mean I just didn't appreciate how,
how good these guys were.
But I got lucky though.
Any given day I could have a lesson with
any of the brothers.
They were one big happy family and they
were always there too.
I got lucky though that when I came to
Carlson's,
Mario Sperry was there.
Um,
Carlos by head,
toe was there.
I got to watch those guys roll.
I got to watch those guys compete.
Vito Belfort was there and it was when
[inaudible] was calling,
they were calling him victor Gracie.
Do you remember that?
I do remember that.
Yeah.
They would spell it with a k,
like,
I dunno what happened.
They changed his name.
I really don't understand what happened.
Well,
I know in Brazil a lot of times the
women are able to keep their original
name so they don't always take the name
of their,
their husbands.
Well,
he was taking Carlson's name.
I mean,
he doesn't,
he didn't.
Belford is his real name.
They're like,
he doesn't have like a gracie
background.
He was taking mother than might have
been a gracie.
No,
but there's some people that do that,
like doesn't,
doesn't.
Um.
Who has that going on?
Angela Gracie know someone.
Someone has that going on.
One of the men.
Has that going on?
Roger Gracie,
his father.
Roger Roger is what?
His father's Gomez.
Yes.
One of them.
Yeah.
So I think Caesar to Caesar have a
similar situations,
so I don't know.
But uh,
I do know it's not uncommon for the,
a married woman to keep her maiden name.
That's interesting.
But um,
anyway,
so like I used to see everybody called
Vittorio Victor back then.
And like if you look at the early UFC,
I'm pretty sure I even call it.
I remember someone pulled me aside and
said,
you can't call him Victor Gracie at UFC
12.
You can't call him gracie because Horian
was suing Carlson.
I remember that.
Yeah.
Like Horian was suing all the other
Gracie's they couldn't even use their
last name.
Meanwhile,
Carlson Gracie is a legend,
like a real legend in Brazilian Jujitsu
and mma,
and he was the guy who came in and beat
the guys that Leo couldn't beat because
Crawson was a bigger,
tougher,
stronger guy.
I mean he was more of a bulldog
approach,
which is why it was perfect that he had
that pretty much to bridge the gap
between Ellias young sons,
you know,
Elliot was getting a little up there in
age,
you know,
and was starting to fail physically a
bit and his own sense.
We're a little bit too young still,
so call us,
call us,
and Greg was like the one to defend the
family honor up until the point where a
Hickson and halls.
Gracie
got into the young man and he had a
fantastic group of students.
It was an unbelievable teacher,
a little boost.
Montay Mario Sperry.
I mean he had some really amazing,
amazing students as well.
His ability to go out and recruit talent
was just incredible.
You know,
he just knew how to do it.
He had an eye for guys that were going
to be really good.
Yeah.
He also had like a great family
environment like that Carlson Gracie
team,
like they were very tight knit.
It said it's a fascinating time in the
world of martial arts.
If you go back and look at that,
the early nineties and what happened to
this [inaudible] Jitsu in America and
how it just sort of exploded and change
the face of martial arts.
It really did.
I had my first experience in 89 and uh,
I just made up my mind.
I wanted to learn it.
I went in as a NCAA division one
wrestler.
I had a really good record.
Uh,
I,
you know,
I was like most wrestlers kind of hard,
hardheaded.
Why do these skinny Brazilian guy's
going to show me,
you know,
and then I'm,
I'm tapped like a typewriter by Heuler
and black hole.
My God,
what is this that he's doing to me?
I got to learn this.
And uh,
I asked Korean,
how can I learn this martial art?
He said,
come out to torrance is the only game in
town at that time.
That was true.
And I see you went from philly all the
way to tour and train and I would stay
for a week,
you know,
I,
I'd have so much money.
I was a former school teacher and I had
like a little retirement accounts set
up,
you know,
some money set aside,
after I quit teaching and money I set.
So I use that to fund by Jujitsu
education.
The meantime I had opened up my exercise
was a personal training gym.
I put some mats in the back,
you know,
and I would usually go and take like a
thousand bucks and when I run out of
money I would go back to philly again.
Says it was my business,
I could just take off whenever I want
it.
Oh,
that's great.
Then I had matt it and it was the first
gym of eastern seaboard.
I would just get all my old friends,
Philadelphia Judo Club,
you know,
like Quito.
Got It.
Just go in there and just work with
these guys and practice my Jujitsu.
And then another,
you know,
a couple months later I go back and
spend time again.
Then I got smart.
I started bringing the gracies to my
place and then they would stay with me,
stay with me sometimes for a couple of
weeks.
Hoist actually lived with me for a month
one time.
Well I think boys in oil or they don't
even know how schools anymore.
They just traveling to seminars and they
find that that's more lucrative and they
get away from the hassle of having to
pay rent and employees and all the other
nonsense that comes with schools and you
know,
they're just welcomed with open arms and
these weekend seminars.
And I mean,
if a guy like hoists are heuler or Hixon
wants to do a seminar,
like who's gonna say no going to say,
well,
that's kind of what I do to myself.
You know,
I just go around and show him the
gracies up the fence.
And uh,
the other thing that I'm really into
these days is just basically how can you
keep your body still in the game?
Because I mean,
it is fun to roll.
It really is.
It's something that you can do into
advanced age,
but you got to be careful and you have
to be very careful with the preparation
of your body and what are the.
What are
the keys to a person.
It's like,
you know,
entering into their older age,
what are the keys to maintaining the
body's inelasticity,
your,
your strength and vitality.
Well,
one of the main cases,
joint mobility every single day you got
to do some type of mobility.
People get confused between flexibility
and mobility.
Mobility has a connotation of strength.
You want to be able to voluntarily go in
and out of the movement,
a given example,
a bang,
Bang,
a grapple,
and Stryker,
I've seen your devastating kick spinning
round house thing.
You do a one way that like the
difference between mobility,
like splash a buddy would be,
you may be doing a split or put your
foot up on elevated surface and just
holding it and stretching,
right?
That flexibility,
but lifting your leg up slowly under
control and extending it out and holding
it like the old Bruce Lee movie.
And that is mobility,
right?
So practicing,
moving through the full range movement
regularly is extremely good for the
joints ache,
you keep your ability to move.
The other advice I have these young,
these guys out there,
tap early and tap off and don't be a
fool.
And this whole concept that you can't
tap to a lower belt that gets so many
guys hurt.
I can't tell you how many purple bouts
or brown bouts get really pod because
some really big,
strong or technical blue bag gets him in
a bad situation.
They feel they can't tap and they'll
literally risk injury.
That's insane.
Yeah.
It isn't saying why in the heroin
fortunate [inaudible].
I don't know how that ever started that
you can tap to Lord.
Well,
the problem is if you feel bad about
tapping,
that's one thing,
but if you get injured,
you're going to feel so much worse,
so much worse,
and it's going to take you so much
longer to recover.
You like if you get.
If somebody catches you in and you're
like,
oh boy,
this is tight.
You know what?
Let me just tap.
Fuck,
I'm an idiot.
How did I get caught in that?
That feeling that you get is actually
good for you.
It's good for you because that way you
realize,
you know you can't just let your neck
hang out there.
You can't not defend.
You can't think about those potential
steps.
And I see in a lot of Jujitsu
situations,
I see when when a higher belt will go
with a very enthusiastic and the very
ambitious lower belt,
they oftentimes disregard the
possibility getting tapped and that's
how they get tapped bore as some higher
belts I've seen.
They've.
They'll roll with a purple belt or a
blue belt or a wipe out and they'll roll
with everybody like that person's a
Ninja.
So we'll roll with every.
Every single person like that person is
like the greatest grappler that they've
ever faced in their life and if they do
that,
not talking about like going hard and
being like really physical and hurting
them,
but being aware of all the possibilities
and being on your toes and being at 10
at all times.
If you do that,
you're going to be fine or purposely
just put yourself in danger positions
and get caught.
Yeah.
Just,
you know,
just to practice.
But what I think,
I think it was a horrendous boys,
uh,
either a henry here on one of those
guys,
they,
uh,
they mentioned a,
a guy that worked in their school,
a blackboard in his fifties who was
really a down in the dumps over been
haven't been roughed up by a bull boat.
And they were saying,
well,
how old was the pool about,
you know,
and the guy was like in his twenties and
he outweighed by about 30 pounds and I
think they were the ones who came up
with the idea that like for every 10
years of age and for every 10 pounds of
weight,
that's like the guy having an extra belt
on you.
So if he knows how to use it,
I mean,
just a bit,
let's just say a big,
strong athletic white belt.
It's 20 years old,
you know,
and maybe outweighs me by 40 pounds.
That's going to be like me fighting a
guy,
you know,
like a much higher skill level.
What he,
what he lacks in skill and technique
he's making up for with Hustle and youth
and you know he's not going to get tired
and strength.
Well,
I also think it's very dangerous to roll
with people that are much larger than
you.
I mean,
I think there's lessons to be learned in
it and I certainly did my share of it,
but man,
there's a lot of times Rowan,
with much larger guards would come off
and your neck is fucked up or your back
is cracked.
Making weird noises.
It's like,
Jesus,
is this really worth it?
Or rarely really tactical.
Yeah.
Well,
if someone's really,
really technical,
then it's completely different.
But if you like,
I could roll with you and we could have
a great job.
You want to try to kill me,
you wouldn't try to crush me.
Maybe it's sweet being taught,
but you know,
the smart big guy.
If he's rolling with the smaller guy or
an older guy,
he's going to put himself on the bottom
again.
Now that you swayed me or whatever and
just practices defense in the bottom,
why would re way rather roll with a
larger than me black belt?
Then I would have larger than me.
Purple Belt.
Well,
good point.
Yeah.
I mean it's just.
It also like if you roll with a larger
than you black belt,
like a or grace or something like that,
they don't have anything to prove.
You know what I mean?
Like they've also been doing it for
their whole life.
They know how to do it correctly.
Like you can get away with so much with
physical strength and explosiveness and
and,
and just wait and power,
but that doesn't make you any better.
It's one of the reasons why I always
tell people,
if you want to learn Jujitsu properly,
learn it from a little guy from a little
guy learning from like a Barrett Yoshida
or a boiler,
Gracie or an Eddie Bravo.
If you learn Jujitsu from a smaller
person,
you're going to learn like really
technical Jujitsu,
master Leo.
His self defense still stands the test
of time,
man.
Sure.
That's,
that's another thing that makes me
really pleased to see that it's kind of
gone full circle.
You know,
Jujitsu was kind of going the way of a
lot of other martial arts,
like judo became like just a form of
jacketed wrestling really.
And you know,
taekwondo tank,
pseudo that they were at one point
deadly martial arts,
but now they're,
you know,
they're,
a lot of the bars,
furnaces has been lost in a lot of these
different,
especially if they go Olympic.
But that was happening to Jujitsu,
you know,
people are just basically shaking hands
and jumping on their ass and it was
like,
what,
you know,
and that's a fun game.
I'm not,
I'm not driving it.
I'm not saying that the guys are not
formidable.
Athletes are amazing,
but you know,
for the average guy,
they're never going to be really great.
You know,
they're just going to be so.
So they're doing it for fun I think is
important that you back yourself up with
the self defense.
And I see now a big trend to going back
to the origins of Jujitsu.
The self defense has been really big.
Guys want to know the basic standup
street defense and it was extremely well
developed in the old Brazilian Jujitsu
it.
It was very well developed,
gun knife stick club,
you know,
all kinds of clenches.
Defend yourself against the gods trying
to ground and pound.
It was all there,
but it was lost.
It was last.
Well,
it is unfortunate when people were just
trying to chase metals and win by points
and in doing so the they become
extremely unrealistic in the actual
application against a,
a fight or a fight or rather a who knows
what they're doing.
But one of the things that's really
exciting right now is I'm Nogi
competition.
That's kind of cool.
Yeah.
And what Eddie Bravo is done.
Did you see Eddie Bravo invitation,
which was number six,
was yesterday now,
but I heard,
heard about.
I heard some of the results in it.
Sounds like a very good way to contest
skill versus skill.
Yeah,
it's amazing.
What Eddie's done is he's figured out a
way to.
They have it's submission only,
so they go after it.
Right?
And but when it reaches a time limit,
if it reaches a time limit and there's
no submission,
then what they do is they start off in
compromised positions sorta like
wrestling.
You know,
in wrestling,
one guy would start down,
one raise position,
so in you have the option of two
positions.
Either you take the back with over,
under just over under.
Not a choke locked in,
but just the back with the hooks in an
over under or spiderweb control meaning
a arm bar.
The other guy,
the guy's defending the arm bar on it's
lying on his back.
You're inside control and you have the
arm hooked and your legs are crossed and
you start from there.
And so either the person gets a tap or
the person on the bottom escapes the
position and then you count up the
amount of time.
So you do it in like you.
I think there's three rounds of this and
if someone taps than the other person
has an opportunity to tap that to the
person and whoever taps the quickest.
Like if one person taps the person
within a minute and a half,
the other person does it in 30 seconds,
that person with the 32nd person would
win and if there's no taps in the,
I think it's three rounds,
three rounds of,
of the submission attempts.
Then they count up the amount of time it
took the person to escape.
So if one person escapes like 30 seconds
quicker,
you know,
then the other person that person would
win.
That's how Gary Tone and wound up losing
yesterday.
What a fair way to do it.
Yeah.
It's a smart way to do it too because it
ensures that you're going to have
exciting situations because if two guys
are just locked up in front of each
other and no one ever gets to a bad
spot,
you're not going to see any action.
But if a guy's on a guy's back and he
has an over under and they start from
there,
that's a dangerous spot.
And so you're going to see exciting
stuff.
So it,
it changes grappling from being this
thing that can really wanting to like
polaris,
you know,
they had those matches.
What Gary Tonin versus some are Paul
Horez great matchup,
but it went to a draw,
you know,
a j last name winter.
They want a clear cut winner.
Plus it gives athletes a chance to
showcase their skills.
Yes.
That's what people want to say.
They want to see the skill sets
showcased and you don't get to see that
because sometimes these guys are so damn
good that they neutralize each other.
Yeah.
It doesn't always make for a great fight
to really good fighters.
I mean,
what you've seen this in the UFC many
times you think,
oh my God,
this is gonna be so good.
And it's like,
Oh man,
this is really boring.
Because the guys just basically
neutralize each other because they're
just so good.
They're so good.
They cancel each other out.
They can't switch.
That is a.
That is a problem and I think Eddie's
come up with the perfect solution with
this format of putting guys in bad
positions in the last stage of the match
and like a fun thing to compete it.
It's excellent.
And it's on fight pass.
Now it's on UFC fight pass.
So now you know,
a lot of people getting a chance to see
it and they put the videos on Youtube
and all that child is at the pro level.
Pretty much.
Yeah.
Twenty $5,000
for the might be kind of fun.
If they just did like a grass roots,
then a grassroots thing just for like,
you know,
amateurs to go in.
It would be great program about purple
bound a brown.
I don't know how agree.
Yeah.
What the logistics of a tournament like
that.
My Bay.
But man,
I'll tell you it'd be fun to compete in.
Eddie's done six of them and they've
gotten better and better and yesterday's
was the biggest one and especially
because it's on fight pass now,
but he's really figured it out.
He's figured out how to make this
exciting thing to watch where people who
were on the outside looking in.
Well you know,
speaking of that cast wrestling,
a lot of people don't realize that pre
civil war and just post civil war
wrestling was the most popular sport in
America.
Really.
People used to sit outside the telegraph
offices to listen to the results of a
lot of these old school wrestling
matches.
It was way more popular.
Well,
first of all,
baseball was in its infancy.
It was like a civil war era sport that
was invented.
A basketball was still only like two
schools.
I think we're playing it and they
actually used real like peach baskets.
Really?
Yeah.
Oh Wow.
It was a physical education guy came up
with a,
a way just to,
you know,
like a game.
So it's just a conditioning game.
Was the origins of basketball to
football was Lakers and yeah,
of course I was like this big watermelon
and welcome ball.
But wrestling was the most popular sport
in America.
And it was real wrestling though.
There wasn't,
it wasn't like catch guys like Georges
Hacking Schmidt and uh,
Frank Gosh,
and you know,
farmer burns and you know,
even up to the Arabs triangle to Lewis,
you know,
they were still doing real wrestling and
then of course they started getting into
more of the entertainment business.
How did it go bad?
Because it's really fascinating to me
that wrestling itself,
it's such an unbelievably difficult
sport.
Like if you watch amateur wrestling in
the Olympics or Olympic level,
it's unbelievably difficult and it's
exciting and fun to watch,
but there's no professional venue for
it.
The appropriate well until the UFC came
along.
Right.
But that's fighting though,
like for people who just want to
wrestle,
they can't.
It is a great basis though for a lot of
different things.
It certainly is,
no doubt about it,
but it's just,
it sucks that there's not a professional
avenue for actual wrestling.
Actual arresting.
I mean think about all the things that
are on television,
golf or whatever.
There's this massive professional venue
for it.
It sounds like Eddie Bravo that was
given one for Jujitsu.
Jujitsu is obviously very different than
wrestling.
I mean just wrestling itself,
getting the pin and scoring points for
take downs and all those different
things.
I mean there's something to be said for
that as a sport.
Maybe not the best as a martial arts for
completing a fight,
for finishing a fight,
wrestling with the rules that are
involved in amateur wrestling,
but to me the guys who get really great
at wrestling,
like I would like to see them have a
professional avenue,
like a way to go from college and then
compete as a professional wrestler.
And so now there's anything wrong with
wwe if you're into that shit.
But I would love it if it was an actual
competition,
you know,
actual real honest to God not
choreographed,
nothing thrown.
They uh,
there was,
there was an attempt for awhile to
actually come up with a professional
restaurant.
Couple temps.
Yeah.
But it kind of fell by the wayside.
Could you imagine if that was the case
with basketball?
If you play basketball in college and
basketballs is like really like people
watched on espn is this big deals in the
Olympics and basketball.
But then when you went to pro,
everybody had a dress like a vampire you
through glitter onto the thing.
You know what I mean?
Like you have music.
When you introduce you,
you have matches in a cage.
People like,
what the fuck happened in basketball?
There are some countries where they
actually do have rail pro wrestling
based on basic,
uh,
not,
not essentially Olympic roles,
but like,
uh,
you know,
each,
each country has their own little native
martial art folk style wrestling.
Uh,
some of the African countries do this.
It's a,
it's huge.
And in countries like Somalia and,
and uh,
what was the other country?
I met this guy that travels the world
for the International Olympic Wrestling
Federation and he,
he was just doing like,
just looking at all the different
aspects of wrestling all over the world.
I met him when I was in Turkey.
I went to the Turkish national
championships of oil wrestling.
These guys are all pretty much like
professional level dudes,
man.
And uh,
this is the one where they were these
buffalo hide trousers that are tied off
at the knee and then they,
they basically just pour a bucket of
olive oil over themselves and then they
go out in a grass arena and they just
wrestle
and it starts out with like 50 dudes and
then you know,
half of those guys lose and then they
just keep going to like two guys
standing.
Yeah.
Why oil?
What happened there?
How did that go wrong?
During the Ottoman Empire?
They had a standing army,
the basically the Ottomans pretty much
conquered the world.
So they had all these young soldiers
with nothing to do and these guys were
getting.
It's the problems,
you know,
you got to keep young men occupied so
they came up with this.
But at the same time,
you know,
these are ferocious warriors,
the you don't want your guys hurting
each other.
So they came up with this idea of coated
themselves with oil to make himself
slippery.
So you can go after each other,
you know,
like a rabid dog,
but no one really gets hurt.
Wow.
And also it helps build t charts because
these guys were wearing armor and the
freaking desert,
you know,
hundreds of degrees,
100 degrees,
and it really builds up a tremendous
heat tolerance,
you know,
when you get used to training like that.
So training covered with oil,
heat tolerance can skin,
can't breathe,
man.
It's pretty brutal.
Oh Wow.
Okay.
I see that way.
So like you just like your,
your pores really can't sweat that good
hope and those guys.
And they were able to keep themselves in
tremendous shape.
Work on his technique.
One of the things they do is reach
inside the pants and grabbed that whole
and it looks a little gay I think.
But I'll tell you something.
I actually put on the kiss but in the
oil.
And I wrestled with the former junior
national champ.
Dude,
he was almost breaking my ribs with the,
with the lever.
Uh,
he would.
He come inside the waistband of your
trousers and put his elbow in your
spine.
And the.
See the idea is to flip the guy over and
expose your belly button to the sky.
If you turn the guy over,
you went,
he had with the guy on the bottom.
This is a terrible look at it.
It looks a little Cherub.
He's like literally waiting.
Let's put it this way,
would never fly.
Never fly in America.
Well,
why is the,
why is there a gap between the waste and
the,
you know,
on the body.
It doesn't start that way.
Is this really tight?
But the oil over time.
But these guys are unbelievably strong
and you can see the physiques and these
guys are like,
oh my God.
And they are national heroes.
They're rock stars in their country,
but they're grabbing each other's
packages.
No,
no,
no.
There's no sexuality at all,
allegedly.
And there's no way you can get your hand
deep in there like that and not have
some shenanigans.
He's looking at his friend and going my
whole hand.
You see how he's holding the,
uh,
the leg and the pant that's used as
leverage to flip the guy over.
So it's almost like Jujitsu in a way or
he's making sure that the guy can't get
away while he's got his hand.
Yeah.
Well,
that's part of it,
but uh,
I'll tell you man,
this,
you can't have this.
I developed a keen respect for it
though.
You.
Oh,
I get it.
Guys are definitely fly in a western
culture now.
But you've done this before,
but these are strict Islam as to you
know,
and any kind of homosexuality is
punishable by death of these countries.
So.
But you also know that that doesn't stop
it.
Like people that have gone over to
Afghanistan have talked about men love
Mondays or whatever the fuck they have
over there where there's a lot of the
mab.
A man boy love.
Yeah,
no super common.
You know,
they have gay relationships.
Like there was an article that was
written about one of those gay websites,
like a,
an APP,
like a grinder or something like that.
And then this guy went over to some
forbidden country where some Islamic
country and fired up the APP and it was
just getting pinged left and right by
all these gay dudes and trying to hook
up your data.
That's forbidden fruit,
my friend.
Oh my God.
How it is.
I'll get up and put on a buffalo hide
and wrestle,
but that's about as good as it gets for
me,
man.
Yeah,
but if you were gay you'd be psyched.
I guess I was.
But you know,
like if you were gay and somebody like
put it this way,
right?
Being a heterosexual man.
If a girl wanted to get all lubed up and
Russell and you could stick your hand
down her pants,
dude.
I'll be there.
Exactly.
So matter of fact,
after the show up,
what's up with a tarp?
Nothing.
Don't worry.
Just lay it down.
Grab the rollout.
The Vat,
the VAT of oil.
You're a Lulu lemon tights on those.
Uh,
those pants look like they're sturdy.
At least it looks like it's difficult to
read.
It took me 15 minutes to get them off
that.
There are so stiff.
They stand up by themselves.
It's almost like armor.
And I literally had to oil up my balls
and my ass.
My thighs just slot in that thing man.
Like yeah,
there's some things.
See,
come on.
This is not good.
That's called a waste track.
He's actually grabbing the front,
like grabbing the Jujitsu belt,
that's what you call it.
It's going to pull them down into a,
uh,
into a takedown.
It's called a cock holster in my world
right there.
Look at that one.
Boom.
Look at that.
That is a,
that is outrageous.
And he's lucky he didn't break his neck,
man.
Yeah,
for sure.
Well,
I'm sure when you're dealing with people
being real slippery like that,
that's part of the problem with actually
grappling with this.
Hey my friend,
he's my friend.
That's the core.
That's the version of like in prison,
they hold onto your pocket.
That's what it is.
These guys looking at each other.
Don't know.
Girls will do unto us to do.
That's what they're saying in my country
there no girls,
we just throw it down,
but it,
you know,
it is a very difficult way to grapple
all jokes aside.
That's really hard.
And in doing so,
like you,
you have to develop like you learn that
about Nogi as well and especially if you
try to do Nogi with no shirts on.
And there's a big difference with bobby.
It was like crazy.
Uh,
the,
the thing also about that was it,
it was very safe for the soldiers to go
full at it.
I mean,
what do you do with a standing army with
no war to fight?
What do you do with the ball?
But at the same time,
you know,
you can't have him hurting each other.
That was the,
that was the so called origins of the
whole sport.
Yeah.
There was an NPR podcast on radio lab
about the origins of football and how
football was created and that was one of
the reasons why it was so appealing.
It was like a way to compete in war
without actually having war.
I mean he had objectives,
you have goals and instead of bullets
and bodies got a football team wrestling
most sort of.
Yeah.
And a lot of ways.
And in a way like if you think of the,
let's say the rugby scrum,
it's Kinda like the old shield wall,
isn't it?
Yeah.
When they,
when they formed the shield wall.
So I mean it's,
it's basically learning to work
together.
Uh,
and,
and there is grappling.
You mean you're basically throwing guys
down pretty hard to.
Yeah.
I think whenever you have young men and
you have competition,
there's,
there's always going to be this desire
to dominate.
Like young men always want to dominate
other men.
That's just always going to be the way
it is.
So they figured a way to have these
workarounds that are acceptable by
society and then in fact it became the
biggest port in the country.
I mean team warfare,
like the NFL is the biggest sport in the
country,
but you know,
it's interesting is the early football
days,
you know,
you just didn't see the injuries like
you do now.
I made there would be elbows,
knees,
shoulders like,
oh,
he's like all tough boy sports where
you're throwing people to the ground,
you're going to get hurt,
but you didn't get the concussions.
And one of the theories I had one.
And you don't see it in rugby or rugby
union or Gaelic football or in that you
don't see it as much.
Not as much,
but you do definitely do see it
directly.
Say it,
but it's not an epidemic.
Like in the NFL.
I think the helmet became a weapon and
they start using the head as a weapon.
Yeah,
definitely.
And you know,
to see what the NFL does now with the,
you know,
all of these lawsuits and all these,
all these injuries.
Did you happen to see a will Smith in
that movie?
Concussion?
No,
I didn't,
but I keep hearing great things about
that movie out because I heard he was a
hell of a job.
A,
I don't know what they can do to
mitigate it,
but they do have a new kind of helmet
now.
I heard that that just came out.
That really reduces the sloshing of the
brain.
Doesn't do that.
Uh,
I think it's some kind of gel or
something in the helmet that like,
kind of like a soft kind of thing.
The team,
the absorption,
you know,
the helmets for.
So when he get hit your brain's still
sloshes.
It's just like,
um,
you know,
when you get hit with headgear a lot,
it doesn't really stop the brain and you
just take more hits because there's no
surface.
It's not only that,
a lot of people think it actually
accentuates the movement of the brain
because the fulcrum effect,
like a fulcrum of they have someone with
his larger object and the head twists,
I believe they've take.
Yeah,
there's a new helmet now that supposedly
is gel like that.
It takes the blow,
but it saves the.
Yeah.
We're seeing in here.
Jimmy pulled up this video.
It says zero one believes it can reduce
the chances of player sustaining
concussion,
and this is interesting because the,
the helmet itself sort of gibbs and
expands.
I would love to see that happen because
I love pro football and I would be
thrilled to see it that they come out a
way that these guys can still play the
game without suffering.
There's horrible injuries.
I agree,
but honestly I feel like the real option
is probably no pads.
No helmet was the same thing with mma or
like the original football in the US.
Well,
I think with mma,
one of the things that saves fighters
versus boxing is that you really can't
tee off on someone the way you can with
boxing gloves,
with boxing gloves,
you almost can have no concern whether
or not you're going to hit a forehead or
going to hit an elbow unless you have
small hands or we can.
It's like very.
It's,
it's much more rare that boxers break
their hands and MMA fighters.
But even MMA fighters,
I think they have an unrealistic amount
of protection on their hands and it's
just to protect their hands.
Like I still to this day,
I'll get interviews.
I got interviewed after that.
Uh,
the,
the guy died overseas really recently
and they were saying,
do you think that they maybe should have
bigger gloves or maybe we should make
people wear head gear?
The,
I think the real answer is no gloves,
not only no gloves,
no risk taping because I think that one
of the more difficult aspects about
punching someone is that your wrist
joint moves when you hit things and it
makes it way harder.
I mean,
you have to really concentrate to keep
your fist completely tight,
make sure that your risk doesn't move
when you make impact and you have to
make impact with the first two knuckles
primarily.
Otherwise you could break your hand and
regional.
You have.
Say I was one of the original vessels.
I told you this.
I actually,
through my little bit of money in there
and um,
was voices a conditioning coach for
those first three?
What did you have him do back then?
I was actually trying to build his
strength as much as I could because
Jujitsu provided all of the conditioning
that he needed.
He was doing a lot of work with just
bringing in fresh partners and he wanted
to stay a Jujitsu purist,
although,
you know,
he used some kicks and so forth just to
Kinda close the distance,
just closed the distance.
Faith the guy I make the make the guy
wonder like what's he doing so that he
could get the clients and so he would
smack guys to,
to open that.
You don't run the risk of breaking your
hand in hand,
but in all those original UFC is the
strikers all busted their hands a lot of
oversight.
I think three broken hands in that
first,
that the first one.
Well that's realistic though,
and that's realistic and ground and
pound would cease to exist.
Yeah.
You can't just sit there and tee off.
We can elbow people for sure just as
much,
but imagine hitting someone in the elbow
with your store at the top of the head
and so that that whole ground and pound
thing would pretty much go away.
We'll just.
Reckless punching
would go away.
You would have to have precision
punches.
You'd see a lot more open hand strikes.
You would see a grab was able to secure
a holds if they can hold.
Yes.
I might be a boring for the subway
because I think you would see grapplers
when a lot of fights you might,
but I think you would also see a lot
better Moitai.
You would see people would have to
develop their Moitai because you don't.
You wouldn't see any change in the
weapons,
the knees,
the kicks,
the elbows,
all would be exactly the same.
The only difference would be the
punches,
so I think really high level Moitai
practitioner,
they'd probably.
Yeah,
they'd probably have a really good
advantage if they can keep the fight on
the feet.
If the fight went to the ground,
you definitely see a big advantage for
grapplers,
especially in securing chokes because
you've tried,
I'm sure to do grapple with MMA gloves
on.
It's just like wearing oven mitts or
something.
Especially like rear naked.
If you try to get a rear naked choke and
sometimes it's really hard to get it
underneath the chin and so and
especially if you like pretzel grips or
something like that.
It's possible.
There's so much you create a good solid
two to three extra inches of space that
you don't want with all the padding on
the gloves and it just gets in the way
and it's also,
it's easy for your opponent to grab them
and pull them.
Awful.
And while I'd love to see a return to
the glove was mma.
Yeah,
it would be really interesting.
I'd like to see a leg somewhere where
maybe on an Indian reservation or
someplace where they didn't have all the
boxing is the reason why they put the
gloves on the first place.
Sure.
The boxing commissions all one.
Well actually it was tanking habit,
you know,
tank Abbott was the first guy to wear
those gloves.
Tank Abbott War,
the Chuck Norris MMA gloves,
which was before anybody had them.
I mean this was tank.
Wore them like I want to say like,
oh man.
It was like early,
early UFC because tank was a power
puncher and he was smart enough to
realize,
you know what,
I'll just taped my hands up,
put these,
these small padded gloves on.
They're going to protect my knuckles and
just molly these dudes was that.
Was that before they went to the club
tank?
Abbott was before they went through
gloves.
The first UFC that I worked at didn't
have gloves.
I was at UFC 12 and they still didn't
have gloves,
did not have gloves.
It was not mandatory.
It was optional.
Vituro wore gloves,
but he didn't have to.
I believe he also wore shoes.
No,
he didn't wear him and those guys were
still wearing leslie.
He was barefoot.
He wore when he fought vandelay.
That's him versus Tara.
Tara,
so all leg has no gloves but tank has
gloves on.
Interesting.
Yeah.
Tank was,
I'm pretty sure a tank was the pioneer
of wearing those kind of gloves and I
think that they would call those.
I don't think they called them mma
gloves back to him because I don't think
they had the term mma,
but the original gloves were century
gloves,
you know,
central martial arts come from hitting
the heavy bag,
the speed bag or something like that.
Yeah,
and that's what the design came from.
Like the design of MMA gloves didn't
come from someone sitting down and
saying,
we need the perfect glove for mixed
martial arts.
Now they had.
They already had a model that was really
not really necessarily designed for MMA
and they just sort of applied into mma
and it became the standard.
There's a lot of like really sloppy shit
that's in mma still to this day.
That shouldn't be there.
That's only in there because it was in
there in the beginning,
the 12 to six elbow,
which I harp upon all the time because I
think it's so stupid that if you go down
from 12:00
to six on the clock with an elbow,
it's illegal.
Even if you hit someone on the thigh,
which is so stupid,
it's illegal and the reason why it's
illegal is because the commissions,
the athletic commission saw people
breaking bricks on those karate
demonstrations that you can't do that
you would kill people.
So that's why that's illegal.
That understanding of that they weaken
those breaks.
Well,
and also the reason why gloves are
mandatory is because somehow or another
they erroneously believed those gloves
protective the fighters.
They don't.
And so,
but not.
But knowing that knowing that you have.
I mean,
I think if we got a room full of
athletes and fighters and martial
artists and we all have the discussion,
we said let's just have a show of hands.
How many guys here think that the gloves
protect the opponent?
So everyone who knows everyone at 100
percent.
I think across the board.
I mean,
there might be a contrary enter to that
would step in and say,
you know,
a personally I'd rather get punched by a
guy with a glove that no glove,
but most people would say fuck that.
Most people would say bare knuckles,
probably safer for everybody.
Yeah.
Involves effort.
Uh,
am I,
am I correct?
Did they not take the headgear off a
Olympic box?
They did.
They did,
yes.
And I think that's a good move.
I think you don't get hit as much when
you not have headgear on.
I used to hate headgear sparring because
your peripheral would get screwed up,
especially kickboxing.
It was really dangerous because,
you know,
you'd get hit with a jab and you
wouldn't even recognize the kick was
coming because of they're coming over
your shoulder until womp.
It's catching the side of the head.
It was your peripheral would get all
fucked up.
He would,
it would close your peripheral quite a
bit.
And I just always felt like I got hit
way more when I had head gear on.
And you know,
it's interesting,
a little bit of boxing and that I did
do.
I always noticed I always kinda had a
dull headache after boxing with headgear
and when I didn't have the headgear,
I didn't have that same headache.
It was weird.
Even back then,
I could never understand why my head
always hurt more after boxing with the,
with the headgear on.
Because your brain's squishing around.
Well,
no,
but I mean at the time I didn't put the
cause and effect together.
I was.
No,
I,
all I knew was intuitively I hated
wearing headgear when I,
when I would train.
Well,
what's interesting,
when I've brought up this to people in
high places,
they always have the same thing.
The public would never go for it.
The public would think it's too brutal.
People would think it's too brutal or
no,
what if we
created what if we created because we've
created something,
you know,
not,
not me obviously didn't have anything to
do with it,
but what,
what MMA is,
is we have a completely new sport over
the last few decades and this completely
new sport is redefined the way people
think about combat sports and fighting.
Right?
Okay.
Well why don't we be honest about what
fucking,
what's happening and why don't we be
honest about like,
how come you can shin kick a guy in the
face?
I can shin you in the face full blast,
but I can't punch you with a bare
knuckle.
Do you know how stupid that is?
Because a guy like,
you know,
take,
someone who's a power kicker,
like a Vito Belfort or something.
The amount of power they could generate
from a kicked in that brush into your
face.
It's so much more than anyone can ever
punch.
I mean like multitudes more three times.
Basically it is a baseball bat,
but we don't have to wear Shin Pads.
How can we not enough to wear Shin Pads?
Because the public's not used to shins
being covered,
it's all it is.
I,
I really honestly think that the
smartest move would be to ban tape.
Don't know.
You can't tape your wrists and bare
knuckles.
I think such A.
Well,
if you go back in the early era of
boxing where it was all bare knuckle,
you rarely saw knockouts.
There's,
there's fights used to go.
So like 30 rounds of all the,
you know,
like Jack Johnson and those guys.
Do you think that's why they used to
fight like this to smack each other with
the knuckles like that?
Or do you think they just didn't know
any better?
I think they know better.
I,
I think,
uh,
the mighty men of old.
There's not too much we could probably
show those guys.
Imagine if we went in at a time capsule
back to Sparta,
the first professional army.
You're in Europe.
Do you think we could actually show
those guys anything about fighting or
warfare and fuck,
all those dudes up.
Send me back.
No,
no.
Honestly,
martial arts.
I bet they'd get fucked up.
I really do.
I.
Because when I look at the martial
artists from 1993 that were competing in
the UFC,
then I look at the martial arts of today
in 2016.
Look at John Jones.
Do you know what the Fuck Jon Jones
would do to UFC one?
I mean,
you know how ridiculous it would be if
you send John Jones in the UFC one,
he'd be like,
get that guy out of here.
It's not fair.
Like he's doing a totally different
thing.
I think the martial artists of today,
like Demetrius Johnson,
who I think is the best ever,
but we're still talking modern,
modern,
modern.
Let's go 2000 years ago.
You put Jon Jones and the gladiator
arena.
Do you don't think he would fuck those
guys up?
I think it'd be a hell of a gladiator.
Fighters would have a chance.
I don't think they would.
I don't think they would know what they
were doing.
I think they knew what they're doing
really.
Yeah,
I really do.
Um,
they didn't know in 1993,
a lot of this information had been lost.
Right.
But even Jujitsu,
which Jujitsu is a resurgence of old
stuff.
Okay,
I see what you're saying.
What I'm saying.
It's like the dark ages,
you know,
where they are in medieval times,
but they didn't have the ability to
share information like they have today.
No,
no,
no.
There's no internet or that's one of the
reasons why Jujitsu's at such a high
level today.
Like there's all these like viral Bj
Jay,
which is one of the ones I follow on
instagram is a bunch when I follow on
instagram where they'll have moves of
the day and they show these moves and
you'd just.
I've been doing Jujitsu for a long time
and I watched something and I'll just go
like the home alone guy.
I'm like,
Oh my God,
look at this work and move like every
day these kids are coming up with new
moves every day.
I saw somebody figured out how to go
some.
Some dude went from being in a heel hook
to catch in the guy in a Kamora and spun
out of the heel hook into a Komora.
And I was like,
what did you just do?
Like you watch you like how did it,
he just kind of replay it over and over
and over again.
There's so many of those.
Now.
Let's go back to what we were just
talking about in ancient times.
Your,
your ability to fight was a life or
death thing.
You know,
you were actually fighting to the death,
right?
We don't have that true.
Unless you,
you know,
but usually in the military is with a
shooting and guns and stuff like that.
You don't see guys fighting.
I mean it could be hand to hand,
but for the most part these guys were,
were trained lawyers that would fight
hand to hand.
That's why I say when you're fighting to
the death,
you're damn good at what you do if you
live,
if you live but
don't live,
you don't get to really learn anything.
But there's plenty of guys that did.
Yeah.
And so my point is that they were well
trained and they really knew what was
going on.
I think there's some good points on both
sides.
I think there were certainly some
incredibly tough people back then for
sure.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
I'm sure the pain threshold of his own
belief,
but I think there's also this longing
for nostalgia that a lot of people like
to apply to,
like the ancient martial artists in the
ancient fighters and they elect to look.
Oh those guys,
boy,
if they could fight,
you know today,
like if you could get this guy,
I Look Jack Dempsey,
who's a hell of a fighter and amazing
boxer and just unbelievably tough man.
Wouldn't last one round with Mike Tyson.
Mike Tyson is prime,
would have ran through Jack Dempsey.
He would have ran through all of them.
He would have ran through gene tunney.
He would have ran through all those
guys.
Course.
He rammed through everybody Iron Age
too.
So.
But he.
Was that because he was mike or is it
because those guys were really good.
It was also because he had a lot of
modern guys look pretty shitty.
He certainly did,
but he had the benefit of having all of
those guys on film and see.
He had the internet when he had his,
his version of the Internet,
which was custom motto and cussed out.
I mean,
it might not have got them on Reddit or
showed them all the funny memes on
Instagram,
but what he did do is he played him
these films,
these black and white films of sugar,
Ray Robinson of Jersey,
Joe Walcott of Rocky Marciano.
He got to watch these old school Jack
Dempsey tapes and he got to emulate
their techniques and understand and
custom.
Ana would go over and meticulously
different positions and different ways
to encounter different styles and
different ways to move to get better
angles for counter shots,
and he learned from all those techniques
in a way those guys really didn't have
the opportunity to do.
They had to train,
they had to learn from.
They had to watch other
people do it,
but they didn't have the benefit of
having a library of films made a very
strong point.
Did you happen to catch them in net man?
Three.
What is it,
man?
Three know.
What is that mean?
You know the wing Chung guy was one of
those crazy kung fu movies.
Yeah.
Yeah,
but Mike Tyson had a.
oh,
that's right.
I saw the scariest shit ever.
Even to this day books,
Nike gets still,
you know,
if he just trained for a six months or
so,
he looks like he's still step in there
and take somebody out.
Well,
he definitely looks like he's still
somewhat active.
There was a video of him hitting the bag
recently for some shoot for something.
You'd be dead.
And uh,
you know,
he starts,
it starts off slow,
starts getting loosened up,
and then he starts teeing off in the
baggy.
Like,
oh Jesus.
Oh my God,
he's still fuck people up.
He would still fuck people up.
Joe,
you would still fuck people up trying
to.
We're still,
I'm still,
I still haunted by that spinning back
kick you did in your garage that time.
You're freaking banana bag.
Bennett.
Half man.
My ribs hurt.
Just watching that man.
Well,
kicks are always going to be more
powerful than punches.
And I think that kicking technique is
one of the few things that is a little
bit behind in mma in comparison to some
of the traditional martial arts,
especially like the spinning kicks and
straight kicks.
Round kicks are pretty simple.
It's pretty straightforward.
If you look at the round kicks of like
the best Thai fighters in the round
kicks of like the best Jujitsu guys,
like in Edson Barboza,
Barboza is right up there with pretty
much anybody and as far as far as like
kicking technique in the world,
but spinning technique,
straight techniques like it's turning
side kicks.
There's a little bit of lost knowledge
in those.
Not so many guys know that man that
Sarah used to have that awesome spinning
back fist,
man.
Wow.
That caught by surprise.
And am I correct?
You were the one that taught GSP that
spinning back kick and he knew how to do
it,
but I helped refine it.
He actually came to me,
John Danaher,
who's like one of the best Jujitsu
coaches in the world.
Who's.
He's the guy who was in charge of this,
what they called a doner death squad.
He's all these guys that have Henzel.
Gracie is like Gary Tonin.
Eddie comments to talk to the young man
that one yesterday.
His name is Ryan Gordon.
Ryan,
I think his name is who won a ubi.
Can you find out what his name is?
Young kid is 20 years old,
one the Ebi Tournament yesterday,
but Donna and I were having dinner in
GSP wanted.
Um,
he asked me if I knew anyone who,
um,
because he knew that I came from a
taekwondo background and he's like,
do you know anybody who's a really good
taekwondo guy that can show gsp the
fundamentals of the spinning back kick
her turning sidekick?
Yeah.
Gordon,
Ryan,
young kid.
Twenty years old.
One the Ebi Sixteen Man Tournament.
So I stand for Ebi.
Yeah.
Bravo,
invitational.
Invitational.
Okay.
Um,
and so don her asked them and I said,
well,
I could show him some shit.
Like I know it's going to sound
ridiculous being a comedian and you
know,
just a commentator.
The skies man.
Well,
it's,
it sounds even to me.
Ridiculous to me to say to John Danaher
was one of the best Jujitsu teachers in
the world,
you know,
hey,
there's a guy that I know,
his name's me,
you know,
it's just,
they're so short,
Joe.
I'm not,
I'm not so much dear house and trained
here a few times.
You're a beast.
Had had had been another time,
I think you probably would have been a
hell of an MMA fighter yourself.
Maybe people ask me that all the time
and I say,
Joe Probably.
I mean you.
You're a superior athlete.
There's no doubt about it.
You've got the fast twitch muscle fiber.
You've got the power.
I think a ha.
Had you had a chance,
let's say maybe 10 years prior to when
it started,
you know?
Well,
that's very nice of you.
I don't know.
I mean,
I'm not being nice.
I'm being honest.
You know,
you're really athletic,
strong guy.
Well,
I certainly would have competed in mma
like I did and kickboxing and taekwondo,
but I totally.
Honestly though,
I've always been terrified of brain
damage.
I knew too many people when I was young
that I knew were punchy it.
It scares the shit out of me.
It's still to this day scares the shit
out of me.
That's one of the reasons why I tell
anybody.
If they're even thinking,
even they even have one foot out the
back door through thinking about getting
out,
get out,
just get out because it's going to be
some animal in there that's not thinking
about getting out.
There's going to be some,
some crates,
young psychopath who's only thinking
about putting his shit to your face and
he's probably going to do it a pro.
Well,
sooner or later is going to happen.
You know,
I lived in Philadelphia for many,
many years and uh,
smoking Joe Fraser used to be down in my
neighborhood.
Sometimes the poor guy could barely put
two words together.
Hello to him.
And he didn't even know what he said.
It was just really sad he was gone when
that happened to a lot of those guys.
I've seen it.
I've seen it in my time in the UFC.
And,
uh,
I,
I saw it in my kickboxing days.
I saw it with guys when,
you know,
when I went from taekwondo to
kickboxing,
I spent a lot of time in boxing gyms
and,
um,
I got to watch a lot of guys get beat up
and training.
And over the course of just a few years,
like three or four years,
I could see deterioration.
And that's why Jujitsu and submission
wrestling is so much fun because you can
pretty much go full tilt,
really spend yourself,
get a nice workout.
No one necessarily needs to get hurt if
it hurts,
even if it's highly uncomfortable.
He just,
you know.
Yeah,
that's it.
Yep.
You know,
I mean,
provided you godly,
let's go.
You always have to have trust with your
partners,
but that is one thing you can do well
into advanced stage and it is a great
anti aging tool if you go at it in the
right way.
Yeah.
And I think one of the things that you
brought up earlier when it comes to
joint manipulation or joint mobility and
just flexibility and mobility,
it's.
I think it's very important
that people realize that if you want
your body to be healthy,
you have to use it all the time.
You can't have any excuses like old men
have to actually have to work out more
than young guys.
I got to work out every day,
even a couple of hours every day just to
maintain seven days a week.
Yeah.
It's not hard.
I'm not doing high intensity every day,
you know,
high intensity twice a week.
So I don't burn out.
Uh,
even younger guys,
especially if you're involved with any
kind of sport,
you got to be really careful that you
don't.
Overtrain overtraining is a epidemic
amongst grapplers,
Jujitsu guys.
Uh,
even mma guys are just chronically burn
it and burn it out,
but you know,
too hard workouts a week is enough and
everyday you guys do plenty of mobility
and I'd like to do plenty of breathing
exercises,
walking cardio and I do some static
stretching,
but it's enabled me to still,
you know,
I can still hold my own in the mat.
And I surprised guy sometimes when we
get on the mat and roll around,
you know,
at first they start baby in May and then
they say,
oh,
stevie still gotta go in there.
And then they start upping the ante a
little bit.
Of course,
you know,
at the end,
um,
I'm usually the one tap in,
but how is your shoulder,
I know you were having some shoulder
issues for.
I still got some issues with it ever get
it looked at by a doctor.
I did.
Here's the big old bone spur and there
just from doing silly stupid shit,
not tapping quick enough,
had a couple of injuries to it,
you know,
it started back in college actually.
So I don't do any overhead pressing or
anything anymore.
I can still do Hindu pushups and things
like that.
I could still do depths.
Will you still do those shield cast with
uh,
with kettle,
with a club's?
Not so much because I,
I can't travel with that stuff so I
pretty much went to bodyweight and
isometrics and so forth,
you know,
a lot of mobility stuff.
But uh,
I would,
uh,
here,
here's a good resource for your
listeners.
Any of you guys out there listening that
have shoulder issues,
go and buy the book shoulder pain.
It's solution and it's prevention by Dr
John M Kirsch.
He was a former orthopedic surgeon who
used to do surgery for a living.
That's how you know a doctor can either
cut you or give you medication to mask
the symptoms,
but it can't do anything to really help
you.
Well,
cursed found that bar hanging with a
brachial hang [inaudible] cure.
Almost every type of shoulder ailment
would get people out of pain.
Will explain.
A brachial hand gives you,
just made a lot with the palms facing
away.
Shoulder width.
You know,
I usually don't use my thumb or finger,
uh,
I mean my,
my thumb just grab it.
Like you would grab a baseball guy just
like amongst call,
which is what you would do for a
grappler anyway.
You never really have like you Americano
holder and you just hang and it
stretches out the coracoid bone.
And then the Uranus has loan as a.
it's like a little bone in the shoulder
that,
that.
What happens is as you get older,
it starts to impinge back,
bring it up,
that book,
a shoulder pain and solutioning and make
a t shirt that says,
bring that up,
Jamie.
There we go.
His shoulder pain,
shoulder impingement,
rotator cuff tears,
um,
labral tears,
you know,
four and a half stars on Amazon,
135 customer reviews.
That is a strong endorsement rotarian.
I'm telling you,
man,
when of course,
part of my problem is it's hard to find
a horizontal bar sometimes when you're
traveling,
you know,
they take all the pull up bars out of
that.
The plane routes.
Why?
I don't know,
maybe you know,
poor johnny's to obese to pull himself
up.
We,
you know,
God forbid you feel bad about himself,
does it have to be this way?
You've got to be a break your hand,
so it has to be palms facing forward.
Let the shoulder come out of the socket
and you just hand passively until your
grip starts to get tired.
You can do it multiple times.
You will be absolutely amazed how good
your shoulders will feel from doe.
That so full arm strength or full arm
locked down just completely.
Yeah,
and you just completely,
completely relaxed.
Okay,
so you just hang,
just hang and just let the shoulder,
let the humans come out of the socket.
And Hack.
So is it,
what is it doing?
It's just like relax.
He just opens up the joint.
He gives the universe more ability to
move.
Even with the bone spur I have in the
shoulder,
when I hang regulate,
I have zero pain.
Whoa,
that's crazy.
And this guy stopped doing surgery.
This is the guy who made his living
doing surgery.
Now he doesn't advocate Shaw.
He says this works better.
Why?
This is an orthopedic board,
Certified Orthopedic Guy,
and he shows the,
a study where he did a study with the
old folks.
I'm telling you,
it feels really,
really nice.
Really,
really,
really good.
So we'll pull lists.
I use this for all my clients.
I do a lot of online personal training,
fat loss diet programs and such.
And uh,
all my guys that have shoulder issues,
I get them hanging.
And Yeah,
there is interesting.
I'll tell you,
Joe,
if you having any shoulder stuff going
on right now,
just start hanging everyday,
even multiple times.
Shoulders and full of good.
That sounds counterintuitive.
Like it's too simple to be true,
but it's one of those things that is
true.
Well,
I had some tears in my shoulder and uh,
I got a,
it was having some pain so I finally
went and got an Mri,
apparently had been dislocated and I
never even knew it had been dislocated
from Jujitsu.
I don't even want to see the damn
pictures,
you know.
And uh,
had a,
uh,
had a labral tear.
I had a torn bicep tendon and I had a
um,
what is it?
I'm liberal and a rotator cuff rotator
cuff tear two,
you have any experts in there and he got
a bunch of shit going on there as well.
And anybody that's played hard boy
sports like we have all our lives,
you're going to get that shit.
But I'm telling you a what curse found
it didn't matter what the source of the
injury was.
The relief is profound when you do that
daily hanging it,
it's just that amazing.
Hawaii I'd done.
What I have done is um,
get stem cell.
I got stem cell shots in the shoulder
and it is incredible what the healing
for.
So I had always clicking and weird shit
that was going on there.
All that shit went away.
Throw the hangs in there.
I'm in,
I'm in.
I'm hanging.
Wish I could hang right now.
I'd like to do it right now while we're
doing the podcast.
The lender.
Hey,
I need to find some kind of portable
device that uh,
what about one of the ones that goes in
front of a door?
Like those,
those ones that you do in a doorstop be
great,
but you know,
I'd have to buy one in each city and
then it just dump.
It gets annoying.
You're committed to this.
Are you were,
you were saying before that you might be
thinking about Maui as a base?
I am slowing down just a little bit.
What?
I've been doing this since about 2005 I
think.
Well,
when I met you,
you had a truck?
Yeah,
I was living in a van,
a camper and know like I can't be
bothered with this fucking truck.
And I,
I really liked it.
But then I started traveling.
What's the hell do you do with you,
your rv?
You know,
you can't just park it somewhere,
store it.
You got to find somebody you like and
you got to turn the engine over.
You got to maintain,
you know,
mice get inside.
A lot of these are vision to the
electrical wiring up and yeah,
totally destroys your electrical system.
Yeah.
Abandoned vehicles.
Uh,
you know,
if you just sit it,
a little critters get in there.
Yeah.
It's not uncommon at all.
So what the hell do you do with it?
So I finally just sold it,
talking of the power of the Internet.
I sold my camper van to a guy who had
never seen.
I was in Germany.
He was in San Diego and the van was up
in,
uh,
in Seattle.
I sold it to him sight unseen to send
him pictures as very honest.
I had a bunch of shit wrong with it.
I told him every single thing that was
wrong with it,
you know,
we agreed on a price.
He wired me the money.
I mailed him the title and the key
because I traveled with,
you know,
I kept a key and I had the title with
me.
I mailed that to him.
He went up and got it.
And drove it back down to San Diego from
Seattle.
Wow.
The power of the Internet.
My friend.
That's amazing.
Put it on craigslist and a boom.
I got a uh,
you know,
I had a few people bid on it and uh,
if you would've told me,
oh,
even 20 years ago that I'd be making a
living on the internet,
you know.
Well,
essentially you make a living doing not
to seminars,
but you do have a lot of online stuff.
A lot of live stuff.
Yet what?
Say a understood the,
uh,
the power of the Internet for doing
online personal training.
Uh,
wow.
Well,
a lot of people found out about you and
me included because of the Internet.
I mean I found out about you from
research and Kettlebell exercises and
that's how I got some of your early
stuff.
And also I knew about you because I knew
that you were one of the first American
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu black belts.
One of the first hell Helson Gracie is
first to be sure.
But that a,
I think there was a bunch.
There was a couple of guys that
Machado's given,
but I was like that first tier of actual
Gracie Jujitsu guys,
and then Horian and a Master Leo had
the,
uh,
Gracie instructor training program.
They were concerned that,
you know,
of the teaching quality.
There's a lot of guys out there teaching
that probably shouldn't have been
teaching.
So they wanted,
they,
they had a specific educational style
like how to teach the move.
And I was the first person to graduate
from that instructor training program.
It was really good.
Will you,
I'm sure you're aware now the
controversy of this Gracie University,
the thing that they're doing online,
they're doing.
The son's got a little carried away with
that blue about,
uh,
I,
I'm not real thrilled with them.
Oh,
there's one guy who's given a ride brown
belts online here.
Yeah.
Do you mean a Gracie?
No.
Oh No.
I don't even want to say his name,
but he's pretty respected guy.
I read on the underground that he's
given away up to brown belt online.
How could you possibly respect that?
I mean,
I guess the only way I would think
physically tested and proved himself.
That's what I was gonna say.
I,
I have seen guys that have trained
pretty much from the Internet.
I went to Tahiti,
I was hired by a group of grapplers to
prepare them for the Society Society
Island Championship.
It was very popular.
A grappling is a traditional sport in
amongst the Polynesian peoples.
And I went to Tahiti.
I stayed there three months.
I trained these guys for the Society
Island Championships and the guy that
was running it was still a white belt
and uh,
he was a prison guard there and Tahiti,
big guy and a unbelievable grappler.
He outweighed me probably about 50
pounds yet he was very soft,
relaxed,
technical.
He had never actually had a teacher.
He learned it all watching online on the
Internet,
speaking of the bow then.
And I loved the way he trained with me.
He was very respectful even though as
you know,
like 30 years older than him and much
smaller.
We x a good training.
I just gave the guy that blew about
right in the spot.
Wow.
I mean,
there was no way that that guy was a
white belt and I've done that at
different places where people don't have
a good instructor where they are under
promoted and I'll get on the mat with
them,
I see what they can do and I say,
wow,
okay,
this guy is under promoted.
He just hasn't had a chance to have a
legitimate guy give him a promotion.
I have got rolling with a group of
students and he was the teacher
basically because people.
Teacher.
Yeah,
out teacher and his guys were good.
They were really,
really good.
Well,
if you just really pay attention to the
fundamentals and you really understand
the principles behind each individual
technique,
you can learn a lot online to learn a
lot online,
but not brown belt.
Now I just feel like I need someone
there right there with you below about
almost anyone can get.
Yes,
I agree.
I mean,
I heard a really funny analogy one time
from a,
I think one of carly gracie's barbells
or maybe it was health got bit.
He said basically a white belt as a
sperm.
The seed.
By the time your four degree a wipe out
your like,
like a little baby that was just born
and then the blue about is like a little
toddler,
like just a little little kid doesn't
even know what he doesn't know yet,
but the time you're like a four degree
blue about your,
you're like a child.
And then the purple bow is like a
teenager,
dangerous teenager.
Well you know,
you got the technique but you just
starting to know that they can do it to
purple belts.
I feel like it's like some of the most
dangerous.
That's a dangerous guy because a lot of
times he's still using a lot of power
but he got the technique to.
And then of course by the time you're
your brand brand,
you're like a young man and you know,
basically a brown belt is a black powder
and the skies,
it's just once you make Brown bought,
you've got to make black belt unless he
does outright quit.
Yeah.
And you know,
and,
and then a black box like you know,
a grown man.
But for me,
I don't know about you,
but once I got the black bow,
I felt like a whole new layer of
learning was taking place at that point.
Well,
you'd never stopped learning and Jujitsu
as long as your bodies to work.
So what we're talking about these new
moves that are constantly coming out.
But then you know,
John John Machado has this really
interesting take on things.
He said,
the more you know,
the less you use Lsu.
He goes,
I might know 10,000
techniques but to win match I might use
to solve the said that one time he says,
look,
I know 30 ways to pass the guard,
but I only use two.
I have a backup,
move a and then backup plan.
Big Case it doesn't work.
And I think that's just the way it is.
Man was really good guy follow game that
that song's pressure.
Solid top gaze.
His bodyweight.
So well,
you know when I used to train to Sala he
could tap me out on the cross side
without even putting a submission hold,
just crushing me with his weight.
And he's not,
I mean,
he's heavy,
but he's not that heavy.
He would rob your breath.
It was just the most horrible feeling.
It's like being waterboarded or
something,
man.
It was like,
oh my God,
the pressure he learned to do that,
you know?
But yeah,
uh,
the,
I think for,
um,
as far as moves and so forth,
probably one of the most outstanding
clinics have ever witnessed was when
John Shock Machado was in the second
abut Dhabi.
I actually went over to the Arab
Emirates and I wanted to support Salo
and whoever at that time.
And I couldn't believe the clinic he put
on all closed guard too.
That's another lost art.
You don't see too many guys use it,
you know,
cron uses.
It could close guard.
But John Jock put on a clinic.
Unbelievable man.
He had this super fight with Mario
Sperry.
I never saw such a.
He almost put sperry out,
man.
Yeah.
John John is no joke,
man.
He's always been a beast.
He's a really brilliant person to like,
uh,
like as a human being.
He's a great guy.
On top of being this amazing Jujitsu
practitioner.
It's just a beautiful human being,
and from that closed guard,
he only used for basic moves,
triangle arm block,
Omoplata a gay attain.
And of course some sweeps to back it up.
That was it,
you know,
and he,
the way he put them together,
it was like a machine got attacked by
Bup,
bup,
bup is like,
the guy in the guard was so hard
just not to get caught,
never saw anything about it.
It was like,
wow.
It just goes to show you that the basics
done well.
That's all you really need.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
Hickson and crone,
crone to this day still just uses the
basics.
Unbelievable.
I mean,
you know,
and that's,
it sounds derogatory.
Almost like someone like Minotauro
wants,
got upset that Vinny Magalhaes many lace
was talking about his,
um,
his Jujitsu and he said it's very basic,
but that's not bad.
NASIC is not bad at all.
So,
and said that about me,
I take it as a cop.
Well,
personally,
you know,
basic is just honed to a razor sharp
edge.
All of the basic techniques that you
know,
I think there's um,
like harder gracie's another example,
another example,
one of the best Jujitsu artist in the
world,
but very basic.
What year was that,
where he,
he.
One is the vision and then he tapped
everybody in the open division with an
ex chuck from the mountain.
He used that one take down that one
throw heat does he mad at every single.
And these were all professional level,
best black belts in the world.
He tapped every single guy with the
basic extra for the mass.
Crazy.
Just the first thing you learned,
right as a,
as a,
uh,
your first,
first couple months and just Jesse,
you learn basic extra.
The guy tapped the best in the world
just doing basic stuff with.
It's such an advantage in Jujitsu to
being tall and long.
Oh,
what a nightmare.
It's a giant advantage because of the
tall and long guys have so much leverage
so much.
And also the ability to get techniques
and lock them up or a short,
stubby armed person like me just
doesn't.
My arms don't connect in spots like with
Doris chokes and things along those
lines where you just,
you can have more space.
They have their arm goes deeper.
They can bet.
You'll see people with every type of
physique type lounge just there because
yeah,
I'm speaking like fireplug kind of
built.
I mean,
no one was shorter and stubbier than
sallow.
Right.
Yet he's like one of the most winningest
Jujitsu guys ever in the world.
True.
Wow.
You know,
he just maximized.
He,
he adapted the Jujitsu was to his
physique or horse Mr Paul Harris.
No,
perfect example.
Exactly.
So tank,
that's the cool thing about the game.
You know,
it doesn't matter how you're built.
Big,
tall,
short,
you know,
uh,
whether you carry a little extra weight
or you're really skinny,
you can adapt this to your,
your own body.
So we were talking about you moving to
Maui.
Yeah.
After we got up,
we got off track a little bit,
but yeah.
Why,
why Maui and what?
What makes you a.
well,
you're going to laugh at this because
it's not scientific,
but,
but it is a.
I use an astrologer.
This guy is amazing.
He used to be a stanford professor.
Can say his name.
Sure.
Okay.
His name is Robert Koch.
Uh,
his,
his website,
his star center.com.
I've been using this guy for a few
years.
When I first heard about it,
I thought this is such bullshit.
I'm never going to do this,
you know,
the person that turned me onto it was
my,
my girlfriend,
and she says,
listen man,
just do it reading with this guy.
Just do a reading.
And I'm Sandra,
are you mean you take advice from a guy
you've never met and you're going to
listen to those guys.
So I gave him my birthday date,
the time of birth,
whereas born,
that's it.
Plus my name.
He read my life to me as,
how are you doing this?
Well,
maybe you got on Wikipedia,
maybe,
but this was an impromptu call.
So I don't know.
All I know is that,
uh,
it's based in mathematics.
He believed,
you know,
like,
uh,
the Pythagoreans,
you know,
they believe that everything can be
explained in numbers and in mathematics.
He was a former,
a stanford professor.
He came from academia and he gave it all
up to basic to this basic astrological,
but even more important.
He's like an old philosopher.
He's read all the ancient Greek
philosophers and he's also a.
have you heard of this?
Mental Science,
mental science,
mental science.
Basically your,
your,
your reality is based on your thoughts
and your,
your current reality is based on the sum
total of all your positive and negative
thoughts.
Thought thoughts are a vibrational
pattern and the vibe you put out is the
vibe you attract.
So if you're like a real negative person
always,
you know,
think saying negative statements and
fill in a lot of negative emotional
things,
you're probably going to have a pretty
shitty life.
And if you're thinking like a higher
thought,
ha her,
of course,
the highest would be love.
That would be the highest vibration
you're going to have.
Good things happen to you.
That's the basic.
Yeah,
in a nutshell,
as much more complicated than that.
So like the secret essentially like this
grit,
right?
Which is a great little book.
Well anyway,
Robert Developed his,
uh,
his astrological,
based on,
on,
on mental science as well as a basic
physics.
And so anyway,
he read my life,
he looked at all the places in the world
because,
you know,
you put off a vibration like,
like an energy vibration,
it can actually be measured,
right?
Your,
yours would be as identifiable as your
fingerprints or you know,
like an eye reading iridology or
whatever.
And uh,
there's places on the earth that put off
a vibration also.
And the place that vibes best with me is
anywhere in the South Pacific,
but in particular,
Maui.
And he really,
he really honed it down to the town of
[inaudible] to try to sell you a house
there now.
No,
the spot 67 clover lane.
Yeah,
there we go man.
Let's go online and look at that.
Oh,
the house is for sale ads.
Damn Robert,
you're amazing.
No,
but,
uh,
so anyway,
now he is supposedly the best vibration
for,
for me,
for you,
for me.
So I explained to me how this guy goes
about it.
So he finds out what your address or
what your,
your date of birth is,
well,
part of the world you're born,
what time?
And then once he has some kind of
computer program with all his charts and
numbers and he plugs all this stuff in.
And then I asked them like,
well,
what is it?
You're actually looking at the computer
and it says it's just basically he says,
I can't make exact predictions.
Said if I could make exact predictions.
I played the stock market and you know,
but uh,
you know,
I,
I can come up with high probability for
certain things happening.
And also he's looking at you ever hear
the collective consciousness,
you know,
you have your higher consciousness,
you have your subconscious.
But then there's a collective mindset.
It's like everyone's emotions and moods
and thoughts,
right?
Right.
Now it's one of fear,
you know,
everyone's so afraid,
I'm traveling all over the world so you
can literally feel the fear right now,
Europe is all up in arms because of the
terrorist attacks and things.
And people are really scared with the
Isis and all this.
There's like a real fear mentality.
The problem is if you give into that
fear mentality,
you actually create the very thing
you're afraid of because you're
basically concentrated on them.
It's like a form of visualization,
right?
If you're always like.
It was like the shark thing we were
talking about,
I probably would create a situation
where I'd meet a shark if I went
swimming in the ocean because you know,
I put too much energy into that.
Yeah,
me too.
Whenever I was the snorkel,
the goggles underneath,
I'm like,
where is he?
Yeah,
exactly.
The soccer for you and I,
we,
we would probably possibly actually
attract a negative situation like that.
I just sad.
But anyway,
there is a collective mindset.
You can even feel like different
countries have different moods.
When I get off the plane,
I can actually feel that I'm pretty
sensitive to this.
Like in Russia,
it's real somber,
kind of almost depressed.
You know,
a place like Maui.
It's like,
oh my God,
I just feel so happy because I was so
lucky there in paradise there in
paradise,
you know,
the mood is much higher.
The aloha spirit as they say hello.
So he told me that was the single best
place.
Other places were a place in Alaska,
was a place near a little town I can't
even recall.
And then another place was little part
of Alaskan coast on the coast.
The coast is not bad.
Yeah.
Like near Anchorage.
Yeah,
it was near Anchorage.
You use a little town.
Just be amazed at how moderate the
climate is to everyone says it's quite
nice there.
So you know.
But.
So Alaska,
Turkey,
Maui,
Alaska.
Uh,
I think it wasn't a hard choice.
Well,
it's a very relaxed environment in my
only to like the places relaxed.
It's a relaxed place to live,
you know,
as far as like the people that live
there,
they're really cool and chilled out and
totally children.
My webmaster lives there.
Chris Crook,
awesome guy.
So I,
you know,
I always have business to do with him.
He's been doing a great job for me.
You know,
what does the guy told you you need to
live near like oil minds and South
Dakota be less reluctant or more?
That would be oil minds near South
Dakota.
You know what I'm saying?
Like someone that sucks.
You can live right outside of like some
fracking fucking compounds.
Yeah,
that's an interesting point.
I think someone with a really negative
mindset might have attracted a place
like that.
So then I tried to keep the vibe heavy
and I mean a light and at a higher
higher level.
And uh,
you know,
you can attract goodness and abundance
in your life,
just like
the sacred.
That's a,
that's a good book for people to start.
Well,
it's us.
Anderson was,
was quite an interesting guy.
You the power of positive thinking for
sure is real.
I mean for sure there's a lot of good
that can be done in your life.
If you look at things,
if you have a positive approach,
you can,
you could look at things in a good way
and have those things have positive
attributes,
have have benefit in those things.
Or you could look at the exact same
thing exact same moment your life and
just decide that this is the end.
Life is terrible.
You're a loser and people have these
deeply grooved patterns that they've
carved out in their consciousness over
years and years of approaching different
situations with very similar reactions
and it's almost like automatically like
something happens to you.
Everything always goes wrong for me.
God,
my life sucks.
I'm such a loser.
But if you compared your life to someone
who's born in Bangladesh or Ethiopia or
some someplace where people are like
really genuinely unfortunate,
they would be laughing at you.
They'd be like,
you live in America and you're white and
you don't have cancer.
We just shut the fuck up.
You know,
like what's perfect example of that
would be a George Costanza,
this character right on,
on Seinfeld,
right?
The guy that no matter how good he had
it,
he always had managed to screw it up
somehow and things would always,
always turned back.
We've all had the experience of being in
a room and someone would come into the
room,
kind of a dark vibe and the whole room
vibe with shore,
but then we've also had the experience
where a guy would come in who was a real
bright,
positive thinking person and everyone's
mood,
but just let that collective conscious
you've got to be so aware of because not
every thought that a person has is that
wrong.
You know,
it can come from the outside.
We don't manufacture our own thoughts.
You can be influenced by negative
thinking from other people or positive
thinking from other people and you got
to start to be very conscious of they
kind of thoughts passing through your
brain and reject those negative thoughts
and it's not easy.
It's a discipline like working out.
It really is and it's also one of the
more important aspects about surrounding
yourself with positive people.
When you surround yourself with positive
people,
you find them to be inspirational.
You get excited.
You all think along similar lines.
You support each other and help each
other and it benefits everybody and you
develop.
You develop like a real keen sense of
like love and community,
whereas if you're around people that are
constantly negative,
like you're,
you're in conflict all the time,
all the time.
You're wearing out,
you're constantly getting exhausted too
by the stress of an eye.
I have a theory in that too,
and that's just my theory.
I mean,
it's part of the mental science we were
talking about.
Um,
I believe that those people are the ones
that attract all sorts of degenerative
diseases and,
and,
uh,
you know,
bad things happen.
Well,
it certainly can play a factor,
especially stress,
you know,
stress has been shown to be devastating
to your immune system.
People that have really stressful lives
and don't get enough sleep and are
constantly negative and thinks about
things.
Sleep is more important than diet.
You know,
people
that are overweight,
a man,
I'll tell you could be in the best diet
in the world and still having a lot of
struggle with weight if you're missing
your sleep.
I've seen that many,
many times,
even with my own clients because I do a
lot of fat loss programs and you guys
will be eating pretty decent and not
losing the weight and then,
you know,
I'm looking,
they're only getting like five and a
half,
six hours a night and they're really
stressed.
You know,
you have a tendency really hold onto
water and,
and uh,
your body will hold onto that body fat.
It's an oil.
It's hard to dilute.
The of that is an interesting aspect of
a lack of sleep is that your body holds
onto fat.
It really holds on.
And also fluids,
you know,
what they call false fat.
It's not even fat is just like all this
fluid.
It just gets trapped in the tissues.
It might as well be fat because it's
just as unattractive and just as
uncomfortable,
you know?
So did you
bother investigating what this guy is
doing about this astrology stuff?
Did you bother looking into it?
Listen to him.
Well,
his,
his website is quite interesting.
Is radiant.
Last is like fantastic.
You know,
for people.
What is the astrology itself based on?
It's based on the position of the stars
time you were born.
Yeah.
Haley is Haley heliocentric.
The old astrology with earl was earth
based because they believed the earth
was the center of the universe.
He created his own Heleo is Hetrick,
you know,
with the sun is the center and then it's
just basically created his own
astrology.
He did.
How does one do that?
How does one create their own astrology
and what?
I couldn't.
I got almost,
and I would say almost almost understand
how someone could imagine that if you
looked at thousands of years of data,
you could figure out that people develop
certain personality traits if they were
born during certain times and you could
sort of try to align those times with
the constellations in the sky that are
moving and the,
you know,
just the way the earth wobbles and where
the stars are at any given moment.
That kind of almost makes sense.
But this guy doing it on his own,
like,
how's he doing that?
You know,
I don't even pretend to really
understand it.
What's know what sold me.
I didn't have said Maui.
He's at valley.
He did,
I,
I didn't have to understand it because
he,
he basically read mine life to me like a
book.
It says there's no freaking way that he
could have known this information.
What kind of stuff that could he not
have known.
Just the way my life went,
man,
you know,
like my relationship with my parents and
the relationship with my ex wife and the
way my marriage went,
a way my marriage dissolved and like,
you know,
just all sorts of stuff like that.
Like sort of like a Tarot card reader.
Yeah.
But Tarot card reader is bullshit.
Yeah,
exactly.
And this is not bullshit.
I don't have,
let's put it this way.
He's told me not to do stuff and I've
done it and
never has worked out for me,
man,
but isn't impossible that one of the
reasons why it didn't work out because
he told you not do it and that you
thought about it and your negative
thinking and negative thinking.
But like,
and the brand.
All I know is every time I go against
him,
it just usually doesn't work out.
And when I listened to the guy,
right,
it almost always works out
right?
But this is sort of contrary.
This goes along with what you just said,
like you're almost not giving yourself
advice.
You're not following your own advice.
You,
you literally were just talking about
thinking about things in a negative way,
like,
like things are predestined.
So this guy has sort of created these
scenarios that you shouldn't,
you shouldn't engage in
thing.
Like he's told me something on my chart,
right?
And then I'll call them a day or two
later and just completely changed your
charts changed.
Yeah.
Like,
something changed.
And I says,
well,
wait a second,
two days ago you said I shouldn't do
this.
Now you're saying it's okay.
He claims it's like quantum physics,
right?
If you change your thought or your
vibration level,
he actually sees a change on his chart,
on his computer.
What?
Yeah.
Okay.
This makes zero sense.
Well,
I'll give you another example of how
this might work.
I had,
I had this guy that was a,
uh,
by a professor of,
he was,
uh,
actually a phd in biochemistry and Board
Certified Nutritionist Name is Dr
Gregory House and uh,
he used to take hair samples,
right.
And he would test these things out for
like various deficiencies,
this,
that,
and the other thing.
Right.
And he,
he,
he was into this,
um,
uh,
electric.
Uh,
basically I am attached that hair
forever and as my body would change,
the hair sample would change even though
I was no longer connected to it.
Change how it,
it would no longer show the deficiency
when he would retest it.
Why?
Uh,
I know,
man,
it's crazy.
Crazy shit.
Not Violent.
He was a hardcore scientist man.
PHB just set up tumor.
This doesn't make any sense.
I just,
I don't buy that.
It doesn't make sense.
Your,
your,
your physical hair is not going to
change.
Changed what actually changed?
I don't believe it.
Well,
I,
I had trouble believing in myself.
Did you see it?
You know,
for a fact,
if you read into it,
if you looked at data,
I tested really actually understand the
process,
right?
But I knew him not to be a liar.
He was.
He was sure he's not,
but he might just be delusional.
So looking at something like that,
you're talking about something that
defies physics.
It defies science,
Physics that completely through physics
on its ear,
right?
But we know that electronic can occupy
more than one space,
which now opens up the whole door for
parallel universes,
all sorts of stuff.
Stephen Hawkings just recently claimed
that the black holes are like a door
from one universe to another.
So there's all this crazy
stuff.
They just put everything on end.
What we know about physics and medicine
and everything else.
I believe there's one called vibrational
medicine that they actually talk about
this.
Check out that book,
right?
But see,
here's the problem where you're not
testing subatomic particles when we're
testing hair,
when you touch someone's hair and you're
testing here for various mineral
deficiencies in vitamins,
those things aren't flying through the
air and going back and forth.
So if you're here,
he was actually,
he was actually testing it,
the,
the vibrational level of the hair.
What does that mean?
Like it,
like everything puts off like a,
like an aura.
You can photograph it with Kirlian
photography.
You can actually photograph the energy.
You know everything has an aura.
Even this cup,
this table,
your body and aura that you can actually
prove a real aura or the someone who
believes they've actually taken pictures
of it.
You've heard the Kirlian photography
know how to spell that.
A fuck.
How do you spell that?
Kirlian photography and they actually
have taken pictures of this and he can
actually measure the energy coming off
this and it matched me.
But Jamie's a photographer.
Jamie's should know about Kirlian
photography.
Ever hear about that Shit Jamie?
I can't say I've ever heard of.
Have you ever tried to bang some chick
was really into crystals of it's to talk
to you about it.
Check it out.
Anyway,
that's.
It's pretty simple and it works for me,
man.
Well I understand that it probably has
its application in the mind,
the power of the mind.
So.
But is it a big giant placebo effect?
I don't know.
I do know this.
In a recent study,
they found that placebo drugs work about
40 percent better than real drugs.
What test is this?
Uh,
there was,
uh,
there was a thing that I did mushrooms.
I read a whole.
They,
they've given people like regular
medication,
you know,
from pharmaceutical stuff.
They found that placebos work way better
for what application though.
You know what I'm saying?
Like when you say that it,
the placebos worked way better for
relief and pain relief makes sense
because a lot of pain relief you can
actually do with your own mind.
I don't take pain pills.
I got knee surgery and I didn't take a
damn thing.
I just read so many negative side
effects of the Ibuprofen and the this
kind of stuff.
Well,
Ibuprofen would say probably the safest
evolve them.
And it's still not good for you.
But my fear was always,
I just knew too many people that got
addicted to pain pills.
And I'm like,
well,
what's,
what's the worst part about pain?
It just doesn't feel good.
Well,
isn't that just okay?
Can you just deal with not feeling good
while you heal like the least.
Now I know I'm in pain because I'm
healing.
An awful lot of pain is cut,
you know,
a mind thing like how you approach the
signal that,
that back pain guy,
uh,
but also the steward,
Miguel de,
they were looking at x rays that
people's backs and you know,
people with chronic back pain a lot of
times it would not have any physical
reason to be in back,
back pain.
Right.
And then they were all at,
you know,
pictures of guys that were active like
us and their backs are a mess.
All sorts of slipped disc and the guys
are not in any pain at all and it must
be afraid of we'll get an x ray on my
back,
you know?
Yeah.
Right.
Yeah,
right.
If anybody would have a messed up back,
it got to be me all the falls and throws
up taking over 45 years of wrestling
users using little tiny micro injury
constantly.
But yet I'm not in any pain at all.
Yeah.
Well,
pain is an interesting thing in that I
think the mind can regulate pain,
so that's what I meant by
pharmaceuticals,
but it doesn't make sense with other
applications where we,
you know,
we find like anti epileptic medications
or things along those lines where you
just know for a fact as a physical
effect on the body that these drugs have
and that they don't understand placebo
effect.
You know,
that's one thing for sure.
They know that placebo effect is real
and it does work in certain
circumstances is the power of the mind.
Well,
it especially dependent upon who is
receiving that effect and you know how
much the person believes in this thing's
gonna heal them.
And if people,
you know,
what I find is a lot of people are
really into the body but they're not
really working with their mind or their
thoughts are or anything like that.
You know,
it takes a lot of discipline.
It does,
but it also,
you really have to clearly establish
what's woo,
what's nutty,
crazy crystal bullshit and what is an
applicable modality like what is,
what,
what can you really do as far as
meditation as far as things that are
repeatable,
things that people have shown to have a
beneficial effect on your consciousness,
a beneficial effect on the way you
approach life.
And um,
and that is pretty much individually it
is,
you know,
you really have to,
like you said,
you self experimentation one I just
talked about might sound pretty damn
weird to a lot of people,
but so far it's been working for me well
as long as I feel good about it.
Yeah.
And I don't feel like it diminishes my
life in any way.
No one's taken advantage of me,
uh,
you know,
um,
I feel like confident and really good
about those type of information I'm
getting and I found it worked.
But like you say,
power of the mind.
Well,
if you,
if you just approach it on that level,
if you say,
okay,
this guy's going to give me advice and
I'm going to find this advice to be
beneficial and I'm going to follow
through with it and I'm gonna use that
as a guideline and I'm going to have
good confidence in that.
These choices are going to be correct
because of this guy and his knowledge.
And my problem is I've just,
I've seen too much bullshit.
And so,
um,
whatever beliefs I might've had like
even six years ago before I started this
podcast,
a lot of them have eroded just under
scrutiny.
Just understand.
No,
I hear Ya.
I always advise people,
give the guy a call.
The first session is free.
If you think he's a crackpot,
never call them again.
Yeah,
but I mean,
what I would want to do my problem with
someone like that as I want,
I would want to go down the rabbit hole.
I would want to find out,
okay,
how are you making these distinctions?
Like what,
what,
how did you devise this method?
What's going on behind the scenes?
What do you base this on?
How do you know?
What are you saying?
Like what are you saying when you tell
someone,
hey,
don't take that flight to Germany
because something bad's going to happen.
Like who the fuck are you?
How do you know that you don't know
that?
And that's the reality is you tell
someone don't do something.
If you tell someone,
hey steve,
I really don't think you should go to
Florida.
Oh fuck.
God says I shouldn't go to Florida.
You're already starting at cascade of
negative thoughts and that,
to me that is a very good point.
And I had thought about that.
You know yet.
Well there's not a fucking person in the
world that can tell you that if you pick
up your car keys and drive your car to
Minnesota,
something's gonna go wrong.
So if this guy's telling you that I call
bullshit,
not only do I call bullshit,
but I think that that kind of stuff was
kind of dangerous because what he's
looking at it is like,
you know,
you were really influenced by the
collective a lot,
you know,
like people's general moods and stuff.
He gives me like a little heads up,
he's able to see that helps you.
Like if I wanted to do a seminar to a
certain date and he'll look at the
charts and he'll just say energy is
pretty off that.
Okay,
but what does that mean?
The energy is pretty often looking at
the charts.
What does that mean?
But it's looking at it.
I might be tired.
I don't know.
I haven't seen these charts,
but I hear them clicking in the
background and the computer that guys on
facebook,
he's looking at pictures going on.
You just checking out girls assets.
GimMe a call.
No fucking way.
No.
Yeah,
I don't care.
I've got.
Time is not.
Time is valuable.
I just think there's a guy in the world
that can look at a chart and tell you
where the energy of the world is.
I think there is man.
Really?
I've experienced it.
So this guy know you.
That's why I'm questioning this wacky
guy who's out of a suitcase.
Maybe that's enough to.
I think you're a beautiful,
brilliant man.
But uh,
if I was your friend and I was,
I am your friend,
but if I was there while this was going
down,
I would be asking this guy a fuck load
of questions.
I do find he's a really good guys I've
talked to about stuff too.
He's almost like a kinda like a
psychologist or a psychiatrist in a way
is like an ancient times.
The scientists were philosophers and all
the great.
Even Alexander the Great and you know,
uh,
all the great Roman emperors,
you know,
uh,
they would have their own private
philosophers to advise them on things.
Mark Israelis for example,
and they would listen to these
philosophers.
I kind of look at this guy almost as a
philosophy,
as an advisor,
an advisor,
and I can buy that.
I haven't always taken and I have gone
against the guy.
Like in what way?
I just didn't listen to what he said,
hey,
get my advice.
Don't do the seminar this weekend.
Why would he tell you not to do a
seminar?
And he said,
this is bullshit.
It would be a better day to do it in
this day.
Oh fuck.
Why,
you know it's Voodoo because he threw
chicken bones in the ground and one of
the sticks,
I have done it and it would be not such
a good one.
Maybe he told you that it was going to
be a bad one.
You had it in your head.
Then you went and did it.
Maybe.
Has He ever told you not to do
something?
He did and it worked out awesome.
No,
that's what made me think.
Well,
it's because you're thinking about it.
What we talked about with negative
thoughts,
maybe maybe more likely than a fucking
chart can tell you the energy of the
universe doesn't want you to fly to
Miami.
That's crazy.
There's some pretty brilliant guys out
there that,
that knows stuff that we don't,
man.
Um,
yes.
There's definitely some brilliant stuff
that we know,
but this one guy that's got a computer
that can tap into the collective energy
of the universe and tell you where the,
where the energy is and what.
You should definitely not go to Ohio.
I've looked at your charts.
Fuck you.
That's what I'd say to that guy.
Haven't you crazy man?
Haven't you ever gone and done a set in
your show and it just kind of bombed,
you know,
it just didn't work out that if anything
ever went wrong,
there are a bunch of reasons why it went
wrong and I could look at all of them.
I could say maybe I was tired,
maybe I was overworked.
Maybe I didn't prepare well enough.
Maybe I have new material that's not
worked out,
but it's not because I shouldn't have
gone to Ohio.
You know what I'm saying?
It's not because some guy shows me a
chart and the collective energy of the
universe is that,
but just maybe there are people,
this guy in particular that could
potentially write,
have seen that for sure.
What the set going back,
wouldn't you want to have a hold on a
second because this is very important.
Well,
where do you want to have a method that
you would clearly understand how this
guy's making these arbitrary decisions
and choices?
Because you're.
You're talking about bullshit.
You're talking about like Voodoo.
All right,
and if you're talking about,
if it's not bullshit,
then it's science.
So if it's science,
it's repeatable and you should bring it
to people that are experts and they
should analyze it and study it,
but for this guy to just sit there and
click on some things and tell you,
don't go to Ohio.
That's bullshit.
Well,
all I can say is this work for me so
far.
The proof is in the pudding as far as
I'm concerned.
Okay.
If you.
Your mind decides that something will
work out well and you have full
confidence and your playing doesn't get
hit by a meteor and everybody gets out
alive and at the end of the seminar or
the end of the trip that you took,
you say,
hey,
that guy's advice really turned out
well.
It really did.
What you've done,
you've done it.
You basically give yourself a little
mental shield to go into battle with.
Well,
there we go with.
That's what it is,
but it's not real.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Plus I have that mental shield,
isn't it though?
Well,
it is real.
It is in the sense that it was effective
because you had confidence in it and
because you approached all of these
events like you had confidence in it,
but is it real in that there's a guy who
actually can look at a computer and tell
you whether or not you should go
somewhere based on the energy
of the universe?
No,
no.
That's not real.
It's definitely not real.
I will tell you with 100 percent
confidence it's not real.
Do you know how I know it's not real
because there are millions of brilliant
people out there,
millions of scientists and Co and we
talk about quantum physicists and
theorists and all these different
people.
They would have heard of this.
If you're talking about the guy who's
making a computer program,
they would analyze this.
It would be something that people would
be talking about.
If this guy really believes it,
he wouldn't just be holding onto it.
In Maui,
he would be telling the world,
listen,
there is a way where you can accurately
predict events.
There is a way in you.
It would be up to peer review.
People would be studying it,
they would be putting out papers on it.
It would be something where we would
understand,
we have figured out a code,
whether it's like the fibonacci sequence
or something like that,
a code to the universe and if you follow
this code,
you have predictable,
repeatable events.
How do we know that there aren't a lot
of people are doing it is the problem.
This is a problem,
this phrasing that you're using,
how do we know it could be?
It could be it's not enough to base your
life and any decisions and this will
will bullshit that comes along with
Tarot card reading with palm reading,
with all that stuff.
It's all the same and it's all one
person telling you.
First of all,
he's telling you stuff you already knew
about your life.
Okay?
This is the strategy of charlatans.
I mean this is what Tarot card readers
do and palm readers do and fortune
tellers do.
They tell you shit they are that you
already know and they tell you it
through leading questions and they tell
you it through a bunch of signs that
they can tell for being really good at
reading people.
Then they go on to tell you what's going
to happen or what you should and
shouldn't do,
and in doing that you can plant some
thoughts and seeds of doubt into
people's head.
This is the reason why people used to
think that someone could put a hex on
you because if I put a hex on you and
you believe I put a hex on you and you
leave this room and you're like,
I am fucked Joe.
Just put a hex on me and we went around
in life.
That will be overwhelming your thoughts
and if you allow that to happen,
it will be true.
You can manifest bad things by having
bad energy and bad ideas.
This is exactly what you were talking
about earlier,
but this is done through like a strategy
and a in a,
in a,
in a repeatable pattern.
Well,
oh,
I can say is maybe it works.
Maybe five,
man.
Crazy talk,
that's not as crazy as just say.
Um,
it's definitely crazy.
Okay.
I'm certified crazy.
Well,
it's just,
if there's a method to it,
like if this guy says,
oh,
here's the reason why,
the reason why is,
you know,
there's a,
like the golden sequence of the universe
and you can tap that golden sequence
into a computer and it's based upon all
these different factors.
If that guy has information like that
and he's,
he's just holding onto it and Maui or
wherever the fuck he is and he travels.
I got.
Yeah.
Just kind of a,
a nomad by the way.
Someone who went to Stanford and there's
a professor,
it doesn't exclude them from being out
of their fucking mind.
Dr Oz is on TV
and he's telling people about weight
loss medication.
That's a miracle.
And that fucking guy had to go to
Congress about it.
Guess what?
He still on TV,
the guys on TV telling people about
miracle weightloss fucking berries.
It's bullshit.
He's a,
he's a charlatan,
right?
Tons and tons and tons of guys out there
selling,
you know,
there's,
there's this kind of stuff as you know,
I'm pretty much an anti supplement guy
and I just feel you used to take a lot
of sort of $120 worth of supplements a
month and I didn't notice a damn thing
when I stopped taking all of that shit.
No one thing.
In fact I felt better felt.
That's interesting.
And once again,
you know,
a lot of this is placebo,
you know there is some but there's also
some that's been proven by science to
have beneficial effects on a lot of
different factors.
But you know,
you're a guy who's a healthy active guy
who's constantly eating correctly and
not allow yourself,
streamlines strict with the Diet.
How do you do that on the road?
Like when you,
when you're in in these different places
and like say if you're traveling to
countries and you might not even speak
the language,
how do you make sure that you get the
right food?
Well,
I try to always keep the quality is best
I can,
but as you know,
being a frequent traveler yourself,
you know,
you can't always get the best quality
stuff talking about placebo effect.
I won't let it get me bombed out.
I want to start thinking negative
thoughts,
eh.
Let's say for example,
I have to eat a,
Oh,
I don't know,
a bag of pretzels or something.
I believe I can sublimate any ill effect
of that food and that just just by being
grateful,
just by visualizing my body,
being able to respond well to the food,
it's just calories,
you know,
I see myself digesting it and
assimilating it and I won't let it
negatively negatively affect me.
You just look at it as raw cowers
characters,
you know,
so it's some starch.
It's not the best stuff in the world and
it's not like I'm going to be eating
that as a habit and I,
I'll be fine because you can work
yourself up into like a,
a,
you know,
a real negative thing.
I'm going to give you an example.
When I was younger,
I had a friend that was,
uh,
taught me a lot about higher mind
science and uh,
we were in a restaurant one time
together and this is,
I guess maybe in the late seventies and
there's a guy smoking this is when
people could still smoke.
And uh,
those guys bought in to smoke on me and
I'm getting madder by the minute is
really pissing me off.
So I asked the guy if he,
if it's,
you know,
if he would please not blow smoke over
to me.
And the guys started doing it even more
and I wanted to punch the guy right in
the face.
And uh,
I'm looking at my friend Tim,
and he's totally relaxed.
You know,
about the whole thing.
And it says,
doesn't that bother you?
Doesn't that really aggravate you?
And he said,
Steve,
you get yourself all worked up because I
can sublimate the bad effects of the
smoke,
but not letting it get to me.
He says,
all those negative emotions and the
anger and upset your feeling are 10
times worse than any amount of cigarette
smoke blowing on you.
He says,
you're actually doing harm by the way
you're thinking about it as opposed to
the actual harms the smokes doing and
wow,
that blew me away and I've seen him so
relaxed and I started thinking,
well,
that's probably everything in life.
So I started looking at food the same
way.
You know,
if you're,
if you eat something that may be you
know,
isn't the best quality because there's
just no other thing available.
Well,
so what?
You'll be fine,
you know,
you just go back to eating a really,
really good quality stuff after that.
It's what you do most of the time is,
is the kid.
Not What happens upon occasion,
but I will say this as a,
as a full time traveler,
I will pack my own food as much as I
can.
I always carry it like a little grocery
bag.
Yeah.
I was just telling your instagram and
your girlfriend got food confiscated and
what did they confiscate?
A lot of times you can't take anything
that looks at little liquidity through
the security.
Sometimes they'll grab fruit,
you know,
like going from Mali,
back to the mainland,
all the fruit and stuff.
Any fresh produce they will.
They'll take a for example,
I had a salad,
right?
Uh,
the lenders was fine,
but they wanted the tomatoes,
the cucumbers off that would impasse.
Yeah.
The Department of Agriculture Guy,
speaking of Buddha,
right.
It was just the craziest thing they
asked the just why I did,
but you know,
he had no real format.
They never have an explanation for it
and stuff.
It's just band or whatever.
I don't know.
Certain flies.
Well,
they're attracted to the liquid,
be attracted to the stuff.
But uh,
yeah,
usually I don't have too much trouble
getting stuff through.
And it's funny,
some countries are so amazingly lax,
like whereabouts is the Australia?
He could take liquids through the
security.
You can.
Yeah,
you can take water and all sorts of
stuff,
but you can't take a dogged Australia to
see what happened with Johnny.
Johnny.
Johnny Depp is still in trouble with
that.
Did you see his video that he made?
I haven't seen it.
It's hilarious.
It must be really fun.
It's hilarious because he mock serious,
talked through his video,
like,
you know,
he's an actor,
so he made it look like he was being
serious but did so in a way where it's
pretty obvious to anyone watching that
it wasn't serious.
Like it was so subtle that one of the
politicians,
one of the main people in Australia
actually had a comment on it,
you know,
how it's pretty obvious that he wasn't
taking it seriously and made this video.
It's really weird what we'll go through
security and what won't,
you know,
for example,
in China,
they were absolutely scrupulous.
I couldn't believe how good this girl
wasn't that screen.
She got all my little secret shit I like
because I do all carry on now.
I don't check bags anymore.
Uh,
I had a little key that's actually a
knife.
It opened up into a little night because
you didn't need a blade,
you know,
have to,
you always could use a blade no matter
where you are to cut stuff or whatever.
You just always have a need for it.
She found that kid,
I don't even know how the hell she knew
that that was a knife.
They,
um,
I carry like little survival tools with
me.
I have like a little flint still
firestarter sometimes when you start
firing a fucking Zombie apocalypse ever
come up.
Does your astrologer telling you that
you need to carry that around that.
But I watched the walking dead fear,
the walking dead,
speaking of,
you know,
creating a mental but also have like one
of those little drinking straws.
But you know,
I'm in a filter.
You can actually drink a ton 40.
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
when I saw that,
remember the tsunami hit badly,
that resort,
you know,
I'm in places like that and I just
figured better safe than.
Sorry.
Yeah,
I do believe that,
you know,
there's,
my astrologer will keep me safe from
these things,
but let's just say we would have a
situation where the water would be
really shitty.
Like I've been in like places like a
Novosibirsk in Russia.
Dude,
that's like in the middle of absolute
nowhere.
You know,
if there would be any kind of natural
disaster or something,
at least I know I can drink.
Right,
right.
And you know,
I have like a little thing I could make
flour.
I mean you never playing,
playing,
playing go down and I'm surviving in the
Andes or something.
Have you ever made a fire with one of
those things?
Yeah,
I have actually really packed.
Yeah.
I just wanted to see if I could do bring
kindling with you as well.
You.
Yeah,
you get,
you know,
it was like a whole little art to doing
a fire from.
It's fun to try those.
They call them earth skills are ancient.
Ancient skills with a lot of people
bring like steel wool or something like
that.
We'll go with batteries.
Works really good.
And I also have a little magnifying
glass thing.
I travel.
I always have a compass,
you know,
bring a company.
Well,
you know,
as old school I've learned how to use a
map and accomplishment as a kid.
As a boy scout.
You do orienteering.
So I knew how to do the uh,
the knots,
you know,
my little thing.
So when you're going to these places,
like say if you get an offer to go to
some strange place in Siberia,
are you reluctant to take any of these
or the just like anybody who wants to do
a seminar?
I'm open for the journey,
much open for the journey.
I like to go to different places,
you know.
But in China there's last time,
my God,
they were taking my to fricken nail
clippers,
nail clippers.
They found that little key.
They took my little fire starter.
How she even knew what that shit was.
I have no clue.
They must be well trained because she
nailed me for everything man.
Wow.
And then you get in trouble when the
nail you for that.
They just take it because none of it
could be considered a weapon.
However,
I was arrested in Switzerland one time.
I had been traveling by train.
I had one of those.
A Gerber or was it cold still?
It was like a knife.
The spring assisted rock climbers use it
because you know,
if you're rock climbing and you're
harnessed gets tangled,
you may have to.
You have to hold on to cut yourself free
from your harness,
right.
So you need a knife,
you can easily open up with one hand.
So I just liked it.
It was a great little knife and uh,
I had been by train and had it in my
little,
my little man purse carry on thing and
forgot about the damn thing.
So it went through and they pull me
aside and they,
they,
they pulled that knife out of there and
I was like,
Oh shit.
And they said in Switzerland,
a assistant opening night is considered
a weapon.
And the place took me back.
I sat there,
I almost missed my plane.
They,
you know,
they,
they obviously were going on Interpol
and doing all this bullshit to find out
who I was and what I'm doing with this
knife.
While to add insult to injury,
I also had like a little credit card
thing and it also had like a little
teeny blade in it.
It was like one of those,
uh,
multi-tool in the shape of a credit
card.
So they found two blades in my freaking
carry on.
I could have got away with a credit card
because they wouldn't have even looked
at that,
but once they found one thing that tore
my shit apartment,
they looked at everything.
Oh my God.
But it's weird,
you know,
like Australia,
China,
you don't even have to take off your
shoes most places you don't have to grow
up shoes,
but us,
you still do fingernail clippers.
All that stuff goes through even small.
Even small knives,
you know,
they don't even bat an eyelash
multi-tool we can take through Tsa,
but they're looking for stuff like
liquid and,
you know,
any kind of shoes,
electronics.
A lot of times I saw them this past
time.
I'm making them,
um,
making people prove that their computers
could turn on a saw a number of that
because you know,
that one dude tried to slip a bomb
through the laptop.
And recently have you traveled lately?
Uh,
did you find the security lines were
like crazy internationally mean or just
even within the US?
Seems normal.
It's always value is ridiculous.
At lax was absolutely awful.
Uh,
that,
that lady got through security and
actually boarded a plane with no
credentials are boarding pass one.
There's just,
it was just,
I read like a Bang News.
I usually read the,
I don't like to read the actual news
because it's always talk about negative
mindset.
I just look at the headlines just to
see,
like,
just give me a clue like what's going
on,
which I be scared of.
What new virus.
Well,
yeah,
I never read that shit,
but I do like to read travel stuff just
to see what the latest and greatest is,
you know.
And uh,
anyway,
there was a new,
it hit international news.
Well,
yeah,
there we go.
She actually went,
got the whole way through and the word
came down because TSA was already under
fire basically just for being
incompetent.
So,
uh,
the.
Anyway,
this woman got through and now all of a
sudden now this will be going on for the
next month or two.
They're just,
Oh my God,
it's,
the travel is so delayed.
That's interesting because I've been
traveling a lot.
It seems totally normal.
It always sucks.
Well,
I usually go pre,
uh,
this last time I took the budget spirit
airlines,
they don't have any contract with TSA so
everybody goes through like the long ass
security lines,
but one of the best things I ever did,
I did global entry and I can just walk
through like a freaking Rockstar when I
come into jetpack.
Global entries.
Nice.
Oh my God.
It's so nice.
But along with it,
you get the pray and I usually fly
business or first class these days,
especially for the really long flights.
Man that Prius so nice.
No shoes off.
I'm going to have to take off your
jacket a.
yeah,
it's interesting.
It's changed,
you know,
short how that's changed over the course
of our lives,
you know,
it used to be you don't even have to
have an id to get a plane,
get used to just hand them the ticket
and you could give a ticket to a friend.
That friend could go on the plane
instead of you.
Yeah,
that's right.
That was the old days.
The old days,
man.
You could just drive through Canada.
No problem.
You know,
come back.
I mean,
it was none of that kind of stuff.
So this astrologer told you to move to
Maui,
you gonna,
you gonna follow his advice.
You're going to go there and I'm gonna.
Uh,
I'm setting up a little home base to
work out.
I'll start travel somewhat due to some
seminars,
but I'm going to set up a shop and yeah,
because I was thinking for a guy like
you,
a lot of people would come to you,
like it might not be a bad idea to just
family van Damn Nice place to attract,
right?
Yeah.
And not only that,
but you could set up seminars on a
weekly basis and do them literally from
the comfort of your own home.
You could just have a program where you
run people out of Malibu and make a
great living or Maui rather and uh,
and go back and forth if you so choose.
You could kind of go anywhere.
If you did do that and you could
establish your own gymnasium and like
have like a real gym there.
Would you start changing your own
training?
Because I know a lot of what you're
doing now is mostly by way back,
get back to some of the things that I
really,
really enjoy,
you know,
like what I liked the clubs that I club
swinging.
I like swinging the light clubs,
you know,
just as a mobility thing.
It makes my elbows and shoulders and
wrist feel good.
You know what I'm talking about?
The little one pound Indian clubs I used
to.
I used to be quite the expert.
You know,
I actually learned that as a physical
education major in college real as a
freshman.
Uh,
as all pe majors had to learn basic old
school physical culture systems.
And one of those was the old wooden club
system back in the day,
Huh?
Yeah.
That was a 1970 when I went through the
school of Health and physical education
at Westchester.
That's interesting that now 40 plus
years later,
those sorts of training modalities are
coming back.
Yeah.
Well,
so old is new,
right?
Yeah.
That's the little kettle bells is a
perfect example of that,
right?
Page example,
they,
you know,
that was old school training tool.
Uh,
then they came from Germany,
by the way,
not,
not Russia really at the Germans were
the ones that actually established.
He called him ringlets in those days.
No kidding.
A lot of the old German strong men use
them and it looked the same like a
cannon ball with the handle,
a condo.
So there was a lot of really weird
designs.
Some of them really like circle just on
a cannon ball,
you know,
they used to use real heavy ones in,
there are,
a lot of them were hollow and he would
unscrew it
and they would put weight inside and
screw it back on.
That was kind of interesting.
Oh,
so you can adjust it.
Yeah,
like adjustable weights and so forth.
If you had your own gym and you could do
whatever you want and lift weights and
you know,
what would you like,
how would you set it up?
What'd you do?
Like standard,
like Olympic style weight lifting type
exercises,
or never been a real fan of Olympic
weightlifting.
I don't believe that it's the most
efficient way to train athletes and
there's not a lot of Ncaa a strength
coaches and uh,
uh,
nfl strength coaches is shy more and
more away from the Olympic lifts.
They're fine.
They're athletes just getting to busted
up and hurt,
you know,
even just doing a front squat.
Why?
By our risk of million dollar athlete,
you know,
to teach them the Olympic lifting is a
hell of a sport.
I mean,
it takes a lot of coordination to Joe,
my big lips.
Yes.
And as you well know,
one sport doesn't make you better at
another sport.
It really doesn't.
It just causes motor learning confusion.
There's no doubt that Olympic weight
lifters are incredible specimens.
They're strong,
they're fast,
they're explosive,
but it doesn't follow.
The doing Olympic lifting will make you
stronger and more explosive and fast.
It's like self selective.
The gods had already had those
attributes to weld Olympic
weightlifting.
So if I take a slow twitch wandering,
give them Olympic lifting,
I can't select.
We recruit those fast twitch muscle
papers and make them at fast twitch guy.
A pride is going to get them hurt.
If I was a wrestling coach or an mma
coach or a football coach,
I want to be spending most of my
athletes time out practicing the skills
that the sport,
that's the most important thing,
the skill of the sport and most of your
sports specific conditioning come from
the practice of the sport itself.
Aside from that,
I went to general strength training
program to make his skeletal muscle is
as strong as humanly possible.
So I'm going to use modalities to do
that and the idea is to keep it is,
is as safe as possible.
And I see Olympic lifting is pretty on
dangerous.
I've seen a lotta guys busted themselves
up hurting themselves,
you know,
we're trying to do it.
So I'm not a big fan.
So you're seeing motor learning
confusion is the term?
Yeah,
like sometimes people think that a power
clean is like the snap,
uh,
finish off a AA pickup,
thrown something,
but it's a completely different skill
set.
One isn't going to make you better at
doing the other.
Do you think though that strengthening
your muscles and having more explosion
and more the ability to close the
distance quicker from box jumps and
sprints and things along those lines can
directly translate to things like
martial arts,
like I don't think it's very specific.
Yeah.
Doing a box jump as a whole lot
different than shit into double egg
throw.
Right?
Ever.
The best way to get guys really
explosive of doing that is just do those
things over and over and over again and
get really good at it.
That's very controversial,
isn't it?
Oh yeah.
There's A.
There's as many guys that a talk like
me.
There's just as many guys that would
argue to the death the other way,
but I've done both.
You know,
as a young boy,
I learned Olympic weight lifting from
the last Olympic world champion,
Robert Bednarski.
My Dad used to take me down to York,
Pennsylvania when the United States was
still the Mecca for Olympic lifting and
I actually learned Olympic lifting down
there,
the Old York Jim.
Wow.
Yeah,
and I used to lift in my basement,
but what I've found even when I was just
in high school as a wrestler that it
wasn't really helping that much and even
then I just sensed like a real danger to
my body in wrestling is a tough sport as
it is,
right?
What your training should prevent
injuries.
If a person needs to foam roll and do
massages and is hurting themselves in
their supplementary training,
there's something wrong.
If it's really a good training modality,
it should prevent injuries not caused.
So I,
I'm a firm believer in getting rid of
all of the,
uh,
of the dangerous stuff out of your
training because uh,
you know,
what we do,
martial artists dangerous enough as it
is,
that's really controversial though.
I mean there's a lot of really high
level strength and conditioning coaches
that think that strength training and
power training and things along those
lines actually improve all of your
skills,
your skills.
As a martial artist,
I've been strength training for 53
years.
I didn't find that myself.
Right,
but based on your own body,
in your own life,
but also with clients.
Remember I've trained literally hundreds
and hundreds if not thousands of people
over the years and I did find a good
correlation.
It's just interesting because in was at
men's journal,
there was just an article by a guy who
is like one of the leading experts in
speech reading and he,
he found that the thing that correlates
most to your ability to run fast,
like in a sprint a was the trap bar
deadlift.
He tried leg presses,
cleans front squats,
all this stuff.
The thing that had the greatest transfer
into improving your,
your,
your ability to sprint was the trap bar
deadlift.
Why is that?
Just the way it positions the hips and
the way that the weight is centered,
you know,
like instead of out in front of you
where there's auto spinal sheering,
the,
your hands are on your side.
So it's like you're almost inside the
weight.
Yes.
Uh,
and the way you hinge out in that trap
bar deadlift,
I'm a big fan of that.
The only way I do them now,
they always felt just intuitively like
such a damn good exercise.
Well anyway,
it was just in this month's issue,
uh,
I think it was men's journal.
My only feeling on trap bar deadlifts is
I always felt like I didn't get deep
enough because the 45 pound plates were
so large.
Well,
he was saying that is not necessarily
get that much range of motion for
sprinting because your legs aren't
really bend that much anyway.
But there's a lot of strengths in speed
coaches,
like really well known guys,
they're now going against power cleans
front squats and all that.
Judge a Franco is really a famous
strength coach.
He,
he won't risk the injury to his athletes
anymore of this stuff.
He's finding guys were messing up their
elbows or wrists,
their fingers.
I mean,
if you have a guy that's like top level,
instead of deb away,
you know,
a wide receiver or something,
you do not want to use risky modalities
and risk hurting this guy because what
they do as an athlete is risky enough,
you know,
out there in the way they run and sprint
and cut and so forth that they kind of
collisions that they have.
You want to make that training is safest
possible.
You want to make it as general as
possible so they get,
as you know,
as much strength transfer.
It doesn't have to be fancy exercise it,
you know,
basically squat,
hinge,
push,
pull,
horizontal and vertical,
some type of rotation or anti rotation
and then work the ancillary muscles of
the neck,
the fingers,
the hands,
the forums,
the grip,
and obviously the feet.
Calves and ankles are really neglected
in a lot of people's training.
Week,
feet,
weak ankles.
And we'd have a lot of guys leave that
out.
And of course the neck.
Man,
I,
you know how many guys I know the try
their neck is crazy man.
Even your jaw,
you know,
I can remember watching Mohammed Ali,
uh,
you know,
the old videos,
they do like these little snippets of
his training.
He used to do a lot of [inaudible] and
he had this really cool thing where he
would take like a sling and hook it onto
a,
uh,
you know,
like a pull down and then he would open
his jaw against the resistance that is
freaking brilliant to,
to strengthen the muscles of the jaw
because,
you know,
it's well known fact that if your jaw is
stronger,
uh,
there was a lot less chance of a
knockout.
Yeah.
A lot of who used to chew beef jerky so
as to strengthen their jaw.
They used to chew bubblegum all the time
because,
you know,
your jaw gets tired when you have bubble
gum.
I get to the bubblegum gets old.
I can just keep chewing on it.
And they would do that to keep their
draw strong.
You know,
it's funny.
Uh,
they show,
you remember when we brought up the,
uh,
Alexander's ass with the tif lifting
with that bank.
I used to actually have a mouthpiece in
two teeth lifting when as a kid.
Really?
Yeah.
It was,
uh,
it was very popular back in the sixties,
you know,
teeth lifting for your neck and your
jaws.
I used to lift my little sister up.
She used to lay down and I put the,
a little sling and a feeling on those
like neck harnesses with the chains
attached.
You like those?
Yeah.
Entrepreneurial too because my trainer
hates him.
Uh,
you have to be careful and some of them
are really crappy design,
man.
They hurt your ears and you know,
I already have qualifiers.
I don't need to make it any worse,
but uh,
they can be good.
I think one of the best things ever
invented was the old nautilus for wide
neck machine.
That was a damn good piece of equipment
and later the hammer strength for way
net.
See those things.
That's like Kelly Starrett.
I talked to him about those things,
those neck machines.
He's like,
those are terrible for you now.
That's bullshit,
man.
Really?
Yeah,
I do.
I know who to believe.
Yeah.
Well you gotta try it yourself.
I tell people to experiment,
but you know what works really well that
I don't think would be too controversial
for anyone.
Neck isom metrics.
Yeah.
You showed me those with a belt.
They aren't Tocqueville.
Fantastic.
You know,
Hixon used to do a lot of neck
isometrics.
He used to use that rubber band.
Well,
he would walk back and just hold it.
Yeah.
You know,
it's almost like someone trying to pull
you down into a front headlock or a
front good team and then you go from
the,
with it on your forehead and on your
side and you to develop tremendous
stability.
I don't think you know the other stuff.
I could see where it can be
controversial because it all comes back
to your technique,
your form.
You know,
if you're an idiot and you're using a
lot of momentum and you know you're,
you're,
you're using poor technique.
I could see where he can really mess
your neck up,
but isometrics.
They're pretty safe.
Okay.
But excluding isometrics,
those neck machines,
like moving your neck when those next
machine neck machines,
where do you think the problems?
I think the problems lie and people
using momentum too much,
too much weight,
too much momentum,
and not using good form.
I mean,
okay.
We know that you can get really strong
and really fit using shitty technique
and form.
You see it all over the gym.
You see huge guys seemed really muscular
dude.
Just thrown the crap out of the ways.
That doesn't necessarily mean it's the
best way to go.
Many of those guys don't stand the test
of time.
Remember earlier I was saying,
you know,
anyone under 60,
Eh,
if they haven't passed over,
of course that's pretty convenient for
me now somehow,
but no,
seriously,
if you haven't been to the other side,
there's a lot of stuff that I did in my
early days.
No way that I would advocate that stuff
now,
man,
but I was always a firm believer in work
in the neck and I used neck harnesses
successfully using really good strict
form,
not necessarily heavy weight.
If you put yourself in by mechanically
in efficient position,
you can really work those muscles really
hard with very,
very safe.
Now when you talk about neck,
neck harnesses and you lift your neck up
and you can lie on a bench and put a
plate on your head and lift your head
up,
what about side to side movements or you
can also join the site and you're,
you're cool with those.
Yeah.
Another one I remember to.
And,
and,
and violent context sports.
Someone's going to put your neck in some
pretty weird businesses whether you want
them to or not.
So you got to kind of endure yourself
to,
you know,
uh,
the basic positions and what kind of
repetitions you talking about when
you're doing neck exercises.
Pretty High Reps.
I was like,
well it depends on the speed of movement
to it.
I mean like I,
I like a slow high tension speed and
movement to really fatigue the muscles.
So it just depends how fast you going.
Real slow.
Usually I go by Tom under load,
so somewhere between a minute to 90
seconds.
Time under load is good for the entire
set.
Yeah,
for the set.
When your 92nd set.
One of the things I've gotten into over
the last year or so is a long negatives
like exploding on the initial movement,
the power of the movement,
like say if I do a chin up,
exploding up and at a very slow,
maybe like four times as long,
maybe even more than more than that on
the way down.
And they do training.
Yeah,
it can be very,
very good.
It's been used for awhile.
One of the big proponents of that type
of training was the famous Mike Mentzer,
the only guy I ever squash nigger.
We're talking about bodybuilding now and
as real interesting because Mike used to
use these very intense brief,
uh,
exercises the year he'd beat Arnold and
the,
uh,
and the Mr Universe show,
Mike was only trained about 90 minutes a
week and Arnold was trading about 26
hours a week.
How's that possible?
Because of the high intensity training.
Ninety minutes of non.
Yeah.
He was very much into a high intensity
training,
like 30 minute workouts.
His discipled Dorian Yates.
That's 3:30
minute workouts a week.
That's right.
Go check him out.
He has a whole website called heavy
duty.
Uh,
he was a real pioneer in the high
tension.
Uh,
he used a lot and negatives for the,
doing experimentation with isometrics
towards the end.
That's,
that's crazy though,
that he could do this 90 minutes a week.
And of course they're all using the
steroids,
you know,
obviously,
with the,
you know,
that's helps.
Yeah,
that's what that would give him,
but people can't say it was just the
steroids because arnold was using
steroids to,
um,
we were talking about Paavo before the
podcast,
Pavel Tsatsouline,
um,
and he is a proponent of low reps of
doing things like under five reps,
five reps are under.
Well,
remember his sport is his strength.
That's what he does.
He's not a fighter.
He's not a martial artist.
He's not an athlete.
His sport,
his weight lifting.
If your goal is to lift as much weight
as you can,
his system works extremely well because
that is the sport,
right?
If you're an athlete and you want to use
strength training to better you and your
sport,
the majority of your time should be
spent doing your sport.
Right?
Right.
So you,
the amount of weight isn't the most
important thing necessarily because an
athlete is not a strength specialist.
So once you can deadlift or press a
certain amount of weight,
it's pretty much you're going to get
diminishing returns.
I mean,
how strong do you need to be?
Right?
You know,
in a weight class sport.
I mean,
if you're,
if you're able to do a double body
weight,
deadlift,
how much stronger you need to bear in
order to get stronger,
you're going to have to specialize.
But that's going to take me away from
the skills in my sport.
And also a lot of the,
uh,
low repetition stuff.
You know,
that they come from the field of,
of,
of weightlifting.
There's no doubt it's,
it's a strong dude,
but it's not necessary for me to do that
low of repetition when I'm just training
for general strength.
Well,
his philosophy or his claims are very
interesting because what his claims are
was that people doing these low rep,
uh,
exercises like five reps are under,
they experienced benefits and all of
their sports and then it translated to
all that power and strength translated
to gymnastics.
And
Oh,
all extra strength training is going to
translate into sports to an extent.
Olympic lifting works power lifting
words,
you know,
low reps work,
high reps work.
I know many guys that did nothing but
super high repetitions,
you know,
been plenty of guys like that.
It all works one way or another.
What you want though is to get as
efficient as possible and you don't want
to be beat up for days after your
workout.
Obviously.
That was one of the reasons why he liked
the little rep stuff,
you know,
because it,
it doesn't seem to beat you,
beat you up quite as much,
but I found that doing short,
brief,
intense workouts,
usually even single sets translated just
as well as is his anything.
I'll give you an example of.
You've heard of a 1973 Miami dolphins?
No,
they were the.
Only there were under Don Shula,
they're the only team to go undefeated
and win the superbowl.
No other teams done it before.
Since ever in the history of the NFL.
They use cocaine well here in Miami,
but you know how they're trained.
They're trained a nautilus machines with
single set trend.
Why?
Yeah,
there we go.
So it all works.
It all works.
You can get in great shape,
no matter what you do is just what works
best,
what works best.
I personally believe for a lifetime,
and believe me,
I have a lifetime of vendors.
If you're getting hurt in your strength
training,
you're doing something wrong.
Strength Training should prevent
injuries not caused it.
So there's something wrong with your
technique and your form.
Me being a wrestler and a Jujitsu Guy,
I can't afford to hurt myself and of
course at my age now you get hurt.
Oh my God.
It takes for ever to get back.
We know that fast explosive training
works,
but we also knows as a much higher
chance of injury.
So for me,
I like slow,
high tension reps really controlled and
like you discovered that slow negative.
Yeah,
slow,
negative,
seem to be having a really positive
benefit on my training lately
and I found that,
that uh,
doing my exercises,
fasting supposedly did not make me
faster on the mat.
I had to selectively pick the movements
I want it to be fast and explosive bond
and do those federal those and drill the
crap out of him until it was like a
freaking machine.
One of the things that I've gotten into
also over the last few months,
his grip strength.
Captains of crush.
Yes.
I have 167 pound one that I just smashed
that fucker.
I'd do it for three reps and then I
throw it down.
Well thanks for taking it easy in my
hammock.
We shook hands that well.
I started with 120 pound one and then
uh,
I got 167 pounds one that I use now,
but I have a 200 and something pound one
that I'm saving for when I get tired.
One hundred 67 pound
one.
But it's like a,
there's a rabbit hole with that because
I,
I'm,
I'm like a maintenance squeeze and
things.
Now.
It's really weird.
It's like,
just make sure it's not people's hands.
Oh,
well I just have gotten excited about
the idea of strengthening my hands
because my strength hanning has all been
accidental for my hands.
It's all been just attached to dead
lifts and Kettlebells and Chin ups and
all the different stuff and that's how
my hands got strong.
But I've never just actively trained my
grip.
So when doing this I've been doing it
like I'll say like four or five months
now,
which has been just smashing these
things all the time.
Well,
you know,
there there's different types of grip
strength,
you know,
there's that crushing strength which the
captains of crush we give you,
but there's also like endurance
strength,
which is really good bars for grappling.
Well just hanging off a high bar,
you know,
either 100 or two.
Well that's one of the things we found
on fear factor.
That was interesting.
We did this thing where we had people
hang all over water on a bar just
hanging by their body weight and the
women all beat them in.
We have strong men really like big yoked
up guys,
but they were too heavy and the light,
the weight ratio,
and they probably just did curls like
bunch of bitches.
Well,
the grip is really a lot of it.
People just don't pay enough attention
to it.
Uh,
one reason why rope climbing has stood
the test of time as a grappling modality
is it's a very specific vertical type
grip,
like grab a hand or a neck or a wrist or
forearm or even an ankle.
A really good for grapplers and man,
it takes tremendous grip to climb a
rope.
Is a lot of stress on your joints?
Well,
there can be,
yeah,
you have to know how to climb,
but it's,
it has been an extra.
Hasn't been around forever.
Yeah.
I've got a big fat rope in my garage.
You know,
you've seen the gym that I have set up
in my garage.
I got this rope that like,
I can't even get my hand all the way
around it.
It's like one of those ropes that would
tether off a,
an ocean liner.
That's what they're for.
Yeah.
I mean,
that's where they get them,
but I'll tell you,
just hanging on that are squeezing it,
you know,
just not even climate.
Just hang it until your hand get that is
a tremendous grip exercise.
Oh,
for sure.
But um,
yeah,
for Jujitsu wrestling,
I found the captains of crush don't
translate as well as doing things like
Tao Chin ups,
you know,
obviously a climbing a rope.
A lot of guys throw a gooey over a chin
up bar and just pull up with tactics,
specific grip strength and uh,
also just hanging for time like we've
talked about for shoulder health,
awesome grip exercise.
And there's a very interesting
correlation between a biological age and
chronological age.
You know,
old people have really weak hands,
you know.
So with that,
I'm like 20 smash it.
There you go.
Um,
I have a friend who,
um,
does the scapular exercises,
he's an archer and he hangs the way
you're talking about.
And then when he gets to the hang
position,
he just lifts himself fantastic exercise
and holds it.
He's like pinching his shoulder blades
together,
just pulling his body up slightly with
his arms completely locked out.
Those muscles have so collected and it's
good for posture to.
Yeah,
I'll tell you,
I'd like to superset that with a set of
regular pull up sometimes.
Woo.
Do you feel that upper back?
As you know,
usually when you do pull ups,
your arms get tired first by,
by present,
preexisting,
the lats,
Rhomboids,
and you know your tears.
You know those back muscles.
Uh,
when you do your pull ups.
Whew man.
You really feel your back.
So you do pull ups.
I got all your sets.
Well,
not all the time,
but I would just the scapula retractions
first,
jumped down,
shake out my grip a little bit,
and then jump up and do the pull ups.
Wow.
What a great little back workout that.
Oh,
so you do this capital exercises first.
Pretty exhausted has those muscles
because they're bigger and stronger than
your little teeny grip forearm.
And so usually what gives out first and
pull ups is the hands,
the forearm,
sometimes your biceps.
So by pre fatiguing those upper back
muscles first,
they get much better workout when you
add in the arms.
Uh,
that makes sense.
It's temporarily fatigue.
Those.
So when you do these sets of when,
if you do like those scapular
contractions,
what would you call those?
I always call them scapular retraction,
retraction,
retraction.
Um,
how long would you hold that position
for?
I usually like two seconds up,
two seconds down.
Oh,
short,
short little movement.
He's 15 second to when you could.
I've actually done static contraction
where I just pulled myself up and held
it so I couldn't hold it,
you know,
like,
uh,
like 30,
40 seconds,
you know,
just depends.
That was another thing that pavel was
talking about with planks.
He was talking about like doing a plank,
but contracting every muscle in your
body and holding that position.
It's an isometric.
That's called a,
uh,
overcoming isometric.
There's two types of evaluation metrics.
One is a,
I'm sorry,
a Yoni isometric,
uh,
one is where you have a measurable way.
It could be your body weight.
Let's say you hold a chin up at the top
with your Chin over the bar.
It's a classic exercise called the
flexed arm.
Hang.
Okay.
You have a measurable wait there,
right?
The other version of that would be you
just grabbed something and just pull as
hard as he can.
No way to measure it.
Both ways.
We'll get your strongest as can be
strong as a beast,
so that plank that you're talking about
it,
it's like a yielding isometric and that
you have a measurable weight which is
your body weight and rather than just
hang out to see how long you can
survive,
what happens is you start to let the
bank collapse a little bit.
You start to relax certain areas of your
body and now it's just not nearly as
effective,
but if you're really trying to shorten
the abdominals and it really squeezing,
you create this tension,
you create a tremendous amount of muscle
fatigue in.
That should be the true purpose of
exercise to create that,
that overload,
that muscle fatigue and allowing your
muscles to recover from that.
And then it's the base of strength.
Yeah.
Um,
I have a friend and a lot of Jujitsu
guys getting into this now where they're
doing super slow sets.
I love super slow,
says I was one of the original super
slow trainers back in the day.
I still do.
And as a man ages,
and you have all the dings in your
shoulders and elbows and stuff,
you'll find that you'll be drawn more
and more to nice,
slow,
high tension sets,
real,
very safe way to train.
Um,
how many seconds up and down do you
suggest like save for something like a
chin up?
Well,
Mike Mentzer for bodyboarding
hypertrophy,
he found like a four to four where you
would like four seconds up,
pausing the contract position and four
seconds down the contract position to
push up.
The hard part would be the bottom part.
So,
you know,
just off the floor on a chin up,
it would be the top part.
So for a pushup,
say you would,
uh,
you would slowly go up for like one,
two,
three,
four turnaround.
Now you would then turn out or just have
a good back down and hold it the bottom
line.
One,
two,
three,
four,
and then how long would you hold it over
a thousand bond.
One thousand two and then two seconds
and then backup one,
and that's surprisingly difficult to do
for someone who thinks of a pushup as
being a pretty mild exercise.
Dude,
you can just sand blast yourself with
just about five or six reps if you do it
right.
Yeah,
I've even done them slower.
I've gone like,
you know,
10,
15,
tried doing a try this if you'd like.
Negative accentuated sometime you're in
a hotel room.
You want to get a quick pump for your
comedy act to start at the top pump for
comedy.
I stretch out.
You're a dude.
You got the rep,
but a private fit is con comic out
there.
Don't you find that comics in general
are pretty bad.
A lot of alcoholics and smoking.
A lot of small can.
Yeah.
The nature of the nightclub life,
you know,
it's very unhealthy.
It's also there's this false correlation
that you have to be an abuser of your
body to be funny.
Really?
Yeah.
I know that a vanity and I'm taking care
of your body are connected and that
vanity is ego and then having a big ego
and being vain,
like it's anti comedy,
but I just think,
I don't think it's vanity to take care
of your body.
I just think it's intelligence.
I think it's foolishness to not take
care of your body.
I know.
I just know too many people's bodies are
literally falling apart and who are my
age or younger who have massive issues
seeing it myself,
man.
It's really scary.
Yeah,
and they realize with time the error of
their way and it's usually too late if
you start a rigorous physical fitness
program,
but when you're 45 like boy,
you gotta kind have an uphill battle
there and got an uphill battle.
Although I didn't pause.
Well,
you know Anthony Bordain,
you know what's going on with him.
He's a Jujitsu guy now.
He started at 58 of lifetime of drinking
and smoking and even a problem with
heroin in his youth,
getting himself cleaned up.
I heard that.
I heard him present to it too.
Oh,
she's way beyond.
She's pretty good,
she's very good and she's obsessed and
that's
one of the reasons why he got into it in
the first place because his wife is a
maniac and he didn't want to get choked
down.
Well,
no,
I mean she talked him into it because
she,
she loves it so much and then once she
actually bribed him with narcotics,
whoa.
That's how she got him in and she told
him she'd given vicodins and so,
uh,
she,
she got him into it and then once he got
into it,
he's a,
he's a very,
and I say this in a good way,
he's very obsessive guy.
He gets obsessed with things,
you know,
that's why he's such a great chef and a
great writer and he's great on his
television show and he got obsessed with
Jujitsu.
He travels everywhere.
He brings his gay.
He trains everyday.
He trains twice a day.
He'll do a private and then they'll do a
class every day.
Everyday.
He trained with the Chris Crook.
The guy was talking about family.
My,
my web guy.
Yeah,
he trained with Anthony.
He said it was really fun.
That's awesome.
Oh,
back to that pushup.
So try starting at the top right?
You very slowly.
Usually your iphone,
like a little timer on there or
something.
I use one with a metronome so I can hear
the text and I go on down in 30 seconds.
And when my chest just barely grazed
instagram,
I do a slow,
what we call turnaround,
where you change direction very slowly.
Come back up in 30 seconds.
I don't walk out of the top.
There's no resting at the top because
the top is just too easy.
Right?
You can hold it forever.
So I keep my elbows just a little unbent
and then 30 seconds back down dude,
you have the pump of your life.
Ninety seconds time under load.
It's like wow.
What an amazing workout.
One fricking rep,
Sassy one and a half Rep.
negative.
Positive,
Just negative.
Positive.
Negative for 90 seconds.
So do you set like a timer for them?
Not for 90 seconds.
Just this running stopwatch.
I,
I use like a little thing on my iphone.
It goes tick,
tick,
tick.
So what is it?
Uh,
what is it?
I don't know,
it's just one of those many apps,
but I wanted one that had an audible
tick,
so if I can't actually see the iphone,
at least I can listen to the the
seconds.
So it's real easy to fool yourself when
going too fast.
No.
Do you do the same sort of technique for
squats or for any other exercises?
I have this one body weight squat where
you faced the law where you can't unload
by meaning forward.
You know that your torso leaning
forward.
Who Man?
What a killer.
You face the wall.
I faced the wall.
Great figure posture,
man.
Your toes against the wall.
So what are you doing?
Like you're facing the wall and how
close are you to wall?
My toes knows everything's touching the
knees and my hands are out to the side
as slowly lower down and you keep your
face on the wall so you know,
barely skimming and it's great for
posture because your back is really
arched.
So you're working isometrically and I
don't do the top third of the movement
with a body weight squat because it's
just too damn easy.
I would recover so mechanically
efficient at the top that there's no
work,
so you get to the top third and then you
go back down again.
Damn.
Sometimes they use that 30,
30,
30 for that one.
It's absolute killer.
When you're done,
you just basically your legs are just
crippled for a second or two.
I've been doing slow Hindu pushups and
I'm just amazed at how tired you can get
a set of 20,
slow Hindu pushups in your heart is
ready to explode.
It's amazing,
isn't it?
And you don't have to go fast to get a
good cardio metabolic workout.
I'm a big fan of that Hindu pushup too,
just for the range of motion and such a
wide range of motion in that spinal
mobility.
Yeah.
I would say arguably that might be the
only pushup a person would need just for
fitness,
you know?
I mean really it's a hell of a exercise.
It's basically upward and downward dog
of yoga combined with the movement.
Yeah,
and I do it with a 40 pound weight vest
sometimes.
Third Year a beast.
Well,
it's just such a great workout.
Just signed it down even more.
Try do in 10 seconds so you don't have
to keep adding more weight to your vest.
Yeah,
well as I remember,
Tom Angelo is really important.
I'll give you an example.
I went to the gym one time.
I saw this guy just jacking off pull ups
like crazy.
He was using a lot of momentum.
It was basically one second.
One second.
Damn.
The dude did 25,
which is impressive,
you know,
but he was pretty much yanking up as
joints,
you know,
so I had my client client do a set of
six,
but he was doing for two for each one.
So the guy that did the 25,
his time under load is only 50 seconds.
My guy did six.
His time under load was a minute.
My Guy Actually did more mechanical work
and was physically in some ways
stronger.
Better strength to weight ratio.
So what do you think about those
crossfit style?
Put Chin ups.
Absolutely insane.
I mean La.
Well we talked about this last time.
That guy keeping that Greg glassman guy,
the guys in a beast.
Crippled man.
Well,
he's got health issues,
was a man.
I know that he kind of started.
The man is like,
what the fuck?
I could have.
I could have had health issues.
Usually the injuries that I've had,
if anyone has an excuse for not
training,
I'm not.
I don't mean to toot my own horn,
but man,
I never missed a training due to an
injury.
I always,
man,
if you hurt your shoulder,
you got your other shoulder and your
legs that you can work into your core
right there.
I.
I busted up my fault one time so you
know,
I was able to work.
You always work around it.
There's something to do.
Always something to do.
Not Training,
just because you're injured.
I pull out L for my spine one time just
doing the stupid abdominal roll outs
from the feet.
What's an abdominal roy?
Oh,
I saw this Jackie Chan movie and I was
really a.
You know,
you use those ab wheels and there's
little wheels from your toes.
You roll the whole way out whole way
back.
I was pretty good at that.
One time from your toes.
You roll the whole way out in the
hallway back,
which I'm not exactly sure what you
mean.
Can you ab Roller Jackie Chan.
This is pretty inspiring.
So you mean like you'd make a masters in
like a,
like an inch where.
Oh,
okay.
And you blew your back out to them.
Now I left my back is guy it started
doing it.
Here got Derek go.
I could do that.
I probably still could do it,
but I'm just too afraid to do it.
Is that hard to do?
Fuck yeah.
It's unbelievable man.
Trying to.
Well No,
don't try because I don't want you hurt
your back,
but you got to really,
really braced your abdominals and keep
recruits tight because the shearing
force on the lumbar is really high.
As I found out,
I don't do those,
but I do do a lot of ab wheel stuff,
but I just never do it like that.
You could do it off your knees.
It's the same movement is hanging leg
raises.
Very safe.
Some people call it toes to bar.
Try doing it with no momentum.
Slow up.
Touch your tippy toes to bar pause for a
second.
Slowly lower if you do three or four.
Wow.
You're pretty strong core.
So it's the same level that with Lake
Street?
Yeah,
with extra.
Like try to almost like you're touching
your toes.
Toes to bar,
ankles or shins.
That means that person's too tight in
the hamstrings.
But,
but yeah,
I blew my back.
I had an l for a subluxation.
And your thesis and uh,
I was told I might need surgery.
So the bulging disc.
Oh my God,
I had Sciatica so bad y'all.
I couldn't even walk when you were
hanging.
He did I have the reverse hyper machine.
The bank when you were here?
Yes.
You did?
Yeah.
What do you think about those?
Have you used those at all?
I have,
but the strength curve I think I told
you is off because right where your,
your glutes and your lower back or in
the weakest part of the curve,
the resistance is at its highest.
Right?
I see what you're saying.
Yeah.
You know,
you'd almost be better off putting ankle
weights on and just doing a reverse leg
raises.
Man,
I just love it though,
for a decompression of the spine and
strengthening the,
the lower back area.
I mean that my whole back area is just
so thick and strong from doing that.
That exercise,
it gives me a lot of relief.
I'm a,
I'm a big fan of that machine.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm not against it per se.
Uh,
I think there is this as good if not
better exercises that you can use
because I mean,
you know,
in my case,
I,
I can't travel with a reverse hyper.
Yeah,
you'd have a hard time checking that
thing.
I'll tell you what I do enjoy is the,
uh,
a 45 degree,
a back extension bench where you do back
extensions.
Fantastic exercise is that called Roman
chairs?
That was quite a Roman share,
but it's kind of along those lines.
I'm not talking about the glute ham
raises.
I'm actually talking about 45 degree
extension.
Uh,
I,
I was at Arthur Jones ranch when he was
doing his experiments with Fedex,
which was a,
uh,
a machine for back rehabilitation.
And the medic studies is doing it with
this Dr Wayne Pollack From University of
Florida medical school and they found
that people's backs are pretty
undeveloped and pretty weak and it can
cause a lot of problems.
So they were trying to invent a machine
to work that area,
but the freaking machines were like
$50,000.
It was ridiculous.
You know,
you're getting all of these electrical
feed out and all this stuff.
So I said to Arthur,
I said,
surely there must be a very simple
exercise that you could do that would
give you really,
really good results.
Because he was basically poopooing most
back exercises is not really working the
back.
Most of them work the glutes and the
hamstrings.
I kettlebell swings or deadlift more
gluten hamster.
So he said the back extension,
he says that would come as close.
And I started religiously practicing
back extension and man attire.
That's one area of my back.
That was always strong right up until
that point where I did those abdominal
rollouts.
That was the first package driver.
Hey,
how'd you get over that?
Well,
I went to a,
a raw for.
I had this woman that was actually a
professor at the Rolf Institute,
you know,
they,
they do circuits really good hands on
rover.
She was the one that I heard the word
surgery.
C'Mon Bruh.
Bath,
because she was pretty much anti surgery
as a first time I ever heard someone
say,
oh Steve,
you really did it this time.
I don't know whether I can help you.
Really.
You really messed your backup.
I'm going to try,
but I can't guarantee anything.
So she would put me on their table like
in a tense position where the table goes
like this with my bent or listening
readily,
taking your fingers and trying to rotate
the vertebrae back into position.
And then I was going to this guy for
pain.
I didn't want to take painkillers.
This Dr.
Frank Goo and Philadelphia and art
straight a.
He was shooting me with the needles,
acupuncture,
acupuncture for pain relief.
And I would walk in absolute agony and I
would walk out probably 60 to 70 percent
reduction in the paint and it would last
for a day or two and then he'll come
back of course.
But uh,
I was just doing it just to get out of
pain and over the course of say how many
sessions was it?
It was like eight sessions by the
eighth,
eighth session.
All of a sudden I woke up one day and
the pain was completely so slowly
relaxing in the disc was going back in,
finally squirted back in the stretching.
Anything like I was in a back chair,
uh,
I used to be the trainer for the owners
of the Philadelphia Eagles.
The Jeff occurred scene,
or they're divorced now,
but jeff's still owns the Philadelphia
team.
He used to have all these really cool
nifty devices because he suffered a lot
from back.
It was a chair that you sit on a sling,
like this playground swings with these
two clamps and grab you underneath your
armpits and clamp.
Right?
So your clamped,
you can adjust it and then you slowly
release the slang.
So you're just basically sitting with
your back completely just hanging there
from your armpits.
Huh.
And I would sit there and watch tv for
an hour or so with my back in this
traction.
That really gave me a lot of relief.
Yeah.
Despite the decompression.
The back chair,
it was a really expensive thing.
I just borrowed it.
I borrowed his for like a couple months.
Man,
that thing really helped.
What do you think about those?
Like where those hangups were you like
those?
I do a.
I didn't have the table where the room
for it at the time,
although I do like it.
I did have an inversion boots that I
used to hang off,
pull up on.
My problem was with the Sciatic.
I couldn't get into the position.
It was just too painful.
I had to,
you know,
I was in two minds are so far gone so
far gone.
Everything was killing me,
but once it went away it was like,
it never happened.
Never happened.
But you know,
despite that I didn't stop training.
I was still doing super slow a machine.
We're pulldowns and chest presses and
interestingly enough with that injury,
riding the Schwinn Airdyne,
you know,
those air bikes with the handles that
did hurt,
it actually felt good.
I would feel good for like 30,
40 minutes after that workout with zero
pain and then it would slowly come back
on mega.
Those airdyne machine seemed to be like
a really popular exercise for strength
and conditioning for fighters.
Lot of wrestlers use them because I'll
tell you a man's.
The faster you go,
the harder it is.
The air displacement.
The thing that's so cool about it is
you're getting both upper and lower
body.
Yeah.
So it's not just lower body aerobics.
Your whole body's involved in like a
strength endurance.
Do those bother you with your shoulder
leave shoulder?
Any kind of vertical movement?
I mean horizontal movement in price,
the overhead press that,
but interestingly enough I can still do
Hindu pushups.
That is interesting.
It's the angle I can angle it and also,
you know,
corkscrewing the hands gripping a,
activating the lattes and all that kind
of stuff can really keep you out of
pain.
Steve,
we just did three hours.
Holy Shit.
Flew by.
Wow Man.
I know you have this video though.
Tell people about this video,
your isometric video.
I just came out with my second isometric
because I was so thrilled with the first
one.
Uh,
I started looking deeper and isometrics
and I found these old school techniques
that I've made an advanced isometric a
video.
So is it a war,
a full workout,
and go through it.
What I did was in the first one I had
either yielding or overcoming
isometrics.
Here for vans,
guys are really strong like yourself.
I combine yielding,
yielding,
and overcoming isometrics in the same
exercise.
And Boy,
I'll tell ya,
even an Olympic athlete could,
could get a full workout in a hotel room
with virtually no equipment.
Just your Jujitsu belt is all you'd
really neat.
Dude,
you would know you had a workout.
Very safe,
no chance of.
I mean,
of course some Ada could screw it up and
get himself hurt,
but the chance of hurting yourself with
isometrics is virtually none.
Good way to also work around an injury.
You know,
if you have a foot,
ankle,
knee,
elbow,
and you could still do isometrics,
uh,
you could even potentially do isometrics
if you're in bed.
You know,
let's say you had an injury in a car
accident where you could actually keep
your muscles in shape laying in bed.
Whoa.
It's pretty cool stuff.
Where can people get it?
How do they get it?
The website is maxwell s c Dot Com.
S as in strength,
C as in conditioning,
Maxwell,
SC.com.
And uh,
I think,
yeah.
Uh,
oh yeah,
there's a link to the page.
Uh,
let's see.
Maxwell SC training,
is that what you say?
Maxwell [inaudible] dot com.
Yeah.
See Dot com.
Really good video.
I put a lot.
I did.
I shot it in a Malvasia Jitsu and it's
really,
uh,
one of the best ones I've ever done.
Alright,
beautiful.
And people want to get ahold of you on
twitter.
It's twitter.
Steve Maxwell.
Sc.
Yup.
So you track all that jazz.
Instagram feed the media machine,
baby immediate machine he had got.
Thank you brother.
I appreciate you being on man.
Thanks for having me again.
Appreciate.
All right friends.
We'll be back tomorrow.
See you soon.
Bye.