The joe rogan experience.
You know,
I have to sit back and all the time and
try to think for myself that
you,
you've,
I love my library,
that I have all the books within it.
I love the cars that I have.
I love the relationships that I have,
but there's a give her instead of the
relationship,
but just the things and it's like these
are all great things,
but if I don't have them,
I am still me.
I still have everything that I need in
this world.
I don't like to think about them being
lost,
destroyed.
I certainly hate the idea of it being
destroyed because he was,
it wasn't in my hands.
I'd like them to still exist for others,
but without them.
I'm no different than who I am now.
And I guess that's kind of a thinking of
like the Stoics,
uh,
you've been more defined by your
accomplishments and your thinking and
your philosophy.
There's lots of things that people,
obviously they couldn't know about me.
They,
it,
because it's not the kind of thing that
is,
is just my who I am.
Right.
And I don't need someone to know whether
or not I'm smart or whether or not I
know this or whether or not I can do
that.
It's like I'll do it when I need to do
it and I,
I have to try and look to see that I
have my own inner peace is based on my
own self knowledge and knowledge also
that I am lacking,
that I can be better,
that I,
and if I want to,
I can choose to.
And those days that I don't,
it was a choice not to be better.
It wasn't that I couldn't because even
going and failing like we talked about
before is a worthwhile endeavor because
it will move you towards either a
eventually getting there or b,
that it's not something that's going to
be yours,
but you know what it is and you know
what it takes to get there.
And that's a different perspective
altogether and
okay,
that is where I feel like that's where I
can be okay in this world and deal in,
in.
There's all kinds of things that you can
draw your focus and really eat at you
and bother you and you're giving weight
to these things and allowing them to
have an effect on you and that's
natural.
That's a normal thing and it's easy to
fall into.
But if you can be okay with all right,
if all I'm left with is just me and what
I have,
if I no longer have anything,
no,
no more luxuries,
no more this,
no more of that.
Can you be okay with that?
You know,
what kind of life would you make of
this?
And I like to think the same one I have
now.
You can pick me up here,
take all my shit away,
throw me some other part of the world,
the third world country and it will be
jarring.
It will be difficult and there'll be
some lament of course,
but I will continue to be who I am.
I will see what is necessary to,
to communicate with others and to
continue to propagate this that I'm
trying to create in me.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
Did of the new,
have you ever been a place where it felt
weird?
We found out that someone died there.
You ever been in a place where you felt
the presence of it in?
That felt weird
because you know some violence was going
to pop off and I knew it,
right?
Oh yeah.
I was like,
let's get the fuck outta here.
Right.
As you can tell,
you can feel that somebody's dying.
No.
I was at a concert once in a brawl broke
out and I quit.
I was a security guard and a,
I was a neil young concert and it broke
out and I put a Hoodie on.
I zipped it up and covered my security
outfit.
I'd walk right the fuck out of there.
I was like,
you out of your fucking mind,
jumping into this fray,
getting clocked in the head by somebody.
Like people were fighting and they were
there.
They canceled the show and kicked
everybody out.
People are lighting fires.
I was at a,
what was it?
Just not this odd vibe awards when when
Dr Dre got jumped at it and a young buck
stabbed a guy.
Oh,
I was there.
Wow.
And I was doing a show for UPN and this
was back when upn was still a network
and a one of the execs from upn was
there with her young son.
He will who wanted to see all the
rappers and he's sitting at the table
with us and I saw like the g unit group
come in.
Then I sort of death row guys come in
and I saw drays group commit and I'm
sitting there and I tell,
I forgot to get lady's name.
I said,
hey,
you might want to get your kid out of
here.
Something's about to go down.
Wow.
And she's like,
what do you mean?
I'm like,
it's about to,
it's about to go.
And she's like,
he's so excited.
He wanted to see dre and he loves 50
sending them,
listen,
get this kid.
It was a little white kid to them.
Oh my God,
there's,
can I go say hi and I'm like,
you get them out of here.
And when it's like the second time I
said it like,
Yo,
you might want to really get them out of
it.
It's going to pop off.
Boom.
Dre gets punched in the face,
Malay young bucks stabs guy.
And I'm like,
I told you Jesus.
And like two days later on set,
she's just like,
how did you know that?
I'm like,
I know that.
I know the energy in the room.
I could feel it.
I've been around it too many times.
That's a crazy feeling to when people
are about to do something with this.
Yeah.
You see them,
you see them walk,
you see the look.
You know,
it's like,
it's sad,
but it's true.
Like when you grow up in the hood,
you have that instinct.
You have that,
that look,
you look at a guy walked past,
you would one time and you look at,
look around the room and okay,
it's about to go.
It's about to go.
People that have never experienced that
probably wouldn't know what to do.
Right.
They wouldn't,
they would think nothing of it like that
lady.
Like she never seen those signs before.
Yeah,
I've been on the road.
It's uh,
this was recently,
like maybe three months,
four months ago.
I had a my feature at my feature comic
with me,
he's from Chicago actually and we're in
a club after the show and it's a couple
of guys talking in the corner and I said
something to a girl,
she's like,
Hey Tony Rock and have a little small
talk and she walks over to the group of
guys and one guy walks over and stands
at the end of the bar here and one guy
stands ended up out here and I turned to
my friend Dave and I go,
Yo,
you ever been a fight in a ball before?
And he said No.
I said,
get ready motherfucker.
You got to be in one cause I saw it,
Jesus.
And then third guy comes over.
So funny,
the third guy comes over and he's like,
Oh shit,
you are a comedian.
And I said,
yeah.
He said,
I thought that was you was over there
talking and I was like,
I thought that was the comedian guy and
he's got a good picture man.
I took a picture with him and he's
called all the guy,
but like,
yeah,
was was comedian.
It was him that was like,
he kinda just squashed it cause he,
I guess they didn't know who I was.
Oh,
it was going to go,
but because I said something to the
girl,
oh no,
it was the comedian is hit.
And I'm like,
hey fellows,
what's up now?
I,
you know,
I turned into the community like,
what's up guys?
I got to do and y'all,
all right,
what'd you guys need to drink?
Let's do a round of shots,
you know?
Oh man,
Dave's like,
that's done all that.
And I'm like,
I know mother fuckers going to go.
It was going to go.
Oh yeah.
If he ain't never been around violent
people,
you probably don't smell that vibe.
Right.
You smell that vibe.
Who knows who's on steroids.
When you saw it,
it came through,
you know,
the guys that kind of like,
their body's changed some of the people
who dropped off radically.
Yeah.
So quick,
really quick.
It's like,
whoo,
I never thought,
yeah,
well not just change,
but change to the point where like
you're not even the same person.
Yeah.
You're like doing an mph and the guys in
their 20s doing them an impression of
who they were just a couple of years ago
on the sauce.
Yeah.
Shit's happening man.
Well he got caught up in a band.
I'm snitching.
I saw the thing was he was the golden
snitch.
I,
he's a Mac.
He sent it to me.
He was texting me as well.
Novitsky he's a good guy,
man.
He's just like,
he's got a bad reputation from a lot of
people.
Like it'd be cool with them cause I know
me and I'm not cheating.
I'm not a guy that
now he's,
what is his official title?
It's like athletes.
Those how would cheat on,
wouldn't be hanging around him like the
way I would or wouldn't be as friendly
with them because they didn't want him
sniffing around.
Well he's there to make sure that
someone doesn't cheat on youtube though.
100% and I'm like,
please,
I'm,
I'm not mad at it.
Yeah.
What's that?
Oh,
was we competed?
What does it say?
The Golden Jeffrey.
John Devinsky.
The golden snitch is the vice president
of athlete health and performance for
the UFC.
Holy Shit,
Brendan Show Up.
Made it.
Brendan Schaub living.
When did you smoke weed?
You ever get paranoid?
One time I did an edible.
I ate too much.
So you know Jim,
our neighbors.
Sure.
A very funny comic.
He gave me an edible one time and this
was before like anybody could just walk
into a dispensary.
Like,
cause now you just have to show your id
and you can get anything from the
dispensary.
But this was when you had to have a,
a card.
So he went in and got it for me and it
was this lemon bar that said award
winning on it.
And me being the weed novice,
I was like,
oh this is going to be award winning
because of the taste.
Right.
It's like,
I was like,
this is like a Paula deen recipe.
And so
I ate like half of it and I was by
myself and I woke up,
I was laying down and I was in my bed
and I sat up and I said,
am I talking to myself?
I'm not talking to myself.
Oh my God,
I am talking to myself.
I'm not talking to myself.
I am and I was saying this out loud.
I have to check.
I went on my phone to get on twitter to
see them,
make sure the world was still happening
because I was like,
I felt like I was in some weird twilight
zone.
It was,
yeah,
it was awful.
So I got on there and then I made my
forced myself to go to sleep because I
was like,
I can't be awake like this.
So I forced myself to go to sleep.
I woke up the next morning,
I was still high for like five more
hours.
It was awful.
Yeah.
I gave my friend edible and he called me
up a day later and said,
I'm still high a day later if you don't
know what you're doing with it.
Because I had a conversation with
someone else the other day and they were
like,
I ate there,
I for some Rice Krispie treats and I was
like,
why would you eat four of them?
He called the cops,
call the cops and then checked him.
Set you like went to a hospital because
he thought he was dying.
Do you ever see the one where it was a
nine one one call?
The cops took weed from these people.
They pulled them over and then the cops
use the weed to make pot brownies and
then they ate the pot brownies and they
called nine one on themselves.
They called for an ambulance.
They said there were dying.
Please send help.
Time's moving very slowly.
But what's hilarious is it's a fucking
nine one one call from a cop from a cop
and the cop is calling to get an
ambulance.
Can we say the time is moving slowly and
they stole the weed from these fucking
kids that they pulled over.
The whole thing is just,
it's brilliant.
It's so funny.
Oh Man.
It's one of my all time favorite nine
one one calls cause it's just so sad.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Can,
can you,
can you please send help times moving
very slowly.
What to play it as I was looking up an
article about it,
uh,
the cop had to,
he resigned before he got in trouble
for,
he resigned.
Taking the weed and be using it so he
quit.
Yeah.
That's probably good movement as part of
you at that point,
you kind of have to,
yeah.
He called nine one one and we're talking
about in a podcast years later,
everybody's heard that.
Yeah,
I didn't.
You'd never that fucking a guarantee.
The video is probably been played a
million times.
Easily more than a million.
Do you have a jamie?
Yeah.
I just,
I found this a shorter version.
Okay.
Listen to this.
Poor fucked.
Just think about this and to save
marijuana.
I don't know if they had something in
it.
Hey,
police and rescue.
You guys have fever?
No,
I'm just,
I think we're dying.
Oh,
how much did you guys have?
I Dunno.
We made brownies and I think what that
time is going by really,
really,
really low
lady laughing.
See,
pot is something that even when you're
having an overdose,
people laugh at you.
Okay.