Is that it?
And we really live.
Let's see.
Let's see if it works.
Boy,
does the Internet here sucks.
So high.
I know you are,
but you're also on the air.
So hold on.
I'm going to miss for this.
Hold on folks.
I'm going to log in,
see the little spout,
these waters anywhere.
Well,
excellent.
This is the longest,
most unprofessional pause in the history
of my podcast career,
but I had to do it because uh,
uh,
Jamie's running the mic here,
so we're making sure that everything is
going well.
It seems like we're live and online.
This episode of Joe Rogan Experience
Podcast is brought to you by
audible.com.
Uh,
if you've never been to audible,
they have thousands and thousands of
audio books available for download and
they have one thing that's really cool.
It's a whisper sync,
a application for the kindle fire hd.
And what it is,
is the way it works,
you're reading a book,
say you stopped on page 32 and you go to
sleep,
but when you get up in the morning and
get in your car,
it syncs up to your cell phone.
So it automatically starts an audio
version of the book right where you left
off.
That's a good idea.
So he says,
can you say that one more time?
There's Brian.
Katelyn.
My pain.
There's an application called whisper
sync for in.
The way it works is when you,
uh,
you have one of those Amazon kindle hds,
you those bad ass.
Okay.
Then you can use this when you're
reading a book on it.
You,
if they,
if it has a companion audio book with
this whisper singing allows you to sync
it up to your smartphone.
So you have a smartphone,
iphone,
whenever you have syncs it up.
So then when you get in the car it
starts playing audio companion to the
book you're reading.
That's,
I've always wanted that.
I read by a professional actor.
Yeah.
I listened to two competing versions
though because listening to books a
little bit different than reading it.
So you'd be getting parts that you
listened to parts that you read?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It can be good unless the guy sucks at
reading books.
Like you ever read A.
I
know,
but I would love it man.
You burned through way more books.
Oh yeah.
Wait,
because you don't want to start a new
one.
Sometimes you just want to keep doing
what you're doing
and it makes use of time and you know,
in,
in traffic,
and I listen books all the time.
If you're,
if you're one of those elliptical
riders,
just get on that thing and yeah,
it's great.
What else?
You got to a audible.
I do like it ca.
I think it's [inaudible] dot com forward
slash Joe.
I should know this right?
Let's,
uh,
let me see if I get it right.
Call a risk sync and doing that.
Dude.
It's the shit.
It's a,
it's beautiful.
I love audio books,
but I love the fact that the two of them
tie in together.
I mean,
it's just such a brilliant idea.
A lot of stuff done today.
Have the Golden Globes on tape.
Don't know if they do all cry.
Um,
but anyway,
if you go there,
I will tell you,
but my internet is fucked here.
We're getting a,
a pipe drilled into this location.
We have to get a 100 megabyte video and
audio of capable,
like constantly on fat pipe because the
will we have is dsl.
It's fucking terrible.
We're like living in the stone ages
here.
DSL.
Whenever GSA with new the hunting.
Hey,
do you ever bring a.
You bring satellite clinic.
That's right.
Yeah.
We played.
Were talking about.
I wonder what kind of radiation I got
from that.
Oh,
you'd probably be dead soon.
I've never heard of it.
Yeah,
they were here.
What's.
But the thing is no one would be able to
really afford to do that much damage to
themselves on a satellite phone until
the price comes down a little bit.
It's true.
You get in a fight with your wife on
there.
You're looking at like,
you get a fight with your wife on a
satellite.
It's expensive.
That's an expensive to fight.
You do not want to have that go to
audible.com
forward slash Joe.
And what I believe it is,
I believe you get one free audio book
and a free month.
Uh,
I wish I could read it off the website,
but like I said,
this piece of Shit Internet is not
letting us even open up webpages.
Jamie,
Jesus Christ.
We're not even uploading anything.
There it is.
Try audible three free for 30 days and
get a free audio book.
So check it out.
And I think that application is fucking
brilliant.
We're also brought to you by on it.com.
If you go to o,
n n I t enter in the codename Rogan,
you will save 10 percent off any of the
supplements.
I just keep Steven Rinella the gift
pack,
the sweet box.
I love that gift.
I thought his mind and my heart sank.
I should have done for you.
Got To be a president.
You have over to run our sweet friend
taking me hunting it.
I get you some all the time.
You can have some too.
It's just when that was the last packet.
It's Buffalo Jerky out of that one too.
What the.
We have this delicious Buffalo Jerky we
sell now.
Do you know when I got into today for
the first time my,
my,
my dear backstraps delays because I was
eating all the damn leg meat and I was
like,
God,
this is good.
This is good.
Those back straps.
Ridiculous.
You're eating all the Truman's first.
Yeah,
that's what I was doing.
Most people eat all the favorite parts
and then they did that.
That backstrap is crazy good.
It's good to work that way.
I was frying it up and butter and salt
to.
I would.
I would like to eat that forever.
Steve,
how could you forget our bear meat?
You smoked bear meat.
You know what I'm telling you?
My wife had,
we have a baby that we had a baby a
month ago and like I said,
I've been sleeping on the floor next to
the bed and asleep bagging all night.
It's just like I'm like getting
interrupted and I'm doing and I can't
remember anything.
And last night at one point I'm like,
I know I'll forget the bear me.
I should go put the bear meat in my bag
now family.
But that's,
you know,
when you started thinking about like
ours without refrigeration and I just
thought I'll just get up and to remember
it.
It's sitting there right now.
It was good to mad to the sample,
slice off it really.
What's it taste like?
Taste like really?
Well,
just the way I did it.
He's like really dense ham,
you know,
but you sound like a pursued.
Oh,
kind of thing.
But darker.
Darker,
yeah.
Do you know when you say you smoke at
that means you're not cooking it.
So I could get you a hot smoke it.
So I've Brian.
Oh,
okay.
For about a week.
And then tie it real tight,
you know,
is there a commercial version of this?
Can you get like,
no,
no one's done it,
man.
No one's done it.
Um,
you know,
there's so many.
Like when you get wild game in a
restaurant,
it's either imported,
like come from Scotland and New Zealand
and be deer.
But the domestic,
like the,
the.
I'm sorry,
the,
the indigenous animals here,
you know,
people have done wild game versions,
like you can get elk or deer,
whatever.
But I think that the bear thing,
I've never heard of anybody trying to do
commercially produced bearings of
course.
So while you can't,
you know,
you can't sell wild game,
you gotTa,
you gotTa have it be inspected and
produced in a controlled environment.
But I think that it would just be so
expensive to put weight on a bear.
How gangster would it be if you were
farming bears to eat them?
I don't have to do it would be illegal
because one time I looked into like
bear,
I had to say I wrote this article about
eating a,
our oldest article goodbye.
I went to Vietnam and did a piece about
eating dogs around the Tet holiday
because it's like really auspicious to
eat a dog in the last days of the lunar
year.
And when I was reading,
yeah,
well I was writing my article and I had
this line in there and I'm like,
you know,
of course it's illegal to sell dog meat
in the US,
but in other,
you know,
some line like that and this fact
checkers like,
well how do you know,
like,
show me where you got that.
It's illegal to sell dog meat in the US.
I'm like,
well,
I didn't.
I mean,
of course it is.
You can't sell dog meat in the US is
said,
well we need to see something you know,
you to have.
You got to back it up.
And I started looking into it in a real
way and I called someone from,
uh,
the Usta and the other things.
And there's nothing matters to like
California and New York.
It's illegal to sell dog meat.
It's like the only two states or someone
ever really pushed it.
In Michigan,
the rule is you can't sell dog meat
unless it's property labeled.
And this guy from the Usta,
now this is a conversation I had with
the guy from the Usda
and he told me this,
you said within their guidelines,
there's no reason you could not have an
inspected dog production facility.
Of course someone's going to come out to
like the minute you did it,
you'd probably have tons of people
coming after you for different reasons,
but there's nothing per se that's like
one cannot produce commercially produced
meat.
It's fascinating when we commit like
that to like being really kind to one
specific animal and that animal
domestic pets,
right?
Yeah.
Like the three horseplays,
you know,
there was three horses,
places that all got shut down some years
ago.
Now.
I think they're opening one backup.
A lot of it's just,
a lot of it is.
I think if you opened a,
you know,
dogs are very emotional for people,
if you do a movie and emotions and
people were saying when he did,
uh,
that movie,
what's it called?
Um,
road trip and Jamie Robertson,
Junius spits on Zach's dog.
That was a big conversation because how
do you get somebody who spits on a dog?
How do you then kind of get them to be
sympathetic?
And this all got an,
an awesome tangent.
I got to finish this.
Well,
we get back around to it.
I want to remember,
I want to talk about the media man.
Wolf mcquade.
Okay.
Awesome movie.
They told us everything until they kill
his dog.
His dog is.
I know everybody's going to pay anyway.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and buy some
shit.
We got a lot of cool stuff.
The end.
Use the rogue and save some money.
All right.
Hit The music.
Let's see if we could do this Jamie.
Nice Joe Rogan experience podcast.
And it looks like everything is a go
except the image.
Are you seeing the image?
Because all I'm seeing is that,
uh,
the opening screen.
You see the image
second.
Oh,
is there like a big ass delay?
Very good.
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo.
Do you see it online?
Because,
uh,
I don't see it online.
All I see is the opening screen.
It looks okay from here.
Check.
Hold on.
But
are you seeing it on ustream?
Because I knew streaming.
See it.
We'll figure this out.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Brian has a new kind of aids that he
created himself in his own body.
So don't feel sorry for him.
Not You.
I'm talking about Brian,
my employee.
Yes.
I don't know what happened to the poor
boy.
He's got got strep.
I guess apparently.
Did he?
Yeah,
he's had it before he gets it.
Stress.
Poor guy.
Uh,
so uh,
he loved little buddy.
Um,
he's a,
he's hurting right now.
I can't even talk.
That's,
that's bad flu going around,
man.
All over the news.
I didn't get a flu shot.
Did you?
I figured you did.
I think I remember you telling me
something like that.
Uh,
you know,
I think you have to keep your immune
system strong thing.
It's very,
very important,
but
I'm not,
I don't necessarily know that they've
got that whole flu shot thing down.
You know,
there's a lot of talk that people
actually get the flu because they take a
flu shot of her.
People say that because apparently it
can make you sick or weak.
The CDC was saying 64 percent effective
this year.
Sixty four percent.
Really.
I mean,
I'm talking about a bunch of mugs.
They must take bunch of mugs,
give them the flu shot and then spit on
them.
How a guy with the flu spit on him and
64 percent of those guys didn't get the
flu.
I'm completely talking out of my ass
because I don't,
I don't really.
I mean I'm sure it does some good.
And especially maybe for some people,
maybe some people could use the boost of
a vaccination,
but I think that from what I've heard,
there's so many different strains and
it's really hard for them to like to
predict which strain is think.
I think they'd give you a,
an amalgam of different ones.
What they do.
Yeah.
But usually there's one strong,
very severe flu,
whether it's swine flu or they are
supposed to be particularly severe.
So they'll,
I guess they inject you with a dead
version,
but it still give you a fever and stuff
because it's a new agent in your body
and this and that.
Fuck that.
They all come from farms.
It's like almost all of them.
I liked the chicken flu or things
jumping over from buying guns,
germs and steel.
Jared diamond says agricultural status,
breezeway,
nastier germs because animals from the
cow pox,
smallpox,
he said.
And the minute that that indigenous
hunter gatherer tribes,
because they were small,
always moving.
So and epidemics couldn't really build
into those environments.
Usually you're Kinda kinda healthy being
at 100.
And that's why I like here in this
continent,
like when they pass through the Arctic,
like Siberian stuff,
they came down and really clean.
That's right.
Because they leave there,
they all say where they are and they
move.
Whereas farmers live within their shit
man.
So that's when they would come in.
He's these big agricultural societies,
not only they have systems of
governments because they can be more and
they could grow more because they grow
their own food and stay in one place.
But they breed nasty germs,
man.
In fact,
by some accounts,
the native Americans,
by the time after Cortez came back,
our Columbus Columbus came and they were
talking about huge populations of in the
Mississippi Delta and stuff.
You know more about this.
And I do Stephen.
But then when they came back in 15
years,
nobody was there.
It was literally did.
And they think that the talent are still
doing epidemic killed off 95 percent of
Americans.
God Damn it.
But I had my flu shot though.
And I'll tell you why,
because we have like having that little
baby.
Yeah.
What I mean,
like any little thing that like any
paranoid thing I could say about having
a flu shot,
like if you came home and gave.
Yeah,
you don't want to do.
I mean like I'd rather have an increased
chance of something weird happening to
me then I don't think.
I don't think you can give the food a
little bit.
They had their mother's immune system
and the breast milk is a real breast
milk is pretty amazing.
So she probably got the flu shot through
her mom anyway.
Yeah.
It's incredible.
How quickly
brings him back from colds and stuff
like that.
There's everything there.
Little Body needs in that.
That's really insane that your body
makes food.
You know,
really when you see a woman's body
produce food,
it's a trip.
It's like really hard to wrap your head
around.
I had a buddy that would use it for
coffee creamer and stuff.
Okay.
That guy's a freak.
I talked a lot about.
I talked a lot about drinks and I talked
so much like for our first get talked so
much garbage,
but I was like,
oh,
I'm gonna drink it.
And did it,
uh,
and when the time came,
I'm going to tell you guys a story.
It's hard to get back to sucking on
those things too.
It's strange,
you know,
it's like,
once you think of them as,
oh,
it makes it where the food comes back.
I mean for the,
where the food comes out for the baby
and then all of a sudden you're like,
yeah,
maybe a couple of strange.
It's like,
wait a minute,
what is that place exactly?
That's when a man becomes a man.
When the first time he just takes,
you know,
there's like a state of grace where it's
like for like six months,
at least after she stops breastfeeding,
you leave them alone.
But you can't mess with them during the
breastfeeding phase.
That's just rude.
It's creepy when you have children,
you see a woman goes through that.
You do look at women differently.
That's for sure.
Like,
yeah,
that was my twenties,
girls were,
they were soft boys.
They were like,
oh,
look,
play.
I'll play with it.
How come you're not just like me?
Why doesn't your mind like mine?
Why can I get along with you?
What do you mean you fell asleep during
the raging bull.
Tell ranges.
Yeah.
How do you not like fighting and stuff.
You know,
but I thought that's weird,
but then you realize a completely
different.
It's totally different species,
different species.
It's,
that's my,
my take has always been that we're never
really the idea that we're gonna like
somehow or another be able to understand
what it's like to be pregnant or do we
even want to be pregnant?
The whole idea of being attracted to a
guy,
it's like so alien to us.
For Steve.
We really told this earlier,
like guys that say like we're pregnant.
He goes,
yeah,
you know,
my wife just had a baby.
Right?
How was like,
that's the way to say it.
Don't be like we just had a baby.
You didn't know we are pregnant is the
worst.
That's the worst.
We just had a baby's okay because you're
together.
I would say my wife just had a baby.
I might say we just had a baby.
I definitely wouldn't say we're pregnant
though.
That's stupid.
It's supposed to be a solidarity thing
or how about guys who have sympathetic
with their breasts hurt?
It's a guy just given up as balls way
too quick too to just ready.
He's ready to drop him off.
He's pulling on himself.
He stretched them out of themselves like
where do you want to cut?
High and low dollar brother.
Don't trust you.
You're not coming hunting with us.
Crafty Bitch.
We're pregnant.
Shut up.
Stupid.
You'll cry when the shit hits the fan.
I know you will know your brain.
Shut up the dearest smelling your
estrogen.
You will break under pressure,
bitch.
Okay.
You and your bitch tits.
You're gonna fucking sink this canoe.
Stupid.
Do you notice,
do you notice colors and fabric to.
Yeah.
What is that?
When a dude will like try to Feng Shui
Your House.
Oh Man.
You know what you really should do.
You should move all this over to here
and fuck.
Are you man.
If I go romance house,
I expect to see just fucking if the
dudes single aspect,
chaos.
Total chaos.
I came to your house one time.
It's just like literally you were 28,
your house was.
He lived.
He was doing news radio and he lived way
out in the middle of no where and and
his house was so messier than mine and
mine is massive,
but there was just nothing was nothing.
No,
no,
no.
We'll use that.
I said,
well,
why don't you get a mate?
He goes,
I don't want somebody to rummage around
rummaging around my stuff.
This is my mess.
It was a fucking psycho.
Had never seen crazy,
was great,
couldn't take care of myself,
but that's how almost every one of my
friend's houses are.
If I went over your place when you were
single,
it's the same shit.
You didn't even have a door knob.
He didn't have a door.
I did.
It.
Didn't have a door knob.
I'm not bullshitting.
He had a place in Venice and he didn't
have a fucking door knob.
Humans,
and one time while he did have a door.
Now when you run into,
I literally didn't have a door knob and
people know what's going to break into
my house telling the story about the.
And so one day he fucking wakes up and
there's a homeless lady inside his house
cooking breakfast.
Literally,
literally like,
like cooking.
She goes,
you got to call it on.
I'm like,
what do you mean I gotta go on.
I'll actually,
it wasn't.
I didn't wake up.
I came in,
I came into my neighbors go,
there's a woman in your house cooking
and I come in,
she's got a meal prepared,
she's got your pit bulls.
They're like,
hey man,
she was feeding my dogs.
Know you guys have children.
And she wasn't.
Yeah,
unfortunately it wasn't that attractive
back then though.
Listen.
But the being attractive wasn't really
on the criteria.
If you were a girl.
I was like,
all right,
I'm in.
If you go to Ari Shaffir his house,
he tells me that sometimes he doesn't
change the sheets for six months.
Skies,
dude in college.
Change my sheets.
Only one that changed girlfriend.
The only time I'd ever want.
I'd be like,
Oh yeah,
that's probably why it's actually.
If you get used to living camping style
and you're hunting all the time like you
are.
Like in college,
we kept dishes in the sink for so long
in college,
me and my two,
my two other roommates,
I swear to God that we had shit growing
out of the drain.
We had sprouts in the drain.
We'd grown fucking sprouts show you that
thing that ruined my toilet.
They ever show you the thing that
growing up there was apparently a crack
in the pipe below my toilet and a route
got in there and grew to this size of
like a Muskrat.
It was crazy.
It was like this long and it was
growing.
It's like my toilet wouldn't flush or it
would drain really slowly.
I couldn't figure what is.
It was an organism living off my shit
water and we literally live,
ring off my shit.
Water and fat
and sick.
What?
It wasn't.
It wasn't going to animal,
but it wasn't.
It was a bark.
A piece of pipe men.
Yeah.
The root grew roots are crazy,
man.
They can grow through pipes and they can
see that some editing called route
killer.
Oh yeah.
You forced on her toilet.
Somebody being like really?
Like,
but I'm so fussy now and fastidious
about my home now because at a point
like identify with your home,
you know?
Yeah.
No,
I like everything.
Just like I'd be like lining stuff up,
man.
Yeah.
And you know,
you're a father and you have children.
You don't mess.
I grew up in,
I grew up in a neat home.
Take a break and then you go.
Then you like,
act like your parents.
Kind of true.
Like I,
I kinda grew up like,
I remember one day things had to be
neat.
I got tired of the mess and things had
to be ordered and,
and simple and clear.
I don't know what in the fuck that
happened to me,
but I know it happened some one day I
was like,
just woke up.
It's messy.
I need to.
I don't know.
I got tired of the message.
Maybe it's hormonal think so.
I don't know.
I just think it's smart.
It's smart to have a clean environment
when your environment is clean and makes
you think better.
If you're completely cluttered.
That's exactly it.
Largely it's mental peace of mind when I
get up.
If I'm writing or whatever and I get up,
I can't write until the dishes and stuff
are done really.
And in a way it's like a procrastination
thing,
know,
because it helps you put stuff off.
Like if you were really digital,
diligent,
really discipline,
you'd be able just to work through the
mayhem,
you know,
for me,
I got,
everything's got to be like Nice,
buttoned up,
you know,
Jj,
Jj Abrams,
you know,
the guy has directed and written
everything created last to like every
genius and I,
I just tested for to show up.
Greg Rung Burke,
who's Heroes,
he's uh,
he's his best friend since he was three.
And then Greg's a great guy and he said
that when he pitches Jj Abrams and idea,
Jason Goes,
I don't want to hear it,
write it.
And he goes,
I know,
but I just want to hear if that,
I don't want to end it now.
And he goes,
why are you doing?
the energy that you're using right now,
all the energy that you're excited about
should be in,
in,
you should be doing this with that
energy.
Why are you not doing this with the
entity?
Why not writing that energy into the
idea?
Because this is procrastination.
You.
You're waiting for my point of view.
That's procrastination.
It's kind of cool.
Like he wastes no time.
His all his energy is is that we use for
to worry or to think about other things.
It's in its.
It goes right into his channeled under
that Jack Son of a bitch to step down
and in the last season he talked to a
pilot guy.
He dialed it in the last season I gave
up on loss because of him.
Oh,
I didn't say it.
I've been obsessed with breaking bad
man.
I'm almost done with last for a
brilliant.
I'm just fucking around about the pilot.
If he's out there,
listen,
just.
It was one episode that was ridiculous.
I forget what it was like.
They were by a puddle that brings
people back to life or something like
that and he's just standing there like,
what the fuck am I doing?
Because the last guy,
like they went off the crazy train life
and shit.
I've ever watched time traveling back
and forth.
I mean it was like,
all right,
where's the fucking polar bear man?
Whatever happened to those polar bears.
Where are those ended up being in
purgatory,
right?
Isn't that what the.
Didn't even stick around to the end.
I'm like,
whatever the wind monster.
Remember the wind monster come and fuck
everything up.
So great show,
great show.
Wondering what was going on.
It must be so hard to do some blending
that.
Do a show like that.
Just to create it.
Keep coming up with ideas.
She's just basically,
you have to keep up.
You keep it.
You have to keep surprising your
audience for years.
It was a brilliant show for years,
like a brilliant show that really left
you hanging on the edge of your seat.
I moved,
I got onto it on the DVD form though,
so I got to watch like a whole shitload
of.
Yeah,
it was awesome.
I watched like the first two seasons in
a row,
you know,
so it was great.
And then you know,
like you don't,
you don't get tortured.
I got to do that with home.
That like style a TV watch has changed
in the TV experience in a way.
Do you think so?
Yeah.
Because I think like just the idea of
every,
you know,
of a cereal being like everyone has this
cliffhanger element and there'd be like
time to anticipate,
but now I think it's largely
generational,
but now you get turned onto something
and you're like,
well,
am I going to do that?
I'll just go random and watched the
whole thing all the way through.
It's just a way different experience and
kind of like watching a little bit and
then for a week thinking about it and
watching a little bit and I think you
burn out faster,
you know,
every time I'd get into Charlotte and we
get interesting to show my wife and I
will just go netflix that or rent or
whatever and we and we burn out before
you would because it's not meant to be.
You're not supposed to sit there and
watch for half hours in a row or
something
unless you're Joe Rogan.
Do you know what I mean?
Know you can do that.
You can watch it either.
Yeah,
I'm a,
I got a problem.
And then you get eight episodes in and
you're like,
you know,
I'm over here.
I was supposed to play.
What are your favorite?
What?
Do you have a favorite TV show?
Like?
Really?
I just don't take in a lot of.
I don't take insulin,
a of TV,
but if the show I like,
I feel like they quit making them.
I watched.
I like curb your enthusiasm but I don't
watch it.
It's don't you like comedies?
I like stuff that's so far.
I like some of this is so far removed
from anything in my life or anything
that I do or think about,
you know?
And so it's just like a show like that.
You're like a comedy like that is funny
to me,
but I just don't.
I just have never been that interested
in watching TV shows.
I don't know.
I like to watch movies a lot.
So now 10 more to watch.
I'll watch a lot of foreign movies.
I don't know,
I just want stuff that's just coming at
me from way outside.
There's so many good.
Like drama,
TV shows now there's so many shows that
it's like breaking bad.
It's because it's so hard
to make movies right now.
Is that going into TV?
You're getting these like,
like that homeland show.
That's a fucking unbelievably good show.
I mean that is seen four episodes.
I'm not going to watch breaking bad.
I'm on that too.
It gets better.
Gets it,
keeps getting better.
The that shows incredible.
That's a good fucking show.
And it's like this is like a movie,
you know,
like watching like this is like movie
quality.
Whereas before you were watching like
the $6,000,000
man,
you know what I mean?
TV,
it was like filled with dog shit in the
golden age of TV and so I really think
so.
Yeah.
But the thing I always feel about tv
when I watch and dramas,
I feel like I'm watching people.
Like oftentimes I feel like it's being
written from an angle.
They don't really understand the world
they're writing about like a period
piece type shit thing.
Like the Hbo Vampire Show where it's
like,
it's like a bunch of dudes like
imagining the south.
It's like,
I got it,
it'll be the,
Oh heck,
you know what I mean?
And it just kind of to be like anything
you've ever.
And I don't know.
Yeah,
I'm not,
I don't know much about this,
but I know enough to know that it just
feels like someone picturing what it
would be like in their world.
Well,
the guy who created it,
I lived in the south.
I would have liked that
Paul was from the south and he was a gay
man in the south.
And I think if you look,
if you watch trueblood vampires,
you know,
that's his experience.
It's,
I think,
I don't mean to put.
I know Alex,
I don't want to put words in his mouth,
but I think I think it's been a vampire
in the south,
like this take place is what it was.
It felt like to be gay when you were
younger and it was a violent place,
like really can't be true,
but I think was a book or something like
that.
But I think that at the end of the day,
if you can hear so you can see so much
of what it was like to be gay as a young
boy growing up in the south,
you know,
just knowing that they can make a watch.
That's what I believe I saw thing and
that's what made that shit.
No,
I didn't,
I didn't.
I wish I was like,
I'm going to do with gender,
gender analysis of the TV show.
I find it fascinating.
I've been,
I've been really fixated on this lately.
How pussified movies and television and
getting to the point where the vampires
that we have to do not like vampires to
like they can be kind of your buddy,
you know,
they can hang out with you.
Nine.
Oh two one.
Oh,
with vampires man.
It's like why?
But why Vampires?
Like why would you want to make like
this horrific monster and change its
nature and tournament to this romantic
figure.
Like what did.
But my,
but my point is what I'm freaking out
about it.
So like this whole trend,
like that Bourne movie,
you know,
that Bourne ultimatum or the fucking is
the new dude.
No Dude,
it's pretty fucking bad ass Jeremy
Renner.
He's bad ass.
He gets no posting and the whole moving
saves.
Everybody girl's weeping.
She's all over him.
But there's never a kiss.
Never any desire on his part ever
exhibited these,
even remotely attracted to these
unbelievably hot women that he just keep
saving and they're falling in love with
him and he's just kinda like blank and
nonchalant.
Like what the fuck is the message?
They're like,
are we becoming,
we want superheroes to be robot men
there to service women and keep them
alive.
And that's like the,
the ultimate goal.
But no sex at the end of the movie.
There's sitting on a boat together,
throw it in a love interest.
Unless it was a loving,
wasn't luncheons clearly.
Yeah.
I mean he saving her.
I mean,
you know,
the idea is that he's not really a
single and she's hot.
I mean come on.
What do we.
Stupid.
We live in a really interesting
observation though,
because if you actually think about it
like the TV shows I've seen even
homeland and,
and uh,
and,
and certainly breaking bad,
the sex is,
there is nonexistent.
They,
in fact,
your heroes aren't even allowed to be
lusty or any of that stuff.
They're not allowed to be like,
holy fuck.
I don't know.
I,
I only saw the first five episodes,
so I don't know,
but they get their goal,
but it's just interesting how that,
that,
that I wonder if that's true.
It sounds,
it sounds good.
Anyway,
I just feel like there's some
pussification going on and on a giant
scale.
It's like this toning down of male
energy.
Well,
look at fucking every show on NBC
community.
All those guys have never done a pushup
day.
It's all about being well that's okay
too.
I mean that's not what bothers me.
What bothers me when I see like
suppression of Mail Shit.
Like I loved double o seven,
like the James Bond movies because he
still gets laid.
He's just a single secret agent out
there killing and he's drinking and
he's,
uh,
you know,
women want to have sex with them.
Let's do this.
Okay.
I,
I enjoy a full superhero lifestyle
movie.
I don't,
I don't want a guy who,
for whatever reason is not sexually
attracted as chicky saving.
This guy's a sociopath.
He's a fucking psycho.
He's just out there kicking ass and he
doesn't want to get laid.
You don't want them to be like monastic
to hill.
Yeah.
You mean the beginning of the movie like
comes out of the water and he's like,
it's freezing cold,
but he's naked.
He's not even fucking freaking out.
Not even shivering.
It's just so powerful.
Shriveled up.
No,
no,
no.
But it's stoker road track Kyla in some
ways as a reaction to the Victoria and
the repressive Victorian age.
So when Dracula would come and he'd be
this big handsome guy and a girl was
sleeping and he would fight her neck and
drink or blood.
It was very kind of.
The idea was she had an orgasm when she
was being sucked dry is.
It was Kinda like a very taboo book when
it came out.
It was very,
it was kind of a,
a rebuttal to how repressively sexual,
uh,
the victorians were.
And Brahm Stoker wrote sort of that,
that reaction to it.
That's interesting.
I always thought it was just a fictional
movie or book rather,
a written about a vampire.
Just an angry.
What was the connection between the Vlad
typists
because there was a vlad the impaler,
he was the original Count Dracula.
They say that the idea was,
was,
um,
based on this Hungarian,
I think maybe a prince or a warlord or
whatever,
who was an evil mother.
Probably a serial killer,
probably serial killer who,
you know,
did all kinds of horrible things.
He would cook pieces of people and eat
it in front of them.
Yeah,
he would,
uh,
he would put people on stakes.
Just,
that's what they call him,
Vlad the impaler.
He would shove stakes up their ass and
then let them slowly rive in pain and
just associate them.
He would leave them on,
on,
you know,
on these big pillars like all through
the town.
He was an unbelievable evil guy.
All the depictions and images of him or
him dining with like all these men on
stakes,
like all around you about these things.
I think it was Ivan,
the terrible in Russia when,
when,
what?
Whoever the artist was that did the
winter palace.
I think it was the winter palace like
this beautiful,
like this,
this guy.
There was a lifetime of,
you know,
20 years of his.
It's like his opus,
this great artists.
I mean if you look at it,
it's I think,
I think it's out of the winter palace to
her discharge this incredible church in
Russia and when he was done with it and
he presented it to Ivan,
the terrible Ivan,
the terrible was like this is the most
incredible thing in the world.
Thank you.
And then he took his eyes out so he
couldn't do it to anybody.
Oh Dude,
this is a good point that you couldn't
be like,
you could be a serial killer and just
getting the exact right situation where
you have a lot of power and just be able
to just do it,
but it'd just be normal.
Do you remember that woman who's
responsible for killing thousands that
she was a noble woman and she,
uh,
was a serial killer of young women?
I,
I gotta,
I gotTa pull this up on wikipedia
because it's a fucking fascinating
stories.
This lady,
um,
but they say serial codes.
There's a book called the murder room,
and the guy who specializes in sadism
and serial killers,
he wrote what's called,
kind of like the double helix of the
serial killers profile.
And he said that,
that,
that a lot of serial killers will
definitely be.
I can't camera what the word was,
but they become like,
they drink your blood,
the lowest,
the lowest rung where you're the full
fledged boogeyman.
They eat flesh and drink blood.
Elisabeth bathory,
that's the crazy bitch out of.
And what did she do?
Killed.
She killed thousands of girls.
Who Was Hungarian?
Oh yeah,
she,
they called it a blood count is
apparently she,
uh,
she just started killing chicks and
really got to love it.
And so it just torture them and killed
them and find pretty girls just torture
him and kill him,
which has killed thousands until they
finally,
they,
they didn't even kill her in the end.
They,
they locked her in a room.
They gave her like a house imprisonment.
Like she was such.
She was a royal figures too.
So I mean,
Mr.
Crazy fucking shit man.
I mean that they didn't even kill her.
She killed thousands of checks.
They don't even know how many kills say,
like unbelievably evil.
They're out there.
But uh,
yeah.
Elizabeth bathory,
that's the chick's name.
A lot of times serial killers,
like I have a particular taste like
that.
It's got to be a specific kind of
person,
you know?
Yeah.
There's something,
something that snaps,
allows you to get a thrill off of
killing a bunch of people.
And there's a weird thing that happens
to people with this whole royalty thing.
The idea of royalty is fascinating.
That's been killing me lately because I
don't know how you guys feel about
watching Americans get so gaga over the
English royal drives me nuts.
It's so stupid.
It's bad enough.
When the English student,
but what Americans do it.
Oh,
that's their version of Kim Kardashian.
It's the same fucking thing.
There's this.
Who are they?
What are their father?
Father met a count or do my duke.
He was a duke and and they were at
dinner and somebody said,
what are you doing?
He said nothing.
Nothing at all.
Anyway,
it was so natural for.
I take a stipend from the English
government anyway,
but you know,
nothing.
Of course I don't do anything.
I'm,
I'm rolling and royalty.
They get paid.
They get paid the that I believe they
get state policy.
You guys met,
you know,
Mo,
he think they get paid the shooter on a
show.
He,
he was present when he worked on Ali and
for some reason or another,
I remember how it came up,
but he was like presented to one of the
British royalty and it was like a guy
comes in and breaks down.
Okay.
When he comes in,
don't do this.
Don't do that.
Put these gloves on.
Yeah.
Somebody said that to me.
I would be like,
no,
no thank you.
No,
thank you.
Said you want,
in his defense,
he's like every like every part of you
wants to just say like no way.
No way because you're part of this other
thing.
Like you're there with a ritual and
you're with people were at work.
You kind of like,
I could make like my statement,
like I could express my liberty,
you know,
and like my,
the fact that I'm not deferential at the
expense of like all this other stuff
that's going on and he's like in the end
you just.
But it's like,
it's like,
it's like covering your head in a
synagogue.
It's like covering your shoulders.
If you're a woman in Italian church
there,
there becomes a,
there's a ritual and a protocol to
everything.
But the things that traditional with
religion,
no,
there's something much more.
It was like a much more deep seated,
but this is just strictly like I,
I'll honor you because you belong to
some lineage.
I'm not really quite sure how it came to
be and I'm not sure on the rules and
regulations how it gets passed along.
But you were picking you to now be the
one that were deferential through,
but it's actually a little cover on
American,
very everything that we don't stand for
will I get the fuck outta here with your
crown.
But in Britain,
in Britain,
they had what's called the great chain
of being.
It's very.
It was very,
very central to sort of the British
history and character
of the notion that the king,
the God was there,
the king was bottom.
Then you had the aristocracy,
then you had no ability.
Then you had the merchant class,
then you had,
you know the serfs.
Where does game of thrones fit in there?
Well,
you never stepped out of for many years.
That's why Britain was.
It benefited from the notion that they
had very strong institutions and so when
you had a royal,
a royal person that you came in contact
with,
it was very important to observe ritual
protocol and ritual sort of greeting and
interaction because it kept the wall
between you and and the royalty because
the entire society with the benefit of
the royalty.
Well,
no,
but the but also the whole society was
built on not only the,
the idea of,
of this caste system,
but also very central to the British
character was that to esteem out of your
class was actually considered heretical.
It was considered a to the detriment of
the entire community and society.
Right.
Whereas Americans were like on thinking
about his climb and the fuck out of this
whole,
you know,
what's interesting,
a lot of people that believe that a
society like ours,
or at least how ours initially was born
is only built in response to
suppression.
It's like you have to have a situation
like England where they're completely
suppressing it to the point where you're
willing to take such a great chance,
but you already have a semblance of idea
of order and society,
which is based on their system of canes.
And that's the weirdest thing is it's
almost like the only way for us to ever
gotten to a position of power or
position of,
uh,
you know,
creating a culture,
creating civilization is that somebody
had to take control and that ultimately
we are these weird fucking Alpha Apes.
And we really want to be like led by
like one person or one group or one
leader,
or at least have someone at the very top
that we can all agree to clap for.
And until we fill that goal,
then it becomes this wild fucking power
struggle.
It's like the only way we can work
together.
It's through one person.
It almost seems like what's interesting
though is the founding fathers had a
rebuttal to that.
And George Washington and most famously
when they wanted to make him king said,
I am not only going to not be the king
because we don't have kings in this
country where we have presidents that
are part of a structure,
a structure that is directly responsible
to the people.
Right?
But,
but,
um,
that,
that was sort of the idea.
And King George,
when he found out that Washington had
refused the kingship and instead went
and fucking retired was like,
that guy's the greatest guy of all the
American character.
That,
that was kind of sealed as.
That was the great example of George
Washington did.
He said,
don't ever call me king because that's.
That is exactly what we thought against
sleazy.
The exact opposite of this guy who's
running Egypt now,
who tried to turn himself into a king,
mostly most of them,
a little more sluggish and crazy.
It's so bewildering,
man.
It's so funny the way people act when
you turn,
when you turn the tide on,
man,
it's just amazing.
He's like,
oh,
now I understand what Mubarak was
fighting for.
Yeah,
he's just this right here.
That's.
That's unfortunately a great deal.
That's the biggest challenge for the
Arab nations is,
is,
is learning the benefits of democracy,
not get through that case system.
They look at Molokai in Iraq,
we basically created a Saddam light
because Molokini now has his own police
force.
The reports directly to him.
You know,
he's still.
That's why the Sudanese are setting off
bombs.
There's still whether or not he can
share power as a whole different story,
you know,
I get it with like watching the Arab
spring stuff.
I mean,
I was always skeptical of it and one
thing,
one way,
it was always kind of embarrassing,
like just understanding the history of
some of those areas,
the way Americans would so quickly
forget our allegiances and so,
you know,
we're going against Qaddafi and like
everybody's like,
yeah,
you know,
the number one us enemy could be like
for getting the.
We were doing all kinds of things
through there and you know,
and in some ways supporting Mubarak in
some ways,
you know,
later on in some ways we support them in
burke for 30 years and then so we gave
$10 and eight every year and 3 billion
year.
Yes,
every year.
But then this so quickly people.
But so quickly people wanted to make the
jump that like here's this logical
enemy,
you know?
And that was frustrating a little bit.
But the main thing is when I was
watching all that,
I wanted to be optimistic,
but I just feel like there's no way.
This is just going to be smooth
transition and there's this,
there's this competing idea like when
you're an American who's like this
competing idea we have between being
pragmatic,
you know,
like we want these countries to be such
and such way in order to secure our
interests,
but also we had this thing where it's
like the only legitimate form of
government is a democracy and as we're
going to find again and again and I'm
definitely not.
No,
definitely not an expert on rural
politics,
but we're finding again and again that
other countries being democracies isn't
always going to serve our own national
security interest.
You know,
I think that we want to think that it's
like that dovetail and it's not gonna be
that way.
Like maybe they're better off having
kings was depends on the actual actual
people on the ground in those countries
is like,
yeah,
I want to support democracy,
but then there's someone like,
you know,
collect and you're like,
that's not a democracy.
Democracy is voting for the guys.
I like.
It just depends on how you define it
because one of the things,
we're already parker,
I believe that's his name was,
is that British MP,
a part of the parliament and he.
He's walked these.
He's walked every remote village in
Afghanistan,
every remote village in Africa,
and he said he'd never been anywhere,
any,
any room,
even the most remote village in
Afghanistan.
He never met anybody.
Anybody,
no matter how strong their tribal notion
of the tribal systems,
where he never met anybody who didn't
want some say in who covered them,
so that,
that that's.
That seems to be a human,
a need and a human right
and a human compulsion to,
to have some say in who fucking
otherwise you get a guy like Ivan,
the terrible who just amassed this
power.
We all have a natural.
We all have a natural revulsion for
that.
We all have a natural kind of.
I do think you're right that human
beings need an alpha,
a leader and they always find the
leader,
but I also think at the same time they
want some say in that,
in that process and in the ongoing
process that is who governs them,
you know,
and it really feels like,
like we talked about with kids,
if you try to take a spoon out of the
hand without explaining that you need
the spoon,
they,
they'll hold onto that fucking spoon
and,
and human being seemed to have a
resistance,
a natural resistance to those that would
have power over them.
You know,
if you think you're going to be the
president and everything's going to be
smooth sailing,
you know how many haters you must have.
The moment I think that's probably half
the gray,
the gray is realizing how many fucking
people hate you.
Sure.
Those guys age badly and mean.
It can't just be this.
You make one choice,
you're going to make 50 percent of the
people happy and 50 percent of the other
people,
the way they got it carved out,
that's 51 percent.
It's like they got to carve down to 50
point one percent,
you know,
they're going to find books about you
and how much we give Egypt.
Every year they're going to write books
about you.
They're going to make up lies about you.
They're going to constantly,
every person on the opposite side of the
fence,
whether it be Democrat on your side,
repo,
whoever's on the other team they're
going after,
whatever.
No one ever does it,
and then no one ever does it for four
years.
Has maybe they have,
if they would ever done it for four
years and just said,
you know,
it wasn't for me.
No,
no,
not enjoy something like,
as much as I hate this,
I'm going to keep doing this.
I also think that whoever got you into
that position of power,
you will,
you owe them this obligation.
I always think about what George Bush
said about her,
uh,
Hurricane Katrina.
They were like,
you didn't go down to New Orleans for
five days or whatever.
And then he said,
well,
here's the problem with me going out in
New Orleans during that crisis,
if I go down to New Orleans,
I got to take 60 police cars and and,
and the resources of the city to protect
me and to escort me to the damage sites.
It costs a million dollars an hour when
you tie up a helicopter,
helicopter type of all the rescue,
all the stuff that should be given to
the people on the ground at that time.
And he said that was the catch 22.
I was going to get criticized if I land
air force one the day before.
And that's one of the examples of being
a president and you were always the idea
that you have to physically be in an
area in order to observe or to respect
the fact that a tragic incident is took
places,
observed its pageantry man,
because it's like you're playing a
psychological game.
I would always hand it to someone if you
could,
if you could make that point.
But people are like,
people are so addicted to the pageantry
of it.
They'd be like,
Oh yeah,
in order for us to recover from this,
I need to fly around in a helicopter and
have a governor show me that it's
flooded because I'm not going to believe
it.
You know?
Be Like,
oh,
you're right.
It is a visitors come to visit us
pageant trees at great word.
By the way,
I love the joke that Jeff Ross got up
from the standard.
We did this a charity and after
Hurricane Katrina and he goes,
I went down there.
It's not that bad.
Oh,
no,
fucking terrible.
But the way he said it was,
no,
it's so ridiculous.
Like that was his job.
He goes,
I don't see what the big deal lips.
No,
he was kidding.
I used,
there's a.
there's going to be a higher incidence
of those fucking gigantic.
One hundred year storm is going to be.
There already is,
man,
there's going to be even higher because
we're together and I was supposed to go
to Texas and I flew home.
I flew home for that thing,
for the,
for the.
That was sandy.
Sandy said I wasn't.
Yeah,
I was in.
I was like,
I went home to be with my family and I
was there and if you like,
if you were in my place you would and
you didn't have the news or anything,
you would adjust that mic a little windy
last night,
like a mile away or not even a mile,
a half mile away.
Cars like floating down the streets and
stuff.
But it was so crazy.
It was just like,
well no,
it just like,
because it was so much the storm search.
Right.
Don't mean like if you were,
if you got above a certain elevation,
you know,
you were fine.
It was just,
he would never have ever have known.
It was like there was a few more leaves
on the sidewalk,
but then just wow some short distance
down.
Like you dropped to a certain elevation
point.
Absolute may have been under water,
I believe before.
Anyway.
Really?
Yeah.
So the c level kind of went back to it.
That's what happened in parts of Jersey.
The he level just went back to what I
was,
you know,
it was the weirdest thing.
It wasn't just,
it was,
I mean it was just like,
it wasn't like blowing and lightening
and all.
I was just like,
the,
just the ocean come up,
I'll take that.
You know what I mean?
They said parts of Jersey in that those
areas will never be the same.
They may never come back.
There was areas it just got so wiped
over there to build something out there.
Like the odds that,
that would stay there and the eyes,
the water's not going to hit that spot
again.
I was watching some of have footage of
the uh,
that title was in Japan and how they
roll through and it looks like just
water and you think,
well it's just water.
If they take everything like cars and
boats.
That was something that haunt that
footage from.
That haunted me for the longest time.
Trying to get away from that and that in
historical perspective compared to some
of the events that we know have
happened,
like giant titles.
So they know about that Canary Islands
Shelf.
Apparently there's like a shelf in
Africa.
There's a gigantic volcanic shelf and
when it breaks off,
the fucking water comes at us and it
could go deep in on the east coast.
Many miles.
How many miles?
Yeah,
the weight,
because you're talking about essentially
a mountain falling into the ocean and
this incredible blast of energy which
carries this water,
this huge tidal wave that starts in the
middle of fucking,
you know,
wherever that is,
the Canary Islands and goes 500 miles an
hour across the ocean and then slams
into 500 miles an hour.
It's.
You could imagine.
I mean some of the catastrophes,
but there were so few.
It wasn't just last civil Muslim
civilization.
Whatever sounds good.
I made it up,
but whatever it is,
it's going to.
Yeah.
I mean,
look,
they found many,
many,
especially near Spain,
many sunken civilization.
They found the one that they were
calling it Lantis,
whether or not Atlanta was actually a
physical place,
but it's got concentric circles just
like they believe Atlanta still maybe
inspired by.
No,
not craig total because that wasn't
recorded history.
What those 1800 explosion never heard on
Earth Day,
right?
The pyro plastic glass that just feel.
I don't think it's really.
There's a general consensus.
I don't think they've reached that
conclusion with the Atlantis was asking
was whether or not I didn't.
This is troy.
Yeah.
It was real.
That's a fascinating.
Like what was troy?
Troy and troy was the guy made a bunch
of morning the California gold rush or
something went and kind of like started
mapping out what troy was a German guy.
Can't remember his name.
So is it like under contention whether
or not that's actually troy.
Yeah.
There's this guy that,
and I don't know where it's at now.
I just remember in college you're
talking about this and registered by
this guy.
This Guy German had made a bunch of
money in the California gold rush.
Then went to find any little computer
there and went in and spend too much
time trying to locate troy and they
don't think that it was over Helen,
but I was like a trade war and there's
some mention of like,
um,
some of the integral characters,
like not odysseus or,
um,
but some of the agamemnon or some of the
higher up kings,
there's some like historical allusions
to who these characters might've been to
got involved in that war,
but it wasn't like the face that
launched a thousand ships.
I think it might have been a trade
dispute,
but I'm telling you some data stuff,
man,
because I was in college in the mid
nineties,
mid to late nineties.
So that was what I knew.
Then you'll find that guys name it.
So the idea was that this guy,
uh,
he,
he believed that it wasn't fiction.
He believed that it was,
but he had devoted to him the latter
part of his life to identifying what
troy would have been.
And he had a.
He had a somewhat accepted.
When I learned about this,
he had a somewhat.
He had come to a somewhat accepted
conclusion about what troy was maybe
some of the principal characters were
involved,
were in fact like some of the people
that are discussed in the Odyssey and
the Iliad were in fact living people at
that time and they were engaged in a
large and there was a large battle in a
siege of the city and out of that was
born that legend of the siege of troy in
the story of the Iliad.
You know what's really fascinating about
like ancient Rome and ancient Greece and
these incredible
structures that they built,
is that they just all fell apart.
Like nothing's going on there now.
I mean,
I guess the people live in and having a
good time living their life,
but no one thinks to be greases almost
bankrupt.
Right?
Onto your bank.
They're fucked.
And Rome.
I mean,
Italy is just kind of hanging out in
Europe,
but if you stop and think about what,
you know,
the,
the insane society they had at one point
in time where no one anywhere else in
the world at anything comparable people
fucking people that don't work.
And people have written
books and certainly articles about how
Greece has never,
hasn't produced a whole lot of artistic
expression.
That's world class artistic expression
for three 3,500
years or whatever of our long time.
Mainly because,
you know,
you had some examples are examples,
but mainly because they have that legacy
looming over them.
You got to Athens,
the Acropolis is right there looking
over the city and humbles you.
It humbles you.
The idea of why would I do anything when
I come from,
when it's already been done,
sort of the idea is looking at us now
and uh,
she was at home with really shitty books
that I was trying to write a script and
I read faulkner and I was like,
what the fuck do I have to say about
anything?
They the great genius.
I'm reading his imagery and stuff.
And I was like,
first of all,
I don't even know.
It's the craziest.
He was such a crazy,
unbelievable writer.
Like on every level either beat,
beat you down or.
Yeah.
But I was like,
but what do I have to add to the Canon
of literature?
Zero.
Hey Bri,
you're going to run a fucking screenplay
about,
you know,
but you got to keep doing it.
You just can't think like that.
Getting be inspired.
You have to be inspired.
That can be very self defeating,
but people do think like that.
They fuck themselves.
It's a trick.
You got to just go.
You're.
If you do the work,
you have something to say,
right?
I mean your experience,
you.
Someone said to me,
he goes,
well,
you know,
listen,
I'll never be well off.
I go,
what the fuck is terrible?
I can even say that.
How can those words even come out of
your mouth?
I'll never be well off.
That's it.
You tap,
you're done.
Just gonna like the
coast from they've been to.
They've allowed other people to define
them.
Lot of times that's how you define
yourself and you hold onto that
definition.
Those lines become very strong because
trying to step over them is too scary.
It's you've been disappointed too many
times and you've given up,
but it's just.
It's all false belief system.
Yeah,
and it's how much energy do you have?
How many did you do?
Have enough energy to really pursue.
Yeah,
but energy,
I transfer energy to being something
called inspiration you may have or you
have no energy unless you,
unless somebody provides you with a
blueprint or the inspiration to do so.
Right?
You know,
one of the things they say is that,
um,
if,
if you can,
you can,
a lot of times you can,
uh,
you can motivate yourself by,
by defining on what you're going to lose
as opposed to what you're going to be.
Again,
we're really good at dealing with
things.
I didn't get that and then we just come.
But they,
they say that psychologist sometimes
they'll tell you what do you.
If you don't do this thing that you want
to do,
what do you actually lose?
What are you not going to get?
What are you going to lose that you
already have?
And when you start framing somebody in a
motivational incentives that way they
will tend to.
They will tend to work a lot harder
all the time.
And I'm always motivated.
I'm always motivated by what you're
gonna lose as opposed to a man because I
always feel like,
like I've carved out an existence that's
way better than I would imagine out of
carved out,
you know what I mean?
So it's like I'm not motivated,
but what I didn't get,
I'm always motivated in a way,
but what I did get,
now I want to do something like I want
to be spending much time outside,
I won't be able to on a lot.
And then now it's not that I don't feel
like I got gypped.
I'm like,
man,
I got to hang on to.
Well you're not sweet situation to hang
onto it.
It's kind of scary as anything.
It's,
it's as scary as striving toward
something.
But.
Well I did
to realize that like I went and bought
some mats and I,
I'm,
I'm enrolling with my buddy and my
garage and I was like,
why didn't you.
That's like what?
He goes,
what do you want to do?
Because you don't want to lose.
I don't want to gain my black belt.
I think,
I don't know,
but I don't want to lose.
I don't want to feel like I lose my
manhood and I think that's what I'm kind
of working through.
Eight.
Yeah.
I think maybe I'm holding onto something
something and I'm trying to.
What I'm doing in my garage for an hour
like I did the other day.
I think I'm trying not to lose something
as opposed to gaining something.
Maybe.
I don't know.
Maybe we're just.
Maybe I'm kind of playing.
This is a great.
I'm glad I came just for that little bit
of insight about like,
you know how to have bill loser losers
by the prospect of lost rather than
motivated by the prospect of loss rather
than motivated by what you might get.
That's right.
Fucking man up and do the work and show
your bullshit mouth talking nonsense.
Just fucking do it.
If you want to get better at wrestling
and Jujitsu,
do it because it's fun.
Stop with all this nonsense.
You're running your own brain because I
like horse shit.
Am I doing this because I'm afraid to
lose?
Or you're going to write poetry now to
bring me flowers,
bitch until you stuck.
Now you squash my poetic spirit is
talking nonsense about to break into a
song.
Rolling because it's fun.
Stupid.
You're a monkey.
Monkeys like to choke each other.
It's awesome times.
Whatever.
Why am I doing?
Come on,
man.
You can waste slipper.
You can waste your fucking energy.
What?
Why?
Why pursue these things?
I enjoy.
Just fucking pursue the things.
You enjoy it.
That's why you got to get rid of that
fucking Prius.
Hey man,
no,
no.
You don't want to drive that car.
I know.
I'm trying to talk him into a shelby
Mustang.
I'm telling him that he has done his
stand at this stage of life that we in
the cars that are available to you right
now or like little ride.
Give me.
Take three cars to get and make them
practical.
Fucking practical.
Whore mouth.
This is what you need.
You need a shelby Mustang.
The new one run your engine and when
you're stuck in traffic or something
like,
oh,
you want to hear it?
You want to be able to hear it.
You want to be able to hear the rumble
under this blue bubble.
It bring you back to your childhood.
It will give you a burst of endorphins
as you drive it.
A make you feel you never had one.
That's why.
Because you never had one.
You don't even trust me thinking like,
do I love this car?
Because I'm afraid of losing something.
That's it.
Yeah.
That's what you think.
This,
that's an old [inaudible] 69.
No,
no,
no.
Uh,
I have,
uh,
one of the modern ones.
I have a modern one.
The shelby gt 500.
There's a new one that's coming out now
that has 606.
Two horsepower.
Am I going to do with that thing?
Oh,
you're going to enjoy the fuck out of
it.
That's what you're gonna do that.
Because I think about horsepower in
terms of boats.
It looks like when you have a $600,
that's a lot of horse preposterous car
for a human being to drive.
Absolutely.
Proportionately.
Not Getting that,
but give me something else to get that
just to just to fucking for once in your
life.
Just have something like that and
understand what the fuck is going on.
I'm trying to tell you about something
awesome and you'll let go and want to be
awesome.
I know what you like.
Stupid.
I just have never done one.
This motivation.
You're tapping into my 12 year old
psyche.
Me and him have.
You just don't want to be as
consumptive.
Now I just know what Joe's doing.
Yeah.
I'm just lazy,
but just doing justice.
Just tapping into my.
He's like,
come on,
get to fucking get that dog.
Get the one that's going to now go
heavier more and more and I'm like this.
I'm like,
no.
I'm a naturally moderate person.
Stopped and he's like,
he's always behind me going,
come on,
push,
push.
He's the.
He's my canary in the coal mine.
We have.
We've had fun for years.
Their greatest.
We've had a good time,
my friend,
but I always end up coming around.
We don't want to tell you about the
show.
Wait,
wait,
don't tell me.
Wait,
wait,
don't tell me on NPR quiz show,
but there's the head of the thing about
the news.
I want to tell you,
this guy apparently I might have got
this wrong,
but I don't think I did last week.
They were talking about too weird.
Nine slash 11 calls that came in and a
guy called nine one one because it's a
hamster had had babies.
Apparently some guy last be called nine
one one because he saw a big foot.
Oh my God.
So I think that would be the correct
move if he really did.
Now let's say now I know you don't
believe in big foot.
I've talked to him.
You've talked to big foot.
No.
Your theory about why big foot can exist
because he has.
He has no hair on his top of his feet
and his hands.
Right.
That's someone else.
Mine is just that he can't exist because
he would have.
There would be dead ones laying around
known.
Then like every other thing,
that's how many times have you ever seen
like a dead mountain lion?
Have you seen him?
Like just.
I mean,
no,
I mean not ones you shot.
I mean,
have you ever run across one that you
found that it just died of natural
causes or.
I'd like to lie to you and say that I
have found lions died of natural causes,
but I have not found natural causes,
but
um,
I've seen them in the wild three times.
Three times.
Yeah.
The,
I mean I don't,
I don't have any chips in the sasquatch
camp,
but Jane Goodall says that she believes
that it exists and that's fascinating to
me.
She didn't say was that there's a
species we and she thinks it's a
gigantic pool.
What about those ones?
So what more do we know about those ones
in the Congo that are totally different
animals,
chimps?
Jane Goodall believes,
I'm pretty sure is that it's a gigantic
pythagoras,
which was a real animal existed in Asia.
The most recent example of it was
100,000
years ago.
So the idea is that we think is extinct,
but it might not have been because we
know it coexisted with people.
And really it wasn't discovered,
I think until the 19 twenties who's,
I think it was discovered some somewhere
in early 19 hundreds.
There was a guy who came into apothecary
shop where they would sell like a
fucking home remedies and shit,
ground goat,
Dick and stuff like that.
Chinese places are really into that and
they had this giant primate tooth and
this guy examined it.
He said,
well,
what the fuck is this?
Well,
it turned out it was a totally different
species and nobody ever heard of.
And it's an eight foot bipedal primate
that buried.
It's young are buried.
It's dead rather.
Wow.
Yeah.
They believed they stack their dead.
So the,
the idea that this thing existed
alongside human beings and it really
did.
I love how they can,
how they can like take a piece of bone
and construct an entire.
But thanks.
They often can't.
I mean,
you can tell a lot.
There was a lot.
I mean like as in I don't criticize
people,
like a lot of people get off on looking
at mistakes,
you know,
that scientists have made like,
oh,
they thought this.
And other times it's like they're trying
to put together a cohesive narrative and
it's in the scientific process is always
inviting people to add on and make
corrections.
But some people are fixed on this idea
that if you can't get everything exactly
right the first time,
you have no business even dabbling in.
So I'm like,
when people have made mistakes in
talking about like lineages,
I'm not down on them,
I don't like glorifying the mistakes to
point out that it's all few tile and you
know,
it's all bs but.
But they make mistakes.
Mistakes are made and I think you've got
to continue chipping away at it and can
you try to add to it.
But the,
but the big foot thing of all the
species that we have,
the endangered species that we have in
talking about North America,
the ones that have,
that we knew we had and they went away,
went away.
And in some of the ones that we knew
were hanging on,
we still have a big problem with
mortality on those things.
And we find them.
You have very few Florida panthers every
year they're getting hit on the highway.
Thank God.
Kill those creepy Fox.
Hey dog eating assholes.
Dog Eaten.
How would you like?
Not like panthers.
Eight.
My dog.
Dog to him.
The line here?
Yeah.
No,
that's awesome.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
But
they're killers.
They're fucking killers.
They shouldn't be in America.
Sorry.
Two minutes.
None of them that I'm not tolerate.
Yeah.
Anything that could kill me.
You go fuck yourself.
If it might eat you one day.
Did you ever see that video of the woman
in Russia where she's in town in Russia
and a polar bear,
it's made its way into the town,
isn't attacking her and everyone's
screaming and throwing shit at the bear.
Ever seen that Jamie?
Oh Dude.
Yeah.
Woman attacked by a polar bear in
Russia.
A tough fucking.
It's terrifying.
The bears just legit.
No 100 percent.
And she got away.
She got away because it got through like
it looks like you threw a tire iron at,
at the bear and the clunk the bear and
the bear just freaked out and ran away.
Wow.
And she,
uh,
she had her pants down and she's like
pulling her pants on,
but trying to get away the bear like,
just launched it.
Why wasn't he over there trying to help
her out?
They were all yelling.
They're in apartment buildings.
They were terrified film and everything
instead of getting in there.
And.
Well,
that's when you don't want to get eaten,
you know,
if they don't have guns,
if I see a polar bear,
polar bear,
I'm running away guys.
I love you all see a polar bear.
And he and he started gouging you with
these,
right?
I would never be like,
oh,
I'm going to make a movie of this.
It's really flattering on his graph to
compare.
Her shoulders is a big gym.
I winced brian trying to eat people.
This is the woman to see the,
um,
the middle of it to that lady right
there.
It's like near that fence.
Watch this.
This is really fucked up,
man.
She's ducking right now here.
Cozy bear.
Look at the shit.
Look at this ad is a fucking polar bear
man.
And so see,
or some guy throws something and hits
them.
That's a young poet.
But it's big enough dude.
Then they're little babies.
They will fuck you up.
That shit got jacked and look at her.
She's getting up and her pants are all
fucked up.
Yeah.
Run girl run.
She's,
I think she's really hurt.
That's a scary ass.
It's
that thing just took a couple of nips in
a village.
Just came into a village,
you know?
Yeah.
They don't fuck around there.
They eat everything that moves.
That's polar.
Bears are way scarier,
right?
That's what they're worried about.
That hybrid.
The hybrid between the polar keep
turning up.
I got shot one now.
Really?
There's a lot of them now though.
Why?
They didn't know they know about it.
Okay.
Steve.
This is a.
they're not,
they're not viable.
They're not sexually violent.
Right.
So this is a global warming thing.
Is that what's going on?
I know that that the theory I'm familiar
with is people suggested it might begin
to happen more as you lose as the polar
ice cap recedes and polar bears aren't
able to spend as much time out on the
CIS that they'll be coming inland.
More so.
I think there's been.
My understanding again is there's been
an increase in the distance inland that
people have been encountering some bears
and it's a greater likelihood of
bringing polar bears into what would be
traditionally like interior grizzly and
saw
some hybrids have turned up,
but I don't know.
They're not viable and I don't know if
anyone knows like in a bulletproof way
that this wasn't happening before and
it's happening now.
But I think just in a logical sense,
if bear,
if there's not going to be the
availability of sea ice,
you know,
bears are going to spend more time on
ground which is going to bring them
into.
You know,
when grizzly bears are out of
hibernation in the spring is going to
bring them into more contact so that as
people say,
but a guy,
you know,
there was a guy not know.
It was a couple of years ago,
a shot one,
and it was legit.
He knew it was weird when he shot it and
took it in.
He was a native guy that gives it a shot
and it was checked out and that's what
it was.
What I want to know when we go hunting
in Alaska,
I'll be calling anywhere where there are
hybrid,
barest because I will come with an
arsenal,
my friend.
I don't know that you can really make
the case that hybrid bears.
I don't know that there's a case we
made.
The hybrid bears are more dangerous than
900.
Well guess what?
Since you can't make the case.
I'm going to call.
How about I make the case at all?
Bears are fucking dangerous.
What are you talking about,
man?
What do you like?
Oh,
it's because he's only a grizzly.
Fucking look at you.
Whatever.
Cold and fairs week.
Silly Bitch.
I'm going to leave some honey and you
can just go to that.
I'll use if we don't.
If we go up there would probably be
okay.
It depends.
Like if,
if we go to an area like a black,
like just category,
I don't worry about you don't worry
about black students generally don't
worry about black bears,
but if you go to go to an area that has
mixed populations where you have an
interior areas that you might be wanting
black robes with,
grizzly bears around,
you deftly got paid more attention to.
I mean it's just like,
yeah,
but when you got to pay more attention
to a,
mainly you owe it to the area and you
owe it to the animals to,
to pay attention to it because if you
just have negligence and just.
And it leads to a conflict,
you know,
and you need to pay attention.
You got to look out for them all the
time.
Be Be aware,
don't do stupid things in your camp.
Don't invite disaster,
which has food.
Just being clean.
Keeping,
keeping like being cognizant of what
threats are.
Well,
let's say where it's either.
Here's the thing,
it's dark.
We're cooking meat.
Okay.
Yep.
Which we did last time.
That seems to be inviting bears in.
Yeah,
I think that.
I think that the,
the,
the goal,
those kind of strike a balance.
I mean you could live like this really
like,
and I know some people we call them
being bare annoyed.
Okay.
I'd also bear annoyed guys who like
their whole experience in the woods
becomes tainted by their fear of bears.
They know they'll only like,
they'll go off in some other place,
hundreds of yards away and eat food that
they imagine would be unappealing to a
bear and,
and do all this kind of crazy stuff.
And like,
you know,
they got there,
they brushed her teeth off in a
different area and hang her toothbrush
out in a tree because it might smell a
thing or they don't go out in the woods
if their,
if their wives menstruating,
you know,
they don't want to go out in the woods
with her and you're going to go crazy.
Or you can be like crazy in the other
extreme and just like,
you know,
drag kill an animal and drag it back to
camp and garden and leave the gut plain
air for five days to ripen in the sun
next to your tent.
Which would be like the other kind of
ridiculous or you can kind of walk a
moderate line and if you can do things
without tainting your experience,
but just like little common sense
issues,
not camping right on top of carcasses.
If you're cooking smelly food like fish
and fish,
guts and stuff.
Be careful about getting rid of that
stuff.
Put in your food up in a tree.
If there's trees available,
if there aren't things,
then you put your food somewhere where
you can see it and monitor it.
Lay sweaty clothes on top of it to
enhance the human odor in the area.
I mean just little things you can do
that don't ruin your time,
but you're generally trying to like
decrease the chance that you're going to
have a conflict.
It's going to have to get the government
bomb.
They're going to come out and have to
kill some bear because he so grizzlies.
When they smell humans tend to avoid him
I think.
Yeah,
and even the ones,
even the ones that don't have experience
with humans.
You know,
like if you go on a really remote area
where you run into barriers to,
you run into like a two year old bear,
three year old bear and it's reasonable
to assume he has not had a direct
interaction with a human and it was
possibly he just hasn't.
His parents who is his mother could be
12 years old and she's had a handful
throughout 12 year life,
but the other one might not.
But when they smell you,
oftentimes it's just,
it's new.
It hits them unlike a d,
they just smell it.
I think they got the world divided into
smells good,
don't smell good.
Yeah.
And I think that some human smells kind
of like,
I don't like that smell.
It was like a behavior posh and we were
talking about uh,
you know,
we did on the show were had to run a
bear out of camp and just come and at
that bear and trying to look big and
pissed off and like unyielding speaks to
the bear.
He's not.
Yeah,
well there is a person and he's likely
to be armed.
He's just thinking whatever that is.
That thing is pissed off and coming at
me for the folks who don't know what
we're talking about,
the Tim Ferriss episode of a mediator is
when they went terrible hunting in
Alaska,
so if you were looking for the one to
watch on TV,
that's the one I'm looking for this
particular situation,
but these were big bear sister.
There was one you saw and they didn't
even bigger one that was running towards
the camp.
A lot of people are more afraid of the
little ones really because the little
ones haven't.
They haven't accumulated that.
A set of experiences.
The teachers,
I'm like,
what's good and what's bad?
You know about.
Just think about like adolescents,
it,
you know,
if you think about if you're going to
get in like a road rage incident in some
ways a road rage incident with a guy
that's 50 isn't quite as dangerous as it
might be with a guy that's 18.
Like the guy that's 18.
You don't know what I mean.
He still might be like sorting through
some stuff.
Willing to like.
Yeah.
He's not aware of how long like driving
cars and I think that
so some people that,
and these are guys that know,
some of you guys know so much more about
bears now do,
but but people that know,
like look,
particularly the particularly dangerous
bears the bears have to watch out for
are the ones that have been recently
kicked out by the mother and the males
will will get kicked out and tend to
have to go farther afield to find a home
range everywhere they're going,
they're getting beaten up by a resident
bear.
They don't.
They don't have a good lock on available
food resources yet is very likely that
they're hungry.
They're inexperienced,
they're pressured and when you encounter
those,
those are the ones that people watch out
for that.
That's a theory about black bears as
well,
but I think that those blackberries are
more likely to end up like in some tree
in the middle of a town.
Young displays ones.
But again,
I just like generally,
and you can cite examples of things that
happened,
like generally like blackbirds are just
not.
I don't think it as a dangerous bear.
I don't think of blackbirds been any
more dangerous than deer being
dangerous.
I just,
I'm just not bothered by blackberry is a
crazy video or recently from somewhere
in Canada where these dudes are treat
their in tree stands and they're
standing there and the bear for whatever
reason,
just runs up the tree and is beside him
in the trailer man in like a couple of
seconds and he's like,
they're talking to each other in the
filming this.
The bear price smelled something like my
dad's buddy got as much as I just said.
My Dad's buddy got mauled because he was
hunting bears from a tree and a sow with
cubs came in and he didn't want to shoot
the south cubs.
You know,
most places you can't,
but that sounds,
smelled something.
She smelled a person and her response
was to shoot her cubs up the tree to
safety and she shoot him up his tree.
So when they came past them on history,
they started squealing and then she came
up and mold his lower legs.
I remember her.
I remember one night we're sitting in
our house,
my dad got a phone call guy used to hunt
with,
had gotten his lower legs mauled by a
bear,
and he eventually founded her off,
was trying to fend her off of the Arrow
and that you call this bench.
She came back down the tree and then
she'd let him be.
Oh my God.
So yeah,
there are,
there are incidents,
but you can also.
I mean if you're just cruising youtube,
I mean there's plenty of places where
you go find a deer,
knock the hell out.
Someone to look at his spirit.
He's climbing a ladder.
You know,
it's not a big bear though,
because look at it two years.
No.
Is it the best thing to do?
Just talk to him.
Look at that.
Bear ran away.
That's big enough.
That's pretty good.
I just didn't like the,
the accepted.
Well see,
here's the thing.
It's like some people say that,
but again this,
you know,
it's like every.
If you look at like when people own
bears actually tagged people,
it's so.
It's oftentimes just like weird
circumstances are unpredictable things,
but the general,
the general thinking it the general
wisdom on if a blank bird does attack
you,
it's predatory.
Okay.
He's not defending territory.
If a blackberry tanks where he's like,
I'm going to eat that was thinking is
you fight hell to fight like hell riced.
If a sal grizzy with cubs,
you spook it into attacks you.
What it's doing is neutralizing a
threat.
So then the thinking is play dead,
get covered.
You know [inaudible] right.
Here's where,
here's where they're going to kill you.
You cover this and curl up and don't
move.
And she's like,
take that bastard and walks off,
you know,
and again,
align,
they've aligned was to hit you.
You're supposed to just go ballistic on
it because it's a predatory response
that it's happened.
So when black bears,
like when you do hear of black bears,
when they attack the attack kids and
you're like,
lions often attack like small women
joggers,
like small women joggers seem to get
attacked by lions or young kids need to
get attacked by lions.
Yeah.
It's at that thing is like,
I'm going to eat that,
you know?
Wow.
But then grizzlies enough people to man,
like you hear about people,
you know,
they,
they get at by bears.
Yeah.
There's a guy recently,
they think it was a hybrid.
I don't know what I'm saying.
Well,
there was a guy who was
minor and he went into get groceries in
town.
Apparently his boat died.
His engine dies.
So he pulled over and that's where they
found his body.
It had been mostly consumed.
Yeah.
And they think they think that might've
been a hybrid.
You know what's weird?
I was reading,
I was reading this book by,
I was reading this bear hunting book by
this writer Tony Ross,
and
he's talking about with that,
like on Kodiak island,
like in the last couple of insulin areas
that just have really dense grizzly
populations are brown bear grizzly.
The same thing.
Just people generally say like brown
bear for Coastal Grizzlies,
grizzlies free anterior.
And um,
he was saying that the grizzlies,
that the male grizzlies will come out
and when they come out in those areas
that have,
you know,
they'll may have like a grizzly for
every one or two or three square miles.
So a lot,
a lot more dense than most other areas.
They'll come out and they,
when they come out in the spring,
they're heart and copes.
Wow.
That's like,
that's what's on the menu man.
Cause it's like there's so many of them
there.
They're so vicious that they come out
and like they,
their primary food source for somebody
mature boars is grizzly cubs.
Oh my God.
And you go after.
But he said a weird thing is,
and you know,
they'll kill those companies that we
said in all of his hunting when,
when they'll kill a grizzly bear brown
bear and skin it,
you know,
he said all these hunting,
he's talked to other guys too.
He's never seen a.
he's never seen where brown bear
consumed the skin dot carcass up another
browser.
So the cubs.
But they never read the bear.
And He,
and he mentions in his book,
he talks to some other people,
he's talking about some Galligan,
20 years of hunting,
whatever,
if they've never seen the carcass of an
adult get cannibalized.
Wow.
But they'll,
they'll put down and it's like a,
it's like a active pray for them.
So when they're hunting the cubs,
do you think that it's a response to
like controlling the environment,
not letting any new members in?
I think it's.
So I think it really is food,
but it's also that they know that,
that,
that will go back into estrous because
she's,
she's only gonna.
She's only going to put off.
She's only going to put off cuff maybe
every few years.
Tyra dolphins do that as well.
Dolphins,
murder babies.
If they know that the woman she won't
meet with,
uh,
with the dolphins that blue,
the blue whale drown.
Um,
you know,
they'll drown a female's calf because
she knows she'll bring it again,
if not,
she's not brief for years.
It's rough man.
There's a lot of people that really try
to like dress up the animal world as
kind of like,
oh,
innocent this.
It's like there's some,
there's some wicked stuff out there,
but those,
those big bars,
he was talking about this dude Tony Rust
on with these big boards.
They'll go out and dig dens,
Jesus Christ and the females will come
out later,
so the females being the Danza cubs and
those boards will go around doing site
visits.
No dig covered out.
Then you got in and I imagine they're
probably a little bit indiscriminately.
There's a chance he's going to consume
his own offspring.
She's also thinking that all these
sounds that wouldn't be available to me
for two years,
three years are going to be available to
meet this June.
Oh,
June or July.
When they go to the females defend.
They have to,
you know,
they have to anyone life and I feel like
I've seen and also talk to you and her.
If people who talk about that,
they've seen instances where a female
has fought them off.
Yeah,
we're the mail wasn't that committed,
you know,
because I mean it's going to come out.
It's going to come at a price to them,
but then some of these may.
I mean,
some of these males are so big that
they're,
they can get off to be where there are
nearly twice as big in their battle.
Hardened man.
Yeah.
This wicked though,
that movie grizzly man,
when those two bears go to war and they
start to do things like unbelievable
footage,
that guy got to tell you what.
That's some of the most impressive
people are always down on that guy,
you know,
for all these reasons.
But I'll tell you what,
man,
that dude's a hard camper.
Oh yeah,
you go do it because I play a foot heel
out camp anybody and people in Alaska
always like,
but people will ask,
get really offended when like an
outsider will come up and do some like
thing like go camping for a long time.
So like he gets eaten by bears and it
was like,
oh,
he's so stupid.
But the guy knew he was going to eat my
bears and he camped.
Everybody.
You go onto an area like that.
It just rained and he camped seven
summers in a row all summer long and be
like,
well yeah.
But he had his girlfriend with him that
could make it worse,
man.
To be uncomfortable with your girlfriend
is,
is like worse than being uncomfortable
by yourself.
Being uncomfortable for two people and
there's a certain amount of
responsibility that comes with that.
He was a hard.
Especially if you like her because
you're just watching it crumble.
Yeah.
And he was a hard camper and he
collected some footage.
That fight is unparalleled.
Unbelievable.
It's just amazing power in those two
bars is just like they duked it out for
quite a while.
He got like really close up footage for
the folks who don't know what we're
talking about are these two bears.
It's fighting over territory.
It's worth watching.
That movie alone is worth watching.
Grizzly man alone wash those boards go
at each other.
They devastate that area.
Yeah.
And that's not like a common thing to
see like in that,
that close,
that good footage for that long.
It's a long ass fight.
I had a,
but I got like,
but like you can hang out in the woods
so much,
you know,
and not you're getting out in the with
so much.
And then when you look at all the things
you've seen out in the woods,
it's like,
it's startling.
Like how few really weird things.
You see,
what disproportionate,
you know,
no one does,
spends a little dinky bit of time out in
the woods and then sees tons of weird
stuff.
It's like you got to put in the hours,
you know,
to,
to catalog stuff.
Like there's a guy,
I know this guy,
he's a Guy Jay Scott,
and we're talking.
I'll start one day,
like I was feeling cocky because I had
seen three.
I've seen three mountain lions,
wells hon,
you know,
and um,
was Guy Jay Scott just haunts.
He's one of the best big game hunters I
know.
And I was saying like,
uh,
you ever seen a lion?
He said,
I'm looking for number 33 right now.
Oh Nash.
Not hunting lions that sitting in
watching Jesus sending,
watching,
sitting in,
watching for game.
He had,
he had logged 32 that he spotted,
not running them,
a dog,
just being there in the woods,
watching,
looking for lines,
what is looking for game,
what has been oculars and that right
there.
You can't buy it.
You can't.
Like.
He's a very honest guy.
That's like,
that means like,
oh,
that dude's spent tons of time out there
and some of the things that.
That guy that was in the footage,
and I'm only going by and on a grizzly
man,
I don't want to go and buy whatever I
saw on that to our herzog movie.
Like Lord knows how many things didn't
make it.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
He was out there and witnessed some
amazing site.
Yes ma'am.
Yeah.
Well that's what people have to
understand that the Timothy Treadwell's
footage was all turned into this Werner
Herzog documentary,
but this is just a piece of what this
guy got when he was living up there,
and I think a lot of people believe that
they're going to so powerful.
The good Greco Greco,
good under good control and neck
that this guy had suicide by bear.
That was the way he went out,
that he knew that if he was there as
late as he was,
that the bears that would still be
around would be really desperate.
There were older bears on you.
Imagine one of those things getting old
you.
Yeah.
Power man.
Oh yeah.
They're going to town and they use it in
real Jujitsu.
Look at this.
He's passing the guard.
Look,
it's filled in the hips.
That's.
Guy's got a good open garden.
Not.
I don't know.
It's not unreasonable to say it.
Those are 800 pound plus animals.
Oh yeah.
Those are enormous.
I mean we don't.
It's hard to put it in perspective,
but that's good.
Jujitsu,
I'll tell you that.
He's inside control right now.
He just passed the guard.
He's in full sight control right now and
he's got the neck and he could deliver
knees to the head if that was allowed
and bear fighting,
but it doesn't see like that.
See that move,
that move.
Reclaimed Guard got down.
That is natural reclaimed guard.
He reclaimed guard.
You can't let him get back to guard
against this.
Bear is fucking crafty to bear on the
bottom is doing a real good job
defending himself.
This for real,
even though the other barrier is bigger.
This what's going on there.
The way the bear fight is how they teach
you to fight in Jujitsu,
for real foot on the hips,
controlling his body out,
letting him get all of his weight on top
of you.
Shifting your hips so your feet touch
onto his hip.
You see the chunks of hair flying.
Here's an interesting bit of like
bipedalism in this too,
man.
Like they're pretty adept at another
bank.
You know they're pretty adept at being
under back
looking at.
Well,
when you see him standing up like that
on their hind legs,
that's when you realize how fucking
enormous they are.
Look at the big chunk of hair missing
from his back leg,
an arm drag.
Look at the size of the fucking light
one.
Look how big the light.
When his youngest check him out.
He's been back down to the younger ones.
Got Better Jujitsu,
I told you,
fight off his back.
It might be old and crippled.
Man,
he wore out the big deal,
the big deal,
got tired of the big one,
had a pipe,
had hold of his face though
these are blackberries when I'm
principles on where my brothers and I
got a little shack,
the biggest bear I've seen out there,
and that's famous for big barriers.
The biggest barrier I see now.
There was a big injured old bear on what
happened,
but he was just packing leg and he was
kind of in the autumn of is in the
autumn of his career,
you know,
so he had been like probably the man and
now he probably just kiss his ass
kicked.
Wow.
He's sees guy.
He's done by a salmon stream that
couldn't really move and you can imagine
now all the people he'd beat up because
he,
he could be old now.
17 one time.
17.
That's from Duluth to tooth tooth
dentist analysis.
17.
He could,
you know,
he could have a lot of grudges against
him.
Now he's kind of down one of the big
board or one of the cool things.
Yeah.
About the trip that we went on.
We should probably talk about that.
We're talking about everything else,
but what the fuck?
Yeah.
Go Pee.
And when you come back we'll uh,
we'll talk to you about,
about hunting and manly shit.
Yeah.
You're allowed to say pee on the show.
The show is casual as fuck.
Don't have to worry about saying p.
what'd you do this weekend,
pal?
Uh,
what did I do this weekend?
Um,
I dunno.
I just watched the playoffs and I
watched nate's fight.
Safford and fought a great fight,
man.
It was a good fight.
The whole,
the whole card was good.
Asked me to tell Josh Barnett.
Got a big win.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Josh Barnett is tough.
He's an animal.
It's good.
A good wood for him because he was sick.
He,
uh,
he had like a real tough camp.
Apparently there was a,
like you've got a real bad flu or some
sort of a bug,
something,
you know,
some kind of a cold and could not shake
it.
He said he only had a few days of good
solid hard training during the entire
camp or certainly like just fucking half
ass it or trying to,
uh,
do his bass,
but try not to get sicker.
It's interesting to see like where MMA
is coming because like if you're not
prepared for someone's,
you know,
weapons,
and if someone hits you with something
you haven't seen before,
like I was thinking about naked and get
caught with those leg kicks over number
eight and 18 million times.
I think terex happening is a,
he's a really classical technical
striker and it nate Marquardt,
although a amazing
striker,
you though the knockout of Tyron
Woodley,
that,
uh,
that sent that insane dot Kao towards
the end.
But I think that technically if you look
at all the best technical fighters in
less,
they're freaks of athleticism unless
they're just much faster than anyone
else.
They,
they follow a certain number of rules
when it comes to defending yourself when
it comes to carrying your hands.
When it comes to how you fight.
And I'm one of them is you've got to
respect everyone's techniques.
So you got to respect,
like kicks you gotta check leg kicks
whenever possible and I think the idea
is that,
you know,
nate was going to eat a few of 'em and
just tag them with a big punch.
That sub strategy that works.
So there's no.
Tim Silvia,
Tim Silvia knocked out Rigo Rodriguez
the same way.
Rico Rico hit him with a leg kick and he
was planted take,
he decided he just gonna eat the it and
blast the punch and catch a guy.
So a lot of guys do that and it got like
Marco who's got that kind of power,
probably banked on that.
And then somewhere along the line safdie
and hit them with too many of them.
And he was like,
Oh fuck,
I should have checked those.
Right?
So it's just a matter of absolutely
could and he might be able to beat 70
when they fight again.
You know,
it's like,
it's when you get,
when you're dealing with that level,
you know,
that high,
a level of fighting terex happening.
It's a lot of times what it is is a,
it's also how they match.
Giles is a really good wrestler because
it was time with team quest like he's
really hard to take doing Greco with
Olympia and it's like.
Exactly.
So you saw like when nate was really
struggling to take them down to nate was
forced to stand with them and he was
forced to stand with them and 17 is
being more conservative and he's being
more tactical until he kept landing
those leg kicks and neighbors looking
for the big bombs and Woodley fonts
happening.
He just hit him with those low doubles
and singles wrestle.
Fuck them.
One thing they say when they say that
crack,
Greco guys have a tough time with
freestyle wrestlers.
Oh yeah.
Well a lot of people have a hard time
with a guy like tyron woodley.
He's just a fucking.
He's a super strong dude with great
wrestling fan,
you know,
and he's in condition.
Any smart,
you know,
anywhere,
trains hard and it's a fucking super
athlete and he can punch the shit out.
His wrestling's ridiculous.
He gets a hold of you.
You're going to go on your back,
you know,
it's a big,
strong guy,
but nate beat him and that was probably
the most sensational.
They look so to go from that fight where
he looks unbelievably good to this
fight,
just a little wake up call,
she would just be more,
a little bit more tactical or
conservative when you're fighting guy
like that and to realize that that kind
of accumulation of eating,
those kind of shots really can pay off
or can can,
you know,
it tends to maybe nate,
I don't know,
but maybe I wonder if nate felt he was
bigger and stronger so he could call
them.
Probably did.
He probably thought he would just blast
them.
Look after that Woodley fight,
man.
I mean he knew it was gonna be a tough
fight.
He can do.
A lot of people said it was a gigantic
upset.
I don't think it was a gigantic or
I thought.
I think it was terex afternoons finance
performance,
but it wasn't like a gigantic upset.
It was an upset.
I think it would.
I would see the taffy into extra and
stryker.
I said a great fighter.
He's a complete fighter.
He realized it's potential that night,
you know?
Yeah.
But,
um,
back to what I wanted to tell you about
our trip,
man.
And thanks for bringing my skull.
Thank Ryan Callahan.
Man.
I love that dude.
Callahan was one of the guys that we
went with,
a real man.
He saw it through.
He's such an awesome dude.
Um,
the um,
the place where we went for,
uh,
for dinner when we first came back.
We haven't even showered yet and we
stunk five.
If you need a great hunting guide,
right?
Call Ryan Callahan.
We were out in the,
you know,
camping by the side of the river for
five days.
We hadn't had any showers.
And then before we even got to a hotel,
we decided let's go get some dinner
somewhere or get some lunch.
So we go to this place in this fucking
Dick Wad who owns the place,
has this shrine up to the fallen
marines.
And he comes up to us and starts talking
to us about Obama.
And Are you guys the attack?
Yeah.
Oh,
they killed my boys.
He's just as overbearing,
blowhards a real a whole,
and then he starts yelling at his staff
and he starts yelling at a woman who
works there and what.
It's just like dressing or down for no
reason.
It's just really embarrassing to.
All of us are down over order confusion
that we created by having like a
complicated order.
Yeah.
And it wasn't anything that any of us
had any problem with at all.
It was just like,
oh no.
Oh no worries.
You know,
every,
everybody was fine,
but this guy is treating her like she
just took a shit in the middle of your
fucking chicken soup.
It didn't make any sense.
Right.
So Ryan,
at the end of the dinner,
he gets up and he goes over to the guy
and he starts calling the better
business bureau on the phone and he
tells the woman,
quit,
you need to quit.
You may not work here.
Just get out and quit right now.
And he goes,
you sir are an embarrassment.
You know,
I'm a native Montana and I have some
people in here.
I'm showing them what Montana is alike
and they have to see you exhibit this
kind of behavior.
Wow.
That's a John Wayne.
John Wayne.
Man.
He was sitting there.
He defended that girl was embarrassed
for his age.
He started trying to talk and he goes,
I am not talking to you sir,
but I cannot understand for the life me
why you would speak to somebody like
that.
I just can't understand.
And Ryan Ryan is Ryan,
so polite,
but you can tell he's a,
he's,
he's such a moral upstanding guy.
Like he's just this great guy with a
mustache,
you know,
just stand there like just just standing
up for what's right.
And it Kinda like shamed all of us.
We were like,
God,
I guess we should have done that for
like,
I'm not good at that
because I,
I,
that Guy Matt made me mad.
You know,
the way.
It's almost like he's trying to sabotage
his own restaurant.
It was the weirdest thing to have.
They'd be like,
I'm going to go into your restaurant and
buy the products you're selling and
you're going to come start like quizzing
me into things that I know are traps.
Yeah.
You know,
basically we were like al Qaeda.
He was asking.
He was asking us how we felt about Obama
because it was right before the
elections.
He was like,
yeah,
you're not,
you're not voting for Obama.
Right?
Yeah.
But in his,
his political,
his political was this,
oh,
you're going to boat go barbara.
You're going to get.
He started dancing around like I guess
Obama's gay or some stereotypical,
like it was the weirdest thing.
Or if she fucking with
like I hate when anyone makes um,
like,
like when people come up just uninvited
to like talk political makeup,
political insinuations.
I remember when we had our kid,
we had to get a pediatrician.
I remember going to guy who like started
making cracks like this,
assuming like Kinda like,
like that were in the club,
like one of the left wing club.
Like he just knew that we were like in
left when Columbus started making like
cracks about like right wing people.
I remember walking out,
I'm like,
there's no annotate my kid to a
pediatrician who when I walk in I want
to talk about my child's health once you
get into it with me and like make
assumptions about my politics has
nothing to do with the services that I'm
seeking and when I wanted to eat that
guy's hamburger,
the last thing I wanted to hear was his
like analysis of,
I think it was like the Ben Gazi
duck boat.
He said he tried to talk to you.
You talk about Joe.
I was messing with the guys that you
guys got drunk.
I was like,
Nah,
just a little blow.
And he's like smart ass and Joe Joe
Finance.
I was like,
I stopped talking to that guy.
You're encouraging them.
I don't because I can tell when you clam
up.
I don't.
I,
yeah,
I didn't like that guy.
It wasn't nice.
When you see a guy who's not nice to his
employees like that,
I don't.
I really don't want to talk to them,
but the upside is that Ryan has,
is fuck that.
Uh,
that was a fun experience,
man,
to,
uh,
to have our first hunting trip with you
was a,
was a real treat man.
It was so much fucking fun.
We keep telling you that.
I love seeing it through.
I love seeing people's eyes,
you know,
that's got to be weird for you.
Right?
I mean,
you've spent your entire life
essentially hunting.
You can't even remember the first time
you killed anything,
right?
No,
I don't.
Well,
I remember the first day,
I remember the first deer I killed,
but as far as hunting small game and
just be around it,
you know what?
I never,
you know,
what I never had is uh,
not that I read or seen in other people,
whatever had that.
Like the shock of death that people,
you know what I mean?
The,
the people experience kind of like the,
the,
the shock of how serious it is.
So if someone grows the business arm.
Yeah.
And they see that all the time,
don't have it,
you know,
I didn't grow up on it.
I didn't grow up in agriculture but grew
up in Boston hunting and it was around a
lot of things.
But I never had that like that,
that level of surprise.
And I think that when you,
when you take someone out,
um,
for the first time in my brother's
opponent,
the same thing with their wives or
girlfriends out or friends out that
there is,
that there's a real reckoning that
people have,
you know.
And um,
the funny thing is,
despite someone's response that usually
people,
if you,
if you kill an animal for the first time
and you're going to eat it regardless
what you can do with kill,
killing animals for the first time,
it struck.
It's not,
I don't want to say it's humbling,
but it stops other thoughts.
You just,
your loan with that thought for a
minute.
But the interesting thing is,
as much as I've seen that happen,
I've never had anyone later come to
regret having done it.
I had weeds in some way strengthening
for people to go to go see that like
that.
That template gives you more relief.
That desk thing.
No one's ever called me back and said
that was a terrible mistake
for you.
I'm intellectually intellectually
knowing that this is a unique experience
for most people.
How do you know,
how does that make you feel like when
you see it through their eyes and the,
the idea to you being so alien?
It's,
it's exciting for me and I'm,
I think that
I'm looking at.
I think that I already kind of in a way
I know what the,
what the experience is going to be for
the person because I think in some ways
we're talking about really base aspects
of human nature,
you know,
and so I kind of can anticipate like if
I take someone out on their first hunt
and just kind of want to show him
hunting first,
what I usually do,
you know,
because like I respect you guys might
have a good time and respect your
opinions on things.
So I'm like wanting to like taking on an
experience.
It's gonna.
It's gonna be a good one,
you know,
there's going to be like an immersive
kind of experience,
so I know that there's a certain thing
that goes with that just to kind of get
away from stuff and be out in an area
where you've diminished some of the
noise and you're allowed to be in the
moment.
It's just going to put you in a certain
spot
and I think that that
it's like to take someone on a first
hunt.
I'm not worried about like a wild card
scenario because I've done it enough to
where I've seen that it just doesn't
happen.
It's like people go on a,
on a kind of predictable journey on a
hunt.
You tell them a wild card.
I you have some crazy response to that
would be like really unhinging for them
or that it would,
that it would put them into the.
They would be so depressed or that there
would be so guilt ridden.
I've just never had,
you know,
it's not like when I go into it I don't
think like,
wow,
who knows what's going to happen when
this happens.
I'm saying like,
you know,
what's going to happen is the person who
have a very fulfilling experience,
you know,
and they're going to appreciate the
challenge.
They might not ever go hunting again,
but they'll always remember back on that
and have come away and found out
something about themselves and it's
like,
it's never been otherwise.
If I,
if I,
I would probably stop if I found that
there was a high degree,
you know,
there's,
there's a thing that happened to me
though with,
with my own wife.
She didn't grow up around hunting,
you know,
and she eats a lot of wild game and has
eaten a lot of wild game since ever
since she eats more while gaining the 90
percent of the hunters I know,
but she just hadn't had.
She's like,
I don't want to see an animal.
I don't need to see an animal get
killed.
She's like,
I'm fine with the hypocrisy if you want
to call it that piracy.
I'll eat wild game.
I'll eat meat.
I prefer to eat wild game over domestic
meat.
I just don't want to see you dear.
You're killed in one day.
I invited her,
we were up at my cabin and I invited her
out on a deer hunt with us and my
brother wanted to get a deer.
We took our boat out and landed our
skiff at this river mouth and she was
reluctant to go along because she was
afraid of what she might see and I had
encouraged her to come because I'm like,
what's going to happen is you won't even
know the there.
We're going to spotted deer that's far
away.
Probably obscured by brush.
You'd have to look for it really hard to
see it.
Anyways,
we're going to shoot it by the time we
get over there,
it'll be dead and it's not really the
experience you're imagining,
but we beat our skiff and started going
up this gravel bar to stream bank and
here comes three deer.
Something scared him.
A bear.
I don't know what some scared them
because they're running toward us and
they get so close that I.
I'm not kidding.
I'm looking at the eyelashes on this
deer.
Oh my.
They're just there and I see that one of
them's got spikes on them is a buck and
it was a buck only sees him and I see my
brother were kind of hunkered down by
rock and I see him like raised and his
wife.
I'm like,
you son of a bitch.
I was like,
do not shoot this deer right now.
We'll just get another one later.
And He,
you know,
piles that deer up.
And when my wife looked at it,
you say,
piles that deer up shot at point blank.
How far away we talk in 10 feet.
And you have that monitor clove and,
and it turned and she turned and she
thought that he had missed.
That fell over.
It was foreign.
I'm exaggerating.
I was fired.
That was very close.
Maybe twice that distance.
So even twice I just seeing it's eyelash
talking about like 30 feet and very,
very,
very close.
And um,
and when she looked at me after seeing
that she was looking at me across a
vast,
vast Gulf of difference of distance.
It was like,
it was like she looked at me like she
had never seen you are known me and I
asked,
we have ge,
we were,
we were just married.
We were married not even a year and it
was the look she gave me.
I was like,
oh,
this could be the end of our
relationship.
Did she find it sexy?
No,
no,
no.
Come on me.
Like,
like we were the barbarian.
Yeah,
yeah.
Will,
you just assassinated was right in front
of it,
but you know,
what was weird it we're sitting and we
got,
we drug the thing down and she didn't
think we drug it with enough ceremony.
She's like,
his head was banging,
you know,
we got it out and drug it back through
this gift and started motor and back
toward our shack and um,
and no one was saying a word in the boat
at all,
but then within 45 minutes,
within 45 minutes was enough time for
her to process what she saw and her take
home was,
you know what,
I guess I'd still rather eat that thing.
Then you know,
an animal from a feed lot.
Of course it was just like,
it just took her a minute because she
was like.
Later I felt like she's like,
I feel like I should feel something
different than I do.
I feel like I should feel outrage
intellectually.
Yeah.
But then once you sat in that bowl and
thought it was just like,
it just passed,
it passed.
She's like,
you know,
I don't know.
Things die.
It's so fascinating that you have this.
You have this different point of view on
death.
Then you know so many people and for
your wife
to experience it in its most shocking
form on the first pass,
you know,
I'm not sure it would take a little
while to intellectualize something
instinct by butchering the deer and get
my hands in that deer.
And I kinda thought to myself,
I can see how I can certainly see how a
hunter would have an easier time taking
a human's life with a knife or
wonderful.
That'll tight.
I think you have an intimate experience
with that animal.
You know,
you're not as squeamish.
Maybe you,
you.
It is a strange feeling when you reach
in there and you feel the guts for the
first time.
Okay.
The whole experience was really
fascinating,
but I passed out when my wife had an
epidural when she's having her first
baby because I used to tell people I'd
be like,
and I want to write it off as the needle
thing.
I told you I could cut your arm off,
but I can't watch you get a shot.
Wow.
That's so weird.
I don't know.
It was thing,
but I don't know that it translates.
I think people do it.
There's like an argument against
hunting.
Is that it?
Like the attorneys you into like,
like you're so comfortable death and
you're like an animal.
That should be the necessarily trans.
I don't think it translates to being
comfortable.
I mean that's the same argument than
that.
Someone who runs a chicken farm can be
killed chickens.
Okay.
I just think that violence transform you
transforms you fundamentally.
For example,
like when you've done combat sports and
you've gotten punched and knocked out or
kicked in the head and knocked out or,
or just put into a choking and you are
different.
You are different about your own
mortality,
your own relationships to other men do.
Do you know what I mean?
Like when you,
when you've been,
when you've been taken,
when you've been taken to a man or you
had somebody do like whatever they want
to and you realize,
oh,
I'm very vulnerable.
You or you get knocked out and it really
hurts her hitting the body that I think
fundamentally changes you,
um,
in,
in your relationship,
not just to other men.
How do you think it's related to hunting
though?
In the same way?
Like when you,
when you have an intimate experience of
harvesting your own meat,
which actually requires a really loud
noise,
a killing of an animal,
and you see that blood and you feel that
just was alive and you're touching it,
then you go butcher it.
I feel like I approach.
I don't know,
man,
it,
I don't even know how to articulate how
it changed me,
but I do think that something that,
that,
that is that intimately violent.
Yeah,
um,
is going to keep saying violence because
I don't see it as violence at all.
But I think it's,
it's pretty abrupt in it's ending.
I mean there's violent attacks using it.
Violence I used to not use,
I started like coming to turn because I
don't want to like sanctify it,
you know what I mean?
And,
and,
and I'd be careful about,
this is the thing in the hunting world
where people were very reluctant to use
the word kill.
There's euphemisms for kill harvest.
They kind of like harvest or take.
But I feel like,
I mean the obvious to the gunshot is
violent,
but the,
the butchering and all that stuff didn't
post violence.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
But I just mean the blood very graphic
and real temperature of the blood,
smelling it right up to my arms.
I'm not trying to imply that shooting
animals wasn't violent.
I met the butchering and everything like
that,
but the whole experience,
I didn't think of it as a violent
experience.
It was very surreal.
Very,
um,
you know,
the,
that's a,
like a commonly used term,
like the connection to nature.
It's one of those terms I think that's
used so much that the meaning of it gets
a little fuzzy to get a little
bullshitty,
you know,
oh my connection to nature and Sot nom,
but that is what it is when you're out
there living in that animal's world,
sleeping on the ground,
just basically like they do and then
following them around and shoot one.
Then you're pulling it's heart and liver
out.
That's,
that's a fucking connection to Sirius.
I still got a different respect for what
a knife can do.
It's weird,
like you go,
wow man,
they really do.
Yeah,
we talked,
we talked about this,
you know that that's the thing that I
found like being out with you on that,
on that
trip.
And then the thought of having one with
Tim Ferris wants is people that have
been the fighters.
Like I'm there.
I'm not a fighter like I haven't,
I've been hit a couple of times but
never beat anybody up or anything.
Well I beat up one guy in ninth grade,
but you know,
but I think that you bring a level of
calmness just to the act of shooting,
like being able to like get down to
shoot some people are.
So I'm unable to control adrenaline and
fear.
They become.
They can't shoot.
Yeah,
I could.
I was.
I got a buddy who guide
and he was saying one time he took this
guy up and they were hunting tar in,
in New Zealand and the guy shot in my
buddy's watching through his binoculars
where the bullet hit in any show me,
someone was rolling a video.
When did it?
And you hear my body say you,
you're 20 feet high.
Hi.
That's hilarious.
A lot of,
just the amount of time I've reversed
his mind.
He left his mind when I was um,
when uh,
the,
I would have been able to shoot that
deer with the first time we saw him.
But I didn't have enough practice with
that scope and I was too close to the
scope and you know,
he get that weird thing.
I couldn't find him in there too.
It was almost like to like a black half
moons criss crossing over into that.
Couldn't like get the image more than
that.
More than that.
Anything else,
um,
is cause of,
of beginner hunters.
Not Getting shots at things is the
weird.
I like the,
I really fishes,
it becomes very second nature but pretty
precise like where you put it and when
you're in like in a weird position and
things were happening fast.
It's tough man.
Yeah.
For folks who don't know what we're
saying,
there's a scope on the top of the rifle
and if you're too close to that scope,
it distorts your view.
It fucks up.
You have to be just
in the right spot.
And the first time we saw the deer I
couldn't get it in the right spot.
And then he went behind this little area
and then came back out again.
And when he came back out again,
I was able to figure it out.
I pulled back a little bit.
I was like,
oh,
there it is,
but I was freaking out.
I was like,
I can't fucking see this thing and if I
lose this fucking deer because of this,
I'll go crazy.
We have been stalking them for days.
Just excuse me.
Just one.
Yeah,
to get it done.
Yeah.
I was desperate to motivation.
That comes out,
man.
There's a lot of things that like
there's a lot of things that come out in
Huntington I think are applicable to the
life and work and stuff,
but you get like when you've been out
there a couple of days and you start
getting accustomed to that.
I think it's easy to go for a day and
walk me.
They already didn't happen.
You got a couple of days into something.
Most people like what I would almost
call it,
like a work ethic or like something
comes up where you're like,
you know,
we've committed ourselves to this.
We put time into it.
We're out here and you just want to make
it happen and it brings out a level of
drive.
That's what happened to me.
Good to come to fulfill the goal of that
moment becomes such a gigantic sweeping
moment and that's why it's hard to like
stay calm,
but it actually happens when you're
building up with two days of fucking
shitty camping and one with a Bahraini
and pouring outside and coal every
morning and going to bed at like eight
because there's nothing to do.
It gets dark.
We all just go to bed and then we'd get
up and like where are we getting up at
like six,
six in the morning,
whatever.
And then just wandering around trying to
find a deer and um,
but the,
the,
one of the craziest visions was when we
were on the top of one of those hills.
And you look around at the vastness of
that area.
And man was that fucking humbling.
We were standing.
I remember,
I remember this.
We were on the top of one of the hills
is one of the first time you spotted a
sheep.
You were,
you were glass in the area and you
spotted a big sheep way the fuck away
from us.
And when we're on top,
we're looking around.
You just get up looking over at the
vastness of this thing,
like you could just start walking and
starve to death and nobody would ever
find you.
I thought when we ever find you out
there talking about how cold it was all
the time and starving to death and how
you have no light,
you can keep that stone age shit.
It was fun.
I enjoyed it for five days.
I'll tell you that.
It is a humbling area though,
man,
and it's one of those cool areas that
really,
and again to talk about the Missouri
Breaks region,
it's one of those cool areas that really
just kind of on its own resistant
development.
If there's some spots that were,
were so stunning that early on people
were like,
this is like you'll 70 yellowstone.
It was like the momentum was always
going toward hanging onto it.
You know,
people wonder like this is special.
I mean we got hot guys was shooting up
out the ground.
We should early on like make sure does
not screw this place up.
And there's some great areas in the US.
Like I would argue hell's kitchen,
hell's canyon.
The Missouri breaks reason that just
remained peer,
just through toughness and tenacity.
Like everybody went in there and tried
to do something.
Yeah,
and it's like one of those places where
you go and it's like they try to do that
didn't work out.
Like one of the things that that place
is known for is it horse thieves use.
It does go there because they knew they
could go hide out,
you know,
it was like useful to them just as a
place to hide out and there was some
campaigns where it was like,
we're going to go into the brakes,
we're going to find them all,
we're going to hang him from cottonwoods
and they'd go down in and root out the
guys.
And it was like a spot that held
wildlife for long time,
you know,
it was a spot where some of the plains
tribes could go down and hide out in
there.
In the Mussel shell that goes into that
area was one of the last place they had
free roaming herds of Buffalo in
Montana.
It was just like a spot where people
would try to get a grip and it just
didn't hold and now it still isn't
really.
There's some protections there,
but it's not like categorically
protected like a place like yellowstone
is,
but it just,
after awhile people almost kind of threw
their hands up in the air.
It interesting that you're talking about
is
because I don't know what you're saying.
It's like the people trying to settle in
that area couldn't,
they couldn't live.
They couldn't run farms grow stuff
couldn't grow.
So
yeah,
people would go in and try to um,
do you homesteads they try to run.
Government says that if you stay on this
land for x amount of time,
yours is,
that you do improvements on it,
you do improvements.
So there was all these homesteads sites
where we were walking around and we'd
find these really old logs that used to
be a side of a house.
The sheep shacks or sad houses.
Root cellars.
It's fucking weird.
What's our root cellar be like under
like a climate controlled area where you
dig down into the ground and have like a
cruel place to store things or.
And it also be freeze proof because
you're down,
you know,
you go down to the dirt ways and then
there's still a lot of old structures
there to have sought,
you know,
you can see that it had a sod roof.
How far do you have to go to in the
ground before it becomes freeze proof?
Well,
however far down the frost line is when
you put in,
you know,
people have a frost,
you rise in your yard.
What do you got to most places like in
Michigan member we'd only go to our
frost for your eyes are only went down
36 inches.
How fucked up is it?
They go deep into the ground.
It stops being cold.
When you go deep enough,
it'll burn
your ass,
but isn't that,
is that why it is getting past the
surface and it's getting closer to the
public.
In Alaska what they do is they dig down
into the,
the
permafrost and use that for
refrigeration.
All year.
Oh Wow.
That's interesting.
So does that.
Wow guys used you read about guys on the
prairie.
They used to.
They would in the winter hunt and dig
down into the ground where the ground
was frozen.
There was in the winter hunt and fill
that with animals,
fill it with corridors of meat and let
that freeze in the winter and then pile
canvas down or blankets on top of that.
Put dirt back on so it would freeze and
it dig that up.
Months into the summer.
Net meets
good down there on campus,
frozen.
Dig a big deep pit,
eight feet deep,
whatever and put me in and let it get
frozen and then piled dirt on.
Let all that frees up and then it'll get
warm out and you could dig down there
later.
The mito who's a fucking genius who
figured that out.
That's brilliant.
What about worms and stuff?
I guess not.
I dude,
I've been watching.
There's not getting fly larva.
I mean,
if you let flies land on it and it was
hot out and you buried it,
you'd have a mess on your hands,
but you know,
anybody knows if you dig a hole and put
your hand on there,
it's cool down there.
Wow.
I'm fascinated by these,
uh,
Alaska shows,
all these different subsistence shows.
Have you seen any of those con men and
all these different shows and these
people just live up there and they'd
been living up there for generations
just,
you know,
trying to get by killing rabbits and
eaten them.
And a good,
good lot of crafting this man.
Carnivores straight up with that.
Oh,
100 percent.
I mean they grow some vegetables in the
four months that they have to do so they
have like a greenhouse and shit,
but most of their food they're getting
from,
you know,
shooting animals.
What are the native Americans.
I know it varies on in the country,
but where do they get their vitamin C in
their micronutrient freshmeat GNC
that GNC is.
You don't get scurvy.
Freshman,
there's this amazing story.
Yeah,
there's this amazing story,
but yeah,
this is the blood in it.
Yeah,
drive it,
drive me,
lose it.
So even when you,
when you put in,
when you put fruit in it,
if you're making fruit Jerky,
put bananas in a dehydrated or
something,
fruit loses vitamin C you through
dehydration on there's some loss of it.
There's this amazing story about the
French.
When the French started going,
coming over here to engage in the trade
and do all their explorer and they were
centered around like a focal point of
the St Lawrence Seaway,
champlain guy that's now the father of
new France.
He had this idea where he's going to
take a orphans from Paris and bring them
over and given to the Indians thinking
that the kids already knew French.
He'd give him to the Indians.
They need to go take them off for a
couple of years,
come back and they'd be bilingual and
he'd be able to use these as emissaries,
ambassadors and trade,
and one of the first ones that we know
about that you tried this with is this
kid who's later.
We now people come,
Etienne Brulay gave them to the Indians
and the when the first winter when they
came in with champlain is people came
over,
they died like mad of scurvy all winter,
but this kid was supposed to go hang out
with any of this so they would go out
and fish through the ice and hunt and
they were eating the meat diet,
but they had,
I don't know,
24 fatalities that year.
The vast majority of people all died
could never died and everybody else's
holed up in their cabins,
eating hard tack and salt pork and
stuff,
and this kid that was out roaming around
eating fresh killed,
meet,
survived,
and then later went on to do all these
amazing.
Made all these discovery.
He was the first person to see lake
superior.
First person all over the Great Lakes
went down all the way.
The [inaudible] river might've been the
first white guy ever.
Lay eyes was behind.
It was,
you know,
it's,
it is just A.
Joey is a.
There was apparently something in the
Laurel and hardy called the sasquatch.
Hannah hat company and the Susko and a
hat company,
like they had shitty hats and they'd put
the hats on.
The top would pop off like this is
really old stuff.
And Joey Diaz once went on this crazy
rant for like 10 minutes about how our
weed was Susko handle.
We need this fucking sucks into weed.
And I didn't know what he meant.
I thought he was talking about Hannah
Montana,
so it was totally confused.
I was like,
what the fuck are you fucking feed me
over here?
But anyway,
they eventually eight,
this kid ate quiet dude.
Yeah.
That was common.
That was another gay man
you told me that a lot of the,
uh,
the tribes of the Great Lakes,
like cannibalism,
that's fairly common out there.
Yeah.
Mandated quarter people out.
Wait a minute.
What was the,
what tribes were,
were dealing with the Iroquois eight
Brulay,
you know,
that said that.
See he was going,
he wants to go and totally feral.
He went totally native and in the
French,
even the French even disowned him,
you know,
because he,
he had complained,
he'd come back for the trading season
with Indians and they complained that
he,
that he,
uh,
his morality,
he had conformed to the tribes,
like you're going to turn a 13 year old
over to some,
to an indigenous culture and go away for
a couple years and he's going to come
back still acting like a French
Catholic.
It's kind of ludicrous.
That's the story of target.
They were like really upset that he came
back and he was very promiscuous in his
hair.
He changed his hair and more native
dress modern.
So he integrated and eventually he got
into a legend,
has it.
I don't know how much they really know
about what happened.
Legend has he gotten a dispute over a
woman up on Georgian Bay and Lake Huron
and they cooked them and ate them,
Jesus Christ.
And they would,
they would boil them.
So what these guys would do in this
area,
like a lot of these tribes when the
Great Lakes area,
they would sometimes they would just
carry captives in the boat live and then
butcher one you wanted to eat them or
they would rate an area in butcher
everyone and to stack the quarters in
the bowls.
So there's accounts of people talk about
human legs stacked up and bolts just as
traveling,
food prune long and,
and all of that stuff.
You're making people eat parts of
themselves and you know,
like cutting off their fingers and
making them meet your finger,
you know,
like having a big sport out of it.
Just just comprehensible now man.
But people argue,
you know,
anthropologists argue that all,
all had that,
all that violence had some societal
function.
And you know,
I don't know this side of the function
of them.
So this brutality man legs in a boat for
travel food.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
We're in,
we're in New Zealand film and in New
Zealand we went and looked at this,
this island in this big lake.
And what they say is that the indigenous
people in New Zealand and South Island
Wedding Benner that long,
but they had been there.
They had some people would come from the
North Island and conquered the people in
the South Island.
It would keep stocks,
have them out on this island and when
and staked out and when they want to
paddle out and get them an Itam,
Jesus Christ.
It's like Cormac Mccarthy's the road,
you know,
it's kind of fascinating that,
um,
I got to the road,
I watched the movie until he was showing
the kid at to shoot himself in the
mouth.
And I went,
nope,
no,
thank you.
Need this fucking visual in my brain.
Yeah.
Um,
but the,
uh,
the idea that this was happening on like
a really regular basis is really not.
A lot of people don't know that that's
all in the folklore here.
The native American that's never
discussed.
It's always they were in one with nature
and how they were peaceful.
Do the wide band,
but white van,
they were human.
They were.
I know it's so hard to come to grips
with what happened to the indigenous
peoples here.
It's so hard to come to grips to it that
you people wind up going in wild
directions.
It's like did,
it was just brutal savage re,
you know,
it was just awful existence or that it
was just like peaceful,
harmonious existence.
It's like it's really hard to just be
like,
you know what?
There were complex and varied cultures
that lived here that had,
that were human works and.
All right,
well the Sioux,
you know the idea,
the,
the word sue means Indian and Indian
means enemy there.
They call themselves the Lakota people.
The word sue apparently was what the
other Indians called them.
There's a similar thing with basketball.
It was a derogatory term.
The athabaskan people refer to the
coastal people as you know,
years of raw fish or whatever and it
became like a derogatory term that
stuck.
It's really crazy when you stop and
think about the idea that up until
whatever it was 14,000
years ago and the first people who
wonder when did the Vikings get here?
Me,
the first year was the first humans here
in north for $14,000
was for as humans,
you know,
just think about these people that lived
like no one else in a big continent
anywhere in the world.
They traveled the entire thing and they
had all these little tribes and they
were hunting and they were all living
this crazy sort of hunting,
gathering lifestyle,
like an entire continent filled with
people doing it.
It's really fascinating.
Now,
according to a lot of scholars,
they believe that there are 20 plus
million,
a native American Buffalo.
You know,
when you,
uh,
though the episode that you shot wild
buffalo in Mexico.
That was a fascinating episode and it
made me really stop and think about
what,
when you were describing the imagery of
what it used to look like,
seeing buffaloes roam across the
country,
that they would be like,
like
the shadows from giant clouds,
just like the entire land would be
covered in buffalo.
And this is how it was for these fucking
people that lived here for what,
10,000
years or something from whenever the
water.
The ice thawed and became the Great
Lakes experience in apocalypse of sorts.
It wasn't a fucking Avatar.
It's the,
it's the avatar movie.
I mean,
it really is.
It's crazy shit.
If you really stop and think about the
fact that the entire continent have all
these people living this well we think
of is like a very romantic life,
you know,
campaign with leather,
tps and shit and out there making fire
and dance in and hunting and it's pretty
nuts.
The rest of the country shooting canon
balls off a boats and you know what I
mean?
They're fucking,
they're developing eyeglasses and
navigating the seas and giant hamp sales
and medicine and these fucking people
arrived around even riding on horses.
Right?
It's like they weren't even until the
Spaniards came.
Right.
It's funny that so many,
so many guys that hunt become interested
in,
in like early cultures and it's obvious
that if you'd like to hunt animals,
you become interested in hunter gatherer
societies,
you know,
but just to look at it,
not from that,
just from like how great the hunting
most of bad,
but look at it from other aspects.
Just like to live like,
like the with the plains Indians.
The proximity to death is you cannot,
unless you're living in the most war
torn region of the world today,
you probably can't fathom the proximity
to death that you lived around.
Yeah.
That you could.
It's so weird now.
Like our culture is so easy and so soft.
I always meet people who are in their
thirties and forties and I'll be like,
I've never seen a dead person.
Like you can go through life and not lay
eyes on a dead person.
I didn't see a dead person.
I think like real close up until um,
my grandfather died and then he was a,
they embalmed him so it didn't even seem
real at all.
They had makeup on him and it's really
strange.
I didn't recognize my grandfather in.
They're hard as a rock and then they
just seem like these weird empty vessels
because what they,
what they do is what,
don't they suck you dry.
I mean,
yeah,
they drain,
you name it and then they,
they use formaldehyde I guess,
and do fluid or whatever.
I mean they do,
don't.
They do it with like an IV drip or some
shit like that.
I don't know how they get in the veins
of the formaldehyde.
Yeah,
it's fucking gross out in the woods,
man.
That's what I'd like them all.
So have you ever seen the Tibetans sky
burial?
Jamie put up,
pull up some images of Tibetans,
sky burial.
What they do is they take a body and
they uh,
they,
they quarter it,
they chop it up,
they smash the bones down and then they
leave it out there for the vultures.
Vultures come in there and essentially
pick everything clean if like I could
trust my brothers to do it.
Like I just trust them implicitly,
but there'll be,
they're older than me so
they'd be too old.
But I'd be like if I knew someone I
could really trust and I said when I
die,
I want you to just take my body out to
like a lot of bears and stuff and just
chop it up real good and just stir it
into the ground,
you know?
And that way,
even though it'd be dead,
wouldn't even know what actually
happened.
It would just be nice to have it be the,
as I was dying to be like that,
that,
that will happen to you even want to be
a chopped up because you don't want
people still remains a call nine one one
and say,
oh yeah,
if they just leave you out there,
it's like someone's gonna find you.
They're going to go out there and be a
big investigation and you know what I
mean?
Question about finding animals,
about finding dead mountain lions and
bears.
Is that because when they know they're
going to die,
they go somewhere and squirrely and like
tuck away.
We're noticing.
Is that it or is it.
That's.
Oh,
you see him when you get,
when you get a bad hit on an animal.
Right,
right,
right.
And you get a bad hit an animal.
And if he'd go,
if you,
if uh,
if you get to hit on an animal,
the bow or you know,
firearm and he lives beyond that initial
rush.
They're usually gonna die tucked away
somewhere.
They go into the thick stuff.
Yeah.
You know,
under,
like the,
you'll find stuff tucked up under
juniper's.
I'll just do this year after we went out
and hunted deer,
Montana and found where a,
a really beautiful big bark.
Um,
I'll just happen to stumble into it,
but he had obviously I feel like he'd
been hit because he had a,
he had a perforated antler.
Someone had shy.
Um,
I,
my,
my take home,
someone had shot at him and hit that
antler where the bullet,
because he had a,
he had a big bullet type wound on his
aunt or like a,
like a,
like would bullet hidden would but it
had cracked his skull plate so it didn't
kill them immediately.
But he was so tucked up under this
juniper Bush just,
he just laid up onto there to hide.
Like he knew he was vulnerable,
just died up there.
And I think it happens all the time,
man.
No,
it seems to make sense.
Especially a hug cause they don't want
to get hit by a predator.
They know they're down,
you know.
But what about what a,
like predators,
like bears are big cats.
You know,
I've found bear,
I found
bear schools and I can't,
I've never found a like a fresh dead
enough barrier to really tell it what
its positioning was when it was dead,
but I found a number of like remains of
bears but never where I knew that it
that like this is it spot it had gone
to,
but like I said,
when you get it,
if you get a hit on something with a
ball and you don't kill me,
like you may be hitting liver,
hit it somewhere was going to live a
little while.
When you find it,
you'll generally find it where it didn't
die on the run.
It laid down and died and when they laid
down,
they're usually pretty careful to get
tucked away somewhere when it can be
tough to find stuff.
When an animal like this diocese,
deer dies of it,
left his body behind would eventually
something to eat.
The bones of the head,
you know,
you
wind up with is you wind up with a.
You wind up with this right here.
Oftentimes the base.
Yup.
This is real thick.
You'll delete this one
time.
Just,
I remember one time for the folks at
home that are listening,
what would he.
We're talking about the base of a deer
skull,
so that gets the base is the hard spot,
but around that frame and see that more
than anything else
you see like,
can I get this where you see the problem
is most people are listening and they're
not just people are getting this off
itunes or like listening to it on
Sirius.
So the part on a um,
um,
the part you find most often when you
see like a kill,
it's been consumers,
you find where the spinal cord enters
the skull,
that thick bone area right there
extending up into,
around the base of the antlers running
non antlered game around horned game,
extending up to what would be kind of
the space between the ears is just a
thick and doesn't get consumed.
But one time I remember we killed my
brother and I killed a cow elk.
This is in,
uh,
in Montana,
southwest Montana in areas a lot of
grizzlies.
We killed a cow elk and went back a week
later to see what had happened in
grizzlies had been on it.
They had eaten the hide.
Whoa.
That eaten all the bones.
The only part we could find was just a
disk of bone with the.
The center of the remaining piece of
bone was where to spinal cord passes
into the skull,
that heavy boned dairy,
the frame May and I think it was worth
in a donut size chunk of bone like that
and you could tell that it didn't just
go away,
that it wasn't like a drug.
It's somewhere we couldn't find it
because you could account for the all
that hide and all that bone in.
The shit that was left.
It was all there and it was like a
sounds cubs or something.
Got on it and it was all still there.
That trip we went and killed another elk
and pack that elk and when we went back
up there later on,
the same thing happened to that one.
Isn't it true that a grizzlies tend to
prefer meet?
That's kind of rotten to the.
Yeah.
People say like when it kills something,
when people watch a bear,
black bear or grizzly make a kill,
they'll,
they'll eat that soft tissue first so
that they,
they rip his belly open,
lungs,
heart,
liver,
and generally it's like they'll,
what they'll do is when they covered
with grass,
some people even say that somehow and it
covered a little bit of dirt or covered
in grass aids decomposition.
Um,
and they'll lay around on it,
they dedicate on it,
you know,
other things.
And they'll eat it as bacteria.
They don't,
they don't.
Generally,
they don't generally kill it and
immediately started eating red meat
alliance differently.
Lions don't like all that rotten meat
lines,
like fresh stuff.
It's like the bears like,
bears like pretty like pretty rotten
stuff,
man.
You,
I remember one time being,
being again,
we're remember what we were doing.
We were hunting for something or
another.
And on Prince of Wales Island,
am I the shack we own?
I remember watching the wolves.
You think a wolves like eating fresh
meat everyday.
You will throughout the year.
It takes pounds of meat a day to keep
that thing alive.
But we sat there watching,
we sat there watching for wolves,
eating salmon.
This is after the spawning room,
this isn't a fall and they're eating
salmon that are so rotten that they're
in a putting like consistency of putting
lake state and just putrid like I can't
even imagine like putrid,
like it would take it if you walk
through one of these areas that one of
these stream miles where all these sam,
we're laying dead.
I have a strong stomach.
It would,
I would need an hour or two before I
could eat.
Really.
It was just overpowering and watching
these wolves basically lapping up San
and soup,
putting like salmon or Ryan to uh,
putting leg and says,
I can try to be an animal as I can.
Like,
try to think like an animal.
An animal becomes animalistic.
Now you need serious enzymes in your
stomach and mouth to handle that.
Not get sick.
Do it's a mystery there.
Like the cleanup crew,
the bears,
like the cleanup crew,
your bones like that.
Just eat everything swelled to say like,
like hiring.
As you know,
there's like a,
there's a relationship that a
relationship,
an Africa between like Cheetahs and
hyenas where she doesn't make a kill,
they can't cross the bone and in Hyannis
and go in and hang out and wait because
they know that when that's done,
there'll be the first in their nose and
they can crush bones and I remember,
I don't know if this theory is in in,
in fashion anymore,
but it used to be in fashion that early
hominids like early humans seem to
appear in the fossil record outside of
Africa at a time that was
contemporaneous with the appearance of
Saber tooth cats.
The thinking being that that the saber
tooth cats weren't able to crush bone
because of the makeup of their dental
structure.
Teeth.
They couldn't crush bone and they were
really effective predators and people
have become a cost on the following
saber tooth cats to scavenge bone marrow
and things that they left behind.
I read this long ago,
I don't know if that's been hard,
but other funds can't be.
No,
but I mean just that they're there.
They're leaving kills out there and if
you're like,
if you're the term Apex Predator,
there's a lot of benefits to being the
apex scavenger,
which is after the top dog does what
he's going to do.
Who gets to be there first,
right?
How much can they eat of an elk?
Yeah.
So like the wolves,
Kyla,
if wolves kill an elk and get what they
want off.
It was a big benefit to whoever comes
along behind who's ever the second roll
up.
And it's the little guys that come
later,
you know what I mean?
Little guys later.
But first it was like a coyote hang in
there and he's like,
when he's done,
I'm in there man.
And then you guys get in line behind me.
You know,
it's fascinating that there's a balance
of that system that the wolves want the
fresh meat,
but the bears want the rotten meat and
you know,
it's really interesting.
It's amazing how the system is covered.
Got All the bases covered.
The,
uh,
the way the area where we were,
the breaks,
the Missouri River was like the most
hostile place for life I think.
Uh,
I've ever been
to be cold,
wickedly hot and not much to eat.
Not much.
They're people that it was a place for
a,
it was a place for carnivores,
man.
You know what I mean?
There's so,
there's some edible wild plants,
but the people in there would go in
there and in,
in,
in a historical.
I mean like,
you know,
Lewis and Clark went through there and
generally people traveling through there
would um,
have fantastic luck with hunting.
You know,
it doesn't look like it's still,
it's still got a lot of animals today,
but something about that river.
It was just game down there,
you know,
things went through there.
There's not a lot of water in that area,
so it's reliable place to find water.
It's good.
It's a great place for hunting and other
things.
A lot of agricultural practices and
stuff.
Not so great and it's always been,
it's always been a hunter,
like a place for hunter gathers.
You weren't clued me into what it used
to be that it used to be a gigantic
ocean and now that is really crazy.
I'd heard of them finding a fossilized,
uh,
ancient teeth of different fish and I
think one of the shells we were fine and
I was convinced it was a mining
operation was dead serious.
Like see those hills that's reminding.
Oh no,
man,
this river here,
the reason that run over here,
the mining expert,
Brian County,
that's a classic example of me when I
get a little excited.
I'm like,
I know everything.
Those are track marks,
but.
But it is interesting too
called the breaks because it was that
you're on the bench of the Great Plains
in the Missouri breaks is where the
landscape seems to break and crumble
away down into the canyon and the
Missouri River and it's just like deeply
incised.
Yeah,
there you go.
Yeah.
It was a fascinating place,
man,
of what the folks don't.
If you don't see this,
there's these grey hills and it's
basically these gigantic mountains of
silt.
And what's really weird is there's like
patches of timber and stuff inside of
them,
but as you're climbing it,
like especially after it's rained,
it's all mud clay.
Yeah.
It's this weird heavy clays.
They call it.
It's an expandable clay.
It gets wet and swells and it does seem
you'd look at it like you look at the
brakes from the water and it feels like
use the term loosely,
but it feels like you're in the
mountains mountainous,
but it's almost like the opposite of
mountains.
Mountains would be something that rose
up the geologic pressures.
It pushed up,
but the breaks is the absence of.
It's like the absence of,
of topsoil is something was like washed
away.
So one of the Grand Canyon,
like the Grand Canyon is a very rugged
place,
but it's just because you.
Not that you add in stuff,
you took stuff away.
Don't climb that stuff like I eat.
I looked back at how much ground me and
Ryan had covered.
It was like a lot like even be.
It doesn't seem
like climbing to the top of that
mountain or whatever it was in front of
you and you could because you could get
a foothold that way.
But one of the things that I just
realized how difficult it is to actually
keep warm unless you're moving.
But when you start moving,
you know,
and you're outside,
it kicks your ass.
I mean,
did you spend a lot of time cold or are
you,
you seem like you're.
No,
no,
I get cold and that's the thing.
That's just a basic survival element
that
it's like when you're out and in
conditions are poor and you have,
you know,
especially cold with some humidity.
Like it was overcast,
it was a little bit wet feeling even
though it's a very arid,
dry area,
it was a little bit.
There's a lot of humidity on a trip.
It's just like the only time you were in
your out and moving.
But it's a little bit paradoxical
because when you get cold and
uncomfortable,
your inclination is to huddle into
yourself,
you know?
And so it's like harder to get out of
your bag in the morning.
You're kind of like paralyzed by the
cold and paralyzed by the young,
like how uncomfortable you are.
But you'll notice that the minute you
start hiking up a hill,
you feel great and you can be out there
all day and you're having a good time
and you stopped and you feel like hell.
And when you feel like hell,
it gets.
It's hard to get motivated to do it
again.
And I think that something that comes
from spending a lot of time on
comfortable,
it's just you get in your head that you
just got to move.
And,
and I think that when it's really cold
weather,
you try not to do anything.
Sydney,
you get up in the morning and you go
immediately from your sleeping bag to be
moving.
When it's time to eat you to stop for a
minute and eat while moving.
You never stopped for mealtime.
You this man,
the only way you're going to be able to
deal with over time,
you'll feel cold and you feel great.
And yeah,
one of the things that we talked about
when we did this trip was that I was
never like tired during the day or I
wanted to take a nap or something very
different than the um.
The the idea of getting up in the
morning and just hiking around all day,
but yet all the time completely alert
all the time completely.
Like we were wide awake.
Whereas like,
you know,
if you're,
you have a regular job or whatever you
do after five or six hours,
you're like,
oh,
get me the fuck outta here.
You start yawning and stretching.
I didn't ever feel like I needed to take
a nap and we got to this really weird
regular cycle.
We're going to bed at like 8:00
and that will go right to sleep.
And I'd wake up early and he was like,
it was like this weird sort of natural
cycle that you.
First time we'd ever been living by
natural light,
but we weren't around any of our beeping
gadgets.
Not Wonder fast.
Fuck it.
I think it's a huge part.
I mean,
I think you find something,
um,
I mean just think about just in a,
in a setting like how much we were just
like our physical beings.
We're shaped by that lifestyle,
you know,
of,
of operating according to daylight
hours,
you know,
being out in search of food.
I don't mean to get it,
you know what I mean?
To get out like,
you know,
new age.
I don't don't mean to get all like
nostalgia
and new age.
Those are good words for it,
but when you're out doing that kind of
thing,
you're out.
Like hunting on the land,
using your senses,
looking for food,
you,
you start making sense to yourself,
you know,
I think you,
you can be like,
it's safe to say that there's something
about me that really thrives on this.
You know?
It's like there's something about me
that just likes this kind of energy.
I think most people find it
primal thing that's just ingrained in
our system that from the hunter gatherer
days of,
or it's like all a part of us.
I think there's,
I mean,
just think about what we know about just
like,
you know,
selective pressures.
There's an enormous amount of selective
pressure and being able to do that kind
of stuff.
I think that now people would argue that
the new life we have now in technology,
we were under new kinds of selective
pressures.
You know,
there's probably right now those of us
who are going to thrive,
you know,
um,
those,
those are going to thrive or are adapted
to a technological society.
But now it's not,
it's not tied in now to birth,
you know,
it used to be that we had such low life
expectancies and high mortality rates.
Those are the people that could thrive.
Really good hunters were the ones that
were having that access to females.
They had young.
Now it's kind of a given that you're
going to have reproductive
possibilities,
you know,
you'd be the biggest loser in the world
and not do anything and you still get
people pregnant and have kids.
So I think that selective pressures
don't work on this now like they used
to,
but for a long time we are shaped by,
you know,
you had to be a productive member of
your culture.
You had to be a productive member of
your clan in order to have the kind of
cache that was necessary to be able to
breed women.
When I lived in Massachusetts was my
fishing phase phase.
My childhood.
I go fishing everyday.
It was a member of the Bass Angler
Sportsman Society,
the whole deal.
I spent all my free time fishing for a
couple of years.
Loved it,
and it was.
There's some fucking visceral thrill I
think of hooking one of my first fishes,
fishes.
I said fishes,
fish,
fish.
I know what it is,
stupid.
But the though that visceral thrill,
whatever it was,
it was so shocking to me that to this
day,
like I'll look back and think of that.
I'm like,
that's got to be some like ancient DNA
shit.
Like he got the fish was like,
you don't know what's going to come
around the next corner.
And when I saw my first book,
I think it was the third day I got so
excited because it from where I looked
at,
it looked like it was a world record
bucket at 50 point bucks.
Literally I went,
I was at a buck because buck and I had
that.
I had nothing in my scope and it was,
my scope was moving around so much
because I got so heated and adrenaline
up that I had buck fever.
I could not shoot that deer.
Oh really?
No.
I was like,
Ryan had to grab it.
He was like,
you're going to injure a dog because I
was going to start squeezing rounds off
blindly,
which is wrong,
but I was so excited.
You know,
and then you get addicted to that.
Not only I have the other thing you
going to take the two.
I think when you look,
when you glass,
when you take your binoculars and you're
looking out and for like an antler and
a year,
and then you start looking at things
more intensely and differently,
like you have almost new eyes,
like you're looking at things,
you know,
the way you don't usually look at
things,
paying attention to everything and I
think that keeps you in a keys.
You in,
you just,
you start forgetting about yourself.
That's kind of refreshing
you.
Yeah.
You seize the t to look to look out,
to be on the look for game like you're
out there.
A sense where you're looking for deer
but use everything starts to pop to you.
Yeah,
because you're paying attention to
things.
It also thing I think about all the
time,
like in a place like the brakes.
It is because of the landscape might
seem to some people redundant,
you know,
it's like a lot of the same thing.
It's just like roll upon row upon row of
a hill that looks this way and sandstone
bluffs and it's like everything looks
the same,
but what you're looking for through all
that,
it's just like little subtle differences
and I think it's like the lack of
activity that sometimes helps you hone
in and look at things much more
carefully.
I think it'd be that if you,
if you ever notice if you walk into a
really crowded,
I'm shopping center,
walk into like,
you know,
you're going to like walk through times
square or something.
You get to the other end and he'd
sometimes realize that you didn't ever
actually really look at anything.
Yeah.
Because you were just in a miller,
it was so much you came away with
impressions,
like a sense of noise,
a sense of what you saw,
like snippets,
but there's nothing that you ever like,
like detailed in on it and when you're
in those places,
and I would argue that like the Arctic
is a little bit this way.
I think,
you know,
areas of Montana this way.
It's just like a place that people might
look at and be like,
oh,
it's just nothing.
Just grass.
Right.
You know,
but when there's a deer out on that,
you can focus in on that thing and
experienced that thing in a way that you
just don't get to do,
to an alien.
The difference between a human life
living and walking through a mall.
That experience and the human out there
on the brakes and the Missouri breaks.
Like you want to talk about two
completely different.
Well,
yeah.
One Enrica says that he thinks that part
of part of maybe the epidemic of people
who are have hyper vigilant a central
nervous systems and our become like
weirdly autistic might be that we're
evolving because human beings today
experience more stimulus in one day than
they did in a lifetime.
It only makes sense.
I mean how.
How else could you process the
information that just comes from a
television?
What?
What do you design to really see?
You're not really designed to sit in
front of a fucking television take in
Lord of the rings.
It's no,
that's.
You're not really designed for that.
That's all.
All these signals that are firing off
your reward systems and getting your,
your dopamine levels and your.
Your adrenaline levels up and you
getting engaged in the action.
That's a crazy thing.
It's like a.
it's almost like it's a step away from a
simulated reality,
but it's really moving in that
direction.
You get these gigantic thrill rushes
from a giant television.
It's really weird,
weird stuff.
When you stop and think the impact that
it has
on the way we visualize our world
because so many people visualize their
world as if it's some sort of like a
plot and a movie.
They see the whole thing like a plot of
the movie.
When you're.
Did we talk about.
We talked about the Uda bombers
manifesto.
Interesting elements that I remember I
took this class.
I took this class in college called the,
I think it was called political
rhetoric.
We read various pieces.
Everything from Martin Luther King that
the unibomber and everybody had this
point that I messed up.
This guy was.
He had just pointed out as resonate with
me where he talks about that,
that he.
He looked at levels of difficulty and
there'd be.
I can't remember what way it went if it
went up or down,
but let's just say as level one
difficulty was like,
no matter how hard you try,
you'll fail.
Okay.
That's absolute difficult.
That'd be level two is like if you try
super,
super hard,
you have a slight chance of success on
down to.
If you don't try it all,
you're still succeed.
Okay,
it would be like these five levels of
difficulty and he's like,
his gripe with technology was that
technology had brought human existence,
tilt to the level five.
It's like you don't even have to try to
succeed.
You're just going to be alive now
because you're gonna,
you're gonna be alive,
will reproduce.
You don't need to do anything.
It's just you're just taking care of.
We've got food surpluses,
social safety nets,
everything,
you know,
and he argued that Omar,
like our,
as neurotic as he was,
he argued that all of our neuroses came
from that.
All the energy we're supposed to be
spending to maybe survive,
you know,
was just now spent running a muck in our
brain.
We couldn't handle the free.
We can't handle the free time the
technology allows us and that's why he
advocated for like this human being's
definitely this reactionary existence
where you can go back to like,
you know,
an agrarian environment.
Okay.
Just
try to get your black belt in Jujitsu
though.
That's what I'm talking about.
The goals.
Yes.
You need tasks,
you need things to do.
I'm most happy when I'm going like this.
That's what I'm most happy when I'm
going,
no,
I'm not involved in something or
something's not stimulating me if
something's not,
whether it's training,
doing something different,
trying something.
The hunting experience was a perfect
example of that.
Like the ability to to go and do the
show and you know,
you guys brought to the table with so
much better than anything we could have
ever come up with on our own.
I mean the idea that you were going to
take us in this fucking five day camping
thing with no cell phones and no
Internet connection and you know,
that's completely different than
anything we would have ever done if we
just said,
all right,
let's go hunting.
What do you want?
We would have probably going to hire
somebody.
Yeah.
If we both caught it was time to go
home.
Dude,
this sucks.
Let's go eat.
Let's go get some steaks.
So glad we did and I'm so glad.
Looking back on it.
Ms Dot took five days.
The first day we get there pouring rain
and I knew it was fucking for real when
we stopped at
the,
with one of the spots where Lewis and
Clark camped,
you know that,
you know,
if you have any sense of history at all
and you sort of trying to take this in,
like how bizarre it really is at several
hundred years ago before the invention
of radio and the camera,
there were some fucking people that were
traveling across the entire river.
They were going down the Missouri River.
They were traveling across the whole
country and they were right there
camping where you're going to camp
and it's still like there's some notable
things that are different but it still
is kind of like very reminiscent of it.
And there's a friend who does a writer.
I've always admired a lot that the
writer,
Ian Frazier and he's written a lot about
the American west and,
and we were on that river one time and
he was just saying like,
he just likes it,
that it happened.
You know,
like Lewis and Clark came here and
camped here.
And he's like.
And then nothing ever really happened
over again.
You know,
when I think about that,
I'll point out you can go to site so you
can go to places.
I was at.
I was one time I was 20 because I was on
the phone with innovation one time
they'll sell them.
He said,
where are you?
And I was in New York,
we were trying to meet up and I
explained to him that I was out in front
of this bar,
like the white horse or something.
And he's like,
you know,
Dylan Thomas Drank himself to death and
died,
right?
He like,
what corner you want?
I said,
well I'm at this and such in that booth.
And he's like,
he's like,
yeah,
Dylan Thomas collapse like drain stuff.
The debt there.
And I was wondering anyway,
it's like,
wow,
that's amazing.
But then you think like all the other
stuff that happened,
you know,
people get hit by cars and like,
people getting broken up with and
falling in love and like all these
layers upon layers of other activities
that went on there in some way dilutes
it,
you know,
it becomes hard to picture.
But the Camper Lewis and Clark camped
and look at ego like,
no,
I get it,
man.
It's not abstract for me.
Even though we had stoves and stuff,
you're still kind of living and feeling
what he,
they were feeling to hold the bolt in
the morning.
Dark Brian Callahan just texted me,
heard us talking about him.
Didn't get a chance to listen to
podcasts yet.
I'm sure it was great.
That's good man.
Yeah,
that's funny.
So,
um,
but that was getting the boat.
Make some,
cover some ground on the boat,
get out pitch camp.
Trying to secure.
Meet through hunting.
Yeah.
Get back in the boat pitch camp,
you know?
Yeah.
All in all we went,
what was it?
Forty something miles down the river was
38 or no more than.
Well,
he went a long way because I remember
that,
that that trip back me and tell it back.
I was so cold and damp.
Dirty was really cool.
I go,
what's wrong with me?
Because I'm really cool.
I'd pull the sleeping bag out of my and
we just wrapped up because it was like
12 degrees.
I was watching that I that it was so
cold,
like it was 12 degrees and I was such a
baby.
I'm like,
you know what?
I got lucky.
I was with him and he told me American
Indian stories the whole way and you
didn't even didn't even bother me,
man.
I'm telling you eight hours of American
Indian stories or whatever the fuck it
was different than cold.
It's like the minute something
wet water,
like you get like a little bit of
moisture in your gloves just becomes a
different game.
I was watching those guys play football
and the playoffs in Denver and it was
minus three with the windchill factor
and we were playing football in short
sleeves and Ray Lewis Ray though was
just sitting there and short sleeves
even on the bench.
He's just sitting there like this.
I'm just thinking of himself.
I liked it.
You got no sleeves on.
It's minus three with the windchill.
Yes.
What was the actual temperature?
It was nine degrees,
so it was cold,
cold,
cold minus three with the window and
these guys were hitting each other,
hitting each other.
That ball's got sting your hands at that
time.
I think they have gloves on.
Was on
the river is so fucking shallow in some
spots.
That's the one thing that was really
surprising is that we went bought them
out.
This is a really fragile ecosystem.
That's one thing that's probably a lot
difference.
Of course that rivers heavily damn now.
So we're in that area.
You got dams above you and you got dance
below you.
So.
But I mean you spill a run it with
riverboats like paddle wheel boats,
but it was,
it was a confusion of channels so it
took a lot of skill to be able navigate,
but there was a continuous navigable
channel and when you damn those rivers
now you get a lot of sedimentation.
So the river would,
at times gets scoured out,
you get a mat,
you get a big flood in the spring,
snow is coming out of the mountains
coming out of the yellowstone area,
so it would come down here and just
gouges that area and carry all that
sediment away.
But the dams do flood control,
flood control,
and they form another function,
erosion control.
So you get built up over time,
just mud silt in the river.
And so the river is a lot different
than,
than it used to be in the river as much
as some of the surrounding topography is
very similar in some ways.
Some regards untouched.
That river is now a creation of damming.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
And the river goes to the ocean.
That river heads when Lewis and Clark
were talking about earlier,
Lewis Clark.
So Lewis and Clark,
when they got dispatched on that,
uh,
on their trip and they went up,
I remember they left in 18.
Oh,
two,
eight,
you know,
for her to original for four,
they went up in one of the things.
They had many tasks that they were
supposed to do.
But one of the primary tasks Jefferson
gave him was to find the headwaters of
the Missouri so people knew,
you know,
the knew the Missouri was a major
artery,
but where did the Missouri begin and
wherever it began,
was there a viable way to go up and over
out to the Pacific.
When they went up,
they found the headwaters of Montana or
the Missouri,
just upstream from where we were in the
headwaters they discovered were three
years.
They named the name of the Jefferson,
the Gallatin and the Madison.
So it was a secretary of state,
secretary of Treasury,
and the President I think is what it
was.
The name three rivers.
And that's what heads that river.
So those rivers had won like the
yellowstone heads up yellowstone lake
also national park,
I'm sorry,
the alternate goals another way.
But the Missouri and Jeff had Montana
and in a goal in flow all the way out to
the Gulf of Mexico,
people now argue,
we were so familiar with the Mississippi
that we,
the Mississippi,
his name.
We didn't know that much about the
Missouri because you know,
people have been dinking around
Mississippi long before the Europeans
have been messing around the Mississippi
long for the Missouri hydrologists later
and geologists later argued that the
Mississippi wasn't,
wasn't named properly that by any
estimation it would be that the Missouri
picked up the Mississippi and not vice
versa.
There were those two rivers came
together.
Like the Missouri is a true continental
river.
It's draining all the way from the
mountains of Montana out to the Gulf of
Mexico and the Mississippi heads like up
in Minnesota,
you know,
so they argued that that's actually what
went on.
So the Mississippi by is now the
Mississippi by name,
but in like a physical sense where
you're looking the Mississippi and the
Missouri,
I think the riverboat gambling is one of
the craziest ideas ever that they would
allow you to gamble if you've gotten
something floating and then the state
lines.
All right.
Isn't it ridiculous?
It's got to be in between state lines.
Yeah.
It's a gray area because they like a no
man's land because it's bordered by,
you know,
it's like,
yeah.
Once they don't,
one side was that I think that we should
have a gray area between all states or
you get.
You could do anything you want.
You just.
You can eat mushrooms,
you can get a hooker,
you can do whatever you want.
Anything shy of murder and robbery.
Just a wild west grey area where there's
very few laws that everybody knows.
Everybody knows where it is.
Crossed the Mississippi.
Why does that get to be the lawless
zone?
Like the Great Lakes?
She can't even see it.
She can be a massive area of utter
lawlessness,
but there's no like you can't go out
there and do crazy stuff that you can't
do on the bank.
Yeah,
but I'm saying a little gray area still.
You could have a whole resort out in the
boats on land,
on land.
Anywhere where there's a border,
it's fucking who knows whatever to
towns.
Well,
you know,
the,
the idea is being bandied about by some
really rich investors that they want to
build an artificial city that floats and
they want to put it and put it out in
international waters and the idea that
the international space station,
but something like that,
that they would be able to do this and
make their own,
like the Utopian society.
They're like tired of this nonsense.
He's libertarian ideals.
Everybody wants everybody who joins this
venture to be able to support themselves
and you know,
to decide as a community that we could
all work this out,
going to make a drink,
ganache,
Anglin,
and push that pitch out into the ocean.
But good luck not getting robbed.
There's a couple of good luck.
Exactly.
Yeah,
exactly.
That.
Don't do it in the Indian Ocean to adult
tooth fucking kidnapped all the time.
That's why it's like,
oh,
we went sailing and Caribbean had
notion.
Listen Dude,
people get people get robbed,
killed and raped and thrown all
the time.
Not Me,
man.
If I have a couple of navy vessels full
of navy seals following me around,
otherwise I don't understand people that
sort of trusting,
like we went there and made their
parents lived in the Bahamas on a
sailboat.
I lived there for awhile.
The uh,
they took a sailboat from Florida all
the way down to the Bahamas and lived in
various spots on the sailboat and I was
like,
you guys are fucking after you were gone
before you around.
I was in the middle of the ocean with no
backup and some pirates come up.
Happens all the time.
Oh,
definitely can happen.
I mean,
the,
I,
the odds are pretty small if you look at
how many ships are out there,
but if it happens,
you're fucked and it could happen.
I mean,
rich couple get kidnapped really
recently happens all the time.
There's always some new stories
like up.
Because I grew up,
you know,
in a landlocked state man.
Like for me,
for my,
like you guys might have had that
feeling of uh,
being in the break she had that feeling
of kind of like,
not overwhelmed but like,
like humbled by the landscape some way
for me.
Like I'm so new to maritime stuff for me
to be out on the ocean.
Like I didn't grow up like looking out
at ocean,
you know what I mean?
And for like for me now when I'm on an
ocean and I'm always like,
this is serious business man,
you know,
I mean I get that feeling of just like,
holy cow.
It's unbelievable when you get out where
you can't see land.
To me,
that's when I started getting that.
Like a very nice uncomfortable feeling.
My buddy,
my buddy used to for a living,
he used to take rich guys.
They buy a sailboat and then you'd have
to sell it to them wherever they were,
but promise in that when you do a winter
run along the Atlantic,
that storm season.
So very few people want to actually take
the sailboat when you buy in the winter
and bring it to you because they're
going to get caught in storms.
My buddy did that,
my buddies and he take a 32 foot yacht
and he got caught in a storm out off of
San Francisco in the winter,
well at night and he had strapped
himself in and he was trying.
He was trying to turn the boat because
he was gotten 20 foot swells that were
submerging the boat so he would get
submerged under the ocean and then pop
out for 14 hours and and now I didn't do
it 14 hours alone,
but he,
he had his crew under under ground
because he was the cab for 14 hours.
He did that and they,
they,
he radioed for a guy to get him,
but the guy wasn't experienced enough.
So then they had the radio.
A guy who had,
who did it a lot in Alaska to tow them
back in and they finally get that guy on
the phone.
I guess he flies in,
he gets in his boat now.
He goes out,
hooks onto them and told them to safety.
Fourteen hours at night.
I said,
how'd you know to look?
He goes,
you,
I would have to here.
I'd have to listen for when the swell
was gonna hit me because I couldn't see
it,
so I'd have to listen.
I hear just and I go and,
and you and I said,
well,
you call it.
He goes,
fuck yeah.
He was in a wetsuit.
He goes,
fuck yeah,
you're cold.
You're really cold,
man.
You're facing hands.
Feel like they're going to
fall off growing up near the ocean.
You get,
you get to use to it.
you know,
you don't really take it into
consideration of how crazy it is.
But I had a friend from Oklahoma,
I never saw the ocean before and we were
in Texas and he went to the ocean and he
was like,
he had just gotten back from the moon
who might as well plant wears a life
jacket.
He goes,
well,
they're two different schools.
What do you mean?
He goes,
somebody had done something.
I said,
why?
He goes,
well,
I believe that if you get washed
overboard,
you're probably be injured to begin
with.
It's much better just to drown,
really to sit there and die of
hypothermia for 16 hours later.
He said,
or sharks come get you.
they can be right on top of you.
They're not going to find you.
A lot of times.
My friend who,
uh,
went to my friend who went to the ocean,
he had a ticket cigarette before he
described it,
like you sat down.
He goes,
man,
lit his cigarette,
took a big brother who was worried about
began man descriptive power him because
he was in his thirties to him in his
thirties to just see the ocean for the
first time.
He really doesn't leave Oklahoma lunch
and all of a sudden these in Houston
made a trip down to the,
to the ocean.
He's standing out there watching it.
It's like,
well,
it's Kinda really fucked saying
something out of turn.
But David Blaine,
his his trick,
he wanted to cross the Pacific in a
bottle and so the problem with it and he
went out on a Catamaran in a really
fixed,
warm and people were like at bandied
about bleeding,
knocked out,
and he,
he's like,
I'm good with any of that.
He doesn't get any.
Then he got in the water with great
whites.
He's got video of him.
Swimming was great.
I don't,
I don't want to tell too much.
I hope he doesn't,
you know.
But anyway,
the point is that the guy said,
I'm a Sam Sharon,
who,
uh,
by the way,
his book is Great.
He goes,
dude,
if you get caught in a bottle and you,
if you were in a bottle in the Pacific,
you can get caught in a storm for 72
hours because he's crossed.
Be tossed around in that,
in that bottle for 72 hours.
That's a shitty way to job.
That's a shitty way to die because
you're not going to be able to keep up
with the roles for 72 hours.
You're eventually gonna get dropped on
your head.
You're not out for a second and you're
going to get elevated and dropped any
fucking head and you're going to hit
that thick glass wall and it's going to
cave your stupid face,
and I've got a friend that I wrote about
in my first book who grew up in San
Diego and he,
one of his first jobs,
he worked on a tuna boat and went out in
the tuneable,
sank in one of the guys use withdrawal,
and he stayed.
He stayed on the hatch,
covered with a guy.
He was murdered with drone and he
managed to keep this guy's body with the
judge.
They're pulled out and he was just done
with.
He went to,
he went to vet school,
didn't go back out on the ocean anymore
and change his birth date to the day
changes birthday to the day that he,
uh,
got plucked out and celebrates that is
his birthday every year.
He has a big party on the day you got
out of the ocean liar.
He's a veterinarian
up in St and he's a veterinarian up in
St Helena in the Napa Valley now.
He's just like,
I'm done with the water man.
Wow.
Good for him.
Fuck the ocean.
Ocean.
The ocean can suck it.
The ocean.
It's fucking terrifying meant.
But um,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
But Atlanta,
man,
thanks again man.
Thanks for taking us there.
We had the fucking time of our lives.
It was good man.
I look forward to get you guys back out
and that a sweet looking rack.
Yeah.
It's awesome to see,
you know,
what people are down because they want
last thing.
Yeah,
please.
Issue hunting trophies always comes up,
you know,
and um,
and I decorate my home with schools and
the antlers and horns and stuff like
that.
And,
and uh,
and people are down on trophy hunting.
I think that experience like that.
Like you went out,
you had a legit haunt,
you ate all the meat.
It's like now like that thing becomes
like an emblem of lot more and it's
like,
I think trophies are cool.
I think that having that,
it's like one word for be a trophy in
that where it'd be like a memento or a
talisman.
I don't know.
It's just like you'll always look at and
remember that a lot of cactus quilts for
that whole set of experiences,
you know,
it's not some shadow thing like,
oh,
I'm such a man that I'm not going to
pose his head up.
No,
I don't.
I didn't think of it that way at all.
You know,
there's so much controversy attached.
I don't have to tell you this too,
the hunting experience.
So the idea of killing your own food.
There's so much craziness on both sides.
You know,
the,
the people that are,
uh,
anti-hunting or the people that even,
that eat meat and wear leather and are
still anti hunting.
It's,
it's shocking how many of those people
that it's such a weird thing.
I can completely understand your,
your wife's point of view.
Not wanting to go and do the killing
yourself,
but the idea that there's something
wrong with the people who do it.
One of the things that I saw about this
new town Connecticut thing,
one of the tweets that I read,
I read a lot of crazy tweets,
but one of them I read with this guy
said,
if you're a hunter,
tough shit,
get a new hobby,
no guns,
and it was like tags,
like Hashtag no guns,
and I was like,
what kind of fucking.
What kind of crazy nonsense is that
hunter get a new hobby.
The idea that these people are willing
to get because of crazy people,
whatever.
Many to get all rights to own firearms,
stripped away to the point where you
can't hunt anymore,
and the idea that someone would just
propose that Tim Ferriss had problem
with voting.
The problem voting is fat guy gets to
vote to well Tim Ferriss,
Kosta cortical by somebody.
I can't remember who it was and I read
it and it was about said guns.
Actually I have a lot to do with why
there isn't a lot of violence.
They neutralized violence in some ways.
It's sometimes in the sense that if you
don't have guns,
you the guy with the biggest knife in
the strongest guy going to do what he
wants and guns are,
are,
have always been sort of in a society
they keep.
They keep the strongest guy with a knife
from raping somebody in front of 12
people.
Someone's going to shoot that fucking
guy.
Yeah.
I mean,
you can't have society in this form
without some form of weaponry.
You have to be able to protect people
against aggressive people from somewhere
else.
Right.
Whether it's a local thread or a thread
on a boat from another country like
Columbus and his boys.
Yeah.
I mean that's just.
If you can't control them,
if you can't stop them,
they overcome the same way the Europeans
overcame the American Indians.
I mean,
it's really the same exact thing you're
talking about.
You're talking about people being
overcome by other people.
There's only one way to prevent with
technology people that are armed the.
That's the only way to prevent that is
to.
The threat of retaliation is too strong
for one band of evil people to just go
in and take over a town or whatever with
with guns because otherwise,
how could you stop it if the whole
world,
the whole world was disarmed a Wa,
then you're talking about like some sort
of Africa.
Look at the Congo right now with people
like Joseph Kony and his group and stuff
who come in.
They've got military grade weapons.
They come into a village where nobody
has any weapons,
do whatever they want.
I mean the utopia obviously we'd be no
one has guns and you know,
if you go hunting,
then he used guns.
I guess the Utopia.
What if you did have that?
Then you'd have guys like chain carbon
and nate mark or who would be the kings
and call the shots because I'm not going
to fight those guys.
We'd have to band together.
It's like six guys and be like,
let's go.
So you know,
it's better to have a.
it's sort of a balancing act and it's
better to have some sort of an ability
to defend yourself physically and then
society can move on and if you can't
defend yourself physically just because
of your size and you're dealing with
some Shaquille o'neal type do that.
You just physically,
there's nothing you can do about it.
Then a gun comes into,
well,
they always say they say conflict
resolution in any society becomes
paramount like in a,
in.
In a.
In a society,
you have to have a mechanism for
conflict resolution because inevitably
there will be conflict among men and so
how you meet out justice and how you
keep order is very important for any
society.
If you think about it,
inevitably there's going to be conflict.
I think the thing we're missing is
teaching young kids how to fight.
I really do.
I think it's a gigantic piece of the
puzzle that were missing in the way we
raise human beings.
I'm not saying everybody needs it.
I'm not saying it should be required,
but I'm not.
I'm saying that having it readily
available all the time for kids in
school to teach them a way to get out
their aggression and not just
necessarily defense,
but also just dealing with,
well,
let's stop again.
I think it would stop bullying.
I really do.
I think if you taught kids martial arts
would stop almost all bullying because
kids would be involved in competition
and when they're involved in competition
and not thinking about picking on weak
people thinking about how to advance a
game so they can compete in whether it's
Jujitsu or wrestling or boxing or any,
any,
any of those martial sports.
I think if you teach as many people as
you can,
how to do it,
you're gonna have a much more polite
society,
you know,
and that outlet is very strong.
That's where they say,
that's why they say video games are so
popular.
It's an.
It's an outlet for our problem in this
country.
Countries,
not a gun problem.
Opinion.
Everybody keeps saying it's a gun
problem.
Guns are a part of a mental health
It's a mental health problem.
It's these old people,
but people look at that as being
something that they can achieve easily,
but the thing that I've been thinking a
lot about lately on the issue is that
it's the way that people look at like
constitutional freedoms.
I think there's a reluctance on the
right this traditionally this reluctance
to sort of disregard first amendment
liberties sometimes and and on the left
there's this tendency to want to like
disregard second amendment liberties in
the same way that someone,
this guy that said,
well,
you know what,
if you hunt tough,
you know,
figure something out.
You could look and say,
you know what?
The Internet is used for all these
things and in like nine slash 11
plotters communicated over the Internet
and various things.
So if you use the Internet for
communication,
screw you,
we're getting rid of it.
It was like no one would ever make the
case like we can be used for evil,
therefore it should go away.
You know,
it's just not a very good point.
You want to be in a situation where I'm
like,
for me it's like first amendment stuff
extremely important to me.
Second Amendment issues are extremely
important to me,
like I,
I feel that just to do reactionary
measures against our amendment rights in
thinking we're going to solve some
problem isn't right the same way.
I don't think it's the right to suppress
freedom of speech in order to in order
to like solve a problem that might have
come out of the right of assembly or
that might've come out of freedom of the
press that someone incited violence to
the press so they should be shut down.
Nor do I think that firearms owners
should be shut down.
I think it's a very complicated issue
and I think it also fosters some cookie
cutter type thinking.
Sometimes the people on the left just
follow that predetermined pattern and
behavior and people in the right follow
that.
No one is excited.
Everybody's taking a side on it and I
suppose we're pushing it as a problem to
solve.
Look,
there's obviously something going on.
What is the problem?
It's the problem is that everybody has
guns.
That way you can't stop me.
Everyone would shoot the guy if he tried
to run into a school and shoot people.
Is that,
is that the solution or is this solution
that you have to pull all the guns out
of people's homes and then the only the
military has the guns.
Oh,
people are going to be comfortable with
that either.
So what,
what,
what is the correct solution and how
much is mental health taken into it?
How much are SSR,
i's and whatever these fucking
antidepressants are doing to disturbed
people.
You know,
there's a lot of people out there that
need antidepressants.
It makes their life better.
I,
I've heard that.
I believe it,
but I also know Phil Hartman,
I knew Phil Hartman very well and his
wife was on antidepressants when she
shot and killed him and then kill
herself.
So you know,
I know that it is.
They want a settlement with Zoloft.
I know that stuff creates psychotic
behavior.
I know it does.
It's,
it's pretty,
pretty much proven.
You know,
when,
when you start having to pay off giant
sums,
it's pretty proven that there's
something fucked up going on with
antidepressants and the human mind and
it's not always,
but it's not everybody.
I think there's people that their brain
is just not set up correctly.
I think there's a whole bunch of people
in this world where they got a shitty
roll the dice and their brain is just
not working good and I think if you want
to medicate people and
just start throwing chemicals at the
problem,
you might not always be doing the right
thing and when you do that and you have
a really disturbed individual,
like it's in the case of over and over
again with some of these shooters.
The,
the hypothesis is that these drugs are
allowing these kids to much more easily
performed horrific tasks because they've
sort of changed reality.
That body's chemistry or.
Yeah,
well the blade,
the way they interact with the mind that
they allow you to accept things in a way
that you would normally have like giant
red psychological flags going off left
and right.
And instead it just allows you to like
deal with shit.
And that's one of the ways that for some
folks it helps them overcome depression.
You know?
It's like these things are very unusual
because one of the things that I've
learned talking to my friends that,
uh,
Romney's antidepressants,
including people that absolutely need
them and then people who've tried them
and gave them away is that they never
know exactly which one's going to work
for you and they'll switch medications
on your like,
okay,
let's try this.
How's that one?
And then a lot of it is just everybody's
got a different setup and what works for
you might not work for him and the only
way to tell is they gotta fucking try
shit out on you.
I have a real hard problem with that.
When you're dealing with psychotic
people that might have access to assault
rifles.
Like when you have that,
those things together and then you find
out that 90 percent of all these school
shootings are either someone is on
withdrawal from Ssri or someone who's on
them.
Ninety percent of that they were talking
that these mental health experts on.
They were talking about like jared
lauffner,
the guy who shot the Arizona.
He had been symptomatic for 10 years.
He was psychotic and symptomatic and it
was very clear that,
you know,
and the problem was he said that there's
in the law,
you can't incarcerate somebody against
their will unless they are.
Would love to hear this.
We're going to wrap this up.
It's 3:00
hurts.
Rather it's three hours in,
three hours in the show.
Turns into a Pumpkin.
We go.
What happens is the,
uh,
the audio,
when it gets too long,
gets fucked somehow in the process.
So the only way we could do is three
hours.
Yeah.
So we turn into a pumpkin.
We want to thank on it.com
for sponsoring the podcast.
If you go to one and it and use a
codename Rogan,
you will save 10 percent off any and all
supplements.
We also want to thank audible.com
and if you go to audible.com
forward slash Joe,
you will get 30 free days and a one free
audio book.
And thanks Steve Rinella.
And you could fall Steven Rinella on
twitter.
It's not ph like a pussy,
it's the old fashioned vampire.
Okay,
Steven Rinella.
Follow him on twitter.
And pickup is an excellent book,
which I'm really enjoying it by the way.
Mediators.
So you're really good.
Descriptive writer,
man.
Really bring people into the moment.
It's a great book.
I really,
really enjoy it.
I appreciate you saying that.
And it's called mediator.
And we're going to do this again.
The show is going to air sometime in
April,
right?
So come back again.
We'll do another one of these fucking
podcasts.
I'll bring some bear meat and deer meat
buderim alice that smoke.
And thanks for.
Thanks for taking us out again man.
We had the time of our lives.
Can't wait to do it again.
And uh,
so go,
go buy his book.
You flux.
And uh,
is it available on audible?
Did they have an audio version?
I looked forward to do with audio,
with the audio thing.
Like I don't know if you've ever kind of
backing away from it in a weird way
already.
Jody freaks tomorrow,
Opie,
opie and Anthony.
Greg Hughes will be here and then
Wednesday the Great Duncan trussell will
join us.
So thank you.
And that's the end of the show.
So go find some other shit to do.