Hello Freak bitches when all that shit
went down with Chris Kyle in the car and
when he said that he punched you in a
bar and get you sued the family like,
no,
I didn't.
Well,
I didn't choose.
The family sued him rather.
Excuse me.
I shooed him and he died and then the
shoot automatically goes to his estate.
That's the way the legal works.
She was never in any jeopardy because in
any writers contract you have insurance
from the publisher,
so it's me.
They portrayed and I became the villain
going after the widow and the kids.
Exactly.
That's the biggest lie.
It was a big insurance company that's
covering the whole thing.
They're not out a panty and they won't
be out a panel.
You had to explain that I'm sure over
and over.
No,
I couldn't explain it,
but the tie,
the trial got overturned because the
insurance came out,
so it's okay to lie in court,
but if the truth comes out,
you can get a new trial.
The insurance came out.
What does that mean in court?
You're not allowed to say that insurance
is paying for everything,
even though it's the truth.
You're not allowed to say that in court.
So what happens when you say it in
court?
Well,
it came out and the judge allowed it to
eliminate it degree and then the appeals
court ruled that the judge shouldn't
have did that
because having the judge say that it
sways people.
So they think that a fine tool against
the insurance companies because
insurance companies a big,
even though the other side is doing
what's called poor mouth thing,
they're getting up and saying it's
taxing them financially and lying
insurance is paying for all of it.
Don't get up and lie about it.
So the other side was saying this is
going to devastate our family reality.
Oh yeah.
Trying to influence the.
And in this case,
let me state this.
How overwhelming must be evidence of Ben
for the jury to go against the grieving
widow of the dead war veteran.
Yeah.
It must be pretty overwhelming.
Evidence was overwhelming.
The,
the,
the jury went from.
They came for me.
They said he was lied.
This didn't happen and we're awarding.
Well,
why do you think he did that?
Did you know him?
No.
You didn't know him?
No,
I mean I didn't know even how he was.
Thing happened.
We were there on the same nights we were
at [inaudible] because I was there for a
graduation of class 2:58 AM,
class 58.
It's traditionally every hundred
classes.
If you can you come back to the
graduation.
So class 2:58 was graduating the next
day on Friday I came out along with my
teammates from class 58 to attend that
graduation the next day.
So why would I say bad things about the
seals if I'm there?
That's what he said he punched me for
will tell because people don't know what
we're talking about because probably a
lot of people listening to this have no
idea what we're talking about.
So let me just fill my real quick.
All right.
The,
the book American sniper.
The movie with Bradley Cooper was just
giant hit movie,
very patriotic movie about a guy who was
one of the most successful snipers in US
history.
Right?
A very successful warrior,
navy seal,
war hero.
Everybody loved him.
Then he goes on the opiod,
Anthony Show and he says that he punched
you out.
You know there's a chapter in his book.
Yes.
Where he writes that he called me scruff
face.
Yeah.
And you said that I said scheels
deserved to die.
That in other words,
she accused me of treason.
Yes.
And I was out there for a seal
graduation.
If I felt that way about my old unit,
why would I be attending?
So he wrote in the book,
He gave you a nickname in the book,
scruff,
face,
whoever.
I mean he might not have.
Even when he wrote it in the book,
he might not have even thought that he
was going to give that to you.
I mean,
who knows what was going on.
My thought was at the time I was trying
to wrap my head around why anybody would
do this.
Um,
and I was thinking,
well maybe he's just trying to generate
as much controversy as possible to
generate as much income as possible from
his book.
And it just got out of hand.
I don't,
I mean,
I'm sure I was trying to put it together
because there was a couple of other
fabrications,
right?
There was a,
um,
a shooting at a gas station that never
took place.
And he said that he,
during Katrina he was on the people who
were looting.
Yeah.
That was disturbing because that's
murder.
Yeah.
And he also lied about his medals.
The navy had to come out and.
Correct.
He said he had two silver stars and five
bronze stars.
He had won silver star and three bronze
stars.
So he lied about three medals.
Well,
that's a good one.
In three is impressive enough.
Exactly.
And then they try to give them an excuse
saying,
well,
he was confused.
No,
you're not.
When you get a medal like that,
it's like graduating from college.
They give you a certificate that puts on
your wall if you win the bronze star,
the silver star,
but as a,
as an seal yourself.
And he threw me under the bus.
What does that feel like to you?
But this is obviously,
this is something that's very near and
dear to your heart who hugely.
He has made it to where I can't go to a
reunion anymore.
There were 170 seals that wanted me
kicked out of the Udt Seal Association
over his lie
and the lives of his buddies who came up
and tried to testify for them so it got
embarrassing.
His trial said that it actually
happened.
No,
they couldn't say it,
but they tried to say everything else to
make it seem like it did well.
How the hell they do that?
Well because they danced around the
questions and the lawyer rang and well,
you have to piece together.
There wasn't one witness that saw me get
hit and there wasn't one witness that
heard me say anything.
See attributed to me and weren't you
visible the next day?
No photographs that night.
Them posing for pictures with.
If I had said all this stuff,
why would they have take pictures with
me?
What is that feeling like when someone
just fucking lies horrible and when it
makes about a terrible,
terrible,
and what's worse about it is the media
jumps on it and convicts me of it
because why they broke the story when I
went off the grid,
Mexico where I couldn't even come back.
So they broke the story.
Do you think they knew?
I'm starting to believe that,
but why didn't it happen on the opiod
Anthony Show?
Yeah,
but that don't think that was planned
because I know those guys.
They are,
but that was the whole ball.
They all show did it.
He did it that day on O'reilly later
that afternoon.
So he wants.
He named you.
He just start naming you ever.
Oh yeah.
Then it went viral.
It went viral and everyone convicted me
because they said,
well,
this Iraq war veteran wouldn't lie.
Really?
I just watched a.
well,
let me tell you all that.
It's destroyed my life.
I can't get hired for a job during my
trial.
After it was over,
guess what happened?
Thirty four major media conglomerates
entered the,
the,
uh,
the trial with that Ama.
Ama.
See,
they call it or whatever have of
influencing the court of appeals to
overturn my verdict and they did it.
Thirty four media conglomerates,
the New York Times,
The Washington Post.
All of these media conglomerates appeal
to the Court of Appeals to overturn my
verdict,
but why?
Because I won on something called unjust
enrichment.
They want the ability to be able to
defame you and profit from it.
In other words,
I'll put it what they had,
what these judges accommodated them with
a,
there's going to be another trial.
They've ordered a new trial.
Okay,
so I got to go through it again,
but I'm glad because when it comes out
to juries and judges find kyle guilty
who's not going to believe it then and.
But the point is they.
They've ordered a new trial.
They've,
they dis.
They throughout the whole verdict of the
jury,
the federal judge who wrote substantial
evidence supporting the jury's verdict.
They did all that and they violated
their own rules.
A 76 year rule.
Here's what it states if,
because it happened during summation,
where the judge allowed it in the.
My attorney it,
it ended up for questions in an 11 day
trial and a half,
a page of a 20 page summary and it was
overturned on that and they overturned
it because they felt that it was undue
influence on the jury that they found
out that insurance was paying for
everything,
so was one factor.
Well,
and here's the deal.
If the rules state that if in final
argument they say something,
you must object,
you must object.
So the trial lawyer as a chance to rule
during final argument and the jury has a
chance to hear the ruling,
they never objected,
so they must object to undue influence
because of the fact that it was never
wait.
They never objected.
The jury was dismissed at 1158 at 12.
Oh,
Tuesday.
Then objected.
The judge overruled them and we were
done with it.
Well,
these two judges,
Riley and shepherd have now overturned
the case on something that was never
objected to in trial.
They objected to it,
so they overturned the jury and the
federal judge them.
They also overturned my unjust
enrichment claim because the media
didn't want it.
What they've allowed now is the media
can defame you and profit from it and
you can't get any of their profits and
no matter how they harm you,
while that's the equivalent of if you
went out and robbed the bank and they
caught you and they shouldn't and shoot
a two years in prison for the bank
robbery,
but when you get out,
you get to keep all the money you took,
so that's in this particular case,
this particular which will now be the
standard they ruled that way,
they now make it to where you can profit
from wrongdoing because of this case.
This is such a touchy case because it's
so indicative of the complications of
people because people are not simple.
It's really varied.
Archie,
he lied.
He did lie,
but any harm to be with his lie that,
but that's not what I'm saying.
What's complicated is he's also the
subject of this gigantic movie and this
symbol of patriotism where so many
people will say,
Chris Kyle,
rest in peace.
So many people would have.
I saw a cloud that was.
Someone took a photo in the cloud and
that's on a cloud.
That's Chris.
Chris Kyle.
It looked like a sniper in the car in.
This is Chris Kyle guiding,
guarding the skies.
Like it became a meme.
I mean he became this thing where he
was.
He was a representative of the brave
military,
like the portrayal,
but honestly the betrayal that Bradley
Cooper played in that movie,
that movie was so simplistic and so it
was.
It was like right out of the Joseph
Campbell Hero's journey.
Had I not gone to court,
that would have been in the movie.
Really?
I had to stop it.
They were going to have him punch you in
the movie,
the book.
Holy Shit.
And I had to stop it.
I know when we were.
When we were in trial,
you know what they tried to do to
diminish my role because when they knew
they were gonna lose their lawyer got me
on the stand and he said,
Mr Ventura.
He said,
would it surprise you to know that the
first draft of the doesn't have you in
it?
Trying to prove how insignificant my
first draft of the movie.
That doesn't mean shit.
Well,
the first draft of this.
Yeah,
but so what if the second draft as you
it though?
I said,
here's where my response.
no,
that wouldn't surprise me at all because
I said we've sent two letters to warner
brothers warning them that if I am
indeed in in this movie,
they will be next to be sued.
So we put Warner Brothers on notice that
if this is included in your movie,
you will get sued next and you know
people out here,
they don't want to step into a lawsuit.
That's the only thing that kept me from
being punched out in that movie and
portrayed me as a villain in that
frickin movie.
I'd never seen them fill in way more
than a villain.
Yeah,
right.
I mean that is insane.
It is insane.
Because what's.
What's crazy to me and what's
complicated about this is that there are
thousands and thousands of brave men and
women who have risked their lives,
sacrificed their lives,
and this guy becomes this this way,
and when he rises above,
including me,
including you.
Yes,
very important,
but he rises above all this and becomes
this icon figure.
Yes.
This iconic figure that you can't
tarnish and then the truth is irrelevant
and they're willing to sacrifice people
like you and the truth just for this
overall image of patriotism.
Yup.
It's crazy.
What a crazy place that must've been for
you still is.
In fact,
do you know that this person that I told
you about,
what the seizures,
that she's your disorder started right
after this.
I'm sure that the doctors have said
she's yours can be caused by stress.
So I hold Chris Kyle directly
responsible for the seizure disorder.
All showed that I had to face that
marijuana cured.
Did you ever communicate with him face
to face?
Only one shot the first,
uh,
when we first and June,
I didn't even know who he was.
And then in June of 2012,
after the book came out in January,
uh,
we had a settlement conference where he
kept saying that if he met me in person,
we could work it out,
show at this conference.
We agreed I would meet him in a room,
the judge in the corner and just ski.
And I,
like you and I are here.
We sat down in the room and I looked him
right in the face and I said,
why did you do this?
You never punched me.
He looked me back and said,
yes I did.
I turned to the judge.
I said,
there's no need to go any farther.
if he's not going to admit it,
didn't happen face to face one on one.
And I challenged his courage because
yeah,
he had the courage to go to Iraq.
He had the courage to shoot all these
people,
but he didn't have the courage to tell
the truth.
Daddy,
what a bizarre moment that must have
been sitting across from that guy.
And he looked at me and said,
yes,
I did.
What was the look in his face?
I believe,
and I'm not a doctor,
but I've done some studying,
I think he was a sociopath.
Sociopath can lie and hold a straight
face and they lie to the point where
they believe their own lie.
How bizarre is it that this iconic
figure and then look how he died.
Yeah.
Well,
he had no training and post traumatic
stress.
He's not medical and yet he's taking
this marine to a gun range.
Who suffering from posttraumatic stress
wouldn't common sense tell you not to
put a weapon in the hands of someone
suffering from posttraumatic stress.
Stress is different,
or what do they tell him to man up?
Why would you put a weapon in somebody's
hands who suffering from posttraumatic
stress when you have no medical
training?
House,
quiet,
qualified to treat this guy?
Well,
I would assume it would be based on his
own posttraumatic stress,
but he didn't have it.
He didn't have it at all.
No.
He was never treated for it.
He may have had it.
Maybe that's why he did what he did.
I don't know.
God,
what a crazy place today,
but,
but the.
For me,
it's like I've been accused of something
I didn't do.
I don't even know the guy never.
I may have met him that night briefly.
I obviously didn't get one.
One millionth of a percent of the amount
of hate that you did,
but just read.
I got read off for September 11th of
this year.
I was in New York doing this book tour
and I got read off in a hotel lobby over
this.
What does that mean?
Read off?
A guy yelled and screamed at me in front
of the entire hotel lobby,
Jesus Christ.
That's what I live with now and I
haven't been damaged.
My reputation isn't damaged over
something I never did.
When I was going to say is,
I obviously haven't experienced one,
1000000th of the hate that you have,
but I read.
We read this article on the air.
We were trying to figure out what
happened when your case was going on,
and so we read this article that was,
I don't know,
it was in the New York Times.
See if he could find the article
detailing all the various lies.
Oh,
that's an Yorker magazine.
New Yorker Yorker,
they did an investigation of him but it
stunning and just reading that the
fucking amount of hate tweets and
facebook tweets and you fucking coward
and you this.
He knew that.
I'm like,
Hey,
I didn't write it.
Okay.
I'm just trying to figure out what the
fuck is going on.
And if someone put something like that
in the New Yorker with verified claims,
I mean,
everything's verified.
What they were saying that he said and
what actually had happened.
It was all verified.
It's very,
very,
very confusing that somehow or another
this slipped through the cracks and that
this became their iconic figure.
Again,
not discounting along with you.
The thousands and thousands of patriotic
Americans that risked their lives.
And he is too.
Nobody's denying.
He wasn't a great sniper.
Nobody's denying he didn't do his job.
I've never denied that from him or said
that about him.
He,
he may be the best.
I don't know.
I'll still put my money on Carlos half
cocteau the marine as being the best
sniper I want especially now.
But uh,
but uh,
he,
he did his job and he did it well.
But why did he have to take an old
veteran?
That would be like me taking a world war
two guy and throwing him under the bus.
Why the fuck would he choose you?
Because I had fame.
He.
I think he got jealous that night.
We were at the bar because everyone
crowded around and wanted their picture
with me.
Wow.
I don't know.
He'll never be around to answer it.
I'd love to know why he picked out me.
I think because I'm probably the most
famous maybe or I develop to be the most
famous seal other than Dick Marcinko,
the rogue warrior.
Great books.
I read his books.
He's a friend of mine.
Richard Marcinko.
When you sat down and you're talking to
this guy,
how much time were you actually in the
room with them?
Oh,
a couple of minutes.
Was all the minute.
The minute he looked me in the eye and
said,
I sure did he hit you.
I turned to the judge,
said we got nothing more to talk about.
You didn't want it.
I offered him.
I shed.
If you will walk out to be with the
fresh and admit you fabricated this
story,
I will forgive you in front of the crash
and we will go on with our lives.
He would not do it.
He did not have the courage to stand up
and tell the truth.
It takes a lot of courage to admit you
lied about something that massive.
I mean,
this is in line about speeding,
right?
This is.
This is a massive,
massive.
What about ruining my life?
Ruining my reputation,
ruining my wife's life rule.
I lost my conspiracy theory show because
of it real.
I can't get hired right now.
I can't get a job.
My last job was on the Internet.
That aura tv because the owners Carlos
slim from Mexico.
From that you know who I'm hired.
Do you know who I work for now?
The Russians.
Russian TV are the only people that will
hire me because 34 media conglomerate
centered this case to overturn me.
You think they're going to hire me
now?
Explain that.
Why do you think they did that?
Do you think they did that?
Because if they overturn your case,
if they can somehow or another,
because they don't want a credit check,
but is that it or is that discrediting
you in like that was a gigantic hit
movie.
But if they decide,
if they can discredit you,
it makes that movie still value.
Not only that,
it stops me from running for president
don't,
and if they can discredit me.