Doo,
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo.
Yes.
You said you were in Seattle last night.
Yeah.
What were you doing?
So we'll stand up comedy,
cough it out someplace.
Kurt cobain and Nirvana played.
Whoa.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I mean,
he wasn't there,
you know.
I know,
but it's cool being in those,
I'm mean saying that doing these like a
lot of these theaters is like doing like
a,
like a functional museum.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The fillmore fillmore for sure.
Yeah.
With all those pictures in there.
Dude,
I took a bunch of film of the,
we were in the dressing room apparently
that's like one of the first places that
the led's lepen the led Zeppelin
led Zeppelin played really when they
first came to America.
Yeah.
That's cool.
I don't know if it's the first or one of
the first,
but uh,
yeah man.
I mean that is like as museum,
like is he Florida ceiling too with the
pictures and they're all over all the
way over.
Yeah.
It's a big ass place,
man.
It's not like,
I mean,
as far as like,
it's not that big.
It's like 450 people,
but I mean,
as far as like what it stands for,
like there's a few places like that.
Um,
the Chicago theater is definitely like
that.
You're just walking around that place
like,
whoa.
He had the look of it.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of them that are like
just so old that it's a,
it's kind of weird that they let people
just fucking run around on stage and
tell Dick Jokes in them.
They're close.
Where the first tour.
That makes sense.
I was,
hey,
go see everybody's takes place in Denver
first.
They went straight to Denver.
They knew not west,
not east coast.
They knew that's the spot.
Yeah.
Why fuck around.
How long do they went to New York?
Good question.
Six years eve.
Oh Damn.
1969.
Do you know that their lawsuit is going
on right now for stealing one stairway
to heaven?
No.
Right way,
right against who?
Who's too.
They still from?
It was a band.
It,
Bill Burr was the one that turned me
onto this shit.
Bill Burke called me up.
He,
because you're not going to fucking
believe it.
They were all fucking thieves.
They called,
they stole.
He calls me up and he sends me this a
youtube video to listen to and I go,
Holy Shit.
Like today I couldn't be a bigger led
Zeppelin for sure.
I'd love led Zeppelin.
I mean they're like do like a whole lot
of love is like my get high and sit back
with headphones.
Song,
you know old black people like it too.
Oh yeah.
Cause before they played hip hop on the
radio.
That's right.
They had I guess with whatsapp with,
that's all they had.
Soldiers went back,
pull shit,
white people music.
They were hiding.
Robert Johnson stealing all his music.
Led Zeppelin,
singer claims,
foggy memory and stairway to heaven
lawsuit.
Well,
I mean that's fair.
It's 50 years ago.
I mean that's,
boy,
I can barely remember shit 10 years ago.
How is this guy supposed to remember
shit 50 years ago?
Yeah,
but there's no way,
if I stole stairway to heaven,
I bet I'd fuck him.
Let me hear the boat.
Can we hear both of them?
We can't do it.
Can we play it word zoo for stealing it
for us and not have it on the youtube or
what'll get,
just get us pulled from the youtube.
I can keep it off of youtube.
Yeah,
I can keep it off for you too.
Okay.
So,
uh,
we'll listen to it and we'll be able to
talk to you.
And you want first the original side,
that side by side.
I've already heard the story that
everybody knows what stairway sounds
like.
Good song go up and down and speed.
And these pants.
This band opened for them.
Yeah.
So it doesn't look good.
It doesn't look good at all.
And this is it cause it possible.
This parent was like stole it from led
Zeppelin.
No,
no.
Apparently it's not because they
recorded it several years before they
tore it led Zepplin well sums it up.
Yeah.
I think they were cornered it like two
years before Zeplin did theirs.
If it's just like four chords,
they played the middle of the song.
Oh Wow.
What?
This is the original God.
Let's hear it.
It's God damn so close.
Well and another argument that someone
said,
they're called spirit.
It's the name of the song.
Is Taurus the best of spiritual?
It's a little bit better.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's God damn.
It's really close.
But someone said no,
I don't know shit about music and I know
you don't either.
Right.
This is the led Zeppelin version.
We know that.
Yeah.
It sounds so sandler,
but someone you don't know shit about
music.
Like you don't play musical instruments.
I don't know either someone to Jamie,
you might know this.
Someone said that the music is like a
very common commonly use series of chord
progression.
I don't know the exact,
it was only three chords.
As I said,
he's only three chords and rock and
roll.
Right.
I don't know what that means but there's
still a lot of times songs,
blues scale is probably what it is or
it's a form of interest.
They said that dad has been using many
songs before.
Is that true?
I don't know cause they're foggy there
old.
Once you hit like 60 you just pretend
you're old as fuck and you don't know
what's going on anymore.
That's a really good day.
What happened?
But I don't even know he had,
he had like legit Alzheimer's.
Yeah,
but looking back,
he really didn't remember.
We should have been like,
oh,
you didn't get pills,
man.
Not believing it was a cover up.
I should've like,
oh,
always cry.
Cry for help.
He's telling the world they can't
remember things.
I wonder like they're really close to
cure and that,
you know really they're injecting
people's brains with stem cells and
fixing all kinds of weird shit that's
going wrong.
How is that stem cell?
I've been thinking about,
you asked me about,
I've been thinking about it.
It's crazy.
So you heal like wolverine.
It's very strange.
So,
okay,
we'll it,
how far away are you going to grow your
Dick,
Ari?
Not My Dick.
My hair.
What about hey,
why that?
Why can't it stay there?
We'll probably have something for that
soon.
I Dunno man.
I'll never go back to here again.
How can I shoot back up?
I like having a shaved head.
It's so easy,
so I got a good head for it.
I look better with a shaved head than I
did around,
especially with the hair that I had
left.
It was just all sad hair,
sad,
sick hair,
coffin dying people.
It's like having a cancer patient living
on your head.
Does that though?
Yeah,
it's over.
It's over.
I come on shorter.
I like it,
man.
I like having it.
Sure.
Yeah,
it's bullshit.
It's like it was a waste of my energy.
Her shaved head.
If you have a flat back,
that's the worst kind of head.
It's like a laptop hedge that somebody
with would a shovel in the back of your
head just looks like a laptop.
Is Flowering a book?
It was a lot of dudes that have whacked
domes,
I feel for them,
but you know what men did.
This doesn't look good with Harry either
heads.
Weird heads are weird heads we need to
do is get one of them like a head,
like a fake,
but they just put it in your head and
plants.
That's a girl's like,
I'm like,
why is it will soften the back.
That's probably totally a good idea.
Probably most people aren't touching
your hood.
Well,
you could always say,
yeah,
I was in a motorcycle accident.
I last guys,
he turned me on me mind you just had a a
but put in the back of your head like a
fake it,
but it feels like like a rotting apple
consistency of it.
We were laughing at this,
right?
They do that to Chin's put double chins
and they put a fake Chin and people,
it's super common.
What do you mean?
They put a fake Chin on people?
Who does that?
Plastic surgeons,
I think they go in through the door,
like the lip area where the teeth are
and they shove like an implant in your
Chin because some people have a very
small chance,
like the Chin is tucked up in their neck
and they,
they feel like it's unattractive people.
It's weird.
He's chinless is bothering him.
No,
he makes jokes about it and that's good.
Yeah,
that's good.
Some people don't want to look around
about it,
so they get a piece of plastic screwed
into their chin.
They will take it to the next level and
then go to log.
They do at the back of their head.
That's what I'm saying.
Dudes with a flat back of the head flat
back around that shit out man.
Look like a normal dude.
I'm not against that.
I guess a not against that.
If they can make it feel like a skull
back there instead of just fucking
bench.
If it gets loose stretch Armstrong.
Oh yeah.
It starts leaking out.
What if you're banging a girl and she
grabbed your head and she pops it
losing.
She thinks she broke your skull.
Big Way to go to Goldie.
Crazy bitch.
What might happen to your head?
You did something which they get some
fucking wallboard screws.
Tighten that bitch down.
That's wholesale like replacements seem
weird.
Putting a fucking plastic plate on the
back of your head is not.
I guarantee you there's a plastic
surgeon out there right now running to a
notepad and writing this shit down and
he's going to offer it to dudes with
flatheads.
Are you a flat back?
You have to convince somebody.
They have a flood head.
Did your parents never buy you a pillow
until you were old enough to complain as
the back of your head flat like a table?
Well,
flat back,
no more
thanks to Dr. Crooked Heimer doctrine
quicker and himer specializes in making
your fucking mutant alien wrote looking
head.
Did you think you're fun?
You're not,
you're not fine.
You're not fine.
No.
How about those weird ancient cultures
that used to flatten heads on purpose?
[inaudible]
you ever seen those Peruvian James Peru,
I believe?
Yeah.
Well they think the Egyptian thing was
that implants and the launch of they
could have fucked with the shape of
their head,
but they also could have been like
inbreeding because apparently like two
ton common had a series of like,
well we'll go to two ton common next
Jamie.
Um,
no,
go to these like,
well you see that guy,
the baby up there where they're
stretching the baby's head out so that
the black and white one right next to
add Jamie?
No,
be their photo.
The actual photo go up and up the photo.
Yeah,
that one.
Oh,
that's like that's an actual baby where
they're distorting this young baby's
head while it's soft with pressure by
these chords and they tighten it down.
And this is modern times because this is
from,
yeah,
I mean this is obviously from a,
it's crazy.
It's crazy.
Wow.
Yeah.
So they can make them look like aliens
or they take it off [inaudible] wow.
It can totally like fuck the shape of
your head up forever.
And then that's what your head shaped
like now because it's all done when
you're a baby and your head is really,
so your brain goes into that dude,
you're fucked or you love it.
You know we're here might be your shit.
But if you look at like the images of
like ancient Egypt,
like right there,
he just clicked on that one like this.
They think that that was maybe part of
the practice that they were doing to
differentiate them from the rest of the
people.
So there was that.
But to 10 common apparently had a series
of issues.
He had like a,
some degenerative issues.
They think that he might not have been
healthy.
See if they like whatever.
Try to save him.
No,
not,
don't,
don't Google head shape.
T just go with um,
uh,
medical issues to tongue common medical
issues along that.
Ladies and a in Thailand.
Oh really?
Whoa.
Bigger and bigger than they can't take
them off because there was a kind of
wobbly.
Yes.
He looked like he had a cane and shit.
He was,
his body was all fucked up.
It's like,
why does it say he has breasts?
Why'd they give him breasts?
Ooh,
visit page,
please.
So we're looking at King Tut had
feminine hips.
Feral suffered from several afflictions
because his parents were brother and
sister.
Oh,
whoa.
Reading Good Leslie through on these
ads.
Whoa.
Oh,
game of thrones type shits on Friday
about the human face.
Kingtones list of ailments isn't the
result of ancient Egyptian curse.
The researchers were able to point out a
more scientific culprit.
Incest,
Albert Zinc scientific director of the
institute of Mummies and the ice man in
Italy used genetic fingerprinting and
tests on mitochondrial DNA to determine
the king.
Tut's parents were without a shadow of a
doubt,
brother and sister.
Fuck,
here's his list of things.
Oh yeah.
Rule out club was the curse.
No curse.
Just rolled it out.
Finally.
Anchor.
How crazy is nature,
man?
He had a prominent overbite.
Pronounced overbite,
Feminine Hips,
Club Foot.
Wow.
Workforce lose bones in his foot.
Jesus Christ,
loose bones in his foot.
Lose your los.
You're not supposed to fuck your brother
or sister home.
Not supposed to fuck your brother or
sister.
They worked out pretty good and game of
thrones worked out well.
Not really.
That one.
One evil popped up.
Yeah,
but his body was all right.
The girl was fine.
They made the girl fine.
She had had poisoned.
She was the only one that was fine.
This new one's a pussy.
God,
he's such a pussy.
Such a pussy.
It makes me angry.
It's almost like,
it's almost like they listened to the,
the um,
the protest against them from afar.
Whatever liberal.
I'm like,
okay,
fine.
This is what you want.
This is what kind of coverage you want.
We can do nothing.
Fine.
Enjoy this for three seasons.
You know,
it doesn't make sense though.
It's super hard to imagine someone
abandoning their mom when they're that
much of a pussy.
That's the most ridiculous aspect about
it.
Yeah.
Because that's one thing that puts these
want is they want to be around their
mommy.
Right?
You need your mom for support.
So like all the sudden he's so strong,
but uh,
who's in his ear?
The only chick was ever given out the
post to him.
That's that pussy.
So strong,
so strong.
And she's pretty and she knows the fuck
she's doing and she's got a gay brother,
so you know,
she's a freak to,
this guy's in America.
Killed all those guys.
Killed their girlfriend's ex husband,
her husband.
Right.
That's like a normal thing.
What was that girl's name?
What's that jail.
She tasted like a student in high school
and then made the student kill her hug.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
God Damn it.
That was,
there's been a bunch of them that not
met laterno right.
The Turner was just the one that Pam
Smart?
No,
you sure?
I think it's Pam smart.
I think she was the one who paid the
high school cause she went to jail.
Oh yeah.
You can't do that.
I mean,
I bet there's a bunch of others.
They really can't do that.
It's really just now.
Well people have definitely gotten away
with it for every like dumbed chick who
hired two 15 year olds.
There's a smart lady who hired an actual
assassin.
Right.
I'll,
did you ever go down the block Talia?
Uh,
youtube tools?
Yeah,
I did.
I have.
Oh,
I watched a whole special one of those
crime.
Watch them,
watch them laugh.
I think it's so casual.
Like you want to go for donuts,
good donuts plates over the hair.
Like as they're just finished this,
you're going to kill my husband.
That,
yeah.
And the way they say it too,
like I just can't go through the
divorce.
It's just,
it's almost like easier than letting
them know I don't love you anymore.
For some people it is.
For some people that actually becomes
what they want to do instead,
they're like,
I don't want to go through this divorce.
I don't like this guy.
I'll just fucking whack 'em
shut off.
Yeah,
they just didn't want to do it anymore
because if you think about it,
right,
you got to get divorced.
This dude,
what if he gets mad at beats you up?
What is,
he denies your money.
What if?
What if he fucking kicks you out on the
street?
If you don't care about them at all,
then yeah,
that's the easier way to go,
Joe.
There's just some people out there that
are just fucking nuts.
They're just fucking nuts and if you run
into those people,
you gotta you gotta fucking problem.
You got a fucking problem.
They're just fucking nuts.
And if you marry one of those people and
you live in one of those people for a
long time,
then you try to break up with them.
You've got to fucking problems.
What are you get to do?
What are you going to do?
You some lady from Nebraska just once be
on our own.
Just wants to be free.
She,
the,
the clutches of her father held it down
when she was young and now she's got
this fucking asshole,
this man that she's like legally
obligated and he says he's gonna kill
her if she leaves.
Yeah.
No,
I don't think so.
Bitch.
Dalia Dippolito,
she was calling the guy in afterwards
when she found out it was still alive.
She was like,
mark,
get inher mark,
come help me.
And he's like,
I can't,
and you tried to have me killed.
Stop.
Don't believe that.
He was like,
they showed me.
He goes,
that's fake.
He was almost still swaying to go back
to her.
Oh my God.
It was almost like,
what?
And he's like,
I can't help anyway.
They have you tried to hide someone to
kill me.
It's out of my hands.
They have you on camera,
bitch.
Yeah.
The power that brings you back in.
And they're such good actresses when
they find out,
they find when they supposedly find out
that her husband got killed.
Well,
they're insane.
Yeah.
I mean he's a lot of people out there
that are getting people whacked or
completely fucking insane.
They can shut off.
Oh yeah,
they're just disconnected.
I wonder if you meant from the truth
when,
if you met them,
she would feel that one of you feel that
vibe if you were talking to them.
I think it's just compartmentalizing.
It might be you shut that door and then
let it in as if it's new information.
There's also people that have killed
people before and it gets easier.
Like that story Jamie that you were
telling me about,
that they suspected some seal stabbed
some guy after a fight.
They got in a fight and then afterwards,
uh,
all have to pull a guy's name up.
I don't know.
Who knows if it's even true?
He stabbed him.
Yeah,
he stabbed him cause they're the blood
lust and well they got in a fight
apparently and then afterwards they
arrested him because the guy got stabbed
somewhere and died and they think it
might be connected,
but you got to imagine it.
Just forget about this story,
which I don't know what happened.
Right.
I'm trying to be fair as fuck,
but a guy who you teach how to kill
people who you hired,
killed people and ordered to kill
people.
It's probably used to fucking killing
Right.
And some people aren't and they might
say something crazy like,
I'll fucking kill you bitch.
I'm gonna see you on the street.
I'm going to kill you.
And they say that to a navy seal.
And he goes,
Oh really?
Yeah.
It's like,
okay,
well I'm gonna remember that.
And then he waits to get outside of that
building and say,
hey dude,
I don't really want you to kill me so
I'm going to kill you and he fucking
kills you.
So like who knows what happened?
But I would assume that if a dude gets
super used to killing people and really
good at it,
that's not the kind of fuck with,
yeah,
I'm not going to pull it up,
but I just googled it again.
His lawyer,
he might not have done it.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
There you go.
I heard this thing on her right now,
man.
I'm sorry.
But I'm just going to say,
people that get in bar fights,
they have a lot of fucking people that
hate him.
It could easily be a coincidence.
The reason to that up the fight is what
they're saying is that he detained them
on the pier for allegedly taking
pictures of underage girls.
So it's like,
Oh,
oh Jesus Christ.
Well,
maybe.
Yeah.
Okay,
well there you go.
There might be a lot of people that
wanted to kill that guy.
Yeah.
You,
if you're taking pictures of underage
girls,
you didn't,
you haven't like led an awesome pristine
life and then one day you're like,
you know what man?
Oh,
that's what I wanted to tell you to hear
the shit they found it Michael Jackson's
place.
Oh wait,
hold on.
Let me think of what it could be first.
Yeah,
I mean definitely under our child porn.
Um,
maybe a body,
no.
Oh,
just go ahead with her.
I look
like a whole underground ranch,
like another whole play area for when
the apocalypse comes,
that kind of thing.
Or possibly even a,
some unreleased tapes of music.
They never
would if they found a cash.
Let's be honest here.
They found a cache of photos of Michael
Jackson getting his dick sucked by boys
and right next to that cash was one of
the best God damn albums at Michael's
ever put out.
And what if the music companies,
the ones that found it,
wait and they get together,
they have a little music meeting.
When we going to be here this week,
we've got two options.
Either everybody assumes that he fucks
him kids,
but there's no proof.
So we forgive him and we buy his music
or we let these photos kit out and we
ruined the legacy of one of the greatest
artists of all time.
It would you look,
we're not going to save these kids from
sucking his deck.
They sucked his dick.
It's gone.
It's water under the bridge.
It would be a greater crime if we get to
loose this music to the public that burn
like a Jew.
We burn these dirty photos.
They're going to cost money.
They're going to take food out of the
mouths of your children.
These photos.
That's not fair.
My children to do anything.
Not Fair.
Your kids didn't do anything.
My children didn't come onto a
superstar.
Sal,
your kids are good kids.
They deserve the best education can
point.
We can't sink this ship.
It's got a door in these fucking
pictures.
You probably have a furnace going 24,
seven at any major record label just in
case something like that comes up and
get chuck a hard drive in there.
What did they fine?
They found photos of um,
adult bodies with kids' faces engaged in
pornographic acts.
Like weird.
I'm weird.
Pornography allegedly.
This is all allegedly who allege it
cause I haven't seen it and I don't
know.
I don't know what's,
yeah,
pull up.
Pull up one of the articles so we can,
well it's what's animal mutilation to
right.
And uh,
he had photos of that very good photos
of,
I might have some of that too.
Um,
among the items found were pictures of
adult binds with children's face is
super imposed on them.
Sexy pictures of his nephews in their
underwear.
Pictures of bleeding children,
the animals,
including a photo of a child holding
what looks like a goose bludgeoned to
death diaries.
Audio tapes,
video tastes,
prescription drugs to treat sex
addiction.
One inside of claim that Michael Jackson
had a book called room to play,
which included a picture of Jon Benet
Ramsey look alike with a noose around
her neck.
But that's,
but what does that one insider,
whoever that insider or is like?
I never trust that.
When I read that catch,
you can't show the pictures we're
talking about because other stuff.
Well then how am I supposed to form
just,
it's hard to form an opinion.
Yeah,
but that,
that,
that term one insider sensitize it just
all right.
It could be one liar.
Well,
it,
the problem is like when you say
something like that one insight or what
that tells me is you either don't have
enough backup up,
up,
up.
Right.
I know.
No other way other way down.
Yeah.
Uh,
okay.
Ron Zone and a former Santa Barbara da
was on the prosecution team.
Told radar.
Okay.
And then,
well,
okay,
well that guy,
he's saying something.
He's saying a lot of this stuff was used
desensitize the children he added,
we identified five different boys who
all made allegations of sexual abuse.
There's not much question in my mind
that Michael was guilty of.
Child molestation.
Whoo.
That's heavy.
Yeah,
we kind of that.
but that's also a guy who can never
prove it.
So maybe he's still like,
see,
but what's the weird shit is like the
house looks great and his Mugshot,
he looks really different.
That's Skelton.
Michael.
Well,
he looks like some sort of a creation
that's barely a human anymore.
Whatever he's done to his face,
he looks like Cgi of like two years ago.
So strange.
Well,
you know what it looks like claymation
maybe like a claymation.
I was just gonna say that.
Yeah,
like some sort of a,
uh,
like an artistic representation of the
psalm one.
Not an actual someone.
Yeah.
Like if you ever seen that Barbie Lady,
the Russian Barbie Lady,
no,
dude,
this girl spent like $100,000 on surgery
to turn herself into a real life Barbie.
So she doesn't look like a person.
Her.
She had her,
her like her widened and shit.
That's her.
Yeah.
Dude,
that wasn't a real person,
but it's a real person.
Fucking waste.
Go back to that.
It's just we got,
there's a little issue that is not a
real person.
It is dude.
It is.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of film of her actually.
Make sure that's true.
That's what I've seen the drawing.
I've seen a at least one toe but didn't
show that had her on and she can walk
fine.
Well they're all saying a person that
shape couldn't walk.
Well you can.
Yeah.
Just most people could never be that
shape.
Will they put course it's on.
They smashed their body down,
but look like her.
Her eyes with the [inaudible] logo logo.
It's weird man.
Like right there.
Like that's,
that's a perfect example.
That one photo that does not look real.
Who,
first of all,
that's how old this shit I,
this is like ruins the purpose of this
by them taking these photos with filters
because I could look like Barbie to it
filters.
You know,
you should show this like in a raw,
gritty,
close up.
I want to see her video of her talking.
Exactly.
Well,
that's what she used to look like,
and that's what she looks like now.
Wow.
You know what?
She was hot.
She was pretty,
yeah,
she's pretty.
She was like,
she's ethnic looking and she looked,
she looked hot.
She looks redneck hot to me.
That's what I like.
Yeah.
Barefoot drunk.
No Way.
Crazy.
Yeah.
That's,
look at these eyes.
Sleep.
Why Water?
Look at her eyes and the whole thing is
so strange.
Now that doesn't look too filtered,
but it's definitely filtered.
Right.
She'll look Makena.
Yeah,
right.
That's going to be,
you're fucked all of the future.
That's pretty,
that's close enough that I would go for
that.
Oh,
you would definitely go for it.
Sure.
That's common.
That's coming on,
or percent.
Hundred percent.
They'll that'll be in one of the first
versions of commercial artificial
intelligence.
It'll just have drives every industry
that it was more than porn,
my friend.
Yeah.
That's some sort of a prostitutional
loophole.
No,
I mean people are already using those
flashlights.
Oh yeah.
Wouldn't know.
Real feeling.
Humanity.
Yeah,
that'd be way better.
Oh fuck yeah,
dude.
They're probably gonna figure out a way
to have megan have actual skin.
Yeah.
I mean they can make skin in a lab.
They figured out how to make skin.
So if they make skin,
are they really?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
So I can make actual skin on a fuck
doll.
Yeah.
They can reproduce like little things
like,
um,
they've reproduced a person's bladder or
a woman got bladder cancer and they
recreate it or bladder with stem cells
and put it back in her body.
What do you mean they can't use it to
make hair?
They're going to,
they're going to figure it out
eventually.
But,
um,
the,
uh,
the Oregon thing there,
they're going to figure that out too.
They're going to be able to replace
hearts and livers and all kinds of
different things and make them all in a
lab and then put them in your body.
It's going to be real weird,
but they're definitely gonna be able to
make it a skin.
Did you feel the heart beating while
you're fucking a woman maybe shows now
heartbeat,
bro?
No.
I mean,
can they make that one was the one that
doesn't have rp?
It does.
When it does happen for sure.
Definitely have to beat a human before
they're like,
oh no,
you can't.
You have to ask permission from now.
Well,
you know what,
man,
I think it's going to slip under the
radar.
I'm not cause Hussein's at heart with
they have to go.
Who could?
It could give permission for this shit.
That's it.
He gets into almost like these God
realm.
Yeah.
What point did you get a live well,
if you,
if you keep going right,
if you take whatever sort of a robots
they have now,
they have some kind of goofy looking
robots know mostly just torsos and they
talk and some of the bodies move pretty
decent.
If you just go a hundred years from now,
do you have any idea how crazy,
whatever the fuck they have now,
it's going to be in a hundred years.
It's going to be impossible for us to
imagine because there's inventions that
you need to have before the big
inventions and those,
they haven't even been about this.
There's going to be some leaps in the
understanding of the very nature of the
universe itself and they're going to be
able to change all sorts of stuff that
they do.
And life itself is also going to be on
that list.
They're going to make it,
man,
they're gonna,
they're gonna make it.
And even if they make it like a fuck
doll that it has like a limited brain
that it's only good for like fuck
activities.
You can have it as a friend.
You just come home and this thing has
some sort of an artificial brain that
wants to suck Dick and that's all it is.
She and Joey wants to succeed cars.
She's not,
she's not a skank.
She's not running out fucking everybody
else.
She just wants to wait for you to fuck
the shit out of her and you're at work.
Oh like that.
And you're looking,
you're looking at your watch.
Like,
I can't wait to get home,
man.
Shit.
Well,
how come that's not okay.
It's not a real person.
How come that's not okay,
but xbox is okay,
what can we just go home and kill?
People can wait,
go home and fucking gun people down
online.
How that women are going to protest the
fuck out of those fuck dolls.
Of course they will not.
They are not happy with that idea.
Especially when they give them away with
an oil change and get a free fuck doll.
I wonder if they had like a shelf life
in the beginning.
Like they deteriorate like a person die
job like three,
four weeks when women go the other way
with it too.
But yeah.
Fuck those.
Just ramming them the whole night.
Yeah,
sure.
Absolutely.
Sub would so some women who don't like
Dick,
is that what you're saying?
No,
they don't like guys.
There's tired dude.
Yeah.
Get pounded all night and not have to
deal with.
Yeah,
for sure.
Oh,
so they would just hire some guy builds
on robot stuff.
Sure.
Yeah.
It's definitely gonna happen for some
women.
Slowly there we got a pudgy belly behind
it.
They like,
well,
you know what the problem is going to
be.
There's not just that people don't just
have a desire to fuck.
They also have a desire for a deep
connection with somebody.
Yeah,
sure.
You don't get that.
That would be a negative.
So it's people going to go crazy.
They're going to be sad and crying.
Almost like the same way.
People who live entirely online or
completely socially fuck that.
They said that about chat rooms 20 years
ago.
Look around,
if you,
if you really do take it into
consideration,
I mean,
oh man,
I'm just going to be sad people.
Yeah.
You would be like,
I'm just,
you know,
people will have a porn addiction and
even read those guys.
Oh yeah.
They're like,
I had to stop or it was getting crazy.
I couldn't concentrate on anything.
Yeah.
Well that's what they're saying.
Michael Jackson had some sort of a sex
addiction.
Jesus dark too.
Super Dark,
like midnight.
It's just spooky that that guy was doing
that to these kids while he was the
biggest star in the world.
I mean,
we all know it's true.
What did people still going?
No,
cause they don't want to,
they don't want to believe.
Come on.
There's an elementary school near in
Hollywood,
uh,
the,
the auditorium for the school,
as did Michael Jackson Auditorium.
Feel free to change that one.
At least auditorium.
That's Jamie's version of for sure it's
free.
Oh,
it's so true.
God,
how weird that many allegations.
It's always a hundred percent guilty if
they're saying that they have all this
stuff that's just,
it's weird stuff too,
man.
The mutilated animals and shit.
Like what's,
and if people still be like,
he did everything but he did everything,
but he just liked to cuddle with them at
night.
Didn't do anything creepy to them.
He looked at pictures,
but that's not an actions.
Well,
if you take a kid's head,
here's the thing.
That might be the only way he could
legally possess child pornography.
And for what?
That might be the only way he could have
legally possessed child pornography.
He was taking a photo.
No,
taking a photo of a kid's head and
putting it on an adult's body.
We're two adults are having sex,
which is apparently what he did.
He's impose the photos or had someone do
it.
That might be like a legal loophole that
allows you to watch child porn.
Oh,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
Well you could have that and you know,
he's a really good job of it.
But yeah,
for sure.
I know what I'm saying.
I want to watch,
I don't know if there's any loopholes
for child porn,
but it's not child porn.
I've a guy of a little boy's face.
No,
I think,
I think you might have a point though,
because I think I read something
recently about they were taking God damn
it.
What was the,
they were saying,
oh,
it was about,
it had to do with anime and had to do an
animated stuff and they were,
um,
there were,
it was pretty explicitly saying that
even animated child pornography,
like if you did like CGI child,
that's Toronto.
Yes.
Wow.
Really?
Yeah.
Right.
What does it sound like?
Fosters it urge.
What if they're like little animate baby
pandas?
It seems like a release in urge to let
them jerk off.
It's hard because you know what,
I'm with you and no one gets hurt in
them.
And I feel like a hypocrite because I've
always resisted the pornography equals
rape of women because I just don't think
it,
but then again,
it doesn't do that to me.
Just because it doesn't do that to me,
doesn't mean it can't foster that in
somebody.
But it's one of those things where like,
okay,
look,
if you eat a whole bottle of aspirin,
you could fucking die.
Should we only sell aspirin one at a
time to prevent death?
You do.
Should you have to go to the store and
buy one aspirin or should I fucking
trust you with a hundred Aspen in here?
I said,
trust me,
I trust you.
Right?
So that's gotta be the same way with
porn because for a lot of us,
you watch porn,
you just watching two people have sex.
You get excited,
you jerk off,
you feel better.
You move on with your life,
you're taking care of a biological need.
It doesn't,
it doesn't foster some fucking need to
rape in a normal person.
I haven't had sex in two weeks.
I like how you bend down when you say
that.
You're like,
oh
yeah,
start thinking,
not getting lazy,
not wash up.
Sure.
There's been an update as of today,
since probably maybe since we've been
doing podcasts that say a Michael
Jackson's estate reached out to vanity
fair,
um,
and said everything in these reports,
including what the county of Santa
Barbara calls content that appears to be
obtained off the internet or through
unknown sources.
It's false.
Of course they would be that guy.
Just tell it to get him because he never
saw it's one website that started
reporting all this.
So
that could be called be bullshit.
Yeah,
totally.
It could be bullshit.
You know what?
I'm going to throw out the evidence of
that guy,
the former Da,
cause he's definitely got an ax to
grind.
He's not impartial.
He could be a,
yeah.
Upset that he didn't nab that guy.
Yeah.
So he's just talking about it now.
No,
it was,
man,
it's when you read everything,
start out.
Here's the thing,
right?
If you know,
like if you knew that guy was guilty and
you couldn't do anything about it,
you couldn't get them and you were a
former dea,
you would fucking go to great lengths.
Fuck him.
Fuck his legacy.
I know we did that shit.
You remember that during the Mark
Furhman days?
Would they be accused Mark Furhman a
planting evidence?
I think they're pretty sure he did.
Right?
Dante?
Pretty sure he planted evidence like you
planted blood or something
done that.
A documentary that,
I haven't watched it all yet,
but they were saying something about it.
He showed up with a baseball bat and
some crazy shit and had to like talk him
away from having a baseball bat.
Oh,
Jay did?
No,
no.
Mark Furhman did.
I think he showed up somewhere with a
baseball bat at night when the three
detectives and he was one of the shots.
He had a bat with them like he was going
to feed them Oj or some shit.
They're like,
are you sure you don't have that story
screwed up?
I thought I'll look bad.
I look up again.
No,
Oj was looking at him.
It wouldn't have come out of the house
because he sold out or something.
So Mark Furman was out of his house with
a baseball bat.
He's a loose cannon ready to beat.
Ogf.
But why would a cop have a baseball bat?
Don't you have a gun?
Guns are better to use,
but you just want to beat the guy maybe.
Yup.
Intimidation factor.
Maybe he's not going to use it.
Just like maybe he's into that walking
tall movie.
Oh,
Jay did have mark furhman had to pull
out a baton on Oj Simpson to get him to
drop a baseball bat.
Battered Nicole when called police.
So that was before that happened.
How dare you make me so roping shooting
holes.
How dare you.
It's um,
it's that we can do a hunting podcasts.
Oh,
shooting holes.
Yeah.
Holding dear.
But the point was they think that mark
and planted evidence though.
So like,
yeah,
if he did though,
that's what they said.
Well,
someone said he did.
Right.
I don't know if they prove that to the
prosecutor.
He kept telling the press for sure or
not the prosecutors.
There's a fence.
Yeah,
I mean,
you know,
they just,
there was something 30 for 30 no,
I did not.
I heard it's awesome though.
Yeah.
I haven't watched it yet.
Oh yeah.
Ada.
Yeah.
Sorry.
We washed it and talk shit and have
everybody online get angry.
Hopefully the best documentary ever
made.
Wow.
Like be out for a month before you
decide that it's the best thing.
I was a bit shorter at Sundance and
everyone watched the whole thing there
and then it's got two words for you.
Grizzly man.
Good movie.
Everybody stop man.
Yeah.
This,
but if the guy planted evidence,
my point wasn't,
he knew that Oj did it right.
If Oj had beat up his girlfriend before
his wife before and he had a baseball
bat and they had to talk him down and
you know,
but he was his football star and
everybody kept it under wraps.
If he fucking knew that the guy did it
like he,
the guy was like close to doing it in a
couple of times and never did it like
this with the baseball bat.
Yeah.
I wonder what that fucking thought
process is or I'm just going to take one
of these gloves.
Dip in a little bit of blood.
Chuck it in his fucking bushes.
Yeah.
Fuck him.
I know he did it.
Hey guys,
I found something over here.
Holy Shit,
we got it.
It's the glove.
It's got her blood on it quickly in the
bag.
Zip it tight.
Take it over to the lab.
Tested positive for Nicole's blood.
We got them.
Wait,
got 'em the glove didn't fit.
You must acquit.
How?
How did it not fit?
Cause his big ass hands and he just went
like,
it wasn't really not his glove spread
here.
Just try not to get along and if you
wash it as ridiculous,
if you want to put a pair of gloves on,
you go like this.
If you open your fingers,
you're doing them to articulate your
fingers into the holes that you don't
fucking palm a basketball like when,
you know what I mean?
Like that's what he was doing.
That was another glove on to plastic
glove underneath.
Did he?
I think so.
Oh that's even more.
I don't know.
Let's let's show a video of it.
Oh my God.
Just one of the most preposterous
moments in history.
They interrupted my,
some sort of social,
that sociology class in college and let
one,
but this lady listen on the radio.
Oh yeah,
you're right.
Well,
by the way,
it fits great.
See this a don't know food.
Look at it,
but he's got rubber gloves on underneath
and he's pretending he can't get it in.
It fits great for those rubber gloves.
Look at that
fifth grade.
No,
that's a little off.
It's a little off on,
I can see what he's say.
Kingdom over the knuckle.
One 64 eight through the right hand
glove.
All right.
He's like,
I can't,
I can't do it.
He looks like he's pretending like he's
trying to get them on.
It doesn't look as preposterous as I
remember.
Okay.
What I remember it me Ma Fatty Bravo's
here.
He'd have me convinced me.
I'm telling you bro,
it's his son.
Okay,
let me see these gloves.
Oj pull him up.
He's pulling out.
He's actually legitimate and he's try.
He's trying,
but he does have rubber gloves,
our needs,
but I think
of those are a pair of no idea.
It's a big difference.
If you have a pair of Italian racing
gloves,
those are those are those the thin
little,
yeah,
but that's the point.
Oh,
versus Italian racing gloves.
They fit right over your skin there for
racing.
That's what those are.
Those are like,
and Martin Ran Quebec,
the people on the glove company,
we're like,
can we use this?
This is good for us.
Well,
so it's just like leak it brash and when
I actually don't want to promote it,
that would be a great billboard board at
the time.
Half Mondavi gloves,
you know you've seen them.
Well that's what Joey Dee and said they
were doing in New York after len bias
died.
They were selling sodas,
coke.
They'll just,
this shit that killed been buyers,
dog,
get over and get some of this.
That's what joy said about the
everybody's soda.
Everything is like,
I want that good shot.
Give me this shit.
You Still Freddy Soto,
God's hundred a hold back on Joey's go
to move when someone dies.
That's to use them.
They get better drugs
and use their memory.
No,
we'll do job joke about it.
Saying that he wants that.
It's only good stuff if you found,
yeah.
If there was,
if there was a drug that you could buy,
they'd killed a guy.
Like say if there's a guy like len buys
today and cocaine was legal and uh,
this guy was buying pepsi.
Cocaine,
sorry,
Pepsi.
I don't mean nothing by that until it's
too,
um,
and the,
if they,
they died,
do you think the sales would go up?
Oh,
for sure.
Right?
100%.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah,
for sure.
For sure.
It killed somebody famous like that.
If you got mike's Mike's coke dude,
it's Mike's coke is just the Mike's coke
to kill the basketball player.
Dude.
It's the shit to the,
if I,
if I saw some weed that keeps give in a
panic attack,
I would be like,
no,
no.
Let me try.
People were using it as a bragging
right.
What's his name?
Don't say his name.
Paulo.
Oh,
did he make do of course.
And he was like,
all right.
It was too much for me.
I was like,
saved me that.
We'd need to save that for me.
I'll be home soon.
It was over the winter.
I was like,
I won't be all I need to try that.
He's,
what is he doing the edibles before he
goes to bed?
I don't know.
A lot of people like that.
Yeah,
just relaxing thing for they go to bed.
It's real popular with the kids these
days.
Sleep the whole night.
Yeah,
but you can fucking,
you could go on a bad ride.
Definitely going a bad ride.
You gotta be careful.
[inaudible] went to the hospital.
I had crazy dreams about being on
slippery rooftops.
Ooh,
really?
Yeah.
That'll be interesting,
Trish.
Edible dreams are slippery.
They got scary rooftops.
Slippery rooftops always falling off the
edge.
Near the edge.
Ooh.
Scary.
Why am I up here?
Well,
I've been up here.
You're never your dream.
Like what am I even doing here?
I come to places.
I got up here and what am I doing on a
roof?
Yeah.
That was every scene in a Momento,
not my mento inception.
Oh yeah.
It was like,
wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
When did I get here?
Oh fuck.
That movie was very weird.
It was so good though.
How do you wash it twice?
No,
I need to watch
it.
Yeah.
I,
uh,
I enjoyed it,
but I didn't enjoy it as much as a lot
of people enjoyed it.
I thought it was just it.
Got It.
Here's the deal.
It had me talking for two weeks after.
You know what the problem is?
A good movie.
Yeah.
Well,
it's definitely a pretty provocative
movie and fucking amazingly well done.
But the problem's not,
not even with the movie itself,
but with the idea of it is when your
reality that you're creating whatever
this dream state that they're putting
these people into it,
right.
If the reality they're creating is that
convincing?
Like how is it any different?
Like what you like,
don't enjoy this.
This isn't even real.
Well,
it's exactly the same thing.
It's real.
I get enjoyment out of it.
Yeah.
It's not like,
like if you bought a 50 that was right.
Yeah.
His wife was like,
no,
I'm staying here.
Yeah.
This is great.
Why not?
Why wouldn't you stay?
Where the fuck are you gonna go?
You're gonna go to the real world or
want to go to the world war.
I could touch it.
I can put it on a scale.
Oh wait.
His wife wasn't real.
One of them was a real draw for fun,
just as real.
And he made,
he remade his wife.
That's your tardy.
Perfect.
Like why were you complaining about what
you need to be in the real world?
You Pussy.
It's the same exact world.
It feels exactly the same.
You're going through it the same way.
You get the smell,
dude.
Have you ever tried to quit something
like carbs or cigarettes or anything
like that?
Yes.
And coffee and you dream about the thing
of quit.
Um,
probably I've had dreams about
cigarettes and I wake up with a negative
feel like,
fuck,
I got to have smoked again and it takes
me like 20 or 30 minutes.
Like get the feeling out of me.
Like,
no,
it's just a dream.
But the feeling remains.
You're a weird one when he came through
the cigarette thing.
But you're a weird one in that,
um,
you know,
when you describe it,
you're,
you have a very honest way of describing
the addiction to cigarettes and that,
uh,
you're a smart dude so you know exactly
what's going on.
Excellent.
What do you mean?
But you know what's going on?
Like the weirdness of this,
the addiction to cigarettes.
It's weird.
So when you quit,
when you quit and you would talk about
like this desire,
even though you intellectualize the fact
that it's chemical addiction,
but your,
your way of describing it is very honest
in the way that it's like,
oh,
okay.
It's like you're a,
it's like a demon.
Like you can't get around it.
Like it'll over.
It'll fuck you.
Like
come back to me,
climbs into your breath.
Ah,
I mean you again,
moving around.
Your lungs
feel so good.
I was in Thailand for years and moved
from a cigarette.
I've had a cigar too,
but you know,
it was a quick,
you know,
you don't really have heroin.
We were in a zoo late at night.
PDC had a cigarette.
I was like,
you know,
this feels fucking right.
Warm Out,
you know?
Yeah.
Let me have one.
I smoked like two or three quarters of
it had a,
I was like,
okay,
cool.
I'm done,
and then the next day I was like,
oh,
I want a cigarette.
It was right back in,
just like you were saying,
just like that outcome that's exactly
gets in there again.
I had to be like,
no,
no.
I made a mistake last night.
Smart people smoked cigarette.
No,
we should not have done that again.
Get no
better when I'm relaxing or just coming
for a second,
but then you got to go,
oh my God,
I don't,
we shouldn't do that.
Oh,
come on,
man.
Today.
This is the last time.
That was the last time.
No more after this though.
All right.
Say it.
Yeah,
man.
You just get back on the ride.
You want to Ah,
fuck it,
and then your red big Jay and his
girlfriend started smoking again.
They're like,
no,
we just did it in the weekend in Philly.
I'm like,
no,
you're smoking again.
Like,
no,
we're,
we're quitting.
I'm like,
oh no,
you already saying what we're going to
know.
You've already fully committed to
smoking and it's been like a year and
now they're still smoking.
Um,
you know,
they say it has that nicotine has new
tropic properties to it.
Just like a,
like Alpha brain or neuro one has the
checkbook was,
I mean it's like a mental stimulant in
the salary increases memory increases
cognitive function.
It's not a stimulant.
Like um,
a lot of writers write on it,
right?
Oh yeah.
A lot of writers do.
And you know what I started doing
because of Joey Diaz,
I'll just get one of those blue
cigarette things and I'll suck on them
before a show.
Nicotine.
Yeah.
Cause it's not negative.
No,
it's not nicotine.
You have to worry about nicotine is
actually,
it actually has health benefits.
Nicotine's was addictive.
It's,
I don't know,
man.
It doesn't,
it doesn't work like that with me.
Don't you?
To crave the ecigarette more.
No,
I'm,
I might not have one for a month and
then sometimes I like to suck on them
before a show.
You're in a ring a tech now you're
probably doesn't react to wait tables.
They be though.
I think it does.
Yeah,
I guess so.
Nicotine,
I guess it would would.
Yeah.
Well I've,
I smoked a cigarette the other day with
the duck.
Stan hope.
No Way.
Really.
I didn't smoke a cigarette,
but I took a hit of his cigarette and I
took a hit of Tony Hinchcliffe cigarette
once before I went on stage.
Just good.
It feels good to you.
A little buzz.
So I just want one hit but that,
um,
I remember that blows off a cigarette.
Remember that?
Oh Man,
I'm woozy for a little bit because if
you don't smoke and you take a hit off
of a cigarette,
it definitely gives you like a weird
little buzz was the carcinogen to,
yeah.
But I think there's also some sort of
stimulating factor of all those
different chemicals.
The FDA kindly allows them to put into
that shit.
So what's the addicted then?
What's the good thing that gets you
addicted?
There's a lot of factors.
One of it is smoking of the cigarette.
Like the nicotine in that form is
apparently more addictive in some
strange way.
Maybe it's because of the delivery
method is more powerful and potent.
Maybe it's because of all the other
chemical.
You see that inside or movie with
Russell Crowe.
Did you ever see that?
I know what you're talking about though.
Good fucking movie.
If it's factual,
I'm not sure if it is,
but I think it is cause you got to have
your ducks in a row when you make a
Goddamn Expo's a movie with Russell
Crowe about the cigarette industry.
It's got to sound right.
Most likely.
If they didn't,
I mean otherwise it wouldn't be
available anymore.
They would do or remove it from itunes
and all that shit.
But it's essentially Russell Crowe,
if you haven't seen it,
is a super scientist that they have
engineered the cigarettes to make them
more addictive than he testifies about
it and they go to his house and they
scare him and they threatened them and
all that.
It's,
it's creepy.
It's fucking creepy.
Um,
so apparently it's true though.
There are a bunch of different
chemicals,
like hundreds of them that they allow
these companies to put it into
cigarettes that altered the flavor
profile and all sorts of other different
things to do,
but it also makes them more addictive.
And he outlined them in the movie and
explains how they engineered it.
So that's why when you've taken a hit
off those things,
it's different than a cigar or different
than a lot of other ways that you're
getting tobacco.
But even like chewing tobacco was
addictive.
People get addicted to that shit.
Like in their mouths can get addictive,
but it's soaking jerking off.
So kind of different though.
That's like mental addiction,
soaking coffee.
Coffee can be addicted to coffee for
sure.
Busted Nicotine does not cause
addiction.
They ain't go e health forum just as
about as in you to take cat.
Nicotine by itself is only a mild
central,
uh,
central system stimulant.
Similar to caffeine has very mild
addictive properties.
Also much like caffeine.
Well,
I know for a fact the caffeine is pretty
fucking addictive.
Yeah.
You have the trolls.
Have enough caffeine headaches when you
quit that's like,
yeah,
that's all.
It was a quick seat cushions.
I was going way too hard.
Um,
at one point in time writing where I
would,
uh,
make a pot a fucking coffee and I would
down that shit at like 9:00 PM and write
till five,
six o'clock in the morning,
just jacked out of my mind on coughing.
And when I tried to quit that I had a
problem.
I had headaches.
Like my head was like,
oh,
like I was my brain,
my body was like,
it's going to,
you're going to have to deal with a
ridiculous amount of stimulants over the
course of like seven hours or I gear up.
And then once I shut the fucking fun
farm down there,
we're like,
hey,
where's all got used to the,
come on Bro.
Headaches.
How long do the headaches last for a
couple of days to started drinking
coffee.
I'm no
sure.
I never,
never drank it like that again.
I'll never drink more than a couple of
cups a day,
but I thought it was bad for you at one
point in time,
which has also been debunked.
Tiffin.
Yeah.
No coffee itself.
Oh,
coffee itself is not bad for you and
caffeine in the form of coffee.
It's not necessarily bad for you either,
but it's like one of those things where
you can fuck it up if you just go too
hard.
So like what I was doing when I was
writing,
when I was drinking,
like literally pots of that shit.
Probably like overwhelming my adrenals
and to get that late night starbucks in
Sacramento.
Oh yeah.
And sleep like babies.
What?
It's going bedtime.
Just write them out.
It doesn't make sense.
Tate loves coffee so good.
I never gotten to that shit.
It's delicious.
It makes me feel good
taste.
I don't want people stopping kids.
Yeah,
I dunno.
Well it's um,
there's also like a lot of other ways
that you can get caffeine.
You know,
you can get caffeine and rebase.
No,
you can get it in other ways.
Yeah.
Coke,
Cola,
tea tea's Yerba [inaudible] I think so.
It's good stuff.
I have to believe I have,
it's like a stimulant,
sort of a tea,
like ginger.
There's a lot of those things,
man.
It's a lot of groovy ass stimulants that
you could purchase anywhere else.
A stimulant.
Ari Shapiro at the commerce
Thursday night.
How
dare you work it in like that.
I'm doing my hour.
Only time in la.
I'm doing it.
So come tomorrow and I get
tickets@arishaffir.com and a house is
only 10 bucks.
I have like 80 more seats.
I don't want to fill up Jesus.
Sorry up again.
What does put the wings out?
If not,
but it should be fun.
But I knew I was going really well.
It should be fun.
We'll,
I'll,
I'll tweet it to.
Okay,
cool.
Thanks Gloria.
I need an opener.
I can't,
okay.
So uh,
what the fuck's going on man?
Um,
what's the latest?
I don't know.
I went to,
Bonnaroo is really fun.
Yeah,
it's really fun.
Where is bond or is like tennis.
Tennis.
Yeah,
Manchester.
Tennessee.
Nashville.
Yeah.
Like an hour away.
How big is Tennessee?
Like if you drive through the whole
thing?
It was a full day.
We stopped in Nashville and then we
stopped at Memphis the next night,
like 10 hours.
Whoa.
10 hours through Nashville.
Think so.
Wow.
I would drive until the sun went down
there.
We were just stuff.
See,
I always think of states like
Massachusetts.
If you drive 10 hours,
you're not in Massachusetts anymore.
Right,
right,
right.
In any direction.
Tennessee's really long.
Yeah.
It's big ass long ass hot states.
The wiener dog of states is,
it can I got so hmm.
Based on his length and height.
So,
uh,
Bonnaroo had uh,
there you,
you did some weird shells like you do
that one,
two 30 in the morning show that we were
talking about.
It was great.
That's hilarious.
I just spread it word of mouth a little
bit on twitter last minute.
I was like,
I'm finding out when I get there I'm
finding out where it's going to be when
wow.
I took a sharpie.
Everyone on people's hands.
I run into them like,
what are you doing?
I was doing a show where I'm like a
Chrysalis bar and I was like,
say back to him it Christmas barn.
All right,
what time?
And then I write are riding on people's
arms.
Xmas barn two 30 Friday.
Well,
for people don't understand why he did
that.
Everybody was fucked up on drugs.
We kind of had to do that.
Everybody's fucked up at that point.
Or just super tired.
Even drunk.
But you usually drugs.
That's true.
It's a drug.
It's a drug festival.
But drunk is a drug we fucked up in
classification of drugs in this country
as a new breeding is any of those sort
of thing.
It's a drug.
But somehow or another,
we've found ourselves in this position
where most people are in denial that
they do drugs.
Why they drank.
Yeah.
And then you're gonna put mushroom
heroin in the same category growers
category.
Come on.
It's hilarious.
But we've been hoodwinked by Booz.
God.
Damn it.
Not that I don't like booze.
I enjoy it.
It's so much more sexist.
Socially acceptable.
It's crazy.
Way More drunk driving.
Oh yeah.
Way More everything here.
What,
uh,
what's his name said in Canada should
go?
Yeah.
What'd he say?
He's the first guy to take the stance on
this where instead of saying the other
side always takes,
we've got to protect children,
children are going to get it.
You know,
and the only defense against that is
like,
well it's got benefits to sick people
and stuff like that.
It's not really a defense of their
argument.
Right.
Trudeau is like,
Candida has like I think like top five
instance of underage people getting
marijuana.
It's like really bad there.
He's like we're already not protecting
them cause let's regulate it so that we
can protect kids cause he goes,
look,
I think it should be legal but I also
see there's,
there's problems with people getting it
when they're developing when the mine is
developing.
I agree.
So let's do what we can keep it out of
their hands.
Which is legalization regularization
regulation,
regulation like alcohol.
If alcohol was fully illegal and you
just get it from mafia guys,
14 year old would have the same access
as 34 year olds.
That's a very good point.
That's probably the best point for it.
Yeah.
Because cats are going to find some cool
22 year old.
That's the only way they can get it.
That 22 year olds taking a big chance.
He's days.
It's a giant felony.
Really?
Yeah.
When we were kids it wasn't nothing or
fake id or stealing from your dad always
sold booze.
You would wait outside the liquor store
and buy booze for you.
You tell him to give him 20 bucks.
They didn't give him a feeling of
surcharge than the price of them.
Whatever.
Yeah.
Just tell the guy will give you 20 bucks
if you go and uh,
get a fucking one may or may not view
drive throughs and they just give it to
us.
When we were at 17,
18 years old.
Yeah.
They didn't give a fuck.
They didn't,
especially in Ohio,
that trying to get you drunk.
So stay.
Yeah,
exactly.
I get somebody pregnant.
We can't lose.
Yeah.
That was another,
we need to keep you around.
So if getting your drunk,
just how we do it.
Yeah.
It's weird that we have this one drug we
give a pass to.
Yeah.
And it's the one is the most destructive
to your health.
It's,
it's fucking bananas.
It really is.
You get into fights.
What's the problem is it's existed for
so long and it hasn't changed yet.
In spite of all we know.
So like more recently this Nixon thing
came out where they admitted that the
whole reason why they instituted this
war on drugs is to try to break up the
civil rights movement and to try it.
Yep.
And to try to break up the anti war
movement.
How?
Because they knew that the people
involved in the civil rights movement.
We're doing dry rot.
Yeah.
Tammy or fast Jamie.
He's the best,
uh,
the civil rights movement and the
antiwar movement.
We're doing marijuana.
So they decided there are always the
way.
Yeah.
That was the way to go after them to
break up those organizations by
arresting their members for
drug related crimes,
locking him up in jail.
Really interesting.
Stop Line.
Yeah.
So that means,
but it's a fact.
So it's one of those things where,
you know,
you'd hear like an Alex Jones type guy
talk about it,
you know,
don't believe it.
No,
it's actual proof.
Right.
Then you see something like this and you
know that is exactly how they are still
stuck in your head of like,
yeah,
but they're different.
Well,
you know that there was a wikileaks,
uh,
um,
thing that facebook has apparently
centering.
See that?
That was another one of the things that
I wanted to talk to you about.
What they're saying that there was all
this Hillary Clinton emails at Facebook
is censoring that they don't want to get
out,
that wikileaks is trying to print and
then facebook says we won't let you
retweet that.
I don't know.
I'm not,
I'm not sure what,
how they stop something like that.
Or what about this leak?
About about some Hillary Clinton stuff.
What are the,
um,
the packers said he gave it to us.
Right.
But the problem is like you have to
trust the hacker.
No,
no,
you don't trust the Hatcher who has
Julian assange.
That's who trusts.
Cause he's never let us down.
He's only putting out stuff that's real.
He sounds like a good team.
I'm just saying his word is,
I will put out real shit.
Only keep that up so I get to take a
look at it.
You know,
do your facebook stop censoring or
Hillary Clinton email release?
No,
really stop it.
There is no technical issue,
Huh?
Oh Wow.
Hmm.
And wiki leaks.
Wiki leaks is putting that up on twitter
with a photograph of it.
This is interesting.
So they see,
the problem is when you're getting
something from a guy who hacked into
her,
her email server,
how is it not possible that he could
trick them?
He's so fucking smart that he can get
into her email server trick to Hillary
Clinton.
Like they got into her email to get this
stuff right.
I mean this is what they're saying.
So how do we know?
I mean you could do that,
can make it look like he did it too.
Can make it look like,
say that again.
Someone who can hack into a server that
just tell me if I'm right or a mom,
but there's not the only person that
that was claimed.
I've hacked the servery Russian hackers
as of yesterday.
I think I saw the same say they're in
there right now.
So there's a gang of different people
have hacked it.
I think once you get that,
the issue is she was like,
don't worry about it.
I have this secret server on my own for
no,
no reason.
You don't have to,
you don't need to know.
30,000,
322 emails pulled from a private account
she was using during her tenure as
secretary of state.
You know,
I had this guy in here who,
uh,
was a cia guy know and um,
he said pretty flat out if he had done
any things that she did,
he'd be in jail.
Who that the CIA guy was telling me that
he did any of the things that she did
with this email server should be in
jail.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's kind of Mike Baker.
Very a very interesting guy.
Yeah.
They're talking about with an Africa at
a diner and it's like,
no,
the people doing the indicting are her
buddies.
Like they're not to indict or especially
not till after she,
if she loses then maybe,
but not beforehand.
This is all coming out like right now.
Right.
It's,
it looks like she's going to be the
nominee for the Democrats and it looks
like this is the part at home where
people start going,
oh,
I fucking hate you when you talk about
politics because you know,
no shit.
You're right.
The politics behind and come Thursday
night to the comics for 9:00 PM.
Okay.
How did you get tickets are already the
great.com or go to the comedy store.com.
Interesting.
Bring her friend,
um,
does the terrible time for this stuff to
come out because there's no other
option.
Like it would have to be Bernie Sanders.
That's the only other option.
Like are either,
she would like have to be in debt.
I had to come out like a month and a
half or two weeks ago and they don't
know.
Like when people look at it,
they don't know whether or not Bernie
can win.
Like people are pretty sure that Hillary
is going to win because you can get a
lot of women.
They're going to vote on her just
because she's a woman.
I think they don't want it to look that
Bernie does better against sanders.
I'm we getting started trump than
hillary does against trump.
By the police.
Who are these polls?
Who's taking them?
I don't know who these fucking people.
Yeah,
I dunno.
I don't just look at sports.
Fet here's,
Jamie had a really good point.
It's a very good point.
He said,
how come you see all this hype for
Bernie Sanders and you don't see any
hype for Clinton and yet Clinton's still
wins these,
well,
a lot of friction because you had to
have changed from an independent to a
Democrat like months ago and then when
it's time to vote,
you're like,
well I can't vote in the primary cause
I'm an independent.
No,
they're both Democrats.
How many Hillary?
The primaries?
I'm second in the primary,
so then it's too late for them to vote
in the primary.
Okay,
so they didn't register in time.
That's what you're saying?
No,
they had to be registered as
independent.
Right.
And then they're like,
oh no,
you can't,
even though they're going to vote
Democrat,
why do they have to be registered as
independent?
No,
they are not following you.
It was all these people that are
registered independent.
Some people,
Democrat,
Republican,
independent advice to people who are
registered as independent couldn't vote
in the Democratic primary.
Oh,
okay.
I understand.
That's fucking stupid.
Yeah,
so that's one of the reasons why you see
more support than that.
He's actually getting,
my point was more like,
well,
you don't see it very are.
I don't very many hillary like bumper
stickers and signs and online support.
That's what Santa more,
no,
dude.
It's like joining Costco.
You're joining a club to join the
Democrat club and that's how you get to
vote in the Democratic primaries.
It's fucking ridiculous.
How come he can't just vote?
How come I registered voter can't just
vote.
You have to be a registered Democrat to
vote for the primary.
Yes,
you should be able to go independent
slash Democrat should be able to do
whatever the fuck you want.
Most people don't vote in these
primaries that have been happening,
which is the issue.
This is madness.
We're just picking our candidates.
None of it matters.
So we're all just voting on who gets the
paycheck.
But what a better way to control the
system by making you,
you have to be a registered member of
the party in order to vote in the
primaries.
Yeah,
that's hilarious.
If that's true,
but I don't want to keep going.
It's often not true.
Some states it's state to state.
It literally matters depending on where
you are.
Let's say like a tea party guy and like
you're an independent that beside the
also good buddy guy go drown.
You couldn't vote for the Republican
primary if you're like,
I would definitely go for trump.
You couldn't do that either.
But that's not as I think problematic.
I think the tea party started off with a
good idea,
but somewhere along the line the morons
took over.
Yeah.
And the first of all,
calling it the tea party.
Hey guys.
Okay.
How about a new name?
Why do you call yourself the wallets?
A historical precedent.
The face sat when they threw the tea
into the ocean to protest Great Britain.
You will mot tax or tariff os fuck up
the tea party and occupy the same thing
you guys have Sarah Pailin sober.
Sarah Palin's,
your cow,
right lips.
They let people talk for them.
There were like two down the people,
they should have talked for dummies in.
Well they,
she know.
It becomes like a business.
Sort of like a,
if you're like one of those bitchy
housewives and everybody knows you as
the bitchy housewife,
I'll put more.
Yeah,
you got to ramp it up.
That's what you do now.
You gotta throw drinks at bitches,
like claws leaves off.
That must be tiring.
It's exhausting to be that lady.
Hey,
that's probably off work.
It's probably like the sheep dog and the
coyote born in Sam morning,
Ralph,
and they go off to the other
conversation.
Conversations go.
Excuse me one second.
I have to fill this.
Hold on a sec.
What'd you say,
bitch?
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Where were we?
So I think that's what happens.
I think they,
uh,
they take on a role,
you know,
and they just get caught up in it.
Don't vote.
It's pointless or bought a home,
stay home.
It just seems like this way has got to
fucking meltdown in front of our face
until we come up with a better way.
Sure.
It seems like it,
it's so dumb.
This is like some colonial feather
writing fucking parchment bullshit.
The rich people get money from the
corporations and the rich people keeping
the ones deciding how the elections go.
Yeah.
So they're going to decide to make it a
little more favor towards them.
Yeah.
And you have to register for a party to
vote in the primary.
Why?
That's what I can't do that while you're
voting,
this is stupid.
I'm Democrat fucking gross it primaries
or like a club that you have to belong
to and that's how you pick presidents.
And by the way,
when you become a registered Democrat,
like that's like being a fucking raiders
fan.
The team.
Why can't I feel like I'll see what
people have to offer and I'm not,
not saying anything bad about the
raiders fan base in sports.
That's what I heard.
There's stabby a row savvy.
They're one step below ICP fans.
Stabby stabby Oh,
they're so glad they're not coming to
la.
So glad.
What are they going to Vegas?
Vegas 17 burn with him.
Whoa.
You're very good at vegas is garbage
too.
Oh dear you.
How about that?
We'll see another fucking woman dancing
in a cage on a ceiling.
You don't think that's hot.
So edge to it.
There's nothing to that.
Gee,
it's all such fake.
She's got glitter on her ass.
She,
it's all like,
this is how party seems like they'd be
in movies.
Right?
Well,
it's also a gang of people on Molly.
Oh yeah.
That's mostly what you're handling.
Your handle and the,
I mean,
this is when you're going to these
fucking clubs.
It's not a surprise why they all have
glow sticks.
Oh,
poor tripping balls.
LCD sounds as it was so good on molly.
What's LCD?
Soundsystem is bad,
but they use the lights so fucking good.
They sing that song.
Daft punk is playing at my house.
Remember that?
No minor hit.
They have a couple of minor hits,
but man,
they blue pearl jam out of the water.
Really?
Yeah.
It probably was just fine.
Just fine.
Jeremiah hasn't ever done any drugs and
he thought LCD soundsystem it's better
to wow.
Interesting.
Well said.
They had a real show.
Yeah,
they go for it.
They're not just playing to their fans.
You can't really compete with that.
If you just someone who plays your hits
and you'd like to talk about politics in
between the song and fucking fucking
veteran three speeches and he brought
his daughter out and made us all happy
birthday to her.
Not good dude.
The whole light show was just them up
close playing be booth to
booth to maybe you could do that pearl
jam show Eddie.
It doesn't bother her show.
10% of us know what you are.
That's right.
When some fans,
that's actually super important.
Right?
Yeah.
That's a good way to look to it.
To hand them coast off their fame and
the other half like,
oh,
people don't know me here.
Oh yeah,
let's go for it.
Slayer last year.
They fucking destroyed.
That's a good point.
Yeah,
I would,
you know that and that,
that goes with comedy too,
man.
That goes with everything.
Yeah.
I saw bill burr on that,
uh,
on that.
Um,
it was like a comedy central,
like year in review kind of thing.
They had those flex period four years.
He did five minutes there and he was
like,
okay,
you guys aren't my fans yet.
This was like six,
seven years ago.
I remember that.
Oh,
that was Dane.
No,
it was a different one.
But it was,
bill was in this like politically
correct sort of group of people and they
weren't accepting it and he had a hammer
at home.
Yeah.
When fans don't know you,
that's what they have these festivals.
Some people go,
I've got Chris Stapleton.
We were just sending their lawn.
He came on.
I was like,
this guy is good as shit.
He's a bad motherfucker.
I've listened to that CD,
whatever you want to call it.
An album.
I guess we can call him albums again.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's cool.
Sounds better than CD.
It's not a compact disc.
So what is it?
It's [inaudible] album.
We go back to album.
So his new album or the album that I
have,
I think it's only one know.
I think he only has one out is fucking
incredible.
It's really good.
Yeah.
Amazing stuff.
Yeah,
it was so mellow and nice and a lot.
I told you about the time that um,
uh,
stone temple pilots played a Dana
White's birthday party and they go,
they went for it,
mashed it,
they smashed it all the way to that
might've been a crazy junkie out of his
fucking mind.
All sorts of personal problems and all
that jazz.
But knowing that 200 people there less,
maybe 200 but there were scattered all
throughout this.
We got to get people to get closer
towards the stage and kind of get
excited about the fact that it's fucking
stone temple pilots,
pilots.
That guy could have been in a football
stadium filled with people.
He would have done the exact same show.
That's how strong it was.
You put up a video of it.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
I know way.
Oh yeah.
This is Dana White's surprise.
[inaudible] behind him?
No.
What's going on?
Oh,
that's right.
Goodness.
Where is that?
Um,
that was that.
I don't remember what it was.
And then stone temple pilots is in the
video.
You don't get no,
no,
that's just a surprise.
It was awesome.
That's nice and all but oh,
okay.
I thought maybe the video I definitely
had,
but the sound was so loud.
It was,
it was useless.
Oh right.
Cause those was my shitty iphone video.
You know,
it's like six years ago to six years
ago,
I said,
you can't,
you can't replicate that kind of sound
into an iphone,
but when you're there at the thing,
it was just noise.
But
he couldn't even understand what the
fuck it was saying.
But um,
my point being that guy was all for it.
He went for it more than you could ever
have hoped.
Like he just fucking cranked it out.
Yeah.
It was amazing.
And it made me want to maybe want to go
home.
I can go do better and go right.
Yeah.
Go write some jokes,
go next time.
Be Better on stage.
And to do.
You can go both ways.
I saw,
I saw a smashing pumpkins at rock and
the rage when the air.
Yeah,
garbage.
Garbage.
I mean terrible.
It's just billy corgan and then he gets
a fucking Asian Bass player and a
fucking female blonde,
whatever the fuck she plays.
Isn't he though?
Like a serious republican now?
Yeah.
He might even be like a,
I'm just making things up now.
It changes some of the lyrics of a song.
God is empty.
Just like,
ew.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Is that what he says?
Now he plays his old songs and double
time.
It's just fucking awful.
Then you see all the hands go for it and
you're like,
oh right.
Yeah.
He tried to get rid of him.
Smashing pumpkins.
Billy corgan praises trump.
He's fucking up the political class.
Well,
dots,
you know I've probably said that to
sorta true.
Yeah.
I mean he's definitely doing that
slam social justice warrior as well.
If that was a video of an actual body
slam.
Well
show watch philly corn gorgon going for
it.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I don't.
Why did I feel like he's conservative?
He went south.
He might be,
I think he got Christian diddy.
I think so.
Come on.
I think that's why I changed those
lyrics will appear that before he was
dating courtney love before she put out
that that banging album.
That one really good album,
right?
No,
no.
The one really good one was was Kurt
cobain and then the other one,
he got ahold of her and then Gavin
Rossdale got ahold of her too,
so they have three totally all banged
her.
Well.
Yeah.
You think so?
I think to get that haven't did what you
sure?
No.
Am I wrong?
Yeah,
but before that time,
I don't know.
Why don't you google it?
Just a question.
Hey Gavin.
Rossdale I might be dead wrong.
It might just be billy corgan.
Gavin Rossdale.
That does sound wrong.
Now that I think about it.
Well,
she definitely was a bang and Ed Norton
before it was the hulk.
Really?
Yeah.
She was banging at Norton,
allegedly.
It.
She was such a fun wreck just throwing
around like thrift stores and
Philadelphia just like she was at her
height.
She was such a wreck.
She was crazy.
You see that documentary that thinks
that she,
uh,
she had Kurt cobain killed,
with the recreation's we were talking
about like,
I can't trust us a movie with
recreation's.
Like you weren't there.
You don't know what was said in near
just recently because what happened was
you went over to her.
She said,
do it Kurt,
do it.
Oh,
you can't do it.
I'll do it for you.
Oh yeah.
She claimed on an interview on Howard
stern that she had an affair with him
with,
with Cat Rasa.
The wrong,
you're wrong.
Twice,
Jamie.
How he helped me with that album though.
How dare you?
That was probably Billy Corrigan.
Yeah.
How about you google things first before
you accused Ari of being wrong?
I saw him that same rock on the range.
He was greg.
Kevin,
yeah.
With Bush went and played.
Hey Jude into the crowd and went and
went around to just have to like what
you're doing right.
And you'll win everybody over just a end
to right.
Just get really into the stuff you make.
If it's good.
Some rockers after a while they just get
beaten down by the pressure and fans and
negativity and all that jazz.
And then the intoxicating sound of the,
the,
there were the true lovers of your work
and know they pull you in,
lavish you with praise and get your face
tattooed on their ass.
And I'm not seeing,
you know,
just stopped producing good stuff can
happen to anybody.
Yeah.
And it wasn't like project was bad.
They would just good.
Yeah.
And I was positive.
I told bigJ would end up not coming.
I was like,
I guarantee you a band that's like that
for 25 years they're going to kill it.
But uh,
apparently stone still kill it.
This don's deal.
Apparently Mick Jagger is still a bad
motherfucker and he works out every day.
He does like Yoga and lifts weights and
does all kinds of crazy shit to keep his
body in shape so he can fucking bang it
out for like an hour and a half show or
two hour show.
Mccardy runs around the whole time.
Really?
The guy from iron maiden runs around the
whole time.
Wow.
Yeah.
Cause Mccartney's older.
Let me see if there's a video of a,
of Mick Jagger,
a recent video of Mick Jagger on stage.
It's just the opposite.
He was like,
socks bunny could be worse than ojs
glove.
It's like,
yeah,
maybe,
but I wouldn't get a figure.
He's,
how old is Mick Jagger?
65 I'd say that at 67 67 I'll be 65 one
day.
She has the right when I might go with
70.
Oh really?
Yeah.
What am above 70 72 72 last year and
concert.
Yeah.
Now check this out.
When you watch him,
I'm telling you man,
for a guy who,
wow,
dude,
my grandfather was like that,
that gay a phase that he went through
with,
uh,
what's his name that just died?
That's always looking for though.
Yeah.
He's always looked like trans,
never got fat.
I mean he stayed skinny all these years,
but that's amazing.
I still running around.
Yeah.
And he's got a lot of energy and it's
kind of camel.
Oh Jesus,
that bald.
What the fuck?
And he did not give a fuck.
They didn't give a fuck.
Well,
he's still Mick Jagger.
You know,
that's amazing thing about a rockstar.
Rockstars are the same.
They're the same guy.
It's Mick Jagger at 72 he's shuffling.
Yeah,
he's doing everything.
He's strutting.
But here's the thing,
he's moving loose and relaxed.
It's not moving like a seven year old
guy.
He's got a lot of energy.
Apparently.
He's just a fan.
A fanatic about working out.
Works out every day.
This is according to Brian Count though.
He couldn't might've made that up.
You never know.
Well,
people say it works out every day.
That's all.
It wasn't matching.
So exaggeration for,
he works out like four times a week.
Yeah.
I don't think working out every day is
mart.
Right.
Cause the mill and do that.
Well I eat a lot of people.
Definitely do.
I just don't think it's the move.
I think your body responds better when
you give it a little breaks.
Yeah,
right.
Rebuild one day.
So I've heard,
yeah,
but I think the,
but what is also important is you build
up a certain level like with Mick Jagger
and then you maintain that.
That's very critical that you maintain
that level because once you dip,
like you just can't get it back.
It's hard.
It's super hard to get it back.
We,
you're fucking 72 man,
come on.
So yeah.
You know,
they'll also bone start to break and
then this guy on the podcast earlier,
Shane Dorian,
big,
big wave surfer.
Great Guy.
Really interesting.
Cool Dude.
Really Fun.
But he was talking about hurting his
back.
He's 43 he took five months off of
working out because he was busy
traveling and then tried to go back and
with a light workout.
So light workout,
five months off.
Fucked his backup.
Well,
yeah,
it happens man.
Get old as fuck.
You got to maintain.
Remember that marriage children where a
peggy got a personal trainer?
No,
get fuck them.
she made me eat bon bons until he died.
Oh.
What does it say here is there is,
this is a supposedly as workout.
Okay.
He trains five to six days a week at
this workout's emphasize stamina and
balance leading up to a tour.
Mick Jagger runs eight miles a day,
including sprints.
What he also swims kickbox is in cycles.
This would explain his ability to sing
and move continuously during a concert
without sounding short.
Wow.
He does some resistant training to
maintain his balance and his posture.
He takes ballet lessons,
what and performs yoga and pilates on
stage.
I did not witness any hesitancy in his
movements and he still moves with a
certain amount of fluidity.
Grace,
he's been known to cover 12 miles on
stage while he's dancing.
It's drawing.
Wow.
Sorry.
A concert.
No one's measuring that.
They're guessing.
Yeah,
I
12 miles.
Fuck you,
but how
about fuck you.
Wait a minute.
That's horse shit.
It takes three hours to run a fucking
marathon.
Okay.
It says on here,
it says at that pace you'd be able to do
a marathon and just under four hours if
calculated.
Correct.
That's not true.
He's stopping.
A lot of it is not moving at all.
Total horseshit.
How dare you.
But also our concert before our concert,
they don't put off for 12 miles out of
here.
There's no way.
Oh yeah.
Two hours.
Three hours.
They got greedy.
They went too far.
He said like four miles or five miles.
Thanks Ed.
Even we were misread this thing even
says,
I find this hard to believe though for
two hour concert it means he's moving at
least six miles an hour when you clearly
doesn't run the entire show.
So right there.
So someone who did it was more just a
meme or something.
Must have just put it up to add it.
I don't know.
It's just as he's been known to run that
far.
We don't know about all the rest of that
stuff either.
That shit too.
Right.
Could all be bullshit.
That documentary we saw,
but then it showed like intentionally
stuff that was just proven.
Then you were like,
fuck this then.
None of it.
Yeah,
all of it.
Well all of those things,
man.
He's a big foot,
all that shit.
Big Foot Ufo shows all that stuff.
Oh yeah.
That was like a lot of different,
um,
conspiracies,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
These whatever legends,
legends,
but went to Loch ness.
Did you?
Yeah.
They think they know what that is.
They think that's a big ass fish like a
sturgeon.
Really?
Yeah.
That's what they think like to,
as people left.
Yeah.
There's a bunch of different
explanations.
Some people think it might be some sort
of a giant landlock catfish.
Some people think,
uh,
might be something else.
A giant lake.
Yeah.
I mean,
it's not like,
right.
I mean,
it's like a great,
like,
yeah.
It's just massive.
And this boat,
big boats on it,
you know?
Yeah.
Like ships,
you know that she'll river monsters.
We've seen that show.
Um,
it's that guy.
he's just English dude travels all over
the world and catches fish like crazy
fucking giant paranas and lying and fish
fish with giant ass fucking crazy teeth.
Yeah.
You saw that?
I forget what he,
where he caught that thing.
I believe it was in the Congo.
You remember this stuff in Maryland when
somebody brought it back from China,
it was that there was a snake fish and
it comes out of ponds.
Go on land for a while to find another
pond.
All the waters around it were
contaminated.
That's a Gar.
Wow.
Um,
but yeah,
so Jeremy Wade is his name anyway.
Um,
there was,
uh,
an animal in Lake champlain and they
would call it champ and like,
it's like some sort of another kind of
dinosaur thing,
but they found sturgeon in that lake and
so they're pretty sure that that's
really a big,
enormous sturgeon get,
they look like a goddamn submarine.
They're huge.
And so they had a video of a sturgeon
swimming through the water that they
took like from like a drone or a
helicopter,
something from above it.
And it looks like a God damn monster.
Really?
Gee.
Yeah.
When you see a sturgeon from above,
that's about surgeons.
Is this it
never reaching
the,
I don't remember what he blues.
It must've,
yeah,
it seems like it.
Yeah,
it was probably,
let's see this thing.
Yeah,
it's definitely Moody Blues.
Was it good and Moody Blues?
Yeah.
I never was into him.
God Damn Dinosaur.
Wait,
let's see.
In skin.
That looks like a dinosaur.
It's huge dude.
And by the way,
that's not even like the biggest one
ever caught.
They can size of a man.
Yeah.
Oh way bigger.
How'd or Halibut is crazy.
Fuck.
He jumped in the water.
Oh my God.
That when you get a perspective,
wow.
How big is that?
12 feet long.
It was just size of him.
Yeah.
So if it was dark out and you saw it in
the water and you were in a boat,
you would shit your pants and say
there's a monster in that water.
So that thing has,
that thing exists and he caught that.
It's super possible that there could be
some thing that's super similar to that.
The somebody overhearing you in a bar
like,
dude,
I'm telling you this thing is massive.
It was a monster.
And then you went to the bathroom and
you just spread that.
It could be,
but it definitely could be.
You see something like that,
like what's the most recent explanation?
Look at this.
Look at the size of the sturgeon he
calls.
That's the size of a person.
Yeah.
She got her halibut or they that size.
Huge big ones are hundreds of pounds
bigger than people.
Whoa.
I think it like a world record.
Halibut's like 300 pounds or something
crazy.
I've seen people catch hundred pound
ones on TV and they have to pull it into
the boat and it's just like,
what?
Look,
what the fuck is it to do you?
You caught a table.
Look at that one.
But God is insane.
It may be the biggest Pacific halibut
ever caught back up to the one that was
the biggest one.
That one,
that one.
I go to the visit the page with the
fucking says,
I think of the size of that thing.
We're looking at this lame.
Yeah,
it's in Seattle.
They caught that fucker.
Eight foot,
two inch.
Oh my God.
Was estimated at 533 pounds for a
fucking halibut dude.
We eat like kings.
Those are the things you have to fish
for like two hours,
right.
If like keep on the line to keep wearing
them down.
Where I'm down for those they take
forever.
I never caught anything that big,
but I caught a Marlin once really?
Well,
not a big one either.
It was like a 70 pound one.
That was a fun fifth and trip.
I'm going up there.
Fuck yeah,
there was a great time the time before.
It was like five,
six years before that attended before or
something.
I don't know.
Whatever.
Um,
we went salmon fishing.
Devon went halibut fishing,
but the water was too choppy because of
the wind,
so he couldn't,
couldn't the line all the way.
The bottom we just gave up and went in.
Yeah.
Hallo.
Bid is the best tasting though,
in I opinion.
Yeah.
And when you bake halibut with like some
butter and a little bit of garlic.
I liked like the river,
the river and lake fishes.
Well they don't taste as good.
Oh really?
Sometimes.
I mean I think the,
the fish that are in the ocean or more
hardy and I think they're more durable
too.
Like they don't like,
they don't get nasty as quick.
It seems like this doesn't make any
sense,
but this is what I'm saying.
Like the,
the difference in the taste between
catching them and cooking
them like on the shore,
like a trout or something like that
versus a tuna.
When you gave,
you know you can cook it like a couple
hours later and I'll still be all right.
Well I heard that's what I heard about
those brain,
rainbow trout and stuff like that.
We'll make stuff.
It's like they're better fresher.
Oh yeah.
In a way.
Like kill it.
Eat it right now.
Rainbow Trout tastes really good.
If you cook it right on the shore,
right on the shore,
catch it and then you cook it right away
and started.
Yeah,
I'm about to kill us by the fucker.
Get that hot grease going.
You know how the best way to cook them
too.
How Bacon Grease.
Yeah.
A little bit of corn flour.
Just a little bit.
Just gently or flour,
you know,
just chat links,
upper teeth of bates and put it on the
pan.
Damn.
Bacon Grease.
Woo Boy.
Fry it up real quick.
Flip that bitch.
Get some lemon on that motherfucker.
Woo.
You're doing it all like in a cast iron
frying pan overlooking a river.
Feeling like some sort of a pioneer,
some sort of a day.
That'd be fun as fuck.
Fuck yeah,
we gotta do another fishing trip,
dude.
Yeah.
And then I'll be way more free.
Yeah,
man,
I'm free now.
I don't have a joke in my hand.
Free.
Nice.
Beautiful.
Um,
but like,
um,
we should go somewhere else to work
Saskatchewan catch northern pike.
Ever seen those things?
Oh really?
Pointy ones.
They're like a monster.
It's like a fucking dinosaur.
Cool.
That'd be cool.
They tasted it to do out of the way
enough.
Yeah.
We could find nobody around us.
Well,
when I was in on that deep all over us
and just so you know what else to you
get one of those therma sells.
You ever seen a thermostat like northern
pike?
Nicey Nice.
Yeah,
they have big ass teeth,
man.
Hey,
would you ever do that catfish hunting
where you just
pull it up?
No,
I like my fingers,
dude.
Those guys fuck up sometimes to get a
snapping turtle frog.
Oh Jesus.
These are big ass.
These are big fish.
Wow.
There's a certain type that they call a
muscular lunge.
It's not a,
it's not a regular northern pike.
It's called a Musky and they're much
smarter and much larger and they eat
ducks.
Well,
why don't you check out?
fuck that.
Frogs face,
dude.
Good games or photography is amazing.
That is amazing.
They sacrificed that frog.
They got saved them open.
Why didn't they save him from that
beast?
I think they got frogs just frozen on
that.
Go full screen on that.
Oh my gosh,
it's teeth,
dude.
Now imagine if that was as big as that
cow flying through the air as mouth
opening up right above here.
That was going to get you that frog is
done.
Look how big his mouth is in comparison
to his body to
frog is that is a little reptile brain.
Can't fuck with the mammal brain.
What's the top thing?
Especially flying mammals.
Yeah.
Boy,
if there were flying mammals back in the
day,
thank God our ancestors wiped all those
fuck heads off and that would be an
unfair advantage.
Oh yeah.
But then you had only things live that
we could kill with our hands.
Yeah.
Or they wouldn't kill us.
Well,
can eagle might be able to kill you?
But I like my chances.
Yeah.
It didn't bother anybody though.
But they might fly off with the baby
number.
That fake baby video.
That looks so good.
So good.
I think those guys got work off that
like,
yes,
it's fake.
We faked it.
Please hire us to do fun shit like this.
Oh,
honestly,
I think it was a contest.
Oh really?
I'm pretty sure.
Oh yeah,
thanks.
I might be right.
Yeah.
It looks so good.
The shadowing snatches kid and it's at
shot so well at first it just filming
the bay.
They're filming the Eagle.
Yeah.
And your swoops down.
Grabs the kid and flies off in the
Chinese after out.
And they even went to the ground with
the camera.
That's so good.
Oh my God.
Joe Perry made a fake bigfoot video.
Really?
Yeah.
Joe Perry from aerosmith.
Really?
Let's see if he,
I don't know if he put it up.
See if you find Joe Perry's big foot
video on one.
Put a dude in a Ghillie suit and have
them wander around through the woods and
they filmed it was the climate is real.
No,
Joe Perry is an interesting guy,
man.
See this tape that we took got lost for
about a week with all the hubbub of,
uh,
travel and stuff.
And then we followed it and this is what
we saw and this is what happened.
He's so Boston it out.
Just think of it what you think,
you know,
uh,
upscale blown away by it.
But uh,
uh,
it was pretty scary.
Afternoon.
I go to the,
go to the,
Oh,
here it is
so ridiculous.
Like it's,
if someone will be filming him just
sitting there in the sun
field and it's got like a little cookout
going on,
how he set it up so good.
But I just love the fact they're filming
for no fucking reason.
It's filming God.
His phone.
Yeah,
no big deal.
Just happened to be filming.
Look,
I'm moving around a little so you know
it's real.
I skip had this long video.
Yeah.
What is that?
Did you hear that?
Nope.
Yeah,
I think it would just mark,
see if you can find it.
If you could find that.
We can't go to the spoiler alert.
We know we just get along for sure.
So let's,
let's,
I know what the setup,
is it going to be up here behind him?
I Dunno.
Well,
I'll be right here.
Be ready for sure.
Put your shirt on,
dude.
No,
the sun's out.
that sounded growls.
You had a growl.
Okay.
They're in the woods or anything yet.
Worst acting.
What is it?
That
big
and it was black and he was fucking
bullshit about sasquatch and all that
shit.
Bullshit about sasquatch.
He made a Blair witch bigfoot movie on
his tour bus.
How board is he?
Sorry,
I sorry.
I saw,
Hey Sarit Boston people will add extra
ours that aren't necessary and remove
other ones.
I saw it.
You know why?
Why don't have to say the word garbage
because that's what they are.
Ooh,
how dare you.
But what when you performed there,
you enjoy them though?
No,
no.
Right,
but the ones that aren't garbage,
most of them are garbage.
Come on,
dude.
Boston people.
How rude.
This is a really dumb video and you can
take it down.
Enough is enough.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We don't watch.
The rest is so it's so unnecessary.
They get bored,
man.
That was just there for their friends.
Yeah.
It wasn't really done youtube.
Jamie just found it this just trying to
get them a viral video going on.
Jamie made it.
It was like dude from aerosmith.
It's not the main guy I talked to you
about,
about everybody opportunity bobcat
goldthwait bleeds in bigfoot.
Really?
Yeah.
We discussed this on the movie horror
movie.
Really good movie.
Yeah,
it's fun.
It's like a Blair witch type.
I saw him as a apple store getting my
phone fixed back when I had one and he
was just giving a talk there about the
movie.
Just randomly.
He must've edited it on a movie or
something or I don't know.
They just had them as like final cut
probably.
Right.
I was going to ask when when they said
heat,
who's coming out?
He's supposed to do it.
He was a director.
I've put it together.
No.
Oh,
he was director of one.
Yeah.
Yeah,
the Willow Willow Creek movie.
Willow Creek.
Yeah.
It's really good,
man.
It's a,
I saw seen from it.
Looked like you saw it.
Yeah,
I saw it.
That's cool.
Yeah.
I was like,
wow.
Like you made a fucking horror movie,
man.
It just became a full director like
years and years ago.
Right.
Decades.
Well,
he's just a very smart dude and he could
kind of do anything he wants.
He just wants,
he,
my mom is not a dude.
Fuck Bro.
Why don't your concert on the smart
part?
Um,
he's,
um,
you know,
he could do whatever he wants.
He just has to set his mind to it.
Then he just does it.
It's not shocking to me that he does it
harm movie,
you know,
he could kind of do any kind of movie.
Did you see a call me lucky?
No.
It's a documentary that he did about
Barry crimmins.
He had heard about it.
Yeah.
Really.
Um,
influential Boston's standup comedian,
like one of the most important guys in
the early days of Boston and was
brutally molested when he was a kid by
babysitters boyfriend,
like fucked in the ass.
Like,
well she like watched the door,
like that kind of shit really bad.
Yeah.
And his sister saved his life.
She came down and he's unconscious.
Like he would,
he would shove his head and the couch so
he couldn't breathe.
Like you couldn't scream and the guy
would fuck him and he'd be like
literally black out from getting fucked
with his face and a pencil.
Horrific,
horrific documentary,
but really well done and really
fascinating and really open.
And the way barry crimmins talks about
like getting over it and you know,
and,
and then all the people that love Barry
and talk about what a massive influence
he had on standup in Boston during the
early days of Boston.
And then a lot of the people that he
knew,
like all his life did not know about the
story,
you know,
and he wanted to kind of put it out in
this documentary form and it's so well
done.
I can't recommend it enough.
It's called call me lucky.
Bobcat is a bad motherfucker.
He really is.
He good.
You know,
he's nice.
He can do whatever he wants.
And he's a good dude too.
He's a good dude.
And he's a UFC fan.
Do you know,
do you know the,
um,
the black cards thing?
What's up?
The black cards,
John Jay,
the block cards and Lita Ford or their
managers line them up.
So it's not if you guys become a woman.
I mean just said bend over every and you
just fucking what?
What'd you hear the manager come on Jay,
I guess could be not true,
but he's under that kind of,
he was like,
wait a minute.
So when they were 14 watts,
they're manager fucked him on when there
were the runaways.
Come on ladies,
become women.
Something like that.
Really?
Yeah.
I think it was in some,
like one of those documentaries lead a
or one of them talking about it.
I know.
Well,
you know what,
it's shocking,
but I don't,
I wouldn't say I'm surprised he's a real
piece of shit manager.
They hood and just,
but would you be surprised that like
some crazy show biz manager would fuck
his clients?
Oh yeah.
And keep them as clients to oh for sure.
Right.
The right guy,
the right crazy guy.
100% right.
And it wasn't like we had a lot of
leverage when they were just signing
with some other,
had done anything.
They couldn't do shit.
But I'm thinking about it.
What do you know that you got to go to
TMZ,
we're going to go,
yeah,
they just sucked it up.
Just know where to go.
Look what's happening with that.
Uh,
what does that,
that singer girl's name,
who wants to get out of her contract?
Catia.
Cassia.
Kesha.
Like it hurt.
I mean who knows what the truth is
behind that story or what's really going
on.
But it's kind of a similar thing like,
or producer was having sex with her
apparently,
and she said he was raped her or this is
not what she said.
Like,
isn't that like what the accusation is?
But meanwhile she's tied into a contract
with this dude.
So she can't make music unless she makes
it with him.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
Like that's crazy.
If it's true.
Yeah.
The judge was in a tough spot on that
one.
What do you do there?
Cause he's like,
okay,
you have a contract,
but if nothing happens then you have to
honor your contract.
Right.
And there's no proof of this.
If it's true,
that's horrible.
But either way,
there's no proof of it.
So we can't just go on.
You were saying alleging this cause then
everyone would just say,
well,
right out of my contract,
please.
Right.
Um,
so he's like,
I'm,
unless I have a proof of something,
I can't,
there's nothing I can do like right by
like contract law.
Yeah.
That's a pretty heinous crime.
Yeah,
for sure.
I mean he's denying it too,
but yeah.
Yeah he's definitely denying it.
But it's one of those really heinous
crimes where you gotta go,
Ooh,
how do you find out who the fuck told
the truth?
It's so,
it's such a hard crime to prove.
Well,
especially when they get really upset
about it.
Cause it's like so hard to prove it.
Well that's,
it also sets it up for like this thing
we never supposed to question a victim.
Yeah.
Well Dad,
you can't say never.
Right?
Like you definitely shouldn't
automatically question the victim.
Yeah.
But if something seems goofy,
you should not question the victim.
Like people lie.
I know people that have had false rape
accusations.
I know as a curse.
I was going through it in New York and
everybody in his level,
like we know she's crazy and that's not,
that's just not a thing.
Did it can happen.
They're telling her like,
stop saying this.
You know,
it wasn't,
it can happen just like there can be
crazy men,
there can be crazy women.
There's this crazy people.
There's people that will absolutely
fucking make up a story.
Yeah.
And the second is if you don't know
about it or if you're like,
well how David you,
because you're not going to be yes.
So becomes one of those things where
it's like the person who is
accused of doing it is also being
victimized.
Yeah.
So we're supposed to ignore that victim
and concentrate.
The problems are based on this idea of
lexical better a thousand men,
a thousand guilty men go free than one
innocent man go to prison.
Yeah.
That right.
People don't really like to apply that
to ripe.
No,
no.
Well it's,
it's one of those weird ones that you
can't look at it objectively.
Yeah.
Internet maybe mobs they do now that
wasn't internet mobs.
The mob justice that's in response to
women not finding justice through the
legal system.
Right.
So they were like,
well let's just fucking ruined his life.
Let's call his mom,
let's do these things and get really
fuck up his life.
Well,
we know that's true too.
Right.
You know,
I mean,
we know that people have done horrible
shit and gotten away with,
yeah.
So then it's like,
well let's you know,
and there might be an occasional like
innocent man or,
or or,
or North Carolina Lacrosse team.
Duke Lacrosse team is there.
I know the rape is bad on,
I'm bringing that up,
but is there anything on her on her side
about like you signed a bad contract,
sorry.
Like you should maybe like at the
beginning of it,
you know,
but I don't,
I don't think the contract has anything
to do with her getting raped.
I think if she could do it that that's
what she's doing and miss cause she
can't supposedly make music because of
the contracts.
You guys with that guy.
That's why her career's supposedly
ruined right now.
Yeah.
Well because the record industry has a
long history of that just bearing
people.
Yeah.
But hold on.
We already kind of covered this.
He,
she can't leave and make music because
he has run the contract even though she
says he raped her.
I thought she or interpretation I,
she was saying that she
was raped in order to probably get out
of this contract to break the contract.
She was raped to break the contract.
She's saying she was raped in order to
get away from this guy who has been the
accusation.
Right.
Yeah.
And I'm just saying like,
uh,
it's like,
not that you shouldn't be bringing up
the rape,
but she's,
if she's making it up,
this would be a good thing to make up to
get you out of a contract.
It's sort of,
I'm sort of saying that,
I mean honestly,
if you had an eight and eight contract
in the UFC,
you know,
and then some other company offered you
50,000.
It was a fight when you go to six flags
contract and be like,
so you got to pretend you got raped.
I mean,
it would work.
That's why I just don't know.
What do you say?
Oh,
how dare you not let him go?
I don't know how,
why?
Don't know what it is you would say to
get out of your contract,
but you'd have to make up something to
get out of it.
Not that I'm saying she his side assess,
sort of asking.
I'm asking.
Sorry.
Okay.
Um,
house.
Yeah.
I didn't mean it that way.
I just thought was such an electric
subject.
You say like one word wrong.
It's like,
wait,
no,
wait.
It's entirely possible that either one
of them could not be telling the truth.
You're right.
Yeah.
We don't know.
I don't know her.
I've never even heard her voice.
I never heard her talk.
I don't have know anything about her.
So all I'm,
all I'm seeing is that she went to court
and tried to get free and they wouldn't
let her free and they,
the guy still wandering around.
So they're not prosecuting him for any
sort of sexual offense.
Right.
As far as I've read.
Yeah.
And I just,
we signed a contract to sign one,
right?
Or No.
I mean
he's obviously got some sort of a
contract with her and that's,
but see,
here's another thing,
if I had a contract with someone and
they falsely accused me of rape,
I think I'd fucking let them go.
I got to watch it.
And what would it be tied into a
contract with them.
But if the,
the idea of if in any way,
shape or form,
she's telling the truth of forcing her
to work with somebody,
it's horrible.
Yeah.
See,
but that's not what the judge was doing.
The judge is just ruling on the
contract.
Law contracts are fucking weird man.
Like think of it as a comic.
Think of like you as a comic,
like what have you had a contract to do
your stand up and like you had some guys
six months in front.
It was like a producer that made you go
on the road and you had a pact with him
and he made you do his jokes and he
would,
he would help you write your act and you
couldn't do comedy without them.
I would just stop doing competence.
That's crazy.
That in the music business happens all
the time.
That was the prince thing.
That's why Gerad turned down a new girl.
What does that mean?
Draw comical.
What's new girl?
He was that show new girl with a
whatever his name is Zoe deschanel.
I don't know who that is.
It's like a spin on fussing.
You're acting like you're not giving me
enough information.
Show you,
I don't know what you're fucking talking
about.
TV Show Sitcom on Fox.
It's been off like seven or eight years.
It's got zooey deschanel in it or one of
the [inaudible] twins.
And what did they try to do with drug?
He tested for it.
Right.
And then they really liked him and then
he just disappeared because he saw a
seven year contract and he was like,
ah,
I don't,
I don't want to get locked into this
thing for years.
Wow.
Now has own set of seven year contract.
He balked at it.
He like disappeared.
Hung out in a starbucks.
Tony.
Good for him.
Yeah.
And he was sleeping on couches at the
time.
He's got balls.
He didn't have a place to live.
Smart man.
Seven years and he wanted his own show.
I'll long ass fucking time folks.
Yeah,
seven years.
And what if the direction of the show
becomes more corny?
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Is that,
that you can do,
if you walk away,
you'll never work here again.
What doing bad sitcoms is a horrible
feeling.
It's horrible that I was on that Fox
show that was terrible hardball.
Yeah,
it was terrible.
There was some,
some,
some episodes where it was just
unbelievably,
do you feel like you're supposed to have
to do it or something?
Like feel like a whore.
You feel like,
uh,
you feel like,
you know,
you just feel gross when you say these
lines.
Cause you know they're bad and you know
that the show is bad and you know that
this is,
uh,
the exact opposite of the way you feel
when you're doing stand up at a club or
something.
Good.
Well,
do you mean you're doing stand up at a
club?
If you're doing your best and it doesn't
work out,
at least,
you know,
you could fix it and you could figure it
out.
How to make it funny again,
when you're doing these shows and it's
bad.
They tell you it's good and they make
you keep going and so you're doing this.
Yeah.
And they'll put a billboard up there and
they'd be like,
show you where the,
they've raised in the ratings,
but you know,
it's terrible.
So who cares?
I had to work with kids and work with
this kid.
He was on the set and she had no,
she was fine.
What my point was,
she was a barrel.
Nice kid.
Fuck her.
He's a nice boy too.
It was a nice young fellow and a nice
young girl that were on the show and one
time they were very fine,
fine folks.
But my point being,
they were really young,
they had tutors and shit and they could
only work a certain hour amount of hours
in the day.
What you expose your child to that?
Well I had a conversation with one of
them about it.
Yeah.
And it was just trying to figure out
like what,
what is the idea behind it and they,
you know,
they were kind of saying got to strike
while the iron is hot and when it's a,
you know,
you have an opportunity right now to
secure a lot of money and okay.
That's for their Hollywood career.
Okay.
And like them as children,
as human beings who that's just another
of 50 industries you can work in.
Yeah.
Why?
Why you fucking up like,
okay,
chances are you'll barely ever book
anything and you'll just get filled with
this.
Like Mommy's not proud of me.
She couldn't take me to the things I
don't book.
Oh,
and by the way,
if they've booked two out of 50 things,
that's still really high percentage,
which is you're getting rejected 48
times.
That's amazing percentage.
Most people don't get to things.
So constant rejection.
Yeah,
and then if you get it like finally I
get their love,
that's me.
And then what?
And then what if you book everything?
What if you nail stuff?
What's the best case scenario that way
it,
what is the best case scenario and what
else?
At 24 if you're lucky,
you get super sensitive.
Everybody loves you.
River Phoenix,
they are all whacked crazy except Jodie
foster.
She seems to be okay.
She seems like she pulled us really out
of it was the outlier outliers.
Everybody else's fucking crazy.
They're all whacked up on funding,
never get told the truth.
And you don't grow up your,
your grow up period.
It's supposed to be this struggle.
You never get that struggle.
You don't have to win over friends and
everybody learned how to,
everywhere you go,
they know who you are and they love you.
Thank locking bananas.
That doesn't make any sense and you're
going to have kids at that.
That's a best case scenario is that
thing.
Dude,
I know several child's robots or low or
midgets.
It shouldn't be.
It shouldn't be illegal if you don't
sell for child stars.
Yeah.
Several.
Oh yeah,
the one here.
I know a couple of them.
I know several of them did not quite
right.
Oh,
the day camping.
They're also actors.
So part of it too.
Yeah,
we're still in it.
The garbage because of that.
Yeah.
I think there's just something weird
about developing your personality and
your body going through puberty,
puberty,
puberty and all that shit while you're
famous.
That's how it sounds crazy.
Yeah.
Well it's not good for you.
Can't be.
Where's the,
what's like,
what's important for everybody?
Like what's important like for a guy
like you or a guy like joey or Dunkin to
anybody that I know.
That's interesting.
There was a lot of like stress in the
early years,
there was a lot of struggle,
you know,
was how much rubber friends went up,
fans and friends and like just like
learn how to cope with no money,
just build character.
That's what's built the characters,
right.
Also there's like a certain amount of
appreciation for whatever success you do
attain because you're always going to
remember being poor and fucked up and
sad.
And if you were a waitress for a while,
the enjoy being a movie star a lot more
than just some child star.
Hope we can fuck.
Yeah.
I mean not saying that the child star
can't form some sort of an
understanding,
not saying it's not possible.
Let's go against you.
The odds are strongly against you.
My friends out,
somebody,
one of those award shows,
he just got into one of those workshops.
You said one of those,
uh,
American pie ladies,
you know,
like Tara Reid or something like that.
If somebody pulled up in a,
in a Honda,
you know,
was in ballet and she goes,
Oh,
who brought the Honda?
Like it was like the lowest thing she
could think of.
One of the American pie girl said that,
wow.
It's just like,
all right,
you guys are never gonna relate to
actual people.
That's so weird.
Yeah.
I had some lady mocked me once because I
had an Acura Nsx really mocked me in
front of a restaurant for having a fake
Ferrari too.
To lower car.
Yeah.
$90,000 car.
It's a fucking great car.
To this day,
I still wish I had it.
I should've never ever had you have
that.
Oh,
it was fucking beautiful Honda toys into
the store and you're like,
hey guys,
let's take a look at this first.
Let me play the sound system loud
enough.
They'll hear it in the showroom and
that,
uh,
show you the puck and bootleg video
machine I have.
You can watch full Bruce Lee videos
while you're driving.
And that was the infinity.
He could watch game of death as you were
driving.
I'm like,
wait,
is that legal?
I was like,
all of a sudden a switch.
That's special switch.
I could flipped over.
Like cannonball run license plates,
everybody.
That's what you do when you get that
fear factor money.
Yeah.
You would come with that and marijuana
lemonade before there were dispenser is
that it's like what?
What is,
what is this?
I was ahead of the curve when it came to
marijuana drinkables I used to buy
bottles of this marijuana wine.
It was like a soda or a co,
call it marijuana wine,
but it was like a soda that contains
wheat in it.
Come on and it was fucking
preposterously strong.
Really?
Oh my God.
I say it's pretty good and it tasted
pretty good.
So you drink a whole glass of it and you
just go on a site buyer role.
Ry.
Tornado of emotions just turns you
through the air.
Takes you to another place.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
It's so brutal.
So power and no one had tolerance for it
back then.
Now we that we didn't understand that it
was a different drug yet.
I was five years before that.
Banana bread.
Yeah.
Nobody understood.
Even to this day,
most people don't understand how I
watched.
It's different.
Yeah.
When you smoke it,
you get the thc,
but when you eat it,
it becomes a totally different
psychoactive substances.
Like,
I dunno one Brownie.
I'm like,
no,
that's not.
If you do a dosage,
that can be so varied because those
barbarians,
it live on the east coast.
They don't have fucking regulation.
It's like saying one pill.
Like what?
Milligram?
Yeah.
Dude.
Have you seen this?
No.
It's a breath spray,
bro.
Yeah.
Let me see what this one,
this one.
This is the,
uh,
this is the one 75.
This is very light.
175 milligrams.
Yeah,
John.
And how many sprays is 170.
Let's see.
Light at all.
Here's the problem.
This is one 75.
This is a thousand.
Oh,
the whole for the whole bought the whole
bottle.
Oh,
that's not a very good at between.
All you have to do is pop that cap.
Right.
Squeeze that,
twist it,
throw that bitch down.
Tastes good.
Had to take a second.
1,000 milligrams.
You're bar.
Find that if you don't have a tolerance,
even if you're Joey Diaz,
you're gone.
I think that Joe.
Nope.
He takes a thousand.
That's not true because he sees stars,
the lead tech nine 50 Joey's,
I've seen joey eat two of those stars at
death and what?
It all started death two.
That's 500 that's close dude.
He gave me,
what am I taping?
It does not happen to everyone is here
and I was like,
ah,
I can't have joy.
I eat a corner and it got me,
you know something as small ones like
still get ya.
Yeah.
I was okay for my story.
It halfway through and then it was like,
fuck.
Did you ever have one of those lows?
Harmane states gummies.
The gummy bears go start models.
Yeah.
Let's go me from Montrose.
Those gummy bears are fucking insane.
They should be illegal to those guys
come to the punchline and stuff like you
want to smoke.
Sure.
And then you're just,
you just see a fire going carry torches
as the regular.
That's your like car pipe full towards
giant once more before the UFC the other
day.
But James,
you apparently beat Jamie apparently
doesn't feel it.
Yeah,
it doesn't affect me.
Thin people know it.
Here's my theory,
because I've heard this a lot a lot of
times is people with really low fat.
It binds to fat if they don't have
anything for it to bind on.
No,
no.
The people I've seen lower fat than me
though,
probably.
Yeah,
he's meaty.
that's muscle,
not fat.
There's fat in there though.
Come on,
son,
shredded.
How dare you?
I don't know.
All right,
good point.
I'm not lighter than I've ever been.
I'm not sure where one 90 well,
I'm lighter than I'd been in a long
time,
which means I have lower costs more than
me and I'm so much fatter than look at
chimpanzee.
Yeah.
I'm short and fucked up looking
like a muscle filled with helium.
It's just thick.
It's just all bones and muscle,
you know?
But my point being,
yeah,
I get blasted.
Like when I eat,
I get,
it does nothing to do with body fat.
It doesn't change with me back.
But smooth,
fatty,
uh,
I dunno.
I Dunno.
I guess much fatty foods,
people I've seen that happen to,
that doesn't,
it doesn't hit him.
It's always real thin,
real small people.
But when you're talking about like fatty
foods,
people think of fatty foods like things
that make you fat or fat itself.
I eat more fat.
Yeah,
but it doesn't make you fat.
Your body starts burning that fat to
take it.
I know sometimes when you eat a slice of
pizza after you get high,
it kicks it up again.
Really?
Yeah,
for sure.
Did they sound like mangoes?
Oranges?
People used to,
we used to drink orange juice,
so it's for acid or mushrooms.
The same thing.
Same thought,
I guess,
but I don't know.
I thought it was a god.
I want to say mangoes.
Like someone said that mangoes enhance
your high,
get joy deals on the phone.
I've heard that with mangoes.
Mangoes go to Jamaica called fucking
coconuts.
You're on with what?
I had to Jra.
So 100% true.
What are the mangoes?
Increase the effects of consuming
marijuana.
There you go to smoking more.
Leave your fruit at home.
Pussy Ari wants candy and more pot.
I fuck off punks.
I gotta slow down.
Do you deem del Ray got the diabetes?
What got the candy?
Diabetes.
Watts?
Yeah,
he's reversed it already.
But he told his doctors and lethargic
and whenever he goes,
Oh yeah man,
I think I know what that is.
And he said he got,
not from candy,
he eats a lot of candy,
but from those a tortilla shells and
shit like that,
what turned to fat pizza,
stuff that turns to sugar in your body.
So he's just eating way too many carbs.
Yeah.
Sugar and cart ride.
No,
I'm Sam Harris,
the neuroscientists,
atheist character.
Really great podcast guest.
He um,
went vegan and his blood lipids are all
fucked up because he's consuming so many
carbs,
like somebody pastas and breads and
things along those lines.
And that sort of breaks it down and in
his body to sugar.
So if he looks up your blood lipids,
you gotta be real careful with that.
If you're gonna do like,
he just,
yeah,
if you're gonna do like a carbohydrate
rich diet,
really got to mix up a lot of green
leafy vegetables.
And if you're going to get fats,
you should get them from like you got to
use like coconut oil and coconut butter
and things along those lines to keep
everything.
Yeah.
I'm just going to try to stop eating as
much candy.
Don't eat candy.
I don't need any sugar.
I don't eat any sugar unless it's like
ribs less than something like less than
a certain basting on ribs kind of sugar.
You're like,
come on.
That doesn't count.
It does count count,
but it does in the way your body
processes food.
That's where it gets winter.
Mostly meat than candy.
Let's go.
But it doesn't matter.
Your body doesn't know about that.
Mostly Meat Shit.
Your body knows.
Oh,
I just took in 51 grams of sugar from
barbecue sauce.
It doesn't know.
A matter of fact,
your body doesn't know when you're
taking in sugar from fruit.
I can take it binds with the,
with the fiber that's in the,
if your actual fruit helps,
if you eat it,
but if you're drinking like orange
juice,
like that,
sugar is the same as sugar from Coca
Cola.
Damn.
Your body doesn't know what the fuck it
is.
If you drink a good giant ass 20 ounce
glass of orange juice,
your body's just simply not designed to
have that much sugar come out of an
orange like that's like fucking nine
oranges with no fiber.
So wax your body.
I was probably better for you cause he's
all vitamin seen it.
There's no caffeine and he's probably
better for you than a 20 ounce Coca
Cola.
But the sugar amount process doesn't
matter if it's processed or not.
All right,
let me ask you this.
I've got to pick and I put it in the
spring.
Bottled water.
I just whip your dick out bro.
Okay.
Guess how much sugar that's small enough
for that?
Don't piss all over my floor.
Yeah,
you can do it in there.
Just,
just corn hole that we have to go soon
anyway because a,
I've got to get something somewhere.
He's got a p if folks don't put a camera
on him because that's rude.
I'm like,
there he goes.
Don't put a camera on them.
We don't want to lose our users.
How much sugar is and uh,
last night we put the camera nearest
Dick or the,
uh,
make a first folks,
that's the first time anybody's peed on
the pocket.
Don't take a photo of his dick.
It's blocked by the cup of,
it's just if you guys stay taking a
photo of you,
Dick Brown.
Oh,
that's a full Kombucha.
Definitely don't drink that.
You're going to piss in the pickles too,
bro.
How'd you cut off stream for sure.
You dribbling on my carpet.
Oh,
I fully,
fully pinch,
I believe pinched dude,
that's a lot of pain.
Will be at the comedy store tomorrow
night.
Ladies and gentlemen,
go to Ari,
the great.com and you can buy tickets.
Uh,
tell them that you heard him pee on the
Joe Rogan experience and you will get
absolutely nothing off your ticket price
already.
10 Bucks Cock suckers.
It's only 10 bucks.
Folks.
We got pissed here.
If you want it,
we gotta put it on Ebay for poachers.
We're gonna um,
stop poaching in Africa.
That's a you're juice.
Put out some Jupiter.
We're going to stop the poaching with
Ari's pissed.
Hey,
by the way,
can I say this?
Yes,
you can.
I'm going to Edinburgh and all the UK
people listened to you say bro.
Edinburgh and Bruh Bruh Bruh.
So it tells people in an h in there,
I don't see it that way.
They also have rules against big knives
because they got stabby there too.
It's dot.
Yeah.
They have no knowledge at all bars.
I'm doing my hour this hour that I'm
doing it tomorrow,
the comedy store and then I'm going to
record and October at cap city.
I'm doing this hour.
It's not a British hour.
This is what an American hour looks
like.
Oh fuck your themes or spotlights and
your chairs to sit and get series at the
end.
We don't do that here.
What happens over there?
A few people won this award by doing
this like full circle thing.
Trying to like,
that's when I realized,
you know,
I was just like,
then they all started trying to emulate
that.
We don't do that here.
Well,
so that's my hour.
Okay,
so you're doing American standup comedy.
My right?
Yes.
American standup comedy 2016 yes.
That is the best style at the hive.
Six 30 every day.
25 straight days.
Wow.
Maybe 22 that's increased as insane.
How many people were in the place?
I don't know.
It's hopefully more of you have friends
that are going to tell them about it.
How many did see this place?
Seats about one 20 oh,
that's perfect.
Yeah,
but you got to fill up a Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday.
It's not going to happen.
Right,
but you'll have a good time anyway.
I learned a lot from this thing.
Hey Man,
those fucking,
sometimes it'll shows with 10 people or
the best shows ever.
Yeah,
for sure.
I love this thing or the shows with 50
people.
Sometimes the best show ever.
Also the Scottish people that don't get
your references,
twist it around.
You've got to figure out how to make it
dance.
Yeah.
It's pay what you want.
Whoa.
What do you know communist?
I'm a little bit of a coach because for
certain things that people over the
attribute there,
Edinburgh,
it's so weird,
man.
Even the big guys,
they come outside up.
There was like,
I got a bucket.
It's just like part of it.
Whoa.
A of just to fully free shows and look
if you enjoyed it,
pay me.
And then the great shows it fill up,
get more money.
That is a great idea.
It doesn't feel like begging because
everyone is doing it there.
That's it.
Yeah.
That's like very fair.
If I get out of here,
don't worry about it.
If he really liked me,
support a couple of fucking pounds,
you get way higher percentage.
So less money.
But like people can't afford it.
Can't afford it.
Okay.
And then they might be a bit good she
had and people can feel free tickets in
America.
I don't know if it would work over here
like that.
Yeah,
but they're right cause they were crazy.
No screen right there.
You tell them,
hey you didn't pay,
get the fuck out.
And they just leave.
I don't want to be here.
I'll just go.
But when you comp people in America,
oftentimes you get like a less
enthusiastic,
for sure.
For sure.
It's just an American idea though.
They do treat it more like theater there
twat.
Yeah.
Our folks,
we gotta get the fuck out of here.
That's it for the week.
Watch.
This is not happening.
When I was only on Youtube.
Now,
every Tuesday,
you fucks every Tuesday.
This is not happening.
Uh,
are the great.com for tickets for
tomorrow night's the stork and comedy
store.
That's it.
Throws the stories this week.
It's a good one.
Watch that.
This is the uncut one's on youtube.
All right.
Sorry.
I love these slots as Biz.
Okay.