I mean,
very few people could ever imagine.
Here we go,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
And we're live saddling up to that
microphone.
[inaudible] young lady.
How are you?
I'm good.
Chelsea?
You always
to see you too.
Thanks for meeting with me.
Saying hi to my son's sons.
A great fucking a.
They are man.
And that's what I figured is my next
step in my,
in the tail.
My next chapter as.
What's her name?
The girl that everyone loves,
the girl,
the singer.
She's real tall and skinny.
Kind of swift.
Yeah.
I can't remember anybody's name anymore.
There's so many people to remember.
Yeah.
Well she said,
uh,
she's onto her next chapter and that's
how I feel too.
Oh,
it's going to be about how talking to
women about how to raise functional
sons.
This isn't,
this is needed in America and I'm going
to step up and do it because all these
tales.
What with all the news and such obvious.
It's obvious to me these women who have
not raised their sons correctly and I'm
going to correct them because I'm tired
of them.
Happen in fucking bitch in a moment.
I'm old.
I'm going to tell you what to do to
raise decent sons.
Women.
Well,
your son said something when,
when they were doing a little tour of
the studio,
they saw the picture of Rosa parks and
your son said,
that's Rosa parks.
And I said,
you're one of the few people that ever
just pointed that out and noticed it.
And he goes,
of course he goes Roseanne's my mom.
She raised me right.
A suite in that suite.
That's something that's getting the uh,
what do you call it?
What is link?
Know Pat on the back side of modern
vernacular?
I don't know.
There's some slang.
I hear him.
I try to stay here,
but I can't fucking do it.
Well,
you obviously did a great job.
So shout out to shout out.
Shout out to the moms.
How you holding up everything good with
you right now while I'm smoking like a
bitch was every day was.
Were you smoking before all this?
Hell No.
Well just currently,
secretly doug.
Stan hope got me back on him.
The bastard you son of a bitch for like
15 years in Doug.
Stan hope snuck every time I see doug,
I'd smoke one that he's got an evil
spell on me.
Oh,
he's evil little man.
He's sober right now.
No cigarettes for him either.
Yeah.
That he always says that.
No,
he's doing sober October.
Are y'all doing sober October?
Yes.
Wow.
Why did you ask me?
I would've sobered up for it.
No.
You wouldn't have done it.
I want to do a get fucked up on retox.
Retox detox.
That's what my boyfriend johnny calls
it.
Time to read talks about how many
cigarettes are you smoking today?
No.
Well No.
Who's counting?
You just keep walking.
I'm not smoking.
Less than 10.
Less than 10 is not bad.
Yeah,
not.
It's not as smoking a lot.
See,
I'm cutting
it by 10 every week.
So.
So next week it'll be down to one day.
All week days.
Not Bad.
And I'll see how I deal with it.
If anyone dies,
this whole thing has been completely
fucking insane and you have to tell you,
but you caught this madness is outrage
culture right at the peak.
I think you.
You hit peak outrage culture where
people didn't give a fuck.
If you were making a joke,
didn't give a fuck.
Have you had no idea that that lady was
black?
Didn't give a fuck what your mental
state was.
Didn't give a fuck if you were on
Ambien,
didn't give a fuck if you were drinking.
Didn't give a fuck if you sincerely
apologized.
Oh,
go ahead.
I do want to talk.
But they didn't care that you use
sincerely apologized and did not.
Didn't mean to offend.
You were cracking a joke about a woman.
It,
it was funny how they've missed.
Characterize it and lied about it and
added words to it.
But,
um,
yeah,
I like talking about the tweet.
But uh,
yeah,
I seriously apologize to all whom I
inadvertently offended and because they
were offended for it,
it wasn't even what they say.
They were offended because it didn't say
that.
But they think that I tweeted a said she
looked like a,
you know,
somebody and I never said anything about
her looks it was a political tweet and
it's just proof of how everybody's under
mass mind control because they took a
um,
and of course I'm always
interested in that.
You know,
you know,
that I've talked to control.
That's what I think.
I think people are under the wave of
self mind control.
I don't think it's like there's anybody
pulling the strings.
You can get out of it.
No,
I don't think anyone's pulling the
strings.
I don't think this is.
No,
I don't.
I don't think it's by design.
I think people are caught up in a wave
of fear and paranoia and political
correctness.
And I think one of the reasons why
attack they attack someone like you is
first of all,
you're wealthy and successful and
famous.
You are beautiful.
Thank you.
And one of the best comics of all time.
And you're also a,
you're,
you're an easy target.
You're a white woman.
Your identify as a white woman.
What do you identify as?
I identify as a Jew.
Well,
there you go and this is what you
thought this woman was as well.
What is their next?
Like my cousin Sharon,
she looks just like my cousin,
but it wasn't nothing to do with how she
looks that came after my tweet,
but the busted about the point of her
hands,
what she engineered in Iran and I'd been
on there talking about the,
the,
I call it a woman's revolution in neuron
for years and speaking to people in Iran
about it and what it means to,
uh,
the,
the women who are second class citizens
there.
And uh,
so if you take that one tweet out of
like probably I tweet a lot.
So I was probably 400,000.
No,
I don't go crazy.
I stay crazy.
I admit it.
I mean,
what the fuck?
They're like,
you know what you've said you're crazy
for years and you know what,
you're crazy.
Well yeah,
I set it for 15 years.
Well it's also all of us are crazy.
All comics are fucking nutso least I
don't wash my keys like som.
I know some guys,
they got to wash their keys five,
six,
seven times where they can go on stage.
What's his name?
Oh,
I'm so bad on names.
Chris Farley.
I always asked comics.
You know,
I asked him what's,
what's your secret number?
Which Years Joe?
You don't have a number.
You don't have to do something a number
of times.
You don't have a number.
What's your birthday?
Eight.
11,
67.
Eight.
What's that?
August eight.
Eleven 67.
You were born in 1967?
Yes.
Jesus Christ.
Um,
I was in my,
I was in the Utah State Hospital.
When you were born,
what were you doing given birth?
No,
I was in a mental institution.
That was my first hospitalization.
It lasted for nine months and it was the
Utah State Hospital in Provo where the
osmonds are from.
So it's was always a big Marie Osmond
Fan.
The,
the mental health aspect of this
conversation is an important one because
here's my take on this.
Extremely important.
It is important.
And yesterday was mental health
awareness day.
Yes,
I know and I was quite aware of being
mentally healthy yesterday as I was
smoking.
If someone,
all I eat is cheese.
If someone has a,
an injured leg,
you don't expect them to run marathons.
If someone has a,
you know,
something wrong with their liver,
you don't expect them to process food
correctly.
You don't blame it on them,
but if someone has a mental health issue
and they do something erratic or they
say something that's inappropriate and
then they apologize for it.
Or if they're Canadian or if they're a
comedian and you,
you've had the gitelman real diagnosed,
treated mental health issues,
trauma related issues.
There you go.
How'd you like that?
It's a little bit better.
Kenya.
Yeah,
but for whatever reason,
people to pretend that this
is a deliberate act by calculating
person who is just being an asshole and
that's not the case.
You're not an asshole at this time.
I have been an asshole.
But you weren't there but you weren't.
That's not what you were doing now.
I was talking about Iran and the woman's
revelation there and how,
uh,
how,
and it's always been because,
you know,
what I had my dna done because I wanted
to know and I am of North African
ancestry,
how much.
It's like a very small percentage,
but it was something like 25,000
years ago they left North Africa which
has kind of Syria and they went to
Lithuania and I'm Russia and uh,
some Europe to July 23 and me or
someplace and just answered so many
questions for,
you know,
why I feel this yearning towards that
part of the world.
But I do,
you know,
and especially the geopolitics there,
some have always intrigued me and I have
always attempted to use my voice to um,
you know,
support all of the people there.
Well,
it's fast.
So it was,
you know,
this one tweet was like about.
It was about,
I mean,
it's actually a genius tweet if you
really fucking knows what exactly did
you say it was?
Find the tweet,
Jamie,
I'll tell you if it's a artificially
rendered because an artificially
rendered one.
There's a lot of them were people
distorted what you actually said it was
racist Roseanne,
and then a couple of weeks later it was
disgraced comic Roseanne and her racist
tweet and then after that it was
disgraced comic can her offensive racist
tweet because there's all these hoops
you gotta jump through,
you know,
they're never done punishing you.
Well,
look were saying before all my friends
said,
don't apologize to social justice
warriors because that's the kiss of
death.
That's like chum in the water,
blood in the water,
you know?
It's definitely a little bit of that.
But what I was saying before,
the podcast to use,
I don't,
I don't really.
What I really think happens is they find
a target and they don't care if it's a
viable target,
but once the target gets greenlit,
they go after you until some new target
comes along until only distraction.
That target.
Yes,
sure.
It's recreational outrage.
They find the attack you and they go
after you and they to what the fuck you
said and obviously they don't.
That's what kind of cracks me up.
It's like,
Hey,
look at this.
Look what they're saying and that meant,
and you know,
I'm not going to bow down before them
and say you were right and they want me
to,
but they weren't right.
I'm right.
I wrote it bitch,
so I know what I meant,
so you don't get to tell me what I
meant,
but they don't care.
The thing is they don't want to look at
it rationally and say,
Oh,
here's a woman that has a history of
mental health problem.
She was on Ambien and drinking and she
says something that is slightly
irrational,
but given your explanation of it,
well you did.
She was black dog.
Both Ali think all my tweets make no
sense.
You have been saying that for fucking
here since I went on twitter.
You're like,
her tweets are just buttoned straight up
crazy.
Have some crazy tweets for sure.
I don't think they're crazy.
You just don't get 'em.
Well,
maybe if I was in the same mindset as
you,
I would get them.
Yeah,
but obviously no one is.
When I say crazy,
I think they don't think like other
people.
I know that I've always known that my
whole life I'd always test other people,
see what they were thinking like as even
as a kid I'd be like,
but I try to fit in.
They go play barbies,
you know,
and I'm like,
fucking,
I don't want to.
And I'm like,
okay,
well let's have Barbie be a resistance
fighter that paratroops into,
you know,
into the hidden lines of the German
thing and save all the Jews.
And they'd go,
you have to be her cousin skipper.
Then they'd hand me the skipper doll.
I always had to personify skipper and
they got to be Barbie.
I didn't even know a Barbie.
Had a cousin.
Yeah.
Skipper.
She has a little tiny tits and I
resented that because I always had very
large pendulous breasts since I was four
or five.
I did.
I,
I don't think or look like other people.
I think I'm an alien.
Really.
What planet you think you'd be from?
Um,
well,
somebody told me as from the eighties.
Do you know anything about that?
Yeah,
that's the people that call the art bell
show.
They would always say that they say
round faces are from Pat.
You see you got a round face.
That's what I told you.
I don't even go by what people look like
except for I do look at the shape of
their head.
I have to admit that's how I classify
people.
I classified people my own way because I
don't think like everybody else thinks I
take a person shape of their head and
that's that group they represent to me
and I have noticed that the Dutch have
the largest heads people,
the Dutch have pure score.
Not all of them of course,
but some of them you're the average
height for a Dutch person,
like six feet tall.
I know women vikings.
Yeah.
Biking.
I love all the different peoples of the
earth because they all have a variety of
foods that I enjoy.
So I like to,
you know,
I don't just mix with one kind of person
in my real life.
I'm mixed with all kinds of people and
you know,
because I'll go anywhere for free meal,
but I.
But I love,
I love cultures and I love
all people.
That's all.
I want to say,
you know,
I would never,
I'm not that person,
so you're not a racist by any stretch of
the imagination,
but you are a person that I am a
misanthropy.
I'm a misanthrope misanthrope,
but I am a respect truss of no man or
woman,
but most comedians,
yeah,
we're all like that,
right?
Misanthropic intentions or you have to
hate all people the same,
but you definitely have to mock and
make.
I mean,
it's part of your job description to
mock and make fun of and you,
you look for things that are irritating
about everything.
No Shit.
Right?
That's part of the job and not only
that,
that was part of your character on your
show was part of the reason why ABC
wanted you back.
It's part of the reason why the show
became such a giant hit and it's
returned.
I mean,
it was a fucking huge hit coming right
out of the gate.
Yep.
Twenty 8 million people.
That's a lot of fucking panel number
one.
Every episode.
Yeah.
That's a lot of people and a lot of that
was because people love this aspect of
you,
but as soon as you get labeled a racist,
everybody throws their hands up.
It goes,
Whoa,
I didn't know she was racist.
She's racist,
and they don't care about nuance.
They don't care about the details.
They don't care about ambien.
They don't care about alcohol.
When I called you on the phone was the
first thing that I think I've learned
gel well,
if you're gonna,
take an ambien down.
Not do not drink a beer.
Always only drink a wine.
Yes,
with Ambien.
I have a good friend of mine who is one
of the nicest,
most respectful guys you ever want to
meet.
He woke up in Germany on a plane,
covered in his own vomit with the
police,
standing over him,
asking him if he knew what happened.
He ended up getting arrested.
They brought him to the jail in Germany
and they add and he's a ceo of a large
company and they went over things with
him and they said,
what happened?
What do you remember?
He goes,
well,
I remember taking an Ambien and then
then I went to sleep and then I had a,
I guess I had a beer at some point in
time and they go,
okay,
stop.
This is what happened,
and so they described how he was hitting
on the stewardesses and trying to start
fights with men in the cabin and wasn't
as being as real.
Selfie was on.
Ambient distorts.
He's the nicest guy.
If you knew this guy,
you would never in a million years
believed that he was capable of anything
remotely like this and the German people
actually let him stay in the country.
They let him continue his vacation.
They're like,
okay,
for gay family promise not to do that
again.
He goes,
I'm never fucking taking that shit again
in my life,
and one of the things that I said to you
when I called you up,
I said,
what were you doing well?
And you told me you were on Ambien,
and I said,
okay,
we'll stop right there because I know
quite a bit about that because I've had
personal experiences with friends that
have had real issues with ambien.
I had a bit I did in my act about a
friend of mine who literally made a meal
while he was on Ambien cooked at the
supermarket,
what God
food look at Tiger Woods that he was on
that and then he'd go driving off in the
golf cart to meet some check,
you know,
g and that I don't understand where
people said they had sex on Ambien.
People say that's a big thing that
people take ambien to have sex.
I don't even know how they can stay at.
I guess they don't stay awake,
but another part of them wakes up and
their sex part comes out.
That's all I can figure.
I've never taken it.
I'm terrified of the song ever take.
Yeah.
I,
I get.
Nope.
I have no problem going to sleep.
I've never had.
I do,
but you know,
what I found is thc.
They sell it down at uh,
the dispensary and there's one for sleep
at night.
And um,
I've been doing that and I,
I've been sleeping through the night
when I was taking the sleeping thing,
the sleep and drug ambien.
Well,
I don't want to say it because we don't
want to get some candy,
man.
You don't want to say it three times.
You don't get sued.
Not
say an Ambien.
I bet you they give a fuck.
Did you see their choice?
They said,
I didn't see that today.
Do you see that?
Yeah.
Well,
you know,
I had Hamilton Morris on the podcast who
is a drug expert and he.
He writes for advice and it does a piece
for vice and he went into the advice
after your incident.
He came on and went in great detail
about how that.
That is something that happens to people
that were.
They have no idea what the fuck they're
saying.
It's called a hypnotic.
That is the classification of drugs that
it falls under and people do all sorts
of involuntary things when they're on
it.
No,
it doesn't just make you say racist
things,
but you didn't say anything
intentionally racist.
No.
About the work of Valerie Jarrett's
hands and I also was referencing my very
favorite movie.
So if we could talk about how fucking
awesome that movie planet of the Apes
Great fucking movie.
It's the definitive people get your come
on people now.
It's like,
come on.
It's like the hundredth monkey.
Is that the thing?
Is that the name of it?
That's what it is.
100 monkey on the typewriter.
They write up those monkeys.
What is it?
How is that work that if you have a
certain amount of monkeys,
the hundredth monkey that changes
everything,
right?
If,
if a,
if a species does something 99 times in
a row,
the hundredth time it's gotten into
their DNA.
Oh yeah.
Yeah,
and then they evolve to the next level.
Hundredth monkey effect or just monkey
effect is a hypothetical phenomenon.
Which new behavior ideas co claim to
spread rapidly by unexplained means from
one group to all related groups.
Once a critical number of members of one
group exhibit a new behavior or
acknowledged that new idea.
Yeah.
Well the thing is a lot of people put
pictures of that woman right next to the
lady picture.
I understand the picture was put up
after my tweet.
I understand,
but I am not going to do with that.
I didn't say she looked like anything
real seriously.
I'm not that fucking shallow.
Okay.
I never talk about nobody's looks unless
they're thin and blonde and I'm jealous,
but you know,
and youthful now but or whatever.
But wasn't there another tweet that you
made a long time ago about?
Who was that other woman?
Susan Rice?
Yeah.
Well you said she has giant swing eight
balls that she's a man.
Let me explain that now because this is
the regional listic regionalism.
I'm from Utah and all the girls in Utah
when we got married and are we heard our
moms do it too.
It's always,
where's your ape?
They go,
what?
You're doing this Sunday it.
And he's like,
oh,
he's watching football.
All good.
Let's go out to lunch,
you know,
is all,
all of the men were all apes.
That's how it is in a breeder culture,
like Salt Lake City,
breeder cheerleader culture.
So it's like,
where's your ape?
And was like,
man,
you're a passive big fucking swing and
eight balls.
I give them that,
you know,
it's a regional,
holistic thing.
And uh,
you know,
so I used it and apologize,
but you know,
because I didn't realize,
you know,
I just sometimes forget what race
everybody is as if I could tell half the
time anyway,
I can't even see people that tell you
the truth.
I need like bifocals trifocals and I
never identified other human beings by
what they looked like for God's sake.
I just could tell if I felt a liking to
him.
You know,
whatever they looked like.
Point is the only two things over the
course of thousands of don't mess my
point.
I said,
Susan Rice,
let's say that she has,
she has incredible audacity.
That's what I meant.
And she does.
But you didn't mean it in a
complimentary way.
If someone is audacious,
is that negative or positive?
You weren't you talking about her in a
negative way though?
I said she has a lot of audacity.
That's what I meant.
She does whatever it was that was,
that was one that got brought up as
well.
That was also in the middle of a huge
conversation about,
you know,
Ben Gazi and the Iran deal.
Those are the two things are two of the
three things that I like to do on
twitter,
although I'm no longer on there.
Yeah.
For you.
I was glad to see Kanye west got off to.
Yeah,
he deleted all his account last week and
I was glad to because you're just like,
once you're a target it's just too
painful.
Well definitely shouldn't be reading
that shit.
No,
I don't read it.
But um.
Well,
when
you become a target,
how do you know if you don't read it?
Well,
I know what I've lived through when it
first happened and that's been like four
or so months ago,
so I just know how I've reacted in my
real life since that happened to me.
How long for things die off to die off?
What do you slow down where they weren't
just coming after you constantly,
like I told you that news crews,
when they found out that you were going
to come on the podcast the first time
they were trying to show up at my house,
they were trying to show up at the
studio.
They were trying to find me at the
comedy store.
I mean they were just trying to hunt
down anything about you.
I know I'm snake and segues from my
boyfriend because we were at my mom's
house when I did it.
You know what we were at home in Salt
Lake City when I tweeted at 2:11
AM.
I just woke up and I had this thought in
my head,
oh my God,
this can make so much sense.
And then I tweeted it and I went right
back to sleep and when I woke up at
seven,
the shit had hit the fan,
you know?
Yeah.
But I was like,
I'm going to expound on this later.
That was one of those kinds of things,
right.
You just want to get it down.
And I,
you know,
always slept with my computer and tweet.
When I wake up like one year old,
you have to go to the bathroom a lot.
So I always tweet and fall back to
sleep.
See?
And then on the ambient tweets,
my daughter,
I used to always,
when I took my Ambien,
I call my daughter and she or she called
me.
She goes,
mom,
you,
you're starting to do the Ambien tweets.
Get off,
get off the twitter,
you know.
But uh,
I saw,
I just called my daughter.
Then every night when I,
when I was doing the Ambien and I'd go,
you know what,
here comes a big fish.
She recorded it.
Here comes a big fish right through my
window.
All he's getting stuck in the mirror and
should,
that's for sure.
He goes,
mom turned it all off and go to sleep.
I have to have my family telling me that
because it almost need her standing
guard by your bed.
Hold on,
let me read that before you tweet it.
No,
no,
it doesn't.
Now
she don't.
She took my twitter account away.
We'll use tweets.
All these liberal things that I want to
get just get up in her face and smack
around for no on her own.
And I'm like,
well how come it's okay for you to say
this?
But it ain't for me.
Well mother,
I didn't lose everything.
Oh,
she's trying to help you.
I'm like,
AH,
yeah.
You and your fucking hell
sticks it in your face.
Is your issue serious?
Liberal?
Are
they all.
All three of my daughters are serious
social justice warrior types.
And what did they think about your
position as well?
They think I'm a frigging correct.
They think I'm crazy.
They always did like,
you know,
they always thought all my choice for
president were crazy.
But then oddly they were all very
supportive when I personally ran for
president in 2012.
They were really supportive of me.
Then you're their mom.
Yeah.
That was cool.
But like all other times it's like,
Oh god,
mother,
it's your generation.
The baby boomers are the reason
everything is all fucked up.
So stop letting yourself pop back up.
Conversations in the bar.
Household.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
What,
what was it that when you first got
brought into a mental hospital,
what was it about?
Well,
I had got hit by a car and the,
uh,
the hood ornament went in my head and my
brains and scramble them and I,
I used to be an a plus math student.
I was just great in geometry.
Oh my God,
I loved geometry.
I got straight a's and then,
you know,
I sort of fell apart after that.
Took a long time to heal from it.
And um,
you know,
uh,
how much did you personality change?
Oh,
it changed drastically,
but you know,
you read all that stuff about a
traumatic head injuries now because I do
read a lot and talked to a lot of
football players who have the same thing
and we do discuss it.
Yeah,
you change right away.
it's still you,
but it's like a,
it's kind of like an artel artificial
intelligence.
You do you find that,
did you find that you became much more
impulsive?
Oh yeah.
I,
well,
yeah.
Here's what happened.
I was crossing the street on my way to
school.
How old were you?
I was 16.
No,
it's 15.
Go on to first week of high school and
uh,
I was a big nerd and anyway,
was crossing the street and it was a top
of the hill and this woman girl,
she was on her way to the university and
the sun blinded her and she ran me over.
And uh,
the rest is history.
How,
how long were you in the hospital for
[inaudible]?
So first you must have been,
you must have been in a medical hospital
first and then you were admitted to a
mental hospital after about three months
in between.
Right?
Uh,
but I was in the hospital for awhile,
you know,
and uh,
I had a head concussion and a brain
concussion and I had hamburger,
meat for legs.
So they did all these,
um,
what do they call them?
Skin grafts on my legs.
A and m?
Yeah.
I was in there for awhile.
Then I came out of there and I had
forgotten everything about math when I
returned to school where it's a matter
of weeks after that,
maybe two months.
So I'm really bad on time now.
But uh,
and I had forgotten all my math and it
was just terrible.
That was a big depressive depression I
went into because I couldn't remember.
I couldn't remember things,
you know?
And also I became way more impulsive.
Then I was like,
I don't know what I did.
Then I started going really out there
into the ethers.
I went way out there.
Like how so way out,
you know,
how you go way out.
Do you ever go away out?
Not really.
I've had a lot of head injuries.
Oh yeah.
I've been but not terrible.
Mostly just punches and kicks,
nothin like car accidents or never
played football,
but my head injuries have,
you know,
there were just more of a cumulative
when I was young,
until I was about 21,
22.
I stopped,
stopped fighting,
stop sparring,
but nothing.
But uh,
definitely
I'm subject to impulsive behavior.
Stealing.
Yeah.
But I can't keep it under wraps.
I keep it under control because I'm
aware of it.
But when I was younger I didn't
understand what was going on.
I would just be subject to whims,
very addictive behavior.
But I've tried to keep it positive,
but it would be addicted to things,
addicted to doing things,
addicted to games,
addicted like ridiculously addictive,
like spend 10,
12,
14 hours a day playing video games.
That kind of shit.
My Kid.
Yeah.
Well it's just normal because video
games are awesome.
But yeah,
it would be for me to be everything,
martial arts,
pool,
whatever do is I'll just be completely
obsessed with it and be thinking about
it all day in port where it wasn't
necessarily healthy.
And just on a whim I would just want to
go do something.
I just,
I almost had no control over
compulsion's,
you know,
and I think some of that is it.
Whatever brain injuries that I've had
are very mild in comparison to a lot of
people that I know,
certainly very mild in comparison to
yours.
But there was a lot of trauma in the
state hospital that,
you know,
I'm like,
being there and seeing and experiencing.
And how long did that for nine months.
So what was it that they brought you in
there for?
What was,
how were you behaving that they decided
that you needed to be admitted?
I was out there.
You say that like,
what does that mean?
Um,
I don't think there's any words.
The English you just can't understand,
didn't have a control of reality.
You didn't have control of your
behavior.
Your thinking was screwed up.
I was,
you know,
not thinking like the normal thing that
they say you should be thinking about
and,
but people round you had realized it,
that it was,
it was so bad that they had to admit you
to a hospital.
It wasn't just A.
Oh,
Rosanne.
She's eccentric.
It was.
She needs
actual medical help.
Yeah.
I asked to be admitted.
Do you knew something was really wrong?
She
finally admitted it was.
Did you know at the time were you
completely aware that it was connected
to your car accident?
Uh,
no.
You just knew something was wrong.
Yeah.
And back then they didn't really kind of
understand that the way they understand
it now,
no,
they didn't understand too much about
bipolar disorder or they knew nothing
about multiple personality disorder.
Trauma related trauma related.
Yeah.
PTSD,
now they call everything pts.
Yeah.
They don't even say d anymore.
They say pts post traumatic stress.
So when they admitted you,
what was the treatment like?
What did they do to you when you were
inside the mental hospital?
Well,
they right away put me on an anti
psychotic.
What was it?
Do you remember?
Mallory?
What did that do?
I don't know.
I wasn't there.
You weren't there.
You were gone.
I was gone.
I was just watching these people.
I was in the mental institution width
and I wanted to tell that story because
there was this one lady.
I think I told this to Paul reubens too.
I think it might be worried.
Got Large Marge.
But there's this one lady and she's in
this cage.
No,
she's in a cage with keys on our ward
there.
And uh,
uh,
Christ,
I can't remember her name either.
Marge,
her name was march.
Yeah.
And she's about 600,
700 pounds.
And uh,
she is funnier than hell,
you know,
I thought,
man,
this,
this chick's got smooth lines,
you know,
and I,
it's traded lines with her and she'd
laugh.
You know,
you know,
I was like jokes,
you can always find a job wherever you
are,
you know,
that's the key to life I think.
But um,
so she,
oh,
everybody called me junkie.
That was my name Chunky.
And uh,
there was another girl in their name
shorty,
so it was chunky and shorty where you
were like a duo,
but anyway,
um,
so she's like,
hey,
Roseanne,
get what's her name's keys when they go
to dinner and open this up here and you
know,
come in here.
I'm like,
okay,
you know,
cause,
after all I was crazy too.
And uh,
I don't trust it.
I don't know,
I just always,
I never questioned that there was danger
anywhere.
I always got in trouble,
you know,
got beat up something,
you know.
But uh,
so I did it,
you know,
and I can't all cut.
That was her name,
the head nurse.
I hated her because she told me I needed
a baby.
I'll tell that story later.
It was horrifying.
It changed my life.
But anyway,
so they all go to dinner.
So I go in there and steal the keys out
of the thing where they are,
you know,
the attendance and not go in there with
marge and leave the keys in the door and
close the door.
Yeah.
So I'm like,
hey mark,
how's it going?
Margin.
And she's like,
chunky.
You know why they put me in this cage?
Don't you take some draggers everywhere
I go,
well,
why?
No,
I don't know why.
Well,
chunky because they consider me to be
dangerous.
I'm like,
how come I am?
I'm like Gomer pyle,
serious
play and I'm total gold when you're like
16 at the time.
15 about eight minutes into it I
realized,
Oh shit.
Oh Shit,
something's going on here.
That's how long it always took me to
like zero in,
on what's happening because I'm not even
there,
you know?
I'm always ignoring when other people
talk.
I don't listen to me,
you know?
So I'm always in my own head.
I never get out really except for when I
work.
But uh,
so uh,
then it got done.
It took a turn,
you know,
she's like,
so it got to a why do they consider you
dangerous?
You know,
I had to ask it because she kept on
getting me there to that point where she
wanted me to ask it.
I was trying to delay it,
you know,
because I knew they'd be back in 40
minutes and it was like going on 20 now
she goes,
I'm in here because that's my voice.
I got to do margin.
I'm in here because I broke a couple
attendants backs and they tell you that.
No
My.
How'd you do that?
And then my head,
I'm thinking,
don't change.
Don't miss a beat.
Don't miss a breath.
Don't look nowhere.
Just to keep on Ecmo.
You know,
Utah,
your dog girl.
She knew she was dangerous.
Well that's when it hit my head that it
was,
oh,
she's talking about,
you know,
I'm a,
I'm feeling like pray,
right.
You know,
and I go,
how'd you do that?
Because I'd figured out,
oh,
it's an accident.
You know,
it's good.
All Marge,
she tells good jokes.
She goes,
well,
it's easy.
You just know I'm doing me again.
I got to do her.
It's easy.
You just put one hand here and one hand
here and then you're like,
oh,
oh
hmm.
Where'd you learn that?
I'm changing the subject and 100.
How was your mom?
What was the school like?
You went to.
What's your favorite book?
What's your favorite color?
What kind of ice cream you like?
You ever seen that there's worms in the
oatmeal.
You ever noticed that she started?
That one.
Got Her.
She's like,
yeah,
I did a good notice.
I was crawling motherfuckers.
I go,
yeah,
next week.
Does the effect that this shoe,
this one,
you know,
I like suddenly I'm transported to a
confederacy of dunces when he's on the
thing of,
against Levi pants.
You remember that rant in that book?
So I'm just tap dancing really?
And uh,
then I hear it click.
Fuck man.
I grabbed,
I got fumbled the keys out of the door,
put them back in the uh,
attendance room went my room.
When you said you hear click.
Yeah,
I knew the first door got opened.
There was two doors that I heard the
first door open.
They're coming back from,
from dinner.
So you got away from us,
be sick,
you know,
in my room.
That's why I didn't go to dinner.
Yeah.
So Ms Dot lay in there.
And that was like daily.
I mean there were so many weird people
in there.
We had this one girl,
Rosie,
her name was where she'd always grabbed.
She always ended up with a pair of sharp
scissors and lunch for someone's throat.
We're like,
where'd you get them?
Who's bringing her them scissors,
you know?
But anyway,
I went on an anti psychotic medicine and
um,
that was good that I was on there for
the Shit I saw.
Now when you say any my friends hanging
and stuff like that.
Sorry,
friends hanging in the mental
institution.
So I saw worse than that.
Would you say hi?
I saw,
you know,
victims of abuse was terrible by the
guards.
Know,
have kids coming in know victims of
abuse that came in that were mentally
scarred by that.
Yeah.
Now when they put you on anti
psychotics,
was it because you were exhibiting
psychotic behavior?
What kind of psychotic behavior?
While they thought it was psychotic high
was just scared that they.
I think I was throwing them off because
I want to think.
I was like,
got it.
I didn't want to think them to think I
was schizophrenia.
I knew enough not to let them near me
that if [inaudible] once you got the,
uh,
once you got the diagnosis of
schizophrenia they would just shocks and
they experiment on,
you're basically,
you're in Guinea pig and I didn't want
that,
so maybe I,
you know,
and then you know,
so yeah,
I was doing weird things like walking
down the middle of streets after I hit
by the car,
I walked down the middle of the streets.
I don't know,
I thought,
Oh,
you got to get over your fear of
crossing the streets.
That's what was in my head.
And then I'd walk down the highway,
you know,
I was in a whole other realm.
It was like a real surrealistic and
metaphysical realm and I grew
comfortable there.
But,
you know,
I think most artists,
writers and performers are in that
world.
I mean,
we've got a toe in it,
at least I've gone in and out,
you know,
depending on,
now I think I'm on the right
medications.
That helped me.
Um,
there's a lot of comedians that have
similar stories,
you know,
some of the grades,
Kinison as a similar story to,
you know,
he was hit by a car and change changes
personality radically.
And it happened in a similar age.
It happened when he was young as well.
And he was one person and then you get
hit by a car.
And then after the car he was just wild
man.
Wild didn't give a fuck.
Well,
totally impulsive,
but I didn't give a fuck it.
So I just thought different,
thought,
different.
I was just,
um,
I don't know,
my mom says when I was 18 months old,
I used to go out in the street and
direct cars.
We lived on a highway and uh,
you know,
that,
uh,
she'd come and find me there just 18
months.
All the holding up my hands,
Jesus Christ,
stop in traffic.
It's always had a weird thing going
there.
But uh,
you know,
I don't know.
I think I watched too much of that
police show,
you know,
where they'd stopped traffic.
I used to love TV shows and think they
were real.
Some of it.
But how many people do you think know
this about your mental health history?
You know,
anybody who knows me,
I don't think very many people know
what,
that we're angry you.
Oh yeah,
they did.
I don't think they did.
Yeah,
they did.
I don't think people look past the
surface.
I think they looked at you as a rich
white lady who said something that they
considered to be racist and they decided
they were going to attack you.
And then the perception,
the optics of this is the reason why ABC
canceled the show.
The reason why was ABC,
right?
Yeah.
It's the reason why they canceled the
show is the reason why everybody pulled
back away from you.
And what did that feel like when nobody
defended you?
People who should know you the way I
know you and I defended you from the
very beginning because I said,
look at my son told me I might.
Thank you.
This is not a racist person.
I go,
this is a woman who's kinda crazy.
He's brilliant.
Hilarious.
Fun To be around.
Yes.
It was one of the reasons why I love
you.
Well,
you know,
they try to outlaw comedy.
That's what I.
Well I was surprised that more comics
didn't say nothing because you know,
they,
I don't know,
they're scared.
People are scared.
They're scared to support someone that
they considered to be racist,
you know?
I mean,
I got a lot of shit from it,
but I don't give a fuck.
Yeah,
I didn't.
I didn't think what they want and call
me what they want.
It don't change me.
It doesn't change you.
Well it just takes time before the dust
settles.
And I knew that once I knew that once
you and I talked,
if you and I sat down and talked like
this,
people get a chance to see who you
really are,
you know?
Well,
you know,
they might not like me,
I don't have to know.
They don't.
You're not a bad person,
you've never been a bad person.
I'm not a bad person,
but I've done bad things and like I was
talking to,
uh,
you know,
I'm a name dropper.
I hate to drop his name out,
but forgive me,
I should have asked him first,
but you know,
I was talking to Mike Tyson,
you know,
and uh,
he's been through some stuff and uh,
you're like,
well,
the thing is you gotta you gotta become
a pacifist.
That's,
that's your only.
Yeah.
Don't battle with people who don't know.
I can't battle with people back and
forth online.
You know what I mean?
Um,
there's too many people,
there's not enough time and you'll go
crazy.
You'll get wrapped up in conflict and
you'll just be involved in it every
minute of every day.
Yeah.
I call it feeding the beast.
Because that really is tower of Babel,
twitter.
Well,
it's,
it's definitely a strange,
strange environment where all these
people are just,
they don't even know you.
They have no contact with you other than
your this person they could reach and
get to react to certain lines and the
more explosive and the more derogatory
and insulting the lines they say to you,
the more impact it's gonna have on you
so that flavors the way they communicate
with you.
Okay.
Yeah,
it was.
It was tough working with a lot of
social justice warriors and remake.
It was tough on me mentally.
So when you mean like the staff that you
were working
with?
Luck.
I was the only one saying I'm not a
Republican.
Dora my fucking Democrat.
I'm an independent and I'm just
anticorruption.
I'm just anticorruption don't,
don't make me into what your idea of who
I am.
What was that idea who you were and.
Well,
they thought that since I supported
president trump or that I was,
you know,
a racist and a scumbag and you know,
anti everything just because I voted for
him.
Why did you support trump?
I love what Norm Macdonald said.
If I can quote him,
can I quote says it better than
anything.
He said the American people.
I hated hillary so bad that they voted
for a guy.
They hate it even worse.
Just don't rub it in.
That is normal Mcdonald.
That's brilliant.
But you know,
I wasn't,
I wasn't for Hillary and I was a woman
and that was like a big.
No,
no,
right.
That's Alec basically down to because it
was a woman's turn.
But,
you know,
I'm,
I,
I just want a government that works for
the American people,
the Ta.
I pay taxes and I expect something for
my taxes and,
you know,
here's news to all of them out there,
including poultice.
Uh,
I think at some time the American people
need to audit what happened to their tax
monies and I think we should all have a
say in what this country does with our
hard earned dollars.
And uh,
don't just assume you speak for us
because obviously you don't or we
wouldn't have a trade deficit of
$20,000,000,000,000.
So stfu and,
uh,
let the American people handle what they
should handle in this country.
It's a republic and it's a runs on the,
uh,
on the consent of the governed.
And it's really,
really time to talk about that
now.
When you say social justice warriors
that you had to work with specifically,
what were the issues that you were
dealing with?
Well,
trump was the big elephant in the room.
My support for trump and they're just,
they're patronized.
Scheidt can I call it?
Yeah,
well we have to remember that the.
I mean I'm going to paraphrase,
but it was a lot.
Well,
you know,
the ignorant unwashed people who voted
for trump,
it's not their fault.
That was Kinda what it was like.
And uh,
because I said,
well,
you know,
it was working class people that elected
trump.
So I,
I really can't,
I can't let you say that to me because
it's not true,
you know,
they already had in their head what it
means.
And of course they are wrong.
Like they're wrong about this being
about,
you know,
the cabinet being about abortion rights
or wrong about that too.
So,
you know,
they're wrong about that because I don't
think,
you know,
he said pretty much that,
you can't overturn something that's in
law Roe versus Wade.
Yeah.
But you know,
they fear mongered to get everybody
thinking that's what they were after and
I don't think it is what they were.
I don't think that is why they wanted
to.
I think they're concerned with anything
that trump is trying to pass
anyone that trump's trying to get to the
supreme court in any bills
they should put on their adult pants and
get involved and make sure that he
represents,
you know,
the will of the people of this country.
You have to become involved in the
process then,
but don't just sit there on your butt
criticized and everybody and calling
everybody names that,
that's really not any kind of a justice
warrior.
That's all phony.
You got to get involved right
now.
When you were first approached about
doing a Rosanne,
the relaunch,
when they came to you,
how did this all take place and did you
get to pick the people that you work
with?
Um,
I had already said about a year prior to
that that I supported trump over
hillary.
And it was like,
you know,
a big.
It was in all the papers in Hollywood,
how,
how could she and,
you know,
this and that and the other,
but it didn't seem to bother the
American people outside of my audience.
Well,
you know,
I always try to make content for the
audience,
not for the critics.
Right.
And enough for the industry,
not for the industry.
Now the industry is ruthlessly left,
like to the point where it's not even a
thinking thing.
It's just like they automatically go
left because that's the way you're
accepted in this town.
That's the way you stay working.
That's the way you stay invited to all
the time.
That's the way that certain Stalinist
types in show business.
Keep it,
you know,
uh,
everything about the media is tightly
controlled in Hollywood.
So when they came,
who came to you with the relaunch?
How did it,
how like how does it happen?
That was an era where they did a sketch
on Sarah's talk show and everyone liked
it.
And Sarah called me and said,
she said,
John said he's in,
if you,
you know,
if you're in.
So you say Johnson of course is Lori.
Yeah,
Lori's in.
Okay.
Uh,
yeah,
let's do it.
So what,
who turned on you after this was over
while I'm my covenant of lawyers,
Advisors.
I not get into this at this time.
That's,
you know,
I think it's self explanatory where
people could find out.
Yeah,
I don't know that they turned on me.
I think it was always that way since,
you know,
I came in and said,
I said no,
somebody on the show has to be a trump
supporter.
None of them would do it.
I'm like,
it's a great role.
You know,
you could do it.
You're the kind of person who wouldn't.
And they were like,
no.
So I said,
okay,
well then I'll do it because,
you know,
I did vote for him.
Every knows it.
Well people forget archie bunker.
It's one of the greatest characters in
the history of sitcoms.
Nobody wants to be the quote unquote,
you know,
other,
the bad person,
the bad guy in Hollywood or you know,
be the other in Hollywood.
But,
you know,
I,
I was up for it.
I thought it would be great.
I thought it would be,
you know,
I get some lines in there from the other
side once in awhile,
you know,
I,
I let him say all they want to say.
I never told them don't say that about
him,
don't this and that,
like the day of the filming,
you know,
I'd been saying,
I let my writers do their Brighton,
you know,
but I lay out all the stories or approve
them,
you know.
And uh,
so
it was that first show and I'm waiting
for a line about hillary.
I go,
I let you have seven trump jokes in this
show.
And you came in one fucking Hillary.
Joe Didn't want hilary joke.
Now what was the hilary joke?
Do you remember?
I said,
you better get me a hilary joke.
I did.
I go,
it ain't about you,
your name and on this shit.
What did they say about it?
Like why did they not want to hilary
joke?
Did they have an explanation for it?
No,
but everybody knew they wanted Hillary.
Yeah.
They felt it would go against their
morals to say that there's another way
to vote or to acknowledge that you know,
half the country voted that way or that
she's extremely flawed.
Well,
that point they didn't care.
That's what's weird about it,
isn't that the whole thing's weird.
There's a complete denial of reality
like this is not.
There's nothing to do with women as
nothing to do with liberals.
That is another.
You're talking about an extremely flawed
person.
Well,
I don't.
I'm not going to talk about her as a
person.
I just talk about her concepts and her
voting record.
Not even use the word person,
politician.
Extremely flawed politician with a
background of deep corruption and lies.
Demonstratable lies like this.
We're not talking about some amazing
gem,
you know.
Well,
let's just put it like this.
A lot of us people who liked Bernie
voted for trump.
Yes.
I'll put it like that.
Yeah.
Well,
especially when they found out when
Donna Brazile's book came out and they
found out what they had done to Bernie
during the primaries.
Yeah.
It's dark shit.
It's dark that,
that just everybody's like,
whatever.
Whatever they said,
nobody will vote for a Jew,
they'd use that one.
It's hilarious in the cell to this day,
to this day,
they're still doing stupid shit like
that.
But that,
you know,
I didn't want her even though she is a
woman,
but you know,
uh,
I did want her in 2008.
I wanted to her,
not Obama because I liked her healthcare
plan better at that time when I was
still,
you know,
before I walked away.
So,
um,
you know,
they're doing a whole march.
I might show up a march for what?
Walk away,
walk away from what the Democrat Party,
who is they,
who's doing this and a whole bunch of
kids,
youth.
And what's the ID number?
Twenty seven that the cross from the
White House.
They're going to walk from the DNC to
that park there and make statements,
but walking away to wear to an
independent party.
Terrian.
They're going Republican,
Republican.
That's what's bizarre.
The polar opposites.
The right and the left,
the blue and the red
and all those guys golf together.
Let's get to cut through the bullshit.
They're all making deals.
And scratching each other's back,
whether from one party or the other.
Come on.
Well,
trump
paid Clinton to be at his wedding.
He did?
Yeah.
Wow,
that's smart.
He got a photo op and a half out of that
one.
I mean,
he paid those people forever.
It's one of the reasons why when,
when he was campaigning,
he had so much animosity towards them
and towards the system that he was a
part of for so long.
He was a democrat most of his life.
I know.
Well,
he's getting the.
He's getting it too.
But uh,
that just proves it right there.
You know,
they give money to both parties.
in Hollywood,
they don't just get to the Democrat
party because the Republican Party to.
But they stay silent about that.
Well,
it's Kinda smart duck cover your at
bats,
you know,
which government contractor couldn't be
able to dip into.
And isn't that like what Hollywood is
really all about?
Well,
there's so many levels to it,
right?
I mean,
there's the blatant tribalism of right
versus left where people pick a side and
they adopt a predetermined pattern or
behavior and they adopt a conglomeration
of ideas and the program.
Yes.
Yeah.
And they're just bought.
Exactly.
They pair it ever.
And then below the surface he got geo
political aspirations.
And you have the,
the global war machine.
Yeah.
Um,
that's,
that's what you have the money,
the real money.
But you know what Joe,
I always say when people call me a,
a,
a whatever they call me,
but I have optimism and I've said for a
long time when the right people are at
the controls of all the machinery and
technology that will be so great for
humanity.
We have the right within our grasp to,
you know,
make sure that this is a good place for
all kids.
We could do that tomorrow.
So I think we should start thinking
about that and all this artificial
intelligence that gets us fighting with
each other.
Let's just step out of it like the
Matrix,
you know,
let's go to a new place where we're
about solutions and working together and
bringing this country together and
getting some real good jobs,
real good health care.
Things that we pay taxes for better
streets,
good education.
The things we pay taxes for.
Yeah.
And mental health.
Most of all,
I think that's what we need to protect
for our veterans.
They come back and they're,
they're untreated and they won't even
give him marijuana,
which really helps.
They weren't even legalized that for,
you know,
people who have pts and marijuana does
help with pts and uh,
you know,
talk about supporting our troops.
Twenty two of them a day are killing
themselves.
They're homeless.
I mean that,
that's who we are.
I don't want that to be who we are.
Come on.
They'd people think nobody can see us
and we do,
but they do and they,
they want it,
right?
People want things to be right in work
and used for the good of all people and
stop tearing people apart from each
other.
We're neighbors,
you know,
that was why I wanted to go back to the
Roseanne show and say all those things
and I'm so happy that I did.
I did it in nine episodes,
I wonder,
10th season and I did all nine episodes
where exactly the episodes I wanted to
do,
so,
uh,
and it was number one every week and I
just thank my fans for that,
you know,
a,
a turn of fortune.
But um,
I did what I wanted to do and uh,
and it was so gratifying.
It's so wonderful and I don't want that
to be forgotten.
I don't want the ninth season to
disappear.
I'm in the 10th season to disappear.
What do you think about them doing it
without you?
How fucking weird is that?
It is weird.
I'm like,
oh,
I get it.
They're sending me a subtle message to
ode on opioids.
You.
No,
that sounds that.
Where you think.
Yeah,
that's some of it mind control stuff.
Yeah.
So you think that they want you to kill
yourself?
Well,
I don't know why they would do what they
did.
Let's put it that way.
Doesn't make any sense.
I just,
I just think they're being completely
inconsiderate and they don't care about,
you know,
they don't and they,
they so belittled my contribution to the
show too.
It just was shocking.
That was the most painful part of the
whole thing.
But one of the things that I read was
that you hadn't considered the more than
100 people that work on the show when
you did what you did.
And I'm like,
that is,
that's a ridiculous statement.
I didn't cancel the show.
Not only did you not cancel the show,
you were on ambien drunk tweeting.
Did the idea that you did this,
this was some sort of a deliberate ploy
to get the show canceled or the idea
that there was any justification that's
just shows should be canceled at all.
Like what?
You can't just say something that you,
you didn't want to come out that way and
apologize for it.
You guys,
I apologize.
Apologize for three months.
No.
Yeah,
they don't know who you are now.
They tried to wipe me off the,
uh,
off the map of the culture because
people are scared to be connected with
anybody who's a target and they acted
like cowards.
I wouldn't have done.
I mean,
if it were my friend,
definitely I would have years of two
decades or more,
I would have said something and I
definitely,
one thing I would never have done is,
um,
stab somebody in the rush to condemn
somebody who,
you know,
was my biggest,
uh,
advocate.
Well,
there was a lot of,
sometimes an only advocate.
There was a lot of that.
I saw a lot of that about them.
It's just about them.
It's not about me.
I just let go of all of it because,
you know,
I,
I try,
I am a person of belief and I just
always try to do what's right in front
of me.
I feel like what,
uh,
you know,
my higher intelligence plays in front of
me.
I'll do it and [inaudible] it knows
better than me and um,
which is why I don't think like other
people.
But,
um,
and also that,
I,
I was not going to fight not at 66.
I'm too old.
I,
I'm pretty frail and I think,
you know,
I worked really hard to get a second
season and it's kind of ironic.
I crossed time-zones to do promotion for
free for months.
And uh,
you know,
during that time when you're old and you
can't sleep and you're crossing time
zones,
going from Hawaii to New York and back
and then back again and back again,
you know,
uh,
I kind of became dependent on Ambien and
I,
you know,
almost every night took it.
And uh,
you know,
obviously I,
something was wrong because I,
I didn't think,
I thought that tweet was about a science
fiction movie,
which happens to be my favorite movie.
And which I think is a very apt in the
world today,
particularly in Iran,
were just a small group of corrupt
leaders are oppressing the citizens.
And,
uh,
I think it,
I think there's a lot of references in
that movie that,
uh,
go along with what's happening in Iran,
of the human beings rising up to throw
over there to over throw their
overlords.
And that's how I was looking at the
whole thing.
So when I woke up to tweet there,
that was what was in my head.
It was certainly not somebody looks and,
uh,
it was also about the Arab spring in
Egypt,
which,
uh,
you know,
Obama,
he didn't handle it right.
And,
uh,
so all those things are interrelated
with Iran and the Iran deal,
the Iran nuclear deal.
You know,
I'm,
I'm extremely well read on that subject.
I certainly wouldn't be at the height of
my power and my fame
being on there going command key.
Excuse me.
I'm not an idiot.
Okay.
I won't be on the key.
I'm a well read and intelligent woman in
my word and things that I write to
people over in that part of the world
there.
I've brought a lot of people together in
that part of the world with my tweets
and most of my tweets are spiritual in
nature anyway.
So,
uh,
it wasn't what people thought it was and
still,
I apologize for.
I'm inadvertently hurting anyone's
feelings still.
I apologize for inadvertently and not,
you know,
I apologize that they were wrong and
they misheard it and misunderstood it,
but that wasn't good enough either.
And you know,
just get to a point where I go,
I'm letting go of it,
uh,
my fans who know me and my family and
people who like me and know me for my
life,
they know who I am and that's all that
matters.
You know,
they can call me whatever they want.
I don't accept their definition of that
word.
And I think that they should read more.
Well,
one of the things that's most shocking
about this outrage culture that we live
in right now,
this age of outrage is that there is no
path to redemption.
There's,
there's no acceptance of these.
There is though,
be a,
but there's not from the general public.
Oh yeah,
the public.
Everywhere I went,
people run up to me.
I never felt so much love in my entire
career,
in real life,
but not on twitter and I'm not on social
media,
not on social media,
social media.
It magnifies the very worst aspects of
humanity because you're not interacting
with people in the real flesh.
You're not experiencing social cues.
You're not looking them in the eye,
you're not seeing them as a person.
You're just seeing them as a target
online.
Well,
I think that twitter has,
is a purposeful plan.
Uh,
like facebook.
I got off facebook years ago because I
realized what they were doing,
what I think twitter is doing and doing
the same thing that facebook did.
How,
so it's manufacturing consent and you
know,
it's using bots to do it by
manufacturing consent.
It's a place where like Noam Chomsky
says,
you know,
the press manufacturers consent,
that consent of the governed.
So that's what they're doing is
manufacturing the consent of the
governed,
but they also manufactured descent.
They control the opposition to on
twitter.
And I liked getting in between those two
and causing a Ruckus because I knew it
was all artificial intelligence anyway.
It's all just a track us,
we all know that just like they do in
China.
So what are you saying?
You think there's some sort of a grand
plan to get people to argue with each
other?
Yeah,
I think it's a social experiment to turn
one group against another,
which,
you know,
it's smart because it's divide and
conquer.
And as long as we're like,
you know,
it's all these people getting robbed.
All these taxpayers getting robbed,
sitting there pointing to other tax
payers.
They're getting robbed and blaming them.
But nobody.
Everybody needs to look upward of our
government asked for an audit of our
taxes and actually take responsibility
for the things that our country does.
We're getting judged for it anyway.
I think we allowed.
I think there's certainly people that
are capitalizing on all this chaos
and uh,
all the,
all the conflict.
But I don't think it's manufactured and
I don't think it's engineered.
I just think it's happening because this
is a new thing,
this,
this ability to interact with each
other.
I think people have a mind of their own
and people are inherently tribal.
There's almost no way to stop them from
being tribal tribes or tribal,
but the problem with tribalism is easy
sometimes have enemies that are
unnecessary,
so you develop this common ground,
but that would be nice if we all looked
at ourselves as a tribal world.
That's how I do look at the world and
why I didn't want Hillary Clinton
because her party is very much for
corporate law and the Republican Party
is very much for tribal law and I am a
tribal person and I think tribal people
should,
you know,
have their land.
Tribal.
In what way?
How he tribal me?
Yeah.
Well I'm Jewish.
When I go over there to the Middle East,
I visit the graves of my teachers.
That's how I'm tribal.
I go to their graves and that's what we
do.
That's what all indigenous people do.
They want to control their sacred burial
grounds and that is anti corporate law
and that's why I'm anti corporate law.
I can't.
I like to study paypal bowls and
corporate law and a maritime law and all
that kind of stuff.
You know,
I like to read so I have a lot of
information and you know,
it makes me angry or sad is that that
the work of an artist over 30 years,
you think they think that we just pull
that out of their ass and that they can
copy it,
you know,
without the artists,
they can copy it.
You mean your show?
I do.
Yeah.
And it,
it,
it is.
You know,
all the stuff I suffered in my life I
put into that show.
That show is about my family,
my children,
and it's just like,
wow,
this is so huge.
It's so huge.
It's,
it's beyond entitled,
but what are they going to,
what is their plan and how are they able
to do that?
Did you let them signed off?
He asked me to sign off because I felt
like I would be a huge hypocrite too.
Have talked 30 years or more in my life
about labor rights and the rights of
working people if I took away those p
200 people's jobs.
So that's why I did it.
I wanted them to work.
I know how they had planned on another
season and they probably had already
spent the money.
Was there any consideration of
redemption?
Was there any path where they can allow
you to apologize or do something that
would endear yourself to the people
where they heard that?
I said,
let me go on all your,
uh,
abc us and explained my tweet and how it
was a political and not a racial tweet
and um,
you know,
that was denied me.
It's like you can't say anything until
you sign off.
You can't say anything until you sign
off.
So they wanted you to sign off the
rights and then they would have you do
whatever you want to do.
Go on their interview shows.
They didn't guarantee that,
didn't guarantee that.
So they just wanted you to sign off and
they offered you nothing in return.
They offered me some money,
but the idea was just to be able to Redo
the show.
Yeah,
to take all those years of my ideas and
how I thought of 20 years of those
situations to come back.
It took me 20 years to figure out how
would these characters,
where would they be now?
And I did that by living among regular
normal people for 20 years.
I never lived behind a,
you know,
a racially segregated gates like other
stars.
I lived in working people's
neighborhoods and I farm around farmers
and I wasn't going to be that big of a
hypocrite.
Macadamia nut farm.
I sure do.
It's gorgeous.
You should come and see it.
I love the Big Island.
Isn't it gorgeous?
Amazing.
People are dumb.
They're though today.
You know what I read from people.
Some lady took a boat full of people too
close to the volcano to look at it and
the lava over took their boat and thank
God.
Now I'm were killed,
but they were got like about two feet up
on the.
Oh Jesus.
So don't do that.
Hawaiians don't do that.
Somebody got hit with there.
That's probably why it's pretty good
weed.
Yeah.
They got hit by a flying chunk of rock
from the volcano on.
Um,
one of the boats too.
They were having lava tourism and
someone gets hit by a rock.
It's so not smart.
It's so stupid.
It's a dangerous,
dangerous situations.
Shouldn't be.
Don't go on those tours.
Your area safe.
Uh,
my,
my area flooded a bed.
I had to replace my roads for about the
10th time in 10 years.
I always got to replace my roads.
I really got into making roads.
That's one thing that I really did
enjoy.
So I'll be headed back there and be
making more roads.
I'm excited about it.
I can cut a road like nobody's business.
I'm a hell of.
I wanted to write a book.
My granny is a scout and a [inaudible].
I do scout the jungle,
you know,
and make a road in there.
I love the attitude of people that live
in the big island.
It's a very relaxed,
laid back,
friendly attitude.
The,
they just have all the time in the
world.
It's a different sort of vibe when you
go there.
Yeah,
everybody helps their neighbors,
their,
they don't like turn them in where
everybody helps out their neighbors and
their neighbors are like every,
every kind of people you can think of
it.
It's very,
uh,
a very,
um,
diverse cultural.
How'd you wind up Medicare?
Well,
I went there because my son Buck I had,
I made him go to the school out there.
So then I bought a place right by the d
school because this kid,
you know,
he had feel he's 23 now so he probably
won't get mad,
but he had some severe adhd there,
so I had to do what I did to get him.
Now he just graduated from college.
He's doing real good.
Yeah,
he is my first college Grad.
[inaudible] all right.
Adhd.
Maybe he's a comic.
Yeah.
He's so funny.
Oh my God,
he's so hilarious.
Maybe he's a comic to sweet,
so.
Sure it's,
my grandkids are too.
They're all video that you show me.
They're all hilarious.
Yeah,
they seemed very funny.
Oh,
what are they gonna do to your character
on the show?
Uh,
they're gonna kill you off.
Yeah,
I think they did.
They didn't tell you some of.
I know they didn't tell me.
How weird is it?
Some of my spies told me.
They're taking you out of Roseanne.
They're calling it the connors.
It's all going on without you being
there.
What does that feel like?
Um,
it's a mind warp and a mind fuck,
you know.
So I'm just trying to go from a tweet.
Yeah,
a miss.
Understood.
Tweet,
misunderstood.
Tweet while you're on ambien while
you're drunk.
Drunk only had like one or two beers.
Well,
when you have one or two beers with
ambien.
Yeah,
I guess you're drunk.
You're fucked up.
I was,
yeah.
I wasn't in smoking pot too,
right?
No,
I don't think I'd smoke pot then.
I didn't smoke pot then
I was at my mom's house on the.
So I went down in the basement.
I was hiding down there in the basement
because they were surrounded my mom's
house,
Papa razzies and search.
And so as a down in the basement.
And that's where I always used to go
when I was 13 and I found this stuff and
chalk on the,
on the walls of the basement there that
I remembered right when I was 13.
And then I found an old.
But from one I snuck segues when I was
13.
Smoking.
Oh hell yeah.
It smell good.
No,
I'm kidding.
But I was hiding down there smoking.
They were knocking on my mom's door and
I was like,
oh my God.
So my boyfriend got the door.
He's like a big man,
you know,
he's like,
may I help,
you know,
that's my man character.
And uh,
I thought they were gonna,
you know,
say something.
And they're like,
we just please tell Roseanne we love her
and you know,
we don't like this and Blah Blah.
And that was happening all the time.
And that's when I was like,
Geez,
I've never ever felt this kind of
affection
from people in all my career.
So it's kind of a cool.
That's,
that's the thing,
there's the social media outrage and
then there's people in real life that
feel terrible for you because they feel
like you got a raw deal.
Yeah.
They think that there's doubt there.
There are so many double standards of
people who said things on the air.
Remember I just said it to a small
population,
less than 600,000
people on twitter,
but these people say things on the air
and they are not.
Well,
I know joy had to call pants and
apologize.
So yeah.
What a joy bay say about pence.
It was so bad.
She something about his Christian faith
that they're psychotic or something
because they.
So she'd call us.
Yeah,
that's what I heard,
you know,
an apology with your network behind you
really works.
Like with,
what's her name that called Ivanka?
The names.
I can't remember.
Samantha and her network was behind her
and that was far more offensive and it
was on the air and uh,
but when your network is not behind you
that you don't really know they were.
They didn't want me to tweet the whole.
The whole truth is I,
I told him I wasn't going to tweet and
you know,
I promised him over and over and
although they never send it in writing,
which was required,
but anyway,
they called my publicist and unloaded on
him all the time.
Can,
you know,
I should've stayed up twitter.
I did it to myself and uh,
you know,
I made a mistake and,
and the ball kept rolling,
put.
It's just crazy that this what I think
is insignificant mistake,
especially in light of your apology
could lead to no redemption possible.
Yeah.
Didn't no redemption possible.
That this giant fucking hit show.
And I look,
I don't know what's going to happen with
the connors,
but I think it's going to fail.
Asked me if I had some money to bet if I
was in vegas because that shit ain't
gonna work.
How's it?
Good.
How Are you going to do Rosanna without
Roseanne?
If you wanted to have a whole new sitcom
with all those people with a totally
unrelated storyline,
that's one thing,
but you don't think America is going to
know that they killed you off.
Like what the fuck is that and that and
now with time and consideration after
time has passed and people can review
everything,
they're going to go was really this bad
and they're going to think about their
own lives.
Like what about me?
What if I say something fucked up just
fucking around.
I take ambien and accidentally say
something crazy and don't even remember
saying it and then it's misconstrued or
it comes out wrong.
Is it going to ruin my whole life?
Like how can you have someone ruined
their whole life for something that is
misconstrued teen also a in a rally.
I mean that's why I think first of all
us women,
we need to do a better job of raising
our sons and a bet at 17.
Everyone's out of their frigging mind.
I have five kids.
There's not a one of them who didn't do
something horrendous at eight,
17.
What?
We were just talking about that with
Andrew Santina who was in here earlier.
That yeah.
When when young men,
especially young men that don't get a
birds and the bees speech and who knows
what the fuck is going on in their home,
you know,
people do stupid shit.
Yeah.
My son that went to college,
but he says he learned the day he
started college.
They gave out this pamphlet on sexual
assault to all the boys.
I guess I gave it to the girls too,
but he said he read it and he realized
it was any kind of sexuality at all is
don't even do it.
And I,
I told both.
My sons,
do you got to get you.
If you're going to have sex with
somebody,
you make them sign a consent form and
have take it to their lawyer and get it
properly notarized and then make a date
for after that happened.
Live in this dangerous time for our sons
and our daughters.
Well,
it's always a dangerous time for women
right in with the wrong man.
Well,
or the wrong woman.
Are you shitting me?
Women are just as horrible as man.
I'm terrible with women to this one.
Cool assault and rape,
uh,
amongst lesbian couples.
It's,
it's pretty bad,
but I mean,
what about rape in the prisons?
I mean,
nobody talks about that.
That's,
that's the real rape culture where men
are learning,
you know,
it's terrible.
Well,
yeah.
Well we can get into depth about how bad
prisons are in general and how people
aren't reading.
You ever watch orange is the new block,
so I know.
I've never seen it.
It's great.
Oh my God,
it's great.
But the problem with,
you know,
there's no rehabilitation.
I mean it's,
it's very rare looseness in,
in prisons.
What you're doing is you take people and
you make them better criminals or make a
more hardened criminals.
You surrounded with other criminals.
You give them a horrible work,
Lord,
living further because most prisoners
are in their because they're abused
children.
Well,
and what percentage of prisoners are in
there for nonviolent drug offenses just
drives me crazy.
Fucking insane.
When I ran for president,
I ran on legalization of marijuana for
that exact reason.
Well,
slowly but surely.
That's becoming a mainstream idea.
I'm glad.
Glad to.
I mean,
as a rabid pot user,
I love it.
No,
I think marijuana is,
it makes you more sensitive,
aware person.
It definitely makes you paranoid,
but I think that paranoia allows you to
understand all the danger in the world
that you probably ignoring.
Yeah.
One more time,
like I was with March,
you know,
uh,
once I started smoking pot,
then I got real paranoid of people and
that was a good thing.
You shouldn't be paranoid of.
People should be aware of for sure.
Particularly if you watch cable TV for
crisis,
that ID channel.
What are you doing now?
Like what are you going to do now?
You were saying that you have some other
things cooking.
You know,
I got 20,000
ideas a day.
Why don't you do something like this?
I got a focus into something.
Why don't you do this?
Which something like this.
So easy.
So you said You'd help me?
I just can't.
I don't know how to write it in a
fucking password.
Turn this shit on.
Listen,
you don't need that.
We can get you connected to someone who
can do that for you.
That shit's easy.
I'd like to talk to other people who've
fallen from grace and see how they get
back up,
but the,
the real truth of it is that there is
redemption,
there is and there,
there's moving on and there's like
stopping the fight and there's like,
you know,
for me it was a while.
I realized they're not my family.
My real family is,
you know,
a joy to me.
And uh,
I got a great real family.
I raised two good sons and uh,
you know,
of course I want them protected from
crazy women for crying out loud.
I,
I over modulate their dating lives.
I do filter them.
Yeah.
You have two.
How old are your sons?
Once 40.
Try to filter my dating life would be
like,
mom,
I love you.
Yeah,
shut the fuck up.
That's because your mom ain't me.
That's true.
Because I go,
no,
this is,
you know,
we can't have no bitches up in,
can't.
I can't take no second class picks
telling me I'm beneath her.
That's why I helped break up my son's
marriage because she way she treated me.
You had someone who's disrespecting,
you know,
you're never gonna fucking well that and
all my daughters,
thank God all their sons,
they listened to me.
They do what I tell them,
so it's great.
So I have good son in laws.
That's good.
The One?
No,
he's a problem.
He's from Russia.
He's Russian.
And on his wedding night,
here's what he says to me.
He goes,
does he have a Russian accent?
Yeah.
Can you do it?
Oh,
I can't do that.
I try.
Well,
here's what he said to me,
knowing this family,
it's a family.
We do what the law says.
We don't do what the grandma's grandma
says.
I go,
bitch,
are you new?
I go,
okay,
well,
if you want to live a curse live,
go ahead and live in fucking curse life.
I put that Judy.
Yeah,
he's coming around though.
I knew he would have.
Now they have a son and he has adhd too.
And uh,
but he's brilliant and as all my
grandkids.
And anyway,
so they were there.
Those lived.
Oh,
I shouldn't have said that loop towards.
No,
you can't say that anymore.
Now you're
not to say that I forgot because I'm
old.
I mixed them up.
Who says you're not to say that
everybody says you don't say the t word,
so as long as you don't have a reebok
before,
I think you're allowed to say it.
No,
I don't say it in public but not and I
don't.
But uh,
anyway,
so,
um,
you know,
the kid he's bouncing off the walls to
like all my kids were so I know how to
deal with it,
you know,
I said just leave them over here with
me.
I'll take care of it.
So I did.
Would you do with them?
Get them active?
Yeah.
You get them active.
Get them doing stuff.
Exactly.
I go,
I bet you I bet you $100.
You can't run up and down that hill 10
times in a row.
Perfect.
GotTa keep boys tired.
Yeah.
I guarantee I have adhd.
I have all those things.
Yeah.
You probably do do stuff.
Just burning this stuff.
Yeah.
Bring it out and then he can be calm.
Yeah,
exactly.
I think those kids just have a lot of
fuel.
I do have a lot of horsepower and a lot
of fuel and it's all misdirected and
then get in with the girl and she
started telling them what to do.
So I'm telling you,
once they get under the control of a
female,
say there they forget theirselves.
Girls do it too.
Sure.
We get to control the wrong guy.
You gotta not getting control and
nobody.
Anybody.
That's the key.
Autonomy in.
What do they call it?
Sovereignty.
You gotta.
Keep that.
Find somebody who doesn't control you,
just accepts you.
Light should be.
Don't make your shower.
Now they have to make them shower.
Oh,
my boys should at least suggest it in a
nice way to let them know.
Fuck is going on with your smell,
son.
Yeah.
I come from weird line of women that
liked that man's mouth.
It was gross.
My mom,
she is to always go over and sniff under
my dad's armpits.
So girls don't wonder.
I'm like,
I am.
You know.
So when you were tires that she likes
monkey smell,
don't say that word.
Funky white guy.
It's all right.
Oh,
you call white people monkeys.
My Dad was real dark.
How dark he was.
Brown.
Yeah.
Well,
um,
maybe it'd be problematic.
She was real fair,
fair,
scanned a mom.
So I've learned a thing or two jail hear
that to me.
All people look like some kind of.
I mean I didn't say anything about
Valerie Jarrett,
but don the subject,
I think people resemble animals a lot.
So we are animals.
We are animals.
Like I think I look like a beaver when I
look at my pictures,
do anything I looked like a beaver or a
cat detect.
I can see myself as a believer.
My kids think I'm real catlike yes.
Yeah.
My boyfriend says slaw off.
I'd just lay there in bed watching the
ID channel and murderers and serial
killer shows.
Oh my God.
Because I love how this character is put
together,
you know,
writing characters,
you just like,
I liked the forensics thing when they
put shit together,
you know,
and they go,
they are our purpose.
Our purpose of 40 year old white man
lives with his mother needs prevalent.
It was in the navy,
you know,
all that.
So I love all that I would have done
that if I wasn't a comic genius.
I think the real real problem with that
though is that the more you study that
shit,
the more you live in that world,
the less happiness you're going to find.
I've talked to guys that what world?
The world of serial killers,
the world studying it,
reading about it,
the actual people that investigate those
people.
Oh yeah.
They have a real hard time with life.
They have a real hard time because they
know too much.
They know too much about the day.
You watch it show mine hunter.
I didn't watch that one though.
John Douglas.
Yeah.
I've seen so many of those shows.
I've read books on serial killers.
I,
you know,
and I've,
I've known cops that investigated stuff
like this.
Well after I had that thing with marge,
I got really into it like Oh my God.
But you realize that some people out
there that are there,
but dark mind,
they're capable.
Some fucked up shit.
Yeah they are.
And if you were around that all the
time,
I just think you're appreciation for.
It's like it's one thing to know that it
exists and it's real,
but it's another thing to let that enter
into your,
your view of the world and have it in
there as a standard standard trying to
behavior.
I guess it's wrong to do that,
but you know,
nothing else interests me.
Why is it interesting to you so much?
Just because it's such a bizarre how
they get away with it and they're like,
oh,
he was the nicest guy.
How they their front,
you know the golden state killer,
right?
You know that one,
that they just this together.
That was what it was called Golden state
killer.
That fucking guy got away with it
forever.
Patton Oswalt's wife who died of a drug
overdose was actually investigating
that.
She died of a drug.
I thought she died from fentanyl.
Oh,
everyone's dying from that.
Started from that shit.
Everybody's standing from that.
I mean,
where can I get some?
It must be good if that's the conners to
get you.
I don't know what you're gonna do A.
I don't want to say nothing negative.
Bring you back.
You'll be like a.
You could be like a from beyond the
grave.
You could give advice to people on the
show.
That'd be a great way.
They can kill you off and bring you back
to the same time.
Ghost a ghost.
He come to John Goodman the middle of
the night.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Yeah.
You come up with something better than
just
killing you off.
Yeah.
Then just letting it go.
Well,
I think,
I mean they do all these movies about
robots and other words.
I don't want to be connected with a
racist,
a racist,
and that's what's so fucking stupid
about this.
They had a number one show,
a great sitcoms.
It returns.
It's even,
it's just as good if not better than it
was when it first came out.
It was a bit better too.
It was great.
Thank you.
Well,
you know,
that was all I was meant to do so you
know,
I did it.
I did it number one after 20 years.
What about doing standup again?
I'm doing standup.
I'm tillery next year and by then and my
gag order will be over.
You have a gag order.
Can you talk about the gag order or is
that a part of the gag order?
It's a part.
Be careful.
Go are there that I can talk about it.
Let's just talk about.
Yeah,
I just want to say I wish everybody the
best.
You know,
I.
I wish.
Well for everyone on earth.
That's all I'm going to say.
When are you going to do standup next
year?
Twenty,
19?
Where are you going to do it?
I can't remember what they said in the
Midwest.
All across the Midwest.
Are you writing already?
Are you performing at all?
I mean,
are you.
You're just writing?
Yeah.
And how are you going to do it?
Are you going to start out at clubs?
Are you going to theaters,
casinos?
Do you have a framework of what you're
going to talk about?
Talk about raising good sons and all
that that entails.
Are you going to bring someone with you
on the road to warm up or.
I probably should.
I don't know.
I have.
It's kind of saying I wanted to call
headline too.
I thought to co headlined with Monique
would be a blast.
That's a great idea.
Me and her talked about it.
That'd be fun.
Yeah.
I mean anybody just just to get out
there again,
tell me a joke.
I really liked hearing people laugh.
That'd be a great thing for you to do it
better.
Do it.
How long has it been Susan?
Stand up.
Oh,
I did it just before,
you know.
In fact,
I think that's why I got so rundown.
You know,
I got so rundown when I,
you know,
this whole thing.
I was so run down at that point that I
had no b vitamins in my body.
How's it impossible?
Well,
I made was that really low level?
And the doctor said,
you know,
that can cause psychosis.
So that's where I go.
Okay.
That's what happened to me.
Really.
I was at white.
I was getting way out there in Salt Lake
City,
Utah.
Anyway,
after I,
I did do standup all through Canada and
then I ended up in New York doing promo
for Rosanne and uh,
you know,
I just got to run down.
I didn't,
I didn't watch myself and do what I
should have done for my physical health
this time around.
Let's get you sorted it out and sketch
on some vitamins and get your
nutritionist and get somebody who's
going to do some blood work you and make
sure everything's okay.
Blood work done.
I always go,
I go to the cancer center at a whatever
that hospitals called over there.
Yeah,
that's good.
But I always have to have infusions
every three months because I,
I don't absorb minerals or vitamins.
What do you mean you don't absorb them?
Yeah.
I had this gastric bypass about 25 or so
years ago and I can't absorb minerals or
vitamins and so I have to go get
infusions every,
you know,
when I get to down and I,
like I said,
I was promoting the residential and also
doing some touring Canada and I got to
run down and I,
I just,
uh,
I,
I think I had a mental collapse.
I told the network,
I said,
obviously I'm not behaving in the right
way and I will check myself in and get
my meds checked to make sure I'm,
you know,
so I said I have mental health issues
and you know,
I,
I said also I thought that woman was
white and it wasn't anything about race.
It was about Iran.
And it was like,
well,
we'll see how this washes out in
Sherman.
Yeah,
we'll see how this washes.
And then 20 minutes later Wanda Sykes
tweeted,
let me off this show.
And then Sarah Gilbert tweeted,
shortly thereafter a,
something about she was ashamed of one
cast member and a would.
That one blew me away.
And uh,
and Michael Fishman tweeted a,
he was ashamed of my racism or some
shit.
And uh,
that was hard to take.
But,
uh,
it was because it was so,
it seemed orchestrated because they use
the same words,
you know,
a egregious unforgivable.
But in fact it might have been
offensive.
And like when I was talking to Mike
Today,
I said,
you know,
we all say things that are racially
insensitive at times.
All of us do that.
I'm a Jew,
I've heard everything and uh,
you know,
or,
or ethnically offensive to somebody,
but that doesn't mean where the KKK.
Okay.
That doesn't mean we're,
uh,
you know,
fascists or you know,
and especially if we apologize because
most people who are offensive,
they mean to be offensive and they don't
apologize.
And I think that's when,
you know there's a difference and if you
don't have the discretion to understand
that something's wrong with you and I
think something's wrong with people that
they're so hateful and uh,
so unforgiving and if you don't vote the
way they think you should vote,
that they feel justified in being.
So,
um,
what's the word?
Self sanctimonious and self righteous.
And when they themselves are,
you know,
kind of saying far more offensive things
about people's children and such.
For instance,
I think people are just cowards.
And I think when things like this
happen,
they want to separate themselves from
controversy and make sure that they're
not a part of the people that I can
understand that I can kind of understand
that,
but I don't get it.
I don't they do,
you know,
and you know,
I'm like,
wow.
They also get really,
really upset when a few years later
somebody does the exact same thing to
them and go,
what goes around comes around and that's
true and especially true in Hollywood.
That guide that fired me just was fired
a couple of weeks ago for what?
I don't know that his contract wasn't
renewed and his last words were,
well,
I didn't know I'd be forced to cancel
our number one show.
It wasn't forced to do anything.
Well,
he might've been forced.
They're all fools.
This should just.
First of all,
they should have let the dust settle.
Second of all,
they should have examined what you
actually said and what your intentions
were and let you apologize and then have
a conversation with you on one of their
shows in long form.
You May,
in a teaching moment such as Valerie
jarret would have accepted that.
I said,
I would like to debate her on the Iran
deal and explain what I what I said,
well,
you know,
that's not necessarily what Americans
should know about that deal.
Well,
maybe they should,
but I don't think that's completely
related to the tweet,
but it would have been a teachable
moment maybe,
but it also would've been a distraction
from what you were trying to say.
Well,
they didn't let me say it right.
And uh,
you know,
um,
but to get involved like openly,
politically,
the television show,
that's dangerous.
But Taylor swift just did it.
What did she say?
Just get out and vote Democrat.
Wasn't that like,
it's almost abstract.
Get out and vote,
you know,
she's not,
she said vote for the Democrat.
I don't like the Republican.
Marsha Blackburn,
she didn't like her.
Although Marsha Blackburn has been the
author of a lot of great anti rape laws
and all kinds of stuff like that,
but she didn't like her because she's a
Republican,
says she took a stand,
a political stand,
I guess.
Uh,
you know,
some people can do it,
but some people can't.
And the political stand I took,
which I just want to remind people is
that I'm,
I'm,
I'm an independent.
That's my stance.
And I just thought both sides had gone
too far out and need to talk to each
other.
So I came back and did a show about
that.
That's the stance you took with your
show and in my life it's like if we can
even discuss things that's really,
really bad,
that's not American.
We we discuss and debate.
We don't label and black list,
which we certainly can talk things and
maybe that's something that you could
have done once they had a conversation
with you about your tweet.
But I mean I just think that what they
did was just very hasty and very
foolhardy.
And they should have known who were
beforehand.
They should have known about your mental
health issues.
They should know.
They should have known about your
medication issues,
all of those things.
But this is what my point was.
If you have a person with a broken leg
and they can't run and you get mad at
them because they can't run the.
Isn't that ridiculous?
Well,
if you have a person that has brain
issues and then they do something that's
erratic and you're mad at them for that,
well you're a fucking idiot that's
stupid and you call them a racist or
chastise them in front of the world so
that you remove any possible any,
any possible negative opinions that
could be cast your way,
but that's what a lot of it is,
is deflection.
They're worried about negative opinions
and negative feedback that's going to
come their way so they immediately turn
on you.
They turn on you in a disproportionate
way.
While they did cancel the show before
evening,
one advertiser had pulled out.
It's the Sarah Silvermans bet.
I'm against a amber that I'm against it.
Well,
there's a lot of cowardice going on.
There's a lot of people trying to save
their jobs and people panic because
people are aware of the outrage culture
that we live in.
This is an outrage nation right now.
It's.
It's one of our number one forms of
recreation.
People love it.
They love getting mad at whoever the
fuck it is.
As long as you react the way they want
you to react.
Oh,
they love it.
It's an inquisition.
Well,
it's the understanding that people have
way more power to affect change.
Whether it's good change or bad change.
They're pushing buttons with social
media and without rage and with their
ability to express themselves.
It's unprecedented.
There's never been a time like this in
history where people can Salem witch
trials,
right?
Well that was just like,
okay,
well if you swam that proves you're a
witch,
and then we have to drown.
You know,
uh,
it has said there has to be a loser,
there has to be two winters.
Well,
there,
there has to be an understanding of
what's happening here.
And then people have to have an
understanding of the power that they're
wielding and what they're doing and that
it turned back on them.
And it never just stop at one person.
That's why I said I'm surprised that a
lot more comics didn't defend me because
you know,
this means that anything they find it in
your timeline that they think is
offensive,
they can mischaracterize and bringing a
whole a battle against you that you
can't possibly win and take your life's
work.
Well,
how many did defend you?
I'm nobody defended me,
but I did.
You did.
Thank you.
Stan.
Hope.
Did Stan hope dead?
Yeah.
Um,
there was a time that we're working with
no,
none of them that worked with you.
Well,
everybody that works,
you wanted to keep their job.
Yeah.
And I don't blame them.
Don't blame them.
They needed the money and probably
already spent it.
Well,
the other thing too,
the life that,
that fucking schedule is ruthless.
It's growing.
You know what I think it was,
a lot of it was,
um,
you know,
I gave him the gun to shoot me.
I mean,
I wasn't a helpless victim,
although I think my explanation either
make sense or doesn't make sense.
But uh,
well if you're compassionate it makes
sense.
But a lot of people aren't.
But,
um,
you know,
uh,
I forgot what I was getting.
I don't even know if they're not
compassionate.
Roseanne.
I think they're scared.
I think that just chicken shit.
I don't think they're looking at it from
it in terms of like,
I can't win here and I can't lose here.
Let me just look at what's right.
See,
I didn't have anything to win or lose.
So what I looked at it,
I looked at you as someone that I
admire.
Some of that I think is one of the best
comics ever who I think I know that you
have mental health issues.
I knew from talking to you that you were
on Ambien and I knew you had alcohol as
well.
I know what that does.
My mom took ambien.
She woke up in the middle of the night
and drew all over the bathroom rug,
drool over it with lipstick and,
and,
and um,
and nail Polish.
She said like a little kid.
So Shit.
You woke up in the morning.
She had no idea she did it.
She's terrified of that shit.
She won't take it now.
I have friends,
many friends that have had bad
experiences on ambulance tail and I
thought,
well,
they shouldn't have shut down that
conversation like that.
They shouldn't have.
It's a fucking dangerous drug to for the
wrong people in the wrong situations.
Especially when you mix it with alcohol.
I mean it's beneficial to people that
need sleep in certain situations.
I don't recommend it,
I don't take it,
but some people like it.
That's fine.
But to ignore what the actual
pharmacological effect on the human body
is is ridiculous because there's studies
on this shit and that people understand
the interaction between chemicals and
the human brain and there are erratic
and especially when you mix them with
things,
you're not supposed to mix them with.
Weird Shit happens.
I thought it was gonna.
I thought I was going to expand on it in
the morning and you know,
talk about that movie and a too late.
Yeah,
well it could.
It was too late to put.
The whole thing is just fucking crazy
when,
when telling me not to tweet.
Yeah.
Well,
it's probably a good idea,
but now honestly the problem also a
twitter's fucking text is just too.
It's too simple.
It's too crude a way of communicating.
It really is,
but you can get across some ideas like
you can say,
hey,
I went to see little foot's a great
movie.
That's a good thing to tweet.
Real simple shit like that,
but you want to talk about like
political things or things that involve
nuance or seeing things that are
complex.
I just don't think it's the way to
communicate.
I know it's terrible way to communicate,
not communicate.
It's like a,
what did he say?
A search and destroy oil.
For some folks,
there's going to be people that always
want to make things crash and burn.
They like it.
They like buttons.
They like hitting the buttons.
They like to see people suffer.
Well.
They definitely are suffering
themselves.
Look,
there's a giant percentage of our
population that lives in misery that
they do all day long and they.
They have mental health issues.
They're exhausted,
they're depressed,
they're there.
They have despair,
they're overwhelmed with bills.
They're in shitty relationships and
they're overwhelmed and they're angry
and they look at someone like you are
rich white lady,
and I'm like,
fuck that bitch,
and they just want to attack you.
It doesn't have to make sense because
it's a reflection of their own personal
pain as much as it's a reflection of
their irresponsibility with this power
that they're wielding through social
media.
And then there's the mob mentality.
There's a bunch of people that are
already going after you.
Good.
I want to go after a two.
I'm going to show the world that I'm not
racist and you know how I'm going to do
that.
I'm going to shit all over this racist,
this racist Roseanne.
They don't care if you're really racist.
But the thing that gets me about it is
it's,
I'm going to shit all over this Jew
because I was talking about Iran as a
Jew and speaking about Persian Jews and
uh,
you know,
all kinds of error when you're talking
about complexity.
It is complex,
but I always was on there talking,
uh,
you know,
defending or,
speaking for Jewish people.
And so,
you know,
I just,
I think that in the long run I've really
wanted to be known that I,
I am a Jew and we're speaking as a Jew
and when I spoke about the Iran deal and
its effect on a Jewish people in the
Middle East,
and I really thought first they didn't
know that,
but now I think,
well they had to know some of it.
I don't think they want to know.
This is what I think you say when
someone says that's a black woman.
What is she one eighth black,
like what is she?
Um,
something very small,
46 percent or something.
Really?
Yeah.
She had her DNA done was talking about
it and 40 something Caucasian and it
doesn't look like,
but whatever,
whatever.
We can't tell who people are by how they
look on one point six percent African.
Cool.
Awesome.
That's the heart of the world.
When you look at what happened,
I think it's real simple.
I think
she identifies or people identify her as
a black woman.
You said planet of the Apes Racist.
Boom.
It's that simple.
I don't think they give a fuck if you're
a Jew.
I don't think they care if you're not
racist.
I think this is a
viable target.
And they go,
well,
I said I voted for trump.
So that was a target to that too.
And then,
and then they could find a,
a,
a tweet from the past.
I forget either.
Oh yeah.
Maya got in trouble for that alone many
times.
There's just things you can't say.
And then there's worse things that you
can.
So it's weird because they don't censor
anybody who's calling for,
uh,
you know,
to kill all the Jews.
There's thousands of them just shared
about the not famous women with sitcoms.
Yeah,
they are who,
uh,
you know,
people that are,
are tweeting support for Valerie
Jarrett,
you know,
they're pissed at me and saying,
how could you say this about not saying
that because they're saying kill the
Jews.
They don't,
they don't.
Maybe know what your point was like.
I didn't know about her parentage.
I mean,
come on.
This is,
this is the truth.
This is who I am.
And you know,
they,
uh,
they did this too,
but they're not really saying kill the
Jews.
It's not like a valid comparison.
Well I'm a Jew,
I understand that.
But the people,
that's how it feels.
Maybe it feels that way to you guys.
But the people that are robust,
they're upset at you because they think
you said something racist.
They're not saying kill the Jews.
Well,
but they are to us.
Okay.
You see how when people look at your
situation,
I can see how they think.
But you see how when people look at your
situation and they think it's racist,
that is also how you look at.
They're reacting to what they think is
racist and you thinking that they're
saying kill all the Jews.
They're saying like,
uh,
you know,
Iran everyday threatens the Jewish
people in Israel with annihilation and
they've already survived,
you know,
not too long ago,
an annihilation.
So,
and then we make a deal with that
government.
What does that say something?
I understand that,
but this is many steps past.
But to me that you said a racist thing
or thinking you said a racist.
And understand that they think I said a
racist thing.
I understand that completely.
They have no idea that this had anything
to do with Jews versus Iran.
They really don't have any idea.
I've never seen that.
I've never seen that registered.
But because it's not important enough to
them to know that well,
it's probably not been explained to
them.
For one,
I know your position like this,
like you're,
you're talking about now I understand
that they might not even think it's
valid.
Like if they went back and went over it
and you might disagree with the
political aspects of it.
Yes.
And they're free to do that.
I'm not going to try to be know what I'm
saying.
Like they're not the reason why I said
it's not a valid comparison.
They're not really saying kill the Jews,
but to me and to other Jews,
they are in fact saying that.
And,
and that's very common amongst us.
So you know,
that's,
that's the truth that many of us think
and you know,
people are understand it or they don't
care to even consider it.
Well,
they don't have to,
but I'm still going to say it because
that's the reality.
It's the reality to hear that and to
hear the United States wanting gave them
billions of our tax dollars when they're
the number one supporter of terror in
the world.
It is and they always do Kale,
Jews like in Paris and wherever else
they go and they do it in London too.
I mean,
you know,
I hate to wake people up,
but you know,
it is important.
At least it is to me and to people like
me and to many other people.
Many Christians is very important to
them,
to their.
They're under onslaught too.
I'm not exactly sure what you're talking
about because you're talking about
Iranians killing people in Paris and
England.
I'm talking about being the number one
sponsor of terror in the world.
Iran,
but they're killing people in France and
England that are Jews.
Who,
when?
When is this happening?
Well,
when they that theater and a lot of
other times,
but there's a lot of Jewish woman to
death and her and her Paris apartment.
There's a lot of it.
I'm not saying they only killed Jews,
but they do kale juice and the money
goes back to those terrorist
organizations that are funded by Qatar
and Iran.
Okay.
This is a.
This is a pretty.
These,
these are general things you're saying,
right?
Yeah.
It's very general and there's 100
shades.
There's 100 shades,
but I'm just saying as a Jew with a
family in Israel,
this is what we think and this is how we
feel and to not even acknowledge that
and any discussion is kind of
disturbing.
It should be factored in.
I don't think it's a matter of not
acknowledging it.
I think it should be factored in as
well.
They're aware that this had anything to
do with your motivation.
Well,
express.
I've never read it anywhere,
but you can't say it last time I'm
saying it.
He can't say it.
It's not really smiled on to go against
the people who control our media and
say,
especially social media and say that
you're pro Israel or you know,
that you think,
um,
you don't think that the media will
allow you to be pro Israel.
I mean,
that seems like a really common thing,
not on social media for the most part.
No,
it's very anti Israel.
You'll,
I'll send you statistics.
Well,
I see some anti Israel sentiment and
especially in relation to a,
they treat the Palestinians
like I see a lot of that.
Well,
I'm not going to play into either of
those because I,
I really believe that,
uh,
you know,
there's a solution to that problem.
The solution is pace and I think it can
be achieved.
So I'm not going to play either one of
those games about who does this or what.
I'd just like to see a solution that
works for all the people.
They're all people.
They're so,
um,
but it can be but it can't be if one
side has been completely censored and
it,
that isn't a discussion or is it a
debate and nor is it an American scary.
It's scary times when,
you know,
like on our college campuses today,
I know this because my son was on one
and you know,
it's a far left far left.
Professors that espouse that kind of
stuff daily in all of our colleges.
And it does find its way to the media.
You look at the media that most,
what are they called,
millennium millennials consume and it's
heavily,
uh,
to the left it is.
And so that's where they're informing.
They're,
they,
they are getting their opinions from
only hearing one side of things on
social media.
And I don't think that's good.
I don't think it's good that all
conservative voices are being censored
off twitter.
You know,
and not all,
I shouldn't say all,
but so many are because that's a way to
shut down discussion to.
There's quite a few conservative voices
on twitter,
but some are when they think they're
inflammatory or they think they're
espousing hate.
Yeah.
But they get to decide that you're this
deciding that it's people who are
heavily political.
Yes.
That's not right.
It shouldn't be.
It should be more in the middle where
we're both sides are considered to come
to a consensus means is a diverse
opinion and that's how you reach
consensus.
You don't get a consensus.
So nor solution from only listening to
one side blather on the same ship for 20
years.
That keeps people fighting at each
other,
not always fighting.
I think it recruits people for the other
side.
I think it does the opposite of its
intended effect.
That's one of my friends said.
He said he thinks Michael Moore.
That's Michael Moore's role since he's a
billionaire too,
that he's a billionaire.
Well,
they said this is what they said.
I don't know,
but it's in that vein.
It's like,
well,
he did get so many people to vote for
trump when he said that stuff about
people are angry and they don't think he
did it on purpose.
I think a lot of people credit him for
voting for trump for that speech.
Well,
I'm sure my friend said maybe he's a
double agent,
which I don't think he.
I think this is one of the things that
happens when it's like when,
when when you give people that much
suppression and you,
you try to indoctrinate people into
thinking a certain way,
there's going to be people that
resistant a large help sell and seems
larger and larger,
but freedom of thought is the basis of
this country.
It's not freedom of speech or freedom of
religion and freedom of expression,
the second amendment,
those are symptoms of freedom of thought
and it did good to consume endless
propaganda and never have it broken down
or a or debated or pointed out that it's
fault.
There is an issue when you're only
getting one side of the argument and the
people that are controlling the media
only want that one side expressed.
That is a problem.
Yeah,
and the thing too that right now in
terms of wing version of it,
well because they won't let it happen,
but who's they?
You know,
people that are in charge
of programming the networks,
they don't want that.
It,
it seemed to always lean left.
I mean technologically oriented
companies and corporations always almost
invariably lean left.
Why do you think that is?
They're smart,
they're educated,
they're fresh out of college.
The colleges are indoctrinating leftwing
kids and you know,
you have a vast majority of professors
at universities all across the country
that identify as Democrats.
Right?
So this is the indoctrination they get
from people that they respect deeply and
that they're learning from.
And there's also an understanding that
this is the way you advance,
you know,
and then when someone comes out that has
anything diminish,
you didn't think that it has a brain
center that'll coordinate.
It's not coordinated in terms of the
government.
I think what's happening in the
universities is you've get people that
are,
first of all,
they're existing in this bizarre glass
walled garden where they,
they go to universities to get
indoctrinated into this left wing
cultures and then they start teaching at
university.
So they never get out into the real
world.
And then they teach children these
thoughts and ideas and then most of the
kids leave and they take these ideas
somewhere else.
And then slowly over time they become
more moderate.
Most of them do or they,
they reject those ideas and either go to
the center or go right or some of them
stay left.
But when they go into tech companies,
a lot of them go center,
which is I think probably where sanity
is.
I think Saturday is somewhere in the
center and I think discussion is
critical.
I have a lot of friends that are
Republican.
liberal,
there's nothing wrong with either either
mindset and the only way we find out
whether or not we really agree or
disagree is we let people express
themselves and as soon as you suppress
that kind of expression,
then you run into real problems.
That's absolutely right.
And that's what I wanted on my show that
I would show that there was a,
uh,
a trump lover and a trump hater in the
same house and they managed to deal with
it and get on with it.
That's a great,
that's a great premise for a show.
And it was one of the reasons why I
think people loved it so much is because
there was that conflict.
And because look,
people can love a lovable curmudgeon.
People can love someone who has ideas
that they disagree with.
People can love someone who lives with
someone who has a completely opposing
opinion.
They figure it out and they get along.
That's fine.
That's great.
And my boyfriend,
my boyfriend said,
you have a mistake,
is that you put a cramp in the hate
business.
I don't think that's the case.
I think that just you,
just you,
you became a target.
You fucked up.
They were happy from the beginning.
I don't think they really wanted me to
come back.
I think there's a certain amount of that
when they found out that you're a trump
supporter and then the show became
successful and Donald Trump loved it and
then trump supporters.
Lafayette was a trouble maker and a big
mouth.
They've always thought that,
well,
you're a comic.
I know and everybody remembers when you
sang the national anthem and grabbed
your crotch and spit on the ground.
I remember that.
I do that.
When you do that gastric bypass thing,
is that something they can reverse?
They could reverse it,
but what the hell?
Then I'll wait.
Hundred books.
You really don't.
You wouldn't,
would you just everything.
Oh fuck.
Yeah,
that's all I had it because I couldn't
stop talking about addiction.
Impulsive,
right?
Oh yeah.
All Day long.
Eclairs what have you.
It was great.
I hate those goddamn things.
Claire's no got gastric bypass
surgeries.
A lot of people.
Yeah,
they do,
but I just wish there was a better way
just because it fucks up your nutrient
absorption abilities like you were
talking about.
Yeah,
I mean I've heard that from several
people.
I know guys who have gotten in their
mental state.
Yeah,
I'm sure.
Oh,
for sure.
A lot of it has to do with the.
The,
the health of your,
you know,
your,
your body,
your ability to absorb nutrients affects
everything.
Your mood,
your energy levels,
everything.
You mean food doesn't get in there the
right way.
No,
I just lay in bed till they called for
me enough to stumble in and do my thing.
Go back to bed.
I just had no energy in Brazil.
Why don't you do something like this?
Like this,
this conversation with these.
You could do this on your time whenever
you want to do it without anybody
telling you what to say or what not to
say without any executives,
without anybody to fire you.
You Diy Youtube,
they kick you off everything they could,
but I don't think they would.
And on top of that,
you could do it off of your own website.
You could do it on Roseanne Barr Dot
com.
Yeah.
I'm always afraid they'll come.
I just feel like,
hey,
this the time of my life from 66 is
probably the time for me to just lay
low.
Does stand up sometimes and that's a
great idea.
That's even better.
Yeah.
Go do that then and show us some of my
farming videos,
listen to people like to know about how
to grow food and I'm really good at
growing food.
When you do stand up and you go on a
tour,
I think it's going to be hugely
successful.
I really do.
I think people are going to come out in
droves and I think it's going to be
awesome and I think once you get your
legs under you and you start doing a few
shows and get things cracking again,
you'd be like the Rosanna.
Do you be crushing it?
I was crushing it.
I have to say in my tour of Canada,
I was crushing.
It was a blast I had.
Oh my God,
I just had the most fun,
you know,
get like 90 minutes of beautiful control
over,
you know,
bing,
and I,
I've got like a big laugh every 90
seconds and beautiful,
you know,
I tailor it and craft it and love it.
Love the people that come out to see me.
Then five diverse crowd too,
which is great.
Well,
I bet it'd be even more diverse now
while it's going to be way better I
think,
because I'm going to really start
talking about the real me,
such as my abhorrence and fear of
serpents.
Serpents.
Oh yeah.
I always have been.
Don't go to Florida now.
I won't,
don't go to the swamps for sure.
You heard about what's going on there?
What with people releasing pythons all
know over decades.
You didn't know.
Florida is overrun with pythons.
Oh my God.
Non Native Pythons because people
released them as pets and then they
moved to the swamps and bread.
Yeah,
they've eaten everything.
There's almost no mammals in the swamps.
Oh my God.
Said 99 percent of all raccoons are
gone.
We couldn't find any marsh rabbits.
They couldn't find any bobcat's and the
pythons and started eating alligators.
Oh,
thousands of them out there.
Say the world's gone nuts.
Crazy.
Stay away from Florida.
I,
well,
I had A.
I had a turtle that kind of felt.
Are we done?
No,
I mean we can be done or we can keep
going.
Well,
I had this turtle that fell in love with
me wanting to meet with me and Hawaii.
You know,
it's so weird.
Now.
This is true.
I'm really afraid of serpents.
Okay.
So,
uh,
so I go in the ocean there and my
friends,
they're like,
don't touch the turtles.
There's a $5,000
fine or something.
You don't touch those big old things.
Sound like,
you know,
like I say,
I'm a Jew.
So as soon as I hear that,
I'm like,
yeah,
well fuck them.
I'm catching it.
So I did.
And then it turned,
it went and started swimming around me
and then it went in this big circle and
it's head came out of the water in it
side.
I me,
I was like,
oh Christ,
it's the serpent.
I've been afraid of my own life.
And he chased me onto the shore.
She goes,
that's why we don't touch the turtles,
because they bond with you.
Like this guy wants me to.
Merriam.
Yeah.
If you touch them,
they like you.
They're like,
hey,
she'll go for it as a terrifying.
I've seen them in the water.
They're fucking cool to look at.
Their swimming are awesome.
They're like a little Volkswagen with
these four paddles,
serpent head coming out and like this
where they look.
So my,
that's how I left it locked eyes with.
Yeah,
he did like this side by side.
They go side.
I'll.
No,
no,
it was terrible to think of.
Terrifying.
Yeah.
I've never gotten back in that water.
Well yeah I could see where that would
be a problem and I have a lot of serpent
things.
And also like when I see people I can
see if they're a serpent or not.
You know how they say the Reptilian.
Like I told my kids this the hardest
thing ever.
Type Shit.
Well I really do see them now.
I sort
of believe him.
He's gone down a rabbit hole.
That guy.
It's more like a,
like a gopher hole somewhere real deep
into the core of the earth.
But he talks about that stuff anymore.
Now he kinda laid it back.
But that's because I confronted him.
Dude,
you just lost it.
Yeah,
well that's what I was doing on twitter
too as a DM and people going,
you've lost it.
Yeah.
It's fun.
Like I did it.
And so I used to do these,
a faithful or crank phone calls before
they got that star 69 and I was married
to what's his face then the Elf.
And uh,
he came in the room there and he told me
he stopped doing it and he looked at my
address book and I was,
I was calling a general Schwarzkopf to
do it to him and he's like,
you don't crank called general work
because I had all these numbers.
Anyway.
So,
uh,
what was I saying?
Yeah,
I used to do that,
but then I went to the DM,
you know,
on,
that's the way people like,
just get them riled up that way.
Just go,
come on,
you're losing it.
You will have David [inaudible] said
that like all the big major world
figures,
really secretly Reptilian reptilian
shape shifters and shit,
and I told my kids,
here's what I told my kids,
just the hardest thing I'll ever tell
you,
but,
and I didn't know so I couldn't help but
at the time,
but I recently found out that your dad
is reptilian joke,
but sort of a joke,
but they are half a million,
but I can see like people becoming the
reptile,
like I'll see them and their head goes
up like this,
like on tv,
their head,
their neck goes out like this and then
the tongue comes out on the corner to
let go up like that.
They do it.
I see it on tv all the time.
I see that all them devil worshipers.
Who Do you go to?
Those devil worship parties here they're
talking about and Hollywood is devil
worship to a wedding.
Was it a devil worship?
What is his name?
Anton Levay.
Sorry.
Was a devil worship for Napa.
Like motherfucker,
like people call me a Satan worshiper
now because of it.
Oh my God.
And
Dunkin.
This was like 15 years ago,
my friend Duncan used to have this
puppet called Little Hobo and he would
do this,
uh,
this hilarious bit at the end of his
comedy show where Little Hobo was his
grandfather's puppet and his,
his grandfather died.
And,
uh,
his grandfather's last wish with that.
He bring little Hobo on stage with them.
One more time in the pub would come to
life.
There's,
there's Daca with little Hobo.
Little Hobo was this fucked up look at
pub.
It was a hilarious bit.
It's funny.
Anton [inaudible] grandson.
Is that who it was?
Their son was getting married as Duncan
to perform
at his party.
So me and a bunch of my friends all went
to see Dunkin perform at this bizarre
Satanists party.
It was very strange.
It was in Hollywood.
It was like there's a concert and hang
the third,
Hank Williams a third performed there.
And it was kind of fun,
but it was bizarre.
And uh,
so there's like a picture with me and
the guy and people saying with Satan
worshiper now you're not.
Definitely not.
Oh my God.
You look like a St Louis should have got
a.
someone's hands you the gun on the left
with the hair.
Oh my God.
That's me.
You got to get some better glasses.
Bama.
I can't tell them exactly like me,
but anyway.
No,
I promise you no,
no.
Satan worshiping.
No,
no worshiping period.
There's some real.
I'm sure crazy people out here that
definitely really are.
Yeah.
I'm glad you didn't stay in with them.
I went to one stupid fucking party
because my friend Duncan fucking Duncan
getting in trouble.
You son of a bitch.
Um,
what else?
What were we just talking about when we
were talking about Satan worshipers?
You were saying something.
Oh,
lizard people.
So who's the lizard people whose.
Well you just say nobody's name.
Okay.
But I'll tell you,
I can't say,
but uh,
if you really take a hard long look when
they're talking to me some names for
that net going up and they had twisting
and then the term coming out corner.
Okay.
I'll keep an eye on.
So you're saying I'll keep an eye out
for it.
We'll listen.
Roseanne.
Thank you.
This was a lot of fun.
It was fun.
I think people got a chance to see the
real you.
Well,
I just want to say to everybody out
there before you kicked me out of here.
Hey,
I love everybody.
I believe in one law for all people and
uh,
you know,
I'm not any fucking backwoods idiot.
Thank you.
You're not a racist by any stretch of
the imagination of all people and I'm
happy you're doing standup again because
like I said,
I think you're one of the best ever.
So sweet.
Damn,
that makes me happy.
Thank you.
I really do.
I'm glad you're doing it.
Thank you.
Roseanne Barr.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thanks Joe.