Okay.
Everybody,
this episode of the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by legal
zoom.
Legal Zoom is a way that you can do things
affordably and easily online that you
would normally have to go
visit a legal office to do a,
you can do things like starting an LLC
online in the comfort of your own home
for just hundred bucks,
$99 actually you can incorporate
for $99 you heard me,
you can protect your family with a last
will for just $69 get a living trust,
power of attorney and
more legal zoom guests.
The job,
right?
Nine out of 10 customers would recommend
the service to their friends and
family,
which as we've covered before,
it means a lot because we all know
that one out of 10 people is absolutely
useless.
So if that one out of 10 people is
having a hard time with legal zoom,
it's most likely a very good service.
Another indication,
it's a very good service is the fact
that it got an a plus from the better
business bureau.
A plus,
not an a minus,
not a B plus fucking eight plus pitches.
They can help you out with trademarks,
copyrights,
patents.
If you've got a great idea
and you want to protect it,
legal zoom is there for you.
In the past 12 years,
over 2 million Americans have used
legal zoom and they have saved a ton of
money.
They're online process could not be
easier and they'll take care of you from
start to finish.
They will also connect you with a
third party attorney if you panic.
If you're freaking out and you're like,
oh my God,
I'm going to jail.
No legal zoom.
Oh,
make sure they can connect you with an
independent third party attorney and they
can provide you with the
self help services that you
need and right now you get
a special discount from
listening to this podcast.
Make sure you enter Rogan and the
referral box at checkout for more savings.
That's legal zoom.com and enter in the
code word Rogan to save yourself some
sheckles.
We are also brought to
you by on at.com that's o.
N.
I.
T.
One of the new things that we've added
to on it that's really pretty cool and
fascinating is we have
a gang of motivational,
a gang of instructional videos of,
of blogs,
entries,
things that you can show,
um,
you know,
it seems that you can look at rather
to get you fired up for training,
things that could put you in the right
mindset and things that will show you the
correct form,
the correct a way to do certain exercises
and just demonstrate what on and is
all about.
It's the Onnit academy and a,
it's one of the links@onat.com on
it is a human optimization website.
Uh,
Aubrey started this website arbors here,
by the way.
Well,
it's talking about him like you didn't
even hear you started this website.
Um,
with this idea and this mindset of
creating something that we would wish was
there for us.
Um,
selling things that we would use,
selling things that we do use in stuff
that we used long before we ever became
involved in the company.
Uh,
things like strength and
conditioning equipment,
like the best kettlebells we can find,
the best battle ropes,
we can find the best
steel maces steel clubs,
weight vests,
ab wheels,
all great equipment for
functional strength.
And then on top of that,
the best supplements we can find,
the best new nootropics for Alpha brain,
the best protein powder and hemp protein,
hemp force protein powder,
which we still as of right now
still have to buy from Canada.
But we are hoping that a,
these laws are changing and it seems
to be they're changing pretty quickly.
It seems like the House of cards is
falling down on the whole cannabis.
Uh,
this,
this whole embargo that is been in place
in this country for almost a hundred
years.
It's pretty incredible
that it lasted that long.
And he's had about somewhere in the 85
year range from the time it was made
illegal.
But,
uh,
it's slowly starting to go away.
And when it does go away,
hopefully before it goes away,
even we'll be able to buy our
hemp from America right now.
We have to buy it from Canada.
It's the most ridiculous thing ever.
You can grow it in Canada and sell it in
Canada and you can buy it and bring it
back to America,
but you cannot grow it in America.
It's so fucking dumb.
It's like if you had a cousin that
was a criminal and because of it,
you weren't allowed to vote.
It's that dumb really is,
right.
I mean that's like a good analogy.
Um,
but the,
on an academy,
it's really fascinating.
There's so much cool shit there from a,
there's videos with me working out with
Aubrey and we're demonstrating different
exercises and techniques.
Um,
there's just a slew of cool shit at the
a on an academy and we're continuing to
add to it all the time on.
It is continuing to grow.
When we find cool shit we added,
whether it's the new warrior protein bar,
which is absolutely fantastic.
It's a new buffalo bar that is 14
grams of protein in each serving.
Um,
and it's all made in the same method as
the native Americans used to preserve a,
their buffalo four grams
of fat per serving,
only 140 calories.
And it's super delicious as well.
No antibiotics,
no added hormones,
all natural and made from prairie fed
buffalo cranberries and a spicy pepper
blend.
That stuff is awesome.
It's really good.
It's so good because you're
eating it and it's like,
you know,
you don't have any guilt,
completely guilt free
as you're reading it,
you're like,
this tastes good and it's not a candy bar.
Yeah.
Lakota,
Lakota recipe,
Lakota tribe.
It's still making it up there in
the Dakotas and it's just carrying
on an old tradition with new fancier
packaging.
Then allows it to stay fresh for longer.
That's about it.
So go to Onondaga,
come and check out all
the cool shit we have.
Like I said,
we have the,
whenever we find if it's good,
we even sell blenders.
Why do we sell blenders?
Because we use them.
You know when,
if you're making protein drinks,
if you're making Kale shakes,
if you're making things along those lines,
you need a blender.
And while we said,
oh,
what's [inaudible] on,
what's the best blender and
the best blender turns out
to be a BLENDTEC blender.
It's pretty fucking bad ass.
It really is.
The best blender.
All right,
let's start selling it.
I mean,
that's the attitude that oneand has.
Yeah.
And that's the attitude we're
going to continue to have.
Uh,
we also carry a organic coconut oil,
Stevia Himalayan salt.
We just a ton of shit,
too much to list and one commercial,
but go to on it.
Oh and nit,
um,
get your freak on and use the codeword
Rogan save 10% off any and all
supplements.
All right.
Aubrey Marcus is back from Peru.
He was riding the wizards tail
and he's got stories for us.
Here we go.
Hit it.
The Joe Rogan experience.
Joe Rogan podcast,
my night all day
at all.
My friends that have done drugs
and I'm almost all of them.
Have your,
a,
the most dedicated at these return
visits to exotic locations for a mind,
expanding horizon,
expanding experiences.
And uh,
you're back again.
I'm back.
Do you,
you plan these out?
How far in it?
Yeah,
this one sometimes it's a long time.
Sometimes something just comes up.
And this time was one of those times,
a mutual acquaintance who I met
through actually the Boga world.
He had gone down here and done
this watch human experience,
which is the original way that you
described San Pedro before it got
Catholicized from the missionaries who
came in and freaked out that the native
people were doing these ceremonies
with this San Pedro Cactus,
which is what we call,
but it originally comes from this 4,000
year old recipe from the shoving people,
which was like the peak of
pre Andean consciousness.
And so I heard about these ceremonies
going on and I hadn't had any experience
with that medicine and I was like,
fuck it,
I'm in,
you know,
I got to explore this,
see what this looks like,
see what this unique tool is good for.
So San Pedro is pot,
pot is masculine,
peyote is a different cactus.
Really?
Yeah.
So peyote is a different cactus.
Um,
similarly related in mechanism of action,
but it's a little bit sterner.
It's a little bit harsher.
They described the difference,
you know,
if one's going to whack you on the head.
Peyote,
he's more of a hammer and San
Pedro is more of a heavy feather.
Yeah,
exactly.
I have Wifi,
but uh,
but if it can be pretty intense
work too is I'll describe but um,
yeah,
it's slightly different.
Cactuses and uh,
obviously the Payoti came up through
the North American tradition more
frequently and then the San Pedro,
why Chuma was carried on through
the South American tradition.
Wow.
So,
um,
this place that you're going to in Peru,
is this,
uh,
like a center?
Is this an organized yup.
Regular place that people go to?
I didn't know that there was these,
there's these places online that are
like Yelp for Iowasca retreats and they
rate them with stars.
I mean,
it's so bizarre.
Someone sent me a tweet saying,
you know,
uh,
something about,
because of your spreading the word,
you know,
look at all these different
things that are out there.
So I click on the link,
I'm like,
all right,
what does this,
and it's like fucking 50 different IOWASCA
retreats that all have websites and
they're all yelped and reviewed five star,
four star.
It's fucking crazy.
Gotta be can you,
you need these kind of review systems,
especially if they're of an integrity
because this is pretty powerful medicine.
You're dealing with internal
processes that are very intense.
IOWASCA loan is a very powerful Maoi
which can interact with a lot of things
with your health,
but it's also dealing with you know,
very deep spiritual issues,
traumas that you may have,
things like that.
So getting a really good showman,
a real master is so key.
So having good review systems and,
and really even better is knowing
people that have been there,
talking to people from experience and
finding them that way because there's,
they're popping up just to make money and
just because you're a showman and just
cause you have Iowasca it doesn't
mean you have any integrity at all.
Yeah.
Caroline was telling us about a
shaman that was feeling her up.
Yup.
Then there's all kinds of crazy stories
like that and being schamens just charge
the money,
give you the brew,
which is a brew.
Maybe they didn't even make it themselves,
they just bought it in a market.
Maybe they put a bunch of [inaudible],
which is detouring in there.
And so you're getting more of like that
Batman one hallucination instead of the,
instead of like a really
powerful DMT experience.
There's a lot of things that are,
that are going on there
that are not great.
But if you get to a real ios Guerro and
a real center with really good medicine,
obviously as I've described
in previous journeys,
it can be incredibly powerful.
So this is your newest,
your latest,
you're just back from it.
Yeah.
You just return how long ago or a week?
A week ago.
Yeah.
How fucked up?
Where are you
as as fucked up in the most
beautiful way possible.
I mean,
this to me,
this was,
this was the one,
this is the one,
this was the one.
This was the single greatest thing
for me that I've done and I've done,
you know,
I've told all these stories,
the Iowasca,
the Boga riding the back of a drag and
seeing the flotillas of snakes popping
into the eighth dimension,
doing,
you know,
exploring this advent calendar
of past souls on a book.
All of these crazy stories.
Nothing was as dramatically,
positively impactful as
this experience down there.
And it was a combination,
not only of the medicine but
of the integrity of the place.
And of course being held by Gandalf,
the white wizard himself,
which was something I was surprised at.
You know,
I expected him,
I didn't have any expectations really.
And I was really just blown away.
By what,
what do you mean by Gandalf?
The white wizard himself?
Like you actually met Gandalf,
if there was a Gandalf,
like that myth I hung out with
for eight days and he's my,
he's my homeboy.
So,
so is this something that I'm not,
I'm not sure if you're joking around like,
like did you actually have hallucinations
that you were hanging out with
Gandalf?
No,
no,
just describing that kind of benevolent,
friendly,
slightly humorous archetype of someone
who has access to great power but can
just sit around and,
and,
uh,
you know,
smoke a pipe with you and tell
stories or when he's timed for work,
you know,
he can step up and do some
pretty amazing things.
It's all kind of probably get
through and into this story,
but I'm just really follows that archetype
to at t obviously no direct links to
the Gandel.
So explain like you take this
stuff and when you take it,
what is a like how long does
it take before it kicks in?
Sure.
And what is it similar to?
Yeah,
I'll tell the,
I'll tell the whole story in
succession here and we'll get to it.
And you know,
the first part of any of these medicine
journeys is you set your intent to do it
and then once that happens,
the process already begins.
You can talk to a lot of the
different teachers about this.
As soon as you set your intent
to do some of this work,
some stuff starts to
come up and there'll be,
you know,
some of your dark material that'll start
to come up as if it's almost getting
ready to surface.
And then there'll be a
serious amount of resistance.
Like what Steven Pressfield says,
when you go from something,
you know,
something lower to a higher place,
there's going to be intense resistance.
And for me it was the fact that I was
going down to the lower Amazon in rainy
season,
which means there's going to be fucking
mosquitoes everywhere and I hate
mosquitoes and I'm a bit paranoid
about things like malaria.
So it freaked me out and I almost
canceled like at the last minute.
But ultimately looking back,
you see that that was like,
that was my resistance.
Yeah,
exactly.
And that's going to come up for everybody.
Anybody listening who sets
their intent to do this,
you're going to find at the 11th
hour some serious resistance,
some fears,
some material that's going to
come up that's going to tell you,
no,
don't do this shit.
But that's normal.
You know,
and you can heat it or not.
life is a series of choices,
but expect resistance to come for that.
So that's what came to me and I got down
there and I'd been going through some,
some personal stuff my first time.
I'm single and alone in 13 years.
I just put up with my partner.
She's great but went that way.
I had some other lot
of stress and you know,
we've been pushing pretty hard.
So when I got there into,
into Peru,
I was seriously ready for something,
you know,
and I didn't know what,
I didn't really do that much
research on the watchu honestly.
Usually I like really read trip reports.
I go to place like Erowid and I look and
I read and I didn't really know shit.
I just knew I was going
down there and I was like,
whatever something good is
hopefully going to happen.
But I was still,
you know,
I arrived there.
So you,
you get into,
go into Lima.
I spent the night in Lima,
take the,
uh,
take the flight into a kidos and it Ketos
is one of the largest cities that has
no roads to it,
the only way to get to a
ketosis by plane or by boat.
So it's kind of an interesting place.
But like many of these 500,000 Whoa,
500,000 people and there's no
roads and it's like a jungle town.
You know,
there's a lot of what you
would call in Thailand.
You call him,
took Tux.
You know,
those little bikes that have a,
I don't know,
a big backseat motorized bikes
and just kind of a sprawling,
really dirty,
stinky place,
you know.
So you cruise through,
you cruise through that place and then
we met up with Don Howard who runs the
center down there,
the spirit quest center and he's got the,
the long white hair and
a big friendly smile.
So as soon as I saw him I was like okay.
American.
Yeah,
he's,
so he's Kentucky born uh,
the grandson of a root doctor,
uh,
Kentucky root doctor,
which is like an old natural medicine
doctor and a half native American as well.
So his journey just to,
just to talk briefly about it.
So I learned kind of on the boat ride
cause we hop in a boat to go to the center
because his centers on 200 acres in
the jungle that he's been preserving.
So his journey at 19,
he got called to start working with
Payoti and went and did the kind of
traditional native American
as with his ancestry,
that kind of path to do pod
ceremonies for about 20 years,
both with himself.
And with leading other people.
And then he got called to go down to
South America and start working with the
San Pedro Cactus,
the watch Houma,
and got kind of initiated
into the [inaudible],
which is a c h,
a,
v.
I n.
And understood,
you know,
kind of the old recipes,
the old ways that they
used to make the medicine.
And not only with the watch Houma,
but the Vielka,
which is the second medicine that we did.
And the [inaudible] is the most potent
DMT experience on the fucking planet.
Like nothing else.
I'd have done many of the other ways,
uh,
can come close to that.
It's a combination of nn DMT five Meo
DMT and before Deneen and you snuff it
through your notes,
but I'll go through that story.
That was kind of the grand fucking
finale of this whole thing.
And it,
it launches you so much farther than
even Iowasca or anything else that I've
done.
So he got called to start working with
those medicines along with Iowasca down
in the jungle and had been
doing that for 30 years.
So He'd had 50 years of experience
working with these plant medicines.
And as you can imagine,
that's a long time to,
you know,
to be on the path and just be following.
I'm trying to heal as many people as
possible and show him to show him the
medicine.
So awesome guy and someone that
usually with these Shamans,
they don't speak English,
so you kind of get a vibe from him and
then you do the medicine and it's all
kind of magic with him,
you know,
not only is he leading
the ceremony in that way,
you can just sit around
and bullshit with them,
you know,
talk to them about,
crazy females that he tried to
take him to the dark side and,
and all kinds of these stories
that you would find from a,
from a guy,
like if you're hanging out with Gandalf
and the fucking Shyer and eating supper
and smoking is,
you know,
crazy dragon pipe like it had that
kind of feel to it when you get there.
So I get in,
I get into the jungle and
it's a really beautiful place.
Like the ceremonial hut has,
has iowasca vines that are growing along
the hut and in circling the whole hut,
which is pretty amazing to see.
And then everything is all screened in.
It's like kind of like a nice rustic wood.
As I said,
it's on 200 acres so we go into this
screen in place but I'm still extra
paranoid.
So I set up my mosquito net and I'm
like completely doused in bug spray,
like just wet with bugs strikes
and I'm still super paranoid.
And so we get in there and you know,
ended up talking and go
through the initiation,
get to a pretty good degree of comfort
and we're going to do the medicine the
next day.
And that night I was just,
I couldn't sleep at all.
I was exhausted but I still couldn't
sleep cause I was just so concerned about
like a lot of stuff was coming up for me,
a lot of emotions and stuff.
And when worry about this,
these bugs in this malaria thing,
which was made worse by,
of course,
another kind of test that came up,
somebody who was there said,
oh,
did you hear about those two cases of
malaria that just showed up recently?
I was like,
why you gotta fucking tell me that?
All the things you
volunteer that information.
But of course that's,
you know,
that's what came up.
So that was an opportunity
for me to really work on
these fears and paranoia is,
which for me,
my greatest fear is
that fear of suffering.
Some fear of some illness that,
that I wouldn't be able to beat,
you know,
death I'd seen in my other experiences,
what the other side kind of felt like.
And I was like,
well that would suck.
I don't want to die.
Uh,
obviously have a lot of
stuff to do and I love life.
Life's amazing stuff to do.
But the fear of suffering,
I'd never really kicked that,
picked that fear.
So I was just sitting there and
finally like four in the morning,
the jungles just loud,
loud as shit.
Anyway,
just the CICADAS,
rare air here and you know,
birds and these um,
crazy other jungle and sit her in the
trees making honking noises and all kinds
of stuff.
I mean really,
really loud.
I think.
I know you like the hot that you're in.
Does it have open window?
So it's all just screened in windows so
it's wide open to the jungle and we're
just nestled in the jungle.
So like when you go to the
bathroom and you turn the light on,
you find giant fucking things crawling
on the windows and stuff on the outside
part,
hopefully inside the car because
they haven't got through the screens.
But yeah,
anything attracted to the light will be,
you know,
kind of stuck to the
screen door looking at gas,
fucking dog size bugs,
right?
Yeah,
you're in,
you're in the jungle and there's,
everything was nice.
No hot water,
no showers in the room,
but you know,
everything else was,
was pretty nice.
No,
obviously air or heat or anything.
So anyways,
four in the morning I'm draped and
this mosquito net and I finally,
you know,
finally like I get this idea in my head
and the phrase trust the mud comes into
my head.
It's just like just trust the mud.
And with that final thought I was
able to finally get some sleep.
Trust them,
trust the mud.
Yeah.
And I guess to me that was just a metaphor
of the mud being the jungle itself,
you know,
and the mud being what's me,
you know what's inside me,
this flash,
this life,
this everything,
all being connected.
Just just trust it.
Trust the month that it's
not going to fuck me up.
Trusted some mosquitoes not going to
come in or some millipedes not going to
crawl up my butthole and sting me
and I'm never going to shit again.
Whatever other fears that I had.
And you hear these stories too,
but like don't pee in the water.
Cause then this,
this fish will crawl up your urethra and
spread it spines and explode your Dick.
It does happen.
It does.
No,
it does happen.
So you have all of these crazy,
scary stuff that you hear
about this and that can,
you can really freak
yourself out doing that.
But again,
so finally,
four in the morning so they trust the mud.
Fuck it.
I'm going to,
I'm going to go,
go through with this next day,
wake up feeling a little better.
But I feel like like a,
like a sick person,
you know when you go to the doctor and
you're super healthy and you're gonna get
your blood drawn,
you get that kind of anticipation
before the prick of the needle prick.
It's like,
ah,
it's good for me.
I was like,
I just fucking need this so bad.
Like I wasn't even nervous before doing
this new completely new psychedelic,
which is crazy unusual.
Anytime,
even if I take like a
small dose of mushrooms,
you get those butterflies in your stomach.
Like,
Oh shit,
I'm about to jump.
I didn't even have that.
I just felt like a sick person
going to get some medicine.
So we get in there to the ceremonial
hut and laid out is what's called the
Masada.
And that's a key part of the watch Houma
ceremony is this kind of May said that
they set up and on it is these six goals,
three female shamans,
three male Schamens.
Um,
they're,
they're actual human skulls and set up.
And then there's Jaguar skulls and then
there's artifacts spanning all the way
back to [inaudible],
which is 4,000 years old.
There's a piece of the moon,
it's on this altar.
There's going to be each of the moon.
In doing the medicine,
you interact with a lot of,
a lot of people who've done and
collected a variety of things.
And one of the things after you're done
is you feel compelled to give something
back to what you've researched
for what you've received.
So a lot of these,
most of these are just gifts that have
been accumulated over 50 years of of
work.
I don't know exactly where
that piece came from,
but somebody had that given to them,
whatever.
And then they say,
Holy Shit changed my life and here's
this fucking piece of the moon.
Maybe it wasn't a piece of the moon,
but it was given as a piece of the moon,
which is just basically the same.
Yeah,
I say,
who knows?
But anyways,
lot,
I mean the skulls were real.
The Jaguar skulls,
the all this.
And then they have a big centerpiece in
altar called the [inaudible] and that's
like an ancient kind of shoving,
um,
central pillar,
which acts is like the center of
this altar called the Axis Mundey,
which,
you know,
transforms,
kind of into ceremonially into like the
center of the center of the universe is
what that's supposed to be.
So we're sitting there and he's,
um,
he starts going around in the medicine,
the San Pedro as the liquid medicine.
I didn't even know if it was liquid,
if I was going to chew it.
I had really had no fucking
idea what was going on.
I knew that it acts
that it operated on the,
um,
on the,
you know,
same serotonin receptors that mushrooms
and some of these other things.
Um,
five ht,
two a serotonin receptors that kind of
knew a little bit of the mechanism of
action,
but I didn't really know
anything other than that.
And he starts going around
the room and he's got,
you know,
kind of a warm smile.
He's cause cracking a few jokes.
And to me that's the best sign of any
good showman is that he's willing to like
crack a few jokes and stay relaxed.
Like the ones that are shady and the
ones that are weird are the ones that are
like being Sharman like watch me
play Shawman everybody be silent.
Like a yoga teacher that
insists on chanting.
Yeah,
exactly.
It was really goofy.
Exactly.
Like the ones that are really
comfortable in the medicine,
this is just what they fucking do.
You know,
they can crack a joke.
It's not gonna affect anything.
It's not going to make you think less
of them or them do the work any less and
it's not going to stop the drug and it's
not going to stop the dragon not going
to stop Gandalf.
So anyways,
so he opens up these things.
It's actually covered in the
skins of the San Pedro Cactus,
these little vessels.
And he starts looking around the
room and he'll look at you and,
uh,
look at you for like
five seconds and then,
you know,
kind of get a,
get a read on you and then pour
a certain amount into a cup.
So I was seeing,
and he's pouring little,
little bits in the cockpit.
And for me,
I wanted a project,
you know,
like give me the fucking mother dose,
but I decided I was just going
to trust what he's going to do.
So eventually,
you know,
I watch everybody drank and it looks
like they're drinking maybe two ounces
based on what he's pouring.
And he gets to me and I
just bust out a huge smile,
you know,
it's not like,
all right,
let's,
let's do this.
I was like,
really?
I Dunno.
At that moment I was just
really looking forward to it.
And he got a big smile
and he pours me up just a,
a full Mug,
not quite full,
but at least six ounces of this liquid.
And I didn't know what it tasted like.
So I had nothing to do.
So you get up to the altar,
he blows a little,
the mum Pocho,
which is the nicotine [inaudible],
um,
tobacco in this large joint looking thing.
And that's kind of a cleansing plant.
It's just kind of ceremonial.
They use to cleanse the
space and cleanse your,
your energy before you do it.
When I get the cup and it takes,
you know,
at six ounces,
so it takes like five,
six gulps and it's pretty bad.
You know,
it's thin,
it's thinner than Iowasca.
It's Kinda ruddy and a red.
Um,
but it's pretty,
pretty potent.
It has that kind of bitter or B tonic,
he kinda thing.
But it wasn't,
it wasn't so terrible.
I ended up thinking,
oh,
that's not so terrible.
And then he has one of his assistants,
uh,
bring some lemonade to wash it down,
apparently the lemonade
as good electrolytes.
So you drink that
throughout the day on this.
So drink lemonade and I'm
thinking like usual ceremonies,
you just kind of sit
around and stuff happens,
you see stuff.
And I was like,
all right,
well settling and we're gonna sit around.
No,
not what the plan was.
So he goes,
all right,
everybody,
uh,
meet me out at the front.
We're going to take a little boat ride
to some of my friends in the jungle.
Um,
we're going to bring him some Skeeto nets,
one of the local tribes.
I was like,
what the fuck?
We're just took a bunch of drugs.
You're going to make us get on a boat
and go traipsing through the jungle.
It was like,
all right,
I guess that's,
I guess that's what the plan is.
So we get all our stuff and
meet out in the front and uh,
everybody starts getting really
kind of chatty in this first part.
And he tells us that doing what Juma is
like living a living a lifetime in a day
is what he says.
Like the medicine is going to change and
that the first part is going to be very
exuberant and um,
may even result in
uncontrollable hilarity,
you know,
in,
in the first part I was like,
all right,
and then it'll change from there.
And,
uh,
the theme of this one
was the serpent Masada,
the water massada,
which is a very kind of fluid.
Uh,
the idea is to be like the water,
be very fluid,
be very close to the uh,
close to the earth.
And that's the idea for this.
So everybody's kind of getting chatty
and then we hop in the boat and we,
you know,
we cruise around and you could start
to feel that energy start to build very
silicide money,
you know,
as that kind of,
you feel something start to come on and
you'd want to stretch out your spine
cause there's some energy
coming up through you and
we start to feel that in the
boat.
But then by the time we landed on this
little inlet and you're cruising through
the jungle in these rivers,
and it's crazy because you'd have no
idea how they know where they're going
because they're going through these like
small little openings and the mangroves
and the trees and,
but whatever,
35 minutes later we ended up in
this really isolated landing.
It looks like nothing.
And these little bare chested children
come out and run out to meet us and we
hop off the boat.
And by that point we could tell something,
something very different
was starting to happen.
Like really like coils of energy.
We're like pulsing through our bodies
and it felt so fucking ridiculously good
that it's like indescribably good,
like,
like full body kind of orgasmic
little typhoons of energy.
Like just pulsing through where
you want to kind of stretch.
You don't know if you want to run,
you don't know if you can just,
it's like almost hard to contain it.
And then from the mental side of things,
everything just starts to open
up like the most beautiful.
We've,
we just landed in the most beautiful
place in the whole universe.
You know,
you just start to look around and
it has this kind of look similar,
but the lighting is a little bit different
and it's just kind of glowing to you.
Like you just landed in fucking
Pandora on Avatar world,
you know?
And the only way I can
describe the feeling of that
was this some combination of
like the best Mtma.
Like what Mtma wished it could be in its
ultimate form and a bunch of mushrooms
at the same time just smashed together.
So you had this kind of energetic side
from the mushrooms and this kind of
visionary clarity and
this just pure ecstasy of,
I feel so fucking great
that I can't even stand it,
you know,
which was not at all what I
expected from the medicine.
You know?
I was expecting something
much more visionary,
kind of head down visions,
stuff like that.
So we get out there and we started
interacting with the tribe.
The kids come and then the little kids
start playing with people in our group
and the kids,
you know,
because Don Howard only brings the
westerners out there to this tribe when
they're blasted on Chuma.
You know,
the whole tribe thinks that we're the
coolest fucking nation of people ever,
ever in the history of the universe
because we're just fucking like hugging.
Everybody were like super excited and
we're just looking around in this forest
and it's just beautiful.
Like everything is beautiful.
Like they bring out these little
bananas for us and we look at,
I'm like,
Oh fuck,
that looks good.
And then we take a banana
and you have a bite.
And it's like,
it's the most amazing
banana I've ever had.
Like everything is so fresh,
almost as if you've never tried or
done anything ever before in your life.
And you've just been an,
everything is new,
you know,
like if you hug your friend,
and we had,
we had some good friends down there.
I'll one of the people in the tribe.
It just feels like this amazing
connection you have with them.
It just tickles with excitement.
And if you eat a banana,
it's like the best tasting thing
you've ever had ever before.
And so they,
they come and they meet us and,
and the men were off in the,
off in the jungle doing some work.
So it was just the women from the tribe.
And they start playing some songs and
leading us around and some dances and
we're stomping around and they have a
few like handcrafts that they had made.
And we're cruising around.
And,
um,
you know,
uh,
we picked up a few things to kind of
support the tribe dropped off the,
um,
dropped off in a Skeeto nets.
I got this little thing.
I got you something,
I don't know why I got you this,
but this is a rattling main
that has pink dolphins on it.
So I dunno,
I dunno why,
but this is yours from there.
That's pretty dope.
Yeah.
So it's carved from like
a bean pod that's local.
They're in the jungle.
Well,
I'm a big fan of dolphins.
Yeah.
Maybe that's why.
Maybe that's why they picked off
and called the u s so anyway,
so we're hanging out there and,
and at that point I started,
you know,
we actually,
we had a,
we had a crew there with us.
It was documenting this,
um,
which we'll get to see at some
point when this comes out.
But they were asking,
you know,
about,
well,
how do you feel,
what about all the things
you were worried about?
And it wasn't at that point,
like I had any solutions to the
problems that I was concerned with.
It was just that all of it was meaningless
because life was so fucking beautiful
and so good,
you know,
that any,
I didn't have to figure out any of these
problems and worries and loneliness,
fears,
everything.
It was just such an overwhelming feeling
of everything was so amazingly good
that it just didn't matter.
You know,
it's like we're alive and that's enough.
every breath was so amazingly positive
and such a gift to be in that you
couldn't even worry about something else.
And that was kind of the nature of that
first little stop off in the jungle and
I'm really cool.
But then it started,
so we there for a couple hours and just
laughing and having fun and screwing
around and,
and thinking about things and smiling
and eating little snacks like,
like the banana and then
it starts to get dusk.
And so we go into another boat ride
and slowly before that had happened,
kind of the,
the hilarity of things
and everything started,
the energy started to drop and we,
I remembered back to what he was saying,
how the medicine is going to change.
And certainly that's when
it started to change.
Everything kind of got
quieter and a little bit,
you know,
still very powerful
but in a different way.
Um,
kind of that ecstatic energy where you
felt like you had to run around or had to
stretch or had to do something just to
release this energy that was in your body
that kind of started to die away.
And so we're at dusk on this boat ride
and the way that the shadows where it was
like very difficult to distinguish between
the jungle and the reflection on the
water.
So we're cruising in this canoe and it
looks like we're cruising right through
the divide between,
you know,
air and water.
Everything is just really
difficult to discern.
What we're doing is really
kind of cool visual effect,
obviously made stronger by the what tumor.
And I start to have my first visions from
this experience and I started to have
visions of just what I identified
as the true nature of life and uh,
and that kind of feminine
life giving birthing energy.
And it was just this crazy ecstatic
vision of life within life,
within life.
Like looking at a human,
not only as a person,
but then a collection of
cells filled with bacteria,
filled with parasites,
filled with life,
just teaming all the way down to the
level of the flagella that are moving
around like you know,
and then there was visions of the octopus
tentacles flowing and changing colors
and visions of ever.
Even in the dirt.
The dirt itself was alive with different
bacteria and insects and things.
And everywhere you look,
there was just life
bursting through every seam.
And with that I saw three
women with these long,
venomous fingernails,
big Philips,
Ewas tits and amber skin and amber hair,
dark,
dark eyes.
And I could,
you could see the venom
dripping from their nails.
And they're smiling at me and waving me,
waving me for three of them
waving me forward like this.
And it was the most irresistible
sight I've ever seen.
Just this life everywhere,
tentacles.
And,
and I realized that,
that,
that energy,
that polarity of that extreme life giving
material feminine energy was what was
completely irresistible
to the other force,
which is that that life force,
that source,
the non creation consciousness,
you know,
that has no form and
seeks order in all things,
you know.
And so this polarity of
masculine and feminine,
we're just irresistibly
attracted to each other.
And that what's,
that's what made the,
the balance between
the earth and a phrase,
which I still don't really understand,
but it kept going.
I kept saying it over and over in my
head was that existence is the ecstasy of
dichotomy.
And I think what that means is just
that balance between this life giving
feminine,
succulent,
seductive,
sexy,
ecstatic,
chaotic presence of the feminine and
the other dichotomy of consciousness
itself,
which has none of those attributes.
None of those physical attributes.
But that's what existence is.
It's that dichotomy of both of those.
What about the van Wyck together?
The venom wasn't,
you know,
we think of venom is as evil,
but that's just part of this
visceral life death cycle.
You know,
things burst forth,
things die.
The venom is this kind of chaotic,
seductive element that is,
that's all a part of it.
Like it's not separate.
It's not like this part is good,
you know,
and this part is bad.
It just all comes forth
naturally without any choice.
So the venom and the,
and a banana,
you know,
are really the same thing,
just manifested in a different way,
you know?
So all of it was what was irresistible.
It wasn't just the good parts,
you know,
even these,
even these women with these venoms,
nails were completely irresistible
to the place that I was in,
which was,
it's very kind of consciousness,
spiritually centered place.
And that was completely irresistible to
me and I could see how it would be to
consciousness itself,
you know,
because that's the
dichotomy that creates this,
the polarity and the
interesting parts of life.
So we get finally,
everybody was silent on this boat ride
cause we took it a little bit slower.
So it took us about 45 minutes to go back.
And then my friend Daniel is there,
actually the guy who recommended
it right before we pull it up,
he's like,
man,
that was like the best sex I've ever
had and all of us just fucking crack up
because that's exactly what it was like.
I think very similar visions of
just this entering this weird,
sexy,
seductive world.
And so this,
um,
this dolphin thing came from those
people came from those people.
They make them and they make them,
they sell them or something.
Wow.
Yup.
It feels crazy.
Yeah.
Like listening to your story
and hold on to those songs.
Yeah.
Thanks for bringing this up.
You're welcome.
Really cool.
Yeah.
So the,
uh,
so anyways,
we get back and then he's like,
well,
meet me at back in the Maloca,
which is the ceremonial Ha,
um,
to meet me back in the loca
for the night ceremony.
And the Maloca is all lit
with these different candles.
Um,
you know,
kind of splayed out in the whole,
um,
you know,
the whole Mesa,
if you want to actually bring up a
picture of that because it's almost
impossible to describe.
Um,
what this actually looks like.
It's pretty,
pretty incredible.
There's some at night and you'll see the
candles and you'll see this Mesa table
and we're just kinda waiting there and
waiting for Don Howard to come in and
everybody was kind of getting cleaned
up cause we're sweating from the day
people took showers and
which was a little weird,
cause you're still,
you're pretty fucking
blasted at this point.
Is this it right here?
Yeah,
that's,
that's it.
That's a different night.
There's another night kind of front on,
um,
first because some of the pictures
that are kind of front on it,
but that's the table that was,
that was the second night.
But anyway,
so,
um,
I'm waiting for him and there's these
MoPoTsyo cigarettes on the altar and I'm
wanting to smoke one or us,
you know,
kind of interested in doing that.
But for some reason I felt weird just
grabbing it off the altar without giving
anything back to the altar,
even though he'd been passing them out.
Yes.
That's,
that's what it looks
like kind of from behind.
Um,
but,
but so I'd look through
my bag and I was like,
well,
I got to give something to
get this Mopotsyo and uh,
and I don't know why,
I'm sure it would have
been fine with Don Howard,
but that's just really
what I felt at that moment.
And so I looked through my
bag and I had a little stick,
a cinnamon than I use to light
and burn and smells nice.
But I was like,
okay,
that seems fair.
So I put the cinnamon up there and I
took them a patch on and then I think to
myself,
oh,
I got to light it.
Well there's a bunch of
candles in front of me,
but for some reason I didn't even feel
right taking a light from those candles
without asking first.
So I asked the candles
as the candles.
I said,
do you mind if I borrow some fire and
just clear as another voice as if I was
talking to somebody else
over here to my right.
It says,
sure,
cause you're going to give me some smoke.
And I go,
uh Huh.
Yup,
you're right.
So I go and I,
there's a candle here to my left
and I lied a little bit from there.
And then there was another candle
all the way to my right and I asked,
I was like,
oh,
can I have some fire?
There was like,
yeah,
sure.
So I lied a little bit more.
It's still wasn't fully quite lit,
you know?
And so there was a candle in
the middle and without thinking,
I just went to go light from
the candle in the middle,
didn't ask,
just didn't even,
it was kind of unconscious and
inexplicably when I did that,
the smoke just blasted me in the eyes,
like straight up into my
eyes and really stung.
And I heard the voice come back and say,
even when it's fair,
make sure to ask permission.
And it was the fucking craziest thing.
And what it was was he was teaching me
the principle of reciprocity is what is
one of the biggest fundamental core
teachings of the shoving people.
And the idea is that even if
you don't have anything to give,
at least give your gratitude.
And that's one of the core reasons in
ways that we've gotten off from these kind
of old teachings in that whatever you do,
there's a give and take.
You know,
when you take an animal,
you know at the very least give you for
the gift of that animal when you take,
it could be a vegetable,
you know,
just say a little,
thanks for that.
And as the earth in general,
you know,
providing a home,
providing us place materials,
um,
the principle of reciprocity would be to
do your part to protect that or at the
very least just be grateful
for what you've kind of got.
And that in itself,
that gratitude is,
is enough,
you know,
and it,
but it was funny how that kind of came
up in this kind of very back and forth
verbal teaching from this altar
and this really silly thing.
I mean,
it's my Pocho and fire,
you know?
But that was kind of the,
the example that it used to kind of
drive that point home and a really stuck
with me and as something that,
you know,
always remember like,
all right,
you know,
the give and take of things is something
much older and more sacred than even
just an idea that we have.
You know,
there's like that is a fundamental
principle that should be abided by.
That's something that you feel too.
Yeah.
You know,
you feel like when you see
someone who doesn't tip,
you know,
you get this feeling
when you're with them,
you know,
it's,
or someone who,
uh,
is in,
you know,
same,
similar,
vain,
rude to someone who's in
the service profession is
trying to be kind to them and
they,
they recognize this imbalance because
the person's trying very hard to be nice
to them so they feel like
they can be shitty to them.
You see that in as an observer,
you know,
as an outsider watching that,
it's very uncomfortable.
It's like you're seeing in balance,
you're feeling unbounce.
Yeah.
Or someone throwing a
cigarette butt on the ground.
So common,
yeah.
Incredibly common.
And that's the exact feeling
that you get from that and said,
this is a person that's not in tune and
amazingly so it seems to be the majority
of people that smoke cigarettes in
their cars throw them out the window.
Yep.
Man.
I don't know if it's a majority,
I shouldn't say the majority.
I haven't done a survey,
but I should say a large number.
I see it all the time.
I see it.
I've counted eight Prius's so far that
I've seen that throw cigarettes out the
window,
which I find particularly ironic.
Right.
Just the environmentally conscious car
with cigarette flying out the window.
Right.
Then it makes you wonder why they
chose that environmentally conscious
car for auditions.
Yeah,
exactly.
Look,
cool.
Exactly.
Yeah.
That's uh,
that feeling of the balance,
the,
the reciprocity.
Just the,
the being aware of,
you know,
the give and take of things.
That's a very important principle.
It's very important for me.
It's to me,
I'm very,
very sensitive to that.
It's one of the most
important things to me.
Yup.
And you're right in line with
the very core teachings of,
of the shoving people.
And that was it.
And,
and then they used to give free.
So the shop Vien was not a race.
It was a collection of individuals that
came out of the jungle collection of
Shamans and healers and
teachers set up shop in shoving,
which has an actual location,
but it wasn't racially organized and
they had no hierarchical structure,
which freaks archeologists out because
they keep trying to look for it.
Well,
who's the king?
there wasn't no king.
It was like the fucking round table.
And they cannot,
they can understand that.
And they would give
ceremonies of the watch,
Huma and the [inaudible] to any
of the pilgrims that Kinda came.
And the idea was the
pilgrim brings a gift.
Whatever they have.
Sometimes they have no gift
and it's just their gratitude.
But many times it was actual
gifts that would come.
And that's kind of how the
society work based upon,
you know,
simply that principle of reciprocity.
Um,
you know,
eventually it,
it died out and it was carried on
by a couple of other traditions,
couple of other places
like the Mochi and things.
But from that point,
then other things started creeping in,
hierarchy,
power,
militarism,
et cetera.
Even the INCAS,
which people credit is this great,
highly civilized people,
uh,
which they were to a great degree,
but they were still fully
militarized and you know,
kind of they took over,
they overwhelmed the whole surrounding
area with a military force,
different than the shoving,
but to just more typical
to what was going on.
And The Times the shopping
was a really kind of unique,
unique situation that they had.
And like I said,
their core principle,
there was that principle of reciprocity
and guidance from these two really
powerful medicines.
Wow.
So tonight's ceremony,
the night ceremony.
Yeah.
So we get in there and the first part
of the night ceremony on his altar,
on his table,
he has these ancient whistling vessels
that are somewhere between 500 to 2,500
years old.
And they're like these clay vessels.
Some are Jaguars.
Mine was a two can some,
one of them was life and
death as friends together.
And there's these amazing artifacts,
life and death,
his friends.
So one is the skeleton and
the other is this Philip.
She was a woman and they're holding
each other like this and it's life and
death,
his friends and a and
all of these vessels.
And you blow through the top
and it creates a really unique,
um,
whistling sound.
And so he asked us all
to the altar and he says,
well,
why don't we try to wake
this up a little bit?
You know,
and he always has that kind of rise smile
cause he knows he understates what's,
what's going to happen.
So we all start blowing on
these whistles and together,
you know,
it sounds discoordinate first,
but then ultimately it locks into this
frequency that feels like it's going
through your entire just penetrating
straight through your head.
Like you're not even listening to it.
It's just wiping you clean of any
kind of frequency that you might have.
Like a really strong,
like resonant sound that just goes
straight through your whole body,
which was kind of a cool
experience in itself.
And what they used it for was that,
you know,
aligning,
just kind of sound and frequency and
getting you basically back to that clean
slate so that anything you
have going on in your head,
maybe you got a song stuck in your head,
maybe you gotta beat stuck in your head.
Maybe you've got some late and
programs kind of going on it.
Just kind of wipe straight that straight
through and a a cool experience.
Nothing crazy,
more profound than that,
but just kind of awesome
to be a part of this,
you know,
blowing these vessels that have
been used for this purpose,
like ancient consciousness
that Collin technology,
you know,
2000 years old from the Mochi people
and some other people they would say
that's something,
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
but that's something that
seems to resonate in a lot
of these ancient shamanic
cultures is the need for music,
the need for song songs that
carry through ceremonies,
songs that take you through,
whether it's a mushroom
ceremony or Iowasca,
the ios scarecrows and their eco rose.
Those songs that they sing.
What,
what is the,
what is there,
when you talk to them about that,
what's the connection?
The Ero is their kind of
their own special thing,
but almost every single shamonic
tradition has rattles and that,
and Don Howard had rattles to,
his rattles were a little
different than these ones,
but they talk about breaking up,
you know,
for them,
they can see these energetic forces and
for them they talk about the rattles
breaking up this kind of frequency field,
um,
around you and kind of recalibrating
it to a certain degree.
So the rattles are used
completely ubiquitously.
And then there's other things like singing
bowls which you'd find in Tibet and
in the,
in Peru they had the whistling vessels
and other things that make kind of other
shrill sounds.
And then of course
there's the drum switch.
Make a beat good for dancing,
are good for that.
Um,
the gross themselves or just the songs
that the plant's teach you and are very
kind of DMT oriented is,
um,
as I kind of found out,
cause I found myself singing one of these
songs out of the fucking blue when I
was smoking,
snorting the villa.
But we'll get to that in,
in sequence.
Um,
but yeah,
it kind of just breaks
up the auditory field.
Uh,
and it also an,
a lot of cultures that calls in announces
basically the helper spirits to come
and the allies to come.
Like,
Hey,
here we are,
you know,
come find us.
Uh,
is another reason.
But I don't know.
I can't see that stuff.
I mean I just know it kind of sounds
good and it puts me in a good mood.
Um,
and,
and it feels,
feels good,
but it takes one of those
other seniors to experience it.
And I don't like speculating on things
that I haven't experienced and they don't
actually like talking about
things that you can't experience.
And that's a difference between a religion
and shamanism is they don't tell you
shit.
They show you everything,
you know,
if they can't show you,
they just,
they won't tell you.
You know,
it's like this is,
this is truth and you have
to go find it for yourself,
you know?
Whereas religions by and large are like,
here's the truth.
It's written down in his book.
You better follow it whether it makes
sense or not or will burn you or kill you
or Rachel.
Well,
all that stuff's unnecessary
when you can ride the dragon.
Right.
It really just completely unnecessary.
Exactly.
Cause everybody,
you get to that same conclusion piece
different people to different degrees.
Um,
but it's,
you know,
and it's reproducible in every individual.
So you don't need to go talking to me.
You don't have to believe in it.
No,
he does nothing that you have to
believe in other than just what you've
experienced yourself.
You know?
And that's,
that's the beauty of this kind
of work to solve or to hear those
beautiful.
Um,
so then the next part of that ceremony,
the last part was to snort this liquid
out of what's called a single low,
which is this giant steak.
And I'm,
it's a liquid preparation that
they pour in the tip of it.
And it was a combination
of the Florida water,
um,
tobacco,
some more what Chuma and a few
other plants in this thing.
And um,
so you get up there and it's this big
steak and you kind of tip it into one
nostril.
Yeah,
I have a little bit.
Um,
you tip it into one nostril
and you tip it into the other
nostril and then it fills your,
it fills your body with,
uh,
with this kind of fiery kind of
lightening sensation that you feel.
And it's almost like,
you know,
you're just holding on to the state
because it's burned in as it's going down
this liquid that you just
tilt it down in your mouth,
but it didn't have any kind of great
physical psycho dynamic effects other than
just to kind of like really
align you with the altar.
And,
um,
so there,
so there at the altar,
not too much happened,
but one of the interesting things was
I was the first one to go and I was
waiting for Don Howard to tell me like,
when my experience was up,
you know,
cause I'm up there at the altar,
everybody's watching me.
And one of the great things about how
he worked his throughout the whole
session,
he never did that.
And when you had your turn to go up,
he would never tell you like,
okay,
you're done.
He just completely trusted you that you
would move and you would do take action
at the right time.
And I really appreciated that.
And that to me,
you know,
instilled a great degree of trust in him,
which is something that
I haven't had immensely.
And in a lot of people is this ultimate
trust that he's got this thing kind of
figured out.
And you get that from the trust that
he puts in each other individual.
It's kind of this interesting thing.
So I'm sitting there and really the
only takeaway from that for me was,
you know,
uh,
communication with the altar.
Um,
that said,
um,
basically I said to the,
I,
you know,
I'm going to protect you and the altar.
You know,
I could hear it again,
clear as day.
And he said,
I'll protect you too.
And that was kind of the end of that,
that encounter.
And I look back and Don Howard smiled
and I gave him back the steak and
everybody went around the circle
and that kind of closed off night.
One end of the serpent,
Masada night,
one of three,
nobody tripped,
nobody freaked out.
I mean,
tripped by nobody like had
a bad experience with this.
That is the danger of going down
there and one of these retreats,
right?
That you might go with a loon,
you might go with some crazy person
that can handle the ride.
So he,
he goes through these extensive
questionnaires that he,
uh,
that he reviews for anybody coming down
and he says he's pretty good at weeding
out,
you know,
the loons that are going to come.
He says,
it just comes through in the writing
and how they answered the questions.
You ask them to answer essays for him.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So they're writing,
you know,
writing extensive amounts about
their and 10 about their life,
about their experiences,
blah,
blah.
And so he says he's pretty
good at filtering that out.
But of course some people
who are pathological,
you know,
can fool them and it's happened before
where he gets in those situations.
But you don't want to go down
there and fuck with Gandalf.
Like it's just,
you're not going to come out a winner.
Why is it,
I always have to ask what happens
when things go wrong that's like,
you know,
sad.
It's like,
I'm like,
uh,
in,
in some ways.
And that's a,
I'm a theorist and things
going horribly wrong,
you know,
so I'm looking at this,
I'm like,
this all sounds beautiful.
What could be unbeautiful about it?
Oh,
you go down there with
a Dick head for sure.
And he said he's had that happen.
He's had that happen where someone
came down and intentionally tried to
undermine the ceremonies.
I didn't go into what that was,
but he's,
you know,
but then,
he's there and not only is it him,
he's got two other shamans there as well.
Indigenous Shamans.
This Guy Donald Bear,
who's a,
a Banco current Darrow,
which is the equivalent of like the
coral belt in Jujitsu or something like
that.
There's only like a couple in the world
who've been bestowed this great Ios
Garrow honor,
you know,
so a Carindale Donald bear and his wife
don't [inaudible] who's another like
really bad ass Sean.
So you have like the wizard council there.
So,
you know,
they're able to really
work with some stuff and,
and uh,
and make an impact.
I wonder what happens to those
people if they are a crazy person.
They wanted them doing those drugs.
He imagine if you found that you
could snap somebody back to earth,
like you could have someone
who's completely sociopathic,
give him some of this
and they develop empathy.
I mean,
is that possible?
He always like right off sociopaths.
But is it,
is it possible that I could ever be cured?
I mean I don't,
I don't understand the human mind enough.
You know,
if from a scientific
standpoint the medicine is an,
and he didn't,
Don Howard was really
forthright about this,
that the medicine by itself is neither
going to do good nor bad without the
intent of the user because
the intent of the user,
you can use this medicine for,
you know,
brew whole Brouhaha sorcery,
is what they call it and sorcery.
To what extent that means,
you know,
that is,
but basically by saying that he's saying
you could use that to get your own
power and kind of like the Shaman who
amber talks about where you know to them,
that's the dark side.
So sorcery is kind of a weird word
because they're not like making weird shit
happened,
although some,
there's some weird stories,
but really using it for your own
power and weird stories though.
You have to take into account their told
you by people tripping their fucking
balls off.
Yeah,
I'm sure you think that shit went down.
I bet you're not a liar.
I'm not saying you're a liar,
but God damn,
you have to sort of include that.
And the no CBO effect of believing
something terrible happened is strong.
We were on Opie and Anthony once and we,
there was a woman that they have
who's a regular on the show.
She comes all the time and
they call a stalker patty.
And uh,
we gave Stalker Patty Listerine breath
strip and told her that it was drugs and
this girl,
I mean,
I don't know how much of it was an act.
I don't know how much of it it was.
She's not like mentally completely there,
but she was acting like she was
tripping or fucking balls off.
Like she just ate the
strongest pot Brownie in the
world and she was just clean
to the earth trying to stay on.
And Ari had his balls out like our,
he decided to take his balls out and
stand next to her and pretended as balls
weren't out and we all
pretended his balls weren't out.
Like it's so his balls were like hanging
out of his zipper and she was like,
oh my God.
And everyone's like,
what?
This,
you know,
she's like,
oh my God,
you guys got me.
There's a drug,
I'm on a drug.
Like she really believed that.
Yeah.
Just because of the,
the effect of telling
someone that they've,
I mean,
how many people that get hit with
the Holy Spirit when you know,
you see those people,
they start speaking in tongues,
you know,
when,
what would they do that,
I mean,
would they really be doing that if
someone hadn't sort of pressured him?
Someone had to put in their
head that that's possible.
I mean in a vacuum,
how many people are
really going to do that?
It seems like the only do that if there's
a bunch of other people around them
that are doing the same thing.
The power of suggestion takes over
and then you really believe saw la,
la,
la La,
like the board is talking three
you in Jibberish like hypnotists,
you know,
that there's that hypnotists kind of,
um,
idea that the more people who are there
and the more people who were watching,
the easier it is to
hypnotize you because of the,
the whole dynamic.
And the other people and
exactly our suggestion.
Yeah,
absolutely.
That plays a part.
I've seen that happen.
I've seen a lot of people get hypnotized
because I had a friend who was a
hypnotist.
There was a guy named Frank Santos who
was a comedian in Rhode Island and he was
a dirty hippy and test.
He's doing a show at stitches and his son
is actually apparently a hypnotist to,
I think it's Frank Santa was junior.
Um,
I just got a tweet for him.
His Dad was a super nice guy and employed
me actually way back in the day you
had a comedy club.
Cool.
Hooked me up when I was
just starting to a headline,
but I watched this guy
dozens of times over several years.
I watched him and we would all watch like
comics would come from like if we knew
Frank Santos was doing
a show like at Nick's,
we would go across town,
drive over just to watch.
Cause it was,
you couldn't believe it was real.
You would watch these people and all
of a sudden they believe they're having
with Madonna.
Guys would come in their pants.
They would be having sex on stage and
they'd come in their pants and we would,
you would have a thing that he would say
to women and they would have an orgasm
so he could say it,
I'm a,
you know,
a touch you on the head and I'm going
to say creamy cream filled donut or
something.
He would come up with a name,
whatever you wanted to say.
If it's not,
that should be that I'm making that up.
It's my son's probably why she
ain't never fucking saw that.
My point is he would have,
like,
I would say Abracadabra and he would
touch someone on the forehead and the one
would just go,
oh my God.
And people would be dying laughing.
She women would be embarrassed and there's
people that would be convinced that
they're naked.
Like,
oh my God.
Like they have their clothes on,
they're convinced her naked.
There's people that were convinced that
everyone in the audience was naked.
I mean,
they would look around and
laughing and they really were,
it's like it was really working.
It wasn't that they were acting.
There was something weird going on.
And he knew when people were under,
when they weren't like
people would try to fake it,
they would be on stage with
them and he would look at my,
nope,
sorry,
you gotta go.
No,
no,
I'm hypnotized.
And he was like,
no,
you're not.
No,
It's not going to work with you.
And he would just shuffle them off.
And the ones that it would work on those,
the ones you did it on.
Yup.
Super interesting dynamic.
The mind is so incredibly powerful.
That is one of the main reasons why it's
super difficult to take someone's word
in account of,
of an event when someone
starts talking about an event,
like something that happened,
you know,
whether it's watching car accident,
being participating in
an accident and what,
how much,
how much of what you actually see in
a short traumatic circumstance or you
really,
really collected like say,
uh,
like an asteroid was to slam into the
ocean near Long Beach and kill like a
fucking hundred thousand people and you
were there and you saw something happen.
He saw it hit the water.
You saw how many people are really going
to recount that correctly unless you
watched the video.
Your version of the
events could vary wildly.
I mean,
it could be,
you could be off by hours.
You know,
if you don't talk to anybody,
false cell phones go
down your version of it.
If no one's videotaping it,
we never get a chance to see it.
Who knows what versions
we're going to get.
We're going to a hundred
different versions,
different timelines.
It's one of the things that people
I think connect to a lot of,
uh,
ideas of conspiracy.
You know,
people say,
Oh,
you know,
if all these people told this story,
how much of it could be a line is that
there's another option that's not how
much of it is a lie.
Cause how much of it people who were
just dwelling on crazy shit until it
becomes real in their own head.
And then they have these stories
and they're stories coincide.
Okay,
well there's a part of the brain they
call the simulator and that's what makes
you like think of some weird fucked up
food combination like a cinnamon Manet's,
right?
No one's ever had cinnamon
Manet's probably some weeds
eating it right now where
they're going the fuck he saying use
the simulator to give you an a very
accurate idea of what cinnamon Manet's
tastes like.
And that's a very valuable
part of evolution.
But if you're using the
simulator constantly enough,
it's almost going to be like,
oh yeah,
I had cinnamon Manet's,
you know,
if you thought about that,
and then for 10 years down the road,
Oh shit,
wait,
I actually never actually had
cinnamon Manet's you know?
Well,
they've done that with people.
They've implanted fake memories
and in like in a strategic sense,
they've done it in some sort
of another way with mice.
They figured out a way to
implant some memories in mice,
some weird artificial memories,
like they have the,
I believe if I'm butchering this,
I apologize.
I'm obviously not a scientist,
but I believe that what
they've accomplished so far
as they've attained this
rudimentary ability to
introduce artificial thoughts,
at least in concept and at
least in concept on a less
complex mind is a humans,
but that they can do it through tactics
with a person through counseling.
If someone particularly like tries to
bend your mind and bend your version of
the past over a long series of things and
reinforces it with your friendship and
alienates you and you
don't follow the script,
you know,
I mean that's like watching homeland.
Yeah,
sure,
sure.
It's just what churches do as well.
You know,
if you don't agree with their dog man,
their doctrine,
they'll get like,
you know,
you'll get a lot of rejection,
but if you do agree,
you'll get a lot of acceptance.
And that's one of the
reasons why really it's,
it's really weird,
but what they decide to be upset about,
you know,
like I'm watching all these people that
are freaking out about this gay guy that
just got drafted into the NFL,
right.
First openly gay guy.
And I'm seeing it on both sides.
You know,
I'm seeing people saying
this is an amazing thing,
and then I'm also seeing people saying,
you know,
hey,
why don't you just fucking
keep it to himself?
Like no one gives a shit.
Like we're not,
we're not homophobic.
We just don't want to hear it.
You know?
It's,
it's fascinating to see,
oh,
it's like to what?
What's,
you know,
what is it about this that people are
connecting with religion because there's
so much crazy shit about
religion that no one's freaking,
why isn't everybody
freaking out about tattoos?
Because it's pretty,
God damn clear.
You're not supposed to get tattoos.
Why isn't everybody
freaking out about piercing?
You not supposed to get pierced,
all that.
Isn't that why you
dwelling and the gay thing,
like why is the gay thing
the number one thing?
What about shellfish?
Where's the the outrage
at the fish markets?
Where's the protests?
Where people,
what is really going on?
He was this,
this,
this masculine story that's been told.
I mean you got to figure
somewhere between,
the stats are like in Germany it's 10%
and another places it's 2% but a certain
percentage of men are gay.
Yeah,
they're just gay.
Yeah.
And let's get really good number of
those are just fighting it just barely
hanging on and then there's this story
that's out that if you are that way,
then you're,
you're not a man,
you're not a full man,
you know?
And so this,
this kind of fear of not being
a full man is imprinted in us.
And then the combination of that mixed
with these people who are desperately
fighting it because they really can,
are barely hanging on.
It creates these crazy scenarios.
I hope that it bounces out to the point
where you can goof on gay guys without
worry about being labeled as homophobic.
Like they're on the menu
for being goofed on.
It's like there's like,
if you say anything,
if you see if he joke
around about gay people,
you owe his homophobic comments.
Like was that what it was?
Are you sure?
Because I think there's some gay
people to do some creepy shit.
It's not negative against gays,
but I have a gay friend or a friend
who's friends with a gay guy more.
I know the guy,
but my friend really knows him and
the gay guy keeps trying to fuck him
and you know,
he's like stuck in this situation.
Like,
man,
I can't be friends with
this fucking guy anymore.
Like I thought I was
going to be open minded.
And then you realized
somewhere along the line,
oh this is a dude.
Oh he's a dude.
And so he's like,
just like a guy friend that hangs
around with your girlfriend,
you don't trust that motherfucker.
Yeah,
you don't trust this gay guy,
great guy hanging around
with the hot lesbian.
He's going to want to fuck you.
If you're a guy,
it's okay.
There's nothing wrong with it.
But you know,
you gotta be real careful if you're
a dude and you're in one of those
situations,
this guy won't leave him alone.
So it's like ruining his head.
Like he associates that guard down
instead of with being with his friend.
It's being his friend that says crazy
shit when he has a couple of drinks in
him,
you know where it's like he starts,
he's just trying to like
psychological warfare on him.
He's trying to say things like,
look no one is born gay.
You choose to be gay because
once you try it you like,
it starts like working on
your implanting idea strategy.
He's just working his pimp
camp work camp strong.
He's just flexing on my poor friend.
You know?
And if you,
if you started to do a joke about that,
that would be widely
considered homophobic.
You know why they considered gay men
get a pass on all the douche genus that
comes along with being a man.
You know what I mean?
Weird Women Bro.
We all possess Douchey,
knows it's not gender specific.
We all sort of have things,
I mean we're all working out life.
We're all working out life from the,
the information that was given to us that
people didn't know what the fuck they
were doing.
We are working out life based on what
we figured out over the course of our
lifetime.
And we had to de learn and d program
a lot of shit that was talked to us.
A lot of nonsense that was spoken or
reinforced every fucking which way you
look.
The movies to songs to conscious people,
pressure from your own parents,
pressure from your own.
It's gotta be one of the weirdest things.
You know,
there's,
there's people that never
recover from that shit.
I have,
I have friends that whatever fucking
weirdness their parents put on them,
they just Voodoo a five,
they just don't have any confidence.
They don't have any
ability to be themselves.
That's an interesting thing.
When you look at world religions,
it's the heredity and low and
region is the absolute hands down.
Number one deciding factor
about what religion you are.
You know,
if it was like you're
just finding the truth,
you know,
and you're looking at
everything and finding the true,
it'd be fucking interspersed everywhere.
But really what it is,
it's just you're in an area and that's
what fucking taught to you and that's the
story.
And so that's why you're in that religion.
It's not that that's the best one,
it's just,
that's the one that's been
fucking taught to you.
Eddie Bravo and I pulled,
had very similar,
um,
childhood revelations and we're
having a conversation one day about,
uh,
the moment we realized there
was more than one religion.
Like that's how we,
we both kind of realized it was bullshit.
Like I found out about Jews,
my uncle married a Jew,
a nice Jewish woman,
and um,
converted,
went through the whole
rig tomorrow and I was,
I didn't understand what was going on.
I was six years old,
you know,
and so they had explained it to me.
They said,
well,
you know,
uh,
uncle sal on the south.
So it was just going to change
religions all were like,
okay,
like what does that mean?
Well,
he's going to become Jewish,
so he's going to have to go through
this whole ceremony and learn a bunch of
things.
You know,
how to learn about,
uh,
the really like,
you have to take lessons with a rabbi.
And I was like,
well,
what,
what is,
what is Jewish?
And they're like,
well,
this is some people that have
a different religion than ours.
You can masturbate more.
He can't eat bacon,
but pretty much similar.
It was just the idea that
there was another religion,
blah,
blah.
Do they have the same God
like then shit got weird.
I started asking questions like that.
They have the same God.
I get the God essentially is the same,
but they don't,
they believe in Jesus.
They just don't believe he's the Messiah.
They don't,
they don't,
they don't believe in the resurrection.
You're like,
well,
what the fuck is going on?
And they're right there and all
the sound's going to marijuana.
These crazy people.
What are you talking about?
Like I thought we figured this all out.
Like when I was six,
I guess five,
six,
whatever it was,
which was first grade,
I guess it was six.
Um,
I went through one of the biggest
changes in my entire life as far as my
understanding of the world around me.
And it was caused by one year of
Catholic school and being in that school,
seeing the darkness of that
place and all the evil,
those fucking people and all the kids
who were just like constricted and yelled
at in that place.
I knew,
I knew it was bullshit.
I was like this and uncle sal together.
Okay,
the whole thing is nonsense.
And that was like realizing
when I was six I was like,
Jesus,
this bad word.
He used street Jesus figure speech folks.
All I was thinking was like,
oh my God,
this world is run by crazy people.
Like I was given birth into a land
that's filled with people that are
operating on momentum and the momentum of
like one of the craziest fucking stories
of all time as it's a god Damn Zombie
story and everyone is on this momentum
of the Zombie Story to the point where
the men aren't fucking and the women are
wearing penguin outfits and everybody's
beacon kids.
And I'm like,
what are you guys doing?
What is this?
So
and then what?
What was really bad about it though?
It's not that they were just doing it,
but how aggressively their
mission was to spread it by death,
by baby,
by whatever fucking means possible.
You squash everything.
And that's what kind
of swept through Peru.
You know,
they were doing these
watch Houma ceremonies.
The missionaries come through
and see it and they're like,
oh no,
no,
we can't have that.
You know,
they're accessing higher truth,
finding reproducible,
you know,
knowledge about the universe
through consciousness.
No,
we can't have that.
But they also couldn't
completely squash it out.
So they kind of
reconstructed the ceremony,
renamed the medicine from watch Houma,
which came from the plant spirit watch
human I think is how you say it and
called it San Pedro.
And of course,
Saint Peter is the person
who holds the keys to heaven.
I guess that's who you hang out with
right before you walked through the pearly
gates or whatever.
So,
and then in renaming that they
allowed it to kind of still exist,
but they completely
Catholicized the whole thing.
They changed the nature of the altar.
It became more religio centric and
then reconstructed the nature of the
ceremony.
So it was like communing with Saint Peter
and taking a glimpse through the gates
of Heaven.
So they changed the
whole framework of the,
the ceremony and kind of watered down the
medicine a little bit and then used it
in their own for their
own religious purposes.
And that way it kind of
changed the whole nature of,
of what this was,
which was these guys.
And if you look at the key stone
of art for the shoving people,
it's this tapestry called
the Estella Raimondi.
And it's this dude just fucking head up,
heart forward holding two stocks of
with Chuma turn it into a Jaguar with
snuffed coming down his nose.
Woo.
I need that as a tattoo.
Totally.
If you want to look up as Stella.
Yes.
T e l.
L a Rye Mondi are a I.
Yeah.
Pull that up.
That needs to be a t shirt.
Yeah,
it should be an honor.
It's bad ass.
Put that alongside the Zombie on a t
shirt and then chip on the tee shirt.
So that was the old,
that was the old way.
And I'll tell you in a little bit on the
third ceremony why the Jaguar was the
most sacred animals.
I had an experience with that.
So to go to the second one,
no,
the second one is the earth ceremony.
And by this,
this is day five and I
started to go through kind of
a detox cause you're eating
very,
very clean,
no sugar,
no dairy,
no wheat.
The medicine itself is very detoxifying
and I'd been drinking and whatever,
eating crap and during the normal
kind of entertaining thing.
Um,
I mean I still eat pretty
good for obviously,
you know,
for a normal,
but good enough,
bad enough that I was
going through a detox.
So I really felt like shit in
the jungle on day four and five.
So we go into the Earth Masada and I'm
really kind of dreading it because I'm
like not feeling good at all,
is a wild ass fucking w.
Would you call that a pictograph?
What would you call?
Well,
it's actually,
it's actually carved in stone
and that's a relief of it.
If you want to look,
you can find the one
that's actually in stone.
Holy Shit.
So there's the one that's
actually carved in stone,
so that's 4,000 years old.
So those are what Touma
stocks that he has there.
If you scroll down in his hands,
see him holding onto those things and
he's transforming into a Jaguar there and
all of these different layers of communion
with snakes coming off it all the way
going all the way up to the sky.
God Damn,
that is dope.
That as bad as,
wow,
this is fascinating,
man.
This is a completely different
branch of the whole psychedelic food.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Wow.
And it completely under
known because it's,
everybody knows it is San Pedro,
which is this kind of watered down
Catholicized ritual and medicine.
Because I was down there with some
people who had done San Pedro before and
they're like,
yeah,
it was pretty cool.
It was cool.
It felt good,
but this was a fucking
much different ballgame.
Like the way he prepares it,
the way the whole ritual is.
It's totally different game.
I want to meet this dude
who's from Kentucky,
who lives in the jungle.
You gotta meet him at cat,
you will meet him.
He's,
he's,
he's amazing.
He's awesome.
I just love that there's people like that
out there that are just live in these
very wild lives.
So it's so different than anything
that we have locked into our heads is
acceptable,
you know?
But it's,
it's hard to let go of the idea,
but the,
it really is right there
in front of your face.
It doesn't matter what you do,
you just do what you want to do.
Like you should do what you want to do
because we're all just gonna die anyway.
We live and we die.
And just kind of accept
that it's hard as fuck to do
and in between are just
a bunch of choices.
And that that was,
now I'm getting to that,
cause that was one of the key teachings
of this thing is just life is just a
series of choices.
So anyways,
I go,
I do this,
the Earth Massada medicine
and it's a much smaller cup.
He looks at me and I'm looking a
little fucking shady at this point.
Don't have that same big smile.
I managed some kind of smile,
pours me about half as much medicine and
then we're going to take another boat
ride,
go to see another tribe out in the deeper,
in the heart of the jungle.
So I take it and immediately
I'm just nauseous as fuck,
like nauseous to death.
Not Enough to actually make me Puke,
but it's just pretty brutal.
So we hop in the boat and
we're cruising down the boat.
And where I'm sitting in the boat is like,
I'm getting all this spray.
It was a windy day and I'm getting a
spray on my face and I'm thinking about
like monsters inside of me about
the fucking parasites in the Amazon.
I'm nauseous as shit.
I want to Puke,
but I don't want to puke because I know
if I puke I have to open my mouth and
then the water's going to get in my mouth.
And then I thought it was
going to get parasites.
So I'm in this like locked into this hell
just getting wet.
My eyes locked,
closed my mouth locked,
closed,
just nauseous,
like really nauseous for like 45 minutes.
And so we arrive in this place and I seem
to be the only one feeling like this,
everybody else's fucking cracking
jokes and they feel great.
So we arrived at this place and it's,
it's this entry in the young one.
They're like,
wow,
how beautiful.
And I'm like,
it's fucking not beautiful.
I see this Noni tree and
if you ever had noni fruit,
it's really kind of a nasty fruit.
It's good when they make it
an and health preparation,
but it's all rotting on the
ground and it smells like,
like a jock strap stuff with cheese.
That's what's sitting out in the sun for,
for eternity,
just baking and microwaving
over and over again.
I know that smell.
That's a really good,
that's a really good
description of that smell.
Just kinda like that,
right?
Like this funky ball,
sweaty balls,
sweat and cheese,
and there's pigs cruising
around and it's hot.
Just sweltering,
fucking hot.
And there's bugs everywhere.
And I'm just in like this little hell.
And everybody's like,
well,
look at the jungle.
I'm like,
fuck this jungle.
I'm like not feeling it.
And everybody,
everybody's on this walks were walking
in this tribe [inaudible] and they're in
this kind of Juba and like kind
of like I was the day before.
But whatever reason,
I got locked in this bad kind of space
and I realized I had a key realization
that I was,
I was feeling pain at that point.
I was in pain,
I was nauseous,
I was unhappy.
And so in my world I was closed off and
I didn't want to give anybody a hug.
I didn't give a fuck about the jungle.
I didn't care about the earth.
I was so focused on me
because of my own pain.
And I realized at that point,
that's what most of us are like.
We're in some kind of pain.
Sometimes it's physical pain,
sometimes it's emotional pain,
sometimes it's,
it's other pain.
And when you're in pain,
it's hard to give a fuck
about anybody but yourself.
Your natural instinct is to
kind of cover up and be like,
you know,
I'm fucking hurting.
Fuck you.
So you look at it like
all these youtube comment,
that's a key indicator to me
that those people are in pain.
You know,
that's why they're closed off.
That's why they're attacking
deep inside somewhere.
You know,
there's some pain undoubtedly,
undoubtedly.
And that pain forces more people to
reject them because that sort of negative
energy that they give off
forces more people to shun them,
which sort of reinforces
their bad opinion of people.
Yep.
And it's in this cycle.
And so while I appreciated that kind
of message I was walking through,
I was still like fuck this.
Like I hoped it would be
over when it was got there.
So we didn't even,
we get to this clearing in the jungle and
these beautiful tribal people show up,
but I'm just kind of shifting
nervously from side to side,
everybody else's off exploring,
finding like jungle snail
shells and collecting them,
adding to their collection and they
bring out this fruit and I'm like too
paranoid to eat the fruit.
And so all these different opportunities,
these choices come like they
bring out these jungle pairs.
Right.
And it's just like weird thing
that I've never had half an hour,
half like an apple,
half like a pear and everybody's
like orgasming over this thing.
But thinking like,
what do they wash
this with?
Like what's going on?
So I,
I like nibbled like a piece that I
thought was safe and like didn't touch it,
you know?
And so that was like one choice and
it made me not eating that I felt even
worse.
Like I felt more isolated.
I felt more different than everybody.
I was like,
I'm a fucking Weirdo.
Everybody's feeling great.
And so I started to get more and more
isolated and different things would come
up and an opportunity to
walk in here and you know,
experience this part of the forest.
I was like,
fuck that.
There's probably bugs.
They're so locked in this plate and
I just got worse and worse and worse.
And it was like the universe was
providing me these opportunities to do
something and I kept failing to pass the
test to finally I see this tree that is
pretty,
you know,
looked pretty good for
climbing and I'm like,
I'm going to climb this tree and
I'm thinking about it forever.
And I was like,
how am I going to get up there?
I'm still,
I'm pretty blasted and I see a big
spider in the nook of the tree,
which is going to be my original path.
I'm like,
Oh fuck it just fucking spider up there.
I'm not going to be able to climate.
But then I realized at
that point I was like,
all right,
this is a test.
I really want to climb this tree.
I can fucking figure it out.
The spiders not going to bite me.
And so I figured out an
easy is just super easy.
I just like hop a few branches
and I get up in the tree.
And then for the first time
that in that whole session,
the whole ceremony,
I felt like I passed a little test.
Like I did something that
I was supposed to do.
I made a choice that would
lead to my happiness.
So I started to feel a little bit better,
but then we go back up to the tribe and
they start dancing around and you know,
I really had this strong urge to take my
shoes off and just kind of dance around
because I had these big hiking
shoes are all muddy and stuff and,
but I didn't do it cause I was
worried about the mosquitoes.
Well little did I know.
I found out later that mosquitoes were
fucking biting me through my shoes
anyways,
so I might as well three shoot
through the webbing and my shoes.
He's lit me up through my shoes.
So I would have been better off taking
my shoes off and dancing around in the
mud anyways.
But anyways,
it's failed.
Failed that test again.
So I,
but I kind of get the,
get the game like,
all right,
I get it.
You're presented with tests.
You can either pass them or fail in
life is kind of a series of choices.
But I'm happy when we're
leaving the jungle.
I'm like,
thank God we're getting out of here.
I just basically took a beating from
my own mind the whole time I was there.
And as it was in doing that,
it was one of the most challenging times
I've ever worked with the medicine.
Because you know,
even at Boga,
which feels like hell,
I mean it's literal hell,
all you really are doing is just
completely surrendering to that hell.
You just lie on your back.
Like okay hell come on.
This one is such an active medicine that
you're presented with these challenges
and ask to do things in
a much more active way,
which is great.
But if you start getting
on the wrong side of it,
it can be really challenging cause you,
you have nothing to,
you know,
stop your mind from really running rampage
other than just this kind of gentle
guidance.
So tough experience in
the heart of the jungle.
When we get to the canoe,
I'm starting to feel a little better at
least passed one test and I climbed the
tree.
So I was like,
well at least I did that,
you know.
So we get there and
again,
it starts to be dusk and
that's when the vision start.
And um,
then that was probably
where I got my most,
uh,
one of my most powerful visions.
So I closed my eyes and I just bury
my hands and my head in my hands.
And um,
immediately I see this demonic face that
was made up of fires that were burning
and it's demonic face full of fires.
And then I noticed that it's plastics
that are burning in the fires.
And I looked at,
I'm like,
Oh shit.
And then I see that laid out on the
skin of what feels like a woman.
And it didn't have all the,
all the features,
but I could see like the
jungle was this woman's
pubic Bush,
you know,
like it was life coming out of her armpits
in and her vagina was all this like
jungle.
And in her hair was the desert and
her skin was like the planes and the
different things or the mountains.
And I got this real feeling of,
all right,
I guess I get it.
I'm looking at the earth mother.
But then the fires were burning all
over her skin and there was oil that was
being drawn out,
like,
like someone was taking big syringes,
like a malevolent doctor was pulling oil
out of her skin and then adding it more
to the fire and the fire's kept burning.
And it was this kind of,
this horrific image of this,
you know,
almost rape of this beautiful mother
earth that was presented it to.
And so I couldn't really shake it.
And I'm,
and I'm looking and I'm,
I,
you know,
I start to tear up a little bit and I say,
fuck,
I mean,
how can I help?
What can I do?
And then again,
just like with the altar,
like a really clear voice comes
and answers me and she says,
we don't have an environmental problem.
We have a consciousness problem.
It's like you work on the consciousness
and I'll take care of the rest.
And the way she said,
I'll take care of the rest.
I'll never forget that because
it had such fucking strength.
Like,
you know,
please like,
do your best work on the consciousness.
But don't worry about the other shit.
I'm going to protect myself
one way or the other.
Wow.
Kind of a really powerful moment.
And then what I saw there is what she
showed me or what I saw was people,
you know,
I would touch somebody and there was a
bunch of people and they would just be
kind of running around all haphazard like,
Eh,
I kind of just doing these
robotic motions in circles,
like a windup toy that was just haywire.
There was off balance or something.
Then I would reach out and touch,
touch one of these people and a
light would turn on in their head.
And instead of being
moving around randomly,
they would just stop and then look around
and then they would touch another one
of these wind up humans and
they would stop and look around.
And then slowly it started to connect.
And what it was showing was
the spread of consciousness.
You know,
you turn one person who's just locked
in their own fears and pains and worries
and the patterns and you know,
help show them consciousness and then
they'll do the same to somebody else.
And that's how this problem is going to
be solved and then all around the world
that just kind of all of these lights
started going off in people's heads and
connected and I got this image of the
utopia that the world could be where we
essentially in humans,
you know,
kind of aligned through consciousness,
are working,
you know,
to help prolong life
for as long as possible.
It's going to take a little time,
but I think within probably the next 20
years we're going to see a completely
different version of culture.
Yeah,
I really believe that.
I think that's that wave of touching
people and spreading it out.
It's already happened.
Yeah,
I see it.
I feel it.
It's online and it's moving in a way
that's just never had an opportunity to
move like this before.
The ideas that got passed word to mouth
by fucking hippies and poets and the
beat players of the 1960s the what?
They were so terrified
of what they squashed.
You know the acid and marijuana movement,
what they squashed?
They didn't have a way
of communicating back.
No,
they didn't have this fucking thing.
This is the craziest shit of all time.
This,
this Internet in conjunction with this
new found awareness of the psychedelic
experiences and the lessons that can be
learned from these psychedelic states
with it's,
there's a wave of a change
in consciousness that I've
personally experienced.
I know that it's not,
it's not an imaginary thing.
It's,
I mean,
yeah,
there's people that are holding back.
There's people just still still
still angry or still critical,
are still scared and you know,
I kind of feel for them.
You're not realizing what's going on here.
Like you can be pessimistic.
You can be,
you know,
you can get it into your head if you
really choose to that the world is this
terrible place of awful people and it's
more likely that there's just a momentum
going on that was created by people who
didn't know what the fuck was going on.
And we're awake.
We woke up like we're on a spaceship
that's headed towards an asteroid or
something and woke up going,
okay,
who's flying it?
How are you guys flying?
You're not flying.
Okay.
Um,
how much food do we have?
How much gas is in this fucking,
yeah,
totally.
Can we turn this thing around?
Where's the brakes?
How does it,
why are we moving in this direction?
Is there a reason we're
moving this direction?
Has Anybody thought this through it?
Especially
when you consider,
I mean the Republican right wing side,
like there was a very
interesting thing recently.
Bill Nye the science guy.
He's just a brilliant public speaker
when it comes to defending science was on
the show and on the show.
Um,
he got called uh,
uh,
science bully or something like that.
Or they were talking about
science bullying because,
uh,
they were talking about him talking about
global warming being affected by human
beings,
that it's pretty much a general consensus
of scientists that human activity and
the carbon footprint of human
beings has affected global.
And then the other guy was like,
well,
first of all,
I think his attitude was like,
we don't know exactly what it's doing.
And you,
what you're saying like these
regulations could harm business.
Like that guy for sure
doesn't do mushrooms because
if he had ever done Russia
mushrooms,
he would realize like that is,
you just said a crazy thing you just said,
we need to make money so we'll keep
poisoning the earth to make money.
I mean,
I know you didn't say it that way,
but that's essentially the equals.
You know,
if you put them in a
mathematical computation,
what you're saying is even if
it does poison the atmosphere,
we need it because we
need the jobs and your,
your considerations of the idea that
regulating something that's poisoning the
earth.
We live on that.
That could be somehow controversial
because that poisoning is profitable,
not we need to find other things that
are profitable of substitute it like,
yes,
this is obviously
something we need to stop.
We need to find a substitution.
No,
no,
no.
You could be harming business.
That same mine that can put together
that screen that's showing you the HD
version of those people having
that ridiculous argument,
that same technology
that that technology is,
there is a reason to figure it out.
They wanted and needed a reason to
figure out how to make this gigantic LCD
screen with an incredible resolution
and just vibrant crystal clear colors.
They wanted to figure out how to do that.
If they wanted to figure out how to get
rid of the garbage that's in the ocean,
that giant patch of swirling
deteriorating garbage.
If there was like an incredible
amount of of need to do that,
if people decided to focus all of their
scientific aspirations on fixing all the
problems on earth in a profitable manner,
it would be the biggest
industry of all time.
It would be giant.
We would run out of polluted
places because he'd be like,
shit,
we used up all the polluted place because
we figured out some new awesome shit
that turns pollution into clean air.
That gives you enlightenment.
We found some new air that'll let you
read each other's minds and that you,
you make it by burning out nuclear
fuel rods and some sort of a high genic
process with a dirty ocean.
Water purifies the ocean.
I mean,
they would come up with something.
Some fucking super egghead would come
up with some awesome shit and they would
figure it out.
The key is just the
consciousness has to come first.
Exactly.
Human Innovation is insane.
We send video through the sky.
Okay.
We were fucking sending pictures
to each other on a regular basis.
You know,
you can call him Dick Pics,
but what that is is magic.
That shit is fucking magic.
Sending Magic to each other and
that and that could figure it out.
Ultimately,
that is one of the thing.
That's the one thing that humans can do
that dolphins couldn't do or any other
of these creatures can't do on earth.
Let's say something fucked up was going
to happen to earth like we saw a big
asteroid coming in 25 Oh god,
it's humans who could figure some
shit out to like that fucking movie
Armageddon.
Blow that thing up.
Split it into,
I dunno.
Do you materialize it?
Whatever the fuck it happened.
Like we have machine.
Yeah.
Just keep going back in time
to five minutes before it hits.
We have the opportunity potentially to
use technology to protect the earth and
humanity at large.
And that's what I think all of
this whole technological thing,
why it's good and why it's necessary.
Otherwise we're just completely at
the mercy to these other forces.
I think the problem is,
is that as Albert Einstein said,
it's become appallingly obvious that our
technology has exceeded our humanity.
Like both of those things were
supposed to ride together,
like homeboys,
you know,
a motorcycle and a fucking Sidecar,
both of them right together.
And that shit got split off
by these oppressive forces,
you know,
state,
uh,
state forces and religious forces that
have kind of gone through and kicked out
any of these knowledge centers,
made illegal any of these knowledge plants
and reinforce this crazy idea putting
business above something like the earth.
That is absolutely,
totally possible.
But there's other options too.
And one of the weirdest ones to me is,
um,
that this all has to be in place in
order to move forward with this process.
It's going on right now.
This a process with people connecting
with technology that these all these
forces,
they seem to be moving.
I mean when you,
when you move warfare,
what you move is extreme
versions of technology.
That's the most important thing.
Like that was a biggest
part of the space race.
People said,
oh,
they put so much money into that.
That was an unnecessary,
do you know much military like how much,
how many options they got that they
didn't have before because of the space
race.
Just the innovation of
materials and the rockets.
Richer understanding of what they can get
away with flying things into orbit and
shit,
that's never going to stop,
man.
That's not going to stop.
It just,
it is what people do and sometimes people
need a a push to do it and along the
way they have to do battle with evil
and along the way they have to do battle
with suppression.
Like for the,
the gay people to get married in 2014 to
cheering throngs makes it all the more
sweets because it was
rejected for so long.
And I'm not saying there's
anything good about that rejection.
There's certainly not,
but I almost think that it all has to be
there like that and that we're in this
process of becoming something different.
We're learning about the
flaws of staying what we are,
that this relying entirely on the flesh,
relying entirely on these animal
instincts that we may or may not think are
beneficial.
We have this connection with them.
We don't want to separate,
we don't want to separate from jealousy.
We don't want to separate from emotion.
We don't want to be a
fucking computer program,
but that might be inevitable.
What we call technology
might be a life form.
It might be a life form that we're
giving birth to that we are some weird
worm that becomes a butterfly,
but we don't know it yet
and so we're just push,
push,
push and,
and we're full gay marriage
and pollute the air.
We're lightened plastic on fire and
steel and copper pipes out of abandoned
buildings.
I mean were the weirdest fucking thing
that's ever existed ever at all along the
way.
We're working on technology all along
the way where you could take the dumbest
motherfucker out there and he's
holding onto a Samsung galaxy s five,
you know,
we all along the way we're were giving
birth to artificial intelligence.
I really like your idea of
needing that resistance,
you know?
And,
and I think that's a great,
great wisdom in that.
And that the fact that things may be
are exactly as they're supposed to be,
you know,
at times I think they are.
Yeah.
And that's a,
that's definitely a cool thought.
And then the other thing about technology
is the point that I try to make as
often as possible is,
um,
these medicines,
that's exactly what the fuck they are,
is their technology.
Yeah.
So it's alcohol.
That's technology too.
You know,
like all,
every,
every one of these things is a technology.
Yeah.
Alcoholics causes,
it's kind of what somebody
figured some stuff out.
Shot of whiskey equals
this broken down for you.
Really simply.
It's right there in front
of him for people to people.
You have all these labels and memes and
ideas and the propaganda and bullshit
that goes to it.
Just look at everything is technology.
Alcohol is a technology,
methamphetamines or a technology watch,
humans,
the technology.
But what can that
technology reproducibly get?
Well,
with Meth,
it can get you to clean
your fucking house and see,
see fucking goblins and freak
out and become a stripper.
So that's reproducible on meth.
Like what's reproducible on what Juma,
what's reproducible on Iowa.
And you start to see patterns of how
this technology can be utilized and just
taking an objective look at that.
Yeah.
It's not a panacea.
It's not going to do
everything for everybody.
Nothing is,
nothing is,
it's just a technology.
It's like a phone.
You can call somebody a bitch on the phone
or you can tell him that you love him
and that you'll be there
by the side forever.
Like it's just fucking technology.
Yeah.
It's just a means to communicate with.
That's so true.
And that these ideas or this idea of,
uh,
an infield gin or what we would call
a drug being a technology and being a
method of,
of enlightening or a method of
opening yourself up to a whole new,
whole new dimension of possibility.
Like just a world that you step into
it and now your values have changed.
Like you're a,
you're a different person,
your values,
your ideas of human beings in general,
all those change and they change
in this really drastic way.
It's kind of unavoidable.
You know,
you just,
even if you become a dick
and you get mad at that,
mosquitoes are stinging in your feet.
You're still,
you know,
you're,
you're well who you are is not who you
would have been in those same exact
frustrating circumstances three years ago,
four years ago,
five years ago,
nor will I ever be again.
I think it was on,
you know,
when you came on my podcast
that I said that quote,
no,
no man ever stepped into
the same river twice for,
he's not the same man and
it's not the same river,
you know?
And,
and that's the case with these
psychedelic experiences even more so.
You know,
it's because who you
come there in general,
that metaphor works is
we're always changing.
Situation's always changing.
But you go through one of these ceremonies
and you just have this overwhelming
feeling that the person that you were
prior to doing it is not the person that
you've become nor the
person that you will be.
I mean,
that's going to continue to change.
Um,
but,
but things shift in a really dramatic
way that can be incredibly powerfully
positive.
Yeah.
And I think that the word is out.
People are telling people now it's
starting to spread back and forth.
I mean,
it's not just stories in the Internet.
I'm hearing people tell
their friends and you know,
hey,
we got together and we
did this and you know,
it changed my life.
And I mean,
I mean I hear it all the regular bank
and it's reaching different areas.
I was hanging out with
the Chicago Blackhawks,
the hockey team,
and these are hockey players
are from Canada and farm towns.
They'd been bashing each other and the
boards and skating around on the ice,
not the people you'd expect.
Who'd ever even heard the word Iowasca.
But somehow it got in the conversation
that I'd done a bunch of Iowasca
experiences and you'd
have these guys like,
oh,
I heard about that.
That sounds awesome.
I really want to go do that.
And you're like,
what the fuck?
How do you even know about this?
So it's reaching this
kind of critical mass,
which is really exciting.
Huge.
In the MMA world.
Yeah.
I know a dude who's a
shaman who's a trainer.
Yeah.
I don't think he wants to meet him.
I probably doesn't want
me to mention his name.
He's a legit Sharman.
I mean,
he's a cool dude.
Like you have conversations with them
and you're looking at this dude's eyes
like,
Oh,
you've seen some shit.
You know,
he puts on Iowasca
ceremonies for MMA fighters.
He'll take them for a
retreat in the mountains.
They have the spot that he goes to
and he cooks up the IOWASCA and just,
he thinks it's important for,
for being a fighter.
He thinks that a fighter to really truly
get in tune with who he is as a man,
that a psychedelic experience,
like an Iowasca experience,
we'll get rid of all that extra baggage
she's carrying around that he doesn't
need and it allow you to
perform as an unhindered soul.
I mean,
you may not even want
to continue MMA anymore.
That's the other problem with it.
You do something like Iowasca.
There's a very real possibility that you
don't ever want to hurt anybody again.
And I think that's,
that's a fear that a lot of people have
that they don't want to give up these
things,
but it's just your own minds truth.
It's not like Iowasca is
telling you that as I Wasa,
it's just allowing you to think
about something in a certain way.
So don't be afraid of that shit.
I used to be,
I mean,
this is going to be a ridiculous
statement and I'm prefacing it.
I have to admit,
I know it sounds ridiculous even to me,
but what I was first
starting doing comedy,
I wanted to make sure that I wasn't on
the path of enlightenment because if I
was on the path to be enlightened,
I saw it fucking up my comedy.
Right?
I mean it's a total ridiculous thought.
I mean it sounds like a cop out for
not trying to be more enlightened,
but it was a real legitimate thought.
Like I was like,
I was thinking about all the people that
I think are really funny and what kind
of fun,
what is their comedy?
What kind of comedy do I do?
I like that they do.
And is all this like crazy,
ridiculous drunkin you know,
these tirades and stories that were just
the most ridiculous sexual escapades.
Those are the guys that I
thought were the most hilarious.
And I'm like,
well,
there's no,
you got to drink.
Like you can't.
Like you can't be,
you can't be doing yoga
and eating vegetables.
Like do you have to
drink to be this funny?
Like this is a totally different thing.
And I and I remember thinking that there
was no way that you could be like on
the path,
like even thinking about it
enlightenment and still be funny.
I think the,
the way to think about that for me is,
and I think part of this
experience opened it up,
is being on that path to enlightenment
and restricting yourself from drinking or
having to be in a certain way.
It's kind of like that
shaman that's playing shaman,
you know like the truly enlightened
individual can decide and I think the
Toltecs had a word for it.
They call it your controlled folly.
You can decide to get wasted
and do something like that,
but do it in a conscious way.
I mean obviously doing something to hurt
somebody that's probably going to be a
problem with do things of course.
But you can choose to be
whatever you want to be.
You don't have to be a fucking
raw vegan meditating every day,
yoga kind of kind of person,
unless that's what you want to be like.
You can still choose and it's still a
path with heart and I think that's what
the true enlightenment is and will be.
It's not going to be
playing enlightenment.
It's just going to be
being there and deciding,
yeah,
we're going down this fucking Jack
Daniels hold today and we're going to see
what's on the other side of it.
Well that's why there's a big issue
with people who are trying to combat and
what they seem to be a negative,
like a,
a negative behavior or negative
attitude hate maybe perhaps that they're
combating it with hate.
Yup.
It's like it's the total
incorrect approach.
Like if you,
if you're faced with was
something that hates you,
mock it.
Yeah.
You know,
don't hate,
don't actually be angry.
Point out what's ridiculous about it.
And if you could point out what
[inaudible] about it successfully,
it can even be ignored by
the subject of your ridicule.
Yeah.
That's the beauty of it.
You can't ignore it if someone shuts
you down and makes fun of you and it's a
really funny way and
you look really stupid.
Like,
oh my God,
I do do that.
You know,
if someone,
by the ways he like we always do
the calendar by the way it goes up.
Fuck I do that.
He knows he does it.
Yeah.
You know,
that's,
I mean that's a bad example,
but that's when you're,
when you're trying to
stop hateful,
angry behavior,
the tendency is always to
meet it with a more hateful,
more angry response.
It's almost like instinct,
but there's strength in forgiving
people and there's strength in having a
frustration and an anger towards something
and then just completely letting it
go.
And there's a freedom in
that where you realize,
oh,
that was a choice.
That was a choice.
I was hanging onto this.
How many guys do you know that you had
like maybe a disagreement with or a beef
with or you were worried
about running into them like,
oh my God,
this better not get physical.
Like this guy better not
swing at me or something.
But then when you got there,
like you maybe said something that
explained your side a little better and he
said something and explain his side.
And then you hug,
like you shake hands and you hug and you,
and then woo.
What a relief that is.
What a great feeling that is.
When neutralize this acid you've been
keeping in this little file inside your
body,
you,
especially when it's just a misconception.
And when you can enlighten
that person or you can,
you know,
you can clarify what,
what was really going on or
what you had to do or why,
why you fucked up.
Or that's a nice feeling when people
just abandon the idea of being enemies.
But it makes you feel like what is
keeping us from doing this all the time?
And one thing that I had a,
I mean,
I've had a few experiences that
were pretty changing to me,
but one of them that was,
uh,
that I didn't expect was ecstasy to doing.
Actually,
I didn't think it was
gonna change me very much.
I thought it was just
going to be a party drug.
We're going to do some
ecstasy and hold hands.
Like I was holding my friend's hand,
Dude's hand,
we're rubbing fingers together.
This was the most ridiculous thing ever.
It's so like it would be
so homoerotic or so gay,
you know,
if we did that in a regular basis,
if we're,
if we're holding hands,
you better be a joke involved,
you know?
But when you're on ecstasy
it felt totally normal.
And then I remember
thinking after it was over,
like I know he's not gay and I'm not
gay like w but how come in normal life I
would never let that happen.
But in this state of,
of ecstasy when you're on
Mtma it's totally cool.
Hugging your friends is totally
cool and it's completely nonsexual.
And it made me think like,
man,
we're really insecure and
like the strangest ways like,
and that we don't even
recognize as being insecure,
sexually insecure,
physically insecure,
mentally insecure,
insecure I to whether or
not people really like you.
There's people out there that are
living their lives wondering if people
actually like them or if they're
just pretending to like them,
they're going to turn on them.
Men at any moment.
Yup.
I mean they,
they're going through life flinching,
you know,
these experiences.
That was one of the things with,
with the watch humor too.
I mean just hugging somebody who
you don't even hardly fucking no.
Yeah.
But it's just another human being and
it's like at the end of the ceremony
night,
you know,
just like,
hey that was,
that was cool.
You feel like you feel this connection
with that human being and it's,
it's so weird that we become dull and
we close ourselves off to all of these
possible expressions that are available
and these medicines are a great way to
kind
of open that up.
Yeah.
Well they are technology and they
have been used by people we know,
including yourself to positive
benefit to a positive result.
And that's just something
you can't ignore anymore.
You can't just tell
people they can't do it.
Cause you said right.
Does it,
you can't just do that
doesn't make any sense.
The only reason why this shit is
not in the United States of America,
first of all,
it's holding back our freedom.
Okay?
It is.
It's holding back our freedom.
It really is sacred freedom.
We have autonomy over us.
Well,
the road,
the only reason why human beings figured
out any things cause they had a freedom
to experiment.
That's the only reason
why language was invented.
If you could weren't allowed to say,
how about we fucking make a equals,
ah,
can we do that?
I was,
is this,
you know,
the only reason why anybody was allowed
to do that is cause you had freedom to
express yourself.
Freedom to try things.
True freedom to,
and whether the try that trying that
thing is creating a language or whether
it's figuring out that
psychedelic medicines allow
you to get a better grip on
your ego and how much your insecurity
in the futility of life itself becomes a
focal point instead of life.
The futility of life
becomes your focal point.
Oh,
what's the point?
There's not a point,
but it's going on right now.
When you're blowing it sun and it blowing.
It's like Angelo Dundee said to sugar
ray Leonard before he came out to knock
out Tommy Hearns.
You're blowing its sun.
Yeah.
You're going through your
whole life flinching.
Yep.
Very wise brother,
very when Chin and being angry at
people and he calling that angry.
Yeah.
That's,
that's the key.
And then,
uh,
that's out there that though
it is the secret's out.
I mean,
I didn't invent it.
It's fucking banging around.
Thousand years old.
You gotta you gotta dude holding the
fucking watch Houma stock it his head up
and it's hard for it.
And that's actually,
so to close out the earth ceremony,
they all have the shoving,
you know,
spiritual figures.
They're jagged,
they're turning into
Jaguars in their heads up.
And I didn't really understand that.
And He Gandalf doesn't,
you know,
Don Howard doesn't really tell you things.
He lets you try to figure it out.
So we go through and the night of the
earth ceremony was his kind of big
clearing night where he's working
on trying to clear the energies.
Um,
out of,
out of different people,
much like an ios Carol Wood.
So it gets to be my turn.
And uh,
and he,
he know,
he whispers,
he comes behind me and he says,
uh,
he says,
you're pure Chavez and
brother heart to heart.
And I was like,
all right,
and I could just feel
this kind of warmth and,
and intensity and what he was saying.
And he starts rattling is rattles and
a feather and he starts doing it on my
chest and I'm just sitting
there and for about 30 seconds,
nothing's happening.
And then I noticed my chest starts to
lift like more and more until my chest is
so far forward that I'm not
consciously doing this at all.
My chest is so far forward that I can't
help but tilt my head up to the sky.
And I realized at that point
what the message of that was,
was that,
so we lead with the
cerebral part of our mind.
Just thinking,
constantly thinking,
thinking,
thinking.
But really,
you know,
the best way to do it is to lead,
lead with your heart.
You know,
lead with that deeper knowledge that
doesn't require the magnificent calculator
that we have because it is a magnificent
calculator's great for computing,
innovating,
things like that.
But to chart the course for yourself,
for your friends,
for humanity,
charting that with that deeper,
you know,
empathetic intelligence that
you have at your core center,
which you call we call heart,
you know,
whatever you want to call that.
That's the way to really lead.
And he was able to kind of
get that through my head
and help me understand what
all these,
you know,
graphics,
these tapestries were,
um,
without ever having to say a single word.
And that's,
you know,
some of the cool things about working
with a real master like dawn Howard is,
he could have told me that.
Yeah,
they all have their head up
because their hearts forward,
their heads connecting with source
and their hearts leading the way.
Well,
he doesn't have to say that,
you know,
he can just kind of,
use the rattles,
use the feathers.
You,
you look at it and you just feel it.
So you don't need
hold narratative exactly.
Aeration.
Of the events
pretty clear what's going on.
Yep.
You know,
you just tap in and that same truth
that hit them 4,000 years ago,
we'll hit you.
Ooh,
that's so crazy.
It was fucking
awesome.
Awesome.
You,
do you believe that you experience,
you co experience other people's trips.
Do you believe that trips
are contained like a,
that was one of the,
the ideas that Mckenna had about any,
any psychedelic that
when you're taking it,
you're not just imbibing
in this one psychedelic,
you're actually experiencing all the
trips of all the people who've ever done
it.
That there's a shared space that
the trips live in and that's,
it's what you're doing is literally or
figuratively connecting to something
sort of another dimension.
I feel like that cause I feel like there's
a spirit of the plant now I will say
with non plant medicines,
which I've done a couple of acts,
he told some of those
stories in the last podcast.
I did not feel that with non plant
medicines and I haven't had a good
experience.
And I know there's a lot
of people like smoking DMT.
Well that comes from um,
that comes from extracted from the plant.
Yeah.
You can get synthetic,
you know,
they do like five men.
Have you ever done that?
I haven't done any synthetic.
Everything I've done is from
the extracted from Bark,
so I dunno,
I mean,
but,
but with the plant medicines,
I feel like you're connecting to your,
you're jumping in a lake that has been
there and has a resonance and everybody
else who swam in that lake
and left their stinking water,
you know,
they're beautiful,
stink,
whatever you want to call it.
You're connected with that whole
experience and it has an intrinsic nature.
Sure.
Sorry.
Here's something to consider too.
When you bring up this whole idea of
what is synthetic and what is natural,
and the reality is everything
on earth comes from Earth.
So it is all natural and a certain sense.
It has just been manipulated by beings.
The real question becomes,
is that not natural because it seems
like we manipulate everything around us.
You know,
when bees make honey,
they're manipulating things.
I mean we manipulate every God damn thing.
We get a turf and it does it.
Is it really natural?
If it be made it,
it seems like that bead
just sort of fucking,
well,
maybe it's just that that lake,
you know,
so the Lsd Lake got formed by
Albert Hoffman and whatever,
the thirties or whatever.
So it's like,
it's like 80 years old,
right?
So it doesn't have a lot of essence to it.
It doesn't have a lot of spirit.
I believe it probably does have a spirit
and maybe in 3000 years that LSD spirit
will be strong as fuck and the communal
experience of all that will be there.
But when you're doing something that's
grown and been alive and been in
existence,
it's had way longer to just kind of
feel and collect the energy of everybody
else.
It's been there.
Well,
that's when it had more of a power.
That's what it means.
Sense that it would have
these experiences in it.
Because the idea being that when
you're consuming a psychedelic,
and this is by the way,
if I'm butchering this,
I'm so sorry,
but when you're consuming a psychedelic,
the idea is that you are
becoming one with it.
That during that digestive process,
proceeds knows that I say process.
I sound cooler and
smarter process process.
I wish I was Canadian process.
Um,
as you're saying it,
I guess it'd be English
more than Canadian.
Um,
that this somehow or another,
when it connects to your bloodstream,
when it passes the blood brain barrier,
whether it's a silicide
been or whether it's,
you know,
any of these other psychedelic compounds
that you take in that during that trip
that what's actually happening is you
are changing your frequency and your,
your mind,
you,
whatever you call your
consciousness goes to another place.
What happens in the place where it's
at while it's happening is that while
they're all connected,
the idea that you have to
be in another dimension,
your mind's in another
dimension of your body's here.
That doesn't make any sense.
It does make sense because they're all,
it's a big crazy soup.
Yeah.
But it's a soup that
seems like you can only,
you can only access certain areas of it
when you hit this certain frequency that
you get by imbibing these plant cocktails
and whether they're synthetic because
they're based on the plants or
whether it's the actual plant itself.
What you're doing is you're tapping
into that next door neighbor.
You're just stealing cable from that guy.
You're like using his electricity.
Like,
whoa.
I mean,
it's almost like that you're,
you go into the next door
neighbor dimension and you
agree and all bets are off.
I think I
kind of look at it like you're a,
you're a shish Kebab and
you're going through an onion,
and so all of you and all the
potentials are that whole shish Kebab.
It's all aligned and infinite
onion of infinite layers.
And so doing these medicines
just move your consciousness,
which is like a dot on that shish Kebab
and move it up and down through those
different layers.
And that's,
and that's really kind
of what you're doing,
but you're still connected.
You're still that one,
you know,
infinite shish Kabob on a
fucking infinite piercing,
an infinite onion.
Your consciousness is just
kind of sliding up and down.
Oh my God,
that is what you're doing.
That the idea that you can somehow or
another in mid life alter and change,
like that sounds ridiculous to people,
but is it less ridiculous that you could
run into someone and they just lost 80
pounds?
I mean,
what happened to that guy?
If you're telling me that that guy didn't
make a drastic change in the path of
his life,
whether it's figuratively or whether
it's an actual drastic change,
like what you're seeing from that guys,
that he's,
his reality and his future changed.
His reality was he's a fat fuck.
He eats donuts,
he's gonna die fat,
and then boom,
he starts hiking and then boom,
he starts drinking water every day
and he quits all the soda and boom,
he starts eating fresh
vegetables and then boom,
he started fucking lifting
weights and working out.
He does Jujitsu.
He loses 70 fucking pounds.
It becomes a blue belt.
He's,
you know,
though,
that's a different human
like that is a guy.
How would this in the same world and
how many of those little changes that
happen during the day,
pro and con or this constant
river shifting thing and
the idea that time is this
linear thing and he got to get to 65 and
you got to get a four o one came back
and you'll have social security and
you're going to go into a box and life for
the unconscious robot versus that life
lived on the bleeding fucking edge of
freewill.
And that was what my
last ceremony was about.
The bleeding edge of freewill,
the Air Masada bleeding edge of freewill.
I gotta,
I got a bend that co pis,
that'd be the greatest
name for a punk band ever.
The bleeding edge of free will and then
we could solve the debate is who the
number one fucking drummer
of all time is Jamie.
That shit is erupted on Twitter.
People were apparently very upset
at the choices and drummers,
people take their number
one drummer of all time.
Seriously,
uh,
for folks asking,
we're probably going to wind up doing
one of those podcasts again that we did
last night.
The uh,
the fight companion while the
a UFC fights we're going on.
We got drunk and me Brennan Shop,
Brian Cowen and Aubrey watch
the fights and just talked.
It was one of the most fun podcasts ever.
Cause it was,
it was the for,
it was a podcast plus awesome fights.
It was,
it was a combination because it
really did flow like a podcast.
It's like subjects came up,
we talked shit to each other.
Brian gave out some disinformation.
It was totally like a regular podcast
and on top of it and on top of it,
they were awesome.
The fights going on.
So,
uh,
to the folks that asked,
yes,
we're definitely going to do that again.
Then I had a great time.
It was like,
it was a really,
it was a fresh thing and it made me think,
man,
I might like,
I might like doing that more
than I like doing the UFC.
I fucking,
I don't want to say it,
but it might've been better
because I could talk shit and be
completely free with my language.
We're talking about the fight podcast.
Last one was one of the most fun fight
watching events ever because we got to
just talk,
you know,
hang out,
have fun,
laugh,
joke,
Brendan,
shop toes,
all the various ways in
which he's shit himself.
Do you want to shoot yourself?
No Shit.
I fucking love that dude.
He's funny man.
He said some funny shit.
He cracks me up.
It's a nice fucking guy too,
man.
It's a,
it's a real pleasure when you meet
someone and the more you know them,
the more they constantly surprise
and delight you with what?
The Java sharp is awesome.
He's aces in my book.
He's a funny guy.
A lot of people give him a hard
time because he's real confident,
you know?
But guess what?
He's a goddamn professional
mixed martial arts fighter.
If he wasn't that arrogant and confident,
he would be,
you know,
I would really be suggesting
he tries something different.
This is not for you.
You have to be a crazy person to do
that job and he knows it and he's acting
like a crazy person.
You know?
It's just like there's certain versions
of the crazy person that people don't
like to see.
They don't see it like to
see the cocky credit first,
but it's the authenticity
of it that makes it real.
I mean,
cocky can be an act.
It can be that.
I got a big old truck with big old tires
because I have a little tiny dick kind
of mentality,
you know?
Is there anyone out there?
I would think that if you're a
big old truck and big old tires,
girls be like,
come on,
let me see that deck.
You know,
you wanted to pull up.
Call is least attention
to your dick as possible.
You would want like an old golf of
VW golf if you had a little dirt.
He just would not want to peacock it out.
Saw strong.
That's just my thing that
the word would be out,
but I don't know.
I don't know.
I've never looked at the deck of a man.
Big Tires next time.
Hey,
homework for everybody next time.
Next time I see a dude
with big tires on my,
come on son with that shut out.
Let me take a look at it.
What happened?
Alright.
Bleeding edge of freewill.
It's a great name for a band,
Blah Blah.
I like it.
I like that.
Anybody wants to take it,
go ahead and get,
I got no trade name for a band.
So final,
final ceremony.
The Air Masada.
And I know I have a vague idea that I'm
going to do something called Vielka,
but I have no idea that's
going to come in the night.
Um,
but anyway,
so we get there and I'm
feeling fucking great.
You know,
we had the good end of the ceremony that,
you know,
kind of lead with the heart.
I ended up sleeping well at night.
It felt great.
The next day was writing.
Everything is good.
Um,
so we go to their ceremony and,
and I'm,
I'm really feeling like 1 million
bucks as opposed to the last time,
um,
prior to that and he looks at me and
before he pours anything he gives you like
a long look and you know I gave that
same big old smile from the first day and
he gave a huge mile back and he starts
pouring and he just feels that cop to
that brim till the fucking Brim.
And I'm like,
oh my God,
I could at least eight ounces of
this fucking have this much humor.
And it's funny cause it seems like it
gets harder every time you take it.
Cause even watching like Donald Bear,
this bunk ochre and Darryl Sharman,
I mean he chokes it down cause he
does the watch whom are with us.
He chokes it down like
you know,
because your body is
like,
Oh God,
here we go again on this fucking
crazy rollercoaster into the cosmos.
But anyways,
I choke it down and right away like
the nausea is not there and I'm just
starting to feel good.
Not In that same kind of
uncontrollable way is the first day,
but just in this really kind of
positive good momentum kind of way.
And a,
I had brought up,
I've started playing this native American
flute and I'm not very good at it so I
was super self conscious the whole time
about playing it because there's nowhere
to do it privately and everybody
who would listen and I kind of suck.
I mean I'm okay but it bothers
you just suck at a flute.
Well just to like play it
and have everybody listen.
I Dunno,
I was self conscious about it,
you know,
cause I'm not good I guess.
But anyways,
at this medicine I was like I'm
starting this fucking test game off.
Cause last time I failed like every
test in the heart of the jungle.
On my second ceremony I was like,
this time I made a vow to myself,
I'm like,
I'm a pass every fucking test.
So we go there and take
the medicine are good,
we get ready and we're going to go on
a long hike this time instead of a boat
run.
So we have some time and I brought the
flute out and I started playing the flute
and I could tell as I was playing it.
Yeah,
I'm not great.
But people kind of dug it because I was
playing it as authentically and as good
as I possibly can.
And so that kind of for me started off
this first ceremony and the right way,
like I made a choice to go grab the flute
and I played it and it just felt good
to not be worried about that shit anymore.
Are you telling me you're starting a band?
Are you going to be the new Jethro?
JETHRO Tull was right a law.
I have two instruments
that I can kind of play.
It's a flute and a Didgeridoo and
they don't go together at all.
Perfect.
What are you talking about?
And just need the right mixture of drugs.
The right mixture of jugs in the flute.
That degree do is exactly
what you want to hear,
but
it's true.
So the prerequisite for the whole
audience would just be to be blasted on
something.
Paul revere type,
you know,
one of those real patriotic for faculty.
Those are the only instruments they
had like that kind of a tune and boy,
you
know,
we'll just highlight the
absurdity of our dimension.
Totally.
All right,
well I'll keep that in mind.
Yeah.
So scared of the flu.
So we start on this,
on this nature walk and um,
you know,
I kind of get the game that there's
going to be test presented and you pass
them,
you feel good,
you don't pass them,
you feel like shit.
So we're walking through,
I'm already not stressed about the bugs.
I got my,
you know,
instead of just big shirt and
all this crap all over me,
I'm just kind of in a tank top.
I got bug spray and I'm not
trying to be a fucking hero,
but I'm way less stressed about it.
And we're walking along and we have
this native guide along with us.
And then I see this really long black
millipede and then there's all this spin
hundred spindly legs all luckily
and riding in this weird pattern.
Normally that would freak me the fuck out.
So I see it and I pointed out to the guide
and she picks it up and lets it crawl
on her hand.
And I think to myself,
Oh fuck,
this is a test.
Like I gotta let this thing
on me to like pass this test.
Do not need to do that.
You need me to go with you next
time you go to the jungle and go,
hey bro,
how high are you about to let a fucking
bug that you don't know anything about
crawling on you cause you think
the universe has a test for you.
You're in the bunk house.
The only reason I thought it was
safe is because this guy did it.
But anyways,
and that going deep with
the wool and this and
at that point I had to,
I had to let it crawl on me,
I let it crawl on me.
When you did you ask any questions
about its toxicity or no,
the guy didn't speak
English so she was just
worked out.
It fucking worked out.
So sounds good there and
I felt good after it.
I was like,
okay,
I conquered that little fear,
you know?
And then we had another
chance to eat some cocoa pods.
And last time I passed out in the past
on the Kakapo thoughts cause I was
worried and I hadn't washed
my hands and blah blah blah.
I was all worried about this shit dude.
Do you have like a Howie
Mendell type thing?
I kind of did.
Yeah.
Like that was kind of like the,
it was me not trust in the mud
is worried about the malaria.
I was worried about the
mosquitoes was worried about,
so that was it.
So on this third,
on this third session,
you know,
the cook cow pod comes,
I was like,
all right,
it's another fucking opportunity to just
not be stressed and eat like all the
rest of the people.
So you dig your fingers in his kind of
gooey placenta [inaudible] fruit and then
pull out this pod.
It's like kind of like an embryo.
It's really weird and uh,
plopped it in my mouth and it was great.
It tasted delicious.
I could kind of feel a little burst of
energy from the cocoa and I was like,
all right,
sweet.
So I'm off to a good start.
We're headed up to the altar and I,
and I start to realize that life is just
a series of these choices and you can
either let you know fears that you've
had prevent you from doing this.
Like Howie Mendell,
like constantly living in a world where
he's afraid of all kinds of shit and
that's making him choose
this thing over this thing.
Or you can kind of go the other way and
choose not to be afraid of those things.
Yeah.
Recognize when there is danger.
I'm not saying don't recognize danger,
but to separate the fear from danger,
which will allow you a
broader spectrum of choices,
which will give you gifts of things like
the ability to eat a cacao pod fresh
out of the jungle when
you're blasted on what tumor,
which is something I was
afraid of doing last time,
but I wasn't afraid of this time.
So what were you afraid of?
Like taking it a parasite or something?
Yeah,
something like that.
Some kind of germs that are on my hand.
I don't fuck.
Is that really common?
Does that happen to a
lot of people down there?
Like what are the,
uh,
I mean,
you hear stories,
but I don't know what in relation
to how many people go down there,
those stories,
you know,
I don't know the statistics and
obviously there's some risk,
but there's also tons of people who are
going through a bunch of people in our
group that did it and refined bunch of
people go down there all the time and do
it and they're fine.
It's not like if a lot of people
were getting sick from that,
they'd cut that out of the program.
Yeah,
that's what I'm saying.
It's like people worry about
it and the worry about malaria,
like maybe,
yeah,
but do you know how many
fucking people going down there?
There's a lot of God damn people
going down there on a regular,
uh,
Justin wren.
Um,
he,
uh,
is a UFC fighter then,
went down there.
You guys send them a bunch of stuff.
He's into Alpha brain and he's the one
who's got that fight for the forgotten
charity for the people of the Congo.
And,
uh,
he got crazy sick down there.
He got some sort of horrible
in the Congo jungle bug.
Yeah.
I mean typhoid fever
or something like that.
Something nutty like that on gay fever.
But whatever.
Yeah,
it might've been,
that would have,
I was like,
he was on death's door,
like
really fucked him up.
You gotta be careful in some
places are worse than others.
Peru is in that kind of,
that still happens,
but it's still pretty benign.
And especially in this area,
that's a scary thing when you were running
a bug that can kill people like a flu
that,
you know,
it's just so,
it feels like a flu that's so much
more powerful than anything you've
experienced before.
You're like,
Oh shit,
I might not get out of this one.
That's what I was,
that's what I was terrified of.
And that's what was the resistance that
almost prevented me from having what I
will credit is the
greatest week of my life.
Um,
it almost stopped me from doing it and
obviously it's a week out and I'm healthy
as fuck.
And you know,
I made,
you know,
I assuredly the absolute right choice and,
and worked out,
but it is.
But again,
so that was kind of the message that you
just have a bunch of these choices and
accurately assessing danger versus your
fears and everything that you pile on
top is the key.
So we're approaching like the place
we're going to do the afternoon,
you know,
landing spot,
which is just kind of sky
deck overlooking the jungle.
And I wanted to take my shoes
off as I walked up there.
So I just fucking did it.
I took my shoes off,
didn't worry about the
mosquitoes and that felt great.
Just feeling the grass
and the mud on my feet.
It was a short walk.
So there wasn't any crazy
shit going on in the,
in the brush or anything
I had to worry about.
We get up there and um,
I go to lie down and I'd taken again,
I had taken the most watching,
might taken at any point ever.
So I'm more blasted than I had been the
whole trip because I got eight ounces
instead of sick.
And I go to lie down and I'm pondering
this idea of choice a lot and fears and
you know,
feeling pretty good because
everything that's happened,
I was passed these tests and I see this
little ant crawling towards me to am my
ride inside.
And I look and I go,
fuck,
there's an coming.
And so I totally broke
my train of thought,
stood straight up,
and then I look back at that
end and I just realized,
Holy Shit,
I just let that little fucking aunt have
the power over me to make me sit up,
lose my train of consciousness
and completely move on his behalf.
And it wasn't like a deadly
poison and it was just an ant.
And I then I thought to myself,
how many other of these little things
that are truly ants in our existence,
fears,
worries,
Paranoia's relationships?
Did you feel crunchy about in
this certain way or crunch?
Like something that's uncomfortable
to you in a situation or that you're
projecting and you're simulator is worried
about these little things that went
in reality or no more than these ants,
which are harmless,
caused you to make,
to choose actions that
aren't in your best interest.
You know,
and we,
because we give power,
we give them the power
over us to make us move.
They do have it.
Well,
I think it's what we were discussing
before that it relates to this is that you
truly can't appreciate your freedom unless
you're in some sort of a struggle to
maintain it.
It's a very strange thing.
Um,
and that these,
these things that you're
saying have this power over us,
we give them this power.
They're also causing massive amounts
of self examination and assessments.
Why there's this conflict
in the first place.
When you're conscious,
there's lessons to be learned in conflict
and that you realize the futility of
conflict.
And I think without those lessons,
when people are trying to nerf the world
and avoid all the con the conflicts,
we,
we lose the actual lessons that are
available in these life experiences.
And these lessons of understanding
the repercussions of shitty behavior,
the these understanding what true
violence is really all about.
Understanding how it can be turned around,
understanding,
watching guys hug it out after they have
a fist fight for fucking 10 minutes and
respect each other for it.
And I'm not saying you should do that,
but there's a reality of that.
Them hugging it out,
they're like,
okay,
well on a microcosm,
this works.
Like why can't this work
for the whole human race?
Because if we go to war,
there's no hugging,
you know?
But sometimes after you
Duke it out with each other,
you realize how ridiculous it is.
And that's better than war,
you know?
And people who would think that that's
savagery or that we don't understand and
like we'd have to stop all this
horrible shit that's going on.
Yeah,
we should definitely
encourage everyone to be nice.
But along the way,
the errors are where we're going to learn.
And that's a,
it's an integral part of
developing human consciousness.
It's a very important part.
The conflict is there so
that you can learn from it.
It's not there.
So that it shapes your life
and defines your future though.
And that's where people get fucked up.
That's where bullying is so
horrible because it gives them a,
an equation that they can't emotionally
solve their left in this deficit that
they feel it's futile,
they can't pull out of it.
And then they go into a
funk and it depression.
And it's because somewhere along the line,
someone almost in a way you
could say Stoller freedom.
Yeah,
stole their happiness.
They took it from them,
they took it from them with an act.
And you know,
I think we kind of recognize that as human
beings is just why rapists get beaten
up in prison.
You know?
I mean,
why,
why do they go after child molesters
in prison with such vicious,
vicious attacks?
Because their rec,
you
took something sacred.
But ultimately you have the choice.
All of these people,
however difficult it may be
to take that freedom back.
You know,
and,
and whether you can do it,
maybe you can't do it in action.
Maybe you're going to be subject to
somebody's doing something bad to you.
But you can always decide and
not saying it's fucking easy.
Not Saying I can do it,
whatever.
But you can always decide
how you let that affect you.
Whether that's simply an impetus of pain
or whether that deeply changes you and
is suffering.
And you see that accounts from different
people who've handled POW camps.
You know,
they're stuck in the fucking POW camp.
You can't escape.
And for some people or in,
you know,
in Auschwitz you see,
or you know,
different survivors talking
about different things.
Some of them,
you know,
it was pure suffering and they took
every single fiber of their humanity from
these people.
And some people were able to make a
choice that all they're doing is creating
pain.
But I'm going to keep my own,
you know,
my own sacred autonomy of what my
feelings towards that are going to be.
And at the very end,
that's the ultimate choice that we
always have is maybe we can't control the
input that's coming in,
but we can control our
attitude towards it.
And that's the last thing
that nobody can take from us.
And most importantly,
we can control our output and our
output is someone else's input.
And that's something that a lot of
people ignore or are not aware of when
they're doing something that ultimately
winds up being very damaging to
themselves.
They're not aware of the fact that
your output is someone else's input.
And if you put something
out that's a negative,
it's not going to come
back a positive ever.
It's just not,
it doesn't work that way.
If you put out a negative,
a negative that attacks a negative
just creates more negative.
It's just the only way it works.
And sometimes it's the only way.
That's the other problem
with being a human being.
Sometimes you're walking down an alley
and there's a bunch of people that are
going to fuck with you and there's
nothing you can do about it.
You can either let them beat you up,
you could fight,
you could run,
you could,
but you're going to have to
deal with a real live situation.
So there's no black or white in this.
Crazy world is not everything
that happens to you,
manifested with your
imagination and your intent.
No,
but a lot.
Yes.
You know,
it's not everything.
No.
But why a lot of it is how much work can
you get done in your lifetime to make
sure that less people experience
bad things in their lifetimes.
That is a real ripple.
And that ripple effect is happening
right now from someone listening to this
Garr Ron fucking deed.
I'm listening to your story,
listening to your depictions coincide
and then with their own instincts and
feelings,
maybe a few experiences that they've
had and then choosing an ethic,
you know,
and that that idea and that choice of
choosing an ethic can change the future,
can change the experiences
that people have.
You know,
if you look back on history and you look
back at the horrific things that the
Romans did and the Spartans did and all
these people did when they were going to
war with some other people.
If you look back at just the mounds of
awful stories that we could just go back
and find out about all the different
slayings that the Mongol Empire took part
in that the Romans took part in that the,
I mean just over and over and over again.
History of these horrific,
terrifying acts of humanity and,
and think about what it would be
like if we didn't know about those.
Think about what if they
happen and we didn't learn.
Think about what,
well,
it's terrible that they have
in it is definitely terrible,
but that we know that that
can happen ever is important.
It's important that we know that this
whole thing is just this chaotic scramble
for recognition of the state of,
of consciousness.
We're in this chaotic channel.
What's going on?
This is my land,
that's my pussy,
this is my goal.
Oh my heart,
start,
boom,
and then start all over again.
And then new bodies and your genes
pass onto another new meat vehicle.
It's carrying consciousness and it tries
to deal with all the stupid shit that
you taught it and like,
oh my God,
this mother fucker was wrong about
almost everything and now my heart stops.
Boom.
And then you hope that you taught your
kids a little something so they can,
like my dad was semi
retired most of his life,
but he told me when he started getting
older they realize the maze and he saw
that the,
the puzzle was ridiculous
because there's no solution.
And in the moment the,
this is the key,
the key is staying in the moment.
And then he died and then you
remember that from the jump.
So you go through life,
it's like quiet Chang Caine was a,
you know,
a modern day cell phone and
you try to figure out your,
your interaction with
all these people run.
But that we're a part
of this crazy ripple.
It just doesn't seem like
it because we're in it.
It doesn't seem like it because we're a
part of it cause it's just life to us.
It's,
you know what happens today
while I get up in the morning,
I turn on my computer and I find
out what's happening in the world.
Where's the new stories?
Where's the tea?
That's what I do.
But what,
what is that?
What is,
what does anything that you do in life,
what are any of these
patterns that you follow?
Are there any of these things you do?
It's just consciousness expressing itself,
trying to figure out what the fuck is
going on and trying to make and some sort
of an account of all the things that
are going on around you all the time.
Yeah.
Cause there's so many of them.
And then so these
things that seem to happen automatically
until you find a point where you
finally get to that ultimate stillness.
And you can do that in a float tank.
You can do that in a medicine journey.
You can do that in good
meditation or even yoga,
but to,
in order to properly chart
your course at any level,
you have to find that stillness.
But then the next level beyond that was
right where I'm at here in this story.
So Don Howard comes over
to me and he starts,
you know,
doing it,
seeing,
asked me to Neil and he starts using the
feather over my head and I could feel
like a weird transformation
happening in my body.
This kind of invincibility that
I started to feel at that moment.
And it was this strange
kind of feeling of,
I was kind of crouched over the top of
the jungle and I started to feel like it
Kinda like a rumble in my throat,
almost like a growl and I could
feel like my toes start to grip in.
And it was almost like I was transforming
myself then into this big cat that was
out looking over the jungle
and had absolutely no fear,
you know,
nothing.
The mosquitoes couldn't hurt me,
my other fears wouldn't bother me.
Death was no threat,
you know,
like nothing at that very moment,
could actually harm me.
And I realized at that
bleeding edge of invincibility,
at that bleeding edge of fearlessness,
not that a bullet couldn't kill me,
I'm not trying to be crazy,
but how I felt then,
you know,
was completely without fear.
For the very first time in my life,
absolutely nothing scared me.
And at that point that I realized that
was the only time I've ever had complete
free will because only at the very edge
of your fearlessness is nothing pushing,
pulling you,
prodding you,
you know,
you have no attachments to anything cause
you're not afraid of losing anything
because losing anything wouldn't hurt you.
You know,
you're completely fearless at that.
I was completely fearless at that point.
And that was the very first
time I had complete free will.
And that feeling is
something I'll never forget,
you know?
And I realized that all of these people
that talk about the determinism of life,
oh,
it's genetic.
So it's environment and it's,
you know,
there's a place that you can get to where
you have absolute choice and maybe you
can't stay there.
Not saying that I'm like that now.
I mean,
uh,
but I can remember that fucking place
and I can remember being completely 100%
fearless and knowing that I could choose
anything I wanted in my life and it
would be my authentic choice.
Not pushed.
You're prodded by any other factor.
And that was perhaps the greatest
gift I've ever gotten in my life.
And one of the reasons why this trip
was maybe the best thing I've ever done.
That's some deep shits on.
Yeah,
I'm all,
I'm taking it all in.
Right?
That's some deep shit.
I want that.
That conversation is very puzzling to me.
And I've heard people,
some people say that it's,
it's very simple.
It's very simple.
Free wills doesn't exist.
It can be proven and proven by tests.
Well
then how come you decided to go on a diet?
Like what happened there?
I,
you know,
and I know this is a retarded version
of the actual events and I know that
they're scientifically proved in
some form or fashion that you,
your decisions are decided for
you before you ever decide them.
Uh,
not buying it.
I don't know how the fuck,
you know when someone decided it,
part of their brain was lit up or an
impulse and you know that that represents
consciousness to 100% extent that you
know that that's not the origin of the
very thought itself,
that it comes and ripples and affects
different states of the mind at different
times in the decision.
Like are you absolutely sure?
I do not believe that the,
the,
the data is like that conclusive yet.
And from what I experienced,
I can fucking tell you with assurity,
I would put anything on the line
that that is fucking nonsense.
By the way.
I have no idea what I'm talking about.
A know nothing about neuroscience.
So everything I say
saying they six seconds,
they're saying that
six seconds for choice,
six seconds before a choice,
something triggers in the brain.
But how is that possible?
If there's some choices
that you make immediately,
they're less than six seconds.
Yeah.
It doesn't make
any sense.
Shit.
No.
What is that?
Is that freewill?
Yeah.
No it's and there's no
free will come on son.
From what I experienced there is fucking
freewill and robbing people of that.
Robin is one of the things
that are the most detrimental.
I think it's a semantic,
sorry,
our argument because I think the idea
of is there a completely free will?
Well then what is it?
What are you saying when
you're saying freewill?
I mean,
are you free of emotional baggage?
Are you free of memory?
Are you free of genetic memory fears,
all sorts of phobias that may or may
not have been passed down through your
fucking DNA and you don't even
know why you're crazy about them.
Are you free of all that?
No ma'am.
Not necessarily,
but can you decide,
you know what?
Fuck this man,
I don't like this shit.
I need to get my fucking life in order.
Can you make a choice?
Write something down.
Make a choice.
What is that?
That's not free will.
I don't understand it.
I understand your argument.
I can understand what you're saying
about there's some things going on in the
brain that determined decisions before
the person believes they decided before
they actually have consciously
realize they decided,
but isn't that like what,
how a decision works?
I mean I obviously,
and I keep qualifying this,
but I am almost retarded,
but if you're having this
sort of conversation about
anything else other than
the human mind,
like if it was about a computer program,
it'd be pretty traceable.
You'd be able to trace the code.
You'll be able to see where
the sequence takes place,
where's the,
where's the variation,
what's going on,
where you could watch this
deviation or this path,
but with a human mind like,
God damn,
there's a lot going on.
It'd be in a person and making decisions,
changing your mind,
what's changing your mind?
The thing that these neuroscientists
are failing to recognize is there's,
there is a human mind and the thing
these neuroscientists are failing to
recognize that'll be,
that'll be a meme.
Well,
I think made me,
some of them do,
but I firmly believe and I've been,
I've experienced this,
that there is the mind and then there's
another thing called consciousness and
that consciousness,
it works through the mind and
it's in your connected with it,
but it isn't just the mind and it's the
consciousness aspect of you where the
freewill resides.
So the neurologist neuroscientist may be
able to prove via the mind all of these
different facts,
but the consciousness is ineffable.
I,
um,
I have a soft subject to test.
I have a similar take on it,
but slightly different in that,
um,
I do believe that the issue might be in
just labeling it something with these
feeble human words.
Sure.
I think that might be the issue in
calling something consciousness at all.
I think whatever it is that you
experienced in the psychedelic state,
you're not qualified to
describe and you're not
qualified to cast a judgement on
what revelations that you're a little
puny mind makes when you're over there
because you're in the EXP,
you're in the,
in the,
the face of something that's
so impossible to believe.
So impossible for the imagination to
conjure up that it defies all your silly
little words.
So when you start saying things like,
you know,
we start using in a sense
that we use it to sort of laid down a
scaffolding of ideas so I can understand
what you're talking about.
But I don't know what that means
and I don't think anybody does.
That's why someone who's been doing it
for 50 years isn't going to try and tell
you.
They just act to show you.
Yeah,
they don't need to like,
this is consciousness,
but this is the soul.
Hey Man,
I'm not sure you're right.
You know,
I think the whole thing might be together,
you know,
and that we have these ideas of labor.
This is the human brain.
And guess what?
The human brain is
touching the whole thing.
The human brain directly touches
the center of the fucking universe.
Do you know why?
Because there's no empty space.
Even in a vacuum.
There's stuff out there.
There's dark matter.
There's,
there's fucking air on earth.
There's a direct connection
between some thing,
some Adam's,
some objects,
some physical,
some gas,
some thing connects,
everything.
This idea of space is a
really relative concept,
and if you really look at it,
no,
no.
You're the bottom of the universe,
which is an ocean.
The,
Oh,
it's an infinite ocean.
It's the idea that there's all this air.
No,
there's just,
it's just different stuff.
Like it's still all connected.
The whole thing is a big soup,
the whole thing.
And you don't get away from the big soup,
the ecstasy of dichotomy.
Yeah.
I mean,
this server,
that means gaps in the
cheese here and there,
but ultimately it's all connected.
Connect,
spiraled,
like,
you know,
I mean,
look,
you can look at a fucking
sponge and you could say,
is that thing connected?
Well,
I mean,
so there's a lot of holes in it.
You know,
this is a fucking,
it's connected.
There's a beginning and an end.
Shut up.
Stupid.
He'd get it wet.
The whole thing's getting wet.
It's fucking connected.
It doesn't matter.
Your holes are in there.
That's you and the universe.
That's you and the universe
are like I fucking sponge.
Like you're not getting
away with anything.
Your brain,
your consciousness,
your mind,
they're all the same thing.
It's all the universe.
We just have compartmentalized our biology
and these very specific ways in our
attempt to understand
what the fuck is going on.
As we wake up at the front,
we'll have this spaceship
as it hurls into the sky.
Like what is it?
Okay,
this is the brain.
Agreed.
Okay.
It's all the brain.
The brain is independent of the spinal
cord and when the spinal cord is severed,
the brain can no longer communicate.
I'll great.
Oh Great.
And we figured out how this
little biological creature works.
Boom.
While this creature is just a reacting
part of the soup of the universe,
slowly getting to try to understand
itself during this very brief,
finite in obscure existence.
It's a part of the infinity and it's all
just popping off while you're trying to
figure it out as it's happening.
That's us,
man.
Indeed.
Well I want to tell the story of the
[inaudible] cause that's the finals is the
DMT snuffs.
So we leave the thing,
the days of the other.
Yup.
So this is the same night.
So I leave the Aleve,
the temple.
I,
I'd felt myself feeling like a big cat
and that feeling of fearlessness,
bleeding edge of freewill,
that experience go down.
I'm feeling just fucking
amazing at this point.
I'm like,
wow,
this is awesome,
but I know we're going
to do the [inaudible].
And the way Don Howard
described it is he says,
you know,
tonight we get a chance to go home.
And he just said it just like that.
And,
and he didn't need to
say much more than that,
but you knew that it was,
he's like,
if you do it right,
you'd go home.
And I was like,
whoa.
All right.
And at this point I had just such immense
faith in what he was doing that I,
I was like,
all right,
this is going to be pretty significant.
So walking into the hut,
I put into practice what
I'd learned up there.
And usually on the way to the hut.
I was like someone,
you know,
scurrying from one Fox holder the other
cause I was worried about mosquitoes and
I was like,
I'm going to just walk into this
fucking hot at my pace when I want to.
I'm not going to let the
mosquitoes bother me.
And little choices like
that we're already wasted.
I was putting into practice
this knowledge that I got,
which is why I love to
watch humor so much.
So I take my time,
walk into the hut,
take a seat.
And uh,
he brings out the,
the snuff,
the snuff tray in the snuff,
um,
tube basically.
But to snuff tube is not
just a normal snuff tube.
It's a 4,000 year old.
Well,
it looks like a human metatarsal bone,
like a bone from the knuckle bone from
your foot that's hollowed down the center
that the shoving people themselves
had used to snuff the VILC,
uh,
some 30,
500 years ago.
And the tray itself that held the,
the,
uh,
the [inaudible] was 3,500 years old,
used for exactly that purpose.
And he smiles to us and he says,
now this thing is used,
it's not new.
And he just kind of smiles and we chuck
a little bit and still at the very edge
of doing this most intense DMT experience.
You know,
he's got a little chuckle and a laugh
and that was one of the beautiful things
of this.
So anyways,
this guy goes before me and he's kind
of struggling with it and having a
challenging time and he
finally gets some down.
And then after you do it,
you're supposed to go to your room
and how do they get it up your nose?
So you put the,
so yeah,
I'll tell him when I'm going.
So I hop up there and I
look at it and it's the,
it's hollowed straight down the middle.
I don't know how they
did this without a drill,
but it's like this,
you know,
hall,
I guess they had something,
they just twist it
until they went through,
when they start a fire stick.
So it's like a knuckle bones but as
longer and it's hollowed straight down the
down the center of it.
And so you put the knuckle in your nose,
one knuckle in your nose and then the
other knuckle has been cut off in a
certain way that lays flat in the tray.
And then it's this bunch of
brown powder that's all in there.
And you basically just in one nostril
and then in the other nostril as as hard
as you can go.
Whoa.
And so he gets up there and he,
and he gives it to me.
I put it in my,
you know,
I got a big nose so that helped out.
So I stick the knuckle in my nose
and I just take a rip in one nozzle,
take a huge rip and the other nostril.
And at that point,
I mean burn like hell,
but more than that it felt like you ever
watch the old Highlander when he cut
someone's head off and he is like
absorbing the soul of the vanquished foe.
It was like the most incredible power,
like coursing through me.
I was like,
Whoa,
like just shaking.
Like lightening struck me or
w I was really crazy feelings,
a painful feeling.
And at the same time it's
burning at the same time.
Intense DMT trip.
Well not yet.
So it didn't kick in the DMT part,
but just something electric happened.
Like I just got hit with lightening,
like my body knew like,
oh fuck,
like something crazy is going to happen.
So Don Howard just looks at me and he
knew I got a bunch of it and so he goes,
you better go to your room and just
kind of said that with a smile.
And like I take off out of the hut and
I go to the room and everybody else is
going to go.
So I start lying down in the bed.
It's completely dark.
I got a blindfold on and um,
you know,
the snuff still kind of burning a little
bit and then a pretty familiar DMT
experience starts to happen.
That kind of chrysanthemum of energy,
except it's way fucking
thicker than I've ever seen it.
I'm used to like seeing it in
above me in this kind of thing.
But this was completely threw me like,
it wasn't like I was
looking at it like I was it.
I was this nexus of energy and lights
and spider web and there was really no
separation between me and it,
which is an experience
that I've never had.
I've always kind of known
myself and then this other,
and I was able to kind of look at
the other as myself this I was like,
oh fuck,
I am becoming this thing.
I am not really myself anymore except
occasionally things would happen to my
body.
I'd be like,
okay,
body is still there,
but it was in this weird like it was
in another room or something like that.
So that happens and it,
and I kind of pass through that
section and then I find myself in this,
you know,
all that whole nexus of
light chrysanthemum whatever
that DMT thing is gone.
And I find myself in this room with a
bunch of different spirits and one is like
this Harry hippopotamus
looking frogman with a staff.
And then there's these
other figures in hoods.
And then there's these figures all
around me and I feel like I'm in this
neighborhood bar and everybody's
kind of looking at me like,
the fuck are you doing here?
You don't belong here.
So I say,
I say,
you know,
if it's in the greatest good,
if anybody wants to speak with me,
you know,
please do so.
And all the,
all the spirits just
kind of look at me like,
hmm.
Not,
not in a mean way,
but just like,
man,
I ain't got shit for you.
So I'm sitting there for a second
and then I say grandma year.
And uh,
and uh,
so,
um,
you know,
I was really close with my grandma.
She's on my tattoo here.
And,
um,
I asked for,
I said grandma here and to my left.
Um,
she started approaching in the most
familiar way that I remember probably from
when I was 10 or 12 in that kind of form.
I remember the clothes she
was wearing and her face,
and now everything was,
and she said,
hey,
Aubrey.
And in her voice.
And I held out my hand,
my left hand,
and she grabbed a hold of my hand and
I could feel it just like her same
weathered hand used to be when
I would hold her hand as a kid.
And we started talking and we
talked for a few minutes and then,
um,
you know,
said we loved each other and I said,
grandma,
I got to go now.
She said,
yeah,
I know and I let go.
And um,
and she left.
then I started the process
of coming back into my body.
But how real that,
that moment was,
you know,
I mean,
you could say it's all in my mind and
it was a projection of my grandma,
but I could feel her fucking hand.
I could hear her voice and
I know what she said to me.
And what doesn't matter what anybody
wants to try and explain that,
you know,
that was my grandma.
That was her.
Well this is a very touchy subject for
people cause people love calling bullshit
on these kinds of stories.
Yeah.
But this is what's really important.
It doesn't matter whether or not it
was a hallucination or whether it was
actually your grandmother is
the exact same experience.
It's still is.
That experience was that is what's really
crazy about a psychedelic is that it
may be able to bring
your grandmother to you.
It might really be able to do that.
Like that might be real if
it might be a hallucination,
but it's the same experience.
It is.
Your grandmother came to you that that's
a really weird thing for people to
adjust to.
That the idea that there's more than one
possibility going on here and the ideal
that you don't have to debunk this.
Like you don't have to debunk
something first of all,
that you haven't personally experienced,
and two,
that it doesn't matter.
Like the debunking is not important.
It's very important not to get caught up
in some crazy woo woo like faith healer
nonsense.
It's,
you're right.
It's very,
but if you really don't believe him,
take it yourself and until
then shut your mouth.
I understand you're trying to be all
scientific and everything and I understand
that.
You know,
I take offense with these
pseudo scientific explanations.
What,
what can it be easily
explained by modern science,
the workings of the human mind?
I don't think so.
I don't think we finished.
I don't think we've even dipped
our toes into what the fuck.
Being a conscious entity in the universe.
Really.
Truly,
yes.
I don't think we have.
And so for anybody,
you know,
I didn't have any of this kind of kind
of unfinished business or anything.
It was just an amazing
opportunity to connect with her,
you know?
But for me,
the change,
the truth of that experience,
you know,
for someone who did have and not that
this happens to everybody and this is
reproducible and you go
in with this expectation,
I'm going to do Vielka and talk to my
dead relative who I wanted to say I love
you too.
That may happen.
It may not.
So don't go with expectations.
But for me that's,
this is my experience and this is what,
what happened to me in this,
in this vilc of ceremony.
The idea that that see when
people say is it reproducible?
Yes and no.
DMT is reproducibly ridiculous,
but if you think that the exact
same experiences reproducible,
what you are ignorant of is
the catalog of possible events.
Stop and think of that that catalog
of possible events is infinite and the
universe of DMT dimension,
the DMT experience when you tap into
that would it really truly represents is
something you had no idea you could ever
even think up if you're just thinking
it up,
you had no idea it was there and
it becomes infinitely more complex.
The more you pay attention to it and
it's never ending and it can change
constantly.
And,
and the sameness in my little feeble
attempt at using a human language to
describe this experience is so useless.
It's so,
it's so silly.
But the point is that along
the way you realize that yeah,
you could probably reproduce it,
but it doesn't matter because this is not
the same thing for a 10th of a second.
Yup.
Every 10th of a second it's a new
thing and it impossible new thing.
Like,
okay,
now I understand.
Well there's these colors
and the iseries chat.
Oh,
what the fuck is this?
what is this?
This is the new thing,
right?
This isn't even possible.
This can't be real.
Oh my God,
this is crazier than that.
This is,
and it just keeps going
and it never stops.
It's con you can't catch up.
You can't,
you can never cattle catalog at all.
You can ever say,
why don't we have got a very clear catalog
of the possible effects of being on
dime metal trip terrain and Oh,
I'm,
or you went to page 54 now this
is on page 54 bitch just doesn't,
it doesn't end a book and you
don't have it in your head.
You don't have the database.
It's you don't have,
it's like,
you know,
it ain't trying to figure
out how satellite works.
It doesn't matter.
She's a fucking,
it's so,
it's so out of your world.
If it falls out of the sky
and hits you in the head,
it's the only time you should
ever worry about it until then.
Carry on.
Totally.
You're not already.
And so the cool part,
you know,
with the smoking of the DMT,
it's the kind of this in and out.
This was stretched out over,
you know,
40 minutes and it was a long
way kind of back from that.
You could maybe call that the peak.
A lot of other things
happen and I actually,
one of the things that I have going on
in the psychedelic experiences as I have
kind of like a recorder almost,
it's like a stress of consciousness that
consciousness is another weird word to
use,
but a shred of mental capacity that I
keep open to record this and store this
information.
One of the reasons why I
can tell these stories,
remember what,
as I was coming back from that place,
I could feel that thing.
It was like almost like knowing that
these microphones are on or something,
you just have an awareness that it's on.
And I remember consciously being like,
I got to shut this off now.
And so for the first time in any
of these psychedelic experiences,
there's a good period that I don't even
recall and I couldn't even talk about
here.
But what I can recall is as I
was coming back even closer,
um,
I could see a lot of these attachments
onto my body is I was kind of from a
bird's eye view,
different things,
different relationships,
different other things that had know
attachments to this form or attachments to
this idea or attachments to that.
And I just was able to just clear them
all away and you're just kind of move
through with my breath and my hand and,
and just kind of cut all these little
hooks that were in my body and then just
found myself coming back in
and just marveling at the
magic of this machine that
we have,
you know,
like hands that could squeeze.
Yeah,
yeah,
exactly.
Exactly.
She got,
you got hands in that tongue debt,
you can move around.
I remember moving around
like some wiggle toes,
it wiggle and in that process I
remember I started singing a like a,
like an eco,
like a little song like,
oh no,
no,
I'm on,
I'm a total nonsense gibberish.
But it just started to come out and I
was singing that as I was getting back
into my body.
And,
uh,
I remember I was still singing and I
maybe I was seeing a little loud and I saw
this vision of this woman in this kind
of crystally gown comes up and she smiles
at me and then puts her
finger to my lips like,
hey,
sure,
sure.
That's a great way when you're tripping.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
did you want to talk to her more?
No,
she was just there to tell
me to shush cause I was like,
okay,
I'll shush now.
It's always a chick.
Yeah.
It's the Yin and Yang,
you know,
either Alfalfa had a fucking
shitty group of friends that he,
man,
woman haters club in little rascals.
It's terrible bullshit.
You don't want to be in the
Heman woman haters club.
We could all get along.
Well they stopped [inaudible]
southern hut got built,
bitch.
Yeah,
I'm excitable.
So yes,
I get back in my body and then
I walked back into the hut.
I was one of the first to do the snuffs
was one of the first back and I sat and
he asked me to sit in his chair
and then look at the alter.
And I remember just looking at the altar
and just kind of merging with one with
the center of the altar and
realizing that the core of my center,
that kind of,
that principle of nonduality that you
talked about touching every part of the
universe,
the core of my being really started
to merge with the core of that.
They'll none zone in the middle.
And I just felt unbelievably connected
with the entire universe at that point.
Realizing that within me
is that same connection is,
is within that.
And,
and then that was pretty much the,
uh,
the wrap of the ceremony.
You know,
we,
uh,
we all got kind of back in
and candles burned out and,
uh,
had a feast,
ate some Cayman,
some alligator at the end of that night.
And I think came in,
he came in as a crocodile,
right?
Is it came in and correct the difference
between the way I'll get her taste and
Kroc came and tastes delicious.
It's kind of like a tougher chicken.
But anyway,
so we finished that off
and go have a feast and uh,
there we go.
And,
and really the last kind of
words from Don Howard is he's uh,
you know he told me as I was leaving,
he says,
you know,
is renaissance time and
that's what he believes.
It's time for a new renaissance,
spiritual and responsible
consciousness renaissance.
And he's out there,
Johnny Appleseed and this motherfucker.
Yup.
He's been holding it down for 50 years
waiting for waiting for word to get
critical mass.
I think it's out there.
Do you think its critical mass now?
It's getting there though.
What do you experience,
what's the difference
in your life since uh,
you know,
you feel like you've been
exposed to these ideas.
So now at this point I
have the roadmap back.
Anytime I get in a,
in a weird situation,
I'm not immune to fears and I'm
not immune to worries and concerns,
but now I can see them and I can choose.
And I can almost say,
okay,
I recognize you,
I see you coming.
But I also remember a truth,
so much deeper that I felt and while
you may pester me for a moment,
I'm going to find my way back to
that eventually cause I felt it,
I saw it.
I chose to be that way.
And for me because of how
active this whole ceremony was,
knowing my way back to that
feeling of fearlessness,
knowing my way back to that connection
with the center of the universe and the
lessons about reciprocity
and all of these things,
I just have the fucking roadmap to find
my way out of any kind of maze or worry
or concern or situation.
I know there's still going to come up.
They're still going to
kick my ass occasionally.
You know,
resistance is still going to get a foot
hold every now and then and when for an
hour wind for a day when?
For a week,
I don't know,
but I'll kick its ass eventually because
I found the way and I've seen what is
capable for me and what I want to be.
As you get older,
do you find less and less
battles with that shit and more,
a little more smooth sailing?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I do.
Um,
I mean I like everyone experienced
similar moments of a malcontent or similar
moments of a lack of ambition.
You know,
I find a way to fight them back.
And a,
I think that one of the big things that
I keep harping on and that we harp on a
lot at on it is take
care of your meat wagon.
Fuck it has a big effect
on how your brain works.
It has a big effect.
The other day I did a Kettlebell workout,
I did a chin ups with a weight vest
on and ankle weights and then I did 10
rounds of the heavy bag while
the fights are going on.
So I did a renegade rows
with the kettle bells.
I did a alternating cleans,
I did clean presses and then I did these
weighted chin ups and then I just had a
ruthless savage bag workout.
And after all that shit was done,
you couldn't bother me.
It's not possible.
And anything you would say.
I would find curious so he could be like,
you blog a douche bag.
You can say stuff that totally
mean to me and be like,
well you got an issue.
I don't know what it is,
but I'm not really interested.
I got to go see him like you.
You have a bank of bullshit in your body
and if you could blow that out in the
gym,
man,
and this,
that's a lesson.
If you want to talk about something that
I need to learn over and over and over
and over again,
although I know it,
although I have espoused it,
I still need to see it in action because
sometimes your ego and your body get a
little tricky and he'd
take a few days off,
take two,
three days off.
You're like,
I'm fine.
I don't need to work out.
I don't need it.
I'm busy right now.
I'm handling everything very like you
don't even realize like you're on the
verge.
You're on the verge of stepping into
that new or that next sort of vibration
that a little bit more hostile vibration.
You can pull that back.
You could easily pull that back.
But if you don't do that,
if you never do that,
if you never take care of your meat wagon,
boy you don't know man.
You don't know there's a,
I was high as fuck after that workout.
After that workout was,
I was high like I was.
I was floating like it was filled with
endorphins and everything was beautiful.
I went outside,
I sat down in the backyard,
washed when chickens run around,
and I was like,
the world was filled with love.
I might as well been smoking weed.
I'm serious.
I was high as fuck.
Just stretching,
you know?
I mean,
it's gotta be similar to like psychedelic
effects of yoga when you're just
completely stressed,
relieved,
and then stretching out
and just taking in nature.
It was gorgeous.
It was beautiful.
It's just like a drug man and people
who don't exercise that option,
just do it.
It's not about,
it's not,
a lot of people worry that it's about the
way you look and it's about vanity and
they don't want to be misconstrued as
being vain or they don't want to compete.
They don't want to acknowledge the fact
that being physically attractive or
sexually attractive is beneficial because
then it'll hold weight over them and
then they'll judge themselves
on not chasing after that.
So they sort of take pride in being
a fat fuck or joke around about,
you know,
being lazy and this,
some of those people are my
favorite human beings on the planet.
But the reality of it is if you
took better care of your meat wagon,
need to have a fun ride.
Fuck yeah,
just shocks would be better.
Your system and run smoother.
You get better miles to the gallon.
It doesn't fucking break
down the highways much.
It's a completely different experience.
Just force yourself
at the bare minimum.
Do enough to keep your body out of pain.
Do some yoga.
It's not hard.
I mean it is hard,
but it's not hard to
find a place to do it.
It's not hard to find a video online.
Just fucking just do that,
try it,
please get out of pain,
then get out of fear and then you
have a chance to connect to that.
They know that other,
whatever that other is,
but the first steps you gotta
take care of the base root,
you know,
you gotta get your body right.
Anthony Bordain started doing
Jujitsu at 57 years old.
His wife and kid got him
into Jiu Jitsu cause his kids
have and as kids like
really getting into Jujitsu.
So he's like,
Holy Shit,
I guess this kid older than five now,
but clothes somewhere in that range
is kids really getting into Jiu Jitsu.
And uh,
his wife is quite a bad ass.
Like she's like really obsessed with it.
She trains daily and so
now he's fucking training.
There's all these
pictures of him trainings.
He's got a stripe on his white
belt is doing arm bars and shit.
His cardio is improved.
And Octavio Bordain uh,
I don't know what the source of it is,
like where,
where you can find it online,
but if you Google it,
she wrote an article
about Anthony Bordain,
uh,
getting into shape and doing Jujitsu.
And it's,
it's a fascinating article.
First of all,
she's a really fucking good writer.
I mean,
I always knew she was smart.
She is very interesting,
but I didn't know how good her writing is.
It's very interesting.
It's like a,
I really like it.
It's a great style.
It's an enviable style of writing.
Like,
like,
Whoa,
she's got some skills,
you know,
so she's documenting him,
as like a test study,
you know,
it's obvious who he is.
It,
oh,
it's obvious,
but she knows she's talking 57 year old
man was a frequent smoker until he was
38 and has done,
she names off all the
different drugs and how Wa,
how little exercise he gets
and all these different things.
It's really fun if you get a chance,
check it out.
But good on Anthony.
Bordain man.
Good for you.
Him.
I love someone who's willing to take
a chance at 57 years old and learn
something.
No.
Exercising is exercising
his right to freewill.
Yeah.
Apparently she doesn't drill with them
cause she says he gets fucking too
intense.
He just fucking gets crazy.
He's trying to,
you know that guy's got
a little bit of Ptsd.
We sees fucking shit on his show.
This little amp
up man.
Well I'm Bro,
we ran out of time.
It's another fucking
awesome podcast though.
A lot of fun.
Beautiful.
Remember that last time you were worried
that we're going to run out of things
to talk about.
Yeah.
That was hilarious.
That was silly.
That's funny.
Did,
did,
did that come up at all in the,
in the psychedelics?
It didn't cause I,
cause I kind of figured that,
but it would have if I'd have had that
thought of it and like that was a silly
thought.
But all those little things,
those are just ants.
Those are ants.
And you can choose to give you power
that you can choose to be like,
that's a fucking man.
But like ants,
you need them or the world's
going to fucking fall apart.
That's what's really crazy
about the whole thing.
You really can't eradicate any of it.
It's impossible.
We're all going to be humans
and just enjoy this shit right here.
Not My deck on that point in my Monday.
I mean this life is what I'm saying.
Enjoy what's around you right now,
what you're experiencing right now.
And I think that whether
science can determine that free.
Will's just an illusion
because of your circumstances,
your genetics,
your life experiences.
That's all well and good.
But that's not empowering to whoever's
listening to this and it's actually
affecting you.
You w whoever that is that,
here's that me saying you,
whatever makes you can alter this thing.
You have it.
Yeah.
I don't know why you can alter it.
I Dunno,
but,
but I've done it.
You can do it.
There's nothing special about me.
I'm just a normal human being.
I can do it.
You can do it.
We can all do it.
And that's what your shaman friend
is Johnny Appleseed into the world.
And do you know out of a fucking
crazy place in the jungle
in the middle of nowhere,
but you have to fly into.
Yeah,
indeed.
Wow.
Do you want any more information on that?
I wrote this all up in a 26 page book.
Oh,
she booked with articles and stuff.
It's all on my warrior poet
wrote a 26 page book about that.
It's like a holy shit.
Yeah,
it's a wow.
The days that I wasn't doing ceremony,
I was writing about it and
who was filming this for you?
You hire someone to,
and then we got a bad ass crew.
We've got Mitch Schultz from DMT,
the spirit molecule.
Oh,
I love Mitch.
And then we had to have
Mitch on the podcast.
Donald's shelters is
crazy like wildlife guy.
I think I talked to you about him.
He's the saving the rhinos and
done a bunch of shit like that.
And then we had one of Mitch
is main film guys there.
I would love to talk to one of those,
saving the rhino guys and see how they
feel about those weird camps that they
have in Africa.
Donald will,
Donald knows all about it.
He's been there a couple of times.
You've got some crazy fucking story shot
at by NYPA rifles from the hunters and
crazy shit going on.
Yeah,
I would love to talk to him and get his
perspective that I had Louis Theroux on
the podcast and he spent a good deal of
time down in one of those camps and it's
one of the most fascinating
documentary said that he put out.
It was all about this contradictory world,
these African hunting camps.
Really fascinating.
If you get a chance to watch it,
first of all,
Louis through,
if you don't know who he is,
I'm just Google him.
I don't want to tell you how to
spell it because I'll fuck it up,
but figure it out bitch.
It's a day suggested spelling
[inaudible] spelled Louis and um,
you know,
he did some fantastic
documentaries on the um,
the Westboro Baptist church.
The God hates fags guy who holds up
those signs at funerals and shit.
That was incredibly fascinating.
But this was one of his more fascinating
ones and the contradictory nature of
these hunting camps is that
because of these hunting camps,
these animals are more healthy,
their populations are healthier
than they've ever been,
but people are hunting them and they're
kind of given inside cages and everybody
else's people are freaking out.
And it's a,
it's a,
it's a real complex freak out.
Cause I can see both sides.
I can see the size of the people that
are running the hunting camp because they
are in fact making these animals safer,
giving them a value.
And then also the money spent is making
sure that their populations will stay
steady and strong,
but they're going to be hunted.
You see?
That's,
I do like that's crazy.
You're,
you're fencing a man and then dudes are
coming in from out of state with one
reason to shoot these fucking animals.
But that's where you get the
money to keep the animals alive.
Like,
Ooh,
that is the universe
in a fucking nutshell.
Donald grew up in South Africa,
so when he,
you know,
if he comes on or whatever,
you have a conversation with him.
He's got a lot of opinions on that.
I won't steal his thunder,
but I need to hear them.
I would love to hear them.
Yeah,
so Louis thorough documentary
was God damn incredible.
I would love to hear,
uh,
someone who's trying
to save those animals.
What it's like.
It's just if you really pay attention
to a really good documentary on Africa,
like there's a great BBC
series called the Congo.
The diversity of life there is so stunning
that it's almost like you're watching
something that's a window in a forgotten
time when these animals existed because
they don't seem like they should exist.
They seem so fantastic and the almost
mythical of these shoe bill birds,
he's gigantic Berge this enormous long
beak thing that looks like a giant,
like,
like I could knew coming out of its
face and it's like five feet tall.
It's walked,
it's prehistoric and there's fish.
The climb out of the water and walk till
they get to the next pond and dive in.
There's antelopes that have evolved
the swim underwater and eat fish.
They have an antelope that eats fish.
Man,
it can swim under water a hundred yards.
And it's in the antelope family.
There's rhinos and elephants that are
trapped inside this rain forest because
the grasslands turned to
rain forest and all these,
these plains animals just got stuck there.
So you see these herds of
gazelles running through swamps.
It's madness.
I mean Africa is fucking incredible.
And that,
that somehow or another,
those animals are in jeopardy,
that the gorillas that come
down off the mountains,
you see them walk through these,
these little dirt roads walk across these
dirt roads and a family and the male
grills looking out if they're wild.
He's a wild gorillas today in 2014 like
we have to do something to save those
fucking things.
I mean I don't necessarily think it's
keeping them in fences and shoot arrows
out of me either.
I mean I think this,
this is a,
this is a crazy thing.
Like you have the most
incredible diversity of life,
of exotic life in the world,
all coming from the place where life,
human life apparently
was originated and the,
and when people are conscious
they'll want to enjoy those things.
Cause it's part of the fucking magic
of this crazy blue rock that we're on.
You know,
it is.
And as soon as seaworld gets shut down,
the next thing is zoos.
You take your kids to the zoo now.
Now I can.
I know why you can't and won't
be Susan the future folks.
We're going to realize how gross that is.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
this has been fun.
It's always fun.
Um,
we,
we appreciate very much
all the love that we get.
A Twitter comedy shows just the
vibe that we're all riding on,
you know,
and like we said,
there's hiccups along the way.
There's blots of negativity,
but there's lessons to be learned
and all of those things for me,
for you,
for all of us.
And,
uh,
I think one of the most important
things about having these kinds of
conversations,
you get to highlight these things and
we all get to think of these things
together and we all get to
acknowledge that these are,
you know,
we,
we were all experiencing
life in this weird,
strange,
figure it out as you go along style,
you know,
don't be too harsh on people
bitches get it together.
I try to be nice,
be good to your brothers and sisters and
the earth to your brothers and sisters
and the earth.
And on that note,
thank you to legal zoom.
Go to legalzoom.com use the code word
Rogan in the referral box and save
yourself some money.
And thanks also to onnit.com go to o n n
I t use the Codeword Rogan and save 10%
off any and all supplements.
We got a pod cast filled week,
ladies and gentlemen,
including late night episode 500.
It will take place Tuesday night at 9:00
PM with the Great Doug Stan hope and
the great Tom Rhodes.
Oh good googly Mooglie.
Maybe possibly the greatest drunk podcast
of all will be this Tuesday night,
and you'd have to look forward to that.
Alright,
we love you.
Take care of big kiss.
Hey,
Ooh.