Yeah.
The Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by
[inaudible] dot com if you
go to on@dotcomjustgotojoerogan.net.
Click on the link for Alpha brain
and use the code name Rogan.
You will save yourself 10%
off any and all supplements.
But we also have some new stuff in stock
and that is kettle bells and battle
ropes and they're pretty fucking bad ass.
We want to get yourself into caveman
shape. If you want to train like,
like Brock Lesnar does
in the countdown shows.
If you want to do some manly man working
out or if your girlfriend has big boobs,
it's probably cool to watch
her do it. Oh, the ropes. Yeah.
You don't want to watch the kettle bells.
You don't want it would have sharks.
Don't like slams amount of
chips around that bruises them.
If you've never seen kettlebells before,
you don't know what they look like.
A cannon ball with a handle on
it. And then it's, in my opinion,
the most effective way to uh,
produce functional strength for, uh,
for martial arts, especially for Jujitsu
and Muay Thai. And things like that.
That's mostly what I do for
my strength and conditioning.
I do kettle bells and I do body weight
squats and Chin ups and stuff like that
and dips and um, just,
uh, it's a, it's a brutal,
brutal way to work out.
There's one DVD that I recommend
always to everybody if you can get it.
It's all sold out now because
I recommend it so much. Yeah.
It's called the extreme
kettle bell cardio workout.
This guy kicks your ass with
one Kettlebell. It's like
one 35 pound kettle bell.
It's fucking brutal.
You would think I'm a manly man.
35 pound Kettlebell kind of
a fucking pussy workout. Am
I going to get with that?
Trust me. You'll get a workout, a brutal
work. I would just body weight squats.
Just look up Hindu squats. Do 200
of them in a row and get back to me.
See what I'm talking about, bitch,
we're talking crazy shit here today.
I'm getting fired up, ladies and
gentlemen. All right. Because, uh,
James Bobo Fay is on the podcast.
We're going to talk some big foot.
You sons of bitches were going
to get down to the nitty gritty.
We're going to let people know
what the fuck ticks or yeah word.
So go to [inaudible] dot com that's
our sponsor. Thanks also to Alienware.
You're hooking us up with some
fucking sweet computers and uh,
if you can't follow them on,
on Twitter, Alienware MMA,
they sponsor a lot of
good fighters and uh,
make it a lot easier for these guys to
compete and pay their bills and pay for
training and all that stuff.
So we support them here at the Joe
Rogan experience podcast. Sorry,
James Bobo phase here and his dogs here.
You talk to him again, man. Monkeys,
monkeys here. Hey Monkey. All right,
let's get this motherfucker started. Ryan,
she's actually a squash trash
fish or experience.
Try my day.
Joe Rogan podcast all day.
That's a new one. I'm not sure I like
it. That new fade out you do at the end.
You crafty devil. That's a squatch
trained dog. Ladies and gentlemen,
if you hear a dog or see a dog,
if you're watching us on Ustream or Vimeo,
and you see a dog in the background
that is actually a squatch trained dog.
And this is an official tracking squatch
hat. This is a gone squatch and hat.
Did you sell these?
Because if you don't,
you should because it will show like
fucking I thought Animal Planet trademark
that they thought I
did. Oh, so nobody did.
Somebody else trademarking
some guy in Taiwan now. Oh,
those sons of bitches just fucking
sell it and make them sue you because
everybody would want an official
Bobo con squash and hat.
They sold tens of thousands
on a cafe press cafe.
Presto.
Like anybody could go on cafe press and
pretty much like make your own shirt
though, right? Uh, yeah. Uh,
last time I looked there was like
670 websites selling those hats. Oh,
that's hilarious. Dude.
You've created a, uh,
like you looking at your Twitter
right now. I fucking, oh, sorry.
I promised my buddy I texted when
it started because they're driving.
I can try and text him right now. We say
it's on, it's on. When I was a little kid,
I went camping with my parents. We
were, I was probably like six and uh,
we were in Yosemite and, uh, I
met a dude who was a trapper,
gave me like some,
some stinky fucking feet of like animals,
like killed like bobcats and stuff. But
when you're sick it's fuck it's bad ass.
Like whoa, this is cool. But uh, you know,
that's when I got obsessed with big foot
was talking to this guy cause he, uh, he,
uh, hundred percent believed in Sasquatch
is, and he, I remember it was just,
he was six.
I was six years old when he told me this.
He was just saying that
the woods are so dense.
There's no way everybody's been to
every part of it. Nah, there's no way.
He's like, if you draw, if you
fly over the Pacific northwest,
I guess that's the only time where you
really get a true sense of how intense it
is. Because we kind of think of it
like, especially the Pacific northwest,
we kind of think of it
as like, you know, yeah,
they're Seattle and there's Portland
and there's some cities up there and I
guess there's highways dude.
A giant chunk of that is just
fucking dense rain forest.
No, our people are not aware of
that. And that's where the, the Pr,
that's the majority of sightings
in America, right? Um, the most,
but what people trip on is they're all
their continent wide. They're worldwide.
How is it possible that
something can be kind and,
and the only video footage available
in 2012 is that shitty Patterson film,
Low Fat Patterson.
I think he's a fraud dude.
Know what happened. It was a camera.
You rethink Israel. You think
that was a very emotional response?
Say that if you were to search
or NASA, Delaware, the table. No,
I'm saying it wasn't Patterson known
to be a, a, a con man. I'm listening.
I believe firmly that Jane
Goodall believes 100% right.
There's a Sasquatch, I believe
very firmly. It's very possible.
I think that if they found one, all of a
sudden people would start, uh, you know,
it would make sense to people.
There's,
there's all sorts of
primates over this is planet.
And they know that gigantic [inaudible]
lived with people in Asia, right? Like,
you know, thousands and thousands
and thousands of years ago.
And the real legit scientists that,
that talk about big foot say it's
possible that an animal came down with a
humans do during the Bering strait.
But you know,
realize humans are cunts. They're a
pain in the ass to fucking shoot Ya.
They stabbing, they make rugs. Any let's
hide, let's, let's go hide in the woods.
Show me a big animal that we don't kill
out in the woods. It's true. But how it,
oh, we would definitely kill one
for sure. Why there's a killed,
there's a guy who's on youtube right now.
I'm subscribed to the big foot
report on Youtube. You know,
whenever the new video comes up,
they'll send that guy.
But there's a guy who claims he killed
big foot. So he did you really think so?
I bought.
Does he have,
I bought that camera cause I wa I got
invited to go on the bottom of recovery
mission last year and a, it's a
real story, but where's the body?
What happened was,
I'll just give a rundown real quick.
I'm actually friends with the guy I
thought I'd never be friends with the guy
shot a squash, but he's shut the baby,
right? Yeah. Shot adult and a baby.
He first thought would happen.
They're doing, they're driving.
They were doing a huge,
when they just saw a warden and they were
duty turn way up in the Sierra Nevadas
but 8,500 feet and it was like Halloween
I think, or the day before Halloween.
Sierra Nevada's are in California.
Is that the huge mountains like Taco hub?
I just all the way down to the
Clara County. What is it? Yeah,
they run from current kind
of to like Oregon border
base. Okay. That area though,
I'm like northern California, we're a
hundred miles long and 50 miles wide.
That's a big, big foot
siding area, right? Oh yeah.
So this guy didn't believe in big
foot or anything. He's total redneck,
like kills it, like likes to just kill
shit out in the woods. Right. And, uh,
the big adult came out, was waving
his hands and wiggling his fingers.
They'll wave their hands and Lidl their
fingers just show that they're not bears.
We think they're pretty smart.
They're like people.
So he drives a beat on his buddy, had
just come back, just got a jacket,
just come back from Iraq and Afghanistan
combat vet and like he just was
overseeing stuff shot. He's like,
firstly say, don't shoot it. It's uh,
it could be a person in to see it.
And Justin was looking through the
scope and he's looking at it going,
it's not a person. He could see it through
the scope. It was, uh, it was a squatch,
but it wasn't one of those big buff ones.
He said it looked real frumpy,
kinda like saggy,
like wasn't sure if it was older or what.
So he's started squeezing one op and
when the thing realized he was going to
pull the trigger because
they were locking eyes,
he turned and he shot it through the ribs,
uh,
like lung shot. And it dropped, went
down like to a sprinter position,
then got up and sprint.
It's super fast,
stumbled once and then went
crashing down this Manzanita,
well they get out of the truck and
they're walking into their trip.
They never even thought of big fit.
They're walking out of their trip and
balls like they just saw a huge thing.
They call it a monster shot it,
it ran out there looking for them but
they heard it crashed out in the brush.
This guy's a registered bear hunting
guide so he said he could tell it,
you know that that was the
sound it makes when it crashes.
Well they get about 40 yard.
It was about 70 80 yards when he shot
it and they got about 40 yards there and
right where the thing was around two
identical twin babies like the size,
like three or four year old kids.
But with way bigger heads came out,
came out of the brush,
we're running around looking for lack
of the parent and they were running back
and forth cause he went,
he was going to shoot one of the babies
right off the bat and his buddy wouldn't
let him. I kept yelling, don't do it,
I'll kick your ass. You shoot that thing,
go shoot it.
Things are running around like 10 minutes.
They couldn't find the adult and they
realize okay there's two babies and they
were identical twins.
They'd run around,
they'd sniff the ground and look
around on all fours, like totally,
totally countable on all fours like
quadro pad, you know, just run around.
When they came near each other they'd get
up on two legs and they'd come up face
to face and he said they sounded
like too profoundly mute.
People talk and they go like
just real guttural sounds.
But like he said like a language
and they'd get back down.
They were moving down and they were
working their way towards where they heard
the body crashed and they realized,
well shit, they thought it was,
they shot the mobs like well if we just
shot the mom and then daddy's probably
around like this thing is eight foot
with a shot was probably eight foot tall,
600 pounds.
Hmm hmm.
Sort of thing. And we'll
shit, it's getting dark.
We want to go here and Jack and Justin
split up because they're covering
different territory and the one of the
little babies kept like bought without
Wallace and just still this rise.
We went to the spot with them.
We weren't like Doctor Meldrum went and
mine ski like you like the big name guys,
scientists. We went out there when
the snow melted the next summer.
Are these the big name guys that believe
in big funds or no beliefs for shit you
can't see, right? Well they know it
exists. It's like people believe in Jesus,
but I never find like a Jesus heritage.
Jesus tracker, Jesus Shit in the woods,
you know,
or where Jesus killed the elk or anything.
But what if you found
personally, so you're saying
historically one of the bags,
so then that would a dick,
I know
he feels bad now, but it could even
tell that story, you know? Yeah.
I had a film that you shoot a
baby. I know, Dude. Well he put it,
he wanted to prove the story was real.
He's just redneck dude.
That's killer shit for fine. That kind of
mindset, you know, he's not a bad dude.
That's just how he was raised.
And uh,
he's actually a smart dude when you get
to talk to him because you think he's
just some dumb shit redneck when he
talked to guys is pretty sharp dude.
Why didn't he take a video?
Why didn't they didn't have a camera?
They didn't have a cell phone with them.
I teach a pretty red nose and
12 yeah, this was October, 2000,
whatever. 11th 10th how could you
not have a cell phone? I do not.
I'm not justifying what he did.
I'm just saying I watched his video and
my bullshit alarm went off. Oh No, dude.
Well, I'll tell you.
I'll see what happens.
So he shot it and the thing
it rolled down the hill,
he picked it up and look and just
watched it die in his hands. Then he,
then his buddy started screaming at him.
He said he's stuck the body of this Bush.
They took off,
got out of there and they were on a
hunting website and one of our buddies,
Derek Randall is like, you know,
talk to him on the website, whatever.
Like there's like a chat room for hunters.
I was like,
I shot a couple of kind of jokes and
how would you mount a big foot and then
he's all, no, I really did. It really did.
He's all dude, you, you'll get that body.
I'll give you $1 million. Right.
But all you have right now,
it's just a guy with a story.
No, no. He came back and brought,
when he picked up the baby,
it bled on his boot.
There's blood on the boot from the baby
when they're,
they went back out there and snow like
three and a half feet and they're digging
six by six foot holes down to this.
Now they're out there for like a,
I forget what he said,
like eight hours digging,
digging and then there's
bloodhound they found where they,
they thought it was crashed, they found
it and like there's liquid mammal.
I was like how all the grease comes up
the ass like it at least like a greased
slick there.
And they found out there was,
it looked like a bear fed on it cause it
was just torn up and there was actually
some bear prints in the snow as they dug
and they'd say [inaudible] which does
happen. Dan, any animal.
When was the last time you
saw a dead deer in the woods?
They don't last very long.
If they're,
there are a couple of days
something finds it. Oh yeah.
It starts getting torn up
and then like road and seat,
the bones porcupines eat the
bones, whatever. And so, um,
where was I to lead?
How puppy found a chunk of meat and flash?
He couldn't tell. Look, it looked like
the same colors he got and it was like a,
like a girl.
I saw it.
It's like grayish white with brown mixed
in like kind of multicolored and it's
weird course hair and it matches.
Anyways, that is the, the the,
the catalyst of the center piece of
the DNA study is that piece of meat.
That's the first one they got
cause it snowed right on it.
That was the first hold.
And what does it have they
done an analysis so they've
mapped the whole genome.
What is it?
It's a,
what the guys that are working on it
called is a relic hominid and it's not a
gigantic,
Pittsburgh is really so,
so there are 100%
convinced it's not a chimp,
it's not any other kind of
bad word. Word, word lead.
Cause this guy that has done this study,
it's a woman named Melba
Ketchum and there's a lot of
controversy around her and
there's some weird stuff
about her for sure.
Like things she's done in Saje crazy.
Nah, I don't know. Bed. She's a woman.
I was glad you said that.
How many cats does he own?
How many crystals around her neck?
She's cool,
but she's a g Jeanette glass
has a big genetic lab. She
anyways, she's well known.
And what's her, what's the issue
that people have with her? Well,
because she had to come up
with new, um, God what it,
I don't want to start talking
to each teeth when I read it.
I understand that people like the
scandal was it? No, no, no. She, uh,
well I'll just say this from that.
Now Oxford University is doing a study
over in England on the same, they,
I think they're getting some of
the, I mean, I'm not sure exactly.
I hear stuff from different people and I
was just with the guys that are running
the DNA project this last week, last
week, I just slept in two days ago.
And uh, but um, there's
other labs that are,
do you have to like go through
peer review and they have to like,
you give them a sample,
they do the same test,
but she had come up with
these new techniques that
hadn't been used before. And,
and so the other labs that authenticate
that then replicate the process and you
had to replicate it twice each other lab.
And the word is,
and like there's other scientists getting
onboarded cause it words leaked around
in the community of those
type of geneticists and stuff
is that it's, it's real.
Like there's, it's, it's
really close to human.
Like where's chimps and gorillas have 98,
98.1% the same amount of
d the same DNA we have.
These are 99.59 9.6 the samples from age
of the Yeti's or 99.4 to nine or 9.5.
So what are the Yeti samples?
What would they proven to be? Uh,
well that was the thing was that
there's these genetic markers there.
They're really similar to, they're,
they're like a type of PR people.
Like they're there the whole,
that evolutionary chain
they have, you know, his,
his way out of whack and aware that
there was this much conclusive evidence.
So I'd never even learned this before.
Yeah.
People do talk about it on the show that,
you know, it's so aggravating. It's,
it's, um, it's real frustrating
because we were like,
you guys never put any real science in the
show. They're like, they're like, yeah.
And I used to get in fights with them
and I actually quit the show a bunch of
times. Like Susan, why like
in between season one and
season two, you really? Yeah,
I was, I was, I was like, this isn't
what I signed up for. You know,
like some hokey asked, what would
you say? What did you sign up?
They wouldn't like a, we got some,
you know, uh, audio, we've got some,
we've got audio and stuff captured and,
and when you run through spectographs you
could rule out, you can rule stuff out,
you know,
and a lot of times you'll get left with
the only thing that matches it would be
like a, like a howler monkey
or something or given,
and then it goes out of range
of that even, you know, the,
my favorite story is Les
Stroud from survivor. Oh yeah.
Survivor man.
That dude was in Alaska and apparently
he was on a remote island and the Alaska
for folks who will know it as more than
a thousand islands last is a fuck load
of islands, temperate rain
forest in the southeast. Well,
he was camping there.
He's doing one of his survivor of things
where he stays up all night and you
know, sleeps in a tent and makes
his own food. I mean it's really,
it shows amazing. I love the guy. Anyway,
he was in Alaska by himself and he started
hearing primate noises. He heard like,
Ooh,
loud something that didn't sound
anything like a bear. And he's like,
this was like very distinct primate.
And he said,
then I started to make some movement
and when it realized that something was
there, ran hard and fast are the ones
he goes, I don't, don't know what it is.
But it was big and it was heavy and it
ran through the woods and it sounded like
it was making primate noises.
I said it to him, it was a,
it was a real animal. And he suspects
that it's probably big foot, you know,
and he's a guy that goes to these really
remote places in stays for days and
days.
And I think he's got it in his head how
there could be an animal like that that
lives completely outside of human contact.
And even in 2012 as he discovered just
this guy story sounds like bullshit.
I watched a story. I've watched him talk,
watch him talk about shooting the, the,
the thing that it was a baby. I was like,
dude, you're an actor. This is nonsense.
This is, I don't buy, I didn't buy it
or it takes a lot of grief, man. He's
not, and he's not making any money off it.
Like they're doing a book it and
he's done it. And all of them
are crazy. People check this out. When
I took them out, when we went out there,
monkey loves like she's playing with
big victory for up and Bluff Creek.
I didn't actually see her playing with it,
but it's the only daylight setting I
ever had was the same day she was in the
brush in that same spot,
run around and I could hear something
huge running back and forth.
And when she gets excited,
she hates,
she got her ribs all brook by a bear when
she was a puppy and she hates mountain
lions. Wow. And uh, where he
said he's stuck the baby's body.
She like, she'll never hear him make
a noise. She doesn't bark or anything.
She meant maybe playgrounds a little bit,
but she doesn't bark in a whole week.
We were up there. The only time anyone
heard her make any noise was when he said,
yeah,
I still it over that Bush.
And she was just walking around stiff
and she went over that Bush where he said
he's stuck the baby body and she went
crazy and started digging holes and like,
did you guys try to figure out if it
was there to try and dig it out? Yeah,
we had cadet like um,
uh,
Dr measurements set up for some cadaver
dogs to the Smithsonian and stuff like
that to come up. It was like a full,
we had professional trackers and um,
the cadaver p we had two
different sets of cadaver dogs.
They wouldn't do it because if it
was a funny part was, is the lady,
it doesn't search and rescue in
the mountains with the dogs too,
like body recoveries.
And she was certain there that Sasquatch
has lived there and she didn't,
and it wasn't like, I don't
want to do it. That's crazy.
I don't want to be involved in
something that's not real. She was like,
if it is Sasquatch and you try and my
dog picks up on that set and tracks it,
it would like a,
it wouldn't ever train track humans again.
They only track one thing. Those
cadaver dogs. Really? Yeah, absolutely.
Definitely.
His handlers track a Sasquatch then
they wouldn't work for humans anymore,
so,
but yeah,
but if you've got a dog that was trained
to track squats as you probably dog
wouldn't live long. If it caught up to
him, you think they would eat the dog.
They've, they've been known to kill
dogs like real pretty frequently. Yeah.
Really aggressive dogs. Even dogs
were just mind their own business.
They've killed him. No Shit. Yeah, but
dogs barking. Getting aggressive though.
People say they'll see him kick him. Just
know that anyone that's had their dog,
Sasquatch. Yeah, they see it. They see
it happen. I talked to these natives.
We were down squash it on the hickory
Apache reservation in New Mexico and they
had one called the porch and they were
there. Uh, the female dog was a Pitbull,
was gardener. Publish had like,
they were like four weeks,
six week old puppies and they're up
on the site and the store is morning.
The kids are watching cartoons, getting
ready for school, eat breakfast,
and the thing walked up on their porch
and the dog was snarling and snapping and
just walked up like that. It's like,
and just crushed it, broke it's back,
like crushed it and then stomped
all the puppies and walked away.
Whoa. Stomped a puppy. So big. That's a
Douche bag. I think there are like people,
yeah, Alex, summer, total dicks.
And most of them are, are I now,
what is the most conclusive evidence
you'd think it's that Patterson footage
because I think that footage is horse
shit. I take it you're tripping. Nah,
you're so wrong.
You're more wrong than you know.
Do you know that that guy was arrested
for riding a fake check to pay for the
very camera that he used to Fisk
finish that film. That, okay. You're,
you're talking about Greg longs
book, which is what I'm talking about.
Which was this total, is it not true?
He was, uh, he, he had some
financial difficulties,
difficulties for sure.
Bob Gibson,
the guy that was driving him
and the in the Apache Indian,
the tracker guy and the
guy's a legend dude. He's,
there is one guy who is come out and
said that it was a hoax and then he was a
part of it. Right? That guy's a liar.
Told here's some drunk neighbor guy
that used to hang out with them. That,
that um, was Roger and Bob were
real popular. The Roger Patterson,
Bob Galen [inaudible]. They were like
expert Rodeo riders. Um, Bob Gibbons,
the baddest dude you'll ever meet.
Dude,
he was the number one ranked welterweight
in the world when I got in a serious
car wreck. And that his career,
he's in the Rodeo Hall of fame.
He's like the best tracker hunter
you ever saw sobbing. The guys.
He's 81 he's still out there like
breaking horses and roping and,
and what part did he play in
this? He was, he was the guy,
he was the other guy that was
with Roger when they filmed it.
Roger Patterson wasn't a con man. No,
because I've read that he was a con man.
This guy put this heat as arrested
for writing bad checks. Yeah, he,
cause he was so impassioned with the
project and like he knew that there was
real and he was just thought he,
well his brother in law was
supposed to be finding this stuff,
this guy out the athletes. It was a
millionaire up there and he kinda,
he was like his brother in law, like,
you know, crazy Roger running around,
whatever. I think, you know,
and he was his partner on this and then
he was supposed to be putting funds in
and like it didn't happen.
It wasn't like,
it wasn't like Rogers is total calm
man. He was like, everyone, people,
we've talked to them and
say he's a good dude.
And he w he purposely went there to try
to find a big flood and he was there
filming fresh tracks. They were there
to film the Blue Mountain. Trackway.
What does that mean?
There was some sets of tracks that
people had found big foot tracks. Yeah,
there was to try to find a big foot.
Um,
at that time they were just
looking for fresh tracks.
I never thought they'd see it,
especially in the day. Well, listen man,
nobody wants to believe
big foot more than me,
but when I look at that video footage,
it looks fake. Dude, you're tripping.
Let's say a guy in a monkey suit. I'm
just pull it up, Brian. Pull it up.
You're way off chirping. Do you think it's
a real big foot, Brian? No, it's real.
I saw, I saw one of the daylight.
Well, I'm not listening.
I'm not saying that the files are real.
I'm not saying that at all by any
stretch of the imagination. Look,
Jane Goodall beliefs big for Israel.
She's,
she said she believes 100% that there
is some undiscovered primate in the
Pacific northwest. I believe those
were as global her exact words.
What should I look up? Bob
Patterson, big foot footage. Uh,
Roger Patterson,
Patterson.
Gimlin stabilized Patterson.
Big Foot footage.
I'm sure it's going to put up stabilized
cause he wants it. Oh that's it.
It's funny. Mexican
border, big foot footage.
His and a fucking bag of traffic.
That's a,
they talk to a border patrol agent though.
That was tracking some coming across
and saw big foot down the mountains down
in Arizona. Really? Okay. No stable.
Yeah. Original footage. Um, okay.
For one thing,
let's watch she's walking.
If you could say that's not stabilized.
Yeah,
they're going to stabilize it
in a sec. Okay. Okay. Right.
Let me just spit back suit.
Dude.
You're so off the top expert as in the
world like chambers that made the the,
um, okay. Right. Let's see back a little
bit more. Her foot. They have a dope.
If you look at that cash, they have a
double ball foot and you can see it.
They just found this recently right there.
Yeah. You'd have to pause it. Pause
it. When she's picking her foot up,
it's her left foot going down. It's a
total girls over there saying, oh dude,
hitters, big hairy ass tits. Let's,
I would love to believe that. That's
a real big front. I really would,
but it will be soon.
Okay.
Nah, it is. It's it's
way bigger than a human.
It's does.
Do they do the things that you guys do?
That's one of the things I really enjoy
about your show is that when someone has
a a video that they think it's big foot,
then what they do is they sent Bobo out
and bubbles always bigger because you're
a big dude,
but you're always bigger than the the
what they thought was big foot except for
coming up this season. One of the
episodes coming up. Oh really? Got One.
It's way bigger than what they got.
Smart season two they wizened up.
You know a lot of those people
just want to be on TV, right?
No. A lot of them. You don't think a
lot of those people with their stories.
There was one guy I remember a little bit.
Most will, what happens is we go there,
right? Like we're, we have like
a network all across the country,
like big foot researchers.
There's like a lot of like academics,
cops like fishing game officials,
like people that are seen on
themselves and like they get into it.
Have you seen in yourself?
Yeah. When have you seen it?
The last one I saw it funny. The guy just
called me was with this guy, uh, Jamie j.
He was your step maybe Black Hawk
down? Yes. He was the real life dude.
The fifth third squad leader that
shot their way out, like Kimra,
that rescue house and came out and met
up with him and then ran out front and
shot his way up. Me and that guy
were up there and is where I saw the,
my only daylight setting. It was right
on Bluff Creek or that was filmed the PG,
the parish agreement films. Films.
Really? Yeah. You saw one there? I saw it.
That's the one I,
when monkey was playing that day and
the brush or I thought she was gonna get
killed earlier in that day. The
wonders I saw. What she was staring at.
It was leaning out behind a tree and I
saw lean out behind the tree for like
just that fat,
this was gone.
I walked up there and you can just smell
that smell is one of the only times
we're really smelled that smell
real thick. You hear about,
cause I haven't smelled that.
Black people always talk about that smell,
but I want you to call them skunk
apes. Yeah, we think it's like a,
like a secretion gland. Like they can like
if they get agitated or scared or mad,
it'll seep out and like over Millennia,
human brain is when that
pheromone hits your brain,
it just causes total fear
reaction. Really. Yeah. That's
interesting.
So it's like,
you know what p a lot of people
don't realize is that like um,
the parts per million that a dog can
smell of a person is very similar to what
you can smell from a skunk.
Right.
It's really interesting because you really
think about how strong a skunk smell
is. The you're in your car with the
windows rolled up and you're driving like,
oh fucking skunk that's outside.
It's outside,
nowhere near you and it
just a little tiny squirt.
Well a dog can smell a person
like that. That is a trip, man.
That's a wild thing to think of.
If we have a reaction to these things,
some primordial reaction to these things,
and that gland is just like a skunk gland,
just like some,
something that squirts out of to us is
like really distinct. Right. Probably all,
probably all animals through that smell.
What was it like to you?
Like what was the smell like, if you
could describe it? Um, it was it possible?
Yeah.
I'll tell you this.
I walked through it to another time where
it was real thick or had just walked
in front of us.
Like we missed it by minutes where it
walked into broad date across the meadow
and uh, hickory Apache
reservation. I smell it there too.
It was like they'd be like from here to
the wall and you can walk through it and
you'd just be like, uh, and
like if there's no wind, right.
Cause both these times there was not when,
right then it just hung so thick
and it was like real musty,
like a Musk and it was kind
of sour kind of sewage.
He smelled like wet,
like wet dog mix was like bear of when
a bear comes out in the spring when you
smell a bit of smell bears when
they come out of hibernation,
like that kind of smelly,
stinky animals.
Fucking real funk but and like
nut and you would not when people,
cause I didn't smell it for a long time.
I was around him a long time
till I smelt one. Like I,
I'd seen them and heard him around
me before I'd ever smelled one.
What's the first time you saw on the
first one? I saw it was May 21st,
2001 where? Up in humble up in the
bald hills. And that's where you from?
I'm from down here originally. We went
up there in the 80s. It's nice up there.
Oh yeah, that's beautiful. So I,
I was with this, uh, these, uh,
this cop and this probation officer guy.
And then my buddy I left,
I was all excited about
these guys and I had,
I had just bought a gen two Ukrainian
knight's scope. That's when night vision,
all that stuff was super expensive.
It was like a real,
nowadays it just be a piece of crabby,
probably buy one for 100 bucks.
But I'd never had one before. So I
was of like little cheap, you know,
big five ones. And I left on the porch
when I was packing my truck to go out.
We're going to go squatch and for a
week. And uh, my buddy drove it up to me.
We were only there 20 minutes and
it's a long story, Dude. I know.
It's okay. It's um, well, five
nights before that I'd had my,
my first first.
Sure.
Like on an unambiguous Sasquatch and
counterparts scared still to this day,
it was scariest moment of my life.
Like ours not didn't see him,
but I saw like when they ran, when
they bluff charged me, there was like,
it was pitch black but you could just
see black on black movement like,
you know what I mean? Like you
couldn't make out any, any form.
But it was just a big black
couple of black shapes.
Like it was like there was gaps in
between the trees, a starlet behind,
there's just like,
but there were so it was just like a
black blur and they ran on both sides. Me,
um, I've been doing house and growls
and identify all the time and never had,
never had,
in hindsight when we were logging up
there like probably about seven years
earlier, six years earlier,
further down that ridge line.
We've been logging there one summer
and they'd come around as much.
But I didn't realize what they were doing.
I thought it was Indian.
I thought it was pot grower
Indian dudes that there,
cause we were off the Rez and there'd
be Knox and whistles in the morning and
the Indian dudes wouldn't
get out of the truck.
But I like these dudes were like
the baddest dudes in the resin.
No it fuck with these guys.
And like if someone's going to,
they'd be confront whoever would
like these dudes were gnarly barley,
Indian lager trees and would just sit
in the truck and knock it out until the
sun came up because we'd be up there
and sharpen their saws and stuff,
getting ready and just kind of stretching
a little bit and just getting ready
for the day and they wouldn't get out of
the truck of those whistles and knocks
going to sit in the truck. So I'd been
around but didn't know it. And uh,
but this time it was,
they kid I was doing house and this
thing came from the north. I don't,
when you say you were doing house
for folks who haven't seen the show,
you imitate like what you've heard and
recordings and when you, what, you know,
they believe our primate Howell's
tribute to big foot. Yeah. So you can,
there's a bunch of those you
can find on the Internet.
And I was doing those and all of a sudden
I thought I heard a wolf Hollenbeck or
like a wolf cross hybrid.
My buddies,
everyone needs to have like a
while back and seven eights wolf,
Husky and they don't listen to you at all.
And I thought it was one
of those things and uh,
it was coming down the ridge and it has,
it made some weird,
sounds like almost like
more coyote kind of sound,
but that sound and then I'll just
never forget it. It kinda want,
it sounds sorta like mine but different.
It sounded way more primal and
just gnarly. And it just goes,
I just remember every hair on my
body shut up. My son went, Holy Shit,
I'm actually having a big fit.
And countering the things had been
walking towards me at that point had been
walking at me for probably 20 minutes.
I could hear it coming closer and
closer and it was just so loud.
I was carrying forever. I was looking
down over the Klamath River and um,
it just, and when it came into the tree
line, I was sitting in this meadow,
I was like, there's a dirt road
that runs along the top of the hill.
And then the left side is,
um, redwood national park.
And on the right side it's Timberland
and there's a few ranch in holdings,
all family and holdings in there.
And I was sitting up there and I was,
uh, this Indian woman, there's
a little Indian village,
knew of this dirt road about 12
miles down. Said she'd saw one.
And when I was talking about my Chapati
jump freight us that day on the phone,
he said it was real.
This is like cell phones and
humble back then were like real,
unless you were right in the middle
of town, didn't work too good.
And I heard him say, yeah, May 21st,
you know, about a woman's sought,
we'll run across the road.
Right. And I knew were shoot,
cause we logged up in there.
I knew that whole area.
I knew exactly where he was talking
about. It was a big deer. And Elk meadow,
so I was like, okay shit,
I know where that is.
And I was like jammed up there and I had
the nights because I sat there and this
thing came into the tree lag. I started
in these crazy roars and screaming,
snapping trees and it was,
this thing was huge, gnarly,
just I couldn't live when it came to
the tree line to my right and my two
o'clock position. So that was like, it
says like if this is the dirt road here,
there's this metal that's
kind of a crescent shape,
half moon and there was a little timber
stand here, brush and timber right here,
and then there's a dirt road behind here.
I was sitting on the other side of the
road facing the meadow with my night
scopes and then this beach
chair look about this way.
This thing came in to hear it by
nine o'clock I was facing this way.
This is Kevin might nine o'clock
and right when it did it like this,
craziest Roran snap.
This tree from over here at two o'clock
was this gnarly power, not just our rack.
They'll take a branch or something and
just bash the tree or a stomp or whatever
we call them power and actually do that.
Or would Knoxville are lighter
but just as full 90 product boom.
Just to let you know they could do that
in your head. Right. That's what they did.
If they were ever going to kill him when
they would have killed me that night
because, or they're musicians, they're,
they have a really primitive band.
Nuts. I've asked a lot of
natives about that. Like,
cause they come around tribal dances
and stuff and I've talked to you. Yeah.
They'll keep the noise down.
They'll like kind of dig on it.
They dig music. Apparently the, the,
from what I've heard, they don't
make any kind of music. What does it,
what did they sound like?
Like what does the house,
I'm like the house gave us a version
of the [inaudible] my, my version.
It only did mine once from what happened.
Should I do it? Yeah, of course.
I get like a little bit,
yeah, that's good. It's good.
Like a hit and I reckon your law,
uh
wow. But I do it louder. If
we were outside it was um,
the videos that are rather the audio
recordings that some people have gotten of
a, of screams in the woods that they have
identified as priming. Right. You know,
where,
where was that that they got those?
Cause it's pretty all over the
sounds like there's Zuri Mississippi,
Florida. How come numbers game and
pictures of them man, they just,
they're shitty pictures and cameras
don't work like the human eye. Right to,
it's like your eye focused
so quick and it whenever you,
cause they're so used to getting shot
at and they see a shoot at everything I
think. But I think they know what cameras
are but when they see something come up
they're just gone.
Like they're not sticking around.
They're not going to sit there.
But there is videos,
there's a lot of videos but it is like
we know people that have gotten them but
you can't tell him it's just so
shitty, low quality, low Rez.
Like they're almost always in the shadows.
Like it'll be bright outside
then they're in the shout out.
People aren't using high
quality gear cause it you,
if you hadn't personally had an
encounter at a certain point in time,
you have to look at all these different
people with their shitty photos and the
things that don't,
that don't really look like a big foot.
You're showing you these,
there's a lot of hoaxers and crazy people.
A lot of people. Right.
Well Moses for sure hooks.
There's almost not a knowing
that you're dealing with,
you're in a business where half the
people were full of Shit, let's say being,
being nice guy.
I think that's being nice. That
research. Bigfoot? No, no. Not Research.
Big Foot that have claimed to
have seen him I think. I think,
I don't think half of them are full
of shit. No Way. Cause there's,
I've talked to over 4,000 people that
have seen him and maybe a hundred or 200
we're trying to bullshit me.
Only 102 hundred really because this
is before I was on TV and stuff mostly.
You know what I mean? Like I
just be talking about, you know,
people in the community.
Like I've talked a couple of my
professors when I was going to school,
I had seen him, um, we did all kinds
of people. We did this thing once.
You can't trust it once you put it on TV,
like your show right now.
Like I see people that raise their
hands and I'm like, this motherfucker,
this shit up as town hall meetings. When
did you see a big player? I'll fucking,
they just like you could tell some,
some folks will just make shit
up to get on camera. And a,
I did a show for CBS wants,
it was called game show in my head and
one of the things we did was we would
show up somewhere pretending
to be a real news crew. And um,
the assignment that the contestant had
was you have to get someone to agree to
have seen something that they
didn't actually see because uh,
your witness took off
and it's a Ufo sighting.
So you have to get someone tell them
you're going to put them on the news and
say, listen, I, you know, I was
a, we were about to film this guy.
Do you think you could pretend
that you had seen the Ufo?
Every fucking one of them said yes.
It was crazy. You could tell though,
you couldn't tell man.
What do you watch the playback?
You couldn't tell they were bullshit.
It was no different than listening to
people. And you show talk about big foot.
There is a difference though because you
know what's funny is a lot of um, we,
we deal with a lot of law enforcement
will cause they'd go out to rural
residents is like breaking,
it's like stealing chickens or
freezers like big foot steel.
Chickens are omnivores and uh,
a lot of cops watch are the Guy John
Friend is a cop was out before he,
he's certified federally to be a
deception expert when he trains other law
enforcement agencies. And uh,
we've heard like other, uh,
police training and she's like, well
they teach them like, uh, uh, deception.
Like what to look for when
people are lying and they watch,
they watch our show for the witnesses
and they said they're surprised at how
they aren't lying.
Almost all the ones they see how more?
Three cause I bet that guy sucks at that.
I don't know other ones or other, other,
other, other like other people
that did instruct on them
better. That shit. The Nim
I could just see Roscoe Pico.
Yeah. How much rain, you know,
expert in the laws in the
hearts of deception. Oh, Ross.
On the Sni by me. The Duke was, um,
like if that kind of, if that kind of
officer said I was a trained professional.
How many times have you been
out on a show? Right? No
though where you're going with
the witnesses and you go, man,
I think this guy might be full of shit.
Not We just did. Um, well I can't,
I can't tell you what, which ones
haven't. I don't think none of the,
none of the ones that we aired. And
Dude, if someone was pulling a prank,
believe me,
they'd be growing up not pulling
the prank. Just they're crazy
and they want a friend instead.
They have a big foot story. Yeah. Oh
we get, there's some of that for sure.
But you know, we, we don't put those
people on a show. Like they might,
they might show clips from the town hall,
but we don't go out to
their spot with them.
And a lot of those guys
would go out with like,
they've already been
vetted like several times.
Local BFR investigators have gone there
with the person and gone over the old
siding.
Although we did have,
we just did one on the show where we're
pretty sure that we don't know for sure
what we do. The guys were pretty
sure that he was a line, you know.
Well if you guys are sure that guy
was lying, I bet he's fucking lie.
Like moneymaker those. I,
you've seen the show, right?
Moneymakers just real stairs out. I'd be
like, you know, just thinks it's funny.
That is his name. First of all,
it's real name is Matt moneymaker.
That's hilarious. Dad's a famous
bankruptcy attorney here in Beverly Hills.
They enrich moneymaker.
That's even funnier.
Rich money made the bankruptcy attorney,
I mean,
if you were going to have a Coen
brothers movie and it was going to be a
plotline, didn't involved a big foot TV
show, you guys would be perfectly cast.
You know, you blow the Sasquatch
expert is always bigger than the video.
Matt moneymaker,
the guy's name is moneymakers that alone.
It sounds like a character. It's
awesome. Yeah. You guys all get together.
Like how did this show gets started?
Um, I hooked up with Matt, uh,
through, well he runs the BFR bro. I don't
know if you've ever looked at website,
bigfoot field researchers organization.
It's got like 50,000 sightings on it,
whatever. And it was real hard to
get him back then. Like, you know,
and I was just like whatever.
Fishermen lager guy didn't have any
credentials or anything like that.
But I always went out and I knew a lot
of the natives out there and I worked in
the woods out there and I spent time out
there and I talk to people and I just
need to lay of the land. So I hooked
up with this guy, John Frayed is,
and then I was like a volunteer, whatever
it would be a far off for a few years.
And then in 2003,
they were filming that show mysteries
and counters on outdoor left network.
It was Matt, not, I'm not in if ever.
So I was just one season. But uh,
Matt and autumn,
we're on it. And then I was on
like three episodes of that.
We were cruising around in northern cal
and, um, uh, then he made me like, oh,
whatever investment you have to get,
you know,
you had to go through steps
being an investigator.
Like you gotta know what you were
talking about. And maybe now there's,
there's definitely people
that are in the BFR now.
There's like several hundred
people across countries.
It's good cause it's a broader net,
but some of the people just
don't have the woods experience.
Like when they go out
there, they don't, uh,
like people misidentify stuff all the
time. Like, you know, a lot of the stuff,
a lot of stuff I gotta do
appeal to some of that.
I'm a big foot action out there.
You get out there and it's a bobcat and
he or there's a barred owl moved in and
you know, at some bar dot. Yeah.
Could be just stuff like our bear,
whatever.
But I'll say this for all the Times that
people say they saw big foot and it was
a bear. I'll bet you there's way more
times where people saw big foot and go,
I just saw a weird bear, right? Because
they brang came in process big foot,
especially before sixties.
There's my buddy Scott McLean lives
right down here in Santa Monica.
He's compiled that he's putting a book
out and it's all like pre 1950 newspaper
accounts.
He's got like 1500 of them from North
America back to the 17 hundreds of people
reporting orangutans because it was
before gorillas were discovered that wants
to,
gorillas were discovered,
people the description switched
from orangutan to gorilla.
Would they compare it to, or a wild
man? There's wild man stories like,
um, up in humble, they call them,
the loggers call them. Uh, since, uh,
since the 18 hundreds. Wood,
apes and brush apes. There's,
there's a 137 names up and down
the west coast with monkey or ape.
And then they like Monkey Creek, Ape
Canyon, Monkey Ridge, eight ridge.
Like they're all over the place.
And they'd get that name because that's
where the brush shapes lived. Jesus.
How fucking cool would it be if
they actually got some real fudge,
some real honest to good at goodness.
You can't fuck with it.
And at least my phone one footage and,
or quote captured one or captured a
Sasquatch tracked one and dragged it out
there. There's footage. They won't
release it. We just went there.
We did an episode there. Uh, I
won't release. No, it's a tribe.
They got on a security
camera behind the casino.
What and why won't they release
it? Dude, it's, it's super heavy.
Uh, the squatch to the
natives is, um, listen,
anything for money, liquid they did
with these, they'll take the money.
They set up casinos down there. They seem
to offer him some cash. Xavier. Now do.
There's certain, there's some tribes,
there's a few tribes like that,
but most of them that there's still old
people in charge that like they listen
to them about that kind of stuff, like
cultural stuff. So the Sasquatch video,
if they,
that's their culture that you would
never be able to release a video of it.
It's funny because I've talked to some,
some tribes where they
said that that it's,
it's signifies the end of the world is
Sasquatch has brought in like captured.
Yeah.
It'd be like,
that's like their life has gotten so crazy
that someone caught a big foot or you
know, brought in a body, whatever. Well
now this guy who I think is full of shit,
he was telling the story
about shooting the baby.
Why wouldn't you just bring
a piece of it with them?
Why would you cut off a finger if he's
willing to cut killing on these fucking
things? Like it's a, like it's a dog
or like it's a coyote or something.
He just take the blood to
another blood DNA per person.
How Crawford's in at that
point his buddy came over,
was super pissed at him for shooting it
and then they were starting to trick was,
is at this point getting really dark
and they're just going like, okay,
there's gotta be another bit.
It takes two to make babies.
There's gotta be another
big one. They let he, they,
they definitely regret not bringing it
because they could have brought the baby
line weighed like 30, 35 pounds. Like
that doesn't make any sense to me.
I don't believe him. It sounds like
horse shit. It sounds like horse shit.
The guy doesn't have a photo of it.
He shoots a big foot and he's not
going to bring something to it.
There's no way you would
bring nothing back.
But they map the genome of that sense of
that flush sample he brought in. Yeah.
But that's some shit
they found there after the fact.
He didn't take it facility and
bring it with them. Right? Yeah.
There's no direct chain of custody.
But um, did, you can't argue DNA. Well,
if you really do say that the DNA has
been mapped and it is something new
hominid but isn't the woman crazy?
That's DNA. I'll say. I didn't say that.
Well I mean that there's at least that
at least there's some controversy about
it or some controversy. If there's any
controversy, just take it to like a,
like a regular DNA map and starting
like a known company. There,
there is,
there's other and the other labs are
coming up to the same conclusions as her.
What's her name? Melba.
Melba. Mel Lba Ketchum.
K. E. T. C. H. U. M. She has like,
I guess like DNA diagnostics
done in Texas, but we just,
we went to a genetic lab
recently with some, um,
some hair from that back when that
whole thing that, you know, the,
the video he told you about the video
with a 10 foot big foot walks up to the
dumpster. The things about 10 foot.
Yeah. Where was this? Um, Oklahoma.
We got, I never got to
see, but I don't, I,
we know people that have seen
it and they didn't get it.
Why haven't you gotten to see it?
It's it's,
it's locked in the vault and the
tribal chairman won't, won't really,
it won't let anyone even see it anymore
because what happened was word leaked
out. There was a big foot,
there was Bigfoot's anybody.
You go to this place in Oklahoma, it's
what they traveled. The river routes.
They follow the rivers.
There's thick brush and bogs along
the rivers and they've traveled that
especially at night and this casino
was near. It was near enough to that.
They'd come up there and they're,
they're real cut around natives because
natives don't shoot that. I'm very odd.
It's rare for a native to
shoot at a squash. They
respectfully leave them alone.
They'll put out food for him
and leave is what they do.
They don't have any photos of him either.
Some,
some have the upper up in Humboldt there
was a family of some local Indians that
shot footage. It's about from 400
yards away and it's looking down there.
They were out scouting elk and it's
a female was feeding down in the,
in the bottom some kind of
vegetative matter. I'm not
sure whether it was eating,
but she was digging something up.
Like it might've been some kind of
root and they filmed it for like 13,
14 minutes. But you know, it's like
400 yards away with the things,
probably about seven
foot tall and 400 pounds.
So this woman who Ms Ketchum,
who's uh, doing this, this,
this study, uh, it's,
she's apparently putting it out for peer
review. Is that what's going on? Yeah.
So she's made the peer reviews going on
the, yeah. Or her conclusions are done.
The peer review is going on right now
in Oxford University is one of the labs.
It's in on the DNA study now. There's,
um, I can't say, I mean that's their deal.
I can't, I can't say, um,
what other labs are doing it.
But you'll, you would know
the names. There's a, there's
a big public university,
one of the guys who runs the genetic park
department's doing it and, and their,
their initial results
or they're blown away.
There's a picture of a big foot back.
It's the best picture.
I think that was fake.
It's a fig. I Dunno,
I might not be,
I think it is.
What if [inaudible] fleets were
born very big and they only like,
we're big like one day and they grew
really small hole. Shut the fuck up now
nigger backwards or something just broke
every person's brain who's listening to
this thing they're not from or dare you
be.
So your,
your first encounter came after you
were already obsessed with big foot.
Totally. What became, what started
it off? How did you become obsessed?
I told you my story. I talked to a
trapper and he told me it was real.
Then I was really freaked out.
I saw the Patterson Gulen film, like
on some TV show when I was about five,
because I remember I, I had just started
kindergarten and I could get, uh,
I could take books out at school.
At that point I was looking
for bigfoot bucks and it just,
just caught you, like you would just
mess with it. Yeah. And then, um,
I was that, I grew up down here. I was
a surfer and all that and you know,
skate punk and, uh, after high school
I was going to, I was doing it,
I was piloting outer can is if, you
know those Hawaiian canoes, outriggers.
I was racing those and we were like the
top team in the country and you know,
doing like world championships and all
that stuff. So I stayed down here longer,
but I was wanting me to humble
because I was in a surfing.
I like big waves and there was big foot
and big surf up there and I was like,
man, places killer. I'm going there.
So I moved up there and I started, uh,
did some logging jobs and started meeting
people in the community and worked
with some natives and kind
of got in more and more.
I just really started delving into,
like, if I heard about a report,
I'd go check it out. Um,
talk to whoever I could.
I'd like big foot shirts or hats.
I'd,
wherein people country to
go believe in big foot, you
know, you know, I'd say yeah.
They'd say, uh, I saw on one time he like,
it was crazy how many people you got in
rural areas, how many people, and it's,
there's so many,
there's so much hard data form,
like where you live with the
sightings are, it's generally 90%,
90 plus percent of the sightings, over
90% of the settings are, you can fall.
It's like a,
you look at it where there's 20 inches
of rainfall or more like theirs.
That's where they live. Yeah. Yeah.
And there's like, there's a bell curve.
What you'd see, what the natural
occurring animal for like foot size. Um,
without God, I should have
brushed up on this. He said,
I said to think about saying something
stupid on the front of the camera.
When I'm doing big foot step at a,
well, there's a lot of possible
a, you know, when you, when you,
as soon as you start saying you
believe in big foot, it's going to,
it's impossible to, you know,
to have everybody take you
seriously. Right. You know,
let's fuck those people there. They're
the wrong, well eventually it's going to,
if it, if it is a real thing, someone's
going to get something conclusive. Right.
And they're able to justify,
well, what's the most,
what's the most conclusive thing besides
the Patterson footage that I think it's
bullshit that just the enormous amount
of footprints that have been cast for the
folks on Ustream. He brought me a, uh,
a replica of the best footprint and it's
fucking awesome if that really is a,
a from an animal.
Holy Shit is that think big.
Yeah. And I'm actually, I got a,
I got a copy of the ha it left a knuckle
mark to where it stepped up over a um,
uh, like a four foot step up. It went
up and put its knuckles on the ground.
I got that out in the car check at Shea,
but she, those little rich patterns,
only living flashlights like those red,
a cutout foot or like a fiberglass mold
would not leave that ridge pattern in
that moisture. Right. This, all this stuff
right here. The national flag. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, any tracker, I'll tell you that.
Wow.
So this do you think is a for
sure legit big foot footprint.
Oh yeah. It's considered the best one.
It's the best one without clear journals.
And that was cast by a deputy Hereford
and graves county, Washington.
And when you say
creek cleared dermal is
for folks who don't know,
that's one of the most conclusive pieces
of evidence for the people that the
scientific community that support the
idea of a giant primate is dermal ridges
that you have like similar
to fingerprints, you
know, you have those, uh,
on the bottom of your foot.
And these,
these animals actually leave
these in some of the tracks,
which would be incredibly
difficult to replicate.
Do they? Jimmy Chilcott, he,
he talked the FBI labs in Quantico,
Virginia.
Like when you go through the academy,
he's the latent fingerprint expert,
blah blah. Well, they were trying
to see like when they found just a,
like a gun at a murder scene,
there's prints on it and that just no
matches that he was the guy that you used
for 15 years.
He went around and fingerprinted
and footprinted every prime it,
he couldn't zoos research labs
and printed thousands of gorillas,
orangutans, monkeys, chimpanzees, blah,
blah Gibbons.
And uh,
so after all this time it was because
since they have a smaller gene pool,
they don't interbreed was the
idea was they were trying to see,
was there any pattern discernible like
Asians are Africans or Europeans or
native Americans. Like if they just
found a gun with a fingerprint,
was there any thing that would,
that would show it's from like what race?
At least it was right. And the answer
was no. But as a result of that study,
he became the world's leading expert on
primate compensate us. Wrong, dramatic,
dramatic God. Dramatic Lipsticks,
dermal ridges. It's terrible. Yeah.
Right. Can I get a little tongue tied
of them? Some of that stuff, but uh,
I can spell it, but um, and so anyways,
he's testified in court for like smuggling
cases, you know, people bring it in,
they'll say, no, the sound
was born here and he'll,
he can go ahead and show
the fingerprints Bot.
And so he studied the tracks and he's,
and this guy has put people
away in over 400 capital cases.
He was the expert witness is where
the evidence was fingerprints.
And he went on on
discovery channel and said,
I stake my professional reputation
and name on that. These are genuine.
There's an undiscovered
primate leaving these tracks.
And even when people are saying
like, well, you just opened up like,
you know yourself to like have it
like, or these 400 you've gotten. Now
the defense lawyers could say this guy
is crazy. What? Right. And he goes,
I can prove it in court. So he's not
even worried about it and it hasn't,
he hasn't had to,
but he said he could.
The uh, what's interesting to me is, uh,
the idea that there could be
an undiscovered animal, uh,
and that,
uh,
someone someday is going to bring it
in just like they have with this, uh,
the big chimpanzee that was a ledge.
Congo.
It's called a bondo actually, but no bowls
or the, the little ones like regular,
like a cousin to regular champion.
They fuck a lot.
They're horny ones.
Bondo apes are these giant
chimps or ability bill it. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. They're um, in a part
of the Congo, um, which really,
really fucking hard to get to.
And since the 19 hundreds,
there was stories of these big giant,
great chimps and that was from the
Michael Crighton movie, the Congo,
they actually depicted these things in
there, these big giant and they'll walk,
try sometimes. Yeah. Yeah. This is a,
they're called lion killers of time.
Exactly. Yeah. They, they
have two words for champs.
They called him tree beaters or
lion killers and there's some chips.
They have photos of dead ones.
I mean,
these are real legit 100% real
primates that are still a like very,
very controversial. It's, it's still,
there's a lot of people that didn't
know they existed until the 90s were,
weren't sure til Karma. Carl Armaun,
who's a Swiss wildlife photographer, he,
he, um, got some evidence,
some bones and some stuff and then
became obsessed with it and started going
there. But he has camera trap photos of
them. They have a total of 2000. Exactly.
Exactly.
They brought back some classroom casts.
Like those that weren't even as good
as this. Right. And there's more,
there's more evidence for
Sasquatch than those, those, uh,
Billy apes really well.
There's actual real good
photographs of these all the apps.
So high hazard there is, um, but the,
but the point is that for the longest
time people were saying that this was
bullshit and now they know
100% that this is real.
And the Congo as people living in it,
you know,
they ain't nobody live in when these,
they're too much. So up in that area,
they're just pushing their, now, you
know, there's still tons of virgin timber.
They're cutting down up there
and the Congo. So huge too.
Another thing that people don't realize,
it's like literally almost as dense as
the entire distance between California
and New York. Like there's that
much Congo. It's fucking enormous.
I noticed that. Yeah, I might be wrong
about the country, but the Congo, Congo,
the Congo jungle, the rain to
talk about the country. But yeah,
the Congo base,
that,
that animal being something that was
mythological and now is a real thing.
There's that give you guys hope. Does that
like make big, big foot people that go,
yeah. See Bitch, you could see this some
shit out there that you couldn't find.
I used to be pretty militant,
like sometimes
violent and my defense of
the Sasquatch existence,
but I don't even worry about it.
I've seen him and I know,
I know there's enough tissue samples
and they're now getting exam.
There's so much going on.
Um,
there's a lot of hair experts
getting in on the hair cause it, uh,
I'm not sure what exactly what it is,
but some about the platelets
where they line up,
they've gotten better microscopes or
something that they can see him better.
I'm not sure what it is, but the, um,
these hair experts are getting really
into the Sasquatch here because it's
unique. There's nothing that matches
it at, and it's, and there's the, um,
there's just certain characteristics
about Sasquatch or it's like every sample
that's legitimately,
it's handed in and it's not,
it doesn't try to be horse or bear or
whatever, but every sound gets turned in,
has these same characteristics.
And there's a,
there's a joint study going on like
different experts in that field who are
working around like from different
countries even that are all examine these
hairs and like marking these markers and,
and uh,
it's like they're real excited about it.
You know,
it's really going to be interesting when
the skies are filled with drones and
drones can take images of
anything anywhere they want
at anytime and they just
fucking send them over
the Pacific northwest.
They already kind of have that
with everyone having cell phones.
That's just the thing that
I just don't understand if,
if there's so many people
that see this and there,
there's still no photos and then
there's photos and like the hair,
the hair and the blood
and everything like that.
I know that it doesn't take that
long for it to get the, you know,
for them to say, you
know, this is deer blood.
This is so and so blood
that this is something. But,
but if they're all saying that it's
unknown, then why are you, have they,
has there been multiple agencies that
have put out reports about this or is
there any, you know, these teams
you're talking about sun like, like,
like, like if there's been so many blood
samples and hair samples and they're,
they're all being tested and they can't
find out what this blood is because they
could, it doesn't take that long
for them to take blood and go,
this is deer blood, you know, so,
so if they're all saying like, hey,
we don't know what this blood is.
Have they been giving out like
statements or press reports or you know,
stuff about this. Is there, is there
information out there about them saying,
we don't know what this blood is?
Yeah,
there is.
But you got understand is like the
science world is so political and so
backstabbing and so,
and they're so afraid to like do something
unconventional cause you just get
barred in the field that they're real
reticent to like do stuff like that.
But there are some that have like Dr
Fehrenbach and some others that have,
and there's others that
look at it and they won't,
there's a lot of people who work
in the bigfoot field anonymously,
like other scientists that collaborate
with them that just don't want to deal
with any ridicule or get not get
promoted or whatever it may be.
I watched a documentary where a doctor,
uh,
some sort of a professor at a
university was talking about, um,
the fact that even though he supports
big foot, he does it very reluctantly.
He supports the idea big foot exists.
It goes because quite honestly,
until one's discovered it
until there's conclusive proof,
he says it's just a point of ridicule.
It's just one of those things.
Talk about Doctor Meldrum and auto state.
I don't know where he's from. Uh, he's,
and he's just, he's a genius. He's written
like four books on the foot anatomy,
how humans have gone from Quad,
how like back, you know, evolution,
how we went from Quadrat pad to buy pedal.
He's like the foremost expert guy
in the world on that. And, um,
he was actually one of the guys at the
body recovery site with us when we went
up in there and he, he believes that
he believes the shooter story also.
He was there like everyone that
goes there, that guy, yeah.
Everyone that was there that, that's
there that week came away believe in him.
Why did he bring something back?
It's silly.
I'll tell you later off
the air. Okay. All right,
well there's some sort of a secret ladies
and gentlemen and I can't share with
you. That might be the
answer to this whole crazy.
It just would answer some a little bit.
Well they were,
they were,
they were pounding beers and they had
just saw that word and a guy and they
didn't want to, like, they were,
they have a drive to get back
to camp and they had it, they,
the dude was afraid to get uh, like a
DUI or something cause they, you know,
whatever, we're out in the woods
like, you know, just drinking beers,
driving around out the track,
whatever it was described.
And those are the guys that
shot a pig foot baby. I know,
well the only the one guy did,
the other guy was anti the whole time.
And other than that,
like what is a,
what is a good piece of evidence that
someone could look at Freeman footage?
Freeman footage.
I'm convinced that's real Freeman footage.
What is Freeman footage? Fall
Freeman was, uh, he was, uh,
the mill creek watershed
up in the Blue Mountains,
northeast Oregon and southeast
Washington. Um, there's this huge area,
like a lot of municipalities have
their own water districts and they'll,
they'll own like,
you know,
tens of thousands of acres of watershed
land and you're not allowed up in there
cause it's a water supply. They don't
want like diesel in it or anything.
And he was the patrol guy up in there
and he was seeing big foot's find their
tracks and actually seeing
them in the day light up there.
So we started carrying a video camera
and he got footage of that and I'm 100%
convinced that real Brion pull that
shit up. Freeman big foot footage.
This is from the 90s. Yeah.
And then he has another clip
that he wouldn't, he died,
he got diabetes and died
young but about 15 years ago.
But he has another clip where he
falls down and starts screaming,
kind of cry and it gets bluff charged
for when he gets it real close to the big
mail comes up at,
I'm like full guerrilla style charge
and he got footage of it and he never
released it because a, he
looks so bad and it, you know,
he got pissed his pants or something.
I just saw something in the woods
and those tracks are authenticated.
Do you see much here?
Here?
I hear the brush popping and stuff.
Oh, well there you go. But keep watching.
You're up here. Yeah, it's pretty, yeah.
From watching these videos,
like whenever I think I've, um,
potentially I don't want a big foot.
I never take the camera off.
I don't know one thing,
when it costs got up there to
probably drop it on the ground,
it shouldn't be here.
Does he see it again or is that,
I don't think so.
What makes you convince it that's real?
Just like the size of
it and the way it moves.
People went back up there and said it
was well over seven and a half feet tall.
I dunno where the
comparison video is for it,
but people did go up there and then right
after that they ended up clear cutting
that whole thing.
I'm putting like a campground right
there that they're actually staking out.
There's like some ribbons you can see
that flag tie on a couple of the trees and
it was marked for being
turned into a campground.
That to me looks way better than the
Wright Patterson or the Roger Roger
Patterson footage just
because, uh, it's not as clear
anything about the
Patterson given filaments.
You're seeing the copies you've seen on
TV or like every time they make a clone
copy,
and this is like 30%,
30% resolution for the Chris
on the original Patterson,
the original footage piece,
which no one knows where it is now.
Probably Al Adley has it is
really clear, clear than the, Oh,
what you see on TV a lot. Like, um,
nat geo did a good digit
digitization of it and they, um,
they've shown that that's the, that's
like the clearest version you can get now.
But like the stuff you'd see on TV back
in the day, you, it'd be all blurry.
It wasn't, the original is not blurry.
Who's this Guy Bob Herana must.
It says that he was a
Douche bag alcoholic.
I just a liar Gibbons neighbor.
It's like, dude, okay.
You know what the whole
Kennedy assassinations over I,
I'm the one that shot Kennedy.
It was me case closed.
So he's just some crazy dude is
trying to take, he's not crazy.
He's just an asshole.
She's kind of a day's pretty much pretty.
She move out. It really was a big
foot if it really was a, a video
of a live Sasquatch and this motherfuckers
running around pretending that he was
a part of a hoax.
Well, he, he's, there's a, I'm
this guy, if you're into this,
you can look it up Roger night,
but um,
I forgot what it's called and he wrote
like a 74 page thing where he interviewed
Hieronymus it went through and
tore apart his story, all his,
he's made like five different statements
about how the costume was constructed.
Well, Gimlin said that it was possible
that it was a hoax. He said he was older.
He says, I was totally
convinced no one could fool me.
And of course I'm an older man now
and I think there could have been the
possibility of a hoax,
but it would have had to have
been really well planned by Roger.
I told him, he said, he's,
I just, I've talked about,
I was just with Bob this weekend. He's
the raddest I swear to God did, he's,
he was, uh, he was one of the
first guys are evil Knievel.
He was like a dare devil guy. Like he's
just a raft guide and salt of the earth.
And we are asking about that. And he
said, the way the questioning was going,
he was just getting bored, whether
badgered when it, he said, yeah,
there's always a possibility you could be
hugs. And he's like, I know what I saw.
The thing was, I was looking at it
at eye level for my horse. They,
when they wrote their, there's
B roll footage, you know,
they ride the horse next to the tracks
and the horse prints are not going as
deep as those footprints.
Really. Yeah. What,
what do you think these fucking
things eat? Everything. Everything.
A berries. Um, they're omnivores.
They, you know, they're there.
They'd have obviously have a high
caloric intake to be that big.
And so in the wintertime they
probably eat more meats. Like bill,
they'll hunt deer, elk bear, black
bear. They hunt them. Yeah, they,
they use tools to the youth.
Sometimes.
We've seen that some evidence where
they've, um, or the elk, the flesh deer,
elk out of a metal, they'll come running.
It'll take the same routes every time.
And one will be on the,
like one o' rore at one side,
like hundreds and said they'd been up,
you know, bow hunters creeping up on a,
on a little herd in the med or something
else and that just God awful roar,
scream, come from one side, they all
run into their side and there was wack,
you know,
and I'm just seeing like where they'll
just take a club and as a deer go run and
by this club in the front legs and shatter
their front legs and then go over and
break. They'll break their neck when
they kill and they break their neck.
So they kill them with objects.
They used the monetizer,
he's log or something and
you know, I think most of us
use their bare hands then.
Um, they're that big. They would
their bare hands, oh, easy, easy.
They'll pick them up, they'll,
they'll, they'll take a full grown up.
It's looking over their shoulder
and walk off with it. Jesus Christ.
Like I've heard so many stories like do
not do that electronic bullshit and be
like, you know, just people tell
what they saw and they, you know,
obviously there's something
that you could go,
that guy is full of shit or whatever,
but I'm not like genuine people that
you're talking about just going like,
this guy's not shitting me and you hear
these stories and I've never seen him
cause I've, I've only seen one really
moving good. And I was at night,
it was on the hickory again,
the hickory Apache reservation.
How many times have you seen big foot?
Probably a half dozen. Half dozen.
Only time in the daylight.
And I didn't see it.
It was just stand there and I turned, my
head was gone and I didn't see it again.
That's what I smelled real good.
And then I'm the one at Hickory.
I saw 2004 it came,
walked,
we had all these infrared cameras and
stuff planted the tree line and it walked
across the South Alpha field and came
into our camp. Everyone was down to fires,
kind of spread out camp.
We were at the chief of police
for the WHO's according to,
for all law enforcement on the Hickory,
Apache,
Rez and we were on his property and no
one's cute. This deal was a bad ass.
He got in trouble for being
a little too, uh, you know,
he'd beat the shit out of people you like.
Like if he couldn't,
couldn't prove some guy broken as some
old lady's house, you know, it's a razor.
When those terms, it's going on everyone,
this guy's on math, whatever, you know,
he's stealing. And if he couldn't prove,
like if he couldn't catch the guy,
he would just take him outside and beat
the shit out of like one of those guys.
So no one's coming up.
This guy's ranch,
he was the very end ranch then it was a
continental divide behind there and it
went from like 25 miles to the
next set of houses. And uh,
this thing came from the continental
divide side came walking up and I didn't
see it walk up.
I,
I wasn't aware of it until we had this
guy who was a special forces colonel and
the special forces. Dr. Guy, not Jamie,
the guy I was with when I saw the one
that I'm beloved night and I thought it
was him dressed all in black and just
weren't because it was below freezing.
We're like 9,000 feet
and I thought it was him.
I'll bundle it up wearing like a Parker's,
I wasn't sure,
but it was all black eye.
I was going to let you doing cause I
could hear fingernails going down the side
of a tent like it was. She like that
fabric just we'll figure it out.
Isn't that fabric sound nylon and it was
going around the tent and it got over
to the front where the,
it was our bait tent where we're keeping
all the food we were putting out for
bait was that it was, it was new and
then I'm like why? Because it walked.
I get up for a second and show you.
Yeah,
I was watching it for a while and I
had night vision or I had night vision
around my neck and I didn't cause
you don't want to be like the creek,
like get caught staring at someone
through night vision at night, you know.
So I didn't even look,
I thought it was just a one of
us walk like a man except for it.
Um,
there's walking like a man,
but it looked like he looked like he
was looking on the ground for something.
But I think it was was in hindsight
knowing how careful they are about where
they step,
not to step when they leave.
They're real conscious not to leave
tracks like that for the most part.
And it was,
I think it was looking at where it was
stepping so it wouldn't step in and lead
a print,
but it was just walking so it needs to
step in like mud or something like that
to me was walking the walk and
walk like this the whole time.
But they would kneel down like just get
on one knee like that and mess around
the front of the tent and
they want to go to this tab.
The only girl that was kind of there
was going to hurt Ted going back.
It's hard for people to
hear you when you saw him.
This is going back and forth and I
watched it for about five minutes and the
moon was coming. There was almost a
full, I can't remember exact man. And uh,
it was walking and then the moon
was just about to hit the field.
It was an old Alfalfa field this
guy had and he would plan it,
but the deer and elk were so thick up
there. He just up and let them eat it.
He just quit farming and there's Alfalfa
ground for like, like a hundred acres.
And so,
uh,
this thing walked back across the village
as a moon that was coming down and
just walk profiles.
I thought it was the colonel.
I go back down to camp and I was
going and uh, they were like,
was that you throwing rocks?
Pebbles at us there.
Pebbles being thrown down by the
guys and they thought it was me.
And like if you're a squashy not
screaming like you don't do like,
hey that's fool this guy or you just
don't do shit like that if you're out or
you'll get banned, you know, wants
to go out there if you're a squatter.
Is that what you said, the verb or that
I thought you went instead. You were,
I thought you were saying if you were
a squatch like saying here's you throw
rocks at people. Yeah. Yeah. And
so I'll just finish real quick.
It walked away and I got it back on and
everyone's there had this guy that was
bigger than me go stand. By the time
I went back to my original position,
he was walking around the tents and I
didn't you just something seven foot or
like six and a half foot. It's not
real clear. Like I didn't, I wasn't,
I hadn't made mental notes.
How exactly did these tents where in a,
someone was walking around how
big they look in scale. So,
but when I saw this guy was about six,
five or so down there
walking around the tent,
he was just warped by this thing
and it wasn't that much taller,
maybe like you know, six, nine,
seven foot. But just the bull.
It was just easily twice the way
to him or more easily at least.
Where'd this thing go?
It walked back and just walk straight
across the meadow and in the moonlight
just as it walked past him and that
popped up and started hitting that whole
area and it just went back in the woods.
It, my dad who was a total skeptic,
he came out there just you know,
camp for a week and they
have like a father son trip.
He actually heard them
like talking and uh, not,
not at right then, but then, uh,
the night before that he'd heard them
talking like a couple of them up there and
they were actually Hawkin they do like
to his gym. Ever heard the Sierra sounds?
No,
I got in the car,
I'll burn you a copy of these guys
got hours of recordings in the Sierra,
Nevada's of them chattering away and
those things are being translated by
military translators right now.
There's a,
there's a breakthrough on that front too.
There's all kinds of breakthroughs
going down. Right. So this,
this sound that they make it,
was it anything like with this other guy
was talking about the guy who says he
shot a baby. He, they were like
mumbling like almost like death. Yay.
They sound like they were profoundly deaf.
I've heard him do this a few times and
it sounds like to me what it sounded like
to me it was kind of like maybe like a
monkey trying to talk Chinese something,
something like that. You know that's
funny. Monkey to tongue chain.
Yeah. But like more grumbly though, like
more wall and I've heard the low mumble,
they mumble like, so the idea is that
they have a language or they just,
all the natives and he talked to any
native anywhere will tell you the yeah,
they have language and they can
understand certain words. We say
they can understand.
Certain words were saying,
but we don't have a video of the one
of these things. We don't have to do.
The Patterson gave one the freemen yeah,
but they could be bullshit. They I, okay.
Freeman, I'm not so sure,
but I can tell you for, yeah,
there's been a,
and there's other breaks.
Who's going down on the
patterns and Gaylen film? What
does it break throughs? Um,
they've actually found some of the
original trees that were back behind.
There's been so much regrowth
that these guys, this guy is,
he's the State Park Ranger.
Check the range of cop up there for
Humboldt redwoods, him Robert Letter.
And then another guy, Steve Stroop
hurt the guy owns big foot books, sir.
And Willow Creek has spent two years going
out there and going over the site and
finding an actually found from the
original trees that are obscured.
You can't see him from the
creek pay more cause it's been,
it's been 43 years or
whatever, 45. And, um,
they're all grown up and uh,
they've found trees in the background
that one of the original PG fell.
So we're going to go there and,
and uh,
with all this like three
d laser scanning stuff,
they're gonna be able to
get three dimensional,
three dimensional view of
the whole of the whole creek.
Go back in and plugging the PG films,
like overlay it and they'll get a three
dimensional, like to like a half inch.
How big, how big the subject from the
film is? Well what if it's only five 10,
then what do you do if it's only five 10?
I Dunno, I just don't see that happening.
I don't know. You know, I don't know.
I Trust Bob, you know, cause Bob
Gilman is a really good friend of mine.
He was himself said,
but you said that he was badgered
and he'll tell you he loved this guy.
He would love to hang out. And
then I would, I mean I believe him,
I'm not saying he's full of Shit,
but that there's been a lot says no way.
He said there's no way.
He said it had to be over 500 pounds.
And he this guy's expert hunter,
and he's like watching the muscles.
There's like nine different muscle than
men she can see in the video. Yeah,
but isn't that possible? You just
put some fake mussels on it. Dude.
The Guy Chambers that made the planet of
the apes back in the 60s when that was
made, said he could not do that. He could
not. He went to his death. That's it.
Cause there was always a rumor that he
did it and he was just like, nope. Was,
I'd never did it. He goes, I
wish I could have done that.
And you're talking about two cowboys.
You'd, Roger was unemployed at the time,
coming up with mate. Roger
did buy a costume from, um,
his name was Phillip, his name was last
name was Morris out in North Carolina.
He made a gorilla suit and he
did say shitty $400 gorilla suit.
And it was for recreation's in his,
in his documentary.
And that's not the suit that he wore
in. So anyways, there's, there's,
there's controversy around it for sure,
but there's always people looking to like,
I just wish there was some better
shit. Oh, we all do. And you know,
there's some footage it's
going to be coming out.
The con that's in conjunction
with the DNA study.
It's called the Kentucky footage
and I only seen part of it,
but people that have seen it say it's,
it's the real deal. There's a face shot.
How many do you think are alive? If
you had to, if you had to guess, well,
we're going to start getting some hard
evidence on that due to the DNA samples.
But I would say their camp people say
there's got to be at least 2000 just to
have as many as there
are in North America.
And you're talking Canada
and Canada's big to,
I'd say my guess would be probably
four to 6,000 in North America.
How the fuck are there four to 6,000
things and no one has a good night. Yeah,
that's what I'm saying. Because
for one thing, did your shit.
You're looking at some giant eight
managers shitting your pants,
people free sort.
Do they make sleep?
They definitely go to Kay's and extreme
weather. Really cold, real hot. Um,
native state where we live,
they use these. There's,
there'll be fires in southern Humboldt
and smoke pops out in southern Oregon,
you know, 150 miles away as the k's are
all connected. Oh really? Yeah, the knee.
It's the biggest cave
complex in the world. That's,
but that wouldn't explain everywhere,
but that's pretty bad ass. Yeah.
You're talking on the Sangamon? Yeah.
Thanks. Okay. I didn't know about that.
That's interesting.
So they sleep in case they all than it
is telling us that they bury their dead
and caves and we'll like pilot
with rocks just to put big rocks.
No Man could move in, in places where
machinery is going to go either.
And those cover the cave up.
There's,
we need to find out where the fuck those
caves are and dig them up and find some
big foot bones.
That's what we were going to do with those
cadaver dogs is because we knew like,
um, if that was the male that
was shot, um, because the,
the rumor going around
is that was the mom,
but the DNA shows it was a
male was the father. Hmm.
So maybe it was the grandpa urban grandpa,
whatever old and fucked up stover.
No muscle tone.
We'll see. We'll see. So anyways, if
we could have got those, I'm sure.
I can't imagine them.
It was as big as you said it was.
I couldn't see them carrying it
more than a mile or two, you know,
from there and then find it.
And there was cliffs down the backside.
There was other cave interest is
around who they know that area,
like no one else.
And who knows where they put it.
But I can't imagine them carrying a
600 pound carcass that far. Right.
But you got to assume too that you
remember that movie grizzly man love it.
Great movie where the Dude, uh,
they, they shot at Grizzly and uh,
when they, uh, came back just a, I
think it was a couple months later,
there was nothing. Oh, right,
right. Little tiny pieces of bone.
You know what I mean? Even a, a
600 lbs Sasquatch or something.
If you left the bone behind in the
jungle or in the woods right there,
it's not going to last for long
because this is all the ecosystem.
A whole cycle setup. Like people say,
well, where's the dead ones? Well,
where's the dead mountain lions? We
know there's mountain lions. Okay.
And Mountain Lions live way closer
to people and civilization. I mean,
they have like at the edge,
they could kill the mountain.
Mine in Santa Monica for months ago,
there was a mountain mind siting in
my neighborhood a couple of weeks ago.
There's mountain lions,
they're the tiger that got loose stuff
off the one oh one that's 600 pounds,
orange tiger run.
It ran loose for three and a half weeks
in a six by two and a half mile stretch
of, of, you know, up there.
They had helicopters.
They brought in the six best track.
They brought in the six best tracking
teams from fish and game with their dogs
in all of California came in, but
it was raining. It was winter.
I don't often from it was raining,
but they look for that Bangle Tiger
for three weeks right there off the,
off the freeway and you know,
between Malibu and the valley and
couldn't find it until it walked up to
somebody.
His backyard was staring at her poodle
to what a fucking terrifying look.
That must have been looking for a giant
Bengal tiger that hasn't eaten in a week
or two weeks or whatever the hell it is.
And it's wandering around.
So every corner you turn, that might be
it every time you go down a back alley.
That might be it.
Do we just,
we were just in a tiger preserve
and Sumatra looking for the Orang.
Pendek well that's a, that's a, uh, a
different sort of totally different.
Totally smaller. Way Smaller.
Yeah. And they're not related.
I don't, well, you know,
we're all related at some point.
Pit.
And is there evidence of this thing
dude there that that is like that's the,
that have all cryptids that's the one
that all scientists agree is did the lady
that runs the UN program down
there for like wow serve it.
She's seen it three times. Really?
Yeah. And what did she say it is?
It's some kind of upright
orangutan that walks on two feet.
It's about a meter tall or so, but up to
like 200 like maybe three, 300 feet tall.
200 pounds. Ball of muscle. Whoa. Yeah.
And so we were up there at night and uh,
that,
that we couldn't like we couldn't
get to the locals about the porters.
They were scared to death go out cause
those tires, they are their managers.
They'll eat the tigers. Yeah. Yeah.
We were out there at night looking
for a ring pin decks and the,
so you guys went out at
night in the tire preserve.
You did Jesus fucking Christ. What
were you thinking? That's crazy.
I was thinking it's going
to take money maker.
Do you think it was going to
get him first? How's hoping,
why is he the slow one Florida day slower
than everybody slow compared to what
tiger man, uh, you know, they said,
I said, well, we're in a big group.
Like the last guy out here,
like the month before,
whatever they were walking in a group
that went out to a group of 15 people and
it jumped right in the middle of land.
I got crushed.
His skull ran off to the guy dead.
Well, you know what he did once this,
I do a bit about it.
In my act,
there was a boat and I d I forgot
how many guys were in the boat,
but this tiger swam out
to the boat three times,
killed three fucking pizza up before
it, got tired of doing it, swam out,
climbed in the boat, killed a
guy, dragged his bottom shore,
jumped back in the mortar, swam out
to the boat, killed another guy,
and they're just rolling
like a motherfucker trying
to get away from this thing.
They just get bored. Just one night,
just one day hunt. They hunt those boats.
I mean those are those legal would
guys and they have those guys get more,
they get eaten all the time.
They could swim like a motherfucker.
I did not know that they could
swim like that are the aquatic cat.
It's a scary animal man. They're
gnarlier than polar bears. Yeah,
they're right up there.
Yeah.
The thing about polar bears though
is that did just start eating you.
They don't kill you first.
A tiger at least has the,
the good grace crush your windpipe
and then take you out quick.
Polar bears eat you dick first.
They just start chewing on any part
that could hold down just like a salmon.
You were saying something crazy before
that you have to leave salmon out for
Sasquatch is in some places
they throw rocks at you.
Yeah,
like when you talk to the ne I,
my thing was always go to the tribes and
talking to as many elders as I could.
That would most of it's changed
now more and more. There.
A lot of dealers that talked to
me now say the kids, they're like,
they're all on a hip hop,
like NBA,
like don't give a shit about any of
the traditions or the storage of that
knowledge and they just want to be
like it. They want to be Westernized.
Totally. And um, so the, they'll they've
dealt, they said they would never tell.
They were told, never tell white people,
but they'll tell me, cause I'm respectful,
this subject and I'm into
it and I'm listening.
What you hear is you'll hear all these
things like, well my grandma was around,
they used to do this or
they used to do that.
But the one thing that he's still do up
and down the whole Pacific coast from
California to Alaska is the ne you talked
to any of those net pores when they,
they put the Gillnets cross the
rivers when they pull the nets.
And if they don't put a
salmon up on the bank,
on the other bank for the
squatch that it'll come down,
throw rocks at him or pull the
net in and take all the fit.
Well, what they should do then is
do that and then bring cameras.
Don't leave the May salmon and bring
cameras and boom, you got Sasquatch.
It seems like they, they bait them.
They want them to get this food.
It's an offering. Right.
But they don't, they don't,
they almost never almost
never see him take it.
They'll only take it when you're not
there. But you know, set up cameras,
set up some cameras, leave a fish. That
seems like the easiest way in the world.
They're Jed eyes mad like they,
it's so crazy.
We don't know if it's the electromagnetic
field around things they pick up on,
but they are hip to a lot of,
but they have walked in front of game
cameras before and stuff. So they have,
yeah, we just, there's some
game count photos out there.
Really. The work I work at,
I find those camera photos.
I didn't have one this coming to just say
and when the other day
what I want on my phone.
Yep. Big Flood was one of the
first things that Google pulled up.
Isn't that funny? Game camera photos. Big
Foot was one of the very first things.
You know why Google and I
was, I'm a retard. I see it.
It says you're a smart guy. Oh, there's
one that's totally fake as fuck. Well,
most of them are. We just saw, I don't
think this one is on the Internet yet.
This guy, oh, this one's tripping. This
one looks like a monkey. That's like a,
like a four.
Okay.
Like something on four legs
that's fake. It's fake. Yeah. No,
that they have to walk on two legs or
they're not real. They're not legitimate.
They go on for sometimes for sure.
They'll knock a walk.
Especially the young ones. Yeah.
Some of these like really fake God.
Yeah.
Which ones do you, how do you
discern whether they're fake or real?
MMM.
God, I wish I could get ahold of cliff
and have him send you one right now.
A lot of the best ones do.
People don't. You'd be surprised.
Most people aren't looking for
fame and fortune, like with this,
the most of the stuff that gets
caught of the, we're going,
we went to the Mongolian room.
Do you know, you talk about,
you know the Pacific northwest,
the fifth largest pine forest in North
America is in Arizona. Really? Yeah.
The Mongolian rim.
That's where this is.
Okay.
Well this might have even
been the video we did.
No.
What,
what are you slowing down to? Quarter
speed. What is this? I won't say Shit.
It's hard when we take something
from Youtube, um, put her, I I,
I'm not even sure that all the footage,
that's what big foot and none of it's
in like the HD or anything like that.
It's always like this, you
know, we're really low quality.
How convenient. You know, it's funny dude,
is that the best DNA sample from
Asia came from destination truth,
you know that TV show destination truth.
Yeah. It's kind of Hokey. Whatever.
They just aired it I think the Vietnam
episode and we're going to work,
our team's going to go there because
the thing ran past the camera man at the
base camp ran right by him on the side,
like a big eight footer and they got four
good footprint cast cause it's stepped
in mud a couple of spots. And
Really? Yeah, they got d, that's the,
this is destination truth.
Yeah, the Vietnam side,
I think it just aired last night or the
night before or something. I don't know.
I was on, I was up in the mountains
so I wasn't, and it's a big foot.
It's a Vietnamese when they call
them rock ape. So The v the non,
that's called them rock caves.
Because you're worried about
that Vietnamese big foot. No,
I've never heard a rock.
So did you talk to him and Brock came,
talked to a whole alert
guys or any of those?
All the non like the Ford Ranger guys and
the, you know, behind the enemy lines.
Got even even guys, just regular army
guys, when they're up in the northeast,
like in the [inaudible] territory,
they the rocks and throw apes out
and they call them rock caves.
They throw rocks at him.
They found several footprints and they
also caught something on thermal imaging
that um, might have been a bipedal
creature. It says, however, in the end,
Gates couldn't be sure that they
found evidence of a Bot. Toot, toot.
Some of they say it. That's
not, but to toot, which led, uh,
some viewers to vent their
frustrations on Twitter. Well,
people vent their frustrations on
Twitter and I'm minute of what you'd do.
I only want to read Twitter after all the
what ifs that we've thrown in today on
the big foot front. Just for the
smart people. They can't Miss Kate.
I don't have a smart filter. I need a
smart filter for Twitter. Uh, Nah, he,
the idiots are very, they
should have their say to
homes was not constant. Right.
I honestly don't, I don't read
any reviews. I don't read,
I don't read anything. I don't look
at any of those big foot websites.
I don't really, how come?
It's just, you know,
it's like you must get tired of people
saying that you crazy big foot's fake.
Cause like I said that I was going to
talk to you about this today because uh,
all my life, like I said, I've,
I've read so many books on big foot,
I've watched so many documentaries
are always been fascinated by it.
Immediately people were like,
who can big foods? Food, food,
can big foods foods? Like, no you
don't. No big foot's fake. He just,
I used to Dick, you want everything
to be negative, you fuck right.
And there was a lot of, well you
know, it's like when people say,
well I think that this is my third.
It's like,
like I've said to this thing for like,
you know,
over 30 years and have spent 25
years looking in the field actively.
And I mean I know that real, I've
seen it for myself, I've heard him,
I've talked to thousands of people
that have seen him that are legitimate.
I mean I've seen him myself,
I know the real so that when people go,
well I think this last time hap right.
And they just thought of it
in five minutes and it's like,
well that's like me going to some like,
you know,
astrophysicist guy in a lab with
a giant telescope looking up at,
you know, 30 foot telescope looking
at the stars and studying, you know,
he's got a phd in astronomy and I go,
I think the moon's made a cheese.
That's what I think that's like when
people come to me until they think about
big foot in or what the fuck
they're talking about. Yeah.
It's one of those things, man. It's a,
it's one of those things where I would
imagine it would get really annoying if
that was your life's dedication.
Like I can say I believe in big foot and
people call me an idiot and I'm like,
whatever.
I'm freely factor.
I'm the fucking standup comedian,
you know? There's a lot of evidence.
I'm probably in it.
The pig foot thing is just one little
piece of the puzzle that shows your smart
though. Really? I leave everything open.
You know? I leave open the possibility.
There's a, there's a lot of things that
I leave out, but probably ridiculous,
but that's,
to me then that one makes sense.
There's just too many people that have
seen something. If one of them is true,
it's real.
There's too many different names for
it and native American languages.
I believe there's more than 105
508 categorize for North America.
Yeah.
What's that?
There's not that many things that they
believed that aren't real. You know,
they have like they know,
they pray to certain gods that the,
you know like the rain gods and
fire gods and all that kind of shit,
but they don't have like
things that aren't real.
They don't have too many like or their
spirit animals and bigfoots in both
worlds. Big. That's the one at walls.
Some have like they think it's a real
animal in both worlds, but yeah, it's,
they're not dude. No native will
tell you there are animal there.
There are type of people.
So they think it's just a tribe.
A tribe. Wow. They think of it as
a tribe. Oh yeah. You know what?
We were just in Australia
with the aboriginals.
Those guys blew my mind and they have
so much knowledge about these things.
Like they live,
they have them in Australia.
How the fuck did they get to Australia?
We got our folks,
we'll talk about Trillia.
They're not sure they were,
the aboriginals all say they were there
when they got their 50,000 years ago.
So the big foots are
good at avoiding people.
On every content is not like one group
of big foot's. That's a retard race.
They see him in the summer
way North or the, uh,
where it's daylight all day long.
Like way in northern Canada and stuff.
They'll see him like small, like
outpost villages, like native villages.
They'll come in because they'll go to the
garbage dumps in the middle of the day
and it's like, why don't you guys fill
them? They just, they just don't. What,
why would they just not,
that doesn't make any sense in 2012
that you would see a kid's a kid.
There's a lot of kids now
because of our show too.
Like more kids are in it and like,
they're like, oh, you're like, hey,
we're gonna try to film it.
But these people just don't,
what do you mean they just don't, that's
cool. That's crazy. How could you,
it's just his head.
What's that? Is it crazy?
Have you guys spent any time on big it
is Brian. No, I don't think it's crazy.
What do you think they, you know, they're
busy looking for this thing, hunting it.
They don't carry a camera around for that.
One second though.
These people aren't looking for
big. These people live there. Brian,
are you playing devil's advocate here?
What he does is killing me.
I just can't believe that that
that one person doesn't have,
like when those go cams on and it's HD
go camps that cost $89 or something like
that. That has fucking crazy.
If it happens, it's going to,
technology is catching up to
the squatch for sure. Yeah.
That's going to be the drone
to catch them. I Dunno dude.
So do you believe that they're all over
the country and you believe there are?
No, I've, I've, I've
personally heard them.
I personally heard them and Oregon,
Washington, California, Alaska,
Florida, Kentucky, Florida.
Yeah, the skunk ape.
Really.
And it's not a Cuban
dare you get over here.
Well the, they, they have,
I've started seeing a mountain
lions in Florida Jam. Oh,
he's just another reason like government
doesn't want to acknowledge big foot is,
there's a few reasons governors,
Wanda, but everywhere we go,
we go to these places.
Like they say,
there's no mountain lions here
but they're here. You know,
you keep hearing that until one gets hit
by it or someone would get shoots. Wine.
Well one got shot one
recently in the Ottawa.
They thought they'd been extinct in
Canada or in that part of Canada for more
than since the 18 hundreds those last a
citing that they had and they shot a big
one. Man, they're spread out. They don't
want to do a shot one in Connecticut,
but the, you have to have a
management pilot and it costs.
Millions of these states are all strapped.
You had to have a management plan.
They don't want to acknowledge it.
That's what I said.
We don't have them because they
don't want to have to deal with them,
but with big foot,
I think it was more just what's really
the biggest thing when it comes out.
They're real here soon is to be the
whole like I think there should be like a
lot of PhD students write papers
on this and like psychiatrists and
psychologists are going to write
books on this and on how these things,
there's all this evidence and stories
and just everything right there in front
of you and people refuse
to acknowledge it. Well,
I think one of the reasons why they
refuse to acknowledge is what we've talked
about before.
There's so many people that fake it.
There's so many people
that fake UFO stories.
that fake bigfoot stores.
People are fucking crazy and there's a
lot of people out there. Big Foot storage.
Well you don't think so. I think
anything cryptic man, I think loch ness,
anything UFO, anything
big foot. I think ghosts,
there's a lot of people that are
full of shit when it comes to those,
those stories because those are like
fun stories to bring up. You know?
Like if people say they saw a crocodile,
a generally genuinely believed them.
When you start saying you saw some shit
that's, that's in the cryptic realm, man,
you might've seen it,
but it also might be that you're one of
those crazy that likes to pretend you
saw something awesome.
You talk those people long enough,
it comes apparent that's what's going on.
See,
I wish I was on your show then because
I'm way better at that than most people.
I'm really good at sniffing out bullshit.
We're really good.
We're getting ready to jump the
shark here. Probably pretty soon.
It cause we're run out of the videos of
the cat and they're talking about having
celebrities. Come on dude, I'll
come on. We got to, come on now.
Come on and just let me come on
in and screen your guests. I go,
this guy's gotta be, that'd be honest.
This guy's full of shit. This guy's car.
They'd be screaming at me like,
dude, you're not telling the truth.
I know when people are telling the
truth, I smell them. It's weird.
I've always been good
at no one crazy people.
So if you bring me in front of a crazy
dude and he tells you a big foot story,
I'm going to tell him he's full
of Shit. Well, yeah, so I mean,
I don't believe everything I
hear people go, you guys live.
Are they gonna hear on
there? It's like, well,
you see witnesses we're dealing with,
they've already been vetted.
One show where there was this one
obviously gay guy whose like nick.
Yeah. Whose job it was right here.
The big files. Right. I'm like, bitch,
she ain't seen no, no, no. That guy,
he just tried to drag some dudes in the
woods and hope somebody stumbles on your
Dick. That guy was a wildlife biologist.
Is he good for him? He's full of shit too.
No,
I totally believe that.
It seemed like he was making it
up as he went along to me. Now.
He was a great dude. He
was great. Yeah. Yeah.
He firmly believe that that guy
saw a big foot. Yeah. We spent,
he was his camera, this son of a bitch.
We were with that guy for a week,
like he was our local guide and
he showed us around and he was,
he was fun. You'd love that
guy. He's hilarious. But um,
as he was our guide for a week,
so we were with the guy for a week and
Matt knew the guy for several years
already.
He's been on different expeditions around
the country with them and he never,
he's, and usually when people
start telling those stories,
like more will come up and it changes.
His story is just the same all the
way through it. Sally wrote Italian,
he's smart. It's good job, dude.
Well, I'm not saying, I don't know.
He might actually be the one guy
that's telling the truth. Right.
The one guy that we're all sure is lying.
We'll see if you think
he is to this season.
I'm sure I'll think he's lying
if he think he's lying. I should.
I think almost everybody's
aligned. Yeah. Most people.
I think if you lived out in the woods
and he lived in a rural community,
where there,
where there are big foot's around you
and you've talked to so many people that
like, dude, dude, I like big foot so much.
I thought of getting a buying land in
the Pacific northwest just to live in the
summers with hope of seeing a big
dude. I dude, I get stupid. I am.
I know the place. It's for sale
right now. Really? Where is it?
You sound real estate now? No, no, no,
no citing spots. That'd be a good move,
Dude. I'm talking to the guy
about trying to buy it, right?
If you went and you bought real estate,
heavy,
big foot areas and set up a set plan,
cameras and shit, that's the plan.
I have a lodge.
If you live like somewhere in the
Pacific northwest and in an area,
there's a heavy duty bigfoot sightings.
She's fucking set up cameras everywhere,
everywhere, and every day you go and
check those cameras. I said, well that's,
that's what the Olympic project there's
going on right now. They actually,
one of the,
one of the best pieces,
DNA from the Olympic project
is this weird looking bigfoot.
They've got pictures of it comes up
and sniff the camera and licked it.
And they got saliva off the
camera. Olympic project. Yeah.
Did they have these photos online? Can
you see the photos of him? I think so.
So where did they take the,
like they shipped it next day and
brought it to a site that we have. We,
we uh,
we,
there's a lot of,
there's a lot of cops involved in this
and we have like protocol we follow for
collecting DNA evidence. Cause you
guys laugh about this. I used to,
I was on this crazy squatch adventure,
like pride 2000 to 2001,
2002.
And this thing,
this guy bought property had been
abandoned for 11 years and the squashes,
we're living on the property and they
didn't like him moving and all this stuff
happened, but they, um,
they, uh, they were,
we'd finally these huge scats in the
woods or on the property. They, China,
like giant human shits,
like that'd be like a foot high.
And 18 inches across at the base,
like big thick, like two inch cables.
And I'd collect them and bring them
down with a fishing game and drop off.
Like check out this big foot. You know,
Scott, can you guys DNA test it? You know,
what can you do?
Blah Blah Blah.
And then my buddy got a job at the fish
and game like a couple of years later,
I'm all do whatever happened.
If I'd sabals he's like,
we were talking about about you.
I brought all these big foot scat samples
and I brought in some hair a couple
times and it's not, he's like,
do they talk about some crazy guy
brings it bear shit, drops
it off. They throw it away.
They never even looked at it. They
wouldn't even look at it. Yeah,
they're probably like, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well we're going to check on it. For you.
It was like that. Very unprofessional.
And then you pay for something.
You think that they have to give
you some kind of real results.
They should really be checking fuckers.
Tax Dollars.
Glue hair on his chest is big
but episode or he's a savage.
You're a very good catcher.
Brian's an animal. Um, it,
so the Olympic project says they have a,
the researches in the Olympic mountain
range in Washington state. Uh,
the Olympic project is a comprehensive
systematic camera trap program consisting
of 50 plus cameras placed along predatory
travel routes through the Olympic
mountains.
Our primary focus is to obtain a
series of crystal clear photographs of
Sasquatch in their natural environment.
So,
so far it says they haven't gotten
anything. Is that what it says? Yeah,
they have footprints. They
don't have any, none others.
They see everyone had to sign
DA's about the DNA.
So that could be why that's not on there.
But I s I would see the photos.
You didn't like I looked at,
I thought it was a sock puppet
when I first looked at it,
but the DNA came back with jet.
Yeah. This isn't saying here that they
have anything. It doesn't, no. Doesn't,
not on their website, dude. I'll call,
I'll call the Guy Derek that bears
and deers. It's cool looking.
They've won all the game camp photos.
There's those big contests every like
5001st place. They have one bad ass man.
They've got some awesome photos.
They do have a lot of great wildlife.
The mountain lion stocking the duck
and the duck doesn't see it. Yeah,
they weren't first prize last year
with that one. It's really cool, man.
They show this mountain lion walking
through the snow to and they a bunch of
bears, including bear standing
upright, which is pretty fucking cool.
Bears getting really close to
the trap coyotes. Elk. Wow.
I mean their camera chat photos make me
want to buy some land and set up camera
traps. That'd be bad ass just
to see different shit every day.
You know huge elk. Yeah,
I'll do that. Yeah.
A mountain lion got right up to
the camera. Oh Shit. They look,
they'd notice it like animals.
If you look at most of the pictures,
they'll be looking at the camera.
At least on the second shot.
They'll that infrared flash
goes up. They look. Yeah,
and there's been a lot of cameras
through the squatters. We'll break them.
They'll turn flip around backwards.
I put a camera traps from are they walked
into a camp when I was in and I had
the camera.
The camera's all hidden like in tall grass
and stuff and they're all pushed down.
All of them were pushed down so that
the lens was facing the ground. Wow.
These folks usually just check it out.
Just go to the Olympic project.com just
to look at the actual real animals,
the bobcats and the wildlife. No fucking
big foot though. They got, they got a fee.
They got a photo of elk.
Fucking awesome elks.
Paused right in front of the
camera and fuck. This is amazing.
Can you put it back up on that one? I
can see. Yeah, put up an Olympic project.
This is a myth. The, the photos are
amazing man, but no big foot man.
They've got another camera. There's
a two shot. There's two shots of, uh,
of a squatch coming up to the camera real
close. But it must not be on the way.
You don't. I'll call Derrick
when we're done. And this one,
it says bear gets close to the camera.
They don't, I don't see shit up here.
That's a, that says that
even says it's too big foot.
I don't think it's up there just
because of the NDA. Look, there it is.
That's it. Yeah. Scroll down
to photos are awesome man.
It's really cool that they're saying
that Sasquatch right there. What?
That mountain lion looking fat down.
The next one down. That's the squatch.
Oh wait, where's the one where you can
see it's whole arm and eyeball and stuff.
The creature reappears so it go
back up there. That one? Yeah.
Okay. They've done all this analization
on that and that hair pattern,
the and patterns of that and the tha tha
tha that's like seven that things like
seven feet off the ground. So it can be
a bear. Bears don't get over six, six,
six would be the top like a trophy
bear kind of bear black bears.
There's only black only black
pants, like a producer guy. Uh,
six six is like about as big
as a blackberry. Good. Six
foot, huge for black pair.
Brian,
which uh,
which page did you
look@andthebigproject.com
possible squat sightings possible
squatch side.
Is it on the menu?
But did you guys patent the word
squatch cause I had never heard it.
Is that you? Did you come up
with it? Um, I know Scott Harris.
You never know that guy. A comedian
he has got, what's his name? Harriet?
No,
he wasn't like big timer thing.
But I know he did a
documentary called squatch in,
but I never heard anyone say it before.
I've said it was rainy.
Licky man, this is a what?
I was the first one. Shit.
Yeah. Well can't see shit. I agree.
I've not too impressed when they sons
of bitches but do that. But again,
animal experts have looked at it and the
hair does it match and then how could
you tell me you can't
tell him like an animal,
etc. A PETCO and this is the problem.
The problem is the best fuck that their
best shit is blurry as fuck because it's
set there. The camera's set to take
pictures like 30 feet away. Not a foot,
but they're pro their photo
galleries. Amazing man. Yeah.
I don't care if it's set to take 33
this is, it should be a photo of man.
It should be a photo wanting to fuck
up thing. One comment. I hope so man.
Frustrated dude. It's really fresh. What
if they found out that it wasn't real?
What did you find out? You
already stooped. See that
there's no way you got duped.
There's no,
I'm not worried about that.
So what you saw was so
conclusive that you're 100% sure.
Why didn't you have a camera?
One of those 12 times? I did do,
but it was the only one I saw on
that day that I didn't cause my,
my shit got ripped off.
Like when synclavier and you leave your
truck that will not put psychically knew
that your camera wasn't present.
Imagine if there is so sensitive.
I would have had a camera when I got a
picture. Do you think so? I wouldn't have.
It was, it was less. I slept for
like literally like half a second.
It was just gone.
Once Google goggles comes out,
people need to go hiking for Sasquatch.
People aren't goggle cause there's
people wearing those now that those the a
little GoPros. Yeah, we'll
not have a smaller ones.
We were like little spy ones but does
one suck the rate resolution set to the
goat razor HD. So it's like
people are using coke brothers.
People are mountain among the helmets
they have to someone. This is,
it's going to get ridiculous. So
there's a new, there's a new footage.
We take it as real of a squashed down
on the side of the road that some
hillbillies. God with
a Gopro. Really? Yeah.
The new footage maybe if you look up from
like two or three weeks ago it sat on
the side of the road. It's on the
right. It's up in Canada somewhere.
New Big foot footage. What would you
look up on? Youtube. Canadian. Bigfoot.
Maybe go pro. A lot of sightings
come from Katie. Can I Canadia
and like crazy. It was just
crazy. People reporting them.
There'd be just as many settings
in Hawaii. Right? Right. Or road.
I will not really,
because if there wasn't a
place for them in 1900 or 1850,
everyone knew what a Unicorn was
and no one knew what a big foot was.
But you can find hundreds and hundreds
of newspaper clippings about people
seeing a giant ape. There's no people
saying they saw a unicorn. Right?
Yeah, yeah. It's always the
same thing. Right? Yeah.
And it follows the same pattern is
like we were when we were in Australia,
like we, we'd always heard that
you always were different than um,
that's what they call me. The
aboriginals and the struck home galleys,
we'd always heard galleys were different
than big foot's. When we're down there,
we found out there tear Bigfoot's man.
I mean that the way they act,
we hurt the best stuff or recorded was
in Australia you think the exactly the
same. I don't know about
that, but the, the,
the action, the patterns,
all that was the same.
Did you have photos or are of
anything that you got in Australia?
Like what is all the aggregators
are saying? No, they don't.
The behavioral patterns and and what
people describes, there's a little like,
you know,
maybe the difference between like a,
like a European gray wolf in a North
American grill. You know what I mean?
Like same genus and all that. But yeah,
there's a lot of photos of wolves.
Yeah. But they didn't, they didn't
do that. The biggest, the biggest,
they did a three year study on wolverines.
Almost wolverine you see on shows
aren't wildlife parks. They're there.
They've been like babies that were
captured when her mother got killed or
whatever.
But they did a three year study,
millions of dollars spent on this and
the only footage they got was from like
four to 500 yards away on a
snowfield of a wolverine going away.
And that was a well-equipped,
professionally funded looking for a known
animal and they got one clip in three
years. That's pretty crazy.
Yeah. It's like snow leopards.
They didn't get any footage of snow
leopards until like 2007 do you think that
people just underestimate the
amount of actual forest? God, yeah.
You don't need a million acres
of forest for a squash to hide.
But you think you would because
otherwise people would run into it.
People run into them all the time.
They're seeing all,
it's just not that you guys expected
me ever waver. I need a fucking photo.
Just one. Just one. And
you don't find any of this?
I then I've been with squatters
and stuff that had said like, yeah,
I had my camera around my neck or I was
holding it and I saw it and it looked at
me and they just shit their pants and
froze and even after the thing was gone,
I didn't even think of to take
a picture of toe was gone. Yeah.
I'm looking at this, a Canadian, the
new Canadian big foot footage. Is it?
The one on the side of the
road is down on the side,
stand down like below the below.
He's like walking through a trail.
None of those things just,
it's just a car drives by,
it's down on the side of the road
standing there. Oh really? No.
This one's different. This one's
a dude walking through the world.
When I say hillbilly, I don't mean
any negative connotation of that.
Like to me it's like a, you know,
compliment a hillbilly as a compliment.
I do like I say redneck and Hillbilly,
I don't mean anything bad by it at all.
Well,
a lot of rednecks to like being rednecks
and hillbillies don't like being called
the hillbillies, you know? No, I found
that out the hard way. Well this,
well they tried to fight. You does get
mad at him? Yeah, they'd get offended.
Like one of the witnesses has
got really mad that I, you know,
I was just joking around like mad
some hillbilly shit there, you know,
ball and he got real offended and it
was like, well, he's probably crazy.
That's why he's making a big foot
story and getting offended here.
You son of a bitch is the original
original video is over an hour long.
So what were they doing? They were driving
around. Yeah. This one. It's real quick.
It's either, uh, either it's
a dude t they're racist video.
Where's this thing down? The right,
right, right there. Highlight it.
Wow.
What
my not saying that you don't see
where it's to the shadow starts.
It's right in front of the first shot
right there.
See
really if you go one more couple
more frames, it's really clear
right there.
But that photo they just showed oddly
enough with like a million times better
has it loose and vague as
fuck. That was that. So good.
Then this
which is on. Oh that is kind of weird.
But it seems me to go investigate it.
It seems like a trick of lighting
and shadows to me. Really? Yeah.
Cause it seems like it's moot ball.
Maybe it's just because of the
resolution of the video. It could be.
We're going to go check it out
on the side right there. Right.
That's the clearest.
Well there's of their own video.
They went back later and filmed it
and it's not there or it's not there.
So it's either a man in a
suit or a squash. I see.
Okay.
And then these guys, these, this video,
this would have been right here. Yeah.
That's so clear. And I mean
this is the same, same footage
there,
you know.
Listen man, that's some shadows I
can kid money. Don't go on that trip.
Can we got to go look at something?
How many sightings do you guys get?
Like a month that uh,
that they asked you to investigate?
Oh, well there's like the shit, I'm not
going to wade through all this shit.
Like look at every video.
Like they have a whole production
team that just all I did was scour the
Internet.
Look for everyday there's a new video.
Put up your worry now that the show's a
hit that people might still faking it.
Oh totally. We already are. We're
getting that. He must be right.
I mean we're pretty good. I
mean we've been doing this
be clip metal. All they do,
there's like 20 years. We're pretty good
at filtering people out pretty quick.
Like we caught one guy hugs and in
the Ohio Epa side really wasn't. Yeah,
Brian's from so blame him.
They don't and they don't want us to
see a lot of stuff ahead of time if they
want us to be surprised when we see it.
We all know it just cause we're in
the big community. But you know,
I didn't see that video before and I'm
looking at it on a monitor this big.
And then when you see it on home,
like on a big high def TV and everyone,
you are fooled by that video at the
beginning. You know, it's like, well,
I just saw it on a black and
white monitor, like, you know,
five inch monitor or something.
But it was a guy, you know,
cliff busted him clips straight up,
called the guy a liar, right? Dan?
The guy started like trembling
and tearing up and stuff.
So he's a faker in a bitch. How dare you
sir, with your fake big foot footage.
Listen man, I really want to
believe. I really do. And uh,
I might be a little bit more skeptical
than you, but I hold out hope.
I really believe in.
It's no, it, I wish I,
I wish I shared you enthusiasm. It'd
be fun. I'd be out there with you.
I'm very enthusiastic.
I hope it's real.
I just feel like there's
a lot of fucking lot
of fuckery afoot, but so I
feel like, yeah, but it's,
but if any of it's real, it's real. Well
if one of them is a real then it's ready.
Right. So you're, yeah, so it is
real well if you seen it. Yeah. You,
what you've seen is on fuckery.
You, you know more than anybody,
which is probably why
I'm saying you know,
is more than the average person for sure.
And even more than the average person
researching it because you've seen it.
Right. How many researchers haven't
seen anything? Does it, has the chicken,
the show ever seen anything? She seems to
be the most skeptical. What's her name?
Renee. Renee. She saw something in
the Olympic peninsula when she were,
the Olympic project is where I just got
back this weekend. She saw something,
she doesn't say what it was. She said it,
it looked like it was tall and it was,
and there was like a arm, like
an arm and she, she's like,
what could have been a
bear walking upright?
Or it could have been a bear that was
just starting to drop down as it was
running, like picking up speed on two
legs, getting ready to drop down and,
and but it, she probably saw squatch
she's the most skeptical out of the group.
Would you agree with that?
That's her job too.
I mean there's been times where she
was like, Holy Shit though as a squash.
And they're like, you
can't say that. You know,
like oh they tell her
she can't say nothing.
We're in Oregon when we recorded
those ones, 2000 I think it's like,
did they do that? They, they'd tell
you what you, you're supposed to,
what role you're supposed to play in
the show and she plays the skeptic role.
Yeah, we'll just, when we
were in Oregon, she was like,
when it happened she was like, oh my God,
that had like, that had to be a squash.
I had to be a squash. We're like, look,
you can't see why they say she can't
say that. Cause then I guess like,
you know,
then she wouldn't be taking [inaudible].
I'm probably gonna get totally in trouble
for having said that. Probably. Yeah.
Well they don't, well they say they
never been a part of her cause she,
she represents all the people
at home that are skeptical.
That's her job is to represent them.
Like what would they say?
Like the person that thinks it's
all bullshit, what would they,
she's supposed to ask the question
that that person did she, when,
when she was seeing something,
what did she see that made her so
convinced she didn't see? She heard her.
What'd she here do? We heard two
squatters call them back and forth.
I've been Malala river in Oregon and it's,
it's on the episode, but dude, it was,
if you've heard of Murphy's law, Murphy's
laws and nothing, squatters laws,
way worse. Like what squashes law.
If something's gonna go wrong, right?
When that happens, it will, like
your battery dies or whatever.
Like just whatever it may be happens,
right?
When we've got a call from the network
one, camera B, whatever isn't working,
there's no, all the tape you sent
us is blank. And we get this call.
We're out in the woods and it was
like when it finally came through,
somebody would come back from camp,
like the messages come in earlier
that day and they're like,
you got to check the camera
right now and check the audio.
Like there's nothing sync that
and it just turned out to,
the editor was totally blowing
it but we stopped all filming.
He was putting the camera back into
playback mode to see what he had the song.
I was checking his stuff. I had a pair
of boxers, it wasn't part of their stuff.
I had a parabolic to record and it was
going from like would clear up and get
really cold and like kind of clawed back
up and then get a little bit warmer.
So I had like five layers.
I was taken off the lyrics,
I was burning up and I had the
parabolic that were in pitch black.
I put the paralogue in the brush and these
things started screaming and I got my
job. I like my whatever, my thermal,
I'm pulling off over my head
right when this happens and we're,
everyone's like holy shit. Like, you know,
when it first happened were like no way.
And then by the time we got up and
then the salads from between me and the
camera guy was like, the whole crew is
between me shy of the parabolic dish here.
And all it picked up was just these
guys, you know, ripping up and Velcro,
like uncovering stuff. And because
it had been raining on and off,
guys going no way talk. And so you can't
hear any, nothing comes to a parabolic.
I mean it's that fuel the,
and then we hear stuff at homes,
this is what I want them to
put more effort into this
as capturing what we hear.
Like we were the mics that are made to
block out all sound except for us talking.
Right, exactly. And they don't
pick up screams in the distance.
They're designed not to.
So,
but we do have a guy that's going out
of this now that has the parabolic and
he's, you know, but
you have to be pointed,
like if it's coming from right
there and you're appointed here,
you might not get it right.
Like you gotta be pointed right at it
and we don't have the best gear for that.
He's like,
it's kind of Hokey.
Do you know like when you hear something
in the woods too, it's kind of weird.
Things echo off of trees and stuff.
It's hard to pinpoint exactly where
it's coming from. I totally like my ear.
Um, like I was, you know, big time
and a servant for a long time.
Oh you got that soul surfer. Yeah.
So I have one grows and your, yeah,
and it's worse than my left ear and a
fix that with surgery. Yeah they can,
I got to get it done. But my hearings
really good though. It's like, but it's,
my ear will cause the cavities
so small can clog up easy.
So sometimes it's clogged and whatever's
like, they shouldn't always show going.
Is that a squash or something like that?
And they never show like where we go.
Like, you know, after
we hear the Giggling,
oh that was a coyote or that was a
bear or whatever. It was edited Hokey.
They tried to make it a little
bit about season one. They did.
I thought season two, they
did a good job. And, um,
season three we'll see how they
do that. I mean, season two,
the editors did a great job.
I'll show. Got Way better.
How many seasons have you done so far?
This one re we shot through,
they've shown two seasons. We just
finished the third, like 10 more episodes.
We just got picked up for seasons
four and five. We start next month.
So they're going to start
Erin season three in the fall.
We'll already be puppet
in episodes for four.
And so they're going to air like seven
and a half months straight every Sunday
in new episode. So that's awesome.
So when you go out there or how,
how many,
like if you take a hundred trips,
how many trips do you hear something
or see some footprint or something? Um,
uh, it seems to go in waves. Like, I mean,
I haven't seen a squash since 2007 so
I haven't seen anything for five years
being out there a lot. And that's
gotta be frustrating. Yeah.
But from 2000 well is there, which I
never, I never, I don't tell this story.
I don't count it because it was just
so frustrating. But my buddy and bart,
we got flooded.
We note were,
we know we got some but it was such
an old school kind of shitty thermal.
It's just this big blurry heat things
you can't, you can't prove any of that.
We know like all the sounds are with
it. What happened? It was a squatch.
I was walking back out of the same place
that it was big rainstorm and cliff.
They got in a show at me. The other
guy cliff, he had this guy, Walter,
he invented the ACDC adapter is,
it's like billionaire guy that was funding
us finance equipment and clip it just
fried as recording unit,
like a $1,500 a unit in the rain.
And while I told us like,
hey,
you guys can't be keep blowing cause
he grew up poor even though he's like a
billionaire guy, he's still, he grew up,
you know he's frugal guy like hey you
guys can't be frying stuff out in the rain
if it's raining, just put
the stuff away, you know.
So I was walking back out
and end up run the thermal,
it has a waterproof flat,
you have to open that stick in a cord that
goes to a recording yet cause it does.
Now we have built recorders with thermal
but then we did it and I was walking
back out and I got back down where we'd
seen it three weeks before and it hadn't
been a peep on that.
And usually all the action happens way
back up where I was coming from and I had
walked a few miles,
my truck was parked right out the hop
right off the highway next to some houses
and the thing ran,
it was just standing behind my truck.
And if I had filmed it it
would be clear cut. Like, no,
it was way taller than the back
of my truck. I have a shell,
it's about this high and it was
above the shell. So when I filmed it,
why didn't feel it?
I looked at it right when I pulled my,
thrown them out of my pocket.
I'm looking at it and there's water,
big Robert Water drops coming down.
It like went blurry really quick,
what I was looking at.
But you could see it for a second
and it just ran up the driveway.
And I'd never tell that
story cause everyone's like,
you had a recording in it and you didn't
record it. Like, you know, Blah Blah Blah.
That's gotta be frustrating as
fuck dude did it. That was like,
did you ever get tired of people
saying that you're crazy? No,
it says that no one,
when you talked to regular folks,
just like firmly embedded it. I
don't give a shit. I know I'm right.
I know I'm right. I don't care what they
say. I know. To me it's like people going,
you're crazy that you know that
the sun goes around the earth.
So for you it's just a matter of time.
It's just I know it's coming out.
I know it's going to come out like all
this stuff going on. There's no way.
And I mean people are talking about how
there's not better footage and we'll
look who's trying to get the footage.
It's guys like me,
you know like Sony and camcorders
and it's not professional.
It's hard to get equipment
back to where these things are.
If you really talking about deep with
berries, like all that kind of stuff,
like generators, how long do you stay
out there when you do like a camp?
When you go squatch and like me and
cliff did a two month or one time to ma.
Not Deep, but we'd come back
and supply up. I was like,
that was the longest we
went straight months.
So what you would go back like how
often to civilization to get supplies
whenever we wanted like
it at least once a week.
You were just camping out there for
two months? Yeah. Yeah. Jesus Christ
and then home home for like a
couple of weeks ago I went fishing.
Did you get paid some money when you
were out there for two months? Filmed it?
Nothing. No. Cliff took a year,
something cliff lived in Long Beach as
a school teacher and I was like, dude,
you know, all his TV companies have
been call me, but they're going to,
we're going to get a Shugg on.
Just quit your job, come up,
we'll go squatch and just
quit your job slayer house.
We'll go squatch them for a year. And yet
he did. Wow. And we were out for like,
Brian was ready to do that right now.
At least felt like seven months ago.
We did about seven months of
that year out in the woods,
seven months out thermals and
we'd drive at night. You know,
we'd drive these roads. Real slug. We had
it pretty wild, like to get good like,
and uh,
we thought it was going to be game
over because I'd hurt him so many times
around me.
Comfort and growl and snap branches and
stomp their feet walking around on two
feet and stuff like that that I just
thought with a thermal, it's going to be,
give us a week,
we'll have footage two weeks max and I
have it and it's not the case at all.
Like they,
they,
I think they've been shot at so many
times that even when it's pitch black,
they still are always taking that
evasive action they can see in the dark.
Oh yeah.
I know they can.
They can definitely see in the dark for
nocturnal creatures. For the most part,
they're there. They'll come on
the day to like, like, you know,
never seen their eyes up close to it.
Right.
When I see something I seen other I
the one I saw the daylight, the eye,
it was this, the way the sun was
coming down, it's, I was so deep set,
it's brown was out so far.
I couldn't see that.
I remember that was one thing that
struck me because it was that quick.
But the one thing I remember really
clearly was the hair was real shiny.
It was super skinny.
It was the arm was,
it's going to say this one was,
all the ones I've seen at night were
bulky except where I saw one about your
size. Like a lot of it was
about five 10 look like,
like a high school linebacker
or something like five,
10 to 20 something like that. So it
was an adolescence. I try. Yeah. Yeah.
And uh,
but these are the big ones I saw were
all bull like bulky and you know,
these are all through night vision or
thermal from far away and a lot of fucking
food. They would think it would do a
lot of damage and leave shit everywhere.
Well they've been seen shit in like
flowing water and in late like there are
conscious about hiding their scat.
Like they really,
they just don't shit in the trail.
So you think they're like smart enough
to know that people are a threat?
Actively avoid people who they are kind
of people there are kind of people. Well,
I mean that foot's a footprint of a
fucking human. No, no. If there's,
there's no model. Do you know what I
mean? It's built the big toe down hall,
Middle Toe. I mean, not a
gorilla for sure. It looks
like a giant human footprint.
Superficially. It looks
like a human. Well,
there's nothing else like
that in the primary world.
It hasn't felt like that us and well,
that's another interesting thing
that came to light recently. Um, uh,
scientifically over the last decade,
they found that,
I think they call them homo floresiensis
from orient wait at Flory ansys.
Is that it? Oh God, Chris going to kill
me. He's always taught me how to say it,
right. Because I've always said
it wrong because when I read it,
I'd say it in my head.
Yeah. Rock Larissa Ansys.
Okay. Well what it is folks
that it's really like a Hobbit,
like a real hobbit that really did
exist and may even eight, eight people,
they might, there's a lot of evidence
that they're still there. Really? Yeah.
Well this,
this thing,
they found bones recently
within the last decade and um,
but really fascinating stuff.
The absolutely know that a very small
type of human being existed and it was
really like a, it's not like a
dwarf or like a mutation or a,
you know, a genetic screw up or anything
like that. It's a whole species,
a different completely different
species of human being that, um,
they call it the florists man or two.
It's,
they called it like a modern day
hobbit and it's, it's amazing.
I mean this is something that
was mythological up until
just a few years ago and
now fact scientific fact,
they know for sure this existed.
This is a real small animal. And where
do they think this thing's still lives?
Um, well maybe the Cape
York peninsula of Australia,
like the Stranger Torres through their
lecture in Australia and going up in an
age of, there's reports of them on
islands up in there to this day.
And then in the 80s
I'm a really respected,
he was a missionary to the
aboriginals up in the kit. You know,
that Cape York peninsula goes up in,
I'll start that big point. It goes up.
There's only like one road that goes
around it. There, it's just empty.
And he was up there like visiting his
rural remote villages and he got a pack of
them came up on him.
And what he described that
he had a forensic artist
draw what he saw back then.
It,
it matches exactly what the
reconstructions are from
the remains they found in
Flores island. Why the Flores
man? Like, it's uh, um,
how many do you think live up there?
They don't know.
And they don't even know that there's,
like the aboriginal said they haven't
seen him. They said they're still around,
but they haven't seen him in a while.
Well, they said they haven't seen him.
We didn't talk to him and
see them within 10 years,
but they're supposedly up and
those islands up in there still.
And then there's another type
of big foot up in those. Um,
we've talked to this guy,
he's on Australia, Bro.
He's like their version of like a
like public radio down in Australia,
the Australian Broadcasting Corporation.
He's the naturalists for them.
Like he identifies calls this
and that. He's a phd. He saw one,
and I'm Papa New Guinea,
yet like 9,000 feet doing a bird
survey for the UN back in the 70s.
I mean, so that they're see
their, their seating islands too,
which is pretty trippy and well in 2004 B,
if you ask any anthropologist how many,
how many, how many hominids like us,
you know, like homo branch, like Homo
Erectus was alive 30,000 years ago.
The answer would have been to Neanderthal
homosapien and now it's for you notice
that the hobbits and then that
they found that new kind of tall,
like when they call it [inaudible] or uh,
the one up in Russia they found two years
ago and they got the DNA chai knuckle
boom, the knuckle bones,
like twice as big as a human.
And they got DNA out of that.
So now there's four hominid species that
are known and one squatch comes out. And
what with the,
from talking to people that I know that
we're part of the DNA study is that,
that it's not a tree, it's not the
homo homosapiens like how humans came.
The Homo branch isn't a tree.
It's a very bushy plant.
It's, it's, it's a lot of lateral,
a lot of crossing. And uh,
what the DNA shows is that there's
five types of homage species in,
in I'm in us,
there wasn't these clean breaks coming
down through like most people are part
neanderthal. Most white bull spread.
Everyone that's not like your audience.
Let's say that one MMA
fighter is our Lawsky.
Maybe it's 10% what's really, yeah,
there's some, where'd you hear that?
Um,
yeah.
God, I was I talking to you. It was
some of those, part of that genetic say,
but they've,
they've got,
they've got people with 12 think I
would have heard that there was 12% DNA,
12% in the top 12%.
Deana told DNA and people that can in a,
you like that area of above Mongolia
Far East Russia. Really? Yeah.
They've found and we're, you're,
if you're, if you're European,
you're at least 2% like you have
at least 2% nan or tall. Did you,
uh, have you seen that footage that's
been going around the Internet recently?
We talked about it on yesterday's podcast,
the atoll and versatile space,
like the one picture where it's sitting
there on a rock looking over. No,
the aunt and neanderthal that looks like
a gorilla besides the guy's idea that
they weren't,
they didn't look like us.
They at black skin like gorilla and they
were really scary and muscular and they
fed on people and they were like a, a
super predator. He's already got that.
That there has been refuted. Yeah. Yeah.
But it's fascinating. There's a picture,
there's a picture of a,
um,
possible Dan or tall just taking like
last week that's up on the Internet.
Have you seen that? No. Well, Doctor
Melbourne, like he's impressed with it.
He doesn't authenticate it, but he, they
think there might still be neanderthals.
Oh yeah. You haven't heard that? No. Oh
Dude. Who thinks it might be neanderthal?
A lot of scientists over in,
in Russia for one thing.
Okay.
I don't see anything about his
DNA and China's, um, uh, there,
there are launching, um, well they,
they have urine over in China.
We're probably gonna go,
we're there.
We're probably going to go
to Russia and China. Look,
check that stuff out on the show.
Okay.
Well in China they have a,
an animal,
they set aside a whole national park
forum recently. What? Yeah, urine Y,
r e n. And what is this thing?
Supposedly like a Yeti. Yeti.
So, uh, it's in the Himalayas.
Tibet. They, this range out.
Then I remember like that there's
some of the best photos were, uh,
from the Himalaya,
so of footprints and shipping photo.
And there was a scalp dude, I can, I
know that whole story inside and out.
Yeah. Whatever happened when
that scalp that they'd found,
did they ever figured out
what that thing is? Well,
okay.
For the monks, uh, Peter Burns
stole some of this stuff.
He's still alive up in Oregon.
He's about 85, 86. He was an
event. He was on those original
expeditions in the 50s.
He's still involved in big
foot research, but, um,
there's two different, there's two
stores and I'm not sure how they crossed,
but they would,
they replace the stuff that was
out that people could look at with,
with goat skins. And just sewed it like
the Yeti, but they actually kept the Yeti,
the Yeti scalp and like a sacred box.
And the other story is that,
um, you knew who was a big part
of this was uh, Jimmy, um, God,
you know, uh, Mr. Smith goes
to Washington. Jimmy Stewart.
Oh really? He's looking
for Sasquatch high. Well,
they're looking at, he was a hue acts
snitch by the way. He was a what?
You accidentally does that House on an
American affairs committee though when
they blackballed all the people
in Hollywood penis. Yeah, he was,
he was the guy that ratted out all
the guys anyways. Well what a Dick.
He was a full on, I'm like
anti evolutionary, like uh,
really creationist.
Ah,
cause I'm on the air on the throne and
he uh, and it's gone. There's a big four,
there's a,
there's a book coming out about detailing
how he was buying these remains that
it would come out of Asia. Like he bought
like a checkout on pivot, get stuff.
He bought other stuff and
he'd have it destroyed.
What Jimmy Stewart did that part of
the theory, you know that Minnesota,
Minnesota ice man, you know the Minnesota
iceman, that blonde eyes. Oh yeah, yeah.
The guy. I'm like, that's what
they called them, the name.
Um, well Minnesota ice man
is the most common look. Hey,
punch that up cause you punch that
up. Minnesota ice man. There's a lot.
Like they didn't, that was uh, uh, uh,
well the stories either got
shot in Vietnam or in Russia.
I've got shot above the eye
and this guy is writing a book.
I know the guy that's right
in the book. He's, you know,
professor guy and supposedly
there's a lot of Jimmy Stewart
bought that and had it
destroyed. Why? Yeah,
that's I'm thinking of the wrong thing.
I'm thinking of the uh,
wasn't Minnesota thinking of the guy they
found the glacier, the ancient oh yeah,
that guy. Yeah. He was a straight
person. This is Minnesota ice man.
It's all the arm over its head is frozen
in a block of ice and they showed it
all over and then since it's a hoax,
so
probably what does that usually
when they say who said it's a hoax?
A Wikipedia? Yeah, it was a hoax.
Wow. It's just saying it's a hoax. All
they're saying it's a hoax. Period.
History.
What does that look up?
Look up the photos.
Vernal's Hoover men's who was like one
of the top anthropologists in the world
study that thing. Pretty close. And he
staked his whole rotation and it was real.
And what did he say?
It was thought it was at neanderthal that
had been shot like a recently shot man
or tall. That's it right
there. That's the face. Yeah,
because the power went out one
time and it started the, the uh,
I started melting that it was in and they
said a distinct rotten meat odor smell
was coming out like rotten flesh. Now what
do they think if they think that Nina,
there are also real, just went
away from it. There's the body.
It's um,
those are your five year old it. Yeah.
Is that it was wrong. Yeah, that's a,
that's a totally a drawing
cause like look at it.
Yeah, but that's what, that's just
showing you what it looks like.
Have like exaggerated
sized hands and her feet.
Hmm.
Where's your photos or a phone? There's,
I don't know where, yeah, there's photos.
There's like video of it and everything.
I mean, I don't know where that is.
All that. And Jimmy Stewart had
that destroyed [inaudible] I don't,
I mean that's just this guy.
That's what people he's talking to.
That's what he's heard.
Well, if we learned anything on
this show, it's fuck Jimmy Stewart.
I think we learned that.
He usually,
I just strongly believe in Jesus
and don't believe in big foot.
I Dunno man.
He thought it would shake people's faith
in God if evolution was proven true.
What a silly bitch or Joe Fox
Magic Joe. Well, you know,
how does that shake your belief in God?
It's even if the Bible was 100% bullshit,
it shouldn't shake your belief.
It's possible that there could be a god,
but it's also possible that people are
full of shit. And that story sucks.
Right? It's, that's like
simple mathematics. Right.
And that if we apply to big foot means
that there's a certain percentage of
those big foot stories that are bullshit.
But I hope, I hope to real. I hope.
I hope there's a percentage that are real
and that may be soon we get something.
Give me something. A fucking photo.
A dead one. What about the DNA?
Hmm. If it comes out to it's true. Yeah.
I mean, what's, if it's pure review,
study proves, right. Bruce inclusive.
That's the thing that's driving me crazy.
It's like it's it be out by
now or at least you know, it's,
it doesn't take that long
to tell you what it is.
It is when it's a new species
and there's no type specimen.
If they had a type specimen,
it'd be easy.
But when you have a type specimen
for deer berets, right. Real quick.
So when there's no type specimen
takes a long time to do the name.
And when there's all kinds of markers
showing homo sapiens and people,
would people have these misperception
what DNA and how DNA works due to those TV
shows? CSI and shit.
Yeah, I mean that stuffs,
if you're talking about a cryptid
species that is has nothing to do.
I mean those guys will,
you got 3 billion genomes and your DNA
strand and when they go to court they
just have to line up like seven,
seven of those like certain
markers to get a conviction. Right.
So I mean it's like wow, it's when you're
talking about 3 billion and there was,
there had been all thought there was
like 30 if you watch those shows,
it looks like there's like, well they,
they didn't mind it was going to say want.
It's like 30 of them. Oh, right,
right. Oh that's what it looks like.
But they don't line up all 3 billion.
Think when you got a certain
sections and line up those sections.
And what happened was with
that, with the guy, that sample,
he brought in the shooter there,
there's like,
so there'd be strands like
with like 2.9 billion in there,
but the gap right here
in a gap right here,
but you could line up other DNA
samples and those gaps would fill in.
They'd all line up,
none of them are complete.
Then he brought on the first complete one.
So now they just have to go to the peer
review process and other people have to
find the same conclusions
that this woman is.
What is the criticism about this woman?
Again, he never really got to that.
I've never met her in person.
I don't want to bat an eye people that
I really respect and know that our smart
people, professionals are working
with her and really liked her.
And I've talked to other people that
are like, dude, she shady. Uh, so,
so who knows, right? I don't know. I don't
know her personally. Now when does a,
the show,
uh,
when does a season two or season
three reason twos over season three?
They just said sometime in the fall
products sweeps week or something.
They're gonna cause you're
still Aaron episodes.
I was still like show him and repeats, I
don't know. Popular show. Yeah it's real.
Well right cause they,
it's like the second most popular and
animal planet history didn't say didn't uh
South Park parody guys.
Yeah fuckers.
Fuck cause we were all laughing like
wait we all love South Park and the
producers that we're going to show like
comedian stand up comedians and stuff
and like they love this show and
here's money maker and a box.
So we thought well we thought it was
going to be was because we saw that we saw
some little clip that came
out way earlier. Someone
got ahold of somehow of a,
it showed them like dressed up like ass,
like wearing backpacks and stuff and
we thought for sure they going to have
carbon played moneymaker cause he's like
carbon and make her like the same guy
and that's pretty good.
So then they made Clinton and Matt
like normal and then they made me this
fucking short retard that is all scared.
Like it was the most, like they didn't
get it. I like this little short,
retarded is scared.
Like I can't talk.
They don't talk all that great, but
so they got you the worst. Oh Dude.
I'm only guy. They slaughtered
video. Have you seen the episode?
I haven't seen it. Brian told me it's
awesome. It's a find a clip of it. I get,
I get Cartman.
Hi Dude.
We talked about the show on the podcast
so many times that people will yell at,
uh, during comedy shows. Have you
gone squatch in yet? Oh really? Yeah.
People you don't want it to,
it's very squashed
area. Have you seen the
memes of, you were like,
it was like a meme is like
an internet photo that live,
they add a lel words too,
and then it gets passed on so many
times. You know, like a meme would be,
there's a photo of you or like, here's
a perfect example. You know, George,
Josue glows from ancient aliens.
There's a photo of him. It says,
I'm not saying it was aliens,
but it was aliens. It's like,
it's always one of those type things.
There's only one answer aliens
and it'd be the same photo,
but like with different texts.
But there's awesome ones of you
where it's like, that's a tree.
This seems squashy
thank you. See if you can
find them. Brian there in the,
the Rogan board thread for this.
We were, I was thought squats.
Pull one up if you can. I
would say squat. She laughed,
but I started saying it even more when
I found out it was a drinking game on
college campuses because watch are shown
or told me to say squash or squash or
they drink. It's like, I ain't
going to kill somebody. That's it.
Like four times it, it's like you
can tell this places squatch it.
You look around the squatch with k through
here and squashed over there and like,
ah, just to try to give them
alcohol poisoning. Yeah.
It was a drinking game for the UFC.
If someone got rocked,
I said he's rocked and people that drink,
there's a bunch of other things too.
So if you play along at home, Oh, I'm
looking at this photo, this monkey,
this fake thing. It looks fake
as fuck. Dude, man, my aunt,
my cousin Donnie says he
knows he's the little, uh,
Italian guy with a thick Boston accent
that worked with a Subaru dealer in Santa
Monica. Do you remember him? A
Subaru dealer in Santa Monica.
Did I look at a car there or something?
And he's salt. Never called me a Subaru,
so I don't know. He said he knew
or maybe it was from the playbook.
You ever go to the playboy mansion once?
I hosted the marijuana
policy project thing there.
So I was there once there was
a marijuana policy project,
had a thing at the mansion.
It was a,
it's like they rented out,
you know, so it's like,
everybody's like, wow. Oh right.
And they like,
they hired a couple chicks to go around
with like strippers that aren't even
playbase, right? Fucking,
yeah, it's a sausage factory.
It's all done. It's right.
Whereas the girls, people, I know,
he's been up there finding the memes.
Take us out. This is how they
portrayed the big bigfoot field.
Researchers are going to see,
would you stop scaring
everyone with your gun?
People Thought Atlantis was a
myth. Cow. But I was just there.
I explored the depth of Atlanta is,
and now that to prove a new species
exist on a little James Cameron,
they see black going to prove anything.
To believe any of this,
you either have to be a liar or stupid.
These are professional people who go
around tracking. SASQUATCH is cow.
They aren't liars and they aren't stupid.
Look at its trajectory and head
directly to the right. Can't be human.
It's too low to the ground. What do
you think Bobo? Bobo think scary.
I think in a Sasquatch it's not big
enough to be a squatch, so it's a baby.
Squatch that's what I'm thinking.
I've already done my research boys.
What you're looking at there
is a Juba Cobra jump on camera.
It's like a Sasquatch, only
more elusive, more ferocious,
and a little more greening.
Oh, Jupa carbon. That's scary.
If we rule out a human and
a baby, Sasquatch, Juba.
Copper is all we really have left the man.
I guess that's it.
You're going to have to allow only
me and to the Easter egg hunts there.
I'm the only one credit fed
that one. That must be. That
must be awesome to have that.
I mean that to me as a South Park Fan,
I would,
I would faint and they fucking
parody dear show. Fucking retard.
Really. You though. It's
just a character real.
You has the big foot
community quite well today.
Thanks very much for the and squash
and hat. This is pretty fucking dope.
If they did me, I would
be a gay cat. That's
probably right stage that you think is
the good part though. Cause I got Cartman.
Hi, you've got Carmen. I turned
carbon into a Jew. Really?
Yeah. Wow. I'll check out the rest
of it. Go on South Park Studios.
They had all the episodes and the episode
is call it Jeeva, cholera or whatever.
Do you pack a,
I'll just spell it out.
J. E. W. P. A. C. C. A. B. R. A.
It's seasoned 16 Jupa. Cobre. Yeah,
like a trooper cover, but a Jew.
That's what I was thinking it was
God blessed South Park, the best man.
They're there, but no one's
consistently put out funny shit.
Why they heckled fuck the heroin
like, well dude, look at your,
your fucking on a bigfoot show.
Money makers for all of them.
They all looked retarded.
That's what South Park does.
They went after you a little harder,
but come on man.
It's an honor and you're
on a big food show, man.
That's really how they respect that.
Dot. They'd fucked up when big foot,
when you get something solid men,
then the tide will change.
You're going to come in,
they're going to have a fucking float for
you in downtown La Cause it'd be a big
parade every right.
We found a real big foot and
you and moneymaker and the,
and they could put all this
stuff back in the Renee saying,
I think it's squatch because then
we'll know. Now we know squashes.
It isn't always that she did
that when we were in Oregon.
They should have left that
shit in authenticity there.
She says, she still says,
she goes, I don't know
what it was like, shit,
we got to get her on the podcast too.
I've got to find out what makes her tick.
Oh is a bad
dude.
I think you guys have a good time.
What's wrong?
Nothing sounds like she's poisoned.
Gets Sewn Joe. No you're not.
I see what you're saying.
I would have a good time if I was a woman,
I scissors up. Good. She would
have a good time with me.
Your garrison would have a shot.
Well even if she wasn't gay,
hanging out with you guys in the
woods chasing weight, foot turning,
gay or lesbian
when the tooth,
this fucking tweaker tooth that they
can't run out to me with like four little
rug rats, like all licensed
vested kids like on it was like,
I think it was the first of the
month or something. You know,
they just got their checks right.
She was at like the canned food story
and identity can store like cheap stuff,
whatever.
I was walking by and Oh we're big fans
are big fans since you came to this like
just this looks like the Simpsons
evil baby like unibrow and all that,
like frowning and she hands you this
like kid, like two or three years old.
She's all take a picture of your kids.
Like am I, Hey. And I'm like, hey buddy,
how to Cameron?
He just looks at me and smile and he
just looks really wham and headbutted me
and knocked my tooth out.
A baby headbutted you like a toddler.
Whoa dude. I find that harder
to believe than bigfoot.
Well it was already. It was a, I
got hit the face of the surfboard
there. Oh, is already loose.
Well it did cap. I went to,
I went to Tijuana, dude, I
got this deal captain t on,
I got a bunch of dental market teal on
and really do. My dentist is off the hook.
He's like, this is crazy.
He wasn't crazy. He's like,
he's kind of the world's most interesting
man because if I got a short fat
Mexican boy Orbison like short fat banks
get Roy Orbison like the thick glasses.
He's funny. He just had a liver
transplant like six months. I was as a,
did you want to hear that? You got
a minute? Yeah, so I'm going down.
I was going to like this like legitimate
clinic down in Tj that people go to the
one next to the police station and uh,
cause like they want like 20 grand.
I'd been hit in the face with
crab blocks and surfboards and
pool cue, stuff like that. And so
I'd always cracked teeth and stuff.
So I was gonna him all fixed.
They want like 23 grand and the states.
So I'm going down there and stop and
see my buddy's Mexican dude. He's all,
oh my fee, my fiance's uncle is a
dentist and then he's got like, yeah,
it's a cheaper clinic. You know,
it's just like, like there's,
there wasn't even electricity when I
went there. Like the first day, you know,
he hadn't been practicing cause he'd got
a liver transplant, he's be a partier.
And uh,
we go down there and like,
we're doing all this work
and out of the second day,
I've been the chair for like eight hours.
He's like,
we got to go look at pretty good. He's
a total horn dog. He's like almost 70.
He's a little short, chubby guys hitting
on every girl. He's pretty cool. He's fun,
he's interesting and whatever. And he's
hitting on all these checks. He's like,
so he takes this giant strip are called
like the Hong Kong cafe or something.
You ever heard of that? No, it's like
three stories. It's like one of those, uh,
it's like grindhouse or something.
You think when you want.
It's like full narco place. Like you
know, full inky Awana it's three stories.
It's got like big hot tub.
Are you wearing a gone squatch and hat
while you're wandering around this place?
I don't know what I was wearing,
but I'm just probably just like I have
now I want to picture you in a garland
squash and hat. If I don't, if you
don't mind. And the dude, he disappears.
Like I didn't know that.
I thought I apparently every girl in
there was like a hooker and you can just
get a girl, whatever and well he splits
and we're waiting and we had a plan.
If anyone got to separated for a reason,
we were going to meet at the truck back
at nine o'clock or whatever it was,
or eight or eight 30 we,
you know,
we'd meet at the truck was a couple
of blocks away. Well, you know,
it's eight 30 we don't see the guy.
They were at the place. We leave,
we go back to the truck, he's not
there. Then we wait for like two hours.
My buddy's like in going
to school to be a nurse.
So he had to get back head class
like seven years. Her Dude,
I can't wait for the guy all night. Fuck,
I don't know where he is. You know, he's,
he's Mexican. He speak Spanish,
you know, he's probably all right.
But he just had a liver
transplant six months earlier.
He'd had a couple of Margarita,
so like we weren't Christ.
And so we go back to the states because
we were just going to cross the border
every day and he never comes home and the
family thinks I kidnapped and that I'm
part of a kidnapping because they
looked at me and thought like sketchy.
And so I'm getting accused of kidnapping
this old man. So he never came home? No.
So we're like, you know,
like I was starting to get
nervous and they were like,
it was what'd you do it and
be like accusing me like,
you know, over the phone.
Oh Wow. And um, I was like,
oh, said, well I just got,
and I was covering for the
guy, you know, go on. Like,
well I don't want to say all the guys
split with a hooker, you know, you know,
his wife's all upset.
I'm just like,
I don't know where we were
in a Mexican restaurant.
I wanted some barrage drinking out of
all those, you know, pain pills that day.
And I was getting just whatever,
like the shots and stuff.
I said I was kind of groggy and you know,
I just was walking around looking
for some brother and I came,
I didn't even know what,
what restaurant it was.
I walked for like four or five blocks, got
laws. So I totally covered for the guy.
The next day he shows up and he's like,
and the family's like,
where worry you don't know. I don't know
what story he told them, but you know,
you just said that I left
him in a restaurant luck.
He said something like that too.
That was close enough.
So he was so stuck that at this point
of were like he's not a very good,
he's a cool guy.
They go party with,
but he's not a very good dentist and at
this point he's not a very good dentist.
No. All he's all right. He's
wasn't terrible. But um, so he uh,
he goes,
he goes blah.
I thank you so much to all give you
half off the rest of your dental work.
Cause I was like, I'm not going to
get any more dental work for this guy.
I like half off. Fuck yeah. So that
let's say you said, well fuck it.
As long as it's cheap. Yeah. Oh Shit.
Fuck happened. What does that noise, Bro,
my computer's going crazy.
What do you mean it's going crazy?
Shitty music of that.
Yeah. What is that music?
That's the universe telling us
to wrap this podcast up. Huh?
Let's just wrap this podcast up.
You sound Mexican dude. Sounds bad
ass. What the fuck are you playing?
Is that fake rage against the
machine? Turn the volume down, Bro.
Thank you very much.
My whole life I've been
fascinated by big foot.