The Joe Rogan experience,
when did you know that you like the
concept of gender identity to someone
who doesn't struggle with it is it's one
of those things where you try to wrap
your head around and try to understand
it,
but you'd never.
It's like why we say that a man and
woman never really understand each
other.
They just sort of get this thing where
they accept that this is how you are and
this is,
but I never.
I'll never understand what it's like to
want a baby in my body.
I never understand what it's like to
have my period.
I'll never.
I'll never get it.
I'll never understand what it's like in
any way and being a woman and then
feeling like you're in the wrong sex.
What does that like and how did you.
When did you realize it?
It's imagine if you felt all of a
sudden.
One day he started saying,
I feel like a girl.
It would freak you out.
Yeah,
it would take you out.
Oh,
without a doubt.
Without a doubt.
I really most.
I mean,
I can just tell you what most of my life
I felt that way,
but my parents did raise me like a boy
even though I was a little girl.
They completely raised me like a boy
because I wasn't very much of a tomboy.
Tomboys are okay.
A girl who looks like a little boy and
you know your Tan and you dress like a
little boy.
That's okay in this country.
Nobody freaks out on that.
It's when you start reaching puberty and
he started.
I started growing breasts and then I
started getting my period.
That's when everything shifted.
It was totally okay.
My childhood,
but then people are like,
uh,
you need to start treating her like her.
Not like he.
My parents were completely freaked out
because they always just.
It was like,
okay,
was that an issue?
Because I was just like a tomboy and
then when that happened,
I think that's when I'll like basically
everything all hell broke loose,
you know?
It wasn't your folks that have the issue
or the community that had the issue
community or their friends kept saying,
you've got to stop calling her.
He
said,
girl,
you know what I mean,
and I fuck.
The daycare will be quite such a freaky,
weird thing for people in our,
in the world.
Basically I manage this and a woman is
that,
that your penis makes you a man and your
vagina makes you a woman that's just
black and white for most people in the
whole wide world.
That's just how it works.
And so basically that's not true because
it's really how you feel inside your
outer presence is just the shell of your
soul and your being really.
I mean it's,
to me it's that simple,
but of course people don't get it
because people always take things at
face value.
They don't tend to get to know you or.
I mean,
I'm sitting right in front of you now.
Would you say that I am a woman?
No.
A beard.
Beard.
Yeah.
No,
you're basically a man.
Thank you.
I appreciate the compliment from.
It's just that everyone gets so mad.
Oh,
the government doesn't represent the
people anymore.
It's like,
well,
that may be true,
but what are we doing to organize to
make it so that they start listening to
us again?
We need
to do that.
Um,
yeah and no.
I mean,
yeah,
and that something's got to change and
no in that really what would be optimal
is if the people that were in positions
of power realize that there were fucking
over the world,
that would be the best that they just
said,
hey guys,
you know,
we,
we ate some pot and we realized we were
a bunch of cons.
So we're willing to like try to figure
out how to figure out a way how to
reward people for the work they've
already done,
but yet,
and move forward in a much more ethical
way of distributing wealth.
Good luck,
man.
These are good luck.
That's socialism.
Talk you fucking Cami.
People are fucking human fossils.
Look at,
imagine taking Payoti with Baner.
Imagine
can you imagine looking across at that
guy and he's like transforming into
howdy doody in front of you.
His eyes are glowing red.
No Way,
man.
I don't know if it's possible.
It seems like these are a earlier
versions of human beings who,
whose entire operating system as a is
needed an update since the seventies.
There is no.
Imagine if you're.
If you had an updated your iphone since
when iphones came out.
That's what these people are like with
information,
but they're way worse than iphones.
These motherfuckers,
they murder.
They're on a bbs board of in the early
nineties with a 14,
four modem.
Yeah.
I'm the shit cuts out every five
minutes.
They're not gonna.
Want to tell it with a ball at all?
Yeah,
well it's.
It's the whole thing's fucking wrong,
man.
I really liked.
I had Christopher Ryan on my podcast and
he was talking about how in indigenous
cultures,
the people who never are allowed to
become leaders or the people who
indicate that they want to be leaders,
like those are always the ones people
avoid as being the leaders and the ones
who end up being leaders are the ones
who know the most about certain things
like fishing or hunting.
Those people are naturally followed.
They don't fucking throw makeup on and
try to get in front of a try to
hypnotize a country by saying the exact
same thing.
Everyone always says,
my fellow American president talk that
weird cadence.
Why are you talking like that?
What the fuck is that?
We've talked about that times on this
show you and if you were sitting at home
with a guy and he started talking to you
like that,
you would stop him.
He'd be like,
what the fuck are you doing?
Are you trying to hypnotize me?
If you imagine it,
Joey Diaz was sitting across from Obama.
Joey,
what we're doing right now,
bipartisan efforts have been reached.
We have reached out to Republicans for
unwilling to bargain.
Yeah.
He'd be like,
you're fucking killing me,
dog.
Definitely talking to me like that.
Oh yeah.
And also the way he gave me the fuck
out.
Boy,
I was North Bergen,
New Jersey.
Nineteen 78.
Look at this picture.
Look at me,
motherfucker.
I'm on a basketball team with a bunch of
guineas.
One black guy and a Filipino.
Why are you talking to me like that?
What's happening is diffusion of.
Oh,
you're so good.
I've never gone over there it.
How high are you?
On a scale of one to a billion.
I'm like six for Joey Diaz to be this
high man.
Whatever you took,
must've fallen out of
that shit.
Must have come out of a time machine,
dude.
We met in Utah.
That black hole of the bulletproof wolf
that pops out a portal,
open up word,
vomited out.
Whatever you ate.
The orbs basically.
Basically the orbs.
Yeah,
man,
I've got to God as his house.
I've never seen you like this.
You're a fucking human being.