Fuck,
yes,
dude,
I love the video that Tommy made.
Oh,
Tommy's the fucking animation gotta.
Go check out Tommy's animation button.
Motherfucker.
Where is it at now and where can you go?
Where can you get that animation or todd
guarantee on Tom's instagram?
Is it available?
I paid for that.
I know he did pay me this thing.
It's amazing.
He showed it to me last night,
the ice house.
It's fucking amazing.
So whoever did that is really talented.
It's very funny.
His fans are the most creative fans ever
did.
He's got fans in Indonesia who teach
English to children and all they do is
teach them how to say Bertus fat and
jeans and jeans.
Jeans,
high and tight.
Oh,
so strange.
He's kind of weird.
Niche like him and his wife together on
that podcast.
It's a weird like silly show we should
have for the six of us should go out to
eat one night because watching the two
of them interact is there.
It's just inside jokes between the two
of them always and it's so much fun to
be.
There really are one of the funnest
couples that I've ever befriended in my
life.
It's weird that it works so good.
It's like every comedian couple when
they're two comedians.
How long?
It's like a bomb,
like you just standing next to it.
Like I got to get out of here before
this thing blows,
but with them it's like it just works.
He's.
It's so funny too because he's known me
probably 15 years and the other day
we're hanging out.
There's just me and him bullshit.
And he goes,
he's got two kids.
He's,
you could their house,
you can tell they have two brand new
kids.
Ellis is running around like a lunatic
with a balloon running into walls that
kids are wrecking ball.
The other one's an infant and he looks
at me.
He goes,
I can't believe you did this with no
money.
Kids.
Fuck it.
A little workout.
Wow.
Yeah,
that's true.
Right.
How old were you when you first started
having kids?
Thirty two.
I think my daughter's 14.
And how long into comedy where you then?
Oh,
like I started at 26,
so eight years.
Wow.
Maybe.
Yeah.
Eight years,
probably six years.
Someone who could do the math better
than me.
Yeah,
so at six years and that is not a good
time as a comedian.
Six years in is rough.
I was featuring,
Georgia was born on like on like a
Tuesday and I had and we induced labor
so that I could go feature for Dave
attell on Thursday.
Oh my God.
And I was so excited to work with David.
Tell it was almost as excited to work
with David.
Tells the advocate.
Where were you working?
A Miami.
I worked at that stretch.
That a terrible place to work.
Yeah,
no shit dude.
I was just in Miami.
I was in Miami a few months ago and I
did that cell phone bag thing because I
did it before I fill my netflix special.
I did it for awhile where they didn't
have to put their phones in the bag.
Then I stopped doing it.
It's just,
it's complicated.
It's annoying.
It takes.
Especially when you're doing two shows,
it's a giant space in between them,
but never have I seen a crowd like
cause you to use your phone.
You've got to get out of the arena and
then come back.
Everybody was just constantly going out
there.
We're constantly getting up.
I mean it was just,
it was like I was doing standup not in
front of people sitting down in front of
people in a constant state of moving,
sitting down and getting up.
That's fucking insane.
Just constantly moving like no place
I've ever been.
They have zero attention span.
I've always said,
if you want to starve to death,
open up a bookstore in Miami,
a piece,
motherfuckers,
they just do coke and fuck each other
and party.
Not Everybody.
I know.
I'm generalizing.
If you'll look bro.
I read Billy Corbin loves fucking Miami,
so
bro,
I.
So I started headlining.
Miami was one of the first clubs that
let me head.
I had handled the room that just like
take a white guy and he got anyone.
Dude I had.
I had the most crazy experiences I've
ever had there.
One night it's me and two other comics.
I'm headlining right Sunday night and I
say to the manager,
I said,
it seems pretty rowdy.
Or they heckling her and then was like,
yeah,
it's pretty bad.
There's gang bangers in the front row.
I was like,
who can we escort them out?
Maybe he goes,
I think they have weapons.
I'm not comfortable with that.
I was like,
so what are we going to do?
And he's like,
I don't know how to tread lightly.
I guess feature girl at goes up,
there's a hundred percent swear on my
children's story feature that goes up.
They destroy him,
he comes back,
oh my God.
Thinning hair,
matted sweaty to his head and he's like,
it's not good.
So I go out and I do an old Dave attell
trick.
It's,
it's,
I mean it's a comedy trick,
but I watched dave do it where he would
ask the audience a question that he had
the joke for.
So he asked them to set up,
what's the best way to please your wife,
you know?
And then he had the joke,
what's the best way to give oral sex to
your chick?
And the guy's like.
And then the guy would tell his joke and
then obviously you have the better
jokes.
You wrote it like,
oh no,
what you do is you put your lips around
her entirely and go,
whoa.
And so I do that with these gang bangers
for like 40,
35 minutes and it's killing the whole
crowd's like finally we're all having
fun.
I look off to the left and all of a
sudden one of them are darker,
Guy Name's Ray,
gets up on stage and he was like,
on stage,
there was no stopping this with you with
me so I can use a real motherfucker
right here.
Who's a real mother fucker.
You know what real motherfuckers getting
the 305 pulls his pants down and shows
his deck and it is massive,
massive and dark like.
And everyone's silent.
I'm like,
okay,
right,
thank you very much.
He was like,
show Yo Shit.
So I'm like,
not now show Yo shit son show Yo shit
son.
I was like,
not gonna happen now.
Not going to happen now I,
you know,
you might want to leave.
I'm sure they're calling the cops and
he's like,
good looking out and he leaves,
right?
So I'm like,
I have nothing to say.
I'm like,
how do I follow that?
All of a sudden,
lighter skinned dude face tattooed
dreadlocks stands up real slow and I'm
like,
Oh God,
please save another dick gets on stage
and just goes,
there's a real motherfucker,
you know,
real motherfuckers getting the 43,
oh five pulls his pants down and he has
an equally almost like lighter to tone
Dick,
like a purple ring around the lake and
the place is going bananas.
They're like,
oh my God.
Oh my God.
I go,
listen brother.
I go there.
Debbie definitely called the cops now
you definitely want to go catch up with
ray and get a ride home.
Thank you so much for the.
No,
and he's like good.
Looking out.
Good.
He gets off stage,
right joe?
I said,
Joe,
I swear on my children's lives.
They're there with a hairless albino
girl or guy guy.
And I go,
so funny man.
The only Dick I ever wanted to see was
yours and the audience quiet.
He slowly stands up and everyone's like,
no,
please don't have him.
Gets on stage,
drops his pants and it is huge.
No hair.
It looks like a lighthouse.
Just I just dropped the mic because
that's my show and I just walk off
stage.
It was the FA that will.
That club was fun,
insane,
insane.
You know what happened?
They started giving out free tickets and
just went off the charts like no one was
paying and it was all just like young
kids.
And I remember I had a joke once where I
said something about I think Oscar de la
Hoya.
It was like a joke about boxing,
about like,
you know,
taking a left hook from Oscar de la Hoya
and someone yells out,
fuck him,
Fernando Vargas.
And then somebody goes,
fuck him.
So Chavez.
And they just started fucking debating
about what my guys,
this is a joke,
has nothing to do with boxing even what
the fuck.
But it turned into this like gigantic
argument over which Latino boxer is
better.
Oh,
craziness.
I've never been to a club that was more
out of control and I saw it get out of
control because when I first started
working there it was fine,
it was fine,
and then somewhere along the line it
just went to chaos.
They started doing just rowdy and ratty
or acts that getting more and more young
kids.
And then sometimes you'd go there and
the whole audience you'd be like 18.
Oh yeah.
And,
and,
and not everyone spoke English.
That was another real problem in that
club.
You never saw anybody kill like you see
diaz do spanglish in front of those
fucking people.
Oh my God.
Because he came up in that club while he
was always there.
I think him and ricky,
ricky crews,
all those guys had all worked at club
and just wore job at Joey murmured or
Bert.
I'd worked with Joey there a ton of
times,
but you know,
Joey and I,
we knew how to work together like it
worked and I'm,
you know,
from doing the comedy store so much.
I'm just used to chaos and then you get
used to chaos.
I liked it.
Yeah,
it's fun,
it's fun sometimes you know,
as long as you're not filming a special
place.
It was just a shell.
It's just a show and it's chaos.
It's fun.
That was my first taping and Philly
philly's wild ass place to I I call it
called Tommy.
He goes,
that's why we taped to brother.
Have good,
good luck on the next one.
Yeah,
I take for now.
I do.
I do for now.
Dude.
That is genius.
So way to do it.
I really should do six.
Chappelle did nine.
Just the way to go.
It seems like it's not,
but the thing is like you want to make
it the most like a regular show,
but the ironic thing is most of what I
use I use from the first show because
I'm so loose because I know I have four
shows.
It's like it's different.
It's,
it's,
it's when you're,
when you film in one show,
like always remember seeing a bill
Hicks.
Relentless,
which is the one he did in the UK,
is a big theater in the UK and it's a.
yeah,
giant production.
He comes out to like a Jimi Hendrix song
and his fire behind them and all this
shit and you could feel the tension,
like he's got tension because he's got
one shot at this and he did a great job,
but it was stiff.
It's just stiff and like I was dating
this girl at the time.
She's very smart.
It had washed it with her and she's
like,
he's interesting,
but this is not funny.
The way she said that.
I was like,
wow.
Like I was a giant Bill Hicks van.
I was like hurt.
I was like,
I wanted to argue with her,
but I was like,
I can't argue with her because she's
kind of right.
It wasn't.
I didn't laugh when I was such a fan
that like watching him was important to
me early on wanting to watch it,
like because I felt like he was a very
important figure in comedy even though
rh fear shits on them relentlessly,
but I was.
When I was watching him,
he's an animal,
but when I was watching them I was
thinking she's right.
It's not really making me laugh at all,
but I know the materials well thought
out and it's very good.
But um,
it's just that.
And I recognized that one show thing.
You're filming one show.
You got one shot at it.
See I,
I think because I come from a,
like a baseball sports background,
I like having pressure on me.
I love that feeling of you got one shot
so affiliated to and the first one it
rained,
the generator went out and we had to
hold the audience in the rain for an
hour and a half.
Oh Geez.
They lost their buzz right there.
Soaking wet.
They finally come into the show in the
show that they're trying to catch a buzz
again.
And it was a bad show.
Like legit,
like legit.
I didn't even do well.
Like I remember telling my buddy,
Tony,
who produced it.
I go,
well,
I've got bad shows where like when
you're moving,
you're accidentally stand on the mic and
you would go to move and then the mic
moves away from your mouth.
And I did it.
I bugging you will it into existence.
I told my wife who was there I go,
if I flub a word like a,
just write it down so I can pick it up
clean.
And the second one,
she walked into the green room.
All my agents,
all my managers,
producers with a notepad and goes,
I don't even know where to start.
So I get.
So I go,
I got one more shot.
I got one shot and in my head I have
that highschool.
Bert Kreischer,
the like you said,
you like pressure,
let's go motherfucker.
You got one show like it's awesome.
I'm getting chills talking about going,
let's go.
You're not fucking up one word.
You're having to show your fucking life.
My Buddy Tony Hernandez,
who produced it,
comes over and he goes,
let's get a coffee and back in high
school have been like bumpy coke.
But it was like,
let's get a coffee.
We're grown ups,
had a coffee,
went on,
and Joe,
I swear to God on the best show of my
life,
the best show of my life to the point
where I was like,
I even,
I fucked around a little bit on stage
and I just kept it in the special.
I was like,
and I think if I did nine,
they'd be sloppy.
If I do too,
and I go,
fuck,
I got one shot.
I got a guy got again this tonight.
See what you're saying.
I feel like you really go.
This is important to me.
I mean,
I'd love to do it
four,
I think.
Yeah,
I think you do as many as you want.
Honestly.
You know it's sits as a matter of like
that,
that pressure of that second show if the
first show.
I think that's what I was talking about
this with a chuck Palahniuk yesterday.
Did I say his name right?
Yeah,
for sure.
Paula,
Paula Palenik,
politic bar,
like terrible moments on stage.
I think you like the best thing ever for
your act like eating shit,
eating shit.
The best thing ever for your.
Because then you recover from that,
you're like,
Ooh,
I don't want to feel that again ever.
I not feeling too.
It's the worst and you bounced back.
You figure out how to,
how to tighten everything up.
You figured out how to just even a bad
moment,
a joke that doesn't work,
you know,
like jokes that don't worry.
I've got some new stuff,
man,
that is just not that good with some new
stuff that's just like it's in its
infant stage where it's just like
wobbling around every now and then I'll
catch it,
I'll catch it.
Perfect.
And I've only been doing some of them
for like two or three shows,
you know,
so they like wobbly that I don't know
where I'm going with them and I'm trying
to figure it out on stage and fuck
around with them.
That's the whole purpose of doing all
these shows in town especially.
And,
but those,
those haunt you and the ride home,
you're like,
that's why.
That's why I'm grateful I worked at the
store.
Oh yeah,
right before I did my special,
my closing.
But I do on the show on the special.
The closing bit,
I uh,
I sat with you for a fucking hour in the
back room because I took it up in the
main room following like Dalea and I
just said,
we're here we go,
and I,
man,
that club can really let you know where
the silences and you go,
all right.
And then you're like,
oh,
I've been lazy.
I've been performing to fans who will
give you the benefit of the doubt.
Love you.
Yeah.
And they want you to succeed,
but when you do a Netflix special,
you need it to be.
The strangers need to like it.
That's the old louis quote that I used
to hang my hat on.
They were like,
why don't you work at UCB?
And he goes,
anyone can make them laugh.
He was like,
I'm famous gay.
They've,
I go in like,
that's like making your friends laugh.
That's why this is why I do the road is
the art form is to make strangers laugh.
And I was like,
yeah,
it is to make strangers laugh.
Yeah.
Well it's also,
you don't want a delusional perspective.
And one
thing that does happen to some complex
stan hope lives by it.
Like he's like,
why would I go and do someone else's
audience?
He goes,
it took me 25 years to make my own
audience.
I'm like,
okay,
I get it,
but I really feel like to develop
material to really do it right,
you got to do it in front of just
regular people,
people that aren't necessarily there to
see you.
And the beautiful thing about the
stores,
if there's 15 people in the lineup or 20
people in the lineup,
whatever it is,
how many others see you?
Ten percent,
30 percent,
20 percent.
Like,
you know,
maybe they're there to see you and Talia
and also,
you know,
tom and also Christina,
like it's there,
just comedy fans,
crusher fans.
Yeah,
yeah.
That,
that's giant as jarring because those
guys,
they like develop like that.
I've seen a few people that develop an
audience and that's all their audience
and they just get real complacent,
real lazy.
The um,
I mean,
I've,
I say lightly because there's some
internet comics,
meaning like youtube comment,
people that do comedy now.
And some are good,
some are good and some are developing.
I don't know,
I was just saying that to be polite,
but like.
But that one guy,
he got booed off stage in Montreal
because he's been performing to fan.
Oh,
well here's the other thing about that
guy.
That guy goes up on a show where there's
all these other comedians on and then at
the end of his set says that comedy
shouldn't be about about preaching.
It should be about making people laugh,
right?
It shouldn't be about ethics or morals,
sexuality or race or sexuality or race.
It should be about making people laugh.
People pay to forget about that stuff.
Bitch,
you are on stage not making people
laugh.
That is what you're doing.
You silly.
Fuck it is one of the silliest things
I've ever seen in my life.
It's like this is an.
He's essentially a beginning comic,
open,
open mic.
He's maybe been doing standup for three
years,
so he does like videos and the videos
are very popular and they're funny.
Yeah,
if you're from the south,
they're really funny.
Just someone's doing your shit unless
they're stealing or stealing from
somebody else,
just do your fucking act.
Unless something happened before you
that's so egregious and ridiculous that
you feel like you have to address it
when you go on stage because it's just
sitting in the room and to just try to
do ever notice when you pick up your
phone if you just try to do that and
everybody's like,
what the fuck you not going to address,
which has happened.
Sometimes you have to address what just
happened.
Like sometimes someone will go on before
you and just eat so much shit that you
have to say something.
You have to say something.
You have to.
Yeah,
but what that guy did was ridiculous.
It's to tell someone what comedy is and
what isn't.
I'd said I'd read an article about that.
This,
I'm assuming she's a gay woman,
wrote about like trashing Hannah Gadsby
and going,
hey,
we're gay and we're doing standup
comedy.
We're not.
We're not just preaching.
We're doing stand up comedy about her
trauma and it's working.
You just don't see us,
so don't write us off and say comedy is
dead because you don't see us.
I don't think Hannah Gadsby saying
comedies dead.
I think journalists are saying comedies
dead,
and I think we're all buying into it
because these people were writing these
articles.
They're not even in comedy there just
comedy fans or fans of her and what I
think she did and I've only seen part of
it.
I saw the whole thing.
I'll tell you right now.
Let me.
I was one joke I like
a lot.
Whenever she did is fine.
Here's the thing,
it's her artwork.
This is what she's doing.
It's fine.
Like it's.
It's.
If people enjoy it,
that's great.
The problem with comedy is that comedy
is one category.
It's just comedy,
but comedy could be Cat Stevens,
it could be guns and roses.
It could be the Geto boys.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like when you go to see music,
there's very distinct genres.
There's no.
There's just comedy.
Comedy is just comedy.
Like you could go see a folk singer and
what they're doing on stage,
like really slow and quiet his music,
but then you go to fucking led Zepplin
and you go,
okay,
well that's music to how the fuck is
that music too?
You know?
How is motley crew the same kind of
thing?
Is Cat Power?
How is that?
How are they?
How are they the same?
Will they are both music just like we do
comedy and she's doing a version of
comedy.
Some of it is really funny and some of
it is her just talking about stuff and
like a very serious way.
That's fine.
Yeah.
That we're not against each other.
This is what's crazy.
Everybody's like,
you know,
this is deconstructing comedy and comedy
is dead now.
Like what are you talking about?
That's crazy.
We know she's doing what she's doing.
If you enjoy it and that's what you want
to see more of,
go see that.
Yeah,
that's what she goes.
That's great.
She was a great joke about Unicorns that
I giggled about once a week and I'll
tell her jokes.
It's all on Netflix.
You can see that and when I was growing
up,
I knew more facts about unicorns and I
did lesbians.
She goes,
there are no facts about you.
I was just like,
that's a good fucking.
That's a good fucking joke.
That is a good joke.
Yeah.
I mean that's her experience,
right?
She's a lesbian.
It's hard.
It's hard out there for a pimp.
I get it.
It's fucking like where we are.
I think people create unnecessary and
artificial adversaries.
I really do,
and I think this is one of the ones
that's going on right now in comedy and
I see it all the time with this internet
thing.
It's like,
stop,
stop with the art.
I mean I fall into a too.
I buy a new too and I read some of these
articles like comedy is not dead.
What the fuck are you talking about?
It doesn't make any sense.
You read the article and you start
thinking.
She said it like the way that.
Exactly.
You're like,
oh,
she's telling us I can't do comedy
anymore.
She didn't say she just did something
and someone interpreted it that way,
and if she says she can't do comedy
anymore,
that's fine.
To me,
she could just do like now she's famous,
right?
She could just do one woman specials or
one person specials or one entity.
Hi,
how are we
framing that?
I wouldn't even say it.
Joe,
can I say the gender?
I wouldn't even be like.
She doesn't think gender's often off
subject.
You can't.
It's,
it's off limits.
Gender.
I imagine that when you're a kid,
if somebody came up to you,
uh,
one day you're going to have to ask
someone whether they're a boy or a girl
and it's going to be very delicate and
you're gonna have to ask them what their
preferred pronouns are.
He'd be like,
what?
Yeah,
yeah,
it's coming.
It's real soon,
like 10,
15 years.
And then everyone's gonna be this is
gonna be a lot of ambiguity and
ambiguity.
That's a weird word.
Ambiguity.
How often you say that word?
I'll say ambiguous,
but how often do you say ambiguity?
I've never said it.
That's a weird one.
I stay away from a lot of big words,
especially after coffee ambiguity.
Yeah.
But nobody would have ever anticipated
that there would be debate about gender.
Oh,
my daughter's,
uh,
we're outside of one of the progressive
bathrooms were not,
it's just the bathroom.
And my daughters saw her first dick that
way.
Just pushed open the door because it's
no man or woman.
And then she's like,
oh ha ha.
And I was like,
what does it matter?
She goes,
I was just saw a man's penis.
I was like,
why didn't the guy locked the door?
Sometimes you don't.
I've done it.
You walk in and you're not thinking and
you just don't lock the door.
So was it at any sex bathroom or was it
a,
any gender bathroom?
I don't know.
They have,
I don't fucking know.
You know,
I was in a restaurant once,
a restaurant once and I was waiting for
the bathroom.
It's a long fucking white man.
And uh,
finally the door opens and a chick comes
out the men's room and she looked at me
like,
yeah,
I was in.
I was in the men's room.
Like what if I was in the women's room
taking a shit?
What if you were in there?
I've done that.
A big steamer.
I did that coming off of a plane from
Atlanta,
went to the women's room,
Ireland to Atlanta,
Busan on the flight.
There's a while ago,
headsets in Hoodie on bowel to take a
shit.
I'm like,
it's creeping up my pants and I walked
into the bathroom,
starts shifting headsets still in
listening to music,
starts sweating a little bit because
it's so hot in there.
Take the Hoodie off,
take the headsets on.
They hear women's voices and I'm like,
yeah,
oh my God.
I'm shitting in the woman's bathroom.
I did that at the comedy store.
Once I took a leak in the women's room.
I didn't realize it when they put those
new bathrooms and the side hallway
because for a while was it was like a
men and women's bathroom and then they
opened up the men's bathroom over there
and I walked in and there was girls in
there.
I'm like,
hey,
how's crazy?
We're all in here together.
Isn't it funny that you can be next to
people?
Here's what's odd about genitals are
involved,
right?
You could be standing next to those same
people in an elevator.
It would be fine.
Hi Guys.
Doing everything's fine,
but if you stand next to the same people
in a bathroom,
you're like,
oh no.
Oh No.
Private Parts,
naughty parts.
Poopy pep.
When you know like there's something
dirty about.
Even if everyone is just washing their
hands
close to each other in the sink,
it's like everyone's creeped out.
I can't wait to get the fuck out of
here.
The tension is so thick.
That bathroom.
It's weird.
It's crazy that you can't just shit and
Piss in front of people.
No,
you can't.
You can't see.
We grew up where you could ship in front
of dudes like we used to shit in front
of dudes.
Like if if like,
I'm still kind of like this,
but like if me and you were talking,
I'm like,
Hey,
come in and I gotta take a Shit I
would've shot and you would've stood
there and I would've finished telling
you much.
I Bet Joey Diaz is that kind of guy?
Do.
Oh,
joys is taking horrible shits in front
of me.
Yeah,
I saw already knew it online.
Do you remember that clam video was
there?
Oh my God.
I remember seeing that.
I was on the road in a,
in a green room and I saw someone's
like,
you using an artist asshole.
And I was like,
I have not had a hemorrhoid problem and
that's to put it mildly.
He still has them word problem.
Is this still do?
When we were,
when we were in Atlanta,
he was like,
how much blood should come be in a
toilet after you go to the bathroom?
A lot.
But can you imagine Tom's face?
You know Tom,
so drives like a nun.
A Don't put that up.
Don't put that up.
Don't put up.
I was just telling Jamie back like
before you got here,
how important those videos were.
All the videos you shot with Brett with
red band and Ari and Joey,
the joey karate,
all the stuff you guys use to put online
that's so important to where you are
today,
in my opinion.
What do you mean a man?
The I found that stuff when youtube
started blowing up,
that stuff was in such heavy rotation
for comics,
like you'd look for comics and you were
recognizable because of fear factor in
news radio.
But I've got to those videos and I
probably watched every single one of the
videos you guys shot as,
as did all of us.
Tom Did all of us just because it was
like it was the content we could find.
That's what we're talking about with
twitch is like get on twitch now and
start uploading content because one day
someone will see it and go,
oh,
I know that guy.
And,
and I really believe that you guys were
so ahead of that curve where people are
like,
I'm not,
I don't even know how to upload a video.
You guys had edited great content
Heckler in Columbus,
uh,
already dealing with a heckler in DC.
The car,
the feminist arguing with you,
that guy,
you choking that guy out the store.
Like those were videos where you're
like,
I'd watch them four or five times.
There was a lot of those.
But you know,
what was really good about it was red
bands editing.
He doesn't like to do that though.
It's too much,
too time consuming and he's too lazy.
He just doesn't like to do video.
But he's really talented like his video
editing skills like that.
Men See a video that was part of why
that video is so popular because it's a
long ass video,
but he's editing skills are so good.
What was the music you played?
Dead and it was.
The music was perfect.
Yeah,
it was.
The whole thing was,
you know,
he's a really good editor.
He really,
he's really talented at it,
but it's so time
consuming.
It drives them nuts that he'd rather
just fuck around and do podcasts and
have a good time.
But when he was doing it,
like when we were going on the road
together and he was filming a lot of
stuff and splicing things together would
make a video every couple months or
something like that.
It was really fun.
It was,
it was an interesting experiment,
you know,
just just,
just to fuck around.
I got into when I got into blogging or
Jamie was like right there when I
started blogging because we were both
found Casey Neistat I think at the same
time,
and I got really into blogging and I
loved it.
Man,
I don't.
I think I maybe did like 40 episodes and
it was just fun,
but then I started realizing it was
cannibalizing my life to a point where I
wasn't living an authentic life at all.
I wasn't writing any material.
I was just shooting everything.
Everything was shot.
Like if I saw you,
I'd be like,
I wouldn't be like,
oh cool.
I get to hang out with Joe.
I'd be like,
oh,
hey guys,
I'm a Jew,
you know?
And I was like,
that's it.
The trap that people fall into.
You know what I mean?
If you look on some people's instagram
stories,
you're like,
what are you doing man?
You have a million dots.
Your instagram was like little tiny
dots.dot,
dot,
dot.like
your whole day,
you have just a phone in front of you.
What do you just have like constant
battery chargers and you're just
constantly charging up your phone and
film and video.
This is crazy.
I do it this way.
I look at Instagram,
I do it.
I'll do those stories aggressively if
I'm running the triathlon,
running a marathon,
doing a big event and that's not to tip
the hat or whatever.
We're telling you guys my business plan,
but that's what I do like it.
I like to do big things and then that's
how my stories and then I'll fuck around
on the weekend and I'll put up maybe
like three stories a day,
five stories a day and I'll show you my
life a little bit.
But for the most part I like,
I try to,
I try to distance myself from it for two
reasons.
Number one,
it fucks with my eyesight.
Like if I'm on my phone a lot.
Oh yeah.
My eyes are fucked.
Yeah.
And number two,
it does cannibalize your life,
but what I would like,
what I want to do,
I think the next level is businesses is,
is honestly like going backwards and
doing what you and red band we're doing
with those videos.
But getting yourself out of it and
having a guy like red band who that's
his job.
It's hard.
No.
See,
the thing is with a guy like red band,
it's that job is very hard to do.
Like Brian is uniquely talented at that.
I think that's his greatest talent.
He's really good at making videos.
But he,
like I said,
he doesn't like to do it and a lot of
people don't like to do it because it's
time consuming.
So you could just take stuff and just,
you know,
cut it and paste it.
But he did more than that.
He had special effects and music and you
know,
what he was doing was he was figuring
out a way to make sometimes mundane
situations.
Interesting and interesting situations.
Way more interesting.
Yeah.
It's hard to do.
So like for you to say,
you know,
you want to get you,
like you'd have to find a guy,
like you'd almost like to have to get
Brian to start doing it again.
I,
I've,
I'm definitely,
we,
Jamie and I were talking about this.
My next step is doing what you're doing
on a much smaller level,
like getting an area,
getting a space,
doing my podcast and my solo podcast of
there.
But then creating content.
What is your Solo podcast?
You have a solo ones?
Well I do a solo podcast.
Talk to yourself.
No,
it's called open tabs.
So I go through out on the weekend,
like when I'm normally killing time,
looking on the Internet and I just leave
all those tabs open on safari and then I
go in and I just go through and close
them and tell you what they are and show
you the video I was watching.
Oh it's like it's a lot of videos of you
and like all my friends because I
watched all my friends do shit.
Like if bill bird kills on some
interview,
I show that.
Um,
or if you like,
like a lot of,
I mean a lot of them are like the
interviews you have with these guys like
David a Tia and,
and campaigns are campaigns is like all
those,
all those like really inspirational
guys.
I'll pull up videos of them and then I
all sudden I'll get obsessed with flash
floods.
The fucking flash floods is scary too.
There's this guy no joke.
Like I think I'm a good comic this
better at what he does,
but he tracks flash floods and he's
like,
he's like on camera.
Like okay,
I'm in this valley,
see this cloud over there?
It's raining over there.
He shouldn't be doing some 15 minutes.
All right,
we're going to with it.
And this guy finds a plot of land where
the flash flood or run and he can chase
it and almost follow it,
follow it,
hop up on the bank and then cut a corner
and get in front of it again.
This guy is so good at fucking following
flash floods.
There's this girl that,
this is what I find on the Internet
because like I get online,
there's this girl,
Kimmy Warner.
Okay,
this girl is the best.
I'm obsessed with spear phishing right
now and I've never fishing,
never done in my life,
uh,
obsessed with spirit.
I watched spear fishing videos.
Joe Maybe eight hours a day.
Why do like it when I'm in bed?
And you know,
when you're killing time kimmy warner to
pull up kimmy wonder,
this woman is a fucking amazing.
This is the picture of her swimming with
a great white shark to that kind of
spear phishing woman coming on next
week.
Who?
Valentino Thomas.
I don't know her.
I'm googling the fuck out of her.
Google Valentine Thomas.
She's coming on next week.
She was a lawyer who a quitter Gig and
it became a,
like a very active and active on social
media spear fishermen.
Oh,
she's beautiful.
Where's she out of Florida keys.
She's in Florida somewhere on the west
coast of Florida is a big spear fishing
community.
Shooting a lot of hog head groupers.
By the way.
This is where I talk about something
I've never fucking done.
We should do it.
I'll do.
I'm in.
Let's do it.
I want to spear fishing.
Apparently.
It's like hunting underwater dude and
out now.
Are you ready for this?
This is what is wrong with me is that
I've watched so much spear fishing.
I'm going to talk about it intimately.
The thing about shooting out on the west
coast of Florida is they use a lot of
Hawaiian slinks.
Alright.
Very different than the average spirit.
Hawaiian sling.
I'm glad you asked joe to rubber bands
and use a rubber band with a pointy
stick.
But when kimmy werner goes,
she's got like string,
like she'll shoot a tuna and it'll take
off and she'll hold on and ride with it.
Oh Jesus.
Yeah.
It's ride the tuna.
I think it's just based on the depths of
where you hunt.
So when you hunt over on the west coast
and now I'm talking out of my ass.
Do not listen to anything I say been,
but it's a lot of shallower shoots.
It's like 30 feet.
A lot of reef shoots out in Hawaii.
Kimmy Warner goes down like a hundred
feet and chills.
Whoa.
And just chills and feet.
One hundred feet.
Me.
And you'll be good in the Bahamas.
Yeah.
Bahamas.
Six feet.
The Ah,
that's what I'm looking at.
Just over your head where you can still
sand down to nine.
If you get crazy.
Get done.
Nine,
you can push off the bottom.
Pop back up again bro.
I'm obsessed with spirit.
Such a,
such a cool way to live your life opera.
He's done a bunch of it.
Uh,
I would,
I would love to try it.
It looks like fun.
She invited me.
Valentine invited me to go next week,
but I have the time.
It's going to go to San Diego.
They're going to go tuna spear fishing.
See then San Diego,
those,
those.
Uh,
the Pacific Ocean Spear phishing is a,
I think it a little bit of sport sport
like [inaudible].
You got to really know how to hold your
breath for a long time.
It's different.
I think so.
I think only because of depths.
Like everything's pretty shallow out on
the west coast and the east coast or the
east coast.
Everything's pretty shallow.
Every like all the keys you're,
you're doing like 15 feet.
Oh,
15,
20 feet tops.
But uh,
but on the west coast,
everything is a tad bit deeper,
Huh?
At least from what I've been watching
with Kimmy Warner,
there's a go to kimmy and there's a
video of her.
No Shit hanging out at a hundred feet.
Just with the spirit.
Just waiting.
Yeah.
She got four and a half minutes to kill.
Why not?
Four and a half minutes.
She's holding our breaths.
Date.
She can hold her.
She's free diving.
Oh no tanks.
Oh Christ.
All free diving in like camouflage,
camouflage.
Shit.
Not Afraid of sharks.
Loves sharks.
Well,
you know what the heck,
soudas you ever heard of a heck suit?
They got the suit called a h,
e c s.
it's like a suit that there's some.
It's based on something.
I think it's called the Feria Day cage.
And what it does is it hides your
electrical signal.
And one of the things about fish is that
fish,
uh,
apparently they read your electrical
signal,
like the,
like you,
you can take a,
there's certain machines that like you
could hover your hand over them and
it'll register that an electrical
signals coming off of your body.
But then when you put this heck suit on,
you run your hand over the same exact
machine.
It shows nothing really.
Yeah.
So this,
this suit is something that,
it's very controversial in the hunting
community because some people don't
believe it really works because there's
no real clear absolute studies that it
works on animals.
But there are clear studies that had
shields your body's electrical signal
and.
But it works pretty unequivocably on
fish,
on fish.
It's crazy.
You got to pull up hex sue hecs suit,
video fish.
So you basically roll into the water,
like Predator put you put gloves on
Sudan and they can't see you
like they,
for whatever reason you can get right up
to them.
It's fucking weird man.
But you know,
yeah.
You get right up to fish right up to
like corals.
They get right up to coral reefs.
See,
now,
here's the thing,
I don't know how much of this would
happen exactly the same way if this guy
wasn't wearing this suit because I don't
really,
I don't really have that information,
but I do know that people that spearfish
and people that are involved with,
uh,
you know,
underwater diving and shit,
they swear by these things,
they,
they say it absolutely works.
And they had it on shark week two.
There were using it on shark week.
There's something about those suits.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I,
our,
I was going to go out to the Great
Barrier Reef with Ari if Tom was going
out there at the same time.
We're all three going to go dive at the
Great Barrier Reef.
Do a liveaboard.
Arjuna.
Actually,
I've been talking back and forth about
finding a place to do a live aboard and
go overboard.
The other boat and we stayed for like
four days.
You do two times a day.
Do you like him?
Yeah.
Wow.
Archery's adventure or he's all about
living life and if I can move,
fold that into my family and let my wife
understand that like,
you know,
once a quarter I got to do something
crazy,
you know?
Then,
and then my wife's like,
oh,
she's cool with it.
We talked to a few.
What's the ultra marathon runner that
you had on Courtney Dot Walter?
Nope.
Back.
Bitter.
Is that bitter?
Me and Ari,
we're going to find a international
marathon to do together.
Like find an international.
Really 26 miles.
Yeah.
Regular math.
Not like one of those ultras that's
breaking down your liver.
Will you pissed diet coke man,
let me tell you something I've always
had respect for like I've always had
respect for cam.
Never,
never anything shy of that.
But when you run a marathon,
the respect you have for campaigns and
guys like David Goggins it,
it enters a new stratosphere.
Yeah.
I can only imagine.
You're like,
whoa.
Like when David Goggins says,
embrace the hate,
embrace the suck.
Just just,
just decided not to quit.
That's where my brain,
when I went to the marathon,
I was like deciding not to quit and at
22 miles both my calves just seized up.
My quads went into my legs and the woman
in front of me,
shit her pants and I was like,
you watched her?
She washed her shit.
Her pants,
a grown woman,
like an executive shit.
Her pants went down one leg and upper
ass and I went.
Since she stopped.
Nope,
she kept going gangster,
but like that,
that smell.
I asked when I started running pastor,
I was like,
fuck this bitch.
please let her be an exact from fx or
something.
You're like,
hey,
that would be hilarious.
But those guys,
like when I watch cams videos now of him
running in the afternoon and running
here and he's doing a marathon a day.
Your speed he's running and the way he's
talking,
as he's running his inspirational beyond
measure from a guy like me where I go,
I want to get there.
Like I want to get like he's fucking.
I,
I can't.
I mean I can't,
I can't put it into words now.
He's an alum and he works full time job.
That's really blows me away.
Yeah.
Are you not drinking know for how long?
I just haven't been for how long?
Not.
I mean I will be on stage.
Uh,
no.
I mean I'll,
I'll take a drink with me at the end of
the night,
like when I tell the machine story on
the second show,
I'll have that drink.
That's it.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Nothing man.
Cleaning it up.
No,
I'm just,
I don't know.
I don't know growing up.
No.
I know I still party,
but like,
yeah,
like if I saw you at the store tonight,
I still partying and smoking but I just,
I dunno.
I think it is.
No,
this is what sucks about being me is
like people to go with what's going on.
Are you sick or something going on and
you're like,
no,
just I'm also regular.
Yeah,
it's fine.
Yeah.
Nothing wrong with that.
I,
you know,
I did the triathlon and I didn't drink
leading up to it and I did it and I felt
really good.
I just felt really good and I thought,
and you know,
you know when you have friends that I'm
45 and so you start saying seeing
friends that that lifestyle starts to
effect in different ways and you go,
okay,
I want,
I don't ever want to quit drinking.
I don't ever want to quit smoking weed.
I don't ever want to go with Ari and run
a marathon and then not do mushrooms
with them.
It's in Buenos Aires.
I want that to be a part of my life,
but I can't have that if I'm going at
the pace I'm going at like I can't,
I can't have both.
Well you started
to rely on your body a lot more like
what you're doing with all this running
and you know,
these,
the,
what was that one that you did where you
had to do all the obstacle courses,
race,
Spartan,
doing a triathlon.
You relying on your body.
Yeah.
Like part of your recreation now is
relying on your endurance and when
you're doing that and you're drinking at
the same time,
you're just shooting yourself in the
foot.
Yeah,
I mean I still,
like I said,
like we did the Spartan race and right
after you sit up in the stands,
everyone has some beers,
couple of beers,
maybe a hit of a vape pen and then you
just go home and you get a good night's
sleep.
But you're right.
I think for me,
training for the triathlon was just,
it.
I couldn't do both.
I just was not able to do both.
And then when I got done I just,
you know,
I think a lot of like I was thinking
about last night,
I didn't drink,
I didn't drink last night obviously.
And um,
and I was like,
I was in the shower today.
I had a really hard time sleeping last
night.
I was up all night.
I've just been doing a lot of press and
so I think you empty your serotonin
because you're giving everyone and
everything.
And I was like,
and I was up all night with like a
little bit of panic attacks and uh,
I definitely would've drank last night.
You get a panic attack.
Like what does that mean?
Like what happens for me?
Uh,
you kind of get blinders on and for me
personally,
I will start saying the same phrase over
and over in my head again where I can't
get it out like a,
like,
um,
right,
like my brain will go satellite of love,
Sad,
a lot of love Satta Line of love,
satellite.
And then I'll start going.
Like last night I had a phrase going
through my head and I was like,
fuck,
Z,
alarm on is the alarm on and I get up
and I go check the alarm and then I get
in bed and I go,
I should just make sure all the doors
were locked.
And then I go and check all the doors
and then I get up and go.
Did I lock the man cave?
I gotta get up and I locked the man
cave.
Now normally that's where I will start.
Like if I have a few drinks,
that does not happen.
You know what's weird,
what Jamie was talking about this too,
it's at night.
Yeah.
At night when you get weirded out,
it's like when you're getting ready to
shut off,
it's like,
can I shut the body off yet?
Is Everything cool?
I think meditation might help me because
I can't just,
I can't shut my brain off.
And then I'm like,
and then I go a tank for your man cave
to take off all of my man cave.
Joe Makes you man cave.
It's like a office,
right?
It's like half of this probably you fill
a tank in there.
It will be really big in my man cave.
He'll be really big in there.
They get stuff that you don't have to
get one that big.
They,
they'll have a,
they have a smaller one.
Um,
to have like one that's like a six by
seven or four by seven.
Four by seven.
See,
I,
I would rather probably I'd rather
sauna.
I love salt.
I love those infrared Saunas.
I love those songs.
Great to.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Um,
I was thinking about the house,
I was thinking about it this morning in
the shower and I was like,
you know what man,
the sober October we did was so helpful
because I learned how to cope and go to
bed with nothing with nothing.
No NYQUIL,
no nothing.
I was super helpful.
And then I learned little tricks like
drinking on planes.
I still may have a few drinks before I
get on a plane or a couple of drinks on
the plane.
But the difference is if it's an early
morning flight,
I don't need a drink,
get on the plane you don't need.
I don't need it for.
Whereas of ways I just said I just gotTa
do it,
you know,
it was helpful for me to uh,
what's really interesting is it made me
realize what,
what's happening to you dreams when
you're smoking pot all the time because
as soon as you stopped smoking pot and
then your dreams become super vivid,
like really vivid,
like excrutiatingly,
vivid and strange,
bizarre.
You're like,
oh,
what am I doing to myself with the weed
all the time?
Yeah.
That's probably not good for my dreams.
I want those dreams.
The vivid ones.
Crazy ones.
You Take Alpha brain.
I dude,
I told you actually you go to bed.
I took out.
My wife made me stop because I was.
I was a lunatic on Alpha brain because I
could feel it really immediately if you
take it before,
like I take a double dose.
So like if I'm like these packets and
you're supposed to take one packet,
I'll take two of these packets with some
water before I go to bed.
And then you know like maybe an hour
before you go to bed and with no pot and
Alpha brain you will have lucid intense
fucking dreams.
Like they're intense,
they're in,
they're durable.
Like you realize your dream and they
don't wake up like they get lucid and
you're in the middle of them.
You know the way I described lucid
dreams,
like lucid dreams or like a delicate
bubble that a kid would blow it
and you can kind of almost catch it on
your hand and then pop it pops.
These were like basketballs,
like they weren't popping like it'd be
in the middle of the gym,
like,
Oh,
I'm in a dream.
Okay,
now we're in a dream.
Let's just keep going,
and they.
It wouldn't knock me out of the dream by
recognizing that I was in a dream,
which ordinarily would immediately do
it.
Ordinarily I'd be like,
Oh my God,
I'm dreaming.
Well,
I'm waking up and then you just wake up.
I could keep myself in that lucid dream
state for a long time,
a lucid dream.
Naturally and I,
I have fucking insane.
I have.
I've been sold a show to comedy central
based on my dreams.
I have insane dreams.
You should try it.
Do you know what Parasso Tim is?
Never heard of that stuff.
It's another nootropic.
It's a real potent.
And the.
One of the interesting things about
nootropics is there's a ton of them.
There's a lot of different ones.
One of them they found recently is
creatine.
They found a creatine.
Boosts your,
your,
your mental performance.
Yeah.
Really?
Creatines Kinda a lot of benefits men,
because you think about it,
right?
Create team makes your body retain more
water as well,
right?
It's one of the things that people don't
like about.
It kind of gives you like a chubby face,
like get a little little bloated on it,
but what that's doing is just retaining
more water.
Right.
But if you have more water,
it also makes you stronger like an APP.
It's proven over time.
Taking creatine as a supplement,
it's very effective.
It really does make you stronger.
It makes you bigger,
so you've got to think like all that is
like all this tissue and all this water.
It's like it's probably just
everything's healthier.
Right,
and probably the flow of everything's
healthier to the conductivity of it all.
Obviously I'm not a scientist,
but I would think that all that makes
sense.
Like you're like your brain works
terrible when it's dehydrated,
like have you ever been dehydrated and
try to think it's.
Your brain is so weak.
It's incredible how much dehydration
affects the way your brain performs,
but on the other side it should be that
way.
If you're really well hydrated,
your brain would probably work better
and the only makes sense.
It's amazing how important water is.
Oh fuck man.
To everything.
I got this nutritionist when I started
doing the triathlon,
like men's health covered it.
Like they,
they're doing a documentary on it.
What are they doing with the whole
triathlon?
They hit me up and they're like,
man,
this guy connor read really cool guy.
He's like,
he's just a fan of what we do.
And he was like,
man,
I love sober October.
I love you.
And Tommy's bets,
you know,
like there's a lot of people as bizarre
as a sound,
whatever we decided to do with these
competitions that God inspired and lost
a ton of weight and yeah,
I've,
I've seen a lot of that.
It's also an amazing man.
He has been.
And like guys hit me up and they're
like,
I'm running my first marathon.
I'm running my first spartan race.
I'm me and my buddies are doing it.
When you're in Columbus,
can you come hang out with us?
And,
and it's,
it really is.
I know Tom and I've talked about it a
lot.
It definitely was not our intention,
but we just wanted to.
We were fucking around and then when we
all did so rocktober at their do their
people to come up came up to me at the
triathlon.
This Guy Willie Nelson's his name and
he's like,
Bro.
He's like,
Holy Shit,
the machine and it fucking sober October
with you guys.
I was like,
really?
He's like,
dude,
no booze,
no drugs.
Can you fucking believe it?
And I'm like,
yeah,
I'm right.
Like we shared the same month.
I'm doing it again.
I'll do it again.
I'm going to do it every October.
I'm just gonna make it a thing.
We should do something else too.
Like right now it's almost September.
He has it like the 20th or something.
What is it?
Twenty third.
I'm assigned a lot of time.
Basically have a month to figure it out.
Like what do you mean?
Add another thing inside sober October.
Yeah.
I mean we can be sober and we could do
the yoga classes.
We could do it again,
not getting time to do those fucking
yoga classes and those are amazing for
that.
That that was also amazing.
I did nine in a row.
I did nine days in a row just to whack
it out and when I did that I was like,
it's amazing.
Like if you just know that you have to
do it,
you just do it.
Yeah.
But if you don't know you have to do it.
You find all sorts of reasons to not do
it.
Like I'll just go lift weights or.
Yeah,
just go for a run.
I'll just go do this,
but if feel like I have to get seven
more of these fucking things in,
in the next 14 days,
I just do them right now.
Yeah.
You know what's cool about them is that
it's.
This sounds silly,
but now I have hot yoga in my.
You tell utility belt worth of workouts
where I go.
Sometimes I'll go like,
like I'll come off the road and I'll be
like,
comment on maybe I booze that weekend
I'll be like,
Monday I'm doing a hot yoga and I'll go
to a hot yoga and I know how the poses I
don't have.
I'm not embarrassed.
I know I've got the Mat,
like doing your first hot yoga is
embarrassing a little bit,
but when you go back in it and you do it
again and you just pour sweat and you're
like,
shit,
I'm coming back tomorrow and then you of
course you don't,
but it's courageous when you see people
going to those classes that are like
really obese and they take that risk of
being almost naked in front of these
people.
You got shorts on shit and some lady
just did it the other day,
her first class and I was like,
that lady took.
Obviously she's not physically fit.
It's just not that active.
This is probably like super nerve
wracking for her to do.
She took up ballsy chance.
It's a.
it's tough to do.
It's tough to do anything.
It's tough to.
You know,
it's tough to fucking take a kettlebell
class.
Tough.
You've gone there.
It's weird.
You get weirded out.
When I started,
when I started the training and I had to
go to a pool and swim and getting a
speedo.
Now I wear speedos all the time,
but for real to where one,
like for real?
Yeah,
for real.
For Real.
Like to,
and do you have to wear one?
Why is it that much better than shorts?
Oh my God.
The drag is like,
it's you glide like a fucking dolphin
ever jagger off with too much lotion and
you're like,
I don't even feel it.
I need to drive some of this off.
That's a bad example,
but it's super specific to me.
But you swam in the ocean recently?
Uh,
was in Italy last week and I was
swimming in the ocean.
I was realizing like,
wow,
it's so much easier to swim in the
ocean.
Oh yeah.
Salt water to float.
It's so,
it's.
So it's like way easier.
A little easier.
It's like ways your open water swimming
in saltwater in the Malibu.
Triathlon is coming up.
That one's tough.
It's a half mile swim.
But you're in a wetsuit and you're
buoyant and you're in the saltwater
swimming near great white sharks.
I'm doing Malibu in here.
White sharks.
They're everywhere around.
But when you're in a pack like that,
oh well what's the odds of you get bit
and just get into the center.
Yeah.
That's where they go.
Right for the middle.
Shoot up.
Just that movie.
The Meg is supposed to be one of the
worst movies of all time for real.
We've seen that movie and say they say
it's doing great at the box office to
this.
We're.
Everyone's an idiot.
It's supposed to be so bad.
It's a big shark.
They just fucking.
Nobody saw before who?
Here it is.
It's doing as good as crazy rich Asians.
Oh,
crazy rush agents killing it.
Oh good.
Where is it?
Killing it.
Yeah,
I see that.
Hilarious.
I want to see it.
The Meg,
what's it got?
Ninety one percent like this movie.
Forty seven percent rotten tomatoes.
Six point two on imd be.
Hmm.
That's not bad.
Like what's the.
What is the worst well received movie
recently?
It's been some really,
really bad ones.
Right?
Oh,
I got this.
I could.
I could come up with this because I,
I,
I.
There was one that came out recently and
everyone trashed it.
Well,
I'm not going to say no.
I got Gotti movie.
Didn't get like zero the movie.
That's it.
Yeah.
The God,
he will be.
He's writing again.
Yeah.
Let's see.
Does a movie I liked and everyone
trashed.
Oh yeah.
I've got to leave that one alone.
Burnett paper.
Yeah.
That's fucking.
That's a business I don't want to get
into.
I don't ever want to do that.
I see Tom doing it now.
He's doing some movies.
I'm like,
yeah,
good luck.
You know,
it's nice to see him blowing up,
but that movie thing is a trap.
You get on those sets for 16 hours a day
and everyone's depressed.
Everyone's tired and everyone's on the
antidepressants.
Fucking everyone.
Oh my God.
He put on a movie set.
You talked to actors about what they're
on.
Well,
you know,
my,
my Welbutrin wasn't doing it for me,
so I got on Lexapro and I'm on Zoloft
and I really find it just,
it's really balancing me out.
And I started taking this.
I started taking that and Xanax a little
here and a little bit like,
Whoa,
everyone is on something,
dude.
Fuck that.
You go to Columbia for eight weeks and
you live in Columbia and do the.
I know Mark Walberg do that mile 22.
He just lived in Columbia.
Eight weeks.
Fuck that.
I'd much rather just to stand up.
I wouldn't mind doing.
I'm not even joking.
I would love my dream,
my dreams,
doing what I'm doing right now.
Like I like to expand span that if I
could do my own thing and expand that,
that's my goal.
But if you said part of the business
easily like a news radio,
like a,
like an ensemble cast.
That was hard to man.
I would love a multicam well it's fun if
everybody gets along but you've got to
rely on all those other people to keep
their shit together and you know it goes
sideways.
Yeah.
And then on top of that there's.
Sometimes the scripts don't work and
sometimes when the show's not doing well
then you have executives that chime in.
I honestly think that like what you're
doing with like somethings burning,
that kind of shit.
That's way better man.
Like you're the thing you're doing with
all things comedy,
like the cooking show,
that kind of fun shit where there's no
real bosses is way better for a guy like
you are a guy like me,
a great podcasts,
that kind of thing.
You're never going to be able to be
really authentically yourself with all
these executives and producers and
network notes and all that shit.
They don't know what the fuck they're
doing,
man.
That they just don't.
You know,
occasionally you'll get good advice,
but when something gets through with
that,
that sort of system and becomes a hit,
it's almost by luck.
It's almost like,
wow,
what are the odds?
It's like a salmon making its way up a
river.
It's why would it go up river the fuck
are you doing?
This is a terrible way to go.
You got to jump over a waterfall that is
so stupid.
It makes no sense.
It's so dumb,
but the one that makes it and spawns
like,
look,
this is our system.
It works like,
okay,
I guess this is it,
but it's almost like that.
It's like you're doing something that's
like so counterintuitive.
You're doing something creative and
you're being judged and an ordered
around by people who have zero
creativity.
They're not funny.
If there were funny,
they'd be comedians.
They're not funny,
but yet they're telling you what to do
and then you have to think about their
notes and you got to bring in the gay
roommate and the fucking the black
neighbor and the hot chick on the street
that everybody wants to fuck.
And everyone's like tripping over.
Yeah.
It's like,
I don't know.
Thanks man.
So we went into,
when we went and did that,
first something's burning me,
Bill and Tom and I walked on set and I
said,
I'm super difficult to work with.
Just want everyone to know that uh,
don't anyone stop me.
Don't anyone do anything.
I'll let you know when we starting to
let you know when we're done.
And they're like,
okay.
I said,
just cover everything.
Don't ever ask me to stop and do
anything.
Just cover everything.
That's a problem.
When they go stop,
rewind.
Say that again.
What?
Yup.
No,
get a camera on me and stay out of the
picture.
Just sleeping alone.
They don't understand that every time
you break that momentum,
now I'm thinking about you and I'm
thinking about that camera and I have to
reset again.
Yeah,
we did it.
We did.
Me and Tom and bill.
Did that first one.
Just one take both.
I mean both Tom and bill were like,
I got 45 minutes.
I was like,
perfect.
We see we've got it all.
They got up.
I think they are arid.
Almost all of it.
And then everyone loved it and then
deleon and Bobby Lee came in.
Same thing.
I was like,
no one said anything to the best ones.
Shaaban Brian Callin to me are my
favorite because you see Brittany
shopping.
He is so fucking funny in that very
funny dude.
He is so fucking funny in that that
like,
aren't you guys cook?
Oh my God.
Yo.
We cooked crab,
but we had to kill them on air and you
have to kill him in a humane way.
What?
Yeah.
In order to do it,
you have to kill him in a humane way in
order to do it.
In order to kill a crab legally.
Especially on Youtube.
You've got to kill you main way.
Yeah.
So you gotta it's gotta be within six
seconds.
Dude.
That shot an elk with a bow and Arrow on
Youtube.
You can go watch.
Go watch a elk,
get shot through the heart with a bow
and arrow.
Don't even have to be careful with a
crab.
All I know is that the one note we got
wasn't even have senses.
Well,
Brian,
cal take care.
Did he?
He was so fucking funny.
As you start by lifting up their Dick
and they have a dick.
I think so.
I think that's what it is.
And you jam it in and then when I'm it
in,
what is it?
The knife.
Oh,
well what the fuck?
How about you bring that up?
Lift up that Dick and you jam it in and
I'm thinking you're jamming their dick
in.
Why are you putting it?
No,
you take the knife.
He laid the crop.
I don't give a fuck them to death,
bro.
You lift up the Dick,
you pop the knife in,
and then you've got to hit the other
side of it within like six seconds and
that's a humane death for the crab.
Otherwise they're suffering.
So I show that to Brenda and Brenda's
like,
no bro,
I'm definitely not fucking doing this.
And Brian just goes,
I'll do it.
And literally like the Barbara Seville
goes through and kills 20 fucking crabs
like this.
I made them Chia Pino and they,
neither of them thought they'd like it
and they loved it.
What's Chia Pino?
That's like a soup.
It's like A.
Yeah,
it's like a fucking Brian.
He's definitely fucking dead.
He's cutting half.
Well,
wait a minute.
How's this?
Why is that humane?
Like what a weird thing.
Like you have to kill them humanely as
opposed to boiling them alive.
Is that the idea?
Yeah.
So I guess I'm not really surveil them
alive,
but like with lobsters,
they always boil them alive.
Yeah.
And they'll tell you you're supposed to
boil them alive.
But I'm always like,
well,
what do you mean?
Supposed to like says who?
Like what happens if you don't boil them
alive?
Like what?
Magic doesn't know what magic leaves
their body where they don't taste as
good if you don't boil them alive.
Yeah.
I don't know about that.
Come.
You can't just cut their fucking head
off and then they're dead and then you
throw them in the boiling water.
Like what is,
what's happening here?
Why do they need to be kept alive?
That's a well where you want them to be
fresh,
right?
Yeah.
Like there's a big difference in
seafood,
seafood and freshness.
That's huge.
Like you don't see dry age seafood,
you know,
like if you get a.
If you get a piece of beef from a
restaurant,
like a steak,
a lot of times aged because the bacteria
on the meat actually starts,
break it down
and it makes it more tender and it
actually gives it a lot of that mold
that they cut off of it.
You ever see dry age beef before they
slice it up?
No.
Whole ready.
Okay.
Show him.
Yeah.
There's a guy
that uh,
um,
I follow on instagram that was doing
something insane.
Like I think they had like a 200 day dry
age beef,
which is just like even hearing about
that.
You're like,
yeah,
that's what it looks like.
Yes.
That's what dry age beef look like.
It looks like it's rotten,
like rotten meat and you lose some of
the meat.
I mean it's really wasteful in a way
because the outside edge,
that black shit,
they cut all that off.
So you're losing you.
Can you find a video,
Jamie?
Of Trimming?
Just google trimming dry aged beef and
look up youtube.
Were you the guy that turned me onto the
guy that had his own fridge and was
doing it his own fridge in his garage?
Oh yeah.
I know a bunch of guys who do that.
It's like A.
I think it was doing with elk dry aging
out maybe.
Yeah,
if you guys do that.
So this is dry aged meat.
So look at that.
Oh yes.
The outside.
Look,
it looks rotten man.
Hey takes the outside and you cut into
it and then he,
I guess he's going to cut all the fat
off and he's gonna turn it into steaks.
I wasn't going to do with all that fat.
That's interesting.
It was thrown into the garbage.
So this fat has he one easy thrown that
away.
So he's just got a.
It seems like he's thrown that fat away.
Oh.
So he keeps a lot of the fat on and the
fan on top?
Yes.
Dry aged beef on top.
He's just losing the sides.
Well Yeah,
you're losing the outside of that
just in this particular cut,
but on some steaks,
you know,
it depends on how long he's dry aging it
to like when some people go really ham
with that shit though,
you know,
like I said,
they'll dry age for hundreds of days.
There's a lot of experimental stuff
they're doing now where I'm find this
dude on instagram.
Do you do that with elk?
No,
I don't know.
I got to get you and cam on something's
burning.
Yeah,
we'll do it.
I would love that.
Tam.
Can't cook though.
You know Dudley.
Dudley.
He can cook his ass off.
Right?
I'm the cook.
I'll cook for you guys.
Yeah.
You know.
Do you know how to cook?
I know how to reverse here,
but if you ever fucked around with wild
game,
I'll give you some today and um,
you could fuck around with it and then
if you get it right,
you know,
we'll figure out a way to do it.
I'll give you some recipes and stuff,
but it's not,
it's not that difficult,
but it is,
it's,
it's more tricky than beef.
Beef is hard to fuck up,
especially like a fatty beef because
there's so much moisture,
you know,
whereas a elk is basically,
you're,
you're basically eating a bodybuilder,
you're eating an athlete,
you know,
and it's just a richer,
darker meat and has very little fat in
it.
But,
um,
if you do it right,
it's fantastic.
Have you had it before?
I've had,
I've had your ground elk.
That's,
that's good.
But that's hard to like the right way to
do it is to do an elk stake.
I got to fucking set up that God damned
grill out here,
but we don't know how to have proper
ventilation.
I got one of those,
uh,
yoder pellet grills in the back there,
but we don't know how to get the proper
ventilation.
We might need to get some sort of a
permit.
Put like a vent like they would do with
a kitchen.
God Damn.
I can't find.
This guy's got this one.
I'm no rare gourmet meats.
Ooh,
what does he got going on?
See if you find like,
just google try 500 day dry age beef on
youtube.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
These guys don't fuck around.
Can I tell you one of them?
One of the coolest things you turned me
onto what?
Fucking Adam Green Tree.
Oh,
use an animal due to his insta stories.
Like I get bummed when I,
when I skip them.
And then when he's on one of those epic
haunts.
Yeah.
No,
he,
he does not fuck around dude.
That guy,
uh,
he goes out by himself by himself for
months at a time of extreme age steak.
What does it say in there for 20 days?
Yeah.
This one's 400 on this one.
Oh,
go to 400.
Let's see what that looks like.
It probably looks terrible when they
start cutting it up,
back it up a little bit so we can say,
just saw this online the other day.
Like I saw I saw this and I didn't click
on it.
So they,
it's real weird man.
I mean,
you're basically letting it rot and
you're relying on the bacteria to not
completely flourish.
Like you have to have a certain
temperature.
I think they keep it somewhere around
like 40 degrees or something like that.
And it's drive,
like,
look at that.
It looks terrible.
It looks like a rotten piece of what
you're supposed to.
He's going to eat that.
Yeah,
they're gonna.
Eat this shit out of it.
And look at that.
That is so weird.
Dude.
That's so weird.
It doesn't even look read anymore.
I mean it's white and I think that's,
that's why you have you say it.
Why'd you,
why'd you,
what's the other word for that was
another word.
Oh,
coby.
Yeah,
he it.
So keep it going.
Sorry.
So He's,
uh,
he's,
he's going to sear it I guess.
Yeah.
And that throws some time.
Oh.
And then he's gonna Sue v Ah,
you ever Suvi or have it takes forever
to Suvi eggs.
Does it our really for soft boiled eggs,
I love soft boiled eggs.
Susie's interesting man,
because you could have something and
cook it like say at a hundred and 25
degrees,
which is like where you want your steak
to be and you could have it in there for
hours.
You take.
What you do is you take your steaks and
you've got a vacuum seal and beat them
and then you can just let them sit.
You're not going to overcook them.
And then see her that she was some
butter and garlic.
Yeah.
Or with a blow.
I do a blow torch sometimes.
Wow.
Yeah,
they have torches.
Look at that.
That guy's got the butter and the time.
Oh sweet baby.
Oh Jesus.
What are you doing here?
You Fuck?
Look at this camera slicing it open.
That's 400 day dry aged meat looking at
me.
So having a mouth chasm.
Oh,
foodies are such dorks.
They just,
they just get so into it.
They just get so into it,
man.
When you go travel and you go to like
Thailand and stuff,
do you get food and go in and try to
find something dangerous and crazy or do
you just pretty much stay?
I didn't eat bugs,
but I had some really hot food.
Yeah.
No bugs.
They tried to serve me,
bugs my pitch.
I hosted fear factor for six years.
Get that shit out of my face.
Wrong guy.
I'm not interested in your bugs.
Not only that,
it doesn't gross me out at all.
Like nothing grosses me out like eating
bugs or anything.
Throw up.
I remember your wife threw up in her car
one time I think I was.
I came up either.
I came over there and you were cleaning
out your wife's car.
I said,
what are you doing?
You were like,
oh my wife threw up all over car,
one of those green drinks and I was
like,
bring up.
Like in brought up,
throwing up the other day.
Just brought up throwing up and I
started gagging on his podcast.
Yeah,
I'm immune.
I saw so many people throw up.
I've seen hundreds of people throw up
right in front of me and I had to talk
to them while they're puking and I it,
this is a learned skill because when I
first started doing the show,
I would gag when I would see other
people do it,
but yeah,
but then after awhile it just went away.
Like that part of me is dead,
it's dead.
So when my wife threw up in her car,
I was like,
I'll clean it,
can give a fuck.
That's cleaning.
I cannot do that.
I can't.
Even when my kids throw up,
I'm like,
I'm sorry you're on your own.
Clean up all the puke.
If my kid's Puke,
I am the designated puked cleaner.
Oh,
100 percent of the time.
One hundred percent of the time someone
throws up in the bed or somewhere else.
I,
I cleaned it up,
dude.
I came back from Utah one time and I was
firing hot and I had a crazy weekend and
I just wasn't feeling right and I.
and we went and ate a big dinner and I
don't feel good.
I'm in bed,
I'm going to rope.
I'm going to Yankees Robe that uh,
and I get up and I'm like,
I'm not feeling good and I go into the
bathroom and I go to shit,
but I start throwing up before I can
ship and I sit in the road and I shit in
the robe and throw up on my lap and my
wife's a thug.
She went,
we got this.
Let's get you in the shower.
I'll take care of it.
I was like,
wow,
that's a good woman,
right?
Yeah.
That's a good woman right there.
Yeah,
man.
I like literally,
unless I'm out of town,
my wife does not clean up puke.
She would tell me that the kid puked and
not cleaning it up.
Really?
Yeah.
Because she'll start throwing up and I
won't at all.
Does she?
She takes care of the chickens though.
Um,
yeah.
Sometimes,
you know,
um,
we have a guide that we hired to take
care of the chicken sometimes,
especially when we're not there.
He'll,
he'll handle certain things like you
have to.
Chickens are a little bit of effort.
You know,
you've got to up the cage.
You gotta collect the eggs every day.
We had some squirrels,
steel and eggs.
We had a real issue with that.
I got a squirrel that I have to hose out
of our chicken coop.
Yeah.
Well Marshall took care of that.
Marshall fucks up.
Squirrels.
Dude.
Marshall.
He is the sweetest dog of all time and
less your squirrel then.
He's the devil.
I mean,
I never seen a dog so determined to kill
a squirrel.
It's crazy.
He goes out now and he looks for them.
He runs to the chicken coop and then he
circles the chicken coop.
Look and see where these motherfuckers
are getting.
See if anybody's around there,
see if anybody's slipping.
But I was on the road.
My wife sent me a picture of Marshall
with a squirrel in his mouth.
And she's so happy because she doesn't
like squirrels.
The squirrels are fucking up all the uh,
they steal all the chicken food.
Yeah.
I like,
I like squirrels.
I think they're cute.
So like for me I'm like,
so what?
They deal the chicken food,
get,
make more chicken food.
But then they start stealing the eggs.
And I was like,
Oh,
you push up and he can't steal my food.
That's my food.
You can't steal the eggs.
Let me find this for our chickens or
family members.
Yeah,
they are right.
Yeah.
When I came home,
when it was like,
you remember it was like 120 and all the
trees were dying.
Yeah.
And I walked in and Leanne had chickens
in the house.
She's like,
they can't be out there.
It's too fucking hot.
Yeah.
But they do.
They have to be out there.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
He's all happy.
This is,
this is ingrained in his DNA soft.
So he doesn't like.
He's like,
I want to bring it back to you a fully
intact so that you can't.
So that if you need this,
is that blood on his chest?
Uh,
yeah.
That's blood.
Yeah.
Well he brings things to you always
because he's a retriever.
So like he has a little box of stuff,
toys that he has in the house and he's
the only dog that I've ever had that
doesn't mangle every toy you give them
because I've had pit bulls and mastiffs
and you give them a toy and they just,
they just start tearing apart.
He has carries him around.
He carries him around.
He brings to you.
So like when I see him in the morning
I'm like,
good morning sir.
Good morning.
And he's wagging,
his tail is happy and the first thing he
does is run over to his pilot toys.
Grabs one and comes over with.
It brings you a president.
Yeah,
he.
Well he has it in his mouth.
He always,
he's a retriever.
Like if you see retrievers running,
a lot of times they're carrying their
leash in their mouth as they're running.
They love to hold on to things in their
mouth.
Weird.
Does he dive in underwater?
Oh,
he fucking swims like a motherfucker do.
That dog is always in the water.
He just,
he will die from the deep end of the.
Like if the kids are playing in the
pool,
he and I'll let him out the door.
He runs to the pool,
stands on the edge and then leaps into
the water splashes.
How can loves it?
Does he dive underwater though?
A little bit.
That's what we used to have A.
I used to have a black lab and you can
throw one of those rings under water and
she dived to the bottom,
grab it and pull it up.
Oh,
he doesn't do that.
I guarantee you he will.
I guarantee you he will have.
Betty would if I taught them how to do
it,
but he swims like it's instinctual.
Those fucking dogs.
That's my,
my bullmastiff.
I cannot get her in the pool.
Really?
She looks at me like,
like,
like you're trying to
pitch anal sex to your wife.
She's like,
come on.
We both know how this is going to go.
No one's going to be happy.
Yeah.
Johnny cash and people always asked me,
um,
to have pictures of my other dogs.
They're actually both passed away now.
I had to put them both down.
Both your bull mastiffs stiff in the
English of the English bulldog.
She's,
you know,
mix.
They were uh,
they were both 13 years old and I'm.
Johnny couldn't walk anymore.
It was,
it was really rough the last few days of
his life.
Um,
I would,
uh,
try to bring him in for dinner and when
I would try to bring them in,
he literally couldn't make it.
It was a small yard where he was at,
but we're talking about like,
you know,
15 yards.
He couldn't make it 15 yards to the
house.
He would like take a couple steps and
his body would shake and he'd take a
couple steps and he was just sleeping
all day and he was also having a really
hard time shifting and he would
occasionally shit in the house.
Like he couldn't hold his bowels and he
couldn't go outside when he wanted to
look at.
You'd see them trying.
But his,
his body was so old from massive 13
years old.
His crazy old,
like a lot of them died at like eight or
nine and he was 13 and he was sweet,
sweet dog up until the end,
but he just,
he was,
you know,
he was suffering.
It was,
it was hard.
It's hard when you know them when
they're a puppy and then 10 years later,
like you're kind of the same and they're
not men,
they're gone,
you know.
So I think about that with Marshall
because he's only a year and a half and
he's so full of life and he's so fun.
He's so silly and playful and happy.
I'm like,
man,
there's gonna be a day where Marshall's,
this old old,
old dog and I'm going to have to put him
down to,
you know,
it was depressing.
And the other one,
brutus the boot,
you know,
English bulldog mix.
He was better than Johnny for a long
time.
Still I've known for the last two years
that they didn't have much time left.
You know,
they were,
they were both struggling hard,
but brutus took a real hard turn over
the last few months where,
um,
he wouldn't even come in.
Like I tried to get them to come in and
somebody you want to eat,
I try to put a little food in front of
his face and he would try to stand up
and his legs would be shaking so hard,
man,
it's so hard watching them fade away,
you know?
And then also watching them suffer,
you know,
the last,
the last days where you have to decide
where,
you know,
me and my wife had to have conversations
like we have to do something like this.
Like one day we're going to come home,
it's going to be a dead dog.
And it's not like they're having a good
time.
Like this is a horrible suffering.
Slow demise.
So did you have
someone come to the house?
Where did you take them?
Here was rough dude.
That's rough.
Yeah.
Priscilla seven.
And I mean I got her when I first
started doing this 1:40.
That's big dogs had five knee surgeries.
Oh my God,
dude,
that's fucking expensive to.
Oh,
you know,
I do have an idea,
but you do.
I had a,
um,
a female pit bull that had two acl
reconstructions.
She had her,
both of her back legs done.
She blew one out.
I got it fixed,
blew the other one out.
I had to get that fixed to a dog.
They shave the bone down.
They don't like reconstruct it where
they add like another ligament,
they shave the bone down so it doesn't,
so it sits on the it differently.
So it locks in place so it doesn't pop
off and,
and,
and go like at a,
at a socket or whatever the fuck it is.
But yeah,
it's fucking like 10 grand a pop.
Right?
Oh,
it was.
I mean,
I'm not going to tell everyone how much
because I stopped liking me into minute.
They'd be like,
what kind of fucking Hollywood idiot are
you?
You just killed a dog like that.
But she got one acl and then we fixed
it.
Then the uh,
then while this one's healing and
turning good,
the other acl goes out.
So we fixed that one.
We're like,
alright,
we're done.
And then as this one ceiling,
this one goes out again.
And they're like,
and that's when they're like,
do you want to put it down?
I'm not,
I'm like,
no man,
I'm fucking,
it was like five grand a pop I think and
then,
and then it's,
it even adds up more because then
they're like,
we should keep her here while this,
while she's healing to do it and then
feed her diamonds and then they realize
they're doing this one,
that something's wrong with her kneecap.
And then they realize she's got,
you know,
it's overbreeding in her bra and her
breed that are kneecaps are bad.
So they fixed this one,
this one replaced both her kneecaps and
then one more goes out and they're like,
all right man,
shit,
I hit that dog is duck greatest fucking
dog mastiffs are amazing.
There's some of my favorite dogs ever.
They're so chill dude.
The sweetest like gets up in bed with
you in the morning and just puts her
face right up on you and just does one
of those big cal brass like and you're
like,
oh,
I'm here.
They're so relaxed too.
They're just a different kind of dog.
Very relaxed,
you know?
And,
and I feel comfortable when I go on the
road.
I feel comfortable knowing there's a
hundred and 40 pound animal that will
give its life for my daughters.
It's one of the.
One of our dog sleeps on one of our
daughters beds,
one of our dogs sleep.
Priscilla sleeps in George's bed and I
go,
I'm good.
No one's coming in anywhere and no one's
breaking in anything.
Yeah.
I got a buddy who was a German shepherd,
a police dog and uh,
it's uh,
it's,
it's one of those dogs that he has to be
with all the time and train all the
time.
But this dog,
it's disturbing thing to have because
you basically have an assassin that
lives with you.
This is just waiting for orders.
Just waiting.
Yeah,
my buddies,
my buddies got a German shepherd that he
hasn't quite figured out yet.
And,
and,
uh,
you can't work a full time job and just
leave that thing alone in the yard.
You just can't.
They're intense dogs.
Their intent and their smartest fuck.
So in a weird way,
it's like dealing with a complicated
chick.
You're like,
I know you have daddy issues,
but I can't really figure him out and
I'm not spending a lot of time,
enough time with you.
Oh,
you can't fix them.
You could train a dog training.
A woman can't add in here.
You can't.
If you meet someone,
I don't hear a woman or a man.
You meet someone who's completely
fucking crazy.
You gotta get Outta there.
You gotta go.
You can't just.
I want to fix them.
We know a lot of people that try to fix
them.
Like Bryan County,
when I first met him,
it was always trying to fix these crazy
girls and I was like,
dude,
you gotta save yourself.
You got to save yourself,
man.
You can't fix someone.
You can't.
I remember the day I decided I would
never fix a chick again.
It was a one night stand and I came in
like 15 seconds.
She and I told her,
I said,
hey,
I came and then I was about to say,
give me a second.
Let me reboot.
I'm going to go back at it,
but she was on top of me.
She goes,
are you fucking kidding me?
And she punched the wall.
She goes,
you got to learn how to,
you got to learn how to fuck,
you need to read a book and get online
and learn how to fuck.
And I gently rolled out of bed and I was
like,
I think you need to go home.
I was like,
this isn't happening anymore.
And then she was like,
excuse me?
And I was like,
listen,
I'm not your boyfriend and I'm not your
fucking husband and what I just saw,
I'm not going to be able to help.
And she was like,
and then you can see it in her eyes.
Like I gotta get on a train and go to
Brooklyn.
She was like getting.
They started getting pissed.
By the way,
I'm in my kitchen now in New York.
Condom still on.
I go to the um,
this is how it tapped out.
I'm,
I go grab a beer out of the refrigerator
still naked,
condom on.
Start drinking a beer.
My roommate,
we,
Joe walks out and he's like,
what the fuck are you?
I got it handled.
Don't worry about it.
Walk her to the fucking door,
walk her to the door,
miss might be the most beautiful moment
of walking to the door.
And she's like,
are you fucking serious?
Are you fucking like in my face?
And she goes,
you're pathetic.
You fuck.
And like tries to humiliate me.
And I go,
listen,
I fucked you.
And came are one.
And she looks at me.
He goes like this,
it goes like this goes like this.
And I flinched so fucking hard.
I go,
we both start laughing and she,
well we both started laughing
immediately and then she just smiles and
goes,
it's four in the fucking morning in my
apartment building.
She goes,
Bert Kreischer can't fuck it.
Starts Banging on doors.
I'm like,
alright,
this is over.
Take the charge.
What a good catch.
Keep her number follower on facebook.
Occasionally check in,
see where she's in jail.
A really great story.
So before I fucked her one night,
uh,
like I jacked off in front of her like
the Louis Way.
But like we both match for Louis.
We both have masturbated in front of
each other in my apartment.
I think we were doing coke and like
candles lit and glass of wine and she's
like,
I just want like,
and it was cool.
It's playful fun and we get done and
she's like,
Hey,
just so you know,
you can't tell anyone about this.
And I was like,
no,
she knew a bunch of comics in New York.
I go home and say,
so I want to tell us all.
She's like,
I promise you,
I swear to God.
Next day you,
everybody that knows.
Nope.
The next day I'm walking into the Boston
comedy club and rich bosses out smoking
a cigarette.
I go,
what's up?
And he goes,
did you ever jacked off in front of
Jennifer?
Last night I was like,
what?
And he goes,
me too.
She needed a ride home from Brooklyn one
time fucking boss.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
Yeah.
Oh God.
Those were the days I lived those.
Would you,
would you,
if you could go back to one point in
your standup career for one year,
you got a live one year in your standup
career.
You can't pick right now where you are
right now,
but you've got to go back to one point
when one year everyday you show up into
the store.
[inaudible] 97 when you're meeting
Orient everyone and you and Duncan
Duncan's living on your couch or what?
I don't know what year that was,
but around then or you go to the part.
Where is that?
I mean probably one of the more
interesting parts is when you get banned
from the store from them and see a shit
and you're like literally like fuck it.
Like I'm a man on a mission.
Fuck.
Like that's one of the more interesting
parts in your story and your life in my
opinion is when everyone fucking backed
out on you and you were like,
no,
I don't go on like that.
Motherfuckers and you just start fucking
building.
What year would you pick?
I would pick the early days.
I pick like when I was just starting to
get work when I'm in Boston.
Yeah,
it was like a Middle Act.
I picked those days doing weird shitty
road gigs,
you know,
early twenties.
Careless.
No,
no responsibilities.
No worries.
No nothing.
Didn't even have credit card,
had nothing.
Yeah,
those were the good days.
And a lot of ways it's not the today's
not awesome tastes way better for sure.
But what was good about those days is
that there's.
So,
there's so much wild and freeness,
there's so much,
you know,
like I remember one time I did this Gig
in Maine and then uh,
after the gig he met this girl who had a
couple drinks.
We're hanging out.
We're both like the same age.
I think I was probably 22,
23.
She's probably somewhere around the same
age,
22,
23 and we're just young and it's the
summertime and we hung out and we wind
up banging in my car.
I had like a Honda accord and one and we
didn't even go in the back seat because
it was really barely a backseat.
Right.
We like folded down the front seat flat
and then the windows rolled down and
we're just sitting there hanging out and
laughing.
And I remember having this unique moment
where I realized like,
this is not going be my life forever.
I'm never,
I'm not going to be 22 years old with
like $100 in the bank,
not knowing what I'm doing,
not knowing where I'm going,
not knowing what the future holds,
but yet okay with it.
Like you can only be okay with that for
a certain amount of years.
When you're 45 and you have $100 in the
bank and you don't know what you're
doing and your career is not really
established.
You don't really have a clear path.
That's scary.
That's dangerous.
It feels like you're a loser.
You know,
you feel like you feel pathetic.
You feel like you haven't done what you
need to do.
There's like a certain amount of
discipline that you haven't taken part
in and because of that your life is
chaotic.
Whereas when you're 22 and that's
happened in this,
it's like that Bob Seger Song,
you know,
like what was that rambling man?
No,
I'm,
I don't remember which one.
You know,
he's got a lot of songs about that
movie.
He was like a rock.
Maybe it's night moves,
but the idea of that you're recognizing
that this is a unique moment in your
youth that it's all like,
who knows what can happen.
I mean,
he might die in a car accident tomorrow.
Who knows?
You might never make it as a comedian.
You might take a job somewhere and you
might always have regret,
but right now you're having fun.
Right now you're,
you're basically just a couple of years
out of high school and you know you're
in,
you did a comedy Gig and now you meet in
some pretty girl and you guys are
laughing and hanging out and you having
a good time and it's summer and the
windows rolled down and the air is warm
and it's just something.
It was something amazing about it.
Those days were fascinating.
Men and Greg and I fitzsimmons and I did
a shit ton of gigs together.
We worked together a lot back in those
days because we started out within a
week of each other.
We were open mic or is it the exact same
time and we did a ton of gigs together.
Yeah,
we basically,
we traveled all over the place together.
We did a lot of gigs in Rhode Island and
all over the place,
all the Massachusetts hell gigs.
We did all those things together and
what we,
we still do this day.
We'll look back and laugh at those days.
Hey,
uh,
Jamie,
I'm Gerard Carmichael.
Is that the wrong spot?
Tell Jeff to get on the ball.
Um,
those days were,
they're just,
they're just really unique in that you
really have no idea.
You have no idea.
You have no idea what the fuck the
future holds.
It's a completely different experience.
You like your life is a completely
different experience than it will ever
be ever again.
And I just remember that.
I remember that moment.
I don't know why it's at one night with
one girl that I never talked to again
now because back then you'd have to call
someone.
They'd have to be home like in,
in 1990.
That'd be home.
Yeah.
You call them on the phone if they
weren't home and be like,
well,
I guess they're not home.
You know,
it's like it wasn't,
it wasn't like today,
you know,
you can text someone or you can email
them or nope,
you had to call them at their house.
There's a few of those,
few of those that are a member.
Yeah.
You know?
Those are the idea that you didn't have
phones.
I remember road trips with Tom and we
just would talk for fucking hours.
Right hours.
We've talked to a whole.
We talked,
we drove to Sacramento one time,
talked for five hours there.
Five hours,
10 hours.
You spend with a human being.
No one's on their phones.
Yeah.
There's something real about that.
Right?
I think we're definitely missing
something.
Definitely missing something with these
phones,
but they were gaining something to where
we're gaining a lot more information.
I'll tell you what,
my kids haven't lived anyone on fire.
Like we did that when we were kids.
There's no phones.
We a kid on fire one time just because
we were bored.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I don't know man.
There's good and bad.
It's like it balances out I guess,
but if you had to go back to anytime in
your comedy career,
when would you go?
When I just want to write.
When I first started headlining,
like right when,
like that first time I just had kids,
they were young.
I was making 1300 bucks a week on the
road and I was so passionate about
standup.
I was kind of pretty hacky.
I bet.
But like I just would give everything
every night they do a six shows Thursday
through Sunday and I'd fly in early for
press and I get excited to do press and
I come in and I just be like.
And I have my notebook with me all the
time and I was like,
I just,
every idea was like a brand new field.
Like you felt like you were really.
It was not like you just discovered the
internet and every page had so much to
offer.
And then.
And then I think I got into when I got,
oddly enough,
when I got into travel channel stuff,
I kinda just to Kinda,
it Kinda took a second backseat and I,
because I was headlining and I was like,
yeah,
I can do this competently.
And I think I'm there now.
Like right now I feel like I'm back to
this place where I go.
Like,
I'm just writing so fucking much where
I'm like,
Oh God,
like everything.
Like I feel like everything.
That's the thing that happens when you
have to do a special every couple years
when you,
when you're filming,
the one thing that definitely happens is
you're forced into this creativity.
You're forced to.
Whereas we're both aware of those people
that don't.
Right.
And they,
they,
they sit around for a long time but the
same material and then it goes year
after year after year and then it gets
stale or,
and staler and flatter and other kind of
people that write the exact same job
next year,
their hours,
the same hour.
It's just,
just say it differently.
For me.
I took this hour so fucking seriously,
I took it like I was saying to someone
the other day,
I did a hundred and 50 sets.
I performed that our 150 times before I
did it on Netflix or before I did it in
the truck.
I did it a hundred and 50 times.
I do the math.
I went,
wow man.
I,
I like.
And I arranged it like that,
working in our and figuring out where to
play stuff and figuring out why we're
stuffs you go of.
I'm obsessive about that.
Where'd you film at the Trocadero?
Uh,
night two shows.
It was fucking,
it was.
I mean the second show was a dream.
That's a great spot.
I lowered the stage so that I'm in the
audience.
I put a half moon in there.
So it wasn't just a little plank,
no smoke machine.
I'd seen everyone had smoke machines.
I didn't want a smoke machine.
And I think it really paid off.
This sounds silly and you won't notice
this when you watched your special,
but because that place is so old,
there's little particles of dust
everywhere and you can almost see him in
the back.
It looks like it's like little stars in
I love it.
I love because of dust.
Really?
Yeah,
it looks bad ass.
It looks fucking bad ass.
What is your writing process like?
Do you write stuff out on paper?
Do you write it on a computer?
How do you do it?
I write it.
I don't sit and longhand anything
anymore because it just,
it.
I end up losing so much.
I just,
it just doesn't help.
So what I do is if I see something or if
something happens,
it's usually something happens to me and
then I go,
oh,
that's the bit and I'll write it in my
phone and I'll just put it in my phone
or I'll write and I'll also write it in
my book because I bring my book with me
on stage and I'll go to my book and I'll
see the one more thing and I,
and I say I tell stories and I know I'm
known for telling like 12 minute
stories,
but like most of my stories are a little
tighter now and what I'm writing is a
little tighter.
So I kind of work it out on stage
mostly.
But I record every set.
I think go through the recording,
Scott,
right in a lot on stage and I'll write
down all like,
fuck,
that's funny.
Like even stupid silly lines.
And,
and so that's the part where I.
and then,
uh,
once I get it like that,
then I just,
then I recorded again and I find the
parts where the silences or where I'm
lazy,
where I go,
oh,
I need something.
I can't just go suck my Dick.
And that's the punchline.
But yeah,
I record it,
I write it,
but I don't long hand write it.
I just had worked for me.
So when you say you write it,
like how you're writing it,
you just writing like bullet points?
Uh,
yeah.
So I'll write,
I'll write bullet points.
I'm like,
I'm trying to think of.
Okay.
So like I have the joke at my best joke
I'm telling you right now without a
doubt is about,
it's kind of about you,
but it's not about you at all.
But the opening thing was just some.
The only part I'll tell you is I went
into a starbucks and I thought I was
getting recognized and the young black
kid behind the counter came up to me.
He's like,
dude,
like,
oh my God.
And I'm like,
yeah.
And he's like,
I'm a huge fan of Joe Rogan's.
I was like,
oh,
and so then so then me and him had an
interaction and I made them laugh and I
went,
oh,
that was funny.
So then the next day I came back and I
made them laugh again and I went,
oh,
I know where this is.
So then I ride it out and I figured out
and then I,
the next,
that other interaction was so big I
realized,
oh,
I need three of those,
so then I'll,
I'll punch it out.
But I and I and I find the things that
make it rhythmic and the things like for
me,
things that catch and audiences like I
go and then he fell down and then when
he the moment said something,
he gets up,
leans up like it's almost the rhythm of
the way they say it for me before,
along with the joke,
if that makes any sense.
The case,
like if someone's a really good
storyteller,
it's like there's a whole thing going
on,
that physical thing going on.
There's a rhythm thing going on.
Like Stan hope is really good at rhythm.
Like when jokes he says like it's easier
for me to talk about Stan hope then
about myself,
but like when he goes,
when he's talking about Isis and how
they recruit people and it's identical
to how he recruits people.
He goes,
Isis,
I'm working this corner.
Like that phrasing a good phrase for me.
Bird does it.
Amazingly bird does it amazingly.
What does he say?
He does it similar to isis.
The they were,
he was watching a video.
This is on his special,
so I'm not putting any jokes out.
This is on a fast special.
He talks about how isis goes online and
finds like pathetic young men who can't
get laid and have drinking and drug
problems and then they bring them in and
they show them a good time and they get
them drunk and he's like,
that's,
that's how I recruit people and if the
line is so great,
he's like Isis.
I'm working this corner.
Such a great old barker's technique.
He's got the weirdest fucking life ever.
I mean he's basically,
we got a little cult going on and he
wants to do sober October.
Come on.
Yup.
Yoga classes,
yeah,
you should make them.
We should run a house for him in La.
Yeah,
so we give them incentive to come here.
I've been trying to get on to move back
here forever.
I'm like,
what are you doing with your little cult
down there,
man?
Come hang out at the store because he
hung out at the store a couple of
nights.
He's like,
it's a place is incredible.
It's amazing.
I go,
it's amazing.
this is a Valhalla.
This is the craziest.
Like it in terms of what I've
experienced is a crazy era of standup
ever and the store is the epicenter.
I'm like,
you should be here all the time.
He's like,
ah,
I don't know.
What do you mean you don't know your
Doug fucking Stan hope get in here,
man.
Could go just get an apartment near
here.
It'd be great if he was here for all
October.
God,
we can just talk them into staying.
I'm like,
why don't you get a place here and
there.
You were a wealthy man of leisure to
whatever you want.
He is he.
I called him up one morning or one
night,
it's like 5:00
at night and I was like,
bullshit.
And I go,
which up to,
and this is why I love Doug.
He goes,
I'm having a grapefruit and vodka having
a cigarette,
trying to think of some goofs.
Okay.
I'm trying to rework a,
a knock knock jokes.
I'm trying to make knock knock jokes
present like a,
well let me run by you.
And he tells me like his version of a
knock knock joke and it's so fucking
funny.
And I go,
I go talk to you.
It's like,
oh,
49,
50 and go and you're just sitting in
your pajamas right in groups.
He goes,
that's our life.
I was like,
fuck,
yes.
Yeah,
that's his life.
My daughters will see me doing it where
I'm like,
we're out to dinner is something will
happen and I'll just be like,
like mouthing to myself and I'm working
the bit.
Yeah.
And they're like,
are you writing a joke right now?
And I'm like,
yeah,
sorry.
I get up and run.
I get out of the room right back,
right back,
right back.
Oh really?
Leaves me alone.
Yeah,
no,
I have an idea if I have an idea and
anybody gets in there the little,
the ideal escape,
it'll slip away.
Like if I have an idea,
especially kids like young kids,
they just start talking like they just
start and then they demand your
attention and like you have to for to
capture a bit,
you have to have silence.
Like you can have people talking at you
or you consider what they're saying
like,
Oh really?
Yeah.
And then what was I just thinking of
Shit.
It'll go away.
Yeah.
So I treat those things like they're
gold,
like if I have an idea and it's a real
idea,
like a real idea where I get excited,
I'm like,
Oh shit,
I run,
I get up,
I get up off the table right back,
right back,
got to go,
I've got an idea.
And you know,
people were not into that and don't get
creativity and don't write or don't do
standup up.
It'll weird amount.
Oh yeah.
And you have to come back and apologize
like,
sorry,
I just had an idea and how to capture it
in the moment.
I just have to write it down.
I'll show it to them on my phone,
like,
look.
Right.
Oh,
I'm a daydreamer.
I literally,
I literally will sit and just talk in
the middle of dinner with my family and
just talk something out.
Just be like.
So you can hold it while you're talking
to them about other shit.
Oh,
I don't know.
I'm tapped everyone out.
I tap everyone out.
I tell them I,
you uber drivers.
Hey man,
I'm not crazy.
I'm a comic and I just sit and I'll work
a bit out like this.
Like,
like I got high as fuck the other night
I got high.
I got high as fuck the other night.
This is my,
this is before the triathlon because I
wasn't smoking pot up and,
or no,
no,
it was before the triathlon.
I walked in and uh,
I walked in the house.
I was way too high.
I was coming back from the store I
guess.
And uh,
I walk in the kitchen and my bull
mastiff is putting away the silverware.
What?
Yeah,
she's got elbow on the counter,
putting away the silverware,
putting away a silverware.
That's what I said.
And she looks at me like,
are you gonna fucking help?
And then I realized,
oh,
she's eating a cake on the calendar,
but I was so high and then the dog was
eating a cake on the counter just up
with hand stabilizing and just going.
And I started laughing so hard that my
brain thought it was similar that I was
like,
oh,
I walked right out to the man cave and
Joe,
I must've stood there for an hour trying
to write that bit.
Like,
just going.
When did you take the cake away from the
dog?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It was a coffee cake.
We were fine actually.
I went up and helped read it a little
bit.
She looked at me and she was like,
we're doing this together.
I was like,
yeah,
we're running a train bitch.
And so.
But I went into the man cave and I just
was talking to my wife,
came back and I'm standing in the man
cave just going like,
just hands moving.
Like I was like,
oh.
I walked in and she's like,
my wife's like,
are,
are you going to bed?
And I was like,
I'm sorry,
I'm in the middle of a bit.
She's like,
all right.
He just left.
Yeah,
I'll jump up in the middle of the night.
I have a bit and it's in my head and I'm
in bed.
I've,
I've said to myself before,
I'll remember that and I never remember
ever,
never.
Occasionally,
one out of 100 times I'll be like taking
a leak and I'll go,
oh yeah.
And I'll remember it.
Yeah.
Those,
those jokes are slippery.
Like Neal Brennan said it best.
He said that he thinks of his notebook
as like a,
a net for catching ideas.
My Ooh,
I like that.
Yeah.
That's a good way of looking at it.
You gotta have you gotTa have something
on you at all times because something
happens all the time where you're like,
well,
the phone is the best man.
I don't know if you use the dictation
feature.
Never do that one ever listened to it?
No,
no,
no.
Uh,
with notes.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Just talk and it'll,
it'll uh,
voice to text on the plane last night,
uh,
or wherever I was yesterday night I was
trying to type in white supremacist and
it came up white Supreme Hoodie and I
thought,
oh,
that's funny that you'd try to like,
I wanted,
I ordered in a white supremacist totally
on accident.
So then usually I just,
there's nothing to it right now,
but I wrote it and I go,
all right,
well we got that in the pocket.
Yeah,
I got them all.
You never know.
White the fuck up.
I just heard someone say that have,
I have hundreds of them that never did
anything.
So I'll go over through them.
Like sometimes if I'm stale I'll just go
scrolling through them.
I go,
what do I got here?
What do I got in here?
What do I got here?
Oh yeah.
I never tried that.
And one of those I never tried.
I tried last night,
the Ice House Ice House and there's
something there.
There's something there.
It's not good yet,
but it's a seed or something there and
you got to water those seeds and you
gotta take chances with them and you got
to know how many of those dud seeds you
can plant in a set while people are
sitting there paying attention.
Like you got to give them real bits too
bro.
But you gotta also have like last night
anybody came to the show.
I hope you have a good time,
but I had a four.
At least four solid duds in there.
I'm just trying.
I don't know where I'm going with.
Um,
and then I go places.
I'm like,
Jesus,
what are you even saying?
Like so extreme that I,
I will go at the end of my.
So like I'll work everything that's
working.
Like right now I got about 52 new
minutes and so everything that.
Damn,
that was quick when from when I shot my
special.
How many months ago?
Shot in February.
Wow.
Yeah,
I got 52 minutes now that I am.
Why are they spending that much time
before they show it?
I don't know.
That's a long ass time.
February,
March,
April,
May,
June,
July,
August,
six months I guess.
That's right.
Yeah.
Lives was a little shorter but not much
but just like a month maybe.
We shot on the same day and so like,
uh,
that's great though that you already
have 50 minutes.
I do.
I just,
I'm back.
Like I'm just in it.
I like it.
I'm from where I'm at.
It's also my thing.
It's like the only thing I got that's
what's making me money.
So yeah,
that's where my eggs are so much better
than working for the travel channel.
You have no fucking.
I remember when you were doing it,
I was telling you like,
Bert,
you're a funny guy,
man.
You,
you,
you could be making a living doing
comedy and not.
Not having these bosses and be on
rollercoasters every weekend.
Biting your tongue.
Remember,
I used to smoke weed in here and you
guys have to move the cameras to hide
the weed.
You don't remember that God.
That was so crazy.
But that's what happens with one of
those gigs.
Yeah.
Howie Mendell went on stage at the laugh
factory once and he was talking about
how scared he was that uh,
he could say something on stage and
someone could tell his bosses because he
does a family show and then he could get
fired.
And I was like,
wow,
like you're a comic.
Like he's Howie Mendell dude.
When I was just coming up just starting,
he already had specials and they were
really funny.
He was really fucking funny back then,
man,
back in the day,
some of his early CD's.
Really hilarious shit.
But,
and he's still funny.
Let me still a funny guy.
He's always gonna be a funny guy.
But when I was watching them say that,
I was like,
that is the craziest thing I've ever
heard.
He's worried about getting fired for
saying something on stage,
like saying fuck in his act or talking
about something in his act that someone
deems to inappropriate for a family show
and he can lose this gig.
Like America's got.
It was the on America's got talent.
Is that what is on the wall or something
imagined wanting that Gig?
I can't.
I traveled channel.
I mean I'm not gonna travel channel came
back very recently and asked me if I'd
come back and they're like,
what?
It tells us whatever you want to do.
And part of me was like,
I think I'm doing it.
Like I have a Netflix special and my
podcast,
I have a solo podcast.
I've got somethings burning.
I was on the road doing stand up.
Oh yeah.
I love writing.
I mean I'm writing,
I'm writing faster and better now than
I've ever written and this special.
I mean the best compliment I've ever
gotten is tom watched it and was like,
I had tears in my eyes and then you,
you,
it's not,
this is you,
it's who you are.
And I was like,
I was like,
man,
fucking I,
I wish you worked for the New York
fucking time.
So that is the greatest comment.
But yeah,
like what am I going to.
I mean I talked to Jamie about it after
that was like,
I wouldn't,
I don't mind shooting content,
making free content,
putting it out on my own watch,
like going to swim with the orcas in
Norway and me shooting.
Yeah.
And doing it me and you go and spear
fishing in Miami and covering it and
shoot it and editing it so that it's bad
ass music and,
and I don't even care if it's monetized,
but it's something that people watch it
like fuck,
that's bad ass.
You don't mind doing any of that,
but to do something with someone else.
Giving me notes and telling me how I
should behave.
Well not only that,
the travel channel's super conservative,
right?
Well they got bought by discovery so
they're loosening up a law.
Aren't they owned by like some Christian
work or something?
The previous owners were scripts and
they were very faith based,
faith based.
And so like,
uh,
you know,
I think that's filet,
they're owned by chick fil a fuck man.
So yeah,
it's nice to know that you go,
like you say something fucked up on
stage and you're only repercussion is
the one chick that's like,
that was fucked up and you're like,
yeah,
I know.
I took a chance.
I rolled the dice,
kind of know what I was saying before I
said it.
No,
it's beautiful to you working so hard
and getting things done and also doing
that with like,
you're,
you're running and the marathons and the
Spartan race shit.
Like you're a,
you're fucking doing shit man.
You're,
you're getting after it.
It's great man.
It's great to see,
you know,
it's great to see you put together this
special and work so hard at it.
You know,
it's great.
I mean we're in a real cool time right
now.
Like everybody's kind of killing it.
I think.
So I look at what everyone's doing and
neural doing it on their own pace.
Oh,
it's awesome.
Like you look at Ari and he's like,
he's like texting me in big J and
Sally's like,
Yo,
you guys want to go skiing and do a show
to pay for it?
And then we're all like,
yeah.
He's like,
all right,
these are the dates.
Just so you know,
we will be watching the super bowl
together.
Now he's killing it in his own way.
You know,
everybody's killing it in their own way.
It's really fascinating.
It's,
it's,
it's interesting,
you know,
it's true autonomy.
It's what,
you know,
it's like,
no,
we all started doing this podcast with
you and showing up at your house.
The little things we'd see.
We'd be like,
oh,
like I remember Tom was saying something
about.
I remember sitting on that couch.
Yeah,
he's still on the couch.
She's be back in it and you'd be like
sunken and highest terrible,
terrible couch for doing podcasts.
That was [inaudible] couch at his house
for a really long time.
Yeah,
I gave it to him.
I've started,
got it out of my podcast studio.
Uh,
I had shipped over to Ari and then he
used it as his couch.
And then I think he sold it online,
really sold it online.
Right.
There's parts of that old podcast I
missed.
You remember your landline would ring
all the time.
I love that.
How about my kids when they were real
little,
when they were like two,
they'd be screaming in the background,
like someone would stub their toe and
they'd be crying and you would hear in
the background.
That was an evolution one fucking time.
And I had a lot of people come to my
house though and it was weird,
like it was cool with like Bourdain was
over or you know,
Jim Jeffries is over.
But every now and then I'd have someone
over.
I'd be like,
I don't even know if I liked this guy in
my house for some fucking Weirdo who I
brought on the podcast and now they've
been to my house.
It's like she was too intimate.
I just want my podcast is still at my
house and we're talking about a Tom's
doing it.
He's like,
you know,
I can't just have these people in my
house.
And so,
um,
I want to get a studio.
What's Tom going to do?
He's,
I mean I don't want to tell everyone
Tom's business,
but I think he's probably pretty open,
but he's gonna like he's going out,
he's big.
He's going to do what you're doing on
this post.
Smaller level.
He wants to start shooting stuff and
making like his own branded content
that's just thompson.
His sense of humor him and push do their
podcasts out of there to her podcast out
of there.
Make shows you should do is we should
get another space and build it up just
like this space and have one that's got
like four studios in it and a bunch of
us can use them and you just pay a
certain amount of rent per month.
A man.
That's where I'm at.
I look at Jamie and I talked for a
little bit before you got here,
but like you know,
men's health code this.
But I shot the whole fucking thing.
Like I shot all of it.
I shot the spartan and edited it and
it's fun for me.
Like I shot the whole thing.
I just went around and set up a camera,
go do the event,
grab the camera,
set up the camera,
do the thing,
give them a camera to Mike Bertolina do
the thing,
and I did that with the marathon.
Covered the whole fucking thing on my
phone.
So it's like if I could get myself a
junior fucking editor,
Bro,
I'll put out content every day
throughout the bat signal.
Put it on your instagram to say,
you know,
you're the girl.
Just threw it out.
Don't do that.
I just did though.
Yeah,
he definitely just did.
But you really want to make sure they're
not crazy.
That's the hard part because you get
some dude integrated into your life.
They turned out to be insane because
didn't David spade his guy?
He had an assistant,
his assistant tasered him and in the
middle of the fucking system.
Who did that?
Someone else did Davis girl through
their assistant.
So kind of got broke into David's house
and tasered him in the middle of the
fucking night.
How bad must he be to work for?
I'm not saying that it was justified.
I'm not saying that.
Oh,
but come on man,
something.
Something had to be fucked up.
Bag that when they were doing the break.
I do.
I love them as bait.
I'm not shitting on him,
but you know,
when they were doing the breakdown,
the police officers were talking to
David spade there like he did nothing.
Huh?
Like how many does he pick up your
laundry?
How long have you been working for you?
How many?
How many coffees you drink a day.
Hello?
What was it that you said?
Oh,
I love that.
That's your takeaway,
dude.
I gotta wrap this up unfortunately
because I got drawn here.
I found that cartoon.
Let's wrap it up with this list.
Bert Kreischer.
Secret time this Friday.
Is it Thursday night at midnight?
Thursday night at midnight.
Last night.
Viewing party.
That's tonight.
You fucks.
So tonight at midnight.
It airs.
Secret time on Netflix or blow the fuck
up.
I'm in Irvine this weekend or next
weekend,
but yeah,
check out.
Secret time.
Thank you joe.
I love you brother.
Thank you man.
Here we go.
Tom.
This is so funny.
We're about to pass out.
That's actually probably better than a.
they're going to come up with how much
money does he have?
These maintenance,
his own trailer bitches.
Thanks brother.
Oh,
that was awesome.
That was really.