Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Now most people in America consider
Calabasas to be one of the safest places
as where the Kardashians chose to live.
Not Adam,
green trees.
Adam Green tree lives in Australia,
surrounded by Brown snakes which kill
you like instantly,
right?
Be instantly pretty quick.
Yeah.
Pretty quick.
Bunch of spiders you have that'll kill
you instantly.
Like a ton of hundred.
Right.
You got crocodiles,
you've,
you've bathed where I've saw the video
of you and campaigns in a fucking puddle
that crocodile swim around in,
but yet the one day he's in Calabasas,
which is like the safest place in
America on true.
But yeah.
Well tell me what happened.
Well,
so I'll hop down to the hotel first
thing this morning,
the gun trying to find a decent coffee
here in America.
And uh,
the police surrounded the whole,
the whole area where the,
the coffee shop was and um,
they had guns drawn and everything.
And then I heard later that someone
actually had a gun out and they might
have even been shots fired.
Yeah.
Crazy stuff.
And then I'm like,
okay,
at a coffee bean.
Yeah.
It was at a coffee bean.
Find out what happened.
Jamie.
See if there's a story we can.
I said it was probably like some wife
mad at her husband.
It's seamless series called the police.
He's got a gun like that.
That's happened before.
That happened with Ron White.
I think his girlfriend packed a gun in
his luggage and then that happened with
Sam Kennison to his girlfriend,
packed a loaded gun in his luggage and
then call the police on him.
That's crazy.
Straight away.
I'm like,
it's safer in the mountains with the
grizzly bears and crap.
He is definitely not safer if you
actually run into a grizzly bear,
but for the most part it's pretty
peaceful,
right?
Yeah.
Most people are worried about grizzly
bears,
but you could be around him for days and
days and most likely nothing's going to
happen.
Most likely most likely.
But when you,
when you were up there,
you.
Did you run into some walls?
Yeah.
We say,
well,
I seen wolves and then the grizzly
bears,
the one that sort of really scared me.
Um,
I had a handgun out and I actually had
the drawer that handgun a few times
while I was up in the mountains.
Yeah,
there was one real big grizzly,
like size 11 boots that I'm coming
around camp and was hunting all the
trials.
11 boots.
So it's like a 12 foot by 12 inch pad.
Yup.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
How big do you think it was?
Did you see the actual bar itself?
Yeah.
So once I actually killed the bull,
which was about day 10 or 11,
he was sleeping on the caucus,
about 60 meters from it.
He was sleeping in your car and then he
slept on to eat some of it.
He didn't touch it.
What's,
yeah,
it was like the first day,
so.
So I killed that bull in the afternoon a
packed out a decent load of meat that
night.
Went back in the morning,
the next morning to pack out the rest of
the meat and was going in there looking,
thinking they could be a bear on the
caucus.
And sure enough,
I seem to be a brown hair in the creek
bottom.
So he's just sleeping,
just sleeping there and so I yelled at
him a prick disease up and had a look
around and I yelled at him the second
time and he jumped up and he disappeared
like that,
like scary.
That's how quickie this is.
Thick timber,
lot of deadfall and everything and he
just disappeared for that.
And it actually got me thinking that if
you didn't see a bear coming from a
distance,
handgun,
bedspread,
whatever you've got,
you'd be in serious trouble because he
just left that scene dead quiet and in a
flash I think can move so fast and those
pads that they have on the bottoms of
their feet and makes him so sad and
quiet.
Yeah.
And you would think that a thousand
pound animal wouldn't be able to move
that forward.
So I'm strapping meat to my pack.
Uh,
obviously there's always a blind spot
when you're hunched over.
And it took me three times longer to get
the meat on my path because I was just
constantly looking over waiting for that
beer to come back because I haven't
actually been to the carcass again yet.
I've seen the bear on the way back in.
Pretty scary.
How big was it?
Giant.
Big.
11.
Eleven feet tall.
Scary.
You're alone at deep,
deep,
deep.
I was talking to the fish and game
warden in the area and the big grizzly
had gone into another hunters' camp on
the mountain and just absolutely
destroyed these camp.
Now I don't know if it was the same bear
or different bear,
but on three occasions a big brown bear
or grizzly come back into my camp and
each night that he'd come in he'd get a
little bit closer.
So the first 90 circled camp about 50,
60 meters away.
The next 90 circled camp,
about 30 meters away.
And the third time he came in,
he come right into the back of camp like
15 meters away.
Let out these gnarly growl.
And at this point my buddy grant
Hughes's come in to help me pack out
some neat.
He's in his tent.
I'm in my tent when there's here.
This bear walking in for the snow and
lets out a growl.
I didn't want to go like grant.
Did you hear that?
Or Grant?
There's a beer in camp.
I didn't want to let the buyer know that
I'm in the tent man.
I just laid there dead,
quiet.
I had the handgun sitting on my chest
loaded,
ready to go and um,
I laid awake for like three hours,
like you heard the beer walk off and I
laid awake for three hours and I'd get
up in the morning and I'm do.
I'm like,
dude,
did you hear that beer?
And he's like,
did I hear the bear?
Holy Shit Dude.
I didn't want to move on,
make a sandy had the same idea as me.
Didn't want to give away.
He's location.
And I'm like,
yeah,
it took me three hours to get to sleep.
And he's like,
sleep,
you got fucking sleep.
What the fuck?
He was like,
hell,
pissed off man.
He laid awake all night.
It's like a tent burrito.
Yeah.
Burrito.
Even staying warm in your sleeping bag,
you know,
like he's got to be able to smell you
too.
They must know you're your.
Yeah.
What a wondering if they were,
well,
if they smell you and then they smell
the meat,
what they would be more attracted to
the.
I don't recognize.
Smell real good,
so hopefully I bet they liked things
that don't
smell good.
I probably do.
Yeah.
Mate was hanging up probably a good mall
from camp at like a because we were out
a few different drop points because it
was such a.
It was four days hike out of meat,
so we had different drop points along
the way and I never wanted to take any
meat and the campus set for what I'd be
eating each night,
which a cooked meat might smell pretty
good to a bear,
but I was more concerned about the scent
that,
that we will be carrying on our boots
from meat site to meet site and then
walk them back in the camp.
But that Bayer had already been in the
campaign.
He knew where we were and he was doing
his rounds obviously every night.
Have you done an adventure like this
before?
This is an epic adventure because you
went to Montana,
you,
you know,
you parked.
And then how many miles did you go deep
into the woods?
I was probably about 12 miles in the
end.
That's no trials or anything like that.
Twelve miles.
Twelve miles into Montana.
Montana is if you folks who have never
visited Montana is one of the most
unspoiled parts of America,
like below Alaska,
but not far below.
So you're already super remote,
like we're already a long way from
anywhere and parked at a trail head.
And then.
So obviously I had 11 days solo by
myself and then my buddy grant come in
and help me pack that bullet out a ended
up being 14 days in the end by the time
we got the meat out.
Yeah,
it's cool.
I've done done similar adventures
because a lot of hung back home in
Australia is all super remote so I'm 90
percent of it's back country really back
home.
But it's a different kind of back
country.
It's sort of back country bears.
Yeah,
it definitely is.
This was saw low minimal gear because
everything's in your backpack that
you've got for the hunt.
Um,
so it's super light and you're cutting
down on a lot of essentials that you
need,
you know,
just,
just to get back in there when you do
this.
I've been obsessed with a lightweight
backpacking lately.
I've been paying attention to,
um,
these guys that do the Appalachian
trail.
Yep.
Did they hike from Georgia all the way
up to Maine?
It takes five months.
That's insane.
They're insane.
But it's one of those things that
there's a real problem with the human
brain.
It's like we were talking about our pal
campaigns and this a 200 mile run he
just did.
And when,
when there's a challenge in front of you
and you find out that someone has done
it before you start going,
man,
maybe I could do 200 miles.
You feel like there's something fucked
up about people's brains where when they
find that someone's doing something,
like I have zero desire to take five
months out of my life and walk from
Georgia to Maine.
Yeah.
But I bet you once you got it done,
that's the difference.
But part of my brain was like,
I started thinking about it and then my
shut up,
stupid.
You're not fucking hiking to main stop
it,
but part of me was like listening to
this guy.
It was on,
uh,
the rich outdoors.
You've done research projects for his
podcast.
One of his buddies is a,
a,
a trail guy and they were talking about
like lightweight gear and how they
can't,
they pack the different stream where a
guy uses for hunting and what someone
uses for a,
just these long,
long,
long hikes where they essentially were
the same clothes for five months.
That's the hygienic.
Yeah.
It doesn't seem.
Well,
I mean I guess maybe get a chance
occasionally to wash them somewhere,
but they,
everything is the lightest possible
stuff that you could have.
And when you do this,
let's say if you're going to go out
there and you're,
you know,
you're planning on how many days?
15.
I wanted to do at least half the month
in Montana and I wanted to do the other
half of the month in Idaho.
So 15 days and a little bit of the
trips.
Got To be unprepared in that sense when
you're doing 15 days it,
that sort of hunt because the country's
like straight up and down.
There's no other way to do it.
There's no,
I'm going to drive to the ridge line or
I'm going to walk a decent trail that I
reach line or take an atv and it's just
all on foot,
straight up and down country.
So,
and,
and to have a little bit of roughness to
a trip like that,
you know,
we yar roughing it.
That's a bit of the appeal as well and
the experience in doing it.
So,
um,
I was just talking with the guys at hoyt
and they'll ask him,
what's the essentials that you had in
your pack that you wouldn't go without?
And I'm like,
well how about I tell you about the
stuff that I wish I had in my pack and
that I didn't go out.
Like what stuff do you wish I didn't.
I didn't take any rain gear and I didn't
take any rain gear and,
and I didn't check the weather before I
went in deliberately because I didn't
want any deterrent on the trip.
Like,
oh,
it's going to snow or it's going to high
a little.
There's going to be gale force winds.
I shouldn't go in today or I should pack
this extra.
I just wanted to ignore all that.
Just go in,
just live in the wilderness basically
with the minimal.
And um,
I got all that,
whether I've got hail three times.
I got gale force winds,
I got rain followed by snow,
so soaking wet then freezing cold and
you just had to stay active the whole
time.
Like I'd literally get to a mountain and
I'd sit down for two minutes and you'd
go from sweating to freezing cold
because you're wet and actually hiked
the mountain just to get warm.
Were you wearing wool?
Nah,
whole synthetics.
So since the synthetics in some,
in some cases it's harder to maintain
your body temperature when you sweat.
That's probably.
And perks to both.
Yeah.
So like I've got a synthetic sleeping
bag as well at why is it a little bit
more,
but I could jump in that sleeping bag
wet at night and wake up in the morning
and dry.
That's a little bit of the difference
and it will dry out the next day and uh,
it doesn't get,
never carries any weight your
synthetics.
So I just had like a small,
a Hoodie,
a little hoodie and I had some
undergarments and that was about it for
the whole trip.
But as far as like sweating and your
clothes and getting your stuff wet,
wool maintains body temperature better.
It does,
yeah.
Yeah,
it does.
Next the skin is really good.
So like under armour has got some really
good next to skin clothing and I'll get
wedding that next.
The skin clothing and stay warm because
it is,
it's similar to a wet suit wear suits
designed to have some liquid in it and
the liquid gets warm and keeps your body
warm.
That next to skin clothings the same
where it's sitting right on your skin
and it's going to stay warm like that.
So it was it like a spandex almost.
Yeah,
it is.
Yeah.
It looks a bit Pansy when you grow up in
Rhode and tights.
So.
So that was a fuck up,
right?
You should have probably brought some
rain gear.
Well,
I don't want to call it a fuck up
because I delivered it.
Deliberately done it.
Um,
to kate white down so much wheat.
This is like a lightweight rain Poncho.
Um,
I don't want to know how it was really
heavy and I couldn't carry.
It seems like it's not that day,
but where do you stop?
Where do you stop doing that?
Is the big question,
right?
Yeah,
it's,
it's weird.
You stop.
And I was already walking in going this
is killer.
Like this is hurting.
Um,
how heavy is your pack?
Yeah.
I don't get into that sort of stuff.
You don't wear it?
Nope.
I don't why?
I don't.
Yeah,
it just go silent.
Sirens.
A food.
I'll just go.
There's a dinner,
there's,
there's some lunchtime snacks now.
Energy.
And that's it.
If you go in for 15 days,
how many days were the food?
Do you care?
I only took in 10 because I was killing
a bull roast.
Yeah,
exactly.
And um,
I didn't run out because I shot a grouse
and I cooked the grass up.
Then I killed my bowl and I was eating
meat and I was even cooking meat and
then packing it the next day to eat
cold,
which obviously helped.
And it's A.
Have you heard this story about me and
cam going on the,
the Arnhem land tripping over territory
back in any food people haven't heard.
Well,
you.
This is the most ridiculous thing ever
because you guys had to filter buffalo
piss water because buffalo is still.
Tastes like piss the color out of it.
It had the same taste that the science
smell.
And my question is if the water's
filtered,
shouldn't have smelled lever.
Yes,
it should.
Shouldn't it?
Yeah.
You're drinking.
Piss it,
drink a paste,
paste for security for sure.
You guys drank.
But veterans got hell or some energy in
it though because of Buffalo.
Buffalo's Dick if even better,
but my energy.
I don't know why you were thinking.
Get pissed.
Tried to jam the door.
That first at least to told him to drink
the water first.
Yeah.
He can test that.
He saved on.
Will they have those crazy filtration
systems where you like gravity filters?
Is that what you used?
Yeah,
so I took one of those in the mountains
on this trip as well.
I never pulled it out and never used it
once because I was always drinking water
from the highest source directly where
it's coming out of the mountain.
And if you do that you're okay.
You don't have to worry about.
Nah,
I don't want to say yes because they
were go and do it and get sick.
Yeah,
sue my ass.
But I've never.
I've always had it nine stomach and I
think it's from just doing all that sort
of stuff as a kid you sort of grow with
that and I think your body's,
your body creates its own defense
against,
against things like that.
I'm a massive believer in that actually
sign with being dirty.
And I like,
like personal hygiene is obviously a big
thing.
But um,
you know,
Alita,
I'll lead a chocolate bar with elk blood
all over my hands after skin and,
or,
or deboning and elk and I think that's
perfectly natural and normal in that
sense.
Um,
I've never been sick.
I've drunk and some silly looking water
like that.
But I just think if you're at the top of
the mountain where the water's first
coming out of the hill,
out of the rocks,
then you're safe because there's nothing
along the line.
They're like a,
an old animal carcass.
Frigging wolf,
shit sitting in the water or something
like that to make you sick.
It's coming right out of the ground.
It's coming right out the ground.
Literally catch it as a streams.
That makes sense.
That's like a.
well,
and that's handy as well because I'm
cancer at the top.
So I want to find the highest water
source.
I don't have to drop down so far each
day.
Collect water.
There's always a good field.
And actually when you come across
freshwater like that.
So how many liters is your pack?
How heavy is your pack?
It's a 2100.
I was a small pack.
Yeah.
It's not a big.
That's very small.
It's,
it's the badlands.
That's crazy.
Use a 2100 liter pack for a 15 day hunt.
Yep.
That's how light I'm going in.
I have a couple of things that are
strapped to that pack,
which would make it bigger than that,
but generally everything fits inside
that package or what's in the pack.
Jetboil yeah.
That's.
Yep.
So I've got similar to MSI reactor.
They really good.
You can actually use it in the cold.
It was freezing in my tent,
like the whole tent froze over that.
Um,
I actually turned it on in the tent to
warm the tent when I was getting changed
or unchanged at night.
A little bit.
Pansy.
But hey it got to put a smile on my
face.
Boils water super quick,
you know.
So if the weather is miserable and you
just want to get it done at boils water
super quick for you.
Run a tanker.
Propane small.
Yeah,
just a real little backpack one.
And then because I went in there when it
was stinking hot,
like it was always cooking,
like it was the hardest.
Wherever you'd have,
you wouldn't even imagine having a fire
in that,
whether from risk of a wildfire,
you know,
starting the bushfire too,
hightailed,
it rained and snowed,
everything got wet.
It was safe at that point.
They have a fire and then a lot of the
cooking that I end up doing was just
over the fire.
I'll save my gas each night,
um,
because I would have ran out of gas
before those 15 days are up if I was
using just that one canister the whole
time and that you'd end up having to
pack out,
go into town by the gas and then pack
all the way back and you'd end up losing
two days because it was a,
it was a full day walking out with no
weight at all.
Like,
just speed,
walking down the mountain,
trying to get it out of.
There was a full day.
So,
um,
yeah,
I've got my reactor,
I've got my water filter.
But like I said,
I never used it.
I've got a small one person 10,
a mattress at really good sleeping bag.
It's actually overrated for the
conditions,
but I always think you're better off
going overrated.
You get some bad weather log I had and
you've got an underride sleeping bag and
you're not getting sleep.
You're going to Ms.
Hunt now.
It's for sure.
Um,
then I've just got a couple of knives.
I've got a full safety kit,
bandages.
Um,
I've actually been carrying.
I didn't use them on this trip.
Even a little like a water filtration
pill,
which is always handy.
So you didn't have to carry,
you feel to kid everyday if you come
across some decent water that was down
low,
you could just put the pill in.
But um,
we're.
A lot of people go wrong with these
filtrate.
The water filtration and the pills is,
you still require both of you come
across dirty water because the pills
only going to kill bacteria within
reasonably clear water.
It's not going to kill the solids.
So if you're scooping up dirty water,
put an appeal in and then drinking
anything that's within the solids of
that water,
you're still going to get sick from.
So in a sense you're still,
you still need the two of them if you
want a hunt like that.
But the water filtrations or some,
because it's 99 point nine,
nine,
nine percent of all bacteria.
It's going to filter out of your water.
And the pills are world markets or
chlorine or something?
Yeah,
they like a chlorine pill here.
There's a few different ones yet on the
market.
So you take those essentials.
You essentially were in the same clothes
everyday.
Same clothes every day.
I take few changes,
the socks and underwear and I'm saying
clothes,
clothes every day.
And then if I did get a hot hot day,
this was the plan that never ever
happened.
But if I did get a hot day and I came
past a stream,
I was actually going to wash some
clothes in like a dry bag,
just a bit of water and the clothes and
then hang them up and I just never got
that break in the weather and I wanted
to hunt every day and every minute of
light so I'd just get up in the morning
and put wet clothes on if I didn't draw
them on the fire that night.
So it sounds like most of the weight in
your pack is food generally?
Yep.
Just 10 days of food.
And how many pounds of food you'd taken
the day around?
Two?
Yeah,
maybe a bit less.
it might've been a bit less.
I smashed the chocolate bars when I'm
out there.
Dude.
Why talk about smashed chocolate and
nine.
But when I'm in the mountains I really
smashed chocolate.
Um,
I just liked that bit of a fix and a bit
of a,
it's a bit of a pick up,
you know,
and keep you going.
And it's no different than a fire,
you know,
like if you get a fire going at night,
it's at like bit of a boost,
like a spirit spirit boost.
And it's the same as a chocolate bar
just to sit down and go away on a
chocolate bar.
Just,
yeah,
life's is good,
keep going.
Doesn't matter.
But like,
um,
but as far as like energy,
don't you crash when you have one of
those things go up high,
get a sugar crash.
I don't really crash.
No.
It's funny,
I hear it with a lot of people,
but yeah,
I never crashed.
Brendan Burns.
We're seeing the same thing.
He brings like snickers bars,
snickers bars,
really good.
Milky ways.
They like a Mozbar back in Australia,
like milky ways here.
Anything sugary?
Well also I would imagine the amount of
calories you're burning when you're
walking mountains like that with a pack
on heavy pack.
It's huge.
I had um,
but I had the desire to actually go and
do this trip and do a bit of weight loss
at the same time.
I think if I wasn't going to do weight
loss at the same time,
then I'll probably pack some more food,
some more goodies,
but you did it on purpose to lose some
weight and I did,
I lost weight.
I lost a lot of white doing it,
but yeah,
def definitely done on purpose.
There'd be some,
some days where I'd just have a snack in
the morning for breakfast,
like an energy bar and actual energy bar
in the morning and I'd go all the way
through and I wouldn't,
I wouldn't hide back in the camp til
1130 at night because I was trying to
stay out where I thought the balls were
and I'd have a quick dinner in camp that
night and that was it.
And I wouldn't even feel hungry
throughout the day.
Um,
yeah.
I think just from being so active and
obviously good water intake whenever you
can,
I just,
there was never a point where I'm like,
oh,
ahead,
I'm starving the day,
you know,
I'm not going any further until eight or
anything like that.
It was just,
it was all go,
go,
go.
And Yeah.
Now when you take a plan like this,
when you decided to go on a deep,
deep mountain on like this,
what do you,
uh,
how do you pick where you're going?
Are you a,
you studying google earth and you
getting tips from people studying Google
Earth's the big one,
you know,
and um,
I would suggest for anyone that wants to
do a backpack hunt,
you know,
like a do it yourself hunt is study
google earth and I'll do a radius.
I would look for a radius with the least
amount of roads,
any sort of infrastructure around it,
like the most wilderness looking area,
even away from trial heads.
I hate been near a trial head or where
there's a trial that people are going to
be walking in on or anything like that.
Like I mean real back country.
You've got a Bush bash it to get in
there just fine,
you know,
do your research,
find that area with the least amount of
activity and then put a.in
the middle or roughly in the middle.
And that's where you should set up camp
and like getting that live with the
balls or whatever,
animals you're hunting,
get in there and live with them.
And um,
I think not being afraid to fail on a
hunt,
the big one because you know,
a lot of people or they might not even
be any bulls there.
But yeah,
who cares.
It's going to be an awesome experience
anyway.
And it's a place that you can tick off
the list.
I'm not going back there.
There was nothing there.
And then next year,
try the next bottle.
The next week,
try another spot.
Um,
I had hunted around that area previously
and so I knew there was elk in the area.
Um,
I just had never been that far back in
before.
And I tell you,
to tell you the truth,
it is nearly completely filed on me
because I went days and days without
hearing or seeing or an elk.
But the sign was there to say that we're
in,
in there.
It's just that the grizzlies and the
wolves were hunting that area so hard
that it shut the fuck up and pushed a
lot of them out of the area.
Yeah.
And then I was nearly new food source.
So.
Wow.
So when you get in there and you don't
see anything for a couple of days,
like what,
what,
what is
the mindset like?
What do you mean?
He hates a day out and there's always
that like you second guess yourself.
This was a stupid move you shouldn't
have came in here.
You need to change spots,
but then it's like,
but at the same time your experience in
this for a reason,
and this is how hunting should be.
Hunting should be hard.
You should hunting never be unless
you've done your research going into a
place and there's just like game walking
past year everywhere.
There should always be,
because that's the hunt,
right?
Finding it or going through the hardship
to find it,
tracking it,
find and find them where's the better
spot within that area.
So at the same time that when winds
like,
you know,
you've made a bad decision,
this is a crap spot,
the be,
there's the whole experience of like,
no,
this is how hunting should be.
It should be difficult.
You should have to work your ass off to
try and find the animal.
And when you actually do find that
animal,
how much better is it because you know,
it's just like if,
if you hunted for 11 months and you
didn't say a bull,
you found a boy,
you had a shot in your midst,
but then the next one you get,
how good's that next one that you get,
you know,
if that was the case and it was very
similar on this trip where I put in all
that effort,
didn't see an animal.
One opportunity,
a ball comes in.
I ended up calling that bull from like a
mile away.
You could just hear him coming up this
canyon.
And I did that shot and dude,
I teared up.
I was crying because I knew how much had
gone into it.
You know?
And it's not just the effort,
but you know,
like obviously I'm,
I'm away from my wife Kim and the kids.
I'm away from the kids for a month now.
There's all that sacrifice is all the
hard shit.
There's all the effort.
There's walking in,
there's putting up with that absolutely
atrocious wherever.
And then finally one opportunity comes
up and you kill that animal as well as
kill an animal.
That's a hard thing to do,
man.
I balled up.
I was crying like I think I cried a
dozen times.
Every time I thought about it when I was
standing over the ball I was crying and
I'm like,
that's why it's got to be that hard so
you can appreciate their animal.
So you realize what has to go into the
hunt to actually get something killed.
Should I think everyone should be like
that.
I hope they're not.
Well there's,
there's a lot of elk in Montana,
but Montana is so huge.
Yeah.
Massive,
massive place.
And the amount of wilderness that you
were encountering,
if you have,
you know,
herds of elk all over the place,
it's super likely that you could like
wind up in a spot with nothing around
you for miles and miles around.
Yep,
exactly.
So the,
the.
I think the heartbeat with that country
that I've been going into is the wolf
populations getting so big.
I know you love wolves is pitches of
frigging wolves in this joint
everywhere.
But I do love them all.
I want to share to know where they're
scary.
Definitely scary.
What's weird is what we were talking
about before the podcast started.
You were talking about Australia and
what you call the greenies,
which are the green people that want to.
They don't want animals to die and they
want this population to explode,
but there's not a balance.
And that was the idea behind
reintroducing wolves was to create a
balance because there was a lot of
animals that were living in the
yellowstone greater yellowstone area.
And so they introduced these wolves.
But the problem was they had an
agreement when they introduced these
wolves that when they reached a
sustainable population,
they reached a certain numbers of
several thousand wolves,
then they would open up a hunting season
on them to try to control the
population,
but as soon as they reached that number,
the people that were involved in the
relocation of the rules and the wildlife
protection people and all the people
that are like really animal rights
advocates,
they,
they backed out of it and they said,
no,
we don't want any hunting on any of
these worlds ever.
And so there's this big battle and a lot
of states have opened up hunting seasons
on wolves,
Montana included.
But it's still,
there's a battle,
there's a battle to try to control the
wolf populations.
It's funny,
like I went.
So I went into yellowstone last year
after my hunt just,
you know,
thought I had all my photography gay and
um,
I didn't say a single elk,
but you got to go near where the people
are.
I saw a ton of them.
Isn't that crazy?
I was there with my kids.
We got selfies with fucking elk.
No,
it's like the whole time I was like,
fucking wolves.
They've wrecked this joint.
Didn't say anything.
Well,
the elk have decided that people are
super safe because no one has hunted in
yellowstone for 100 and whatever the
hell years.
So when you go to the visitor area,
when you first pull into yellowstone
lake,
yellowstone has like this,
uh,
and this is on the Montana side.
Yellowstone has this area where there's
like a gas station and there's like a
store and it's fucking elk everywhere.
Like I'll show you my friend.
I got selfies,
I got elk selfies.
But they're,
uh,
they,
they're not even remotely nervous about
people that aren't k.
yeah,
you don't,
you aren't doing days.
Um,
access data and having Texas,
the Cheeto d,
your stupid head.
That's how I saying,
but in the background that just living
in the hotels,
but it looks hilarious.
They're just chilling back there and
there was a gang of a man that's all.
They were all over the place.
There were a.
it's,
it's really weird because it's like,
right when you pull into the area,
all you see is like just loads of
arrowhead.
Yeah,
so that,
that the data that we have nightgown
live near the station.
So the station in Australia,
obviously it's just like a ranch and I
like a big farm because of the dingoes
just smashed,
it smashed the population so that those
title did.
I got back on near the homesteads
because the dean goes less likely to
come around the home.
It's really crazy and then you move.
If you're hunting you'd be like,
screw this,
I'm gone back into the back country now.
There's going to be hateful or deer back
there compared to ran in the house and
there'll be no deer out there at all.
What?
They would be very limited,
Debbie.
There'll be the stags that are moving
through the area and that's about
it.
The nucleus of the cheadle deer live
around the homestead where it's safe.
They're not dumb.
That's interesting.
Same thing with deer in around here.
You'll find them in suburban areas.
Yeah,
but he also find coyotes and suburban
areas,
but less mountain lions,
mountain lions try to avoid human
populations more and that's what usually
gets
deer out here.
All the news back home has been mountain
lions in behind your house.
Probably.
There's quite a few.
Yeah.
Cool
pictures of them.
There's Bobcat's I've seen bobcats out
near me,
but there's,
there's a mountain lions in California
for sure.
There's quite a few of them.
California is an interesting place
because,
um,
you know,
California,
they don't want to control the
predators.
They want the predators to control the
game population.
And because of that,
there's not that many
deer here.
Yeah,
yeah.
I understand that it's not.
And I can say the method behind it,
you know it.
Well,
my issue is that humans in a sense of
the ultimate Predator,
right,
and that everything should be not
controlled.
But um,
you know,
what's the good way of saying this?
Is that that Bain,
the Apex Predator that we are,
we are,
you know,
we obviously got a part in that whole
food chain as well when it comes to
things like that.
Some people don't agree with that,
they understand that and I can say,
you know,
we'll talk before about the wolves been
introduced to control the population and
the numbers,
but there's obviously got to be a point
where the wolves are controlled as well.
Right?
So who does that?
Well,
that was all well
done early,
early on in North America because of
cattle ranchers.
So what they would do is they would
shoot wild horses.
They had a huge wild horse problem and
the wild horse problem is actually a,
it's reemerging.
There's quite a few wild horses in North
America and they're trying to figure out
what to do with them.
And it's really controversial.
It's very,
it's kind of interesting.
Um,
but what they would do back then was
they would shoot these wild horses and
then they would shoot a wolf.
They would shoot like one of the Alphas
and they would take the wolf and rub it
and take it sank glands and rub it all
over the,
a dead horse and then fill the horse up
with strychnine.
So the other wolves would come around.
They would smell.
They're missing Alpha friend.
And uh,
they would eat the,
eat this horse carcass,
and then we'd get district on and die.
So doing that,
they extra painted walls from the
majority of the American West.
That's how they killed them all.
Yeah,
it's really.
But then they realized that they did a
terrible thing by doing that.
And so they started reintroducing them.
There's a balance somewhere.
Obviously.
I love wolves.
I think they're cool as hell.
But there's,
there's a,
there is a balance.
But the balance is real tricky.
It's because like there's a,
a very small number of them in
Washington state,
but the small number of them,
the small number of wolf packs,
I've started attacking cattle ranches
and they're killing these cattle.
And so these ranchers want these wolves
killed.
And so they've decided to kill some of
the wolves and it's a huge controversy
in Washington state because they're
like,
look,
there's not that many fucking balls and
you guys are going to kill these walls
because they're killing the cattle,
but you're going to kill the cattle too
if you want to have cattle.
This is what,
this is the price you pay.
But I'm sure you've seen how they run
cattle out here.
They just let them roam around on public
land.
You know,
when we were in Nevada,
we were a deer hunting the Steven
Rinella yet yet.
And we saw a lot of deer.
There's deer everywhere,
but we saw way more cows.
Fucking cows are everywhere and they
just,
they roam all throughout this public
land and the ranchers pay some sort of a
fee and they.
This was,
that was what that whole thing was going
on.
Yeah.
A lot of that happens back home in
Australia as well.
Yeah.
So they roam all over the place.
Just fucking cow shit everywhere.
We're essentially,
we're camping out so we're sleeping on
couches.
There's no shit everywhere.
You live comfortable.
It wasn't happening.
The lox,
spread it out a bit.
I actually wound up sleeping in the back
of the suburban.
We had a suburban and I was like,
why are you guys going to sleep on the
ground?
And you just fold the seats back asleep
on his flat area?
No.
So I camped out in the back of a
suburban while these dummies are
sleeping on the ground on cow patties.
They want to be done with nature man
down with cap,
who if you want to be down with nature,
take off the sleep you want to really
get.
But exactly.
Yeah.
But it's um,
you know,
these animals,
if you're going to let them wander
around like that roam free,
which is nice because they're
essentially almost wild.
They're free range cattle.
They're eating grass,
so healthiest cattle you could eat,
but wolves like to eat them too.
And so it's a real tricky.
It's like where do you draw the line?
There is not that many wounds and these
wolves are eating these cows and.
But to the ranchers,
each cow is worth several thousand
dollars every time a wolf kills a cow.
That's a big loss of income.
Yeah.
I suppose that's working.
There's gotta be some sort of line there
where we work in conjunction with
wildlife,
with your ranch or not.
Whether you're losing income or not,
you know,
that's got to be part of the system and
maybe it should be subsidized by the
taxpayers instead of killing the wolves.
Maybe they should subsidize some of
these ranchers.
I mean if these wolves are killing,
it's only a certain amount as long as
they've taken some measure of
protection,
try to keep the wolves away.
But to ensure a healthy wolf population
would ensure a balanced ecosystem.
See they can't bring it back to where
they used to be because where they used
to be,
there was no wool.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
There's a,
there's a funny thing at home,
how you sign it should be subsidized.
So I always,
my,
my business is in northwestern Australia
for the mines and they've got their own
private train law and they run their own
trains.
We've all I know.
And the train lines on fence so the
cattle can cross the train line anytime
of trying.
It's one of those cows,
they've got to pay the farmer,
you know.
Oh Wow.
And I've heard stories about the Pharma
just going out and shooting these cattle
along the train line.
So the mines pay him,
pay him for the cows,
look like they've been hit.
Yeah.
It's pretty funny.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
So maybe we could do
something like that with where the
wolves just pay out where every time
they kill a cow.
Right.
Some people believe that shit.
Well,
someone would probably do that.
There's probably some unscrupulous
people,
but that didn't get caught and they'd
get prosecuted.
It would balance itself out,
but there's a certain amount of numbers
where they,
the wolves reach a high population
number where all the other animals
started getting threatened.
Like there was a recent situation in
Wyoming where these wolves killed 19 elk
and didn't even eat them.
They just killed them.
Real killing.
Just fucking around having a good time,
you know?
Yeah.
They do that.
That's the point where obviously we've
got to stand in my decision whether it's
a tag system will or some sort of
calling.
You know.
I think before the program we'll talk in
about where kangaroos needed to be
called because it's,
it's a little bit like.
Yeah.
So the Greens don't want to miss the
greenies that want to kill the
Kangaroos,
but for the benefit,
for the better benefit of Kangaroos.
So it has to come a point where the
numbers need to be controlled.
Otherwise they ate,
they sell out of land and home,
they get diseases and it takes weeks to
die like a suffering death.
Like now on one side.
So you can't be just for one and not the
other.
My Buddy Mike Hockridge,
he lives up in BC,
in northern BC,
British Columbia.
And uh,
he,
he was attacked by Wolf,
like he had shot a wolf in mid air as it
was jumping on them.
They have so many wolves up there that
they have literally a,
had open season.
Like there's no tag limits.
You could shoot wolves.
Sounds like to go there.
Yeah,
it's,
we went up there and this is a,
we were moose hunting.
That's where I got this one.
And uh,
we found a calf that had been torn apart
by wolves and it's really fascinating.
But he put this up on his instagram,
his,
um,
his instagram is BC outfitter pcf.
This is him last night.
Listen to this shit.
Oh,
that's awesome.
This is just last night.
It'd be hell and back.
Come in by me and say what happened?
Started.
He actually started it.
He started the howl.
We can hear it here.
Yeah.
He called him.
God,
that's it.
That's a theory.
That sand when you're in camp by
yourself.
When you hear that.
I ran.
Yah.
That's what a fucking awesome in the
area.
At the same time animal ever because
they're smart.
You operate in packs.
They have really complex social system.
I'll tell you these cool little story.
When I was in northwest territory,
good luck just above the arctic circle.
The first time I've been in the country
like the Mckenzie Mountains and I was
actually hunting Moose,
but I had a wolf tag as well and the
very first morning like we get up out of
the tent,
we walk up the river and with a guide,
Byron and I say it like a pack.
Wolves coming down the river and so
they'd been hunting that area I think
ended up being day three.
They.
They chased the Caribou up and down the
river like just to a levering sweat.
Then like chase in the river and I
surrendered that didn't the with the
river and that Caribou and was a bull as
well.
Got to the point.
It's whole body was quivering because
it's been really hot and then it's been
chased into this freezing cold river.
At that point the wolves just left it
and they all went up and sat in the sun
because they a wet as well.
They went and sat in the sun and I got
old dry and then it was like mother
nature just took over.
From that point they they,
they got the Caribou to the point where
they knew it was going to die and left
it and ended up I couldn't hold its own
legs up and end up laying down in the
river and drowned in the river.
How cool is that?
That they knew that,
so the.
The wolves get to the point where
they're like,
okay,
we're going to go and sit in the sun now
and dry out.
This thing's dead.
Anyway,
we're just kind of come back to it now.
Once it's drowned in the river,
what the fuck?
How do they know that?
That's crazy.
And then by that afternoon that Caribou
was just a ribcage.
Like they just,
they absolutely plucked every bit of
meat and organs out of that Caribou.
Wow.
How cool is that?
I've got photos of it actually.
Do real work.
Do you have online anywhere?
They probably all my instagram early
days.
Instagram.
Yeah.
So Adam Green tree bone and tag them on
my instagram.
So if,
see if you could find those champions,
but uh,
you'll see these Caribou just standing
in the water and I'm like,
it was just quivering.
It was,
it was done.
It was done.
And I knew that it was done and they're
just like,
oh,
we'll come back in an hour and a fucking
smarter than fucking smarter than.
Cool.
Have you also heard that in their spore?
Um,
there's um,
something
that,
like elk,
if they sniff it stays in the dirt
forever.
So they basically shoot it out,
stays in the dirt forever.
An elk will go long grazing and eat the
grass.
And this spore attacks the elks lungs in
drinks,
the lung capacity.
So it's,
it,
it's,
it basically makes the elk tired when
they're
running for the wolf to grab them at a
later date.
Wait a minute.
So then we looked,
they thought they shit out.
The what,
what they ate and spores spores are
released into the dirt when the elk
eating,
eating the grass.
Like they take it into their system and
it produces their lung capacity,
reduces their lung capacity.
So it's like they're poisoning the well
before they jack them.
Is that not the ultimate Predator or
not?
Yeah.
How is nature so complex?
And it's cool,
isn't it?
Well,
the thing about wolves now too,
it's really kind of cool to see.
I'm so torn.
I'm so torn because on one hand I love
elk hunting.
I love elk.
I love the idea that they're out there
and they're wild.
But I'm a big fan of wolves.
I love the fact that these wolves are so
fucking bad ass ranch is right now gone.
Fuck you.
Joe Rogan.
Well,
my friend Mike,
he where he lives in BC,
his neighbors ranch gang of them jumped
cow like they got,
they got hungry and that winter and they
said,
you know,
let's just fucking do this.
How much easier of a feed is that?
Pretty easy nail that runs flood out
that's got legs,
that standard,
the grant effect,
Kale that's down here that might even
run away,
you know,
it's a pendant to the ELC was pinned in
or the cow rather was coming in and
they,
they jumped on,
jumped the fence.
I guess,
and this is one of the things that's so
appealing to me about bow hunting.
It's not actually just bow hunting,
it's the holiday though.
Whole pitcher and wildlife.
When you get into it like this and you
start looking at it and thinking about
it,
it's crazy.
Who doesn't want to be a part of that?
Well,
we're so filtered from it for the most
part,
most people's interaction with wild
animals in the zoo or a squirrel who
look,
I see a skunk.
There's an eagle.
Crazy.
Oh my gosh.
Yeah.
I saw an eagle like it's a big day,
but to actually go to a place like where
you went and to hear well,
a lot of people always like,
oh,
that's crazy.
That's crazy.
It's actually not that crazy when you go
out and experience that sort of things
happening all the time.
It's just that people are so
disconnected because they're not out
there experiencing it.
I was telling a story,
but we're going to wedgetail illegal at
home and I can hear these pig squeal and
like,
I'm like,
like a lock.
My knees just can't pick up where these
peak school and coming from and it's
going straight over the top of my head.
There's a which title?
Legal with this pig and it flies it
over.
It knew exactly what it was doing and
flies that gets it up real high and it
drops it perfectly over this rocky
outcrop on the mountain to open it up
like that stock,
man.
You gone.
I need a steak knife to cut into the
meat.
Yeah.
That was just gone on eight,
a rocky outcrop to cut into this meat
and potatoes.
The pig.
That was pretty decent.
It was like this,
like 40 pounds,
50 pounds,
40 pounds,
maybe 30.
I've seen them drop goats off cliffs,
like the goats are climbing cliffs and
the Eagle swoops down and grabs a hold
of it and how bad that video with the
Eagle tries to pick up the baby out of
the pram or whatever,
and that's real,
don't.
Yeah,
I think that's fake Internet.
Seriously.
I'm sure it's probably happened before.
Definitely happened.
When you look in the eye of an eagle,
you realize,
oh yeah,
the thing would eat a baby.
Yeah.
I think the idea that it would need a
baby's a joke they had built for it.
It's just another animal.
Yeah.
They don't give a fuck kid.
No,
no offense to anyone's babies,
but yeah,
no.
The reality is there's a great video of
this guy in Alaska.
We've played it on the podcast for the
guy with all the eagles in his yard.
Eagles in Alaska are so prevalent.
I have a friend who goes up there and
she was telling me that they're like,
pigeons.
She's like,
they're like fucking pigeons were
everywhere.
Like you don't even care anymore,
like these fucking things out here with
this guy's got this backyard and in his
backyard he's got fucking hundreds and
hundreds of eagles.
I mean maybe not hundreds,
150,
15 ago,
10:30,
but they're fucking everywhere.
Is this the video?
So this is the same one.
So what it is,
is he's got a.
where did I come up with hundreds?
How dare me.
So he's got a bunch of fish that he's
got laid out and uh,
they've got it.
I'm like,
look at this,
look at all these fucking eagles just
walking around this guy's backyard.
This ain't shit compared to what we're
going to show you in a minute folks.
But um,
these eagles are wandering around this
guy's yard and he has his kid take a
bucket of fish and dump it out for these
eagles.
And I just would not be that confident
having these fucking monsters coming
here.
My kids.
No,
that'd be a sort of raptors,
man.
This is,
I don't know that saying video.
Grab each one of them.
God,
look at this thing.
There is so weird.
It's such a weird animal that's a living
dinosaur.
Oh,
it really is.
Yeah.
It's such a weird animal too.
It's just so strange.
And we chose that heartless monster is
the American bird,
you know.
I mean,
couldn't.
Couldn't be American animal would be
like a puppy or something.
We've got on our coins,
I've got like platypus.
And wombat.
Nothing would take nothing close.
That's a good move because this thing is
just living dinosaur,
like literally a raptor of flying raptor
look at.
It's just creep once,
once that fish but doesn't want to take
a chance of getting shot.
I won't.
One an eagle.
Yep.
I've got a weight AAPL my property up in
the mountains on my farm.
We've got a couple of wage tiles that
hang around up there and whenever we
kill a deer we leave the coc and say,
oh,
I'll put a scout in camera on it and
stuff like that and just to see these
things come down and they eat and what
they do.
So cool.
Now a wedgetail egos at the size of a
Golden Eagle or a bald eagle or how big
they get.
A couple of meters in wingspan.
They.
Oh Wow.
So it is like that,
but yeah.
Wow.
Have you ever seen the heartbeat eagle?
That's the biggest one.
Yeah.
Lives in Venezuela and they eat monkeys
and it's uh,
it's fucked up to watch man.
It's really stressful with your last
day.
I think that she was on,
like,
I'd just be straight up stressing all
the time.
I just lay out and be like,
guess get it over and done with.
Yeah.
There's a,
they love sloss because sloths are just
designed to get fucked up by the eagles.
I love this eagle is God damn huge.
Look at the monkeys.
Like fuck this.
The monkeys like,
get out of here man.
But the sloths can't do anything.
They're just so slow.
They can't do shit shit except foot
stare at it and go piss off.
He just walks up to it and grabs it.
He's like,
man,
let me just fucking claw the shit out of
you here,
dude.
Bloody get off me.
Don't touch me.
Look at this.
Poor Long.
Not a goddamn thing.
You can do.
Look at him.
Oh,
this is a weird one.
I haven't seen this video.
All right,
watch out.
I'll touch her titties.
Getting out to be the only one I've seen
before is one swoops down and grabs one
says slough fights back.
Oh,
barely.
Really?
A fight.
But no,
get fade.
That's guy that's going to be when
you're 90,
you get in a head lock.
Fucking carrier.
Just so weird that nature gave this
animal.
No defense system in nature.
Just fuck this loft.
How coola off you say that one walk and
it's almost looks like it's got bloody
algae growing on that green one on the
road.
How weird are they?
Will do.
A lot of them do have.
Oh yeah,
they do have green growing on them.
One at a zoo here that has all this mold
grow all over its back and you can.
Yeah,
look at it right there.
That's the ones because they move so
slow that literally moss and shit can
grow on them.
What a fucking goofy ass productive
jaimee.
I like synergy sight sound.
He's like boom.
He's the best.
The best man.
He needs another one.
Another race,
another raise for changing.
Look at this fucking thing,
man.
I mean that doesn't even look real.
If you told me that that was a creature
in a movie,
I'd be like,
that's going to come and get you.
That's the boogie monster comes in the
middle of the night.
He already eats babies and that's what
it looks like.
It looks like some fake crazy that
technology has brought us this fall
where we can look at a video right now
at that slaw.
But to tell you the truth,
if you hadn't traveled the world,
you wouldn't even know that animal
really existed.
Well,
that's why they used to have to have
zoos.
That's one of the main reasons why I'm
opposed to zoos.
Yeah.
I mean I'm,
I'm,
I'm pro zoo as far as like,
they raise a lot of money for
conservation.
There's some animals that actually
thrive in zoos.
Like we were joking around about it the
other day about giraffes.
I used to have this joke in my act about
giraffes don't give a fuck about being
the zoo.
They don't feel bad at all.
They love it.
They just wander around going another
day and then just slowly walk around
because drafts are the only animal.
You let babies feed them,
but what if they don't realize that got
life,
that good luck us today.
You know,
like it takes a back country hunt for
you to go home and go,
shit,
I just flick a switch and a light comes
on.
Any type of hot water comes on.
Those drives are probably just ignorant
and I really don't know.
You know?
They definitely know they've got a good.
There's not lions chasing them everyday.
Well,
what's fucked up about the Santa Barbara
Zoo?
Santa Barbara Zoo is great,
but the fucking,
the a giraffe cage is right next to the
lion cage.
Like literally is that tear?
Remind them,
boy,
this is what it could be like.
That's what they should do.
They should let them out for a week.
They should let him out for a week.
Let lines and shit chased him around,
let them back into zero and go see.
That's what it could be like.
What do you want?
Yeah,
stop being such an asshole.
He let us live.
But look at this,
people can feed them and look at that
little kid.
No one's even remotely worried about the
behavior of giraffes.
They've never exhibited any aggressive
behavior.
Katie looked a bit stressed.
He just didn't know.
He's just maybe a little pissy about
that.
Kids going to grow up,
but Jitsu kick your ass.
I don't think he's got more than Jujitsu
for a giraffe.
Ninety,
you'd be raw.
You need a hoist.
So these giraffes are right
next to this fucking cage where,
I mean there are only separated by a
couple of fences.
There's two fences and right over there
as these lionesses,
that's all.
And you can get.
They have fit glass.
You can get right like where you are to
me,
you can get right up to the line,
but when you get right up to them,
you feel so vulnerable.
Like you know there's glass,
but that cat's looking at you and you'll
let your whole body just starts going,
get the fuck out.
We should.
That's your instinct,
dude.
What are you doing?
Yeah,
there's something about cats.
Oh,
you've seen this one where this baby is
standing there.
It turns its back and the lion,
the lion can't even help it.
No,
it's just the instinct.
Yeah.
But as soon as the kid turns its back,
it's like,
no,
fuck man.
Shit.
Did you see any mountain lions when
you're out there?
A one count into the kill site.
He's Prince role for the snow there.
Really?
Yeah,
and that country's pretty known for
mountain lions as well.
A two or three years ago when I was in
there and we've got fresh.
No,
and I went right up high.
I'm big mountain tracks like in that
space because there was fresh.
Now I'm sure there's fresh mountain
tracks everywhere.
I walked everyday,
but it's just that there was fresh snow
and it left the tracks perfectly in the
snow.
Like how many times do you walk past the
mountain lion and staring at your.
How many times has it been a mountain
lion off in the distance looking at Ya
and you had no idea it was there.
You don't know they're there and then
every now and then you'll get a weird
feeling like I'm being funny sense.
You know,
and I hate saying it because people will
say bullshit,
but I'll get a funny feeling that
someone's looking at me and if I stopped
at that point and have a look around,
chances are I'll find a deer or a fox or
something staring at me from in the up
on the ridge or in the timber or
something like that.
Happened with Shane.
Dorian.
Yeah.
Shane on the show not long ago,
Shane was out hunting with me just
before he come on your show and I
stopped.
I'm like,
dude,
I just got this weird feeling of being
watched and we looked around and then
yeah,
there's a box like looking beyond the
three,
staring straight at us,
you know,
so it's like,
it tickles a sense,
that's for sure.
Do you think,
you know,
this is going to get into the womb.
Do you think that when you're out in the
woods for days on end a week on end with
no cell phone service?
No,
nothing.
Just quiet woods and animals and you're
alone.
It's just you.
Do you think that activates certain
senses or reignite certain centers that
are dormant?
Right.
Ignites
really.
We kind of gone for such a long period
where you had to hunt,
you know,
that's just how people were,
like the natural world is people out in
the woods just like with the animals
that all that ignites and it fades when
we're looking at frigging technology
like we do or you're so busy in your
lifestyle and what you in what you do,
like obviously parts of the body's got
to,
you know,
we to shut this down.
We're doing this now.
You know,
we're moving forward in the world,
move forward in the world.
Bullshit.
Let's move back.
That definitely ignites and it's what I
just said,
you know where I'm like,
I feel like someone's watching watching
this or the way you react or your
listening or what you're here and just
all your senses become so fine tuned to
the wilderness.
A man.
It's a beautiful thing.
Yeah.
The move forward is an interesting way
of looking at it because I don't think
technology necessarily is having us move
forward,
but what it's definitely having us do is
move different.
We're,
we're,
we're interacting with each other less
in the physical sense and more in the
digital sense and we're way less likely
to interact with the rest of the wild
world.
Where in the world the wild.
That's a weird term to like.
I've always felt like the word outdoors,
like I love the outdoors,
like how fucking weird or people that we
call the whole world outdoors,
but I like,
we're so used to being in these shelters
that the sheltered life is normal,
but the outdoors out of the shelter.
Well that's the actual word.
That's actual world.
Yeah.
That's you.
What?
You go to the door to go out there
camping.
You go to the outdoor?
Yeah.
Oh,
well the outdoors.
Like what a weird description.
Yeah.
Outdoors.
You know,
it's a strange way of looking at the
wilderness.
The wilderness is a much better term,
but outdoors is like,
oh,
I love the great outdoors.
What the fuck are you talking about?
I love the world.
How it is today.
I think he said it on a shy not long
ago.
We had never had it better than we have
now.
One hundred percent.
If you don't think we've got a better
now,
it's because you're not looking at and
you're not appreciating everything that
there is,
so I like technology in the sense that I
can connect with a lot of people you
campaigns and stuff like that.
I wouldn't have friendships with you
guys if it wasn't for how technology was
to die.
You live on the other side of that.
Exactly.
How crazy is that?
And the world becomes really small,
so I love all that,
but at the scientologist height,
the disconnect that pay will have a
height that everyone's so busy trying to
work for a living and have a nice car or
a big house or something like that,
and in the end that shit's not even
important.
It doesn't even matter.
It's not like it's not the memory that
you're going to get from going out to
the wilderness or the connection or the
appreciation.
I appreciate me because I've had to kill
myself.
I appreciate power because of going
without power for weeks.
I appreciate hot water.
You appreciate all those things.
Like a car,
a paved road,
rubbish service.
Someone comes to your house and collects
you frigging rubbish.
Serious.
Not Serious about it.
Yeah.
There was a point where we couldn't get
done what we would today because you had
so much else to do,
right?
You're on rubbish.
Probably grow your own vegetables or
drive or walk or horse.
Ride the dye into town to get vegetables
or whatever it was and washing your
clothes.
We didn't sit in there for scrubbing
brush and Washington.
You close over.
Bode would take hours and hours.
Now you just throw it into a machine.
I'll come back and get it when it's
convenient for me and pull it out so you
get to do a lot more in today's world,
but it also.
There's so much to do that it's a lot of
people don't get to do what we do and go
outdoors and experience at or appreciate
those things because they haven't had
that hardship.
You know,
the mountains is a hard can be a hard
and miserable experience,
but it makes you appreciate the things
in modern life
that are hard anymore.
It's a prospective enhancer because it's
a reality check because you realize,
wow,
what a strange world we live in,
that we need shelter and we fire and we
need all this stuff in order to survive
without that stuff.
When you're out there like as as
minimalistic as you've done it,
like doing it with a small pack,
which few days where the food and
sleeping under a cloth house,
a little tent,
you know,
I mean that's a perspective enhanced
because it gives you this real
appreciation of what people have
actually accomplished,
but most folks are not doing that and so
they get really detached from where
their food comes from.
Really detached from the world itself
and it's not,
it's not their fault.
It's just the environment that you're
accustomed to.
We're all accustomed to supermarkets and
restaurants and being able to just get a
bottle of water.
I'm thirsty.
Let me just pop the top on.
This table is still complaining about
that Shit.
That's the crazy thing,
I
think people will still complain about
that and I'm like,
dude,
you need to check yourself.
Went to Africa a couple of years ago and
was lucky enough,
real poor village and in Mozambique and
everyone's still smiling like it was an
unseasonal year and it was really cold.
So,
um,
what we go for this village and a lot of
these villages,
you've never seen what person before,
and we go for these villages and it's
free o'clock in the morning and they're
all standing around the fire.
And I said to the guy beside me,
the local guy,
I'm like,
oh,
did they all start work early?
And he's like,
Nah,
like,
can't sleep.
And I'm like,
what do you mean they can't sleep?
And he's like,
well,
it's really cold.
I don't have blankets or anything like
that.
So they get up in the morning,
they started far and they all huddle
around the fire to get warm because it's
freezing.
And it's not that they don't have the
money to buy blankets.
There's no blankets,
there's no frigging blankets for sale.
It's as simple as that.
There's not like,
oh,
they don't have the $20 to buy a
blanket.
There is not even the resource for there
to be a blanket available for in the
Bot.
There's babies crawling around in dust
that's like six,
seven,
eight,
eight inches thick.
The dust around the village because you
know,
all the,
they'll walk around the village and
created a lot of dust.
No one's complained in there.
That's what they used to.
And they're happy frog fro someone from
our society in that man,
they'd be miserable.
They probably cut their own freaking
risks and,
and,
and all.
I,
I come home from their thinking.
Those people have got it that hard.
It's what they used to,
but they've got that hard and they're
still smiling,
you know.
And it was a bit of a check for me.
I've got power,
I've got running water and I've always
been appreciative of these things
anyway.
But um,
we've got power,
we've got water,
we've got in Australia,
we've got Medicare,
you know,
like real good health services.
We've got everything like that and
people still find
something to complain about and it's
just because I haven't been through a
real hardship in their life that they
don't realize it could be a hell of a
lot harder than this.
This isn't even hard.
It's easy.
It's just what we're used to and we used
to complain in the Baylor.
Well,
it's also one of the strange things that
we've created by co creating houses that
have electricity inside them and easy
access to food and shelter with sleep,
but a nice comfortable mattress.
What?
By doing that and by detaching ourselves
from the natural world,
I think we remove just a little bit of
the mystery of being alive.
How bizarre it really is to be a living
creature and amazing.
It is amazing.
Yes.
I mean,
when you're.
When you were walking through the woods
and you're seeing that grizzly bear who
sleeping on the carcass of the elk,
that bear has been living like that
probably for if you've ran into an 11
foot bear,
how many years is he like 15 years old
and being.
Yeah,
it's a giant fucking huge monster bear.
That's just out there surviving the hard
way for a long time in Montana.
Going through these winters doesn't give
a shit if it rains.
If it's sunny,
if it's snowing,
doesn't give a shit.
It doesn't even give a shit about a pack
of wolves.
Black doll eyes.
You see their eyes when you look.
I ran into one grizzly bear in my life
where it was in the wild only once and
it was last year with Cam and Alberta.
I was actually with Jen,
Jen and Jen said turnarounds at grizzly
and we turned around.
This is grizzly looking at us and this
motherfucker was looking through me.
Yeah,
there's such a difference in the way
they look at you and he's not looking at
it and going,
I'll try Rogan.
No,
they look through.
Look through you and the Strangeness
Apex Predator Way.
Well,
they have like this dead look in their
eyes.
It's very.
It's a very strange,
endless.
Yeah,
it is.
It's like A.
I shouldn't say Saul was probably so
harsh,
harsh way,
but I don't even know if a soul is real,
but that what you're saying.
Exactly that.
I don't give a shit.
They don't give a shit.
That's what it is.
Compassionate.
This is just a part of life.
If I feel like I'm gonna,
I'm going figure it out.
Yeah.
I remember the first video I ever saw a
bear killed a moose.
The bear chased the Moose,
knocked it down and started eating it.
Guts first while it was alive.
Just holding it down and eating it.
That's nice.
Yeah.
This is it.
This is the funny bit.
You know where these extreme greenies
think these animals go around hugging
each other.
Yeah.
Like,
ah,
that's my cousin and I will have cut to
catch up and have it be lighter and shit
like that.
No,
I didn't give a fuck.
They don't care if you're screaming and
hal and it's just going to eat you.
It's like the [inaudible] a dingoes back
home if thing.
Guys get a cough back home.
They don't lock all.
I'm going to be humane with this cough.
I'll,
um,
I'll bought it first.
I'll tear it out and make sure it's
died.
And it's peaceful and stuff like that.
They'll just start eating it right there
and then it will die in its own time.
You know that that's not even a full
process for these animals.
No.
They're just concerned with consumption.
When you,
when you do see them do it too.
When you do see them eat something,
it's just like,
oh yeah,
of course.
That's how they do.
Exactly.
Yeah,
but you don't.
You don't think of it that way.
You know,
it's movies,
man.
Movies have confused the shit out of
people and then being away from them for
long periods of time.
Yeah.
But we can't blame the movies because
it's on that individual.
I'm smart enough.
You're smart enough.
Common Sense tells you that that's a
movie they're not really like that.
You know?
How can people be that disconnected to
think that's actually how animals live
that life.
It's just a frigging movie.
People that just,
I don't think they really think that,
but they're not exposed to the harsh
reality of it.
Like they,
I don't think they really think that the
bears talk to each other and English and
then they hug each other and they help
people.
But,
but the reality of seeing bears in
Klondike bar commercials and Coca Cola
ads,
that does fuck with your head,
it does plants the seeds of what a
rinella calls.
Uh,
what does it call it?
A charismatic megafauna.
These things become,
they become your friends,
your,
your long lost wilderness friends that,
man,
I'll get a cat,
I'll get a dog at home.
I love them.
Like,
cool.
But at the end of the day,
now it's an animal and it's not a
senseless senseless.
Why assign it?
Because I believe hunters or hunters
that augment the most compassionate
people that you'll ever meet because if
it is a hard thing to take an animal's
life.
But I know it's part of the process,
you know?
Um,
it's not like I'm just thought,
let's just go and kill an elk got
killed.
I'm totally not that hunter at all life.
Nothing turns me off more.
I'm not that sort of person.
I'll have a quiet time with that.
You know,
the animal.
I'll put my hand on it and everything
and just be thankful.
I know it's an animal.
I know the meat's going to be used.
I know I'm doing the right thing,
but it's still.
That's the human emotion part of it,
you know,
and that's what,
in a sense,
that's why I got upset when I killed
that bull elk.
You know,
it,
it is a beautiful creature.
I understand.
That's definitely a beautiful creature
and it's a hard thing to do,
but that's the food chain.
Well,
it's also very sustainable.
And what's interesting is what you're
doing is you're dipping your,
your body,
your mind,
your feet into the wild world.
That elk is going to get eaten by
something.
Yeah.
If it's not you,
it's going to get eaten by that bear
that was sleeping on the carcass or
nothing goes to waste of.
I completely understand that after
hunting,
after getting so far in the hunting,
I completely understand that nothing
goes to waste.
Nothing ever.
If an animal breaks his leg,
it's something's going to take care of
that.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's just all part of the cycle.
It's all part of the big picture of the
world.
The biggest,
the biggest creature on the world is the
world itself.
If phase off everything us the way or
even part part of the world's Pri.
Yeah,
and in a way,
yeah,
definitely becomes this super complex
system that has everything in place.
It's got a system to dissolve bodies and
the bacteria dissolves what the animals
don't eat and there's just this really
complex pattern that's in place that's
been in place forever and what you're
doing as a hunter is is going into it
and becoming for a brief week or so,
you're becoming a part of that system or
that's how you acquire your or a month
for you and you're acquiring your food
that way,
which I obviously and you obviously
think is way better than going to a
fucking monster and hiring some
supermarket hitman to do the work for
you and feeling that your guilt free.
I worked at Abbott was for some time.
What is that?
A abetour is like a slaughterhouse.
Oh,
Aba in Australia.
You ever heard of that?
I think it's might be an Australia is a
very secluded here in America.
Will have just know that.
Yeah,
we wouldn't know.
We don't know too much about you other
than like Crocodile Dundee,
crazy.
A land down under.
Sometimes I'll use a signing or say
something unlucky.
You understand that word or not?
How about tool waterhouse?
So is that normal?
Spanish,
central,
central.
Stria bitch.
Spanish speakers.
Is it a Spanish word?
Must Be.
Huh?
Interesting word.
I'll just start cooling the
slaughterhouse and so 7,000
shape would go past on a chain and I
just had the one job to do and and,
and they'd be 700 people.
You're making a slash,
is that what you did?
Yeah,
just cut their throats.
They would be 700 other workers just on
the slaughter floor pot.
So that meet with passing 700 people's
hands.
Males the whole lot for A.
I'm not saying there's nothing wrong
with this because the population of the
world demands that not everyone can hunt
now,
so I don't have an issue with slaughter
houses or anything like that,
but I'm saying that might goes through a
wide different process.
I'd have to say for a better word.
Brutal process where those animals get
hurt on to a,
uh,
like a truck,
like a semi trailer,
uh,
driven to the lord has putting small
yards pushed through a gate to go past
all those people's hands that,
uh,
that uh,
cutting the meat.
That's before it even gets to the point
where it's going to get cut off for
packaging.
And then obviously it gets sent out to
different grocery stores and then sold
from there.
My mate passes these hands here.
That's it.
That's the only made the deposit.
I'll get to inspect every single animal
in its natural form because on the one
that kills it isn't strange that that's
the norm.
The norm is a slaughterhouse and that's
only been around for a couple hundred
years for that.
Everybody did it.
The hardware.
Exactly.
Yeah.
But yet we seem to be.
The outside is for doing it like that
and it's like this is so much more
natural.
This is friggin beautiful.
That the process is actually beautiful.
Once you get the knowledge and you look
at it that everyone thinks,
oh,
you had to get an animal.
She didn't have clean of these together
an animal like it's clean.
It's not a messy job at all.
Um,
and,
and there's no,
like I've got to block my nose.
I don't want to smell them.
There's no smell,
there's nothing.
This is clean meat and that's what I'm
saying.
The blood on my hands at that point is
clean.
Wouldn't bother me to eat a chocolate
bar and lick my fingers after
you can.
Maybe you can eat the meat completely.
Exactly.
Ready to me a predator.
I mean,
the only thing you have to worry about
is if you eat a pig or if you eat a
mountain lion or something like that.
You gotta worry about trick analysis.
We don't even have that at home.
You don't have to else?
Nope.
And so you can eat your piggery rare.
Uh,
you could,
you definitely could.
That's so come here and they cook Bacon
and it's like crusty bit of cardboard.
I'm sure you do the same.
Well,
I didn't know that.
So I cook them some bike and for our
friends that we stayed with Ed and K
Westbrook there on that bear hunt with
us it nk and um,
I'm used to just having my bike and like
slightly cooked so I just slightly
cooked it and put it on the plate.
I had on my bacon,
they didn't eat their bike and I'm like,
oh,
they mustn't be big bacon.
He does.
And then after the fact that I've eaten
my bacon,
thanks Kay.
She's like,
yeah,
we really liked to cook your bacon.
Well because a trick and hostess and I'm
like,
what the fuck?
Like you let me know.
Was it much less of a concern with
domestic pig?
Yeah.
They actually lowered the temperature
that you're supposed to kill a or cook
rather a domestic pork.
Yeah.
He used to be 165 degrees,
which is what they recommend you cook
them.
Bear at and now it's 140.
Yeah.
So you're okay.
I'm okay.
I should be cool.
They don't want to ever get out.
I mean,
unless something gets to them the way
you get tricky gnosis by eating
something with trichinosis,
the horrific nature of pig farming of
domestic,
the way they raise it,
these factory farms,
it's,
it's horrible.
I mean,
it really makes you never want to eat
pork again.
It's definitely really disgusting.
Yeah,
I could.
I'm just happy fill in my freezer with.
We've naturally harvest mate.
One hundred percent key.
Make the kids eat it.
They all love it.
But isn't it interesting that what you
said earlier that everybody can't do
that?
Not do it.
It's bizarre.
It is bizarre.
It's because of what we're talking
about.
Everyone's,
you know,
you've got to have this job,
you've got to make good money.
You know,
you need to be successful in that type
of life.
You know,
that that's the big push.
But,
but I'm always like,
no,
you really need to be successful in this
type of life,
which is the outdoors experience,
you know,
like,
um,
uh,
before it ever been a good father.
Like that's the sort of the worksheet or
whatever.
Who gives a shit?
Leave your job the more if you have to
go and do something that you enjoy in
life,
right,
that's the end story because you're not
going to get to your death bed and be
like,
oh,
I really wish I pushed and got that
better position at work or whatever.
You're never going to do that.
You'll.
You'll always be like,
I wish I did more for my kids,
or I wish I went and climbed frigging
Everest or whatever it is.
That's what it's going to be,
but we don't get caught up in this trap
is now I've got to have the newest car,
the the nicest house.
We need to live in this suburb.
I need to be the CEO at work.
I need to do that sort thing.
Well,
I think we're set up with this desire in
our heads to attain things that we think
are difficult to attain.
That we see.
Like we see a shiny car and we see a
beautiful house.
We see it all the,
all the different trappings of modern
society.
We see those things in there.
They're very appealing to us and they
seem to be like goal posts of success
and then if we can reach those things,
maybe we'll we'll reach more happiness
or we'll feel better about ourselves.
We'll have some status that that we can
brag about and you chase that stuff
until your hearts out track.
Yeah,
I do the same thing.
Don't,
don't get me wrong.
I'll say advertisement for a car or
something like that and be like,
I really liked that car,
but then it's another party minute
clinics and go,
you don't need that frigging car.
Why do you want that car?
That car means you got to work longer or
work more or something else to maintain
or something like that.
Or you want to go in and get that car
scratched in the bush.
That's another thing.
You know?
I'm like,
no,
I've already got a car.
Just be happy with what you've got.
You're,
you're an idiot.
If you go and chase that,
Just be happy with what you've got.
Life's good.
More out time,
more outdoor experience.
More time.
If your kids more time for your wife,
whatever.
In that sense,
you know,
and it's,
it's that said that that's the whole
modern society thing.
So indigenous Australia,
not all of indigenous Australia,
most of indigenous Australia because
it's so young to our culture,
you know,
because Australia was only discovered in
maybe jamie can look it up because I
don't know exact date,
I probably should.
Um,
they,
indigenous Australia don't seem to have
that desire.
They just happy with what they've got
and it's something to be,
it's something to be envious of that,
that,
that they're just happy with that,
that they're not going to waste their
life going and chasing silly things,
you know?
Yeah.
Well,
at the end of the day,
those things that you're chasing,
you can't take them with you.
That's right.
And even if you leave them behind for
your family,
I mean,
they're,
they're only going to enjoy them until
they stop living,
but will,
will.
It's like the masterpieces enjoying your
life to the utmost and having the most,
the most success with your family,
with your friends,
the most relationship,
success,
the most harmony with the people that
you come in contact with.
But that doesn't seem to be rewarded the
same way in our world as someone who's
got some ball or house,
I fucking helicopter picks him out,
but he's got golden underwear and.
But that fight.
Yeah,
it does.
They can have that.
I can have that helicopter and I
guarantee that it fades and they want
something new.
There's something.
There's something new that you're
desiring past that.
What I've tried to train myself to
design and what I do desire now is
experiences like worldly experiences
coming to coming to America for the
month.
Man,
I'd sell my if it meant to have to sell
the house that I'm in Kingwood kill me.
So I wouldn't know if I had to sell my
car to come to America,
America for a month,
I'd do it,
drop it 100 percent because the it's.
And it's not even the stories that I'll
tell you or cam or or Antonio or one of
my friends back home.
It's not even those stories.
It's the stories within myself and the
experience within myself.
That's where the real value is.
That's the real currency of this world
is what's inside me right now and how I
feel after doing this trip and this trip
was miserable.
I won't lie to you,
but it's an enjoyable,
miserable.
How do you work that shit out?
How could been in the snow?
Being wet,
flogging myself out for 16,
17 hours every day into the dark of
night and getting back into the camp.
Been miserable.
How could that be enjoyable?
Because the second you get back to camp,
you're like,
oh,
a fire.
That's awesome.
Second you lay down yet I'm just like,
ah,
it's so good to lay down.
It's like you've got to go through
hardship to find the good shit in life.
I went through this a five days on
Prince of Wales island with Rinella and
my friend Brian Callahan and it was
raining every day.
It's just pouring rain everyday.
The hunt was unsuccessful,
unsuccessful to.
We didn't get a deer,
but we came back and I was so happy.
It was like,
the sun is so warm.
It's so nice.
There's no rain and I've,
I've,
I this the same as it is today,
which is beautiful.
I mean it was beautiful today,
but I didn't really appreciate it the
way I appreciated it when I came back
from Prince of Wales.
Yeah,
definitely.
Yeah.
I really do believe that you have to go
through some difficulty to appreciate
good stuff.
Like if you're born into like a super
wealthy multibillionaire family and
you've got a Ferrari when you're 16 and
you know,
you drive around,
fly around everywhere in private jets
and you live in a giant mansion.
I just don't think that you can ever
appreciate.
Definitely not the difficulty I work for
what I've got today,
you know,
and then like I had a hard upbringing
and stuff like that.
My father was abusive,
alcoholic,
lived on the streets for some time and I
really believe that put me where I am
with my family.
I absolutely adore my family.
Do anything for my wife and kids,
anything.
Cut My arms off and sell them if I had
to.
That's because of the hardship that I
had when I was growing up and,
and lot my business is very successful
today and I believe that's because I
didn't have anything growing up as a
kid.
We Will Paul.
We will.
Very Paul,
you know,
we,
we had nothing.
We didn't,
we didn't do christmases because there
was no money to do Christmas and coming
from a broken family like that to now
have mine family that I don't know how
to treat them right because of how we
will treat it so wrong as kids and how
my mother was treated.
I know how to treat Kim or it's how
unproven that,
that shit don't fly in my house.
This is how it actually is.
You know,
you love your family to death.
You do absolutely anything for them.
And the biggest thing that I'm proud of
in life is having the family that I've
got today.
You know,
like bowhunting aside,
I'd man,
I'd dropped bow hunting.
You know how much I love bow hunting.
I'll drop balancing for my family.
Well,
I'm not going to do it it.
Kim's listening.
Luckily,
don't have to,
but yeah,
that is an interesting thing how people
come from.
A lot of folks that come from abusive,
alcoholic families,
they wind up being like really
considerate.
It really compassionate and really
dedicated to keeping on the straight and
narrow.
You know,
my friend Maurice,
he grew up with an alcoholic grandmother
who raised him and they used to uh,
the ladies to lock them in a room and
just leave them there.
Why they would go out drinking and he
couldn't get out of the room is no food.
He was always hungry and never,
never drank in his whole life.
I'm a nondrinker and it's just because
of how I say my house St my father was
drinking.
I believe I wouldn't be like that
drinking because I'm just like,
I care about the person on the street.
I don't even know that's the,
that's the sort of person that I am.
So I don't believe I would be,
um,
the violent drunk that my father was,
but it's something I don't want to even
promote to my kids.
I don't even want to promote it to me
friends.
So all my drink and I don't need to
drink.
I'm silly enough as you can tell.
Yeah.
I've seen that many times,
man.
People who grew up in that sort of
abusive substance abusing family,
they grow up and they're clean as a
whistle and they don't have nothing to
do with it.
It makes total sense.
Yeah.
Tangier off it.
It's interesting how that works,
man.
Sometimes you have to see someone just
fucking completely ruining their life in
order for you to get it in your head.
Well that is not me.
I just,
I seen all the negatives in it and then
I was like,
I don't want any negatives in my life at
all.
Like I'll do anything to avoid them,
you know,
and that's why I keep on the straight
and narrow and try and be a real
positive person is um,
I just,
I just don't want any,
anything negative like that in my life.
And I've seen alcohol as being a
negative burrito because people do stuff
that they,
they,
they usually wouldn't 100 percent,
but at the same time,
um,
I can be at work or something.
And the guys are drinking and having a
good time and there's no issue at all.
She had all stay up all night with them
having a good laugh.
I,
I just don't need it to have fun anymore
because I've never had it.
And,
and,
and obviously,
you know,
have been turned off it as a,
as a young bloke.
Yeah.
I mean it's not necessary.
I mean it's a social lubricant and end.
I,
I enjoy it,
but I didn't grow up in an alcoholic
environment.
I grew up in a violent environment and
so,
you know,
domestic violence to me is a very scary
thing and I couldn't imagine ever
hitting my wife or hitting my kids are
hitting
just,
I can't,
you know,
it was like,
it was so stressful growing up as a kid
that I think that's why I've tried to
live my life without any stress now.
And having a business.
My own business can be stressful,
but I've,
I've tried to grow up without having any
stress and just to have a figure like
that in your life growing up as kids.
I've got two sisters as well that were
obviously affected by,
by it as well.
Um,
it's a little bit like feeding your kids
the wrong vegetables and not feeding
them life,
but for mental health,
you know,
domestic violence is so ruining in that
sense that,
that it just destroys mental health.
I've had,
I've used it as fuel myself,
but I know a lot of people don't and it
actually affects them as they get older.
It affects them more and more.
It doesn't,
it also affects if you see violence too
often in the car.
And by the way,
I should really expand on this.
Like the violence that I saw was
nothing.
It means,
you know,
my dad hit my mom a few times xeno he
smacked her around.
I saw him hit some other people do.
He's just,
that's alright.
Yeah,
that's,
that's an,
that's enough.
That's bad.
But it's not violence in comparison to
say he never hit me.
I've seen many people who've lived way
more violent upbringing way,
way worse than what I've seen,
but one of the things that happens to
young people when they see violence on a
regular basis is your brain gets
programmed to accept,
not just accept that,
but to be wary of that and to be ready
to respond to that.
And so you develop a much quicker temper
and your,
the consequences of being in a dangerous
situation become much more real and
you're much more likely to act in a
violent way.
And when children see violence,
you see people getting hit and they see
that kind of shit on a regular basis.
The norm,
it becomes normal.
It becomes an option,
you know?
And it's uh,
it's just like programming.
I mean,
you know,
you have,
you have children,
like when you raise a kid like they're
so fast.
It's so fascinating to watch kids learn
and grow and you see what they respond
to and you see like when you,
when you can talk to them and get them
alone and have fun with them and respond
and rationalize with them.
Like I try to talk to my kids,
like they're adults.
I talked to them like they're little
kids,
like I give them a lot of love and a lot
of.
But I try to explain things like they're
really smart and uh,
probably I really like that my kids are
like that.
Well,
they,
they get it kind of and,
but they keep asking questions and we
work it out,
you know,
well,
what does that mean?
Well,
what,
you know,
we've had conversations about what to do
if someone's being mean to you.
Like my daughter was like,
someone's being mean to me at school.
I go,
how are they being mean to.
She was like,
well,
they said something mean about my hair.
I mean,
I go,
well,
do you like your hair?
And she's like,
yeah,
I like your hair.
I go,
do you think they really think there's
something wrong with your haircut?
Or they try to make you feel bad.
She goes,
I just think they're mean.
I go,
well,
it probably trying to make you feel bad.
Right?
And so why do you think they're trying
to make you feel bad?
While a lot of it is because when kids
are little,
they realized that they can affect
someone and they don't.
Maybe they don't even understand that
it's going to have a really bad feeling
on you,
but they,
it's like a toy that they can play with.
Like they can say something mean and you
react and they realize it and this is
something that people have to get
through.
I go,
what you should do is realize that how
that makes you feel and decide you're
never going to do that to somebody else,
especially not someone who's your
friend.
And so we have these like long
conversations about feeling about
communication.
And then I explained to her always that
whenever I tell my kid about something,
I always say,
whatever you've done,
I've done it worse and I'm dumber than
you.
For sure when I was your age because
she's very well.
Especially my eight year old who is a,
she's the middle child,
but she's,
um,
she's a,
she's very curious and very,
uh,
very interested in progress.
Like we talk about things like getting
smarter or what you were.
One of the things I always say is I go,
you're way smarter than I was when I was
eight,
when I was eight.
I was really dumb and I did a lot of
stupid things,
but also it was a boy and I think it was
a little more reckless and impulsive and
a little crazier,
but I'm like,
uh,
so anything you've done,
like if you don't tell the truth about
something or if you blame somebody else
for something that you did.
I did it all.
I did all those things so I'm not mad at
you like it obviously worked out for me.
I'm here,
I'm alive,
I'm healthy and have you so it's going
to be okay.
So no one's going to not love you if you
make a mistake.
It's totally a part of being a person.
There's no way to navigate this life
without making mistakes.
So by having those kinds of
conversations with them,
I think I alleviate at least some of the
anxiety because kids are always worried
about how you feel about what they've
done.
Like they don't want you to be upset at
them.
They don't want you to be,
and I always like because even if you do
something bad,
like I still love you,
so that's part of life.
I fucked up still as an adult,
as a 49 year old man.
I still make stupid fucking mistakes in
the end.
It doesn't even matter.
It doesn't matter.
It's just shit.
You can get past.
It's all good.
Yeah.
So good.
Chill out people.
Exactly.
But it's hard to.
Well,
you know what,
that's another thing that being in the
woods and being in the wild,
like when you see a fucking 11 foot tall
grizzly bear sleeping on an elk carcass
and you're by yourself.
Boy does like insults about a haircut
was getting mad at each other on the
playground.
He was so fucking stupid.
Like,
look at this thing.
This thing is could hate me.
Yeah.
Isn't that funny?
It is funny.
I think I mean again,
like you were saying about how being in
the woods and then coming back here
like,
wow,
I could just hit a switch and I could.
I think,
you know,
having that perspective and being out in
the wild,
he does.
It's an one more thing that gives you
this sort of a greater picture of how
bizarre and amazing life really is.
You have this thing.
No use crying.
I was built milk.
Yeah.
Yeah,
we have that.
I think we invented it.
I think you guys bought it.
I think we invented the lower wifi.
You guys invented Wifi?
I can't believe that one guy's probably
American ex.
Pat Probably went over there,
claimed Australia probably heightened
for his taxes.
Well,
like I just live by.
There's no use crying over spilled milk
like it's happened.
Like if there's even something
stressful,
it's done now let's just deal with it
because it's done now.
There's no use carrying on about it.
It doesn't make anything any better than
just like let's just deal with the
situation.
Let's just get beyond it.
But it's so common to be upset about it
and everybody else does it and it
becomes a pattern.
You see it and you know.
I mean I'm guilty of it myself.
I've gotten upset about stupid shit
before too,
but sometimes just a perspective thing
and also sometimes it's a busy thing,
like sometimes you become.
I mean,
I'm guilty of this.
I'll do,
I'll do too many things and in doing too
many things,
sometimes I get my stress level too
high,
like my base stress levels.
Like there's too many things I'm
managing all at once and then I can be
irritable.
Stuff that I shouldn't be irritable
about.
Kim's design.
Kim's got a little business pretty
little potty and she gets so busy,
she'll get caught out with at that.
She'll get to the point and she's like,
fuck,
I've just got to slow down.
I've got to do less.
I've got to do less so I can actually
feed in more things,
but more things that I enjoy.
And um,
but at least she's got that outlook
least she gets to that point and she's
like,
yeah,
okay,
I'm getting too busy,
you know,
I'm actually losing quality time with
whatever in life that she enjoys.
And um,
I used to be the side of the business
because I'd put it in these crazy hours
with the business.
I,
I practically built the business so it
could support itself and I can walk away
and go bow hunting and,
but to get to that point,
I put in a few years of just,
I'd be out,
I'd be up until 1:00
in the morning and doing things for the
business and trying to keep it growing.
And then how big do you want it because
the more shit you have in life,
in business,
all those sorts of things,
the less time you actually have in life
to do the things that you want.
All right.
So I got to the point and I'm like,
well I don't really want the business to
be any bigger than it is now unless I
get into some other managers and things
like that.
And it's just fine in that point.
Okay.
Stop.
Because you've really not enjoying life
anymore,
you know?
Let's just roll it back a little bit.
Yeah,
I've done that more this year.
I used to do all the UFC pay per views
and I used to do the Fox events too and
I cut it back to only North American
paper reviews.
No More Fox and I cut it in half so I
can blame bow hunting.
Yeah,
shit,
I need time.
That's part of the problem I was.
I was telling you on the way over here
that I really think I need to do a
bowhunting tv show just so I can have an
excuse to go more so I don't.
I listen to it.
I've got to go to work.
Can't just an attendance dry it.
Dude.
You gotta to come in and hunting with
me.
You can only see it.
Yeah.
You can only see it as an online in
China,
but it's going to be huge.
Yeah.
I don't know man.
This is A.
There's definitely a a line that you
cross between not doing enough and then
doing the right amount and then doing
too much and knowing how to pull it
back.
It's hard to pull things back though.
Yeah.
Most people they.
They feel like if they're not moving
forward,
they're moving backward.
If they're not doing more,
they're doing less.
Yeah.
That's the human condition,
isn't it?
Well,
it's part of this,
uh,
you know,
go get them society.
Especially in America.
I mean,
I don't know exactly what the attitude
is over in Australia.
Is that right?
And it's,
it's different with different people,
but I'll have an hour at home if it
doesn't even have to be something I want
to do.
I can be doing housework on the house or
doing something at work.
It doesn't even have to be something
that I actually want to do,
but if I'm not doing something for an
hour,
I am bored shitless dude.
Like hide the knives.
I'm going to cut my wrist,
like bored,
bored shitless.
Like I need to be doing something.
And like I said,
it doesn't even have to be something I
want to do,
but I have to have something to do.
One of the things that I realized how to
do or learned how to do over the last
few years,
it's going an actual vacation where I go
and I could just sit on the beach and
drink Margaritas and put my feet up
because they play with my kids.
No,
I can't go fishing though.
Well,
we were organizing a trip recently to
Hawaii and I was saying I forgot all the
NIH.
I can have access to exactly who god was
shine,
but the problem is I'll be up at 6:00
in the morning.
I won't see my family.
It's like they're at.
Oh,
it's not.
That's not a.
that's not a vacation your vacation.
But fishing is like fishing is easy and
they liked my kids like it.
It's fun bringing,
bringing kids to Australia to.
I'll take you out in some mad fishing
network.
Australia is a strange place,
man,
and this is one of the things I was a 16
hour flight away.
Well that too,
but it's also a strange place in that
like what they've done in America with
reintroducing wolves.
What,
what they've done in Australia.
What I think is really bizarre is feral
cats and foxes to deal with some of the.
That's some of the shit never works to
grow it.
Rabbit's tail.
They brought wrap to fade one of the
early colonies within Australia because
that was for the paypal,
a rabbit's with paypal.
The height.
Yeah,
that's why I brought him in.
Food source.
Well all the animals in Australia,
so particularly New Zealand,
all the game animals,
all of them have been introduced from
somewhere else.
That's,
that's great.
Most so.
The spaces are all gifts from royalty
along the way and.
And then you've got other species that
weren't gifts at all.
We just brought them in because we
thought it was gonna benefit Australia,
but most of them,
if not all of them done the complete
opposite.
So they grow it in the Fox to look after
the rabbit.
Well there's so much other shit that the
fox would just prefer to eat that's
easier than catching a rabbit.
They just hate that and that's it.
It's all.
It's like the spaces that lives in
Australia,
like it's not like,
oh,
it's something else we want to get rid
of.
No,
it's something else we wanted to keep
because they're natives,
you know,
like ground nesting birds,
you name it,
and then you spend enough time out in
the woods and you'll see just about the
craziest things.
And we've seen feral cats now because
the birds started nes than out on lakes
on old trees that were growing into
like,
that'd be safe there right now.
The feral cats were swimming across the
lake at night.
We're actually seen this,
the light swimming across the lake at
night,
climb in these birds that are nesting in
the trees out on the lake and snatching
the chicks and the bird just devastating
to,
to our population of um,
I've
never heard of feral cat swimming and
allies.
He did.
Yeah.
So they just figured out how to do it.
I just figured out how to do it.
Made me body threat.
They will bomb them up,
you know,
that's,
that's the,
that's the is the point right there.
That's the right thing to do is get in
and Carlos cats out when it's to that,
to the,
that sort of.
Well,
that was what I was going to bring up
because when I was in Australia,
you gave me some of your,
uh,
Australian bowhunting magazines and
these fucking pictures of hosing with
cats.
They've got a dead cat.
That's a proud moment for her because of
had devastated.
And I,
ah,
I understand.
I get it the same way coyotes are here
in the lawn and it up.
I'm not thinking about shooting me.
Cut It home.
That's different.
It's a cat.
It's got a collar on and it's got a bill
on and it stays at the house.
But isn't that bizarre?
Like you love that cat.
Another cat.
You'll shoot dogs dingoes and you've got
feral dogs and feral dogs that just,
that's just a domestic dog that's gone
wild and they're the same.
Now we'll kill that.
Devastating to our population of
wildlife.
Wombats take good.
Hit it.
You know,
kidneys will get harassed if sending a
kid.
No Kid,
no kid,
no.
What is it?
It's like a porcupine,
but hate.
Cool.
Whoa,
it looks cool and you'll walk out there.
You have wolves.
You don't even have.
Whoops.
Goes,
I think I would eat a wolf hall.
Oh,
how dare you.
That's so not true.
How big is the Dingo?
I'm not as big as a wolf.
I'm bullshit and you know,
but it's crazy because you guys are so
scared to coming out to true.
You could snakes and spiders and I'm in
the Bush here for one day and there's a
giant frigging Grizzly Bay.
Look at my tent and I'm like,
I'll take the spot.
Isn't snakes please?
Do you think it grizzly bears carry than
a Croc?
Crocs.
Crossfit gets a cold,
cold.
Hard killer like that would just it.
It seems if you went in the water near
any crocodile had come and have a crack
at you.
If you went near any bar,
reckon about 50 percent of them,
40 percent of them might attack you.
It might even be less than that where it
just seems like crocodiles so stuck in
the Jurassic period that anything that
comes to that water's just going to get
chomped.
I tell you a quick little story,
so I'm in Arnhem land last year.
Honestly.
It's like northern territory,
Arnhem land on them,
on them,
but how are you spelling that?
It's I am heights a h,
h,
h.
like when we say h,
h,
you guys put an a in there.
Probably not ask guys.
Just me.
Nigga from Arnhem.
Arnie,
Arnie homeland.
Okay.
There's a vast wilderness area,
or is.
It's God's land.
Beautiful.
Okay,
so you're an for an outdoorsman.
He was hell.
Absolute hell for any city slicker.
It is out there.
Ms Dot g dot.
Hello.
Got a picture is amazing.
Yeah,
it is a spectacular and virtually
untouched.
Yeah.
That's the crazy thing about Australia
is the population that you guys have
essentially the population of Los
Angeles in a place as big as the
continental United States.
Think Cross for that.
Yeah,
it's nice.
It is nice.
Even when we went to like you go to a
nice city like Melbourne,
it's beautiful.
Yeah.
That's like a little country town for
you guys.
Yeah.
All it is.
It's tiny.
It's like boulder,
Colorado and we're like,
get us out of here.
There's too much traffic.
So uh,
you're in Arnhem land and what?
Huh?
I mean Arnhem land and shoot these
massive big boar pig and it runs down.
So I shot it and it just ran down.
It was just on the edge of the water and
it's fighting like it's seconds away
from dying.
And um,
I walk over there and as I walk over
there I sort of sit down and just give
the animal that's piece,
you know,
I don't want to give him an adrenaline
rush or anything like that because it
could take longer for it to die.
So I would just sit down quietly and
snap Massey big salt water crocodile,
just lunges out of the water and grabbed
these pig and stopped swimming out
across this river.
I was seconds away from walking down
there and essentially dragging that pig
back
bank a bit.
So I get photos that crock was sitting
right there,
like within seconds
is that crocodile was sitting on the
edge of the bank or just under the water
where it could grab that pig.
That's how quick it can happen.
People,
we'll walk down and go,
I'll just be quick.
I'm just going to wash my face really
quick.
It's always hot there.
So the most appealing thing in the
Haiti's like you say water and it's
like,
oh well water go down there and just
kind of splash a bit of water on my face
and arms will be real quick gone and
they go for anything,
for anything.
So I don't have a.
They don't have a reluctance to kill
people at all.
Definitely not.
And then um,
there's.
Oh Jesus,
this elephant by the nose.
Well that's not a stride is buddy
elephant.
They.
Yeah,
that's a Nio crock.
They guys your Pyros Jaimee crocodile.
I think the same animals.
Yeah.
It's the difference between the
crocodiles in Australia and those
fuckers.
Those fuckers are in Florida now.
Assholes in Florida.
Florida is just overrun with assholes.
Not Everybody's filed on day.
If you live in Florida and you're a nice
person,
I appreciate Davao and legend.
Yeah.
I'm.
The crocodiles in the Nile.
Crocodiles have been in,
introduced to Florida.
Assholes have just released into the
everglades.
No,
it's not.
They have a shoot to kill.
It's not.
I'm being sarcastic.
I was being sarcastic back.
They have a shoot on sight,
a order literally seeing Nile crocodile
supposed to kill it on site because
they're terrified of him developing a
sustainable population because the
crocodiles they have,
the native crocodiles in Florida are
small,
but they're very aggressive.
They're way more aggressive than
alligators,
but they're smaller,
but now they have these fucking nial
crocs.
We got just absolutely savage and just
swallow a person hall.
You're talking about the everglades,
which is just overrun with things for
them to eat,
so there's a high of them achieving a
large size.
Where did they get that idea from?
The assholes.
People have them as pets.
The same thing as pythons.
You know the python situation in Florida
that people have had to have them as
pets and then release them into the
wall.
Had I got there,
it would get too big and they go,
fuck this.
I'm going to let a kid,
hey,
you little crocodile,
go out and enjoy the wild and they think
they're doing the right thing by
releasing this thing into the swamps and
then,
well,
they have a breeding population now they
have a breeding population of Nile.
Crocodiles in fucking Florida sent back
to the Australian introduced species.
It like,
it didn't stop it at foxes.
I kept making these mistakes.
You know,
the cane toads,
we have a lot of trouble with the cane
toads now.
Keen to cane toad.
What's a cane to virtually overtaken
Australia.
They're going to have their own
businesses and run for parliament and
everything.
Eventually like towed or opening your
hands like a pizza.
Freaking oh,
not a pizza.
Oh my God.
As a cane toad.
Whoa.
That thing's huge.
Bunny rabbit,
they got these glands on their back and
it's got a poisonous toxin in it.
Oh,
that's great.
And so our bird wildlife are snakes.
I hate snakes.
Snakes are protected in Australia by the
way.
You can't just go and kill the snake
when you want and they've still got
their place.
They're 100 percent snakes and got their
place in Australia,
the snakes atum and these poisonous
toxins will kill the snakes that'll kill
that bird life that they had just
horrific Jesus kroger the size,
these things,
so why don't quote me,
but I'm pretty sure they brought him in
to fight off a cane beetle that was
eating now cane crops and there's that
many other bugs in that that the cane
toad would have been like,
I'll just eat what I want.
What a stupid thing.
Can't we learn?
Well,
people are very,
very infant tile with the perspective on
the ecosystem,
like the idea that you could just,
oh well we've got a little problem here.
I got,
well there's a little opening.
I'll stick up a slot in there.
Just shove a Predator in there and I'll
fill that opening like they didn't
consider all the other animals that this
thing would eat.
If they want to do something and what
they should do instead of introduced and
shit like this.
See this,
check your load for a cane.
Toads,
cane toads are great stowaways and can
be easily transported and your goods and
luggage when you were packing up to
leave from an area where cane toads are
present,
it is important to thoroughly check
that.
Were that accidentally carrying a cane
toad?
They're not a good thing.
Tasmanian Tiger?
Yeah,
to the Tasmanian talk like extinct
narrow,
but they got the DNA from one guy,
ray and juice something.
Let's do it.
Are they going to reintroduce one that I
like white,
but they should now if they wanted to
introduce that,
they wanted to take the DNA from a
Tasmanian Tiger and reintroduce it when
they have to have something that was
like a similar animal in and reintroduce
it.
Possibly.
I don't know how it works.
I think I got that from Jurassic Park.
Probably pretty true though.
I think that's how they do it.
Well then in that,
what they said they were going to do
with the woolly mammoth,
like there was this Russian scientists
that we're thinking about reintroducing
the wooly mammoth and they were going to
use the DNA from a woolly mammoth from
some,
you know,
fossilized something or another,
and they were going to combine it with
the DNA from a regular elephant.
Okay.
I think that'd be interesting.
I think in some cases like that,
you know,
not trying to be God or anything,
but that should happen.
That's a good thing,
right?
Togare I think it's only extinct because
of human interactions.
Right?
So out of night,
I don't know either,
but 90 percent of everything is extinct.
Ninety percent of everything that's ever
lived.
It's like,
where do you draw the line?
Do we bring back dinosaurs,
you know,
when do we draw the line?
That'd be good hunting.
Ooh,
tigger impact.
Big Foot.
Would you want the t rex?
Um,
if there was enough of them,
what if they say is good?
Imagine that because alligators tastes
good.
Well,
I do.
Yeah,
I've eaten one.
Yup.
John Dudley kills them all the time.
He eats him.
Yeah,
he's a slave.
He's still there.
He said that their tails like alligator
tail,
like the meat from them is apparently
like more rich and protein than he like
elk or Moose.
Really?
That's crazy.
We packing that into the back country is
supposed to be like really good for you.
Super Lean.
Cook it quick sear it will her it
alligator.
So our crocodiles back home are
protected as well.
Oh Geez.
This not tag or anything for them.
You can't kill a crocodile.
A crocodile.
What they re like hate him.
But city of kill something over here
please.
This,
the city in the northern territory,
which is all part of honestly and ne is,
is Darwin City and the river runs right
into the city and there's crocodiles
right in there.
So guys will go out clubbing or you
know,
drink and get drunk and think it's a
good idea to jump in the river for a
swim and Yahoo.
And I'm now getting snatched.
So they catch oles crocodiles and I
release him like miles and miles away
and these things come straight back into
the science spot.
And they liked the,
this is what I'm hearing about these
bears,
right?
Like catch sleeves,
problem bears and they release them were
near on hunting.
Unfortunately they catch these problem
based and that release them multiply and
then a week later they show back up to
the same destination.
Yeah.
Crazy.
They know how to get back.
They have some sort of internal compass.
One of the things about saltwater
crocodiles,
it's so terrifying.
As a friend of mine was telling me that
they were on some sort of a boat and
they were like a deep out into the
ocean,
miles out and they saw saltwater
crocodile swimming out there.
And what,
how,
how far?
He said yeah,
I think he said he was something like
three to five miles away from shore and
it's fucking crocodiles just out there
swimming by z probably could have
probably gotten a great watch off or
some shit.
Fuck,
it's a goddamn dinosaur hat.
Look at that thing.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
When came,
came out and were up in Arnhem land and
I was telling him about all the
dangerous shit,
you know,
like a crocodile will,
there's crocodiles in any bit of water
here you wouldn't even know and there'll
be a crocodile in there and
how buffalo charge you're in charge
here.
And I told him about all the poisoners
bushes and everything and at the end of
one day we got,
we got back with like half our light and
because I didn't pack any food in,
we had to catch fish every day or try
and shoot some shoots eight.
So we got back half an hour early one
afternoon and we're like,
we'll go for a quick fish,
we're going to catch some fish in and
we've got to get some,
some food into us.
And we walk out and it's stinking hot.
It's like 56 degrees Celsius.
They'd like sweating it out is like
1:10.
That's probably even a bit higher.
Yep.
It's hot.
And unlike how we might be able to swim
in one of the rock pools,
you don't want to swim out in the ocean
because one of them crocs is gonna.
Grab a 50 slash 56.
Oh my God.
Jack it up.
Baby 50.
Oh Jesus.
One 30 to walk in the park.
One hundred and 32 degrees.
Temperature drink and buffalo peers.
Because you had to keep hydrated or die.
What does it feel like to be out in 132
degree temperature?
You get used to it.
How the fuck do you get used to them?
It's like,
it's like that.
All my guys are working with working
that temperature or summer.
You could slip that cooking.
I'm at 115 degrees.
Those birds dying around us.
There's a little video where I've got
like,
it might be a frogmouth,
our attorney our.
And it's just that heart that it's just,
it's on the grant,
it's,
it's out,
you know,
because it hasn't had obviously a bit of
hto and that day and anyway.
So we're going out and there's a rock
pool.
I'm like,
well,
we'll be safe to swim in that rock pool,
and the tide had gone out.
We've got big tires like seven made a
tired,
you know,
they're come in and out every day,
and the todd had been in and when had
gone out to the left,
a bunch of box jellyfish in that little
pool.
Then the ocean itself where we'll
fishing in or you wouldn't be able to
dip your hand in the water getting stung
by the box jellyfish box.
Jellyfish will kill you.
Oh,
you're dead dude.
That was a,
that was a four and a half hour chopper
flight out to get there because we did
it in the wet season.
You couldn't drive any of the roads.
Um,
I had to hire a helicopter to get us out
there.
So it would have been four and a half
hours for a hell of a cop to come in and
then four and a half hours back to the
hospital.
You're dead in that time.
You're dead in the first hour.
Like it's,
yeah,
you've got to have your wits about you
and that sort of country.
So box jellyfish.
What do they look like?
They're the one that nearly clear.
They like,
fuck yeah,
look at that shit and that'll kill you
instantly,
and that's the one thing I didn't tell
came about and we get out to the rocks
and all the crazy shit that I've told
you,
dude.
That's what would've killed us here if
we jumped in the water.
Like,
Nah,
let's just jump in for a quick dip.
Wow.
Who's that?
Mad boss?
That's that crazy fucking river
monsters.
Wow.
Look at that one.
That got that guy's leg.
Go.
Go back to that leg picture jamie.
Go full screen on that man.
That's sick.
Tighter.
I think you keep that person.
Just get close enough to the
knee of the water again.
Is it like an antivenom?
Oh,
is that a baby?
Oh God.
Damn.
One year old.
Oh my God.
That's will Smith was in a movie or a
diabetes organs at the end of the movie
and he's going to.
That's how he commit suicide.
He's going to jumping up off with box
jellyfish.
What fucking movie I am.
Legend.
Scary Shit.
And I am legend.
It is kind of.
I mean,
there's so many monsters that exist.
Seven pounds,
seven pounds,
seven pounds.
What does that mean to you about.
I think that's the one with the kid.
The kid.
Kid.
Isn't that the one where he's poor?
Like he becomes a successful person?
Oh,
I don't want to say that shit.
I'll get that fucking thing away from
me.
Oh,
he actually does kill himself,
so he actually does any tips of box
jellyfish in the water of human?
Yeah.
Get out of here.
I don't want to see this shit.
Get you coming out.
Get the fuck out of here.
That's a movie.
He dies with box jellyfish.
That's a retarded.
No,
get the fuck out.
They're not even that big.
Jamie.
I don't want to say it anyway.
When you come out.
I wouldn't take any of those and there's
so many things that killed.
We'll take him in the ocean.
Then the things that kill you because
they want us to live in Australia.
It's true.
That's what I always think about work
because it's so freaking hot.
It's so desolate that it's like,
it just wasn't designed for people is
part of the earth.
No,
I think.
Well,
people didn't live then,
so didn't balance it out at some of the
oldest earth on earth work that people
didn't live their western dummies,
like uni white people.
We definitely didn't.
The indigenous people that lived there,
I did that.
I lived on the mainland and um,
there's actually some really interesting
areas out there.
It's called the dampier archipelago in
the Pilbara region of Western Australia
and there's over 70,000
a rock in the area that I still don't
know this.
Maybe you can solve it,
but 70,000
rockets in that area.
Wow.
Kangaroos,
sea turtles,
creatures that don't even exist anymore.
When you look at the picture,
you're like,
was that a real animal?
That drawer and all that.
I just like,
ah,
I just got to fuck her.
And so they don't even know whether or
not it was a real thing because it
doesn't exist anymore.
It doesn't exist anymore.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well,
the,
the kangaroo thing,
we were talking about that before the
podcast,
we said we're going to show this video.
Um,
I did not know the Kangaroos were
protected.
Like you can't just shoot kangaroos over
there,
all about naive animals.
You can't have any event.
90 animals in Australia,
everything we can hunt and there's 27 or
28 spaces are old introduced.
They're an invasive species,
like a feral pest.
That's why we're allowed to hunt them.
It's not like the American system where
your hunting unite is lucky at what tile
and oak and everything like that.
And that's why we don't have a tag
season.
Well,
we don't have any,
any,
any seasons at all in New South Wales.
They've just introduced this season in
the last couple of years and there's one
species of d in Victoria,
the lower part of Australia where you
need to tag for.
That's it.
All those other species you don't need a
tag for.
And there's no season.
What species have a healthy body?
You need to type for those.
Oh,
there's not a bunch of them and they're
trying to manage them.
It's really good.
What they're doing,
they're doing a good job.
Mm hmm.
So the kangaroo thing.
I had no idea that the numbers of
Kangaroos were as high as they are.
So you were telling me about this.
Looks like a kangaroo plague.
And then Jamie pull the video up and
this is fucking insane.
Just Google kangaroo plague Australia.
And what you see is something from a
fucking horror movie.
It looks like thousands of Kangaroos.
I mean I have no idea how many of their
head they're just running across this
field.
Like ants.
I bet you have that.
Analysts.
I wouldn't cheeses.
I mean completely insane when you look
at that video.
I have no idea.
Yeah.
So fuck a sign.
The sign people that are lucky,
you can't call the Kangaroos,
you know,
you can't hunt the Kangaroos.
You can't shoot the Kangaroos.
Kangaroos are a deer species,
right?
I don't think so.
I think they're like a marsupial.
It doesn't have a near.
Okay.
I think.
I think they even taste like deer.
They taste good too.
The really rich red.
Meat's super,
super lean.
A lot of the lot of the body builders
and stuff like that.
Love kangaroo meat.
When did kangaroo start getting joked?
Yoked up.
They always had big muscles.
They've always had big muscle.
We didn't see that in America until
recently.
Not really.
Internet over the last few years has
showed us a choking each other.
Hey,
say they doing weights and shit and
pumping.
It looks like they're fucking giant.
Yeah.
There's a video of those two kangaroos
fighting one kangaroo.
Chokes.
You conscious?
Look at that kangaroo.
Just normal.
Like,
come on man.
That's incredible.
We never saw kangaroos.
Yeah.
So that's.
That looks like a big red.
Kangaroos are.
The red ones are the biggest ones,
right?
Yep.
Yeah,
the huge.
My friend Eddie was in Australia.
He does a.
he's done a bunch of standup out there
and he was out there with some
Australians and I forget what the store.
Look at the fucking dentist even.
Look real man does not look real bitch.
You and arm wrestle.
Fuck that man.
So that was what would happen with
Eddie.
He got out of the car for some reason
and he saw this kangaroo and he thought
it was a statue because it was so big.
He thought it was.
He thought it wasn't really so he was
like seven feet tall.
It's like there's no fucking way.
This is a real kangaroo.
He literally thought it was a statute
because it was sitting there and his
friend started screaming,
get back fucking car,
and the thing turns around and looks at
him,
and then he realized that this giant
thing in front of them was an actual
kangaroo and apparently they're very
aggressive.
They're calling as a life feel
threatened now.
They'll kick your stomach out because
what they do is they latch onto you.
If they close.
I've actually got a real big claw.
They got clothes like that.
Yeah,
and then they balance their cell phone,
their tile and like kick with both legs
and they got like a single toe nail
that's like that thing that has legs and
that does not look real.
And the balance that way on their back
tails and credible out balancing their
Bechtel's now kick with both their legs
and then look how he's like balancing
himself.
That's so strange.
Strange animal.
God that is a flex and come up.
Might come down to 100 pound ripped
kangaroo crushes metal.
Oh my God.
He's bending cans.
Look arms and this motherfucker is so
strange.
They are cool animal on the farm.
When you come out to Australia,
you'll see.
You'll see a kangaroo fights.
They do it all day.
Everyday.
Shit out of each other.
Yeah.
They always choke each other out because
some new shit.
Are they learning how to do this?
I'll spinning back,
kick their fucking chest.
He wants to pitch a piss.
I wonder if we could take a leg kick.
I always think if I was going to fuck
with a kangaroo,
I would just arm drag him and take his
back.
I bet if you take us back,
I didn't know what to do.
Oh,
I don't know.
Take his back out and find out and choke
them.
We'll test it out when we get there and
he'd some fit clothing like Kevlar to
where it can't cut your guts out because
you know,
probably won't even go for your face or
I'd probably go for your guts.
Got For you.
Got Getting the guts.
If you can protect that,
if you could figure out a way to like
move in,
Juco them,
fake.
Um,
get them to move.
Get Ahold of one of them,
pause arm,
drag them back because y'all going to be
awesome.
It'd be on the news.
My Dad and tries to take on a kangaroo's
it ain't gets his stomach kicked out.
This is how I die by getting.
There's a bunch of these videos of these
kangaroos choking each other out.
I've never seen him choke each other
out.
Oh,
there's a great video.
Um,
these two kangaroos are fighting in like
a suburban neighborhood and they're in a
street and one kangaroo Canberra.
He gets like a,
like a,
what we call like a vice grip clamp.
In jujitsu you would use or wrestling,
you'd like clamp,
you scoop the back of someone's neck
like this with one arm.
And the other arm comes down and he
clamped down like this,
this is it.
And he fucking chokes him to sleep.
This has got to be Canberra for see if
he could fight this.
I don't think they just start kicking
each other's asses,
but they're in a like a regular
neighborhood fucking each other up.
But see if you fall,
you call the tight.
This shit.
I should.
But it's all the standard moves.
It's very a sock.
'Em robots.
Look how they snap each other's heads
back to two good buck there.
They only go for the guts.
Oh look at that move though.
I like how they balance on that.
Tail it.
It's really crazy.
See if you can find kangaroo chokes out
other kangaroo because he puts him to
sleep like literally the clamp down on
them and it turns his neck like it's
another thing we invented in Australia.
Checkouts,
Kangaroos,
tinder.
People learn from Kangaroos.
Maybe.
Maybe someone actually saw in school to
the Canberra.
I bet people didn't know that you could
choke people out until they saw someone
do it.
Right?
Yeah.
Here it is.
So he,
they,
they start going at it and one kangaroo
is cv could find out where he does it.
He gets a front headlock,
see the one kangaroos kind of being a
pitcher.
So here it is.
She's got the clamp,
we'll get it clamped.
He gets a hold of the neck and he's
bending his neck and a really funny way
and he traps the head up against his
chest.
I mean this is like a Japanese necktie
right here.
And he grabs a hold of it and he's
clamping down on it.
It's not even like he's paying
attention.
It was like he's looking for girls,
hey ladies got this shit.
Looting.
I wonder if he's done that before.
But that's his baby.
So he,
he clamps down on any holds it in place
and the kangaroo fights for a little
while and then Bam passes out.
That's awesome.
And is a bitch.
What a bizarre bodied animal.
There's nothing like them wake up.
It's been so used to seeing these
animals that same way to us.
Uh,
but when I think about it,
I'm like,
these things are on two legs.
Yeah.
What else is on two legs?
Not.
Have you ever seen a platypus?
Well they kinda go on the front leg.
Like look there.
Yeah.
When they're just walking along.
But have you ever seen a platypus?
Not In real life.
A lot of posts is just crazy to look at
it.
Even for me and I've grown up with.
Platypus.
I used to be in the creeks and the
rivers around home.
They were just so weird to look at and
let the kid know and when I stopped
thinking about as species,
like the wombat,
the wombat is just crazy.
They're all over the farm.
You'll see them everywhere when you come
out.
I'm like,
just dig these massive big halls and
they just the craziest creature you've
ever seen.
It's just like the big,
big,
fat stumpy rat.
I know the name Wombat,
but honestly I couldn't pick one out of
a lineup.
I don't really know what it looks like,
but let's get to that kitchen.
What is it?
A kitchen now?
How you say it,
kid?
No Kid.
No.
I want to see what a kid is first.
What's it Kinda just looks like a
porcupine.
Oh,
it's better than a pole.
He Paul and looked it up.
You should jacked again.
They've got this crazy big.
Only one a year again.
Jamie,
it's got a crazy beak.
It's got a crazy big sniffs out like
ants in an ant mounds and it'll dig out
the answer.
It'll go.
It'll dig out and logs,
sniffs them out and just look at that
dude.
Yeah,
that's a kidnap.
Me and the kids would just um,
there was one on the road the other day.
Yeah.
It's got a peek.
Like that kind of.
That's definitely better than a
hedgehog.
What's that thing?
Get rid of it.
Come on bird.
It's got a beak.
Like a bird.
It's pot sick.
Awesome animal.
Look at that.
What a fucking bizarre.
A little thing.
That was one on the road.
Digging the Alvin.
I owe a lot of the month now because
I've been away for so long and a main.
The kids,
whenever we see them on the ride,
we will move them off the road and the
kids got out and,
and you can actually hold ice box is
super sharp,
but you can actually touch them because
it's taken up so much room on your hand,
like,
you know,
there's 100 spots and they chain you can
actually touch them.
And uh,
we,
we moved this thing off the road and,
and I,
and the kids were even normal about it.
I like,
oh yeah,
cool kid.
Now you know,
because they've seen them 100 times and
I was like,
anyone that wasn't from Australia
though,
that was saying this for the first time,
this animal with a beak,
when I started thinking about it and
they turned back clothes like the
clothes turn back like that.
It's for digging,
right?
Crazy.
As animal in the world.
When you think about it in that sense,
you know,
if you'd never ever seen one before and
you come across it for the first time,
you'd be like,
Whoa,
look at this thing.
This thing is crazy.
Yeah.
It's like a porcupine.
Fuck the duck.
Right?
It doesn't have a beak that's not a bad
guy.
Platypus.
To their daily lives.
But there are a mammal.
Yeah,
and they got like a big duck.
Big.
It's crazy.
But the laying of the eggs,
it's so strange.
Like what is that?
They've got a poisonous spark as well.
They do,
yeah.
Where is it on the night of them?
Might be like a anal spark or something
like that.
Mm hmm.
Yeah.
Interesting.
So it probably wouldn't want to play
around don't finger.
It's,
but just the wide variety of animal life
is very weird.
It's very weird.
When you think about how many different
things,
and then again what you were talking
about about the introduction of foxes
and cats.
They all fit into a system.
Like look at that thing.
There's A.
Yeah.
So it as like this funky kind of furry
beaver looking tail.
It has the tiniest little dots for eyes.
Webbed feet.
What?
Have you ever eaten beaver?
No.
Had beaver with Rinella.
It's really good.
Really delicious.
It tastes like beef.
I didn't like the sand event.
I know.
I wouldn't either.
I wouldn't have normally even thought
that you could eat it,
but uh,
he,
he killed one and then a braised it and
then slow cooked it and it was like a
pot roast with like potatoes and
carrots.
It was delicious.
Thank the bear camp.
I could never ate a beaver because
members of dead babies and bear camp.
Oh yeah.
It's the thought now.
Really?
Yeah.
I couldn't do it.
I could,
unless I was slightly hungry.
I'll do it slightly telling you if
Steven Rinella cooked you a bowl of this
beaver pot roast or whatever the fuck it
is.
They made.
It was amazing.
It was really good.
It sounds good.
It was like a,
like a strange beef,
like what an odd,
like maybe dry age beef.
Yeah.
Like tend to me off again.
Was like a beef from that was like,
all right,
this is beef from Nicaragua.
Oh,
interesting.
It's got a different flavor to it.
You know what I mean?
It's uh,
it's just,
it's like it's reminiscent of beef,
like a cousin of beef.
That's what it tastes like.
A cousin of the.
It's very weird and it's kind of fatty
and it's Kinda like tender.
Yeah.
Okay.
Steve,
we'll have to hook me up when I'm
telling you you'd be shocked somewhere
along the line they made it illegal to
hunt them for food though they're a fur
bearing animal,
so you have to have a fur trappers
license and America eat them.
But there's people at the turn of the
century like Rinella is amazing in his
knowledge of the history of animals and
America and the history of hunting in
America.
But apparently many,
many,
many years ago,
um,
beaver trapping and beaver pelts were so
valuable that the richest man in the
world in the early 18 hundreds made all
of his money from beaver pelts.
Really?
Yeah.
We should bring that back in.
Davis for law,
I think it was before felt and once they
came up with felt like for hats and
stuff like that because the gentlemen
war felt hats.
They didn't need beaver as much anymore
and beaver kind of fell out of favor and
people stopped,
stopped doing that to have big numbers.
The beaver population dropped at that
time,
but yeah,
apparently behind animals,
you know when they've got that value on
them and there's just an open slaughter
is what seems to drive a lot of things
to extinction.
Well,
that's one of the interesting things
about America,
like if you buy elk or venison in
America,
most of it is from New Zealand,
which is really strange.
The reason is you can't like market
hunting.
It was like a giant factor in the
slaughter of countless amounts of
buffalo,
of elk and deer.
Even antelope,
like they killed everything back in the
day and it was a lot of men returning
from the war at the turn of the century
that just went on these trips and that
was.
That's the way that you could make
money.
That way you can make money is a go go
hunting for meat and that's when they
brought that to market.
Yeah,
I mean the.
I think the idea of these animals being
precious and preserved and wild life,
the way we think of it,
they didn't have these thoughts in the
18 hundreds.
They were just.
It was a resource and they just abused
it and I just.
I mean we've all seen the photos of the
stacks of buffaloes.
Yeah,
definitely a lot of religious for the
hides where we oxidize.
Definitely.
I think a lot of people think that still
happening today,
like hunt is a still that soda person.
Whereas hunt is a.
The ultimate conservationist now and the
system that America has got in place is
the best system anywhere in the world
where there's a tag,
there's a season,
like they manage and regulate the
population,
so,
so let's just say a elk.
The numbers were down
the following year we'll.
There'd be less tags available.
It's as simple as that and that's why
it's such a good system.
In Australia we don't have that system
in place,
but in a sense it's pushed,
pushed all the responsibility back on
hunters.
Like I can tell you now you Australian
hunters are some of the best hunters in
the world because they've got a conserve
and they've got to manage their
resources,
their self.
There's nothing in place to say,
well,
we're only given 500 tags away for that
area this year.
Um,
because numbers are down,
Hannah's as much as we are conservation
conservationists,
we're not going to go out and just
slaughter the numbers.
You know,
they're,
they're an introduced species into
Australia.
They are bad to the environment.
If the numbers are too big and Hannah's
treat them like that,
we were,
we're not going to go and wipe out the
whole population.
So,
um,
is a very good at,
uh,
you know,
there's only 20 bucks in this area at
the moment and there's [inaudible] there
should be a certain buck to doe ratio.
There's only 20 bucks in this area at
the moment.
We're not going to kill 19 of them.
There's going to be one buck lift,
you know,
we're going to kill the oldest buck in
that area.
There's only 20.
They will,
let's just kill the oldest book in that
area.
That's a good population.
Um,
it's sustainable.
They're not damaging the environment in
that number.
Um,
and I think there's a big difference
there between the American and the
Australian hunter in that sense that,
um,
you guys would do the same thing.
Don't get me wrong,
if there wasn't a tag in place or
seasoned in place in today's society
would do the same thing.
I think I've learned from the past some,
some would,
but there's a bunch of people that
wouldn't know that majority though the
majority,
but a,
I think there's quite a few that
wouldn't,
you know,
that's,
that's a,
I mean that,
that is one of the,
the main stereotypes of the hunter is
beer drinking and shooting everything
that moves and I feel today that it
couldn't be further from the truth.
It seems like there's more of the
responsible hunter,
the one that's got a good job or,
or,
or good business or whatever it is
that goes out and,
and get.
You'll be in the perfect example of
that.
I wanted to thank you when I first come
on the show that the light that you've
shown on hunting is,
is how hunters are today.
The majority of hunters are today.
We're just not these savage kilo
machines that are just like,
yeah,
kill it,
you know,
we're,
we're very conservative in a sense.
Um,
you know,
wow.
It's not just about going out and
getting a shot off.
If you are that sort of hunter,
I believe you're in it for all the wrong
reasons.
It's about the experience,
the connection with the outdoors that,
that meet,
that precious meat,
you know,
that you'd get off each,
each one of those animals.
Also the money that we spend on gear,
the money that you spend on outfitters
and trips that money in tags in
particular all goes to conservation.
Preserving the habitat
of these animals and a lot of these
animals like especially like white tail
deer.
There's more white tailed deer here in
America today than there were when
Columbus came here and some of the
incomes,
all,
some of these small towns rely on,
right?
Yes.
Is very haunting and something that I've
always pushed because it's frowned upon
it in Australia in a big way because
it's not the typical thing to do.
Hunting's not.
It's not definitely not.
Definitely not.
And it's.
And it's not accepted like it is here in
America.
How did you get into it?
Oh,
you got myself into it,
which was really,
really weird.
Hoyt were asking me the same thing.
They lock off.
So did your dad hunt?
I'm like,
no,
you know,
like I come from a broken family,
um,
I seen a barber shop in a store and I
was like,
um,
what's that thing?
Because it was like a compound bow,
you know,
I'm like,
what's that thing?
And he's like,
oh,
it's a bow.
And so I ended up buying the bow and
when I bought the bow he gave me like,
it was just a black and white magazine,
like I was 97 and then I'd run around
with like a fiberglass pole with a
string.
Been on it before and used to make my
own arrows,
like Robin Hood stuff,
you know,
but never had seen anything like that in
the magazine he gave me was a guy with a
massive big water buffalo on the front
cover.
And I'm like,
you can kill things with this,
you know?
And I was like,
the majority of people had never hunted,
been like it like,
so you can kill a rabbit with one hour,
but if you're gonna shoot a buffalo must
like take 20 Harris.
So I was like,
at the time,
I'm like,
he must have shot it like 20 times or
something like that to kill it.
No rabbits got a pair of lungs above
loads.
Got a pair of lungs,
you put an hole through both of those
lungs.
That thing's dead in the same amount of
time.
Well now I've shot a bunch of Buffalo,
you know,
and it's just like,
that's the craziest thing,
isn't it?
It was just like it was a guy and a
magazine with a buffalo dead.
And I was like,
you can kill things that and now
unlocked this full blown hunter,
you know?
And it's just.
How did,
what was the process though?
So you got to go.
And did you take lessons?
Did you teach lessons?
Just taught myself with what year is
this?
Um,
will all 17.
I'm 28.
I wish I was 2020 nights tomorrow.
And just to heat right?
It's my birthday in Australia today,
so I'm 30,
36,
so I was 17 at the time,
so it would have been 97.
So it's almost 20 years,
almost 20 years.
You're dealing with very little internet
back then,
right?
No Internet.
No.
So even though we invented Wifi,
you guys didn't have Australia.
We probably did.
Like I said,
I was poor.
I didn't know,
but you're not.
My point is you're not getting any
information.
Teaching.
Learn.
Oh,
your mistakes.
That's what I was.
I actually was a big part of a bow
hunting for ministry for many years and
I just like if I had that when I was
coming up through boning the time,
energy and money,
that all would've saved by,
by just getting the right information
straight off the internet,
like being able to do research or,
or even us going to a club and there's,
you know,
there's 20 other guys at the club that
you could at least information out of.
I never had any of that,
but it's shit still got killed,
you know.
And that's what I always say to people.
You know,
you,
you don't need the best of everything.
If your budget can only afford you some
raker bow and some cheap arrows,
I guarantee you're still going to be
successful with that gear if you put in
the time,
there's no doubt about it.
Um,
so I,
I just had this cheapo cheap arrows,
probably didn't even wear camouflage at
the time and just went out into the
outdoors and just worked it out myself.
So,
prearranged finders,
free range finders.
So how did you decide like where to aim?
It was a guest.
It was,
you'll use,
it was,
you're using your own knowledge,
you'll use in your own skills.
That's what sucks about someone today's
technology in that,
because you lose that,
right?
You're using a range finder,
you're relying on the range finder.
I still go out to the range sometimes
where I'll just go around shooting
clumps across or whatever.
We've noted rangefinder.
Guess the distance have a shot than
ranger.
Just just so you get to learn distances
and know distances.
Um,
I'm pretty good at like 30 yards.
10 not released.
I just did.
Right.
So you do with your fingers.
When did you start using a release aid?
Um,
I don't know what year it was,
but I'm 10 years in.
Yeah,
about 10 years in where you are making
your own arrows.
Who was making it like mine?
Ours,
our team.
The arrows.
Like you'd use team Barrows,
the big tube light.
Broader.
You're saying timber,
is that what you're saying?
Timber.
Timber like would.
Yeah.
Okay.
So would arrows you making your own wood
arrows?
Yeah.
You're cutting your own dowels and the
whole deal some guys did.
You'd be able to just buy,
you know,
like 12 Dale's already spawn that old
respond tested to say 80 pounds.
And then you'd glue,
you brought it on your lap in the front
up.
You'd glue your.
Brought it on,
you glued it on?
Yeah.
Equally you brought it on.
No inserts.
And then feathers.
You'd use five inch feathers on
everything and just fingers on the
strings.
Free figures on the string.
No sites or anything like that.
It was just one sided.
It was very instinctive shooting or some
guys would use the Arrow and line up
down the road down there at the animal,
but um,
a lot of the times were effective out to
50,
60,
70 meters.
If you did enough practice,
you will still effective out to those
ranges,
but it took a lot more time.
Did you wear your arrows and where your
broadheads way arrows and broader.
So you've kind of kept him in a certain
range.
Yeah.
You keep them all identical.
You'd spin testimonial when.
Why want you put your broad it on him?
I'm good.
You could get spawned as back in those
days and you'd buy and test them and
you'd turn your shop to get to the
closest spinal.
Wouldn't be perfect on each one.
We're talking timber here and you get
your spine pretty accurate on each one.
You'd glue your.
Brought it on in that sense.
And yet.
And your,
uh,
your knock as well.
So everyone was spine the same.
Up and down.
Yeah.
Wow.
Two years.
Sam.
Pioneer.
Simple.
Oh yeah.
That's a funny thing.
Like a mountain man,
trappers and came over here on beaver
skin Qa practice a lot so I can go,
I'll go,
I'll get the height defiant there and
all site that bow in and yeah,
I can,
I'll just shoot once a week or whatever,
you know,
if I can shoot daily I will.
But with traditional gear you had to
shoot daily.
You had to have either 50 or 100 hours
every single day just just to keep the
skill level up.
Um,
and it was same shooting a bow that was
open sites,
no sites or anything like that.
And fingers.
You had to constantly shoot that boat to
be,
to be accurate.
So it's almost like throwing a rock in
that you've got to kind of have a sense
of how far it's gonna go with the amount
of effort.
Exactly.
Like thrown a rock.
Yeah.
Where to pick it up so that if you know
it's a certain distance away,
you know,
you kind of in your head know the arc of
the era.
I wouldn't get a new boss every year
because I would walk.
If you've got a new bow,
you had to start all over again,
whereas I knew the costs of that bow,
you know,
I know we're an RFL.
I know we're in our flat too.
Um,
but like I said,
you hunting,
I used to kill just as much back then as
I do today with today's technology.
But I've got to spend less time with
today's technology.
Well,
you're also in Australia,
which is very different because you were
what you were saying.
You can only eat brown.
You can hunt all year round.
You can shoot things every day.
You could shoot as many animals as you
want.
Exactly.
So you could go out and one day and
killed 12 dear.
And that's fine.
You just take them and give them your
friends.
It wouldn't if you,
you wouldn't,
unless you were just calling because the
numbers have got a badge.
I'm lucky you could,
you could,
you definitely could get and it'd be no.
And then you just have a lot of friends
and just get given to me.
He had.
Do you,
uh,
do you wind up giving a lot of your meat
away?
Heaps.
He heaps,
Yep.
Um,
I liked shooting a deer,
why they fat so before they go into the
rotc because they go into the rotc fat
and they come out looking like a grey
hound,
you know,
they just,
they just lost so much condition.
Um,
so I like to shoot a couple of days
before the Rock and um,
they've also got a lot of fat on him at
that point,
which is really good for making
sausages.
I lock my command and sausages,
I'll feel the phrase with that.
And then I've just got a list of just
family,
like put friends aside.
I've just got a list of family that will
take the meat off me,
which is really good because especially
with the da that a lot of the teammate
gets all used,
some of that big mountain bowls and
things like that.
I'm not a big fan of eight.
And then big rank bowl is,
you know,
it's just,
it's super super gaming but still
doesn't go to waste.
It's doug made or it goes back in the
mother nature right there.
And then have you ever brined them?
Like Brian,
a board had going to try my buddy,
Antonio does all that sort of stuff and
he makes those um,
like,
like big cranks,
sausages,
like a cured sausage man.
Delicious or some.
Yeah.
Apparently like
if you cook them well those old boards
are really delicious.
You just have to know how to like brine
them and cook them.
Well,
the Europeans love them.
Yeah.
So we've got our professional like pig,
his back home that hunt for human
consumption.
They make goes to humans and consumption
and the majority of it gets sent
overseas.
Like they love it and they pay big
dollars for it.
Are they,
how do they consume it?
Like about sausage or anything I
suppose.
I think the whole,
the whole animal gets shipped right,
but I wonder what they,
how they mainly eat it.
Denying him the rod is a crazy thing
man.
And most people aren't aware of,
but deer and elk and I guess stags,
a lot of those other animals,
they only have sex once a year,
so all year.
But what a crazy design like nature has
it set up.
So most of the here,
they're not even horn.
Yeah.
Then one time a year they lose their
fucking minds.
It's just crazy.
I don't drink.
That's the only thing on their mind.
Just go ballistic all day long.
Sometimes all night long.
I've never hunted deer in the Rut.
I've only hunted deer,
you know,
in Wisconsin in season.
And uh,
in Montana we hunted deer and they
weren't in the Rut,
but apparently when they're in the Rut
they lose their marbles.
But I've seen elk in the Rut and it's
the most bizarre thing kind of in
control that tongue anymore.
Just hanging out there.
Dick is flopping up and down when they
scream,
literally they have a rod going all the
time that isn't all over their chest.
They're screaming at the top of their
lungs.
It's a red stags.
I put their head between their legs,
look there in the.
That put the head between their legs.
They piss in their mouth,
they hold the bolt in the mouse Gogol it
as I tried along because my oldest
brother,
he goes all over their body.
So I could imagine doing that before
sex.
Like,
yeah,
I just got to get these done by pissing
my math is right.
I got to get ready baby.
You know how I feel about you off when
that happens.
Like they have prints in there and look,
I'm king.
Shit.
Wonder what that's all about.
Like what kind of evolutionary
advantages there to pissing in your own
mouth and spraying it up and regular we
ever done that and then they're just
like,
you know,
we're not going to write this bidding
anymore because it's just drastic.
We really don't need it.
It's not benefit.
You'd get yellow teeth.
You just lie on your shoulders with your
ass up in the air.
Just with his hold on the back of your
knees.
You've got a scoop them.
Would it pull you towards a.
it's hard,
but it's awesome to say.
I got to see the.
See if you could find that.
Is it a red deer?
Red Deer?
I think at Rusa.
Dave won't do it.
Two days.
Super mediated it.
They're the ones that roar like a lion.
Yeah.
What a weird fucking noise that is so
painful that a lot of people don't even
realize is deer in Australia.
There's six spaces in Australia and
they'll go out camping and now he that
and they've,
you know,
they're like,
oh there's a big cat in Australia,
you know,
like,
cause that's like a bit of a myth,
you know,
like there's big cats in Australia and
that's what makes it,
a lot of people think of it,
you know,
they're like,
we're scared shitless.
We couldn't sleep last night.
And I'm like,
where was,
where's the spot?
I want to know where the bodies,
because I know it's a deer.
Yeah.
Well did you hear that?
There was a rumor for like years and
years and years.
People had talked about spotting big
cats in the UK and then they found out
that there was a fucking sanctuary that
released brands.
Yes.
They just admitted to it.
Then in the nineties,
I think the late eighties or nineties,
they had released like a couple of Pumas
in the UK countryside.
So in this system is Puma Puma's?
No,
like the Sneaker Puma,
like welcome to America.
Oh,
here he is.
He's pissing.
Oh yeah,
like he's pissing in his fucking mouth.
Oh,
what in the hell?
And he loves it.
So he tried it.
That knock it,
give it a go.
Uh,
no.
He's pissing all over himself.
He doesn't even look like you're doing
it for the fuck of it.
You don't think he's in the Rut?
Not.
There's another stag there.
You should be beating the shit out of
it,
but he's a little one now.
The other stag is big.
He probably got to be real careful with
that other dude.
Are they not doing it right?
A piston right in his mouth so he can
go.
Well,
that's the thing in New Zealand,
New Zealand,
a lot of the stags or they're high
fence.
I hide it.
I don't want to piss off some Honda's at
Dewa,
but closed range is against everything
that I'm about because it's a fight
currency for what hunting is.
You get these massive big red stags and
just crazy inches on top of inches.
No one ever writes a.
This is the close range stag that I shot
in New Zealand.
No one ever writes out,
they're just like,
oh,
I've got a big red stag and I Blah Blah
Blah and so many hunters that that
aren't educated in that sense and I'm
not having a stab at them from not being
educated.
They shouldn't have to be in that sense.
Looking at that cow and all that.
That's what you can expect when you go
to New Zealand or Australia.
Now it's frigging they append animals
and they feed them high protein,
high protein food there.
They've been genetically bred.
It's just all that crazy shit that's the
fight currency of a red stag in
Australia and New Zealand,
free range,
red stags on like that.
If you should afraid Ryan's red stag
like that in Australia and New Zealand,
that's going to be the record.
That's going to be the absolute record.
That's not the true.
That's not the example of what you can
expect if you come to Australia or New
Zealand and hunt free range.
Isn't that the.
That's the difference between free range
and fair chase and these high fence
operations and it's very.
It's a very contentious argument because
a lot of people growing these white tail
deer in America and they're,
again,
they're introducing this crazy foods to
their diet and they're growing these
ridiculous racks that don't even look
like racks,
like bushes growing out of their hat and
they looked so fake.
Yeah.
I don't think they're ugly.
They are ugly joy looking at it.
I don't enjoy looking at it either.
It looks weird.
It's like some sort of a strange weird
bred dog or something like when you see
their antlers and you know there are 290
inch white tails,
like what is that?
It should because hunting should be so
natural and that's so far
from being natural,
especially when it's wildlife.
Not talking about walking around with a
stick and a string that you've carved
out of a tree yourself.
I'm talking about just a natural
environment.
Landscape and animal.
Yeah,
well animals that are living in the wild
literally no interaction with people
other than when the hunter and
especially what you're dealing with
because you're dealing with very few
hunters and like expansive areas where
very few people even go into.
Yeah.
And I don't muck around and they see you
and they're gone like that.
There's no like,
oh,
that's what that dude might have food.
Nice pocket over there.
No feed.
No.
They're like,
what?
The goal is another big issue in America
where they have these feeders and these
people,
they put a blind outside of a feeder and
the feeder goes off at a certain time
and these people sit in the blind and
wait for the feeder go off because it
near program to come towards the feet or
when it's going off and you just whack
them.
Yeah.
I'm not interested in that myself,
but I don't,
I don't frown upon it.
Like they call it biting.
Right.
Well what it is is it's like meat
acquisition.
It's not really hunting.
I mean,
it's probably better for the animal and
they have put the effort in that set
that up right and true about animals.
So it's a little bit like,
like I said,
it's not my style of hunting,
but that is the free range thing really
gets me.
I don't want to go on about it because
I'm going to upset too many people,
but I know what you're saying,
but think about what you were saying
earlier about your experience in
Montana.
You're,
you know,
11 days in 12 miles deep into the woods
by yourself.
That's the real deal.
Yeah.
I mean that is as real as it gets.
But this a thing about hunting where,
you know,
people that are really into bowhunting,
look down on people that shoot with a
rifle.
People that are really into wilderness
hunting and fair chase.
Look down on people that hunt high
fence.
And I a,
I get the arguments.
Um,
I even get the arguments for some high
fence.
Like friend of mine went to this high
fence operation and taxes and I was
like,
man,
that seems kind of crazy that these
animals are all pending.
He's like,
it's 10,000
acres.
He's like,
defense circles,
10,000
acres.
He goes,
they put their on.
Well the genetical,
their access deer and all sorts of fun.
Like Neil guy and all sorts of weird and
foreign species.
He's like,
yeah,
they have been put there,
but they're,
they're wild.
They're Roman wild.
I'm like,
Oh man,
that's a weird argument.
Then because I get it.
I mean like I'm not totally like if I
needed to hunt for meat,
it's a good way to do it.
Right.
Even if it's only a few hundred acres,
you know,
the animals are there,
you just go find them and get them for
meat.
But even if it's 10,000
acres,
at what range is it really wild?
Is it wild at 50,000
acres?
Is it wired into wild at 100,000
Like if it's fenced in,
if there's a fence anywhere.
For me it's just gotta be unfenced fence
period.
So when I went to Africa,
I've got,
I've got pretty stitched up when I went
to Africa and it was because it's just
like an operation,
it's just an income for him stitched up.
What do you mean by that?
Stitched up fucked over.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
By the outfit of there,
like he was just,
he was a con artist,
bicycling.
But um,
I don't want to go into too much detail,
but so all is supposed to go straight
into the Zimbabwean hunt.
Buffalo,
Cape Buffalo and those are dangerous.
Yeah.
Before I got there,
he took me to,
he's like call them branches or whatever
there and it's all that means is high
fence operation in the South Africa and
I understand parts of South Africa
because it has bred animals that are on
the brink of extinction and then it's
good for them because they're there now,
but it's just not familiar me that close
range hunting and everything's closed
range,
you know,
it's just,
I,
I absolutely hated it because I just
want an animal that's,
that's,
that's there naturally,
um,
or has not been genetically bred or
brought in or anything like that.
And before I got there these guys were
like,
what size buffalo do you want to shoot?
And I'm like,
well,
we'll just see what the big for the
area.
Like that's all you can do.
You can only shoot the big animal for
the area if you're after an old animal
or a trophy and we can't shoot what's
big for that area.
So usually I spend the first half of the
trip understanding what's a big animal
or an old animal for the area.
Then you'll have it for the other half
of the trip.
They like,
what size?
Buffalo do you want to shoot?
Well,
let's just say what's big for the area.
Oh No,
we'll just bring one in on truck before
you get here.
You just tell us what size you want.
We'll bring it in and release it.
What the fuck.
If I'm going to do that,
I'm going to go to a farm and say,
can I buy that cow and cut it up for me?
Right.
So,
so,
so that's a little bit on,
on lease that operation in South Africa.
I'm not saying they're all like that.
There's a lot of them like that.
There is a lot of them like that and
then I end up paying extra because I'm
like,
no,
if I've got a hunt free range,
it's the only way I'm going to hunt and
that's what I was coming here for.
100 free range a Cape Buffalo.
Then we ended up in Mozambique in
another place where we didn't say a bowl
for 10 days.
The outfitter,
he'd never been to that place or or he'd
never taken a.
have a hunters.
They are or anything like that.
And I got there and,
and the whole time he was like,
yeah,
no,
you know,
this is a real good area.
You'll tag are straight away.
You will see hundreds of buffalo every
day.
And like I said,
10 days later we hadn't even seen a
book.
So,
um,
yeah,
it was,
it's,
it's a horrible industry over there in
that sense.
It's,
it's an,
it couldn't be a blame as well.
I should've done more research on that
outfitter.
Um,
but I,
but I won that hunt for a charity
auction.
It wasn't the sort of thing that I was
like,
you know,
research and for weeks and weeks trying
to find a good outfit or to go through
and shoot a Cape Buffalo so that,
that was speed.
Unfortunately.
Yes.
There's an amazing documentary on it
from Louis Theroux who's a wildlife or
rather a documentary in from the UK.
Great Guy who,
um,
who's been on the podcast a couple times
and talked about it the first time.
But uh,
it's all about these African high fence
hunting trips.
And he was over there for a long time
and got the guy to kind of explain
exactly what's going on over there,
but it was just really bizarre.
See people,
you know they're there.
They had these lions and they had them
like right there.
I mean there were,
there was two cents of fences,
one fence and the fence right behind it
and they took a dead calf and they throw
it over the fence and then watch the
lions tear it apart.
But you're looking at the lines of
looking at the people you can go hunt
those lines.
They just,
they just let one loose,
they take it out and it's all high
fence.
But they were explaining that these
animals were on the verge of extinction
just a few decades ago.
And because of these high fence
operations,
now they're thriving.
But they're thriving in these bizarre
conditions where they're fenced in and
put them in the wallet and let them fry
out there in that area.
You know?
And then there's the poaching thing.
Poaching is a weird word for it because
a lot of those people just hunting for
food for people,
the villages that I went for because
we'd find snares and and I'd rip them
down and it wasn't,
wasn't the commercial side of poaching.
It wasn't locked out collecting the
antlers or ivy or whatever and selling
it and getting massive amounts of
dollars.
These were people that were snaring to
try and catch animals to eight.
Yeah.
If I'm gone broke and my family is
hungry,
I'm going to be the first one.
The fucking step over a fence and killed
something I can tell you right now
because I know I'm doing the right
thing.
Yeah,
so there's,
there's a funny line there where where
there's a couple of different types of
poaching,
you know,
and it's that one that's commercial and
they just slowed her and everything.
Elephants,
Lionel Hollins,
which freaking horrible.
Then there's the villager,
let's just call them locals because I
lived there.
It should be there land for people.
Exactly.
They just trying to feed their family,
man.
I come.
There's no heightened that.
No,
there's no hate night and those people
are shot.
They shoot the.
I mean it's scary shit that is dead in
South Africa,
but goddamn racism is still real strong
and a lot of areas there and those
people that are just poor black people
that live there.
That's the other thing that I hide in
the back of the hunt dude,
the man and the people that I was with
frigging rice.
It's like I come back from that trip and
talking to Kim about it and all choked
up.
I started crying.
I can't believe what those people have
to go through over there and now the
paper that will help me on the hunt.
That was small and now that will happy
the whole time and he his these paypal's
saying he would kill his own mother for
the scraps from the table.
Unlike had.
How can you frigging say that day you
say that you don't know that person?
That's how that is deeply ingrained
generation after generation.
I love the local people,
but I hated the outfit that I was with.
Wow,
that's disturbing.
And it's just sad that.
I mean,
how do you ever fix that and you know
what's really crazy is for a lot of
people that's their dream to go to
Africa and hunt the big seven,
you know,
are the big five or or there's,
there's a,
there's a movement of people acquiring
all these trophies going into Africa and
shooting all these different animals and
that's the way they do it.
They go to these outfitters that can
guarantee they can get in front of these
animals.
I think you've just got to do your
research on outfitters.
Let's run with a scumbag ones out of the
industry.
Do your research on the the outfit or
talk to other hunters that have been
there like and not just one.
Talked to six other hunters that have
been at operation demand for the numbers
or the emails for who their past clients
and go there straight doesn't have that
stray as built a hunting industry which
is tiny.
It's like,
have you ever heard about hunting in
Australia?
Like,
oh,
come to Australia and shooter,
whatever species of deer you don't
because it's not that big.
It's not like New Zealand or it's not
like Africa where they build a big
industry on it.
It's not a New Zealand gets over like A.
I don't know.
They must have the right people or
government pushing it at.
Some people are always trying out.
New Zealand's known for it.
Yeah,
beautiful country.
Awesome.
But I'm.
Australia's industry is built on having
excellent access to excellent numbers of
game.
So.
So if you book a hunt in Australia,
it's not like someone's gone,
you know,
there's a big industry here,
so let's just make up a business,
a Australian hunton safaris and let's
just get people in.
We don't have game,
but they're going to come anyway because
we're known for hunting.
You book a hunt in Australia,
I guarantee you're going to be at a
place as long as you do a little bit of
research,
but practically everywhere has big game
numbers and that's why they've started
the business on a hunting outfit because
they've got so much game and they're
like,
oh,
this is.
This could work out really good for
hunters.
There's a ton of game here come along.
So it's not like that in Africa,
you know,
a lot of those places have really got
nothing,
you know,
it's,
it's arid lands and federal is bullshit.
That hunting is going to be unreal and
it's,
and it's not at all,
which is what I experienced now,
when,
how many people who are willing to do
something like what you did in Montana
or what you and cam did in Australia was
just probably even crazier because you
didn't even bring anything with you
while you have to predicate bringing
that up.
You guys survived off the land.
I mean,
that's how many days before I can.
I,
I just want to feel something up about
that.
The helicopter pilots said you've got to
keep your gear basically to a backpack
hunt because the chopper couldn't carry
a lot of weight.
So,
um,
so then I was like,
well,
I can't pack a lot of food because I'm
already at my white limit cams already
at ease,
white limit.
Nobody.
Body islands already yet kind of be at
his white limit.
So I simply couldn't really pack food.
I couldn't pack fresh water or anything
like that.
Because the chopper actually struggled
to get off the ground once it was filled
up and so that's the story about it.
Yeah.
But those folks won't tell you that part
of the story that might be like,
oh,
we couldn't take food because the
chopper couldn't carry.
They always look at them,
didn't bring any food,
any responsible.
The Way Cam described it was like,
you guys had just made this conscious
decision to try to rough it.
Oh,
that sounds good.
That sounds better.
That stuff.
It was pretty good.
We did because I was like,
it will be part of the experience.
We'll have to catch buffalo,
will have to kill.
We're going to kill,
come on.
And uh,
and we did.
But that the buffalo that were killed
was so tough.
I think it might've been cans.
First bullet he killed was so tough that
you just chewed the meat.
You got the liquid out of it.
And then you had to take the meat out of
your mouth because you couldn't break it
down.
Yeah.
It was an old bull,
a [inaudible] book.
He told me that he was practicing with
his bow with the same piece of meat in
his mouth for 30 minutes.
That sounds about right now.
What about the liver?
I mean,
couldn't you eat the liver?
Uh,
we could off.
You'd want to check it over it.
Most of Australians strikes,
bases and game the disease.
Furry,
like that's one of the beauties in
Australia.
You can cut the raw meat off any animal
in Australia and just ate it.
You won't get sick if you do get sick,
don't blame me,
but you shouldn't get sick.
Just like drink a buffalo.
Piss.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah.
Just,
just,
just so tough.
But you didn't eat the liver room.
We didn't take it.
We should have.
Now that you've said that.
Yeah.
I love liver.
Oh yeah.
Touch.
It doesn't mean he won't eat heart.
You won't eat liver.
He's a pussy.
So he'll run like 200 miles.
But why for seven,
eight hours in a row you to live.
That's not impressive.
He just doesn't like it.
I guess.
Get a new shirt.
Dude.
I just don't understand that.
I think it tastes delicious,
but it's also really good for you.
Yeah.
No,
and it's just,
I think there's some sort of an
obligation they eat as much of the
animals.
Yeah,
I'll definitely,
I'll do it.
And actually a majestic thing like the
elk or the,
the indigenous population a lot.
But when we go out there for a hunt
because because that,
that,
that is free and a half days,
four days drive from my house to,
to go there to go hunting.
Um,
that's hot.
Take meat that far home,
you know,
w,
w what your,
your,
your vehicle,
if you're in a vehicle is already packed
up.
And if you did the chopper thing,
you wouldn't be taking any out.
You'd have to donate it all to the
indigenous.
So when we go out for a hunt,
I love it because we're shooting balls
and cutting up meat and how do they cook
it?
No different than any of us were.
So how the fuck do they chew through
that thing?
If,
if they're out on,
um,
if they're out of community,
which is like a,
like an outstation there on the land.
You know,
they're,
they're out on the land.
Um,
most indigenous cook just by putting the
meat straight in the fire,
you know,
still very traditional way.
They'd just put the meat.
So like if I killed a wallaby or
kangaroo,
um,
they,
they wouldn't get it,
they wouldn't scan it or anything that
front straightened the fire like that
and the skin's like a,
what would we wrap meat in,
like our foil or something like that and
cook it in the fire like that.
The skin just acts like that and it
gives me a lot of flavor and everything
like that.
It's just why do we have to complicate
things so much?
Oh,
let's put some air foil around it.
Let's put some spices in there and stuff
like that because it tastes better.
Taste better because we're so used to
doing that Monday.
If you'd never done that,
if we'd never ever done that meat with
just taste good.
Just how it is implying maybe or they
figured out it tastes better
with salt and pepper and garlic salt.
Definitely.
Right.
So there's like some spice company
that's going to go through a indigenous
Australia now given them more spices so
that they get used to it and they'll get
addicted sales go up.
Yeah.
So they throw it on the fire without
gutting it at all.
And then did they eat the guts?
The guts,
just the meat and everything around it
that would probably eat the organs and
things.
Same with fish,
just fried fish.
Straight on the fire.
I've done that plenty of times so it's
good.
Good.
Eaten like that.
And so it won't be scaled.
And the scales act is like the
protective barrier between the ashes and
everything.
Get into the good meat and cooking the
fish.
Better skills in all the flavor and
taste and the juices.
Once the fish is cooked then you just
sort of watching the scale is often as
beautiful,
clean,
flush right there,
Huh?
Hm.
That's interesting.
I've never cooked anything on ashes like
flat on Ashley will before.
Okay.
Yeah.
You're going to need like a month in
Australia.
A month.
Once a month.
Oh a month.
A new animal that big camp.
And I was like,
I don't know off.
And he's like,
what's a Dane?
18?
That's how I was like eight,
eight,
seven,
nine,
six,
16.
You guys,
you have an interesting way of saying
words.
Yeah,
it's proper English.
That's what I think it is.
It's Australian English.
Yeah.
It's weird because you free if you
didn't know Australians.
You guys sound like you're kind of
English.
Really?
Yeah.
Well there's like South African.
That's very cool.
Well,
we're close,
right?
They only have a few words they say
different than us.
Like a boat.
I,
yeah,
a minute.
We're going to do a to around about Las
Vegas,
but they're polite.
So they're the most polite people ever.
Canadians,
Australians.
They're,
they're pretty polite too.
But Canadians are like for North
America,
they're the fucking kings,
the king.
Kings of politeness.
But um,
so back to this crazy that you did with
Kim,
if you couldn't eat the buffalo,
how the fuck did you guys,
I mean you kind of just chew it up and
you'd fall into softer,
softer spots.
And you guys lived off for that.
Yeah,
that Monday for the whole trip.
And it's a bear Monday.
Yeah.
Real good fish.
Like probably the best fish in the
world.
Oh really?
Yeah.
How do you catch that?
Louis?
We took little fishing rods in and we
took a couple of Lewis.
Is it a fresh water or salt water fish?
They both.
Yep.
Where'd you guys catch them?
Uh,
we'll,
we'll can't throw it on the coast.
And um,
it,
it was horrible in a sense.
It was good,
but it was horrible.
It was nice because you'd get a window
each night but it was horrible because
you'll need a lot of water in a river
mouth.
And the mosquitoes were like,
as soon as it started getting dark
mosquitoes would be impolite.
But coalitions like your arms would go,
black comedy mosquitoes if you didn't
put something on.
Like I said,
we had to get a lot so I only had one
tiny little tube of like an insect
repellent.
That's Ms Dot k dot that brutal
that you'd put that,
you know.
And they'd stay off for like two
minutes.
Cam didn't even have a net.
So I would sleep.
I had a hammock and I'd sleep in a
hammock and I had a net of me,
but my back would just get smashed by
mosquitoes come back.
She is lying against the net.
No mattress or anything.
I'd wake up in the morning just
agonizing,
wanting to scratch and and cam was
assignment.
I know net at all.
They'll just Ashley's face all night.
Yeah.
How do you,
you've highs not swell,
shut and Hud and so can you cover stuff
up with or anything you could if you
went to that effort?
I would have done it.
Yeah,
you would have done a fucking pussy.
Mosquitoes now it's just like that just
dealt with it.
Yeah.
You know,
it's not even part of the thought
process in a sense when you're on a hunt
like that because it's just,
you just want to be a part of the hunt,
you know,
and that's a part of the hunt.
It's a miserable part of the hunt,
but that's just the part of the.
I don't even like a fly buzzing around
my head when I'm practicing my backyard.
Really?
Flaws twice will be trading in the
corner of my eye and I'll just hold a
conversation and people will be like,
oh,
I can't talk to you anymore.
I'm like,
what?
What's up?
You know?
And there's,
he's like,
there's a fucking fly fucking in the
corner of your mouth.
Like,
can you show it?
And I'm so used to it.
Yeah.
How many days did you guys do that,
hon?
I'm must've been eight.
I think it was eight in the end.
Now when you decided to climb into that
water to cool off,
he didn't consider the possibility that
there was in there?
Yeah,
the water was muddy and it's hard to
tell if it's muddy because there's a big
salt water crocodile stirring it up or
because a buffalo gun wallow in every
bit of water there is.
So um,
we walk the edge and you look for
crocodiles slides.
Crock slides doesn't mean there's no
crocs there if there's no crock slides.
But we walk the edge and there was no
crocs slides now.
And Alan's a local.
He's a teacher up in the indigenous
community there.
He knows the ward is pretty well,
you can't,
it's hard to tell if a crux moved in
there over the season or,
or anything like that.
But we walk the edge and you just sat
desperate to get wet.
Like Cam was even to the point where
he's like,
can we just die?
I'd,
I'd actually prefer to cool off and then
die.
Let's just do it.
And then the other side like you're
desperate get sat heart that you're just
desperate.
And in a sense,
since I think it was essential to get in
the water at that point to get
rehydrated,
you know,
just for skin intake and um,
the water was the same temperature as
outside.
Like you'd go into the water and you
couldn't feel that you'll go and into
liquid because the water's at hot as
well.
It's just been boiling in the sun.
But the light in there and just chill
out in the mud and every now and then
you'd,
it's all muddy.
Bought them every now and then you'd
sort of pushed them out and release some
cooler waters that sort of hadn't been
coupla aside and be like,
oh ha ha,
that's what I made you.
You really have to go through that shit
to appreciate things in life and one of
those things that are just appreciate
it.
And
life was pushing for the modern,
getting a little bit cooler water,
you know,
I was like,
Oh,
this is paradise.
And then two seconds later you're like,
oh,
this is uncomfortable as shit,
you know?
Well,
the fact that people live that way and
struggled through those kinds of
environments and those kinds of
temperatures for untold years.
Yep.
Before they ever figured out ice a
frigerator Eskimo air conditioning,
not eskimos.
That'd be like hate baby hate.
Yeah.
That's another extreme.
Have you ever seen when people go up
there and go hunting and like new Nevada
go a hunting for a fucking big hairy
things?
What's the big hairy things?
Ox Muskox,
muskox things.
It looks like a star wars animal.
Yeah,
it does.
Yeah.
It doesn't even look real time.
Enroll in and get warm.
Yeah.
I mean,
I've seen those things and you just go
with that.
Okay,
so people live up there and they have
those things and then they live down
where you are and they hope for cool
mud.
Those buffalo that we hunt,
it'll be like,
you'll think,
ah,
that's not going to be anything out any
way that I.
it's stinking hot.
Everything will be in the shade under a
tree or tucked under a riverbank or
something like that.
Those buffalo as black as I will be
standing out in the open,
complete son,
just graze and nothing even bothering
her,
bombarding them.
Now,
most people listening to this have no
idea what a scrub bull is.
They hear the term spread bold.
They don't know what it means,
but it's a domestic domestic,
a domestic cow that's bald.
I have a many,
many centuries in Australia.
They've all Lena bread and it's a pretty
crazy looking.
That's the scrub bowl.
Cool.
That thing,
that's like a Brahmin there,
so he's.
He's a bit of a breed bull.
Looking back on that thing,
what a strange hump and all it is is
that bold would be living in country
where a lot of different artists,
grable's haven't come through,
so it's still a fully wild bull,
but it is nice to grab a scrap that one
right next to it,
jamie with the crazy horns.
Yeah.
He's a big boy.
Whoa.
That's scrub bill too.
That's man.
That's in America.
Look at the trees in the back.
Those are married.
Is that it says Canada.
Oh,
Canada.
What is that?
Same thing right now.
They can't even come over here unless we
let them and they don't let us over
here.
Over there.
If you've got a drunk driving
conviction.
So they have troubles in Canada.
That's weird.
I've never seen that before.
I thought that was an Australian thing.
What does that one down there?
These people would just fucking shooting
their cows.
Yeah,
he'd be scrabbling.
Wow.
What a Brahmin.
Okay,
so that's a buffalo.
That's not scalable.
That's a big water buffalo at a crazy
thing.
That is.
So that is something from Asia,
Europe from Asia.
Where is that?
That's a water buffalo.
Just just call the water buffalo.
Yep.
So there's a Cape Buffalo that are from
Africa.
What does that one?
Not the lower left corner,
but the one right next to a jamie?
Yeah.
What is that?
What the.
Is that a good scrub?
Say,
Oh look how the color is very in that
because they real interbred animal,
you know.
And that's why bread with other,
other variety of cattle.
Hm.
Now the mate value is not as good as the
breeding values.
Not as good because the visitors there,
bit of this and they're a bit of that
there a bit of everything.
It's like a dog,
you know,
you bought a purebred dog or you buy a
mango,
which is,
you know,
a couple of different species in one.
What has the big value is the purebred
right and assignment these cattle.
So that.
The big issue with the cattle industry,
especially in these northern parts of
Australia,
is these.
They scrubbed bulls.
These feral cattle don't have any
respect for fences.
I would just walk straight through a
fence into a farmer's prize cattle and
stopped breeding with these prized
cattle.
And then all those carbs that he gets on
the purebred cattle anymore,
so it's really bad for the industry.
So they knock the fence down,
some composting.
That's pretty much it.
And a big issue.
What would happen in America if those
cows that I saw wandering around,
if they were allowed to have balls and
yeah,
free day out there,
they'd eventually become just like that,
that that's right.
So they just didn't uncheck species of
animal in Australia at the scrub and uh,
they just free to come and go wherever
they want.
So.
So a lot of farmers really pushed to
shoot them out or get them cold or ran
off or off their property.
I'd say unbelievably aggressive.
Super aggressive.
More aggressive than a buffalo.
Yep.
Wow.
Why underwater?
Because they're pissed off because they
were in a bread.
Really?
Yeah.
They know they just a cranky animal.
We've also got bulls are pretty fucking
aggressive.
I mean,
obviously the bulls,
I'm talking like bull cows that we have
in America.
That's why people ride them.
They only get eight seconds if they're
lucky.
Yeah.
They're trying to be like that.
They're right.
I don't know,
just natural,
naturally pissed off.
It's a good question because like when
you see like bull fighters,
are those bowls trained to try to fuck
up the matador?
I mean,
I don't know.
Ask Rob.
We'll just do that shit off their own
back.
I can tell you now that's really
aggressive.
We've got bank Tang Bulls as well.
I've heard of those cats.
Solly cattle.
What's a bank?
Tang?
What does it look like?
A Jeremy will bring on up.
No Daddy.
Say it.
Bank Tang or spell?
Excuse me?
Um,
they,
I n j.
t a n g a bank.
I believe you've been wanting an ounce.
One word.
One would bang Tang.
So back home that night eve lanes,
they nearly extinct so that,
that'd be,
that'd be back home.
Okay.
So Asia in Indonesia,
they're almost extinct,
but America or rather Australia there
where they run wild and they like a
velvet skin cattle yet I run wild
elephant skin.
Skin man.
They are a beautiful creature.
What a weird looking kel.
That's a good creature
type in.
I'm good hand outback experience.
That's one of my buddies that God's
there for anyone interested and uh,
he's got access to these bank Tang on
some of the most beautiful country that
you've ever seen.
Like in northern Australia.
Yeah.
Bring up something from Carl's.
They lucky they got a bank there.
He's an old one.
See that bolt's going across the head.
It looks like their skin is suede.
Yeah.
And they will charge on movement real
out of those all bulls.
If they say movement vow that I would
prefer to come at you then turn away
because there's a risk in 10 in that
back to you if you get within a certain
distance and um,
is called lay with a Yeti hat on.
Hey,
I'm,
I shot one last year or the year before
we've called and it comes straight at us
and call us carrying a big gun lock.
I showed up with a bow and calo lifted
up the gun and he shot this bank tank as
it was charged and it literally dropped
nine feet from Carl.
Like it just looked straight at him and
just hammered straight out of him.
I'll go to a second shot off as it was
running,
actually broke its leg,
which made it stumble and then it just
comes straight back up and kept coming
into colony,
pulled the gun up and he showed it
straight between the eyes.
It was an amazing shot.
Yeah,
don't go by the way that man that I will
tell you up.
They're scary.
Credo.
What a weird as well.
I guess it's because you fucking shot
over the bow and Arrow to be upset with
you.
Probably.
I mean it's,
it seems like a crazy idea to shoot one
of those things by yourself though.
Like you almost have to have a rifle
backup.
Yeah.
But if that's the case,
why hunt with a bow?
Exactly.
You have a rifle backup.
She's probably time that I did with
buffalo was with a gun the very first
time I went was a good move.
No,
I had the bug.
My buddy had the gum.
Oh yeah.
My buddy iron grant.
He's a really good shot too,
so I was like,
hey,
you want to come on this trip with me
would be good.
You can shoot one,
but in that case,
like why not just hunt with a rifle
because you're not going to kill it with
a bow.
That quick might.
You can.
You can 95 percent of the time you can
have five percent of motherfucker.
So I shot three bulls on that trip.
I got three complete postures with and
I've got three bulls that died.
Right?
In view.
I didn't have a single issue,
you know,
but what the rifle Donnie's is that got
you to go to places that usually
wouldn't like that bulls out in the
open.
And if you didn't have a rifle backup
behind you,
you probably wouldn't proceed out there
and be like,
there's no trees around the client.
I'm going to shoot that bowl.
But when you've got a rifle,
it makes you a little bit game of like,
you know,
obviously my buddy Aaron's on,
he's just waiting for shit to go south
and he's gonna pull a gun off and give
it one that didn't happen.
Oh Man.
I have a trip since I've never hunted
with a rifle backup.
But you've got to know your,
you've got to know your boundaries.
You know I,
there's a big line bull out there.
There's no trees.
He's right out in the open.
You take a shot at him.
He was the first thing he looks.
He looks at,
he's going to clean you up and I do it.
You know that.
That's,
that thing happens.
So fuck that.
That seems ridiculous that you'll come
in and do it.
No,
no,
no.
You're not allowed to.
When they're laughing,
that doesn't.
What?
What's the,
the least likely to kill you if you
shoot it in Buffalo,
buffalo hunting.
Really?
No,
no,
hell no.
The least likely to kill you.
A freaking rabbit.
Rabbit.
You're good.
Yeah.
Right.
Kinda out there.
Was It on a rabbit?
Oh,
awesome.
Well,
you have to kill a lot of them.
Don't show you.
They're overpopulated,
already popping.
You got a skewer.
Uhm,
you know,
get as many as you want.
It's a funny thing.
As big as that animal is,
you know,
and,
and may say,
know your boundaries.
If you do the right shot on that animal,
that's the first thing.
You know,
you've got to make sure that shots right
angles,
right?
You know,
you're confident with your bow.
You put that shot into the,
to the right spot.
Then there's no risk because that,
that,
that animal is dead before it gets to
you staying still off the shop.
You know,
like I said,
I'm not the person to shoot something
like.
Yes,
yes,
I shot it.
I'm not like that.
I think it's a little bit disrespectful
even,
but it's also,
it's also a dangerous and it's on
peaceful for the animal because you do
that.
It gives the animal and an adrenaline
boost animals within an adrenaline
boost.
Man,
that's,
that's a hill reckoning,
you know,
buffalo or Buffalo,
that will carry them.
It might make,
um,
it might make their death longer
because,
you know,
they're filled with adrenaline and stuff
like that.
You shoot an animal and you be quiet.
You put the shot in the right spot.
It's so peaceful.
I've actually shot things and they'd
been like,
what was that?
Put their head down and stop fading
again and toppled over why they fade and
I don't even know their hit.
That's one of the beauties about Boeing
at tasteful and that's why you don't
carry on like a frigging jerk.
Why don't you shoot something,
you know,
just quiet,
nice and humble.
The animal dies peacefully.
That's what every Honda should drive
for.
Yeah.
It's um,
also you'd have to have the proper
equipment,
right?
If you're going to penetrate the side of
a buffalo,
you have to very strong bow and heavy
arrows.
Yeah.
Um,
I like that because you can't tell if
you're going to hit a rebound.
The yes and all the way out.
And we've,
my setup like I mostly shoot 70 pounds
when I'm shooting idea at the moment and
that heavy Arrow and a solid one piece.
It's just a solid piece of steel to
blade.
Broaden those vpa.
Broader Shane Dorian shoot some as well.
Blog vantage point,
audrey.
It's 150 grains.
That's a heavy Bronto.
Yeah.
Then it's got a decent insert behind it,
like 92 grain insert and then I'm a nice
heavy shaft.
And then let's just talk about the ID,
Pam.
We've got 80 pounds.
I can find a rib on the way on the
buffalo and I can find a Freebie on the
way out.
And the arrows still just going to bus
straight through there.
Now how have you used the Arrow?
It's about.
Well it depends what I'm shooting,
but with the IED pan I'm shooting sit
670 grinds.
Wow.
Yeah.
And with the 70 pound boat it's not much
different.
It's about 620 grinds,
670 grains is really haven't.
But that Mike's a quiet bio and it makes
a punch when it hits animals.
And how many feet per second?
Again,
none of that don't.
I don't even get into that technical
shit.
Do you,
uh,
do tapes or do you do it by,
by eye and then write it on the tape?
Not.
I've got site tapes.
So how do you calculate your site tapes?
Um,
if you don't.
Well I've got the tiger or option
archery now and it's a,
the option five option six site.
It's got an adjustable pin.
Oh,
you've got all your fixed pins that you
flip in place now if that one I'll just
shoot my 20 and actually shoot all my
pins in the 50 and then I match it up
with the site type and then I stick that
on the go at the 20 minute mark.
So then when I pull up multiple pin out
of the way,
I've just got the single pin that winds
up and down that day mark.
Obviously I shoot it and check it,
which I have and it's spot on.
It's perfect.
Okay.
So you don't do anything like archers
advantage,
do it through a computer calculation.
It's interesting.
I just love shooting it all myself.
It's so helpful.
We'll move each pin for that shot.
So I'll shoot and um,
you know,
zero to 20 the first pin and then I'll
walk back the 30 and I'll shoot and I'll
just to keep,
keep shooting and adjusting that,
you know,
in tiny little increments if I have to.
Do you have like a range at your house
that you do all this stuff?
I'd do it all up in the farm.
You know,
I sent you those photos at the time of
that cabin that I built.
That's amazing.
Cabins.
So incredible.
I just got a crazy.
I can shoot as far as I like.
Well,
we're.
We're almost done here,
but let me,
let me tell you people about your
photography too,
because you take some incredible
photography when you're out and where
you have this,
like a book that you made of your
photography that I got a chance to look
at.
Yeah,
it did.
I have to bring that along.
Did I?
That's cool.
Somewhere and brought it back.
Brought it to bear camp,
but also you sent me to your website too
and I got a chance to look at some of
the photos that you have up.
Yep.
You take some amazing pictures.
I love it.
That's the other thing that I'll carry
with me.
Pack and paypal.
People Freak because it's the canon five
d mark three.
It's an external Flash Bay batteries at
why's the Tundra there?
How much does it weigh?
Not a ton,
but 20 pounds.
It have to be.
Is that your camera?
Can I hold it then at a flash,
like a big full size external flash to
that and batteries.
That's a lot in the pack.
It's just like it's probably 10 pounds.
Right.
The end result of that is that's how you
get those,
those crazy photos.
Wow.
Do you carry a tripod as well?
Yeah,
I carry a little tripod.
Yeah.
Wow.
Same tripod.
Photography.
You know,
people can actually go to first man
image,
which is a [inaudible] instagram account
that I've got.
God that pictures incredible and there's
a heap of pitches like that on this
picture is from how long ago?
That's all Idaho.
That's just the other day yesterday,
one day ago now.
How do you take this photo,
like where you see all those stars?
Is it just setting the aperture
correctly yet sitting aperture
correctly?
The Lens that I use,
it's a,
it's a stigma outlands.
It's the 20 Mil lens and the f stop on
that Lens is only like one point four.
Like that's super,
Super Low,
right?
What does that mean?
I don't know shit about photography,
like your.
I've been closed up and then United
States,
I say an f four,
right.
Your eyes really closed up and,
and uh,
f one point four would be like that.
But imagine how much more light and
everything he could get in.
That's probably bicycle I have explained
in it.
And then,
um,
I will,
I'll,
I'll set the camera up.
It's got to be on a tripod because
that's like a,
a.
Jamie's got to explain.
Hey,
I've got an f number.
Wikipedia.
It's like exponentially larger.
Every time you drop in a,
an increment,
it gets exponentially larger.
And then as you go higher and f stops,
it'll get smaller.
Okay.
There you go.
So self taught,
this is all luck.
I just self taught so I'm not really
into the lingo,
but they go,
I'll go.
So the same thing is with bowhunting.
You're self taught with photographers as
well.
That's what happens when you live out in
the jungle.
Fucking bank tanks.
Exactly.
Wild snakes and decided that that's
obviously set up on a tripod and it's
about a 15 second exposure.
So you know that it's open for 15
seconds and the guy was in a lot more
like,
damn,
that Montana law is beautiful.
How many days ago was that from Jamie?
Six days ago.
That's not as your.
This is what a amazing fisher.
And it's your tent and your tent looks
like.
Did you have like a headlamp inside the
tent or something?
That tiny little headlamp.
So you left that on,
left that on,
and then set the camera up and the stars
man.
So that's what you're seeing every night
while you were camping up there every
night until the moon.
Come in,
man.
That's fucking pretty.
I love moonless nights.
Just just for that to the best.
Yeah.
It's nothing like that,
that view of the milky ways and saying,
hey,
if he can join me,
if you go back a little bit and you'll
see you'll see some dead buffalo
pitchers.
And uh,
I ran that time.
I was taking some shots when I was in
Arnhem land.
And because there's no artificial,
there's no,
no light pollution.
Anyway,
up to the stars with the knife at all.
I like the,
the,
the aperture and everything can come
back so much further on those nights
because it's just,
even with the human eye,
it's just crazy.
Wow.
Yeah.
It's just lit up like you could actually
walk around in the dark,
just lit off the Milky Way.
No Moon.
You could walk around in the dark up
there just because there's so many more
stars that you can see.
It's crazy and you always come up to it.
There's the benefit of bonding people or
the outdoors.
Don't even get into Boeing.
Just go camping in that door's Nah,
you might have to go off a little bit.
That's pretty cool though.
That was the camp that I had go up or
down.
I'm older.
Older.
That's a pretty good one.
Yeah.
Oh,
oh my God.
It's like you're in a spaceship.
Yeah.
I mean there really is like a spaceship.
So yeah,
if anyone's,
if any listeners are into the outdoors
and not necessarily kill him because
obviously Adam Green tree,
Boeing's got a lot of um,
harvest kilz on it.
Um,
if you just end up photography,
just go to first man image.
And the image shows me an image,
Adam.
Oh,
I had him again.
How many people didn't get that but in
me.
And I'm like,
I just told one of the latest.
Didn't get it.
First man.
Image on what?
On instagram.
Instagram.
Yeah.
Dispel it in some sort of weird
Australian way.
First.man
dot image.
Is that what it is?
I think so.
So it's Adam.green,
tree dot bowhunter.
If you're interested in looking at dead
animals and stars and if you just want
photography first,
man,
first.man
dot image.
And you're a pussy if you dare you
first.man.ms
dot.
Oh yeah man.
God Damn.
He takes some pretty pictures.
Dude.
That's amazing that you're self taught.
I've been thinking about it lately that
I need to get into photography at least
somewhat to just take pictures with your
iphone.
I just.
That's the best when you do so much.
It's the best way to capture a memory
because I can look back on the photos
now and go,
that's right.
How cool is that?
Or whatever.
Sometimes I do so much and I get carried
away with doing so much hunting that
it's lucky if I didn't take a photo,
I'd actually forget that moment because
there's so much happening.
So.
And I just love showing it to my kids
and friends and people that are
interested in it.
It's a really good promotion for the
sport.
You know,
I used to think,
um,
do you call hunting and sport a dying?
I hate that word,
but you just used it.
I know,
yeah.
It's a common word that correct me.
Yeah.
I just,
uh,
I feel like there's a word for it,
like natural life,
like dismantle part of me or discipline.
I think discipline is a better word for.
I hear the sport,
like,
you know,
welcome to the sport.
Glad you're getting involved in the
sport.
And I'm like,
oh.
So like,
or we could call it a pause.
Time of cold pastime doesn't seem
significant enough.
It doesn't.
Yeah.
It seems like it's not.
I mean,
you shoot an elk,
is that a pastime?
No,
it's way more than that.
It's like,
yeah,
a life experience.
Who I am,
what we are,
and then some.
Right?
Yeah.
So you know,
if you're getting into the sport,
I'm not going to say it.
If you're getting into bow hunting,
I guarantee you wish you found that 20
years ago.
Bowhunting.
Yeah,
I wouldn't.
You know what,
I'm happy I found it when I found of
course so busy.
Always the height,
the ID or if someone's going to go
through life and never find this
connection and that's the big push for
me to promote bowhunting.
I've written for the Australian outdoor
magazines for like 12 years now and,
and a lot of people think it's like a
self promotion.
Like I don't care.
I don't care if I didn't have any views
at all.
As long as people were getting a that
exposure,
I was putting that out there for people
to go,
oh,
I should try this.
It looks cool.
This dude's really enjoying it.
Here's the benefits in it and going and
doing it because it drives me nuts.
Just thinking that someone should have
that connection.
They just don't know it yet because a
lot of the guys,
especially the older guys that I've
introduced to bowhunting have always
been like,
man,
I would've never known about this
before,
and they've just got now I can't imagine
them as anything else,
but hunters because they just thrive on
it that much and has done so much for
their lives or just the outdoors.
Some guys that are gonna get into it,
try and been like,
it's not for me,
but I really love camp and being out
there in the wilderness and even
archery.
Yeah,
definitely shooting a target for me is
like a form of therapy.
So Zen moment.
Yeah.
There's so much concentration going on
that it cleanses your mind and if I can
shoot bows for an hour every day,
man,
it just,
uh,
it,
it alleviates stress and some sort of a
strange like,
you know,
for lack of a better word.
Zen.
Yeah.
Well it might be the best word for it
actually.
You were talking about earlier,
like going out to the wilderness,
no technology or anything like that.
What it does,
the demand is,
it frees the mind,
but like it's like it resets me.
It's like hitting the reset button.
That's all good.
It's all fresh now.
You know,
it's just gives you time to think,
you know.
Yeah.
And even
people that aren't into hunting,
I totally understand that.
And like I said,
um,
I've been really paying attention a lot
to people that do these longterm hikes
and also overlanding people that just go
on these crazy adventures,
like they get off the beaten path and
they develop these vehicles that are
capable of driving over adverse
conditions and they just figured out a
way to live out there in the desert or
out in there.
The mountains.
It's fascinating to me because there's a
longing I think that people have to get
away from the concrete to get away from
the electricity and to just feel the
stillness of the actual world
uninhibited,
unencumbered,
and an an uncompressed by,
by civilization and buildings and
language.
And when you're out there,
man,
I don't,
I've never done what you've done,
but when you're out there for 11 days,
you don't even talk to anybody for 11
days
this side,
this trip I did because I had internet
service at the top or a reception and I
kept doing this,
uh,
insta stories,
you know.
Yeah.
Those were great.
By the way.
I,
you'll watch,
watch all that.
I wish you saved them though.
Story disappear.
Absolutely sucks.
You're not hoyt.
Need to do.
If you listen to next year,
send a photographer out or,
or a film did and we'll film the whole
thing.
But then some dude's going to be talking
to you.
I'm not playing.
That's the rules.
He can't talk.
He's got to have your campsite.
And she jump in if a bears is trying to
eat healthy.
But um,
so that sucked.
But,
um,
I've had trips where you don't talk to
people for days and days on end and just
the fact of a common back into
civilization and opening your mouth
feels weird.
It feels absolutely we'd even,
when you're talking up there,
you're talking about.
No,
that's right.
Yeah,
yeah,
I mean you're talking to the phone,
you're like,
Hey,
I'm up here.
I just told myself every now and then
you do you seriously every now and then
you'd be like,
Nah,
you just.
Then you think like,
what did I say that out loud?
Because you haven't interacted with
anyone for so long.
It would be something like,
oh,
you fell over you frigging dummy,
which happened a few times.
You definitely don't want to break a leg
up there.
You'd be screwed.
You bring a satellite phone.
Yeah,
I had a satellite phone.
Yup.
So in case shit goes bad.
Yeah,
and it's got an SOS button built into it
that I even say it to Kim,
my wife,
you know,
like you don't see that side of things,
but I do actually take precautions to
take us sat phone.
That's it.
And a time as this.
There's,
there's management within within it,
but you.
But you just don't see it.
Listened to.
There's a very small handful of people,
even in the hunting world that are doing
what you're doing,
that are taking those kinds of crazy
adventures and just diving into it.
It's awesome,
man.
I was.
I was really blown away by those
instagram stories and following you
every day.
I follow you several times a day I would
go in and check in on it,
make sure everything's going on,
blah,
blah.
So awesome.
Yeah.
Good.
That's good to say.
You log in you.
Unless shit probably like things more.
I just look at him.
I enjoy them.
I need to hit that little heart button.
People love you when you hit that
heartbeat.
Yeah,
for sure.
Alright,
I'll give you a little louder.
Louder.
You need to do one of them tripped.
Yes you do.
I'm telling you you'll friggen five on a
dude.
It's interesting.
I don't think I didn't do that.
You would get love it.
Ah,
I don't mind.
I would like to go and do like a deep
backpack trip solo.
I don't know about all that.
I don't want anybody finding my sneakers
and you know what I'm saying?
Fuck still inside from marks all over
it.
Don't be so ironic or eaten by the
wolves that I love so much.
Yeah,
that's,
that's funny.
Like that.
Well,
Hey Brian,
thank you very much for doing this.
Who's on the show?
Appreciate it.
It's always cool hanging out with you
and I'm glad we got a chance to do this.
Awesome.
And uh,
again,
Adam.green,
tree dot bowhunter on instagram as well.
Where else can people get you first.man
dot image on instagram or you can find
both of those on facebook as well.
And you have a website.
No website,
no website,
no Weirdos.
Thank you know Weirdos.
All right folks,
thank you very much.
See you soon.
Bye.
That's great.