Can we go for three to Henry Rollins?
Ladies and gentlemen,
how are you fella?
I'm better now being here with you.
I'm better now that you're here.
We were just talking about a show that
you've got you and Ted nugent.
Apparently someone.
Did someone.
Did you pitch it?
Who pitched the show?
It was an idea that uh,
my manager,
Heidi and I came up with,
well mostly Heidi.
It was like,
it was called basically Henry and uh,
you put me and someone I might have some
disagreements with or a few agreements
with and we just go somewhere and we
weigh in with a camera following us and
we're thinking what it'll be like a six
part mini series like me and plus six
interesting people.
And one of the names that came up with
Ted nugent because I,
I'm a fan of his music,
I think is one of the best guitar
players I've ever seen yet.
He and I would probably disagree on one
or a few topics.
And so we actually picked,
pitched it to Ted who said he loved the
idea,
but he said,
I got to go.
I'm busy with a,
he had a ton of tour dates.
I think he's on now,
but he said I want to talk to henry to
thank him for thinking of me.
Okay.
And so ted called like on my phone in
the office,
I guess he got my number from the powers
that be and suddenly it's,
it's Ted on my phone.
I'm at my desk like,
okay,
this is surreal.
And we talked for a few minutes and he
said,
uh,
you know,
like,
what do you think?
I'm a bad guy.
I'm like,
no,
I just,
some of the things you say,
I just kind of takes my breath away.
And then we quickly got on the topic of
music.
He said,
you like all that old Detroit music?
I go,
yeah man,
I mean you,
Mitch Ryder the stooges,
Mc five.
I mean it's kind of the best.
Some of the best music I've ever heard.
I mean,
as far I asked him,
I go,
what is it?
Is something in the water?
What is it with you,
Michigan guys?
And Guitar Tone.
Like no one gets tone like you,
Ron,
Ashton stooges,
Fred Sonic,
Smith,
MC five.
I go,
you guys,
I mean,
you're so good.
And he said,
you gotta we gotta hang out some time
and we'll just talk about music.
I want,
I'll do that with you.
So I'll be taking notes.
And he was just telling me,
you know,
like,
yeah,
he used to hang out at the MC five house
and go see the stooges and I'm like,
you're killing me because this is like,
you know,
I,
that would have been heaven for me to
see those bands like back in 1969 or
whatever.
Did you.
When did you know him?
Did you know him back in the day?
Only recently as a punter.
I would go see him like in high school
in the 18 seventies to Neil Carter
administration.
I'd go see him at play in my local arena
in Washington dc in a place called the
capital center in Largo,
Maryland.
And he was as good as rock'n'roll gets.
I mean it was,
I saw the,
the double life Gonzo lineup and like,
forget it.
It was like two and a half hours of just
getting beat up by music.
It was fantastic and to this day it's
still a high watermark as far as gigs
and in the nineties I met him on
politically incorrect Bill Maher and I
said,
hey man,
I'm a big fan,
and he gave me a bowhunting catalog.
I'm like,
well,
you know,
for his whack master,
you get the croquet mallet and the.
Anyway,
I kept it,
I tell them a fan and then I met him
years later and I did this radio show
like St Patrick's Day,
1997 to Kressley promote my next record
and I said we met years ago and we got
to talking for like a couple of hours
and we,
it was just about music and I played him
some of my new record which you really
liked and he,
between the commercial breaks he was
like playing riffs for me.
We had little headphone amp and he was
sitting across from me on a stool
playing and I'm like,
this is pretty cool.
And so that's the kind of relationship I
have with him where I,
you know,
you read some of the things he says,
you're like,
okay,
that's really hard to take and but those
records are,
they're just so good to me.
And I saw him play in 2000 opening for
kiss 2001 somewhere in there.
And he was great.
Great.
The tone,
the playing just fantastic.
And so he's just an interesting,
a bunch of guys,
you know what I mean?
Cause like he can finish a sentence.
He's not,
he's not,
he's not stupid.
He's hilarious.
He has a steel trap memory.
But then he'll just say,
you know,
the Obama's as subhuman,
Hmong girl,
like,
man,
you don't need to talk like that because
there's people you will inspire to punch
some black guy in the parking lot for no
reason.
Like something bad could happen if you
talk like that to the millions of people
who love you.
Like someone will get that message and
they'll go south with it.
And when you're in that position,
I don't believe in self censorship,
but I think you should be careful of
what you say.
I think there's some merit in having
some control of yourself.
And so I don't completely understand the
guy,
this currency and outrageousness that's
what it is.
And you cash in by being the God that
says things he can't.
I can't believe what he just said.
And then you become the guy that goes
places that says things that no one can
believe that you're saying.
You know,
I,
I know that there's some people that's
how they get their next book deal or
whatever,
you know,
for myself,
I would never want to trade in that
because my,
my reality coming up through punk rock
and all of that is very,
very immediate in that I don't say
anything about anybody without expecting
them to hear it.
And with me turning the next corner,
like going to my car in your parking lot
and having that
person waiting for me at the car saying,
hey,
you said this.
And having the meal to hold it up on a
tablet and say.
And so I watch what I say because in my
mind I answer,
I will have to answer to all of it.
And so I would never say something where
someone going really well,
today's the day we're going to see who
can kick his ass because you know,
men have this wrong idea that they can't
be beat.
Are you kidding?
Anyone could get knocked on their ass.
You think you're tough.
There's always,
you know,
you're in the business of tough guys.
There's always a tougher guy around the
corner of guy.
But more than that,
it's like you don't,
most of the conflict that you get and
when you talk and shit about somebody,
like someone like you or I can do an
interview and talk shit about someone
and didn't go public and you don't think
twice about it.
But then now it extends to social media
and potentially anybody could do it at
any time.
And it just seems so easy to do.
But I always tried to think if that
person was in front of me,
how is that treated?
And if I would,
if I would say,
fuck this guy,
like when he's in front of me,
then this is,
I have a real problem with this person.
It's a real bad.
I would always wait until I was in front
of that person and I have waited and
bided my time with people that don't
like.
And you get into a conversation.
And all I have said,
you know,
very calmly,
I,
I think you're ridiculous person.
I think you're a standing,
walking,
talking billboard for cowardice.
Something that people need to hear that
too.
Because sometimes people don't hear
that.
They don't hear that from someone.
I'm not trying to help the guy but
believe me.
But I waited until I was there.
The only people I'll rip on it,
our politicians,
like some member of Congress I think is
just an inactive waste of food.
Um,
that'll say anywhere,
hoping it'll bring him to me.
So I can say it to his or her face.
But for the most part,
the way I was brought up in the world of
music and the street is if you say
something,
that guy will be lining you up for a
broken jaw so you better mean it,
but maybe just wait until you guys are
in a room and see what you really want
to say.
Cause Sniping from a windowless room
from somewhere or being a a keyboard
activist.
That's not.
That doesn't mean much to me.
Yeah.
I think,
you know,
ted is the spokesperson for the right in
that he's this contrast in so many ways.
He's just wild and it used to be long
hair.
He doesn't have long hair anymore,
but long haired guitar player from
Michigan.
I mean he's Ted nugent.
He should be this.
He shouldn't be a drug user or
something.
Right.
It should be on tour all the time,
but he's the opposite.
He was like,
doesn't do any drugs,
doesn't drink.
And he's super right wing and he
supports the second amendment and guns
and he,
there's,
he's in this group of and he has some
very strong beliefs that he really does
hold in that group.
But then comes the outrageous stuff that
he says and you would get a
mischaracterization of him because of
some of the things he says.
But if you meet him in person,
person to person,
he's a great guy.
I talked to them all the time that
texted each other,
only been my experience with him.
Great guy is.
I've had really cool conversations with
him and I'm a hyper fan of the records.
I mean,
it's Gospel to me that those records are
in my dna.
I don't fit.
I'm with you.
And that I don't know what fuels those
and I just don't get it.
I'm not here to rip on him.
I just honestly do not.
I can't reconcile that conversations I
had were super friendly and happy that
you're a fan of the guy and then you
watch some things.
He says,
uh,
you know,
on some stage somewhere you're like,
wow,
that's,
that's as bummed that my whole evening,
that's like,
okay,
that's you,
that's the first amendment.
Go do your thing.
But like,
wow,
that's this currency in that though,
I really think that,
that getting that charge out of it,
saying that outrageous thing.
It keeps the ball rolling in some way.
It's not a ball I'd want to roll though.
I don't want to.
This doesn't seem sustainable.
Uh,
speaking of sustainable,
are you have a showtime special coming
out tomorrow night?
Wow.
That was a great segue.
It's pretty good.
That was good.
I've actually got a radio real radio
show.
Yeah.
Just wanted sequitur Rogan.
Grip it on Ted.
Yeah.
So do I.
A showtime special tomorrow.
Friday.
What's tomorrow?
The oled attempt?
The 10th.
Sorry,
a Friday,
August 10th,
10:00 PM.
East Coast,
west coast showtime.
It's called keep talking pell.
And so the,
there it is a 10 seconds on that.
They said,
what are you going to name it?
And I said,
keep talking.
Pow.
They go,
what does that mean?
It's just,
it's how you talk to yourself in and out
of trouble,
like you're about to get punched out.
Like keep talking pal.
If you don't get a laugh,
you're not getting out of this bar.
And that's kind of how I came into
talking shows was being as a young guy,
skinny,
unwritten,
not a good fighter,
not a good fighter at all,
you know,
just not into it.
And you know,
the local bully,
I've said something snarky or funny and
all of a sudden he's got me by the
scruff of my shirt with a fist in my
face and the only thing you can do is
like imitate him so much that everyone
else laughs and he has to drop you
because he's now like drop will drop
your collar,
not your body.
Um,
because you're now making him laugh.
And so when in doubt,
keep talking pal.
And the fact that I have a quote comedy
special on showtime is so unlikely from
some guy from the minimum wage working
world,
I don't believe it myself.
And so they said,
what are you going to call at night?
A lot of these people,
they have a lot of confidence like going
to call it like just me and my mighty
Wang take this is.
I don't have any of that.
So like keep talking because I know I'm
really not supposed to be there.
So how did you do your first show?
Like what?
What made you do your first talking
show?
$5.
Nineteen 83.
A little venue on Hudson right off of
like about 10 paces north of Santa
Monica Boulevard.
It's like treat the dead ends onto Santa
It was an art space.
They're called the Lasa club and there
was a local promoter in town,
amazing guy and he would get like 25
people on stage in one night.
Everyone gets five minutes and it'd be
the singer of that band,
the drummer of that band,
that artists,
that poet,
like real artists who speak for a living
and then the guy with the funny tour
journal or the guy from the band that we
all like and he's going to be an idiot
for five minutes and these shows were
really fun because it just.
People are offstage all night long,
like running off stage and the bass
player and black flag truck to Koski fed
fantastic intellect.
He would get invited onto these bills.
I would go with him because we were
beach guys.
We lived in the sticks and the gigs were
in Hollywood,
so we'll go into the big smoke will go
see the big city.
I'd go with him because he had the band
van.
He'd go into town,
I'd tag along,
so he'd read out of some notebook,
has apocalyptic rantings and one night
the promoter said,
you got a big mouth next week,
you five minutes or seven minutes,
five bucks.
All I could think of was the five bucks
and like what I could.
Because we're starving.
Yeah,
as any band was.
And so the next show I got onstage at
Lasa told a story about what had
happened at band practice the day before
where a white supremist in a car tried
to run over our guitar player because we
had brown skinned people at our band
practice and so he yelled.
He accused our guitar player of being a
Iep lover and tried to run him over on
his way to the liquor store to get some
orange juice,
so our guitar player comes back a little
shaken,
a nearly got run over by a Neo Nazi and
let's go back to practice and so for us
that was as Tuesday in the life of black
flag for an audience like you hear jaws
hit the ground and then I read something
I'd written,
I go,
well my five minutes are up,
or whatever it was,
and I left the stage and it felt right.
I felt like a fish dropped into water
for the first time.
Like,
Hey,
I'm a fish.
Like I didn't have a band,
but I had no stage fright and this me
and a microphone.
It felt more natural than music ever
felt,
which was cool to do,
but never felt natural.
Just felt like,
is it this thing is in me,
has got to come out.
I'm serving as a monster where the
talking shows like,
yeah,
this is me.
And after the show people came up and
said,
when's your next show?
I said,
well,
I'm leaving on tour.
They go,
no,
when you're just talking.
I said,
well,
no,
that's a one off.
I got this $5 bill.
I'm Outta here.
And so the agent that the promoter guy
said,
okay,
you're very good at that.
You're a natural.
So how about this?
Uh,
I promote all these different poets and
performance artists.
I'll get you,
I'll give you 20 bucks.
You'll do 20 minutes opening for this
guy.
Okay.
So I did 20 minutes and then after a
handful of those shows,
those poet types,
we're opening for me because the black
flag aspect kicks in like the do from
black flag people show up and I guess I
was good enough.
And so those poets weren't that happy.
Like I'm out opening for this guy.
Okay.
And that was 83 turning into 84 by
[inaudible] 85.
I had gone to Europe for some poetry
festival,
which I kind of blabbed onto in Holland.
I had done a cross country tour,
12 to 50 people a night sleep on the
promoters couch,
go by Amtrak.
And started my little book company or 83
84 self published to this day.
That's awesome.
And it went from strength to strength
and now it's a 14 month tour that takes
in 20 countries,
multiple nights in cities at nice
theaters.
Do you only use yourself for your
publishing company or do you publish
anybody else's books?
We used to many years ago we,
I,
uh,
people I knew who I thought were great
writers.
I put them out.
We licensed Nick Cave books from his
publishers in Europe.
Uh,
we licensed a few different titles.
We did photo books and a couple of
novels,
short story collections.
And it's very hard to have a book
company.
It's hard to sell a book in the world
unless it's like Stephen King or
Danielle steel.
It's mega,
you know,
at the,
at the cash register,
at the airport store.
Uh,
if you're selling poetry,
books,
different kinds of literature,
you are nothing but uphill.
My books did okay.
They still,
they always do.
Okay.
Everyone else's books is like trying to
sell dead animal guts.
You know what I mean?
Like,
no one,
no one's that interested in the look,
but they don't want to take it home.
And so we stopped signing new writers,
sold through the press runs,
let the licenses run out,
everyone got to keep their masters and
then we just concentrated on me because,
uh,
I keep a whole staff busy with all the
stuff I've got going.
And so we publish what we publish me and
I've done a bunch of books.
How many books have you written?
About 27.
Holy Shit.
I got nothing else going on.
Uh,
all the two of them.
we wanted to do a photo book a few years
ago.
And Heidi,
who runs all my company,
she's the smart one.
So I showed her the manuscript,
she goes,
okay,
the book is great,
but let's not do it our company because
it's a lot of startup money for a photo
book.
It's just a lot of setup costs.
Let's get you a literary agent and do it
somewhere else.
And so a smart idea.
And so we got a literary agent and we
did get a book deal with a very good,
uh,
Chicago.
It's a Chicago Company,
Chicago review,
I'm forgetting,
um,
and they put out the photo book and that
was a learning experience,
like working with an editor like,
oh,
well here's the cover,
and they,
well,
we're going to have a meeting about that
and I'm like,
you're having a meeting.
It's my book.
It's my book cover because I'm used to
owning my own machine.
But when you work with other people's
money,
everyone has a big opinion.
So that,
that book came out and did and continues
to do very well.
And many years ago I did a kind of a
best of if I have any best of material.
I did a best of for random house many,
many years ago that you still see it.
It's in print.
And that's a lot of people's first book
of mine because it's in stores.
We pulled my company's books out of
circulation because of Amazon because
they can actually sell it cheaper than
we can because they don't mind making
five cents on a book because they're
selling 80 billion books a second.
So we pulled ourselves out of
distribution and now it's very much the
website.
And it live shows and we have less
returns.
We don't get a pallet of damaged books
coming back that were,
you know,
abused in some bookstore,
in a shopping mall in the Midwest,
like heavily thumbed but never taken
home.
So you can't buy your books off Amazon
unless a third party seller.
Right.
And you just sell them on your own.
Yep.
And you might not sell as many,
but you don't get 1100 returns.
You've got 1,112,
you know what I mean?
Well,
when we were selling everyone else's
books to read,
get like a pallet of like books that
looked like a dog chewed them or like
remainder stickers.
It is what it is.
And so I am extraordinarily small of
fame.
I sell lots of books.
They do create a as ebooks as well.
In fact,
that's kind of overtaking.
I'm not an ebook guy.
I like to take a marker and mark books
up and so I buy paper ones,
but apparently the real world likes to
read on their tablet.
And so all my books are on that
platform.
Thanks to Heidi and apparently they sell
very well.
I don't keep track,
I just write them.
I don't count them.
If you had to suggest to somebody,
a good book of yours to start with,
what would you say to start with?
If I was gonna read your books,
which are,
start with.
Oh,
I would tell you to read blood Meridian
by Cormac McCarthy.
I would just tell you,
read a real writer.
I'm getting the van.
My tour journals from black flag is just
A.
People like that book.
It's in a bunch of different languages.
Uh,
it's just a cool,
insane read of like living this very
feral life,
like,
you know,
fighting women and music and relative
poverty.
So that's a fun one to start.
Um,
I,
I like the travel books I've been
writing the last few years.
I've,
these,
I write when I travel all over the
world.
And so I write these books from these
places,
like from a ship in Antarctica,
from a tent in the deserts of Timbuktu.
And those travel books I like quite a
bit.
And I'm a dull roar.
They always have an a,
an a at the beginning,
a dull roar a off to come up with the
rest of the name Sorta.
Your manic dedication to work is very
inspiring.
Like it makes me feel like I need to
work more.
Like when you're writing all the time
and doing all these,
like you're one of those guys.
It's like,
it feels like you're always with your
foot on the gas.
I'm kind of furious for work.
Yeah,
I don't.
It's not what,
it's what I do,
but it's also what I don't do in that I
don't have a family and I'm not putting
it down.
I just don't have that.
I'm just not chipped that way.
I never thought of having kids.
I don't have a wife,
I don't have friends really.
I,
most of the people I know,
uh,
either pay a salary or a commission to
my phone doesn't ring my old best friend
from since I was 12 in mci of the band
Fugazi.
He and I talk every Sunday of possible,
uh,
but past that my phone usually doesn't
ring unless it's an interview or Heidi
going,
hey,
you're late.
Get over there.
Is that good?
It.
It is.
What it is.
Work for you.
Like it's all.
I know I've been that way since I was
five,
but the no friends part.
Well I don't.
I'm not looking for enemies.
I'm not looking for a fight.
Of course.
I just don't want to come over on the
weekend for dinner.
No,
no.
I ever have a good time at dinner with
somebody missed.
Uncomfortable that I'll say the wrong
thing and I just act like look at the
table full of people.
Go Act like them.
You should be friends with comics
because you can't say the wrong thing
because no one cares.
Yeah.
But then you have to.
Then they'll call and say,
hey,
come out with us.
We're going.
Then you have to go,
ah,
you don't have to go a deadbeat.
I'd be a deadbeat friend because that's
fine.
I'd never want to go with anyone to do
any.
You don't have to,
but we'll look at all the phone calls.
I'm saying it sounds like you're
managing expectations versus you know,
like it doesn't sound like you don't
like friends.
It's just you don't want expectations.
I,
you know,
as it's going to get in the way.
So.
Well also I'm just kind of moody in
that.
Yeah,
we're going to go out and do this thing
and then I don't want to see anyone to
do anything until 20,
28 and I don't want to cancel.
And so here,
this is my big,
besides hanging out with you,
uh,
my big social thing as many,
many years ago,
2003,
I did a song with William Shatner,
Bill Shatner on this album and we became
pals.
Henry come by the house for Monday night
football and he invited me to the house
for Monday night football.
He lives a few traffic lights for me and
I'm walking up the stairs to the living
room where the TV is.
And I heard all this laughter and voices
and I froze and I was right at the
threshold of the door and I said,
turn back,
turn turning back Henry.
And he saw me and I'm like,
hey.
And I walked in and met all his really
cool friends and he,
at least for me,
Bill is,
were the nicest people I've ever met in
my life.
And it's one of the oddest friendships I
have in that.
I've been going to bill shatner's house
every year since 2003.
So what's that?
Fifteen years.
Right?
And I will be there this year.
I'm on his next record.
He's doing another record.
Oh yeah,
I did the vocal last year.
Rocket Man.
Um,
this is,
uh,
it,
it'll be fun.
I'm not gonna you know,
for him to announce it.
But,
um,
every great,
once in a while his assistant will
contact me,
hey,
bill,
really wants to see you.
Uh,
how bout like,
next you guys,
are you free for next Wednesday?
Go meet him and the wife and the valley
and go eat.
I'm like,
yeah.
And it's great to see him in his amazing
wife.
And I truly value that friendship.
I mean,
I look forward to seeing him.
I really enjoy hearing what he's up to
because it was doing like five things
and it's become this thing where I
really look forward to football season.
I don't know much about football.
I have no idea what a halfback does run.
I think they run.
I don't know,
I,
I'd never knew,
but I like going there and it's always
the same group of people.
People he's known for like 500 years and
they're super nice and I've kind of sort
of known them for like 15 years and it's
so odd because I have nothing else like
that really in my life.
I'm just a Weirdo.
Just William Shatner.
Yeah,
it's weird.
Sounds awesome.
The other thing I would do once a year
and sadly it ended,
but for a few years I would go to gail's
APP as birthday party on January first
because I would play a lot of her
husband's music on my radio show,
Frank Zappa and one time someone in the
family wrote me and said,
Hey,
thanks for playing dad on the show.
I'm like,
are you kidding?
I love those records.
And then gail,
the mom,
the wife wrote and said,
Hey,
thank you.
And um,
you know,
we know who you are here and we like
you.
I have a birthday party every January
first,
why don't you come up to the house this
year or next next year.
Like he'll and I did and that was like
three or four years in a row.
I did that until gail passed away and in
the more you get there,
whatever it is,
like two in the afternoon,
two hours before,
I'm genuinely nervous to go be in a room
full of extraordinarily nice people with
fantastically good food.
And there everyone was always so nice to
me and like,
it's like a WHO's who,
you walk in,
you're like,
wow,
it's just all these people you
recognize.
I'm not here to name drop,
but some of the tables I sat at that
thing I'm like,
really am I really talking to,
like really fantastic.
And she was always so nice to me.
And like last time I was up there,
one of my books is like in the living
room.
I'm like,
wow.
When she passed away,
I wrote one of the family members.
I said,
I am so sorry.
Thank you for the hospitality.
Your mom was so great to me and I'm kind
of like the rescue dog.
I'm used to being outside so I don't
come inside very often and I went to
that birthday party because the just the
friendliness of that,
I wouldn't as socially nerve wracking as
those things are for me.
I had such respect for that extension of
kindness.
I cannot disrespect it by not going and
wouldn't dare the Samurai and he says,
you do not distract.
You must be respectful even if it makes
you nauseous with social anxiety because
I just don't know what to do.
I can't say no because it's such a nice
thing to do for someone.
Yeah.
Play.
She must not really know how I am.
Otherwise she never would have invited
me.
So,
um,
but things like that,
out of sheer politeness and respect for
someone being friendly to me,
I'm kind of a pushover just because I'm
like,
wow,
that was so nice.
I must salute that.
I think it's so good that you're open
about your social anxiety and then about
how you feel like being around all these
people because a lot of people in the
outside,
they see someone like you,
you know,
black flag.
Oh,
your spoken word things,
your books,
your fucking mean.
I,
I always go back to uh,
that uh,
uh,
the liar song,
your fucking neck was like the size of
my waist and you're screaming and
painted red and like,
you're this crazy intimidating guy and a
lot of ways.
So to hear you talk about social anxiety
and how weird you feel.
And I think we all can.
We all feel that.
I always feel like that.
I mean,
it doesn't matter.
I think no matter how famous you get
your,
if you're paying attention,
you're going to have an imposter
syndrome.
You're,
you're always gonna feel like you don't
belong there.
If you're actually paying attention.
And if you don't,
you'll,
you're probably,
you're probably delusional at some sort
of wonder about the people who don't.
Like,
I never get to do cool stuff.
And the bit before we go into that,
to on your point,
it's easy for me to be in front of
people.
That's a very different than than being
with people.
I can be the party,
but going to the parties,
difficult putting,
put me in front of like five people,
5,000 people.
Stage fright.
No,
I can't wait to be out there.
You're a performer type.
Love that audience.
See if they showed up.
Like,
are you kidding?
I'm a dog with a wagging tail.
I want to get out there and,
and get it going.
I can't wait.
I wait the whole day on tour to get out
there.
The whole day is about o'clock,
you know,
stage time I'm being amongst people like
going to like a gallery event.
I go see a shepard fairey thing or
something and people are Super Nice to
me and I'm always polite back.
But I'm a little nervy.
But if they say,
can you get up and speak for five
minutes?
Oh yeah,
I got this strange.
It is strange,
but it's also um,
it's a way to avoid being with people,
be in front of them.
It's a way to be in the room with
people,
just be the center of attention,
so maybe that's coming from some kind of
neediness or some deprivation as a,
you know what I didn't get as a kid,
but you make a great point about that
when you really think,
well,
this is where I belong.
I think you lose all the fun of it.
Yeah.
And you turn into kind of a jerk.
So when I,
every 500 years I go to one of those
premiers,
I get invited and you're standing,
you're in a room full of tons of really
good food and none of those people eat
side just like go in there and come out
nine pounds heavier.
Bunch of shrimp have I just eat.
But you,
you're a big Hollywood premier big,
big movie years ago.
And it's like that one,
that one,
that one.
And they're all like,
ah,
it is their lives.
And I'm with a buddy of mine.
We blagged in there and we're like,
what are we doing here?
This is so cool because we know we
shouldn't be here.
And after shaking Ike Turner's hand,
10 minutes later,
I'm back in my own kitchen going.
That was so weird.
Like,
what a surreal evening.
And uh,
because my friend and I were standing
next to other and he said,
that looks like I turn.
I go,
no man,
that is eye turner.
He looked,
looked like a human barracuda.
He's like terrifying.
I was like,
we bought a ticket at the dance.
Let's,
let's go talk to this guy.
He was like,
no,
no.
I just walked right over there.
I said,
you invented rock and roll rocket 88.
And he went,
yes I did.
It shook my head.
Wow.
I say first ever distorted guitar on
tape,
which is kind of true.
Anyone that's right.
And I fluffed him up and he was all
happy to meet me.
And I said,
hey,
here's my friend.
And I brought my friend over and we
shook his hand and kind of stood with
him for a minute and went,
okay.
So it's probably not gonna get any
better for us.
So let's get outta here.
We ate a few more handfuls of mini
burritos and we bale,
but it was one of those nights were
like,
we were supposed to be in there and if I
ever lose that then just never talked to
me again because I'll just have my head
would have disappeared up.
Pardon me with that anxiety.
And that insecurity is a big part of the
fuel that keeps everything moving.
Super fuel for me.
You analyzing yourself?
Yeah.
And anger.
I'm mad at I,
I,
I like fighting and not fighting like in
a ring for me.
A lot of things or confrontation like
tourists.
What you think?
I can't do 47 shows in 48.
No,
it actually,
my next tour is 47 and 47.
Um,
I have a day off and I have two shows a
few days later in one day.
So,
um,
what you think I can't will then book 20
more,
200 more in the winter and just give me
a lama and a knife and I make every gig
like watch this and,
and that's so much of what fuels me.
Like yeah.
And like,
I come up with these huge ideas for
books,
like that's gonna take me five years to
write it.
And it did,
and I just finished it.
It's going to the proofreader soon.
This epic project,
I just,
it's,
it's a series of music books.
It's 407,000 words.
It's a bit much.
But so am I.
is this idea pages?
I don't know.
It's a lot.
It's mostly on the hard drive so we
don't have to deforest some park.
Um,
but it was an idea I had.
I said,
okay,
this is going to take a lot of years to
execute this idea.
And so like,
watch me work seven days a week on this
thing,
watch we stay up until the next day
working on this thing and a lot of what
fuels me.
That's what gets me into auditions.
Like I think,
you know,
like,
Hey,
go audition for this TV show.
I'm not an actor.
So am I going,
yeah,
I'm going.
And I sit in that hallway like 20 years
older than all these other people.
And they got the good jim bodies on
fantastic hair,
chiseled bodies.
And they all know each other like this
weird old man going for the same part,
the only guy not dipped in Cologne.
I'm like,
oh man.
And I go in there and I bomb.
Of course I get my parking pass
validated and listen to slayer on the
way home.
Take the lump out of my.
How often do you do that?
How often are you auditioning for?
It?
Depends if I'm in town and there's
interesting things happening more and
more,
uh,
as I don't know what's happening,
but I take more meetings and just get
more offers.
Like,
Hey,
we like you for this.
Yes or no.
Cool.
Yes.
But there's auditions.
I do,
uh,
for voiceover,
for like animated or like car ads or
what have you.
And acting.
I auditioned for all kinds of things and
every great once in a while the audition
will get work.
But mainly I just get offers.
We like you for this.
It starts in October.
I'm in and that happens fairly often
now.
But I get in those lines that at any
major studio you want to imagine or I go
in for the meeting with a casting
person,
they kind of look you over,
but I do those raw auditions.
Whereas you leave and you see like five
head shots on a desk.
It is what it is and you get literally
you're out of there in about 35 seconds.
You walk in,
you're a Henry Henry Harley.
Uh,
are you ready?
Sure.
Do you have any questions?
No.
Stand on this piece of tape.
She'll be reading with you and you,
you know.
No,
no,
no.
Thank you very much for coming in.
And you leave the trailer and you get
back on the one on one and go home and
you never hear from them again.
Often for me,
most of the time out of 100 of those 98
times for everybody except putting it
down.
But I'm going to say,
and you asked about auditions.
Hell yeah.
I go in there.
I think that's one of the things that
makes acthar so fucking weird is not
just that they need attention in the
first place where they told Nola they
get told no a lot,
which sucks.
It sucks and they're already insecure in
the first place and then they sort of
try to model their behavior based on
what they think the casting agents and
the producers want to hear and they
change and they developed this style of
communicating.
That's very actory.
It's a weird way to make your living.
I mean,
I've never relied on acting as my source
of income in 1984 when I was 23 either a
thing that has been serving me up to
sitting here with you now.
I was very young in 23 years of age,
a young idiot and I looked all around.
Me and all my peers are super talented.
Who are my peers under threat,
bad rains,
Husker du,
the meat puppets,
the dead Kennedys.
I'm just surrounded by really talented
people who are brilliant,
great songwriters and between tours,
many of them are waiting tables,
living with mom,
living on couches,
you know,
sleeping at band practice,
with a kick drum,
a pillow as,
as their pillow just like,
you know,
roughing it and I,
I reckon that I'm less talented than all
of them and if they're waiters between
tours,
the only reason I'm not as black flag
never stopped drawing,
like were the ball never hit the ground
because we'd starve.
And so I better get plans B,
c,
d,
e,
F and g ready because music's not going
to sustain me.
Ironically,
it went very well for me and so I was
doing the writing,
so I said,
I'm going to really get better at
writing.
I'm going to really bear down on this.
The talking shows.
I'm getting 35 people a night.
I'm going to get 50 people a night.
And then voiceover people started coming
like,
Hey,
can you do a voiceover?
I got a voice.
What do you want me to?
I better learn to say yes to stuff and
by the mid eighties,
hey,
you want to be in a movie?
Yeah,
that'd be like,
what do I have to lose except your
calories from starving?
And so it was fear of not eating that,
you know,
and knowing I better have a plan and so
I started developing that in the
eighties,
nineties.
And from that came what I,
I'm done with this.
I'm going to go immediately into this
documentary and then I'm finishing this
radio show and then I'm going off to do
this film and then I'm going on tour and
then I'm coming back and finishing this
book and it turned into this like
juggling all these things.
So I never had to be a full time actor.
Like that's how I pay the rent.
That would be terrifying right up there
with being a professional comedian.
Like I don't know how someone acts for
living without being really good or out
of their minds with anxiety.
But being a professional comedian,
at least you write your own stuff,
so you're kind of in control of that.
And then you don't have pain.
It doesn't seem that rough and then you
don't have to pay people,
like
you don't have to pay roadies,
you don't have a drummer that has to
show up.
Also,
you don't have the bass player who
you've got to get along with.
Like there's so many variables with a
band that comedians don't have.
Like we always look at you guys and go,
wow,
I don't know how the fuck you guys do it
because there's not as much like you.
You might do the same size venues that
we do,
but you're splitting the money with all
these fucking people.
You know.
And then a lot of times today the record
company gets a piece.
They get a piece of everything,
right?
They get a piece of your merchandise,
you see bands play really big places and
it's amazing how much money they don't
make.
Or each guy in the band gets like,
really?
Huh?
And then you see someone,
a small comedian playing like a 150
cedar for two nights,
two sets of night,
you know,
the,
the left whatever in the Midwest.
And you're like,
wow,
that's a pretty good weekend because
he's just taking it home in his
suitcase.
Yeah.
You can get by,
get by.
Yeah.
And you can work,
you can work everywhere.
You know,
for a band.
I think it's more the venues are more,
are more limited places you go are more
limited,
you know.
And I think uh,
that's interesting that you're,
it was almost like a desperation to not
have to work a job as a waiter that kept
you just hustling.
What does it mean?
I just knew that the straight world,
because I'd been in it,
I come from it,
you know,
minimum wage work and everything.
And I knew I couldn't survive in it.
Cause I know you get as a young adult,
you start to figure out who you are.
Like,
okay,
I'm not an artist,
but I'm an artist type.
I'm an,
I'm nuts.
You can't put me in a straight shot.
I can pass for normal just because I can
task it.
I can totally do it.
Like you can put me in a Ralph's,
a kroger's,
a starbucks.
I will totally get in there and hit the
work and cleaned it all and serve it up
with a smile,
but I'll be going crazy inside.
I will be punch everybody in those
places is going crazy inside.
I Dunno.
But um,
I can't sustain in that and I haven't
had to for many years.
I've been lucky.
I've been in the world of lunatics since
1981 being a crazy person out with other
crazy people.
And when I look at a straight job I'm
like,
man,
I don't think at this point I could hack
it.
Not because I'm spoiled just because
I've never had to tether my adult mind
too that I work seven days a week.
But on Henry stuff,
to me it's not,
it's a different thing.
It's a different thing.
You enjoy that work and it's,
it's way over 60 hours a week.
I mean it's,
I do two shifts usually to eight to 10
hour shifts depending on every workload.
Well,
I can't do four hours of sleep a night,
but I tie my sleep.
I hit the stopwatch on the phone before
I go to bed.
Just this clock,
sleep patterns.
I did about six point something hours of
sleep last night.
That's good.
It's good.
I feel great today.
I barely ate and I uh,
got into a good workout.
And all last night he did a lot of pull
ups.
I played 15,
seven inch records and between flipping
him over I got a beam in my living room
is a beam coming out of the ceiling that
supports me and I just run over there
and just do a bunch of pull ups and then
go change the record.
So you want more music?
You have to pay and pay and pay and all
this by yourself all alone.
Yeah.
But by bedtime you are hurting and ready
to sleep.
So I got good sleep last night.
So you mix the workout in with your
enjoyment of music.
He just space it in between the song.
Last night was pulling.
Tonight at the turntable,
I'll be listening to more records.
I'll just do sets of pushups next to the
turntable.
That's a smart move because like that's
probably a good interval of rest.
Like get a good hard workout in.
And then you listen to a form and it's
on.
Yeah.
And,
but I do it all night and it's just a,
I'm not doing 50 sets,
50 rep sets.
I'm doing like 15 to 25,
but I'm doing them for quite a while.
By the time I go to bed it's advil time.
I'm like,
Oh,
I'm too old for this.
But um,
I,
I work on something every day on tour.
I don't take vacations.
I'm not trying to brag.
I just can't.
I can't handle not doing it.
Whatever the thing is.
Yeah.
Well you found an interesting way to
live life.
I don't know anybody like you,
but it's working for you.
Yeah,
it works on all levels.
And like I,
I can sustain.
I pay my bills,
I'm not bored and I get for the most
part to call my own shots.
And you seem happy.
Happy when I'm working.
Yeah.
Happy with the task.
I value work.
I'm an achievement junkie.
Like if I'm depressed,
I just picked something to do,
like finish your radio show,
edit this thing,
transcribed this chapter from a notebook
and after I'm done,
I'm like,
okay,
that's the antidepressant was actually
doing something which is not the worst.
It's not booze,
it's not a pill,
it's the treadmill or it's the Oh that
damn thing I got to get it written,
will shut up and write it and when I'm
done,
it's like an endorphin thing where I'm
great for another day.
There was an article written about
happiness and those.
One of the things that they said that
one of the things that seems to sustain
people's happiness or facilitate
happiness is accomplishing tasks,
like setting goals for yourself,
accomplishing those goals and getting
this sense of completion that you've.
You've actually done the work and you
did it and you discipline yourself and
got through it and that this is one of
the major keys to happiness for a lot of
work for me,
totally works for me because I may as
well.
I've tried everything but drugs because
I've been battling with depression since
I was a little kid and I just knew what
is this.
It's just awful.
And you know,
later I found out it was depression and
I don't want to do drugs.
I'm not,
I just don't want it.
My brain plus drugs.
It's like someone else's idea.
It's terrifies me.
So I had to figure out what do you do.
And so that's where the gym you're
working out really is a big help
writing.
But listening to music that is like a
kind of my drug,
you know,
I just put the records on and like three
songs in,
you're like,
oh,
there's that feeling,
buoyancy neutral.
It's like floating in the tank or when
you're scuba diving you get your air
just right in.
You're floating.
That's how I feel.
I have the music on.
I'm like,
ah,
this is as good as it gets.
And that's why I always have,
you know,
record.
I'm always looking at new records,
going to the record store is more
happiness coming in.
Does the exercise work better or the
same as work?
Like for managing depression?
Uh,
the workout is maintenance,
it doesn't achieve much,
but I achieved the workout.
But you feel like the,
the endorphin release,
does that help you?
Yeah,
yeah,
it does.
And I,
as the Buddhists say,
I made merit.
I,
I went in there and did my time on the
treadmill.
I don't want to be there just the last
15 minutes.
I don't.
I'd rather be somewhere else like,
yo,
that's cool.
You'll be fine.
Sit Down,
do your work.
That's why before the podcast how
suggesting hot yoga to you and you,
you seem to be very stiff lately.
You've got some injuries and some things
back.
Dude,
I'm telling you that'll fix a lot of
that shit.
It'll really.
Yeah.
I know you have.
You have a great workout diversity.
You,
when you and I were talking before we
were at your place and you said some
mornings you feel like training this way
and you'll go to that gym or you'll
train like a judo or whatever and then
the next day it's going to be kettle
bells.
So you really like to mix it up.
I think it's good for a body to always
be guessing what's coming next.
Yeah,
I think
I also,
I,
there's some things that are really have
to do.
I think I need at least one day of hard
cardio a week and I think I need at
least one day of hard lifting weights a
week,
but I also think I need at least one day
of yoga.
We call East Yoga is to me it's one of
the most important things that I do
because for that 90 minutes I can't go
anywhere.
I don't touch my phone,
not in the room with me.
It was just me and a jug of water and
the Yoga Mat and the class and a bunch
of old ladies that are kicking my ass.
These ladies are fucking tough man.
This is old lady.
She goes to this workout,
classmates see you there all the time.
She's got to be close to 70.
She doesn't even bring water.
She just tufts it out.
She's there for 90 minutes.
Sweating and grunting through the
postures and those you doing an hour and
a half class.
Those last 20 minutes in a 104 degrees,
it's so hard to get through,
but when you get through you just feel
like you feel better.
I just,
I almost like can't wallow in it.
I can't wait to do it again.
Like while I'm struggling and I was
like,
God,
I need to do more than this.
I need to do this more often.
Rather I can't wait to do this again.
I always feel that and it just lengthens
everything.
Like all the bad things and the leg
things,
the hamstring things just stretches
everything out,
lengthens it and all the tension.
It just straightens it out and loosens
it up and I just feel like for a guy
like you or I who does a lot of a Lotta,
like
especially like used a lot of heavy
lifting.
You were saying a lot of dead lifts and
squats.
This is the antidote for all that stuff.
It's decompression and for your body
maintenance,
it's just phenomenal.
Probably let's lose the lactic acid out
of your muscle tissue.
Yeah.
You know,
here's what I've observed.
I live in Los Angeles,
so there's a lot of yoga people,
but I know them because they have a mat,
but you could also see how they walk,
how they sit there,
so in their body,
and there is a grace to you.
I'm not trying to put anyone in the
pejorative,
but a yoga person where there's not only
are they limber,
they're just really okay though this
their body articulation,
you're like,
okay,
I don't have that.
I'm a Herky Jerky and coordinator
person,
but there is a,
uh,
uh hum.
Coming from that person's overall body.
It just,
it's a beautiful machine.
The way they articulate themselves in
the way they sit,
very unusual balance.
The balance of like,
tell someone who does it.
They have that.
Yeah.
And it's not subtle.
I recognize that you would love it,
man.
You know what?
You would love it because it fucking
sucks.
And while you're doing it,
man,
you have the internal dialogues.
Crazy.
You want to bolt what do you want a
ball,
but you also start going over your life
and your mind and dealing with all your
bullshit and your to do list and all the
things you're.
You're,
you're doing wrong or slacking.
There's something about really
struggling in these static positions for
like a minute where you're trying to
like hold your leg up there and you're
sweating.
Sweat is literally pouring off your arms
and your head and there's something
about that man that it's just really
cleansing.
It just really mtz.
I just think it's a thing that you're
missing that you would really love if
you tried.
I bet if you did it and he came back,
we did a podcast a year later,
like,
Fuck Yoga.
I fucking love it.
It's changed my life.
I know a lot of fighters,
a lot of people who like are hectic for
living.
Yup.
There Yoga people,
like in the seventies you say yoga,
so I was going to punch you like yoga,
wham.
You know what I found out about it?
How do you know Hixon Gracie is well.
Are we talking about the Gracie family?
Well,
the family hoists Gracie is the most
famous because he's probably the most
important figure ever in the history of
martial arts because he won the first
ultimate fighting championship and
showed that a small man could actually
beat larger men with technique and
skill.
Well his brother is Hickson and his
brother is like universally regarded as
one of the greatest Jujitsu guys,
if not the greatest of all time and he
was different than everybody else and
that he did yoga.
Like his thing was like I'd never heard
of a martial artist that got into yoga,
but hixon would do these breathing
exercises and they do these balance beam
exercises and he was always doing yoga
and stretching and it was a giant part
of his workout and he was above and
beyond everyone else in his time period.
Like in the nineties,
everyone scared of Hixon.
He was the man.
I mean,
but it wasn't like there was any debate.
It's very rare that you get something
that is so antagonistic and so tightly
contested as two men using martial arts
techniques trying to strangle each other
and one guy stands above all by such a
large margin and that was Hickson and I
really do believe that part of it was
his mind.
Part of it was his physicality,
but a lot of that physicality was
enhanced by his dedication to yoga.
Oh yeah.
He's a legit Yogi.
Like who does that fire breathing shit
where he sucks his stomach in that weird
way and hasn't move up and down.
You ever see someone do that?
Yeah,
he does that like a,
like a real Yogi.
Like it's,
it's a real trip.
And I think because of his,
uh,
his,
his like physical,
like you can see there.
He's good.
He's got this video here.
You can see him do this fire breathing
shit.
Like watch what he does this stomach
because it's kind of fucking crazy.
He sucks his stomach way,
way,
way up deep into his rib cage.
He does this breath of fire thing and
then as it gets going,
he starts pumping.
Is here,
see if you pull it up there,
Jamie.
The part where it starts to do it.
Look at this.
Wow.
Yeah.
Like what the fuck?
Isn't that insane?
Yeah,
it's crazy.
And this is one of the things he has
abdominal muscle control gets that you
never try and articulate,
make it do anything.
Well He,
you know,
he'd practice yoga for a long,
long,
long
time and because of that he had this
phenomenal core strength and phenomenal
balance and he just had a giant
advantage over everyone else and I think
a lot of that advantage was his,
his ability to move his body was
different,
but it's also just for a guy like you
that's been just lifting weights for so
long,
it's the perfect antidote for your body.
It's like your body will react to like,
oh yeah,
stretch this out.
Thank you.
I've been asking for this,
you know,
Linkedin,
this,
hold that pose.
This is instead of just lifted something
that you know,
which is what men like to do.
Instead of that,
you're
holding your arms out there like that.
You're like,
fuck,
I don't even have any weight in these
things and I want to drop them.
Yeah,
I've done a,
you know,
every once in awhile I've worked out
with someone else and they go,
okay,
we're going to do this and this and
that.
You work with and then you let them.
You let yourself be trained.
Yeah,
and I've done a few workouts like,
go,
okay,
I'm going to kill you.
I'm like,
okay,
what does that mean?
Like by the end of this,
you won't be able to take your shirt off
to change and I've done,
you know where you're benching this much
then this much.
Then this much.
You ended up doing like a hundred and 50
reps and by the time you can't lift the
bar and you can't lift your arms,
you're literally trembling from
exhaustion and I've told that to people.
They go,
that's yoga.
You will tremble from exhaustion and
you'll be so happy when you leave
because of how good you feel and you
can't wait to go back and you won't blow
your joints out the way you will with
lifting.
I already have.
Yeah,
there's no
way around it.
I've paid.
Yeah,
you,
I did a thing the other day,
uh,
on advice of Heidi,
the manager and Joey Diaz.
I tried that Cryo cryotherapy.
Yes.
And I am not,
I'm a,
I'm a naysayer in lowercase.
I understand why would work,
and I'm not saying it's quackery,
but I just feel like I'm in an Annie
Hall scene when I walk into these places
like,
because it's like super,
hey,
where's that?
Whatever therapy and I'm moonlight and
this is.
And then like you shake the guy's hand,
he damn your breaks your arm.
These people are in incredible shape.
And so I said,
okay,
you know,
I got in the robe and I went into that
room for two minutes and 45 seconds and
the endorphin rush,
it's like a ups truck of endorphins.
You come out of there like,
can I go back in?
And since I got out of it,
all I have been thinking about is going
back in,
in the parking lot.
I just wanted to turn around and get
another shy and I asked the guy at the
counter like,
what is that goes?
It's endorphins,
it says,
unleashes them like fight or flight.
You just get this rush.
I said I,
I want to go back.
He said,
come and see us again sometime.
But um,
it was incredible and is not long like
you're out of there before you know it.
Ten minutes you're in and out.
Yeah.
But wow,
it me on and I know that a lot of
athletes and I know that you use it a
Joey Diaz,
but all the brochure,
nearly all these sports teams,
like it's just part of what you do,
but one thing that has been proven to do
it,
there's a lot of naysayers when it comes
to this even scientist apparently that
don't exercise,
but people that do exercise and do try
it all pretty much universally regarded
as being beneficial.
But one of the things that's been shown
in clinical studies is that it reduces
and it produces more anti inflammatory
bodies in the blood.
It is,
that's what I was.
Yeah.
So it,
it does reduce inflammation in your body
and it just.
But I think just for the mood elevation
it's worth doing.
I mean,
it does say that nor epinephrin released
that you get when you get out of there,
it's,
it's unbelievable.
You get that.
It wasn't subtle.
It was like,
wow.
And the sun feels great in your face and
you get outside.
You're like,
ah,
everything felt great.
I mean,
I,
I don't do much as far as stimulants,
like coffee and aspirin I guess.
Uh,
so I'm not even sure what the effect is,
if at anything.
And so it doesn't take much to make me
go,
well,
that's different,
you know what I mean?
And that I walked out back to the
parking lot,
like,
damn.
Yeah,
that was fantastic.
Do three and then I'd take 10 minutes
off.
Then I do three again.
So I do two sessions.
I do two back to back.
So you go in,
you do two or three minutes,
three minutes,
and then my body warms back up to like,
once your skin temperature gets around
84 degrees,
I'll let you get back in there.
And then I'll go back in there again for
another three minutes.
So wait,
how many in an
like you'll go into this place?
Three minutes and then I wait for 10
minutes and then I go on for another
three minutes.
So usually to two sessions.
Two sessions in one visit?
Yes.
Yeah.
And how many times?
How often?
How many times a month whenever I can.
But I've been mixing it up more with
Sauna.
I've been doing a lot of sauna lately.
I kinda like that as much if not more.
Sauna,
sauna,
sauna seems to be really good for muscle
injuries and something about the sauna
for anytime to like muscle tissue or
soreness or weird shit.
Sauna just blows that all out and so on.
Is also one of those things.
It's what it is,
is your body reacting to extremes,
right?
Whether it's extreme cold or extreme
heat,
your body produces heat shock proteins
and cold truck proteins and all those
things are doing is reducing
inflammation.
That's,
that's the number one thing.
Like you want to feel better,
reduce inflammation,
and this,
one of the best ways to manipulate your
body is either through carf cryotherapy
or through sauna.
Both of those things are amazing.
Yeah.
Someone I know that she says it's all
about inflammation.
GotTa beat the inflammation and cut out
all the sugar.
Cut out the carbs,
cut out all the bread,
cut it all the alcohol.
If you can do that,
you'll massively reduce inflammation and
that's for Gospel is all that.
That's nothing good in there for you?
Yeah man.
And once your body gets used to it too,
that's what's really interesting.
You didn't even really crave it anymore.
Like I still like ice cream.
I still enjoy like a dessert or
something like that,
but it doesn't have the same impact that
he used to like I see a sandwich and I
go,
oh,
get that sandwich.
Like that Pastrami Sandwich,
big thick bread and that doesn't do it
for me anymore.
I don't.
It doesn't recognize what that is like.
Well that's the trick.
That's the trick.
That's not even really food.
Yeah.
I,
I don't eat as much as I used to.
I just feel so much better when I just
skipped the middle meal and like,
whose idea was it?
Three meals a day anyway.
You don't need to.
Right.
And I found that I can live very
comfortably.
I'm not into like torturing myself so
like I'm going to starve and nail myself
to this chair,
but you know,
if I'm too distracted to work as I'm
hungry I need to address that.
But what I found is if I just kind of
don't eat a lot after a couple of days,
I'm like a jet in the high air where
you're burning no fuel because you're
just in the thin air where I walked pie
food going like,
Nah,
I've had like two meals in the last two
and a half meals like in the last three
days.
And I feel fine actually.
I feel like really bouncy,
like I don't need the postworkout seven
minute power nap.
I,
I'm feeling really good.
Do you do intermittent fasting at all?
Um,
yes.
On the,
the woman I work with,
you know Heidi,
she does that sometimes and I'll just
follow her lead.
So she'll go,
hey,
let me do this.
I'll try that because I just don't know
this stuff.
And she knows a lot more about it than I
do.
So I just do what she does and so a few
years ago I had got into like one meal a
day.
I was just trying it out,
no one told me to.
I was in India of all places and I was
out all day taking photos and sweating
and I would eat dinner and that will be
it and I would sleep through breakfast
and go back out and with my camera.
So dinner became my meal and the first
three days of that was a little tough
and then it was like I never wanted.
I kind of felt bad when I went back to
the western or I'm eating a lot of food.
Your body adapts.
Yeah,
well we can adapt.
You can live on pizza for the rest of
your life very happily all,
you know,
whatever.
But your body really does adapt to that.
Intermittent.
That time will know what I'm saying.
It'll adapt to anything.
It'll adapt to too much food and little
depth to like a fraction of what you
used to eat right here.
But just,
here's what I have found when I start
limiting the food,
I'm more alert,
my sleep is more restorative and I
bounce out of bed,
like just flying out of bed.
I don't have that afternoon drowsiness.
I just stay with it and I just feel way
more buoyant and present a type faster,
just concentrate more.
And if I,
I,
when I'm on tour it's usually I do one
point something meals a day like I'm
about to leave on tour.
It'll be,
it's an evening meal post show.
I put myself into an eight hour feeding
window and 16 hour fasting window every
day.
And I've been pretty consistent with
that over the last like four or five
months.
And as a,
it has a big impact man.
When you,
when I eat dinner,
you know,
say if I'm done at 8:00,
just I just time it out.
Sixteen hours later is when my first
meal comes.
I can have a coffee in between now and
then.
But nothing with any real significant
calories.
I'm just having some liquid or something
like that.
And that's it.
And then it just,
by doing that man,
just like a wake up in the morning,
I'm not craving breakfast,
I'm not,
I'm not even hungry.
My body's just totally adapted to.
Yeah,
just gives your body a chance to digest.
I think we're always in a state of
feeding and your body just never has
really a chance to digest it.
Juggling,
you know,
the body's like as it's processing,
it's incoming,
like really another order.
So it never gets to realize digestion
and we're done.
It's always in your like a cow.
They're always processing nutrition.
And I wonder if that's a western model
because in other parts of the world,
people live very differently than we do.
It just,
it is what it is.
And a meal is.
It's almost just a thing that happens
now in then.
It's not like it's dinner time and we're
going to talk about report cards and
gathering.
It's like the whole family works all
over the city and they're going to eat.
I think at some point wherever even
sleep you go to like Parse,
like Vietnam and people just like
sleeping behind the counter of the
store.
They work at because they've been for a
day and a half because mom can't come
in.
So there were you running the store and
the sleep business thing that you get
now and then.
And I think food is
like that in a lot of parts of the
world,
like a meal a wouldn't.
The next time I eat will be the next
time I eat.
When you go to these places,
and I know you traveled pretty much all
over the world,
do you go out of your way to try to
sample in as wide a variety as the local
cuisines?
You can.
No,
no.
Depends on where I go and I'm not that
guy who just brings it all from home and
I never leave home when I'm abroad,
but I can't afford to eat a bad meal and
be bedridden,
bedridden for the next day when I should
be out hitting the streets,
looking at stuff.
And so I've had,
you know,
as you do,
you run into the bad meal where you're
like hugging a tree,
watching the arc of vomit,
like wow,
Linda Blair.
And I've done that from here to a
Myenmar and Russia,
wherever I've had some bad meals.
And so when the food looks dodgy,
like in the interior of Africa where you
pointed the meat object and go,
what is that?
And the guy will say,
I think it's goat Clif bar just because
I just can't.
And so what I've learned to do,
and it's hard on your back because it's
a lot of weight.
I take say I'm going to be out in Africa
for two weeks.
I bring about two meals worth of chow
with me.
That's a lot of nuts.
A lot of cliff bars,
a lot of like peanut butter and you
know,
things that just don't go bad.
And heat where I can just look at the
food and gum.
No,
not tonight.
It's going to be a handful of almonds
and this and water.
Also in parts of the world where water's
dodgy,
you find a store,
you buy the box of water,
rip it open to make sure it hasn't been
tampered with by the whole box.
Put it in your backpack and look 40
pounds of water for the next five days.
It sucks,
but you can't be somewhere and go like,
I'm thirsty and I don't know about that
water because they have these portable
backpack filters and stary pens and
things that a lot of backpack hikers
they use.
Uh,
they're,
they're very small now.
They're very small and lightweight and
you can get some,
like if you're staying in a place that
you think it has dodgy water,
you can get a gravity filter.
You put water,
like you can literally get rain water
from outside in a puddle.
And I know a lot of people do that and
they take it and they put it in this
large gravity filter in a drip down,
almost like it looks like someone's
peeing at the bottom of this huge bag of
60 liter bag of water,
but it filters at all and it allows you
to drink basically puddle water,
right?
No,
I've never gotten that high tech.
I've been in some pretty dodgy places,
but I've always been somewhere in prep
like a city before I go into the
countryside where I go,
okay,
it's going to be five days before I see
anything like this again,
so I'm provisioning for eight days.
That's a good one,
but usually google stary pen,
you should get one of these things
because this,
this thing is so,
so simple.
It's like it basically looks like a pen
and it works with ultraviolet light and
you put it in like say if
you have a glass of water,
you just stir this into water.
It kills everything in the water.
Everything.
Wow.
Yeah.
It'll still give us this.
There it is right there.
So if there's buffalo pis and the water,
it's still going to smell like buffalo
pissed.
It's not gonna kill you and it won't
give you Giardia and it won't give you
anything else.
Oh,
that's smart.
Yeah,
and it's not big.
It's a small little device.
You see it,
this handheld,
these,
those are drugs.
That's smart.
Yeah.
I think that's a different thing.
Yeah,
because there's parts of mainly Africa
where you go really in the water,
like that's a lot of sketches,
drinking,
like clearing the larva out of the way.
I'm like,
don't do that.
What do you mean that's,
that's our water.
My good friend Justin Wren,
he runs a charity called fight for the
forgotten where they build wells for the
pygmies in the Congo and he's had
malaria three times from going over
there.
Yeah,
and he's A.
He's a beautiful human being like this
guy sacrifices so much.
He's in the Congo several months out of
every year.
Tough,
dangerous.
It's very dangerous and you know,
he's got some crazy stories about it
too,
but you know,
these people that you see little
children with horrible distended bellies
because they're filled with parasites
and it's heartbreaking.
A lot of it is clean water and so
they're developing their.
There initially partnered up with water
four and now he's kind of doing it all
on his own,
but in through this,
one of my responses called the cash app
and through the cash app,
we've already raised thousands of
dollars to build several wells in the
Congo.
We're constantly raising more money and
building more wells and it changes their
life.
If free actual clear water that comes
out of the ground,
he see these people celebrating and
dancing.
When the wells get turned on like this
is so powerful.
You just think of water is like,
Oh hey,
here's some water.
I've got a bottle.
But to them it's,
it's everything,
right?
Yeah.
I've been working on and off with the
Water Ngo for many years called drop in
the bucket and I've been to Uganda and
south Sudan with them.
They drill it schools and you know,
as a Westerner of water system thing,
we sing in the shower with,
you know,
it's just like,
it's always around,
you know,
you trip over the bottles.
There's so much water in other parts of
the world as you know,
not so much.
And when you,
when you see the impact of water on the
school,
there's so many things you don't think
about.
And so I was at this one school where
they had drilled,
dropping the bucket,
had drilled before and we were there to
visit the well and meet the kids.
Uh,
in Masaka it's,
I think north of Kampala and what one of
the drop in the bucket people said is
like they now have toilets and running
water.
Do you understand what that means for
female literacy?
I'm like,
what do you mean a woman?
A girl hits a certain age.
She goes through a major,
major physiological change.
If there's not running water in a way
for her to clean herself up,
there's a lot of potential shame and
self consciousness.
You stopped going to school because it's
not a way to keep yourself together and
you stopped your learning stops at young
adulthood.
But with running water in a way to,
you know,
as we westerners do,
so you know,
easily you keep yourself a hygienic and
you can go back to class and learn to
read.
And I was like,
I'd never would've thought of that had I
not come on this trip and it hit me like
a truck because he's the water.
I'm thirsty.
Water means so much more.
Just dignity.
Like I want to be clean.
You and me,
we throw our clothes in the laundry
everyday.
Clean clothes.
I mean,
you see these women walking eight miles
each way with the jerry cans of water.
Some of that's for drinking.
A lot of it's for cleaning clothes
because they're sending their kid to a
school and want the kid,
you know,
human dignity,
water and all of that is a big,
you know,
you can't have dignity without the water
because water means I don't stink and
you must take me.
You must respect me as a person because
I don't smell like I've been living in
these clothes for a week.
And um,
I learned a lot of that by traveling.
But traveling with that NGO was a,
you know,
like going to class.
It was huge.
Yeah,
man,
that's,
that's know.
That's something I never would have
considered.
And human dignity.
You know,
why we have a lot of angry people in the
world because you and I as Westerners,
we don't suffer the indignities that we
don't suffer that a lot of people in the
world work hard to not suffer.
Like they have to go like,
okay,
I have to go get the water today.
You know,
that's a long trip.
Got to walk to Long Beach and back to
get the water because there's no tap and
I got kids and you know,
infants and I got to make this work
because I can't have my family stinking
and I got to do the cooking and
hopefully you don't get eaten by a
crocodile and were taught by a monkey.
The monkey.
They smell the water and they,
they mug you for the water.
Really?
Yeah.
Um,
they just assault yield bite and he
grabbed the water,
knock it over and just lick it off the
ground.
Yet people get assaulted in dry season
by monkeys.
Wow.
Yeah.
So these creeps.
But just you see what people do.
They're not trying to be rockstars.
All they want to do is what you and I do
just without even thinking twice and
that,
you know,
it's made me as an older guy,
I'm pushing 60.
It's made me really reconsider human
relationships,
like our current political climate,
the way people talk to each other now.
It's sometimes kind of terrifying and it
makes me really reconsider human
dignity,
respect patients.
Like there's a lot of people like I
disagree with,
but they're coming from something real,
like something very real there,
an honest propelled them to make that
sign or to do that thing and the,
the cause and effect.
I think there may be wrongheaded what
the causes real.
And the effect is sincerely the action
of sincerely held
that the motivation and it's that kind
of travel and looking how,
looking at how people,
they don't want much,
they just want to get by by and large.
And um,
it's made me reconsider kind of how I
virtually everyone out in the world.
Um,
I think I'm getting better at it because
it's so hard.
It is hard.
But I think if you pay attention to it
and you keep concentrating on,
as you get older you do get better at
it.
And the idea that someone who's almost
60 is still learning like that is just
how we are,
you know,
and we have this weird idea that people
are static and they meet a guy and he's
70 when you meet him when he's 75 is
going to be the same guy if not worse,
but no people,
they're capable of growth.
As long as they're alive and and
motivated,
you'll,
you'll grow as much as you want to ask.
And I've met 70 year old who wear me
out.
I'm like,
I can't keep up with this.
Like I go in some little cool eco travel
trips.
You go like Antarctica and these old
fuck,
come on.
You're like,
I can't.
You go to take a photo or shorts.
And then you meet people who are 22 and
they're so burned out and they're so
hard to be around.
Like,
man,
if I had your youth,
I'd be bouncing off the planet.
What are you doing?
And it's just a mindset and you know,
all kinds of surrounding factors and
forces.
But it's really just what you want to do
at a certain part of your life.
I have very little sympathy for adults
in that.
You're 35.
This is all you pal,
your addictions,
your crap marriage,
that's all you like.
I don't have that much.
Well,
I did so much coke.
I don't have a house anymore.
That's a lot of coke and I'm sorry that
you're living in a box or in a van down
by the river.
But come on man.
That's a long hill.
You slid down.
Yeah.
So get up and don't do it.
Don't make the same mistake.
But adults.
Come on,
man.
You know who you are at this point and
you,
you know what you can be.
And at this point I,
I abhor rudeness.
I hate it.
And I hate it when I'm rude.
I'm like,
damn,
I have to punish myself.
And so I,
as I get older,
I'm working as best as I can to be more
clear,
to be more polite and more patient just
so I'm more it unavoidable.
Like onstage,
I don't curse,
so there's no way you can marginalize
me.
Even when you're doing your,
you're live speaking shows,
you have these discussions and you're
talking about crazy things that you've
seen.
You don't swear.
How many times have I sworn in this room
with you right now on that today?
I don't think you have.
I haven't.
I keep track.
Why is that?
Um,
many years ago,
almost 10 years ago,
I was going out with a woman who never
cursed and I work with people who don't
curse in the EU.
They get their point across and I,
this girl I was going out with,
she's fantastic and she never cursed in
my sailor speak.
I was like,
wow,
I don't have any company here.
And also Barack Obama and presidents
have traditionally don't curse,
but he's had such a good way with words
that just admired him on the stump.
I'm sure it was all written for him,
but nonetheless,
I,
I just like how,
how the men carried himself and I said I
want to be more like that.
And I was just in Australia a couple of
weeks ago.
Uh,
speaking and I was on a very interesting
panel about me too.
I was the only male on the panel is
fascinating and a guy came up with his
kids like,
Hey,
I'm a big fan and I want my kids to meet
you and my son's 11 and I want them to
come see one of your shows one day.
I said,
oh,
I think he should see me on my next tour
here in 20 slash 20 will.
He'll be like,
what?
13.
No problem.
And I'm not seeing my show is namby
Pamby,
but I want to be unavoidable where you
can write me off.
Say I'm wrong.
Fine.
Disagree with me that that's fine.
Like,
oh,
he's just a foul mouth so we don't have
to take him seriously.
I don't want to give you that handle to
jerk me around line.
I have a plenty of other handles.
You can turn it around by.
Um,
and so I'm just trying to not give
people that angle and it forces me to
evolve my point of view where those
words are fun and hyperbolic,
but they just don't necessarily don't
serve me.
They don't get across what I want to get
across.
That's interesting.
I would think that you're probably best
what you should do it anyway you want.
But what I'm.
What I'm thinking is that what one way
to use those words is to have your point
is clear as possible and then use them
rarely.
You know,
like one of the things when I was
starting doing comedy back in Boston,
they would do,
they would call the FEC meter.
They would say you don't want to go
onstage and say fuck every other word.
Because a lot of people use the word
fuck and place of the word Om.
You know,
they're like fucking guides fucking says
to me,
fucking,
I don't want to fucking tell you what to
fucking do that as you're just poor
communication.
This is a shitty economy of words.
So that word you've given it,
you've used it so many times,
you've given away all its meaning.
It doesn't mean anything anymore.
So when you do,
and I'm like,
fuck you.
It doesn't mean anything anymore.
Yeah.
But if you say it like once a year,
if you say fuck you once a year,
it means a lot.
Everyone will believe it.
Yes.
Like,
oh,
he's serious.
But yeah,
if you just drop it all the time.
And I,
you know,
I believe in the first amendment.
But um,
to me it's when you use that stuff,
you come in as one thing,
but everyone you kind of read the result
is something else to sell a lot of
people in front of some people's eyes.
Yeah.
I mean,
you certainly limit your,
a digestability yeah.
And impact,
you know,
I,
I'd rather be articulate than
overbearing and I,
you know,
I watched the news and some of these
pundits are very,
very educated and they're very,
very sharp.
They're for living,
they
comp,
they make commentary for a living and
they're damn good at it.
And you're like,
wow,
that's a hell of a sentence.
I might like to be able to have rock,
something like that Monday.
And um,
that's,
that's kind of what I admire as a,
you know,
I start shrinking with age.
Well,
as you know,
it's interesting that the difference
between writing something and saying
something,
so as you do your spoken word shows and
you have these stories that you want to
tell,
but I would imagine that you probably
write out a good most of it.
Do you do that or do some of it?
You just know the story so you just tell
the story the way.
When I'm out in the world,
I'll be out all day,
like taking photos or whatever,
fooling with the locals,
getting information.
Then I come back somewhere and I write
it up or we'll take,
you know,
sometimes you're in a place like Haiti,
you don't want to be outside at noon.
The Sun will just like beat you up so
you find shade,
make your notes.
So I'm always trying to make notes and
then at night I write it all up a lot.
That turns into a book,
like I use every part of the deer.
Like when I go somewhere,
I make soup jewelry,
a coat.
Every part gets used.
And so,
um,
the books come from that,
but some stories from those travels,
I mold them over in my mind and I like
the show for me when I'm onstage,
you just can't be mere rapport.
Tosh,
there has to be something,
there has to be an aroma coming from it,
there has to be built,
there has to be,
uh,
something that,
wisdom or some kind of melody that comes
from the raw information.
Like I took all these notes and got the
houses,
the holy album,
which is just,
if it's component parts,
but it was mixed together in a way where
it's like this beautiful thing.
And so that often takes weeks were like,
so I,
I saw this,
what was the story where the guy fell
over?
But no,
it wasn't six weeks of thinking about
it.
It wasn't him.
He's not the story.
It's the guy who is watching and did
nothing.
That's the story.
And all of a sudden the whole angle
changes.
And so I'll mull these things over
because I have a lot of time.
I live alone.
And so by the time a story gets to the
stage,
it's like a stone that's been rolled in
polished and I will.
There's parts of the valley,
Ventura Boulevard where at night there's
nothing but dog walkers and joggers.
All the shops are closed.
I will park in a parking lot and I'll
walk about a mile each way.
Talking out loud.
He saying the stories out loud.
Know you're looking for you now.
Yeah.
Henry's practice.
That is one man show.
That's why I don't get the location
because you will go,
wow,
I remember that one.
Um,
and I will let my brain here,
my voice say them and I'll make edits
while I'm walking.
Like,
okay,
no,
that's a dead end.
And,
and I,
and I've been doing this for years and I
do it on the treadmill and my,
you know,
like I'll just kind of mumble to myself
where people will come over to Jim,
like,
are you okay?
Like,
yeah,
I'm just,
you know,
just say actor.
And they'll go,
oh yeah,
know that that's the kind of preparation
I do because I don't believe in warmup
shows.
Like who wants to see her warm up show?
I go,
thanks for your demo.
Like screw you,
I paid money,
I won a game,
and so I only understand come in with
the a game and so I do all my
woodshedding alone and so by the time I
hit stage it's that story is very
evolved and then it continues to every
night,
you know,
I keep shading the parts off and it's a
chiseled thing of beauty a few nights
in.
Yeah.
I found that you really can only do so
much on the written page or on the
screen.
You have to evolve it in front of a live
audience,
especially with xander up,
which you're essentially doing.
You're pretty much,
you're doing very.
I mean I listened to a bunch of your
older stuff and it's essentially a form
of standup.
Yup.
It's like there's different kinds of
music,
right?
I mean there's rock and roll,
there's blues,
there's jazz,
there's different kinds of standup as
well.
Yours is a storytelling standup.
Yeah.
And with that,
it's going to evolve in front of the
live audience will,
like on my showtime special tomorrow
night,
tomorrow night at 10 on showtime,
showtime.
You'll hear stories and that's,
I'll keep talking to them.
And a lot of that is just storytelling.
And it is funny.
I mean,
but I always leave room in my resume
because I don't want to tie myself to
comedy because when I'm telling the
story about the,
the,
the part of wherever I would like
Bangladesh I was in that wasn't funny.
I don't want to be in a comedy club with
some guy going,
wait a minute,
I didn't pay for this.
You make me laugh,
idiot.
And so I don't want to be selling a
false bill of goods.
And so,
uh,
sometimes it's quite often it's funny,
but sometimes it's not.
But for me,
events plus time,
if someone didn't,
if there are no casualties,
if it was this mere injury,
maybe an eye it is pretty funny,
was a week later after the scabs have
fallen off a.
it's pretty funny.
Well,
the thing is also the you don't have a
restricted sort of form in which you
have to perform in by doing it spoken
word style.
You essentially can do whatever you
want.
Yes,
and I need that freedom.
He's like,
I can't be dependent on pond to make you
laugh all the time.
Right?
Yeah.
Like there's the thing about standup is
part of it I really liked because it
forces you to use an economy of words
and boil your ideas down into this very
clear rhythm where you really keep
hammering them with laughs,
but part of it is a win.
Where I get my freedom is from this,
like from doing podcasts like so I can
express myself in ways and get thoughts
across where it doesn't have to have any
form.
It can be funny or it can be.
It can be depressing or funny and sad or
it doesn't have to realize itself in 11
seconds.
Right.
And it doesn't have to have an impact
like this is the thing about standup is
that you're always getting a reaction
and if you don't get that reaction is
not successful,
you can call it whatever you want you to
say,
oh this is stand up,
but you know,
I'm talking about stand up or I'm
talking about things that are tragic in
my standup.
So it's deeper and more meaningful.
It's like,
okay,
but then it's not really stand up.
Stand up is funny.
Yeah.
And once it stops being funny,
then you're doing something else,
you know,
you're doing spoken word or you're doing
a play or a one person show or whatever
it is.
Right.
And I would never dare go into a comedy
club and do what I do.
You never do that.
You never go to the Improv or something
like that.
Two Times in my life.
One time the venue I was supposed to be
and got knocked out because of a storm.
And so they said,
we've moved your show too,
like the laugh dungeon that was in
someplace in the east coast with like
80,000 head shots on the wall,
that little part case stage,
the PV boxes,
the PA screwed into the wall.
And I did my talking show my audience.
They're all sitting at these tables
going,
why are we here?
And on the last big tour in 2016,
I don't like nights off.
They said,
okay,
thanksgiving.
I said,
find me a show.
They said,
we found your show.
It's a comedy club next to a strip bar.
And there's no backstage,
there's no monitors is two boxes in the
wall.
Family owned really nice people and I
forget where it was somewhere in
Illinois.
I was a one show one night my,
my tour bus was rumbling away in the
parking lot the next night I think it
was like three nights of Ralphie May,
the great comedian,
but it was a straight up comedy club and
I went in there and I just Kinda did
what I've been doing for the last nine
months on the road.
And a lot of it was very funny and the
audience was fantastic and so the owner,
I came up to her and said,
like,
I played this place again anytime.
Thank you so much.
And he said,
well,
you know where we are anytime.
We loved it,
we like you and you're always welcome
here.
And that I don't know if it was my
audience for a comedy audience.
I said,
how did the show too is,
oh,
it's sold out in a day.
I mean,
you know,
your,
your name and um,
I think,
but this is.
But I said,
so the audience is,
Oh,
I recognize these people.
This is my local comedy crowd.
There's just,
they just know you from sons of anarchy
or whatever.
So we'll see how you go.
And it was fine and it turned into like
this to our laugh riot.
I mean it was just great.
It was a super function.
You don't have an opening act or
anything,
you just go right out.
Because I torture him enough.
It's just me.
Can I ask you a professional question?
Feel free to edit this out when you're
on stage.
And like you're doing a big theater like
where you're the main guy at like a big
Saturday night somewhere.
How long are you on stage for?
Usually an hour and 10 to an hour and 20
minutes.
Seventy to 80 minutes?
Yeah.
Okay.
I just fascinated because I live in a
bubble.
I just do my own thing.
I'm onstage for like two hours and 40
minutes.
I bring an opening act.
And how,
what do they do between 20 and 30 and
how many openers?
One.
Sometimes they bring to that's rare but
it's usually just for fun.
So to have two people the most and
they'll do a total of 40 minutes and
then there's a brief intermission,
three Bang Bang,
Bang.
We go and the show could be 80 minutes.
Ninety minutes.
And so the whole thing you would to two
hours.
It's like two point something hours.
It could be two hours.
Yeah.
Easily.
But that's the whole night,
the whole night.
And Are you ever on your own with
nobody?
Never.
Okay.
So there's always an opener.
Usually one.
Yes.
And so that's 20 minutes and 70 to 80.
So the whole night is a little less than
two hours depending upon the show,
whether or not we have two shows in a
night.
A short show is an hour and a half,
which I like a rock 'em sock,
'em robots.
Hour and a half.
Like a movie.
You go to a movie and it's two and a
half hours.
Even if it's really good,
it's like,
oh no,
no.
You fill out a city last 20 minutes.
You really feel that lack of editing,
but an hour and a half as bang,
Bang,
Bang.
Good.
Yeah.
And so how many two night,
two sets of night do you do often?
Yeah,
I'll do seven to nine or something like
that.
I'll do it pretty often depending on the
size of the venue.
You know,
some places a giant place I'll do one
show or you know.
But I've done.
I've done a lot of,
especially this last year,
I did a lot of two shows that night in
big theaters and stuff.
You know,
it's a lot of turnaround too because you
got to clear out all those people
shouldn't get a new crowd in there.
I just,
you know,
I,
I work alone because I don't have a peer
group really.
If I do,
I'm not trying to find them and I,
I'm just curious about how other people
do their thing because I live alone in a
tour bus with you,
road manager and a bus driver and emerge
guy.
And I have no opener excepted in
Australia.
There's a rule they want one for one.
And so there's this open reviews for
years.
Australian Open,
we want,
you want American one Australia,
which I really like.
They used to do that with music,
you know,
they don't do that with me when I'm
there I bring American openers.
Oh well they with me the last few years,
like I've gotten to bigger places and my
agent and said,
okay,
you're going to have an opener.
And I've met.
I've used this guy,
used him.
He's,
he's done shows with me for like three
tours.
He's hilarious.
Really low keys.
A really nice guy.
I'm forgetting.
I see the guy every three years,
so it's not in the memory,
but he's great and he's,
he's super funny.
He's real smart and the audience loves
him.
I mean I think he's kind of known but
he's great and he's just like,
I don't know,
20 minutes,
whatever it is.
And then I go do my thing,
but that's per.
It's not in every city in Australia it's
like in a couple of places.
Oh.
So there's some kind of thing.
Regional rules.
Yeah.
And that's happened a few times with
what I would do music like,
okay,
four guys on stage we're going to have a
foreperson opener.
Like,
okay
man and I kinda like that,
like give the local band some time or
give the local guy a moment in front of
his hometown audience or let him tour
with me.
I love that idea,
but that's the only time it or every
once in a while.
I was at Bonnaroo once and it was
tremendously lopsided.
It was me and Tig Notaro who's amazing.
I don't know her very well,
but I've seen her on stage and she was
Kinda,
she didn't exactly open for me,
but she did like half an hour and I did
like an hour.
It was like,
and they cleared the tent and then uh,
uh,
cheech Marin came on,
but a Lewis black was before it was like
three tent loads of people in one night
at Montereau and that's the only time
I've ever done a is everyone's.
So I'll be the festival where you're
like the eight to 9:30 guy and then the
10:00 guy comes onstage.
But quite often I'm just on my own on
tour and I'm the only thing onstage.
It's a different thing for me.
I have to have my friends with me.
Otherwise I get bored.
Like I want,
I go on the road like
we want to take on the road with me as a
national headliner that would normally
be headlining somewhere on their own.
Like cool.
Double.
Yeah.
It's a cool double bill,
but it's also I want the best guys that
I can find that I pay them well to go on
in front of me.
I don't,
I don't want it to be a bad show by any
stretch of the imagination,
so I try to get the best guys,
but also by that,
then I'm traveling with the best guys,
so we're having fun.
Like we're,
you know,
it's,
it's a,
it's a weird group like standups.
There's not that many of us.
It was like maybe a thousand of us in
the whole country that are like real
professional comedians,
maybe 500 headliners and the whole
country.
So this,
there's just not that many of us.
And so when we relate to each other and
sort of a weird way.
Yeah,
well there's not many of you.
When presidents get together,
it was like four of them.
They all,
they're kind of chummy because they
might be opposed,
but they all kind of know they're the
only people who know that stuff.
Especially when they're out,
when they're out there,
he did their time and then they can
relax and they just look like they've
been sucked dry by a vampire.
That's why I noticed when the.
When Obama welcomed the president elect
trump to the Oval Office for that 90
minute meeting that trump thought was
going to last 15 minutes.
Obama looked like two-toned come moon.
He just like his skin was so drawn
across his face.
It's like a snare drum.
It must have been so exhausted and his
legacy is going to be taken over.
Just any president like George W dot
Bush was to meet a handsome energetic
guy when he got into office,
but eight years in nine slash 11 and the
invasion and occupation of Iraq on the
way out,
his face had fallen.
His hair had died.
And I,
I'm not a guy who hates him,
just disagrees,
but the presidency killed that guy.
I mean,
I just think the stress,
because you don't get the nice phone
call.
Hey the cat,
we got the cat out of the tree.
It's like,
hey,
we lost eight guys.
That thing you said go.
It went well.
I'm very curious to see how trump comes
out of this because he's one of the
older guys to get in there.
I think he's 70 or 71.
Right.
And in just in the past year,
like there's a picture of Bush for 2000
and 2000 and what I'm saying,
that's crazy.
It just,
it kicked his ass and I'm not trying to
put them in the majority of reality.
It's like when you see those really
amazing photos of Lincoln during the
civil war or Lyndon Johnson in those
think tank meetings,
him and Mcnamara,
his face is sliding off his skull
because he's getting those phone calls.
Hey,
we just lost six slash 600 guys.
Mr President really started to give you
this news because he insisted on getting
the bad phone call and you see what it
does to a human being.
And I noticed it with Bush and Obama
because those were trying times for both
presidents who was trying very trying
administrations and I wonder what it's
gonna do to a guy who doesn't take care
of himself,
who is carrying a lot of weight.
Probably nowhere near the best diet and
I don't,
I hope he doesn't have some kind of
heart attack.
I mean,
I'm not the kind of guy who wants people
to die easily could,
but um,
man,
you look at them,
you're like,
man,
you need to listen to the White House
doctor.
Get on a plan because they can really
rock you.
They can help you lose 40 pounds by
spring of next year and you can really
be,
feel better.
You look at him,
you're like,
man,
there's someone in the White House who
can help you with that.
Like they're paid to get you on the
track every morning.
They could get them up at five in the
morning and get them out there and it's
not going to do it.
He's got to watch Fox News.
Something that I agree or disagree with
those people on the TV's too bad because
the president has all those people who
are ready.
They're already in.
They're jogging outfits like a dog who
wants to go to the park,
waiting to train them.
And it's um,
and a dietician.
They can rock those calories.
I think he wants it.
I don't think he gives a shit.
Well,
you have to apparently drinks like 12
diet cokes a day.
That's one of the things they were
saying.
Would that wind that diet window you
were talking about?
Um,
when you do eat,
are you eating,
you have a family.
Is it the dinner table eating at home
with families.
That's,
that's the meal.
Is your family,
is that meal targeted like nutrition for
the kids' nutrition for Dad,
I'm here.
You guys eat smart.
The kids actually eat very healthy.
Yeah.
We've been eating together really
healthy since they were babies.
That's all.
I mean they're always eating vegetables
and some healthy meat and they eat a lot
of wild game because I hunt,
you know,
so they,
they really healthy.
They have.
It's an interesting thing with kids too,
if you,
if you shield them from interesting
foods,
like my eight year old loves Kimchi,
she loves like Spicy Korean fermented
cabbage,
which to a lot of kids would be
disgusting.
She loves it.
She eats like fucking plates of it.
And because of that she rarely sick.
You know,
she,
she eats a lot of probiotics and healthy
foods,
but they're always eating fruit and
vegetables.
They've been doing it so they're a
little kid.
We don't stop them from eating candy,
but I do tell them what candy is and I
showed them that sugar documentary and
I've talked to them in length about how
sugar didn't use to be something that
people ate all the time and it's a
really recent thing.
I've showed them photographs of people
from like the 18 hundreds and the early
19 hundreds.
Like,
look what these people looked like.
They were thin,
they were different,
they had a different diet,
but now we just eat too many
carbohydrates and it's fine every now
and then like don't keep it from
yourself,
but understand that these are empty
calories and they make your body.
They actually make you tired.
One thing I've noticed,
I look at people when I travel,
I just find that our species is
fascinating all over the world.
You look at people's teeth in parts of
the world were sugar and corn syrup is
just not normal and you see like these
75 year old women like carrying a couch
up a hill and their teeth are these
bright white tree trunks just like of
like they're never a good a fall out of
their heads and like no dentistry,
you know that no noticeable dentistry
and the teeth are gleaming.
White maybe darken from tobacco or tea,
but nothing like in the West where their
teeth are just getting assaulted by our
own diet.
And you see people have great age with
like they look,
they're just ripped and you look at what
they're eating.
Fish,
rice,
vegetables and it's all lean smart food.
And did the sugars are all a
monosaccharides,
like fruit sugar,
you know,
the occasional banana or orange is a
treat,
but you know,
the sugars really not in the Diet at
all.
Maybe shouldn't be,
you know,
but not like we're doing it now.
No one's ever done it by the way we're
doing it.
No one's ever been as fat,
you know?
And then we have these things to shield
people from,
we call it fat shaming,
you know,
don't tell someone their fat,
let them just be morbidly obese and go
through life at a massive risk of heart
attack or stroke or diabetes.
Don't say anything because then you'll
hurt their feelings.
Meanwhile,
you could say something to someone and
it might be uncomfortable in the moment
of,
Hey Mike,
Listen,
I don't want to be that guy,
but you got to lose some weight.
And then that guy could go and look in
the mirror and go,
fuck,
I really do need to lose some weight.
And then they'll lose some weight and
they'll be healthier.
They'll talk to you four or five months
later and go,
you know,
you fucked my head up that day.
And because of that,
I really started changing the way I eat
and I'm so much healthier.
I feel better because he's your friend,
my friend Tom Seger and and Bert
Kreischer.
They did this thing last year,
well,
two years ago where they did.
They had a weight loss competition.
And one of the things they kept doing is
fat shaming each other,
like ruthlessly and they would use
Hashtag bird is fat,
Hashtag Thomas Fat.
And they had this weight loss
competition and they fucking both lost a
shitload of weight.
I they both lost between 50 and 60
pounds and they looked fucking
incredible.
But then after it was over,
Tom was like,
dude,
let me tell you something.
Fat Shaming works.
It works.
It got me off my ass.
I realized I was a fat fuck.
And it made me lose weight.
It doesn't feel good.
That shaming thing is you.
Fat Shaming doesn't work on people
weren't fat,
okay,
it works on people who have a problem
but don't want to address that problem.
So you bring up that problem and then
they go,
oh,
you're making me feel bad by thinking
about my problem.
You're a bad person.
No,
you have a weak spot.
That weak spot shouldn't be there.
A good shouldn't.
You shouldn't Belabor it and constantly
ridicule someone for being fat.
But the idea that you're never supposed
to bring it up,
even with someone you care about,
even ingest or friends busting balls
like,
no,
you should bring it up because that,
that bad feeling is a gift.
It makes you realize like,
Oh my God,
I've been remiss.
I haven't been paying attention to my
own physical sovereignty.
You know,
I have control over what goes in my
body.
I have control over the,
the,
the amount of calories I take in the
kind of calories I have control over how
much body fat I'm carrying around.
And there's ways to fix it.
Yeah,
I think you should use discretion.
Yes.
And she's in line at the supermarket,
you know,
some people you'd like and you know,
it's just.
But it was funny to hear Tom just was
getting angry.
He's like,
fucking fat shaming works,
man.
All these people that say don't fat
shame.
Fuck.
That's how I got skinny fat shaming
works until.
But again,
don't be rude to someone out in public
for no reason to drive an 11 year old to
suicide.
Definitely don't do this.
But.
So yeah,
the little kids is the worst because
their parents will get them hooked on
those sugary sodas and once it's the
Goddamn Sodas,
man,
I mean that is one of the primary causes
for people being fat in this country.
And it just seems so innocuous.
It's just an glass.
I'll just drink this.
It's got some ice cubes.
No big deal goes down so fast,
tastes great.
And the weekends,
um,
I,
I like ginger beer and the,
the,
the Bundler Burke's.
It's the same power as a coke.
I mean it's a lot of sugar and I buy a
four pack and I have one bottle a week,
Saturday night,
my big drink,
like discipline,
he's going nuts.
Look at him.
He's got his drink,
the best tasting stuff.
But man,
it tastes good for a reason.
It's so sweet and like you just want the
next one when you're done.
But man,
I,
and I could drink all day but I just
can't do that to my system.
So I do one a week.
That's good discipline.
But it's like,
you know,
you still need to look forward to.
Do you have a diet that you follow them
that.
Yeah,
I mean I love ice cream so I don't eat
it.
Um,
you know,
I,
I try not to because it's just my body
is slowed down with age.
I just can't shed pounds,
but I've never really had a weight
problem.
I,
I've never like,
oh,
I got to like lose 30 pounds.
I just don't.
My metabolism is such.
Always kind of like a greyhound.
Like it was kind of nervous and we,
you're always working out as well.
I'm always kind of like doing something
and just kind of uptight.
Kind of nervy.
Will you talked the last time you were
about the fact that your parents had you
on Ritalin from the time you were really
small boy.
Who Do you think that just like wired
you in a certain way?
I don't know,
but I,
I would need a doctor to tell me,
but it was a,
it's not a subtle drug,
especially when you're a little kid,
but I try and eat as clean as I can
because more energy,
more,
less need for sleep and not feeling so
bad all the time.
Mentally,
like not feeling.
I don't want to do anything with a good
diet.
I mean I feel better mentally and like I
said before,
I've been struggling with trying to feel
okay,
not,
don't know.
You need to feel good.
I just want to be neutral.
Not just like,
not in deficit.
Okay.
To be here,
that's all I want.
I'm not asking for much and good.
I found a good diet.
Really,
really rocks that were,
I feel when I do the bad meal,
like a depression meal,
like tons of carbs for like a day later
I'm just like,
Oh man,
I'm feeling every bite of that and so I
don't want to feel like that.
So I'm like,
nope,
can't do that because it's just not
worth it.
So what kind of food you like?
What's a typical meal for you today?
I had a salad with some chopped up
chicken with a low calorie dressing on
it and a cup of coffee and tonight I'm
going to have a glass of carrot juice
with a splash of beet juice and probably
a cup half a cup of coffee.
The other half of the cup.
I started this.
That's your dinner?
Yeah,
I already.
Basically the salad with the chicken is
your whole day.
Yeah,
I'll eat tomorrow.
Wow.
I'll be good in Hungary tomorrow if I'm
feeling like I can't sleep.
I'm distracted from hunger.
I've got some peanuts in my room and all
of a sudden a handful of peanuts.
See?
Very clean,
neat,
very clean,
very clean.
Was like some kind of thing.
No,
no,
no.
I to clean because I have found I get
great results with it.
Like it is no joke.
It totally works.
And I,
as we do in our line of work,
I got a lot of stuff coming up.
A lot of suffering,
you know,
I got a TV show,
a lot of shows,
a lot of,
uh,
a couple of speeches.
I got a teaching a class at Ucla one day
coming up November,
but when you're teaching a,
they just want me to talk about music
and culture and I just got asked to talk
about change at another place and I have
a bunch of shows coming up from here to
Kiev,
Ukraine and just a lot of marks I got to
hit.
It's just what I do and so I'm basically
getting ready to walk out of the house
until about Christmas and the hitting
marks and not screwing up day after day,
night after night.
And so diet is a lot goes into that prep
big time.
Well,
I mean it makes sense if you,
if you're demanding that much out of
your body,
you really don't want.
Your body's struggling with shitty
nutrition.
I can't afford it.
Like I,
I,
my car can't go off the road.
I can't fail.
I'm going to be screwing up.
Like if I hit that set,
I'm going to be on a TV show soon.
I can't not know the lines.
I can't be tired.
I can't look like I haven't slept.
I got to be a game.
Do you take any vitamins or supplements
or anything like that?
I try and I forget and that they go
stale.
I have the five lined up.
My friend Heidi said,
okay,
here,
and I got into it and I,
you know,
eventually they get put in the cupboard
and then you look at like,
oh,
three years ago.
And so that's why I do like the carrot
and beet juice just so that those kinds
of vitamins are coming through and I do
that like almost every day.
I just liked the way it tastes too.
Um,
but no,
I can't,
I've never been able to stick with it.
I just forget.
Yeah.
Have you ever had anything that you took
that gave you great benefits?
I never noticed.
The only thing I've ever noticed is
restorative sleep for just general
concentration and wellbeing.
And the cleaner I eat,
the better I feel.
Caffeine,
I don't know if I get jumped up on it.
I can't tell.
And so as far as anything I've ever
done,
working out is an antidepressant.
Good Diet is an antidepressant and makes
me a more efficient way when I'm awake.
Other than that,
like I don't,
I've never taken cod fish oil or
whatever and said,
wow,
my joints feel better.
I've just,
maybe I'm just not aware enough or I'm
not expecting it to work so I.
I have no thing I can hold up and go
this.
This really helped me.
Besides physical fitness,
getting the work done,
like you want to alleviate anxiety
before an audition,
rehearse the wind prepared.
Then there's nothing to be worried about
because he can't wait to show the guy
what you got and so preparation,
good diet and and finishing the thing so
you can really clear the deck.
Those are the things.
Because for me,
my whole life is don't be depressed.
I worked so hard not to feel bad.
A lot of what I do is to not feel really
bad.
It's interesting that you've chosen to
do this in a non pharmaceutical way.
Specifically you've,
you've strategies,
just afraid of it.
Yeah.
I just don't believe that someone I
don't know can come up with the drug
that's going to work for my unique
little mind and I've seen people on
antidepressants.
I said,
so how's that working for you?
Like I think I'm losing my mind.
I've been doing this for three months
and I don't know who I am right now.
I'm like,
okay,
I have that problem anyway.
So I don't want any pharmaceuticals to
enhance that.
I'm just basically afraid that's a
legitimate concern.
Yeah.
I think the brain is real fragile and
I'm not one of those types.
You say all medication is bad.
I'm not that.
I just anything having to do with the
brain,
I'd rather just deal with what I got
right and use these more kind of on the
ground ideas,
like I'll just sweat a lot and I'm going
to do a lot of pull ups and whatever I
do,
oh look like a ton of pushups or like
get on the stationary bike or whatever.
I do feel better and when I eat the lean
fish salad,
you know,
the salmon and the spinach,
I do feel better.
I feel great.
Yeah.
Um,
and that's,
that's good enough for me.
Yeah.
You've got successful strategies they
working for me.
Yeah.
Now when you're,
you mean you do so many different things
at this point of your life.
Do you have specific goals that you set
out for the year or you were,
you would like to be a year from now or
do you just do things that are really
interesting to you and just pursue them
with passion and just let the chips fall
where they may I do that and I don't
have a goal like at,
at 65,
I want to be here.
I have no idea where I'll be.
I'm trying to get ready for 2019.
I have no plans yet.
I'm just hoping for a lot of work.
Um,
I don't have those kind of long range
plans.
Unfortunately.
I'm a short ranged to know ranged person
and a lot of my motivation is vengeance.
And I know that revenge and vengeance
are synonyms.
However,
the fact that revenge has [inaudible] in
it,
like,
you do this,
I do that.
Vengeance is just like the difference
between aggression and hostility.
Where you agro.
No,
I'm hostile.
What does that mean?
Wham.
With the ashtray.
That's hostility,
right?
You just hit me.
Yes,
but I'm not aggressive.
I just like watching you bleed and so
ridiculous.
Right?
But,
and I'm not saying it makes sense.
I know and so I don't believe in tit for
tat.
I believe in tit tat.
Watch me just jump up and down and just
break it all.
You want to prove yourself?
Yes.
This is a primary motivation.
So I wake up every day wanting to get
back at every teacher,
every guy at school,
every bad boss who would ever parent
irked me.
And like everyday I out everything you
man.
And that's why I like,
Hey,
it's four in the morning.
You want to work?
Yeah.
Like I'll work it in a snow storm.
Like you know someone I know,
like they go on vacation,
like Gavin,
nice vacation and everyday you're
getting Tan.
I'm not quitting.
Like it's ridiculous.
It's,
I'm an 11 year old.
It's insane.
So
juvenile and it's not cool but it has
fuel in some way.
I don't spray paint your house on that.
I'm not flattening your tire.
I'm just working.
And when someone goes,
oh,
I didn't get up early enough and get,
how'd you get five of those?
Because I got up at three and I stood
outside and I ate this rat tail and like
climbed the wall.
I got it.
And I got two of them.
And um,
because so you could have none.
Just I'm so mad and I'm not,
you know,
I'm not trying to get somewhere by
stepping on you to use it as a ladder
rung.
You cling to this.
This is not something you ever plan on
an abandoned.
It's the corner I come fighting out of.
It's my true north is like,
oh yeah,
thank you.
And I,
it really works and it's not like I'm
not,
I would never cheat someone out of
something or steal from them.
But um,
whoever gets up earlier is going to get
it.
Then I just won't sleep tonight.
My anger will keep me awake.
What,
what are you having for dinner?
This.
And that's all I need.
Like you say,
I can't,
then I'll just sit up all night to which
I,
that's all I need.
Who are these people like when you say
you say I can,
does anybody really say you can at this
point in time where you have to mentally
in my head.
Oh,
I totally manufacturer.
Are you kidding?
Oh yeah.
Absolutely.
Have these people in your head and as
Henry you're a loser.
I'm a loser.
Oh,
what the fuck are you?
Yeah.
And,
and this,
this doesn't mean I'm walking over to
hit somebody.
I'm not looking to get beat up.
I'm just motivating yourself.
Yeah.
And I don't have a T.
I don't have a bunch of.
I don't have an entourage of just all I
got is me.
So I get the pump pumps out,
go,
push her back,
push.
God is me.
I'm up in my office.
So you know,
like at four in the morning,
just like,
okay,
I'm on Australian jet lag.
I'm going to make it work.
I've been up since 1:30.
I'm going to work for 16 hours and I do
it.
Why?
Cause I'm mad at it.
Do I need to write another book?
Probably not.
Must die.
Yes.
I must.
I must put that into the world.
And so you create these people that are
telling you you can't do it.
Tells me I can't.
The world I make money.
I never counted the accountant does I,
I just,
we talked a few snakes shirts coming in.
I just say,
am I doing anything horribly wrong?
And she'll say it will from your
receipts.
It doesn't look like you eat very much,
but you sure seem to like records.
Are you eating those?
Um,
but past that I just book it,
put me in there like a here's five
shows.
Can I have five more?
So I don't really count.
I want to do well.
I want to pay my bills and I don't want
to lose my house.
I want to keep eating and filling the
car with gasoline and going to the
grocery store.
But I'm not
just trying to,
hey,
I got a lot of money.
I can hang around.
I,
I got some money in.
Excuse me.
I really got to go.
We still drove that boring car.
The Mazda six still keys,
get me from a to B,
super boring,
but damn z keep starting off.
Got Me here.
I love Japanese cars.
I got it because a Heidi said you're
getting this car.
The other car I had,
they took from me.
They,
the powers that be.
I was the voice of Infinity car for
about five years and they give you a new
car every year.
And that's a good car.
Wow.
Nice.
That's a great cod.
One of those big queue trucks,
those cute or whatever they are.
They're great.
Yup.
And it's the car of the future.
And um,
when the contract finally came to an
end,
they said,
okay,
we'll come and get the car.
This is a perfect example.
Joe will come and get the car in 30
days.
So what?
No,
come and get it tomorrow morning.
Screw you,
screw your car.
And I said to Heidi,
because she's the brains.
I said,
I need a new car.
She goes,
you're getting a Mazda six.
It's going to be blue.
And I'm picking the interior,
get in my car.
And we wanted to just get an infinity.
You're driving them forever because they
didn't want me anymore.
Well,
I mean,
all good things come to an end.
Wow.
Double fingers don't want me anymore.
And we went to,
we went to the lot and two hours later I
parked the Mazda six next to the
infinity that got taken while I was on
the set of the TV show the next morning
and I drove my new car to the set and I
kind of shit compared to the infinity
though,
isn't it?
It's a different kind of ride.
It makes sense.
It makes you very humble because you
floor it in the nine.
Durables go calm.
We're working in the sunflower seeds
fall out and every other car passes you
and you're.
I'm coming and uh,
yeah,
you get used to a nice ride.
Um,
but it's um,
and that was that.
She said,
oh,
well why don't you,
we'll take a couple of days.
I'll go,
no new car right now.
But that's my question,
like 9:00 AM tomorrow morning or to a
really nice car.
I mean,
you work really hard.
Yep.
How do you take any compensation or do
you have any like happiness that you
derive from buying something?
I have no.
You have a really good stereo stereo.
Yeah.
We talked about it last time you were
here,
your giant speakers,
but don't you want a car that has a
crazy stereos?
Well,
Nah,
I just go to trader Joe's and auditions
and to the Joe Rogan podcast.
No,
I live in really utilitarian life.
Like in La when I'm off the road.
You don't even wear a watch?
No,
I use the phone.
Um,
I use the watch when I travel just so I
can just see the time,
see the time.
Um,
but when I'm off the road I just use the
phone.
It's just laziness.
I'm,
I live very utilitarian here because
basically I'm just counting down the
days before I leave again because a lot
of my work happens out in the world
location,
like a film or TV show or just touring
or traveling.
Uh,
last year,
uh,
Heidi said something funny,
she's,
you're driving me crazy at the office,
like pacing and huffing and puffing like
a wild animal.
She said,
I'm going to book you a trip and you
can't know where you're going to the day
you leave.
I'm just going to get you outta here for
10 days because you're driving me crazy.
I will kill you.
So I said bucket,
and so I said,
all I need is the right electrical plug
in the basic temperature range so I know
how to pack.
She gave it to me and I picked the
itinerary up,
got in the car to go to the airport is
this nice lady,
takes me to the airport.
She goes,
where are we going today,
Hun?
I said,
let's see where the boss is sending me.
I'm going to Lima,
Peru,
and so I was in Lima and Cusco for a
week working on my book manuscript and
walking the streets up in the Peruvian
Andes up in Cusco.
And so I.
A lot of my life happens out in the
world,
so when I'm here I'm just editing and
prepping to get outta here.
And so a car,
low maintenance,
close,
low maintenance and conspicuous.
Yeah.
I tried trying not to have anything on
this shirt.
I'd love to have a listen to black
sabbath tee shirt on.
I'd wear that one every day.
I love that shirt,
but I'm always trying to slip through
crowds and just head down.
Just blank close.
That's a.
You have a very interesting philosophy
and like I said,
your work ethic and your flow.
It's very inspiring because it makes me
want to work more.
It really does.
When I talked to you and I listened to
you get plenty done,
sir.
I know I did,
but that's one of the reasons why I do
is because I get inspired by people like
me.
I get inspired by you and other people.
Like I love getting inspired.
I,
I live a fairly solitary life,
but I have a lot of heroes.
I'm a fan of bands and people.
I just dig presidents and,
and other people in other countries.
I go to see bands play and they don't
know what I have all their records.
I have the bootlegs Uber Fan of so many
people,
like a fraction my age.
Um,
it because I need that.
I need to be pumped up by other people.
And it works.
You put on someone's record,
Jack.
Yeah man.
That's great.
Well these 19,
what does he know?
He plays a guitar better than I'll ever
be like,
well,
what are you talking about?
And so it can come in all kinds of ways.
I need people,
amazing people when I travel.
So I,
I need that.
I'm in.
The only thing good about me in my
opinion,
is what I do like.
Don't be my friend.
I,
I'm,
I'm no good.
I'll help you move your house.
I'll help you move or painting your
house.
But I don't want to come to Thanksgiving
dinner.
I really don't.
But if you're in trouble,
I'll drive from here to Ohio to get you
out of the trouble.
I'm so happy to bail you out of a jam.
Let's don't want to come over for
dinner.
I don't want to come over for the
holidays and I less your William
Shatner.
Yeah.
Right.
So what's good about me when people are.
I would love to hang out with you.
I'm like,
no,
just use your books are interesting.
Thank you.
Let me go write them.
That's the only the,
the,
when I'm on stage or got the books of
the radio show I do on Kcrw,
that's my great human greatest hits the
rest of my life.
I'm just a nervous wreck trying to get
somewhere on time and kick ass.
And so I travel for months at a time
with road manager award.
My road manager of many years at top
guy.
Fantastic guy.
There's hours that go by where we don't
talk.
He's got a life.
I,
I have a life and we sit on the bus and
hours go by and there's no sound except
the TV,
whatever.
Xyz.
It's fine.
But um,
my,
what's good about me is what you see on
stage on the page when I do my little
radio show,
the rest of it.
I'm not good friend material,
but I will help your ass out of a jam.
Like,
Hey,
I'm in Long Beach.
Can you come bail me out of jail?
It's three in the morning.
I'm so ready to do that for you.
Like that's a very unusual,
quite.
I don't know why it is.
Why do you find,
I don't know,
but that doesn't bug me at all.
I'm just happy to kind of be the dog
with the ball.
The bottle of alcohol.
Yeah.
Yeah,
yeah.
Running up the hill.
Um,
cause I'm so happy to get you out of a
jam.
Just hey,
come and meet the family.
Please don't make me meet your family.
How did you meet Joey?
How'd you meet Joe Ideas?
Uh,
I think Heidi set that up.
You'd never met him before he shows via
Heidi via you?
Uh,
yeah,
I knew who he was and um,
he's a really lovable guy.
As soon as I met him I liked him just by
seeing them online,
but when I met him I read there's
nothing not to like,
he's so honest.
He's full,
full exposure,
like who,
who he is.
You get it in 60 seconds.
But I think it's why people like him
because there's no bs and like,
you know,
there's the good,
the bad of anybody.
He lets you know who he is in the first
five minutes and you can take or leave
it.
Yeah.
But there's no ambiguity.
And I really liked being around that
because you can be yourself because he
has shown up being himself.
He's not holding back.
That's a really good way of looking at
it.
You can be yourself because he is being
himself totally.
And he's not going to judge you on that.
It's going to give you the freedom.
He's going to be himself,
but give you also the freedom to be
yourself unlimited.
Yeah.
I mean we,
we spoke for a while on his podcast,
had a great time and he's one of those
guys.
If he called me at three in the morning,
Hey,
I'm in trouble.
I'm in San Diego.
I'm like,
hold on,
give me three hours.
I mean,
I,
I'll help like come
and meet the family.
I please just send those specific,
like so specific.
But know I'm just a,
I don't want to come over,
but you don't want bullshit smalltalk
and you've got things to do and you're
obsessed.
But.
But I'm,
I'm not what I'm trying to get across
as.
I'm not mean spirited.
I'm just so happy to help.
Just a little awkward.
Yeah.
But he always ready to help.
I think that this thing is,
the thing of that awkwardness is the
fuel.
It's like we were talking about about
having imposter syndrome that I don't
think it ever goes away.
I thought one day it would go,
it would go away.
I'm more comfortable meeting famous
people now than I've ever been before,
but I still feel full of shit.
I think you always will.
And everybody that I've ever talked to
that is any good.
They all say the same thing.
Like they all kind of feel like no one
ever feels like they're anything special
and you always like,
if there were any good they don't know
and you always ruthlessly self critical
and trying to get better.
I mean I've worked with big actors,
big,
Big Rock Stars and the Big Rock Stars
like one big rock star once one time
said to me,
I opened.
He said,
is there anyone out there?
I said,
uh,
like 19,000 people.
You smell the wd 40.
That's how they got the last thousand
people in.
Are you kidding?
He said,
I'm always worried that no one's going
to show up.
I said,
when was that?
Ever Been Your problem?
He said,
well,
never,
but who is this a?
See Jesus Christ who's just one of my
favorite people.
He's just so.
He's another guy.
He's honest.
How many people were like in some
floridian?
Those are the will be anyone other than,
oh,
no,
no.
And he goes out there and the place goes
nuts to show is great of course.
And I said,
you worry about people don't,
she'll get really depressed.
And I went,
okay.
And you know,
I did the beacon theater once many years
ago.
New York.
Beautiful Room.
Loved that place.
Um,
I was,
uh,
a few days later I was at mtv doing
something with like Matt Pinfield or
somebody that was living in New York and
I'm leaving in the courtesy lady.
She said,
hey,
George Carlin is in the green room and
he wants to meet you.
And went,
wait a minute,
dumb question.
The George Carlin [inaudible].
I've been listening to that guy since I
was an eighth grade class clown.
And occupation fool actually came out
for me to go to the record store.
They were not nice price records.
They were what was on.
That's how old I am memorized and by
eighth grade of course,
and I said,
George Carlin wants you to meet me.
Okay.
Walk in and there's George Carlin,
he's there to promote his next hbo thing
and he's going to do like multiple
nights at the beacon theater place.
I would never sell out who's going to do
a month or whatever,
and he said,
hey,
I'm.
I said,
Mr Carlos [inaudible].
I'm George.
I'm like,
wow.
She said,
Oh,
you did a book signing the other night
at tower records?
I said,
yeah.
He goes,
oh man.
It was so cool.
I was in line for like half an hour and
finally I got so cold.
I went home.
I said,
you waited in line to meet me?
He's like,
yeah.
I'm like,
why don't you just walk in like,
oh,
I can't do that man.
And he said,
so you just were at the beacon?
I said,
yeah,
it was amazing.
He said,
did they get the jokes?
I said,
oh,
that's not really what I do.
I said,
I'm sorry,
what do you mean?
He goes,
d to d,
Can you get to the audience?
So that stage.
I said,
it's actually a pretty big place.
It's a lot his feet to before the first
row.
I said,
yeah.
you're George Carlin.
I think you're going to do okay.
But he was sincerely wondering like,
is it going to be okay in there?
I'm like,
are you kidding?
You were handcuffed with lenny bruce in
the back of a cop car and you're asking
me if it's going to be okay.
Was He handcuffed?
Yeah.
It's a great book.
It's an that great book,
Ladies and Gentlemen,
Lenny Bruce.
Ah,
in that book,
it's a great read reading and a half.
I've read it like 22 years ago.
It was fantastic.
I think I read it that long ago to
forgot about dre was a time when the,
you know,
as,
as you know,
the first amendment was not being used
in Lenny Bruce's life towards the end of
his life and that was his.
Every standup thing he did was about the
law towards the end and using,
doing a show one night.
George Carlin was there under age and
George said something and they were
waiting.
They pounced on them and then they went
through the crowd Id id id.
Oh,
come here,
youngster.
And they handcuffed them together.
So I said,
and that's how you met Lenny Bruce,
right?
He said,
no,
I had met him before,
but he said like,
we were literally one pair of handcuffs
together just like the book,
but I thought that's easily.
That's not how we met.
I said,
so how'd you guys meet?
He said,
Lenny Bruce was very sympathetic to
young comics,
so what we would do is like he said,
give me your best five minutes,
and he would critique us.
Wow.
Soon as he tried to take your mature,
said,
no,
no.
He just.
He said,
look,
okay,
leave that part out.
That part sucks.
Do more of that in that first part.
Put it lasts.
You would like help.
When he said he was great with all the
young comics,
he said,
they'll give me your stuff.
Okay,
here's how you redo it.
Make it better.
I said,
so you had known him before?
He said,
yeah.
I said,
well,
because you know,
Lenny Bruce to me is a real,
again,
a hero and inspiration fought back and
um,
I,
I walked out of there until like,
you know,
the freezing,
east New York to take the end of the car
back down to the East village.
But the fact that here's this guy with
the point I'm making is stone cold pro
anywhere where I sell out half the
tickets he does 20 nights there.
I'm in know you'll never get out of that
shadow.
And even he is saying,
Hey,
I have a question and here's what I've
found with all of your big actors and
big,
the ones,
the ones I've worked with,
they are obedient to the muse.
They work for the art.
They are so subservient to the job.
It's not about,
hey,
I'm rich,
I'm populous.
Like dammit,
I gotta make this script come to life.
And they fear it like someone on their
first job.
And there might've been a middle period,
like in the seventies,
they had their idiot phase for three
years and they kind of went sideways.
But man,
the big actors I've worked with are just
so like,
okay,
this take is everything and it's a good
lesson.
You're like,
okay,
never lose that.
Yeah,
because that's what you have when you're
young and you're coming up and you're
starting to show promise and somewhere
along the line it seems like some people
get into this mindset that they deserve
it and when they deserve it,
it's a terrible thing that happens to
comedians.
There's something that happens.
Comedians when they can't relate to
people anymore and they stopped being
relevant and by George waiting in line
to see you outside in the cold shows
that he never really got to that place,
that that bad place and he was probably
the most prolific standup of all time
because he never stopped.
He would do a fresh hbo our every year.
Every year he would just sit down and he
would write it all.
He would write it all out and then he
would just kind of fine tuned it.
Sort of like you were saying,
you do nude,
fine tune it and performance after
performance and then put it on hbo and
then start working on the next one and
then just crank them out.
Yeah.
I was told by someone who had a in as
venue in northern California.
He just sits in front of the mirror
before the show and does the whole show
at hyper speed and the low voice.
Oh,
I did that on a TV show once means the
actors.
It was one of the actors ideas say,
okay,
everyone in my trailer and we did the
whole show at hyperspeed and the low
voice standing in a huddle was really
cool because we were in each other's
face going on.
It's funny and we just kind of did it
like this,
like crazy mumbling fest for like 20
minutes and we're like,
okay,
okay.
We got it.
We went out there and did it.
It was like live in front of a TV
audience and it was like I'd never done
that before.
He was really cool and apparently that's
how George preps.
Wow,
that's interesting.
I don't know anybody else who does that.
Most people don't even look at
themselves.
They don't stand in front of a mirror,
they just don't look at myself.
But I do one thing that actually works.
I pace.
And I,
I,
uh,
I quote Lincoln's speeches as a
centering exercise,
especially as speech from a,
like January 19th,
18,
38 kimmy some,
it's a famous speech.
He said when he was talking about,
will America ever be taken over by
anywhere else?
And he said,
no,
the only way America's going to fall
from within.
So we said,
should we fear some transatlantic giant
to cross the ocean and crushes us a
blow?
Never,
uh,
all the country in Asia,
Europe and Africa with their war chests
combined,
ours with charges of the world aren't
accepted.
And Bonaparte as a commander could not
in a trial of a thousand years so much
as take a sip from the river or a tread
on the,
on the Blue Ridge mountains.
Uh,
if suicide,
if destruction be our lot,
we,
uh,
we must,
either live through all the time or die
by suicide.
And I just take chunks of that speech
because it's so easy.
It's like 28,
29 years of age.
He's so eloquent.
A sentence of Lincoln is worth 10 of
anyone else's.
It's all online for free,
but go to the.
It's called the speech to the young
men's lyceum or the perpetuation of our
government institutions and it's like
3,200 words and it's.
It'll be the best thing you read this
week.
It hasn't work as a centering exercise.
I don't know.
I just get in the Lincoln framework
where words matter to him.
He's a lawyer and a politician,
so he's a double bastard.
I was in the vault of the Lincoln Museum
in Springfield a few years ago.
They let me in and they pull it out of
one of his,
a beaver skin top hats and they.
They won't let me touch it.
Of course I didn't try,
but the guy with the gloves pulls it out
and he said,
do you notice an indentation on the
right side of the brim?
I said,
yeah.
He goes,
what do you think that is?
I said,
let me guess there.
There's one on top and two underneath,
and I looked and there was,
I said that's him doffing his cap,
his hat over and over again,
which,
what wears out the beaver skin.
And he said,
yeah,
how do you think you wore it out?
I said,
he's a politician and a lawyer,
so he's trying to get everyone's vote.
And when.
So he's like,
good morning,
good morning world,
because I have an office and I'm running
for office.
And he said,
yeah,
that's probably it.
And um,
that's funny.
These beaver skin line,
their hats.
Well,
it was the outside of it and this famous
hats,
you saw him in the Lincoln Museum.
They have one in the vault and literally
he wore out the hide.
Wow.
Um,
but I use Lincoln and amendments from
the Constitution.
Um,
the 14th is a,
is,
it's in four parts or five parts.
The top part for we the people,
the rest is legal ease and I'll do that.
Or the fourth amendment.
The privacy one.
That's a great one.
It's not completely in the front of my
brain pan,
but I carry a copy of the constitution
with me whenever I travel and I open it
like people open the Bible and all just
pick an amendment and read it.
Really?
Yeah.
And I,
I have,
uh,
one of those,
the constitution for idiot books were
like lawyers write about here's when it
was brought into law,
here's why.
Here's what it means in layman terms.
And it's never not interesting to read.
The constitution is great.
It is fascinating and we think this is
an experiment in self government that
these people from 300 years ago put
together.
It's Kinda,
they kinda are gods to me in that they
couldn't see the future.
Maybe they couldn't see the Ar 15,
but Jefferson and company definitely saw
how easily corruptible humans are.
You give him a little bit of power.
We can get a little crazy.
And American democracy is really all
about the checks you like,
you're,
you're a bad ass,
but you're not a bad ass as Congress.
Congress is going to check.
We're seeing now with,
I mean trump where we're essentially
seeing the reason why all these checks
and balances are put in place in the
first place because he's just like him.
Yeah.
Because we have president comes from we
the people.
It can be you or me potentially and I
think the framers really saw that like
it should be from the people.
So we got to put this person in checks
because he might be a failed
businessman,
bad reality show actor who doesn't
understand.
I have to read 1500 pages of stuff this
weekend and have five lawyers advised me
no golf for fun for me.
I'm the president and a lot of
presidents do understand before they go
in,
like,
boy,
this job's going to be boring and a lot
of people are going to be mad.
And in my lifetime we finally have a
president who really is from the people
who says,
uh,
he looks at like,
you know,
here's eight folders of stuff to read.
And like,
I don't think so.
Give me the cliff notes.
Yeah.
Like I'll play it from the hip.
Like,
no,
I'm going to watch Fox.
And friends,
you tell me what I needed to know and
you know,
it's not for me to sit and rip on the
guy because he's not here to defend
himself,
but never in my life have I ever watched
an American president thought to myself
I could have done better in that
situation.
And there's presidents,
I've had nothing but disagree with,
but they were way better for the job
than I ever could be.
I look at this guy and be like,
man,
you just got played and there's
something out.
When I knew I was going to be talking to
you,
there's a thing I was thinking about,
um,
because I,
I,
I heard you speak many years ago about
these politicians are gangster.
He said like,
okay,
what that guy did that's Gangsta and
what this guy just did straight up
gangsters during the Bush
administration.
You are just,
I think it was like Halliburton,
all these people that change the world
and you're like,
that's a gangster move.
That's a gangster movie.
I'm like,
I can't disagree with anything he just
said.
And on that kind of level,
I think what I hear is that Donald trump
is a guy who gets consistently played,
rolled,
got rolled by his wife,
who a woman I have nothing against,
but she comes from a really tough part
of the world,
Slovenia as just a rough patch or real
estate.
She's smart,
she's tough.
And she got out cut to America.
Well,
he's not much on looks,
but it's a way in from the storm.
So he got played by his wife.
He got played by Paul Manafort.
He got played by Kim Jong Un.
He got played like Jimi Hendrix at
Monterrey that that particular
stratocaster by Vladimir Putin and gets
played like rock modern off every single
day.
And anyone he does high stakes business
with negotiations.
He gets played,
played and and Manafort just used him to
try and get out of debt and all these
other people,
they just roll all over him.
And unfortunately his Hubris is such.
He's like,
ha ha,
like no dude.
You just got blown out and like everyone
around you is playing you.
We probably doesn't feel that way with
manafort because manafort's on trial and
he's not yet right,
but manafort playdom [inaudible]
manafort really does play in that world
of oligarchs and millions of dollars in
laundering money.
If he wrote a book I was telling someone
the other day as I have all these
people,
he should write the book because it
would be a page turner if he told the
truth,
would get him killed.
He touched the wrong door knob and he
gets poisoned because Putin can't have
him telling what he knows.
He's a man that he probably will go to
prison.
Watch him have some kind of strange
accident.
He was liquefied in the shower.
Something about the water.
Um,
because he knows a lot and there's a lot
of people who can pay a lot of money to
keep his mouth shut.
Yeah.
Well,
you know what's fascinating to me is
that over the last year too,
especially from the Fox crew,
you're seeing Vladimir Putin admired.
It's very strange.
I never thought we would see that.
I was watching a something a couple of
years ago,
a year ago,
and I was like,
some guy,
well,
he's a good Christian man,
and he believes in family.
I'm like,
he's the butcher of Chechnya.
Let's flash back to the 19 sixties.
I'm a young boy on the weekend visit
with my father to the right of my father
is a wall.
There's nothing to the right of my
father.
Just nothing.
And um,
if he's still with us,
he'd be in his nineties and hard as a
rock,
just like nothing.
He's like a bar of Hickory.
Anyway.
Um,
he's an economist.
He's a numbers guy and a phd.
Real smart.
I'm coming home to my mom's apartment
from the Saturday,
Sunday visit with dad.
We're in the Washington DC area.
I'm a little boy,
five years old,
somewhere around there.
Very small economist and Communist.
I don't know what either of them are
arguably to a five year old.
Kind of sounds the same.
I'm in the big buick station wagon to my
father's right.
We're pulling up to mom's apartment.
Henri Dad,
are you a communist?
I don't think my father's facial
expression changed.
His right hand came off the wheel and
his backhand collided with my head.
It was just like,
I hear the word Communist,
a boy get smacked and it was without
hatred or violence.
It was like national security,
like whack.
He didn't even know he did it.
It was like a sneeze,
like Kapow and it hurts so much.
My head went numb and it was not even
the pain.
It was the shock of,
uh,
your dad whacking you with,
you had no idea what you did and all I
could do was hyperventilate.
And he opened the door and he let me
out.
He didn't say a word.
He didn't tell you that there's a
difference between a communist and an
economist.
So I left for like,
till I was like 33,
you know,
you know what I mean?
Cause it's so destabilizing.
Like your dad just walloped you and I
get out of the elevator.
I go into the apartment,
but I did that till I was like,
you know,
until two years ago it was totally.
She said,
honey,
what happened?
I said,
I asked dad if he was a commerce.
She's like,
okay.
The point I'm making is this,
there's a bunch of people who voted for
trump.
Were you say Russia.
They say a bunch of sons of bitches.
Trust them as far as you can throw your
car.
Are you kidding?
And when I see staunch conservative
Republicans is going,
well,
that Burton guy,
I'm like,
are you kidding people like,
my dad's heads are exploding.
He's an old Cold War Guy.
We would wash a Boris and Natasha,
whatever that cartoon was as a Winco.
Yeah,
as a kid,
I'm laughing because the guy with,
uh,
my dad's laughing on a whole other level
because it's Cold War funnies.
It's was written for the parents.
The kids get the cartoon.
The parents got the jokes that,
that was for adults with their kids on
Saturday.
You watch them later on,
you're like,
oh,
this is cold war humor.
I wouldn't have known,
but that's my dad's world.
You say Russia,
he'd probably hate my guts because I've
been there six times for shows and to
take the Trans Siberian express.
And so this warming up to a guy who is a
true bad guy,
he's scary.
There's bodies buried because of him.
He's one of the scariest cars on the
planet in and capably violent.
And we'll have you taken out.
I mean like an a political sky.
One of the greatest journalists of our
time.
She was critical of Putin and she got
assassinated in your apartment building.
Her books are great.
Her books from Chechnya are amazing.
And like he was,
she was critical of him and she had to
go.
And when you see our president cozying
up to this guy,
I just want to go,
bro.
Let's talk.
Let's take a walk in the garden for 20
minutes.
You can't be friends with this guy.
My theory is he,
there,
there's,
there's some kind of finances.
Whereas he's got a stick up for him.
I don't think it's a tape of people
urinating on anyone.
I think it says money too cliche to
interesting.
Um,
it,
it's,
it's a,
it's a money thing.
It's a hotel deal.
It's money sitting in Cyprus.
It's something.
But the fact that we're being becoming
okay with this guy,
that is the part that bugs me the most
and why people in Congress or guy like
Sean Hannity who like probably likes
Communist as much as my dad even me.
I trust people like that at all.
Putin is a criminal.
Should be in jail for a million,
billion years.
And the fact like,
Hey,
he's like when he's a strong leader,
he,
he's a,
he's a human being.
We can talk like,
gosh,
he's a kgb guy who and there's no such
thing as next KGB guy,
right?
Yeah.
Gb for life,
for life.
And he's a supreme operative.
And what he does is he,
he rolls people like you dude.
And like cut you are a guppy.
He's a shark.
Like uh,
no.
Two guys hanging out.
No one guy getting played in one guy
playing someone.
I think he admires the fact that Putin's
able to run his country the way he does
too.
Yes.
And that's why he likes to tear Tay and
wound.
And I've been tested.
We said about,
Ooh.
He said he's a strong head.
And I was.
Countries,
I've been to the Philippines,
I've been to North Korea,
they're tough places to live and like,
you don't want your country looking like
those places.
You don't want America to be like Russia
if the economy is destroyed and there's
a lot of people like in the wintertime,
it's really tough.
How do you think the scene is the scene?
He goes to jail?
No,
no,
because I don't believe in Karma.
Karma.
Here's my two words that disproved
Dick Cheney,
he's got a new heart and a new heart.
He has no pulse,
which is perfectly.
He's got a pulse now with the new heart
machine.
Yeah.
Machine.
And he just heard a wash,
which is perfect for him.
He may very well live because he looked
like he's watching his weight now.
He's like looking lean.
He might live to be 105.
Um,
and so he'll never go to jail.
And like how many millions does he make
a year?
Just from his dividends,
from whatever.
Like who knows what you do with that
kind of money?
I don't know what you do with it.
And so I don't think he goes to jail.
I don't think jared cushner goes to
jail.
I think it most,
they leave like maybe next year.
And they go like,
I drained the swamp I did when I came
here to do.
And the fake news media brought me down
and all his people buy one of
everything.
He makes forever stake vodka.
I think it's possible that Donald Trump
jr goes to jail.
It's very possible they're talking about
perjury charges against him now because
his own dad admitted on twitter.
I follow all that stuff as you know.
I just don't think white collar guys go
to prison for stuff.
I just don't believe it.
You know,
I want to be proven wrong,
but I don't have all the facts.
I'm a,
I'm a news watcher.
I know nothing.
I don't get any classified briefs so I
only know what I read and what I.
He talk about any of this stuff and your
stage act a little bit.
But knowing my audience,
they're very sharp and they read the
readers and they don't need me repeating
what they know.
And so,
well,
good for you for that.
If I make a point as my dad used to say,
you want to score hidden where they
ain't the baseball idea.
And so if I can make a point,
like if I was on stage tonight talking
about trump,
I would roll out that idea of trump is a
guy who's been played by so many people
around him and no one talks about his
wife playing him.
Like there's no love in that marriage.
I don't think she saw a way out.
Came to New York and went,
that guy gets naked with the toad a few
nights a month,
a handful of Prozac,
some Stoli and a credit card and a seven
figure expense account.
You can take a shower and make it go
away.
Um,
so I,
I think he,
and I think he kinda knows that,
you know,
she was not like,
wow,
what a hot gosh.
She's like,
Hey,
and this,
you know,
that happens a lot in this town.
You'll see that yield the couple.
And you're like,
okay.
Yeah,
right.
Harvey Weinstein,
before his,
uh,
for his wife left him.
Harvey Weinstein's wife is beautiful.
Well,
yeah,
but you see that a lot in this town
where you see the,
the old weird dude with like the,
the eight year old girlfriend.
You're like,
oh yeah,
that's a,
that's a setup.
That's an agency.
That's an agreement.
That's someone's getting a salary or an
implied,
you know,
it's,
uh,
there's some kind of quid pro quo.
There's a credit card,
there's an expense account or there's
just a,
a big fist full of hundreds and just let
me chew on you for the next four weeks
or whatever the agreement is.
And,
and I.
So if I was going to say anything about
Donald Trump on stage with Alex and I,
I never talked about any problem
onstage.
And I learned this from,
of all people President Clinton,
because some of his later has
post-presidency I'm not a huge fan of
the guy,
but he's a good speaker.
And he did some speeches in the UK a few
years ago and I happened to be in in
England when he was there and I watched
him on tv the last part of this huge,
the last 10 minutes was here's a problem
and here's three solutions.
Here's another problem here.
Three solutions were like for for
$60,000,000 we could put Internet
through this thing or we could open this
waterway or we could reconfigure this
workforce to upgrade so everyone can get
a paycheck.
He just had logical ways forward.
So what I took from that is to my
audience,
don't propose a problem.
Will he sucks.
Thanks.
Good night.
Don't give them a Gordian knot unless
you can go.
Actually it's not a Gordian knot.
Here's three ways to get out of this
burning rec.
And so like when when trump became
elected,
it was,
I was on tour,
I was doing a bunch of nights in La and
I said,
okay,
you have a new president and some of you
are depressed.
I said,
I know.
And so gay people are on the endangered
species list.
It's as if they've never been brown
people,
black people,
women,
people,
people with ovaries,
these were all on the you're screwed
list.
So instead of being coming depressed and
oh no,
let's we get up,
we start doing more benefits now.
All your words matter.
Your actions matter.
How you stick up for your lgbt friends
really matters.
Now,
how you stick up for women,
how you stick up for racial equality,
equality in the like how you check
yourself.
When you rule a view with other people,
words matter,
actions matter more than ever.
And so to me,
it's an exciting time to show how great
you can be because now it's all on the
line.
The fat is off the land.
We're being tested.
I love a test,
so let's get it on.
It's like a in your line of work.
When the guy goes,
here we go.
That's how I saw it.
Like,
okay,
let's let's get the money to the ACU.
Let's get some money to planned
parenthood.
Let's get a conversation going about a
child suicide,
intimidation to facebook.
Let's start making things better because
this guy is not our ally.
Governments not necessarily going to
help at its best.
It's inactive at its worst.
It's divisive and predatory,
so let's be the antidote by being cool
by not throwing rocks through windows or
like you getting into the Tiki torch and
beating them up.
Come on,
I'm.
You're never going to convince that guy
that he's wrong,
so get to the people you agree with and
let's start sticking together more and
raising more money and get some more
interesting people in office and let's
get some young people in office and I
think that's what's happening.
Like you're seeing all these young
people like twenties,
thirties.
Sadly,
there's a bunch of kids who died at a
high school in Florida,
but look what happened.
Look at all those kids hitting the
streets.
Look at all these kids who through cell
phones and selfies and instagram and
snapchat,
they're already ready for primetime.
You see these high school juniors in
front of a CNN camera going,
hi,
I'm 17 years old.
This happened to my school and next year
I'm going to vote and here's what's
going to happen and here's the march.
I'm starting like,
oh,
that's a future senator.
You just.
That school shooting just birthed a
voting demographic.
Are you kidding?
All those kids are going to vote.
All of them,
all those kids who marched,
there's going to be no millennial apathy
with those kids that are all going to
vote.
I kind of have an idea what side they're
going to vote with and if you think
you're going to sell those kids on their
grandfathers,
drunken homophobia,
racism,
and just overall bigotry and xenophobia,
you're wrong.
He never had a password.
I don't need to travel.
I don't want to meet some damn Mexican.
Trust me,
the kids going to travel.
He's going to go to India.
She's going to go to Columbia and meet
other people and get a more global sense
of the world.
A sense of water,
food,
energy,
where it comes from,
what happens with money,
what happens with mediocrity,
the danger of it.
So I think we're in for some tough
times,
but I think they're going to lead to
good times and so that's.
If I get political onstage,
all I say is like,
here's five ways forward because the
despair part you like,
you need me to tell you,
you watch the news,
so don't get down in the mouth,
start burning more calories and that and
that's not my job,
but I would never weigh in on stage any
other way about that stuff because all I
would be as obvious
and my audience is pretty sharp and they
don't need to be told twice.
Outstanding.
Thank you sir.
Well said.
I couldn't agree more.
Friday night show time,
August 10th.
Henry motherfucking Rawlins.
Keep talking,
keep talking.
pal.
Thank you sir.
I really appreciate it.
That's great.