Four,
three,
two,
one.
Boom.
Tony Rock live.
That's a bold choice in shirts,
sir.
I like that.
Thank you.
I think it brings out my skin tone.
It breaks out.
It's got a pop to it.
Yeah.
And uh,
you know,
a rocket with the shades on so,
and driving windows open and girls are
looking like,
who's that guy?
So yeah,
and you're,
you're an android guy,
you're a different kind of person.
Android people are different kinds of
people.
What kind of people are.
Well the people that like think about
it.
Like I don't know about this,
you know,
everybody's like,
I need an iphone.
Your iphone,
ipad,
android.
People like,
Eh,
I'm not so sure.
I think I could rock a pixel this,
this takes great pictures.
It's very easy to figure out.
So I don't know.
I've never been an iphone guy to choice
that people make.
They just decide it's a nonconformance
choice.
I take the blue pill or the red.
I think they're both like,
it's no denying the iphones are bad ass,
but it's no denying those are basically
just as bad ass.
That just different.
Everything is just different.
Now,
exactly.
It's caught up.
Go with what you're like,
man.
Yeah.
It used to be like if you had a
blackberry and somebody else on an
iphone,
you felt like a loser.
I felt like a loser with you just to
back people had the phones that you
could just exactly your number and you
didn't have one.
You would just ass out.
That's right.
Remember everybody had like a little
laptop.
They send me your number.
You would just scan their phone.
What was that thing called again?
A side something or another.
What was that called?
What was it called?
The sidekick.
Was it?
Is that.
What?
Is it called side?
No,
that wasn't.
That was the original drug dealer.
Right?
You sold weed.
You bought a Suzuki sidekick.
You with a man?
Oh,
Tony Rock.
I'm so happy that you agree that the
fanny pack is back.
The fanny pack is back.
It is right.
If any packets back.
It's a little more stylish fanny pack.
Now people are wearing shoulder.
That's the coward's way out.
That's a coward.
You still want it on the stomach.
Yeah.
You rock it right in front of you.
That's where it's most convenient.
Say Boys,
you don't have to be trying to get laid
all the time of relapse.
You want soccer,
dad?
Look,
you just want the convenience of having
that bag right there.
Why can't I leather?
I don't want to have to carry shit.
If you want leather.
Fuck.
Yeah.
You want a name like Fendi or Gucci?
Cross this right here,
Bro.
Oh Wow.
That's nice,
right?
Yeah.
That's very nice.
That's very naked and afraid.
Wish you could keep this shit on.
You feel uncomfortable.
You got your keys.
You got your phone.
You don't think about shit.
I got keys.
Phone,
wallet in my pocket.
I'm good.
People are tired of hearing about this,
but I'm telling you it's the way to go
to pack his bags.
I got one that I wear when I run.
Oh,
so you have more than one?
Yeah,
I've got.
I've got a neoprene one.
You have the running fanny packs.
Dude.
It's nice.
You slip your phone in there.
Get a little headsets on.
You can cheat with your music.
Jamie.
I've been cheating.
I cheat when I run.
Now I listen to music.
It's better.
You guys were all right.
How's that cheating?
I used to say that if you run,
if you ran running,
especially running hills is difficult,
so you should do it with no music.
You shouldn't be like,
you just zone out.
Just fucking do the work that I get it a
couple of times with music.
I'm like,
this is way better.
Yeah,
I think you're supposed to.
You supposed to hear a little,
you know something that gets you going.
Yeah,
it's way better.
It's way better treadmill.
You get on the treadmill,
just music go.
Yeah.
You just got to hear it.
As long as it's not too loud.
The thing about running in the
mountains,
it's like,
what if someone's screaming for help and
you know you're running by there already
in the mountains and the they need help.
There's nothing you can do already.
This Laurel Canyon,
you know what?
If you just run it up,
the candidate to be a good person,
if they where they need help,
they need you to help them take an
instagram picture.
Probably in Laurel Canyon,
half of the people there just like I to
get a good shot.
I know how many people hike just to get
a good shot at the top.
It's good instagram photo a lot.
You can get a lot of likes.
Yeah.
That's where they go for.
They go for the legs.
Hey.
It's some sort of commodity seems to be
right.
Uh,
if you're,
if you're a girl with a,
with a nice body,
a bunch of likes seems to translate into
a hosting parties for some reason.
Oh yeah,
that's right.
Yeah.
You only have a certain amount.
You go to a club and it's hosted tonight
by like,
who is,
who the fuck is this girl?
Well,
it's the minimalist approach,
right?
It's like not only is it not,
she doesn't display a talent,
but you also don't even hear a talk.
He just see the pictures.
But just that enough is enough that
people are going to want to go see it.
It takes less and less and less and less
to be a celebrity these days.
That's a strange one though,
isn't it?
To be considered a celebrity.
Yeah.
That's,
uh,
that's one of the weirder ones.
One of the weirder ones is getting down
to just being famous for photographs.
Yeah.
They call them instagram models.
So there's an instagram modeling agency,
but here's the thing,
am I hate her for saying that because I
like to look at them,
be upset.
I appreciate you ever at someone who's
making something that I like to look at.
Right?
There you go.
I'm not mad weird that people would be
like,
fuck these instagram posts.
They're big ass isn't okay,
but don't you want to see those
pictures?
I love to see the pictures and I think
those are the guys.
Those are the guys that they're not
fucking medicine that,
you know,
we're all hypocrites.
That's just nature,
right?
It's the way it is,
the way of the world.
We have the land.
Yeah,
that is right.
And is just,
it's just such a fascinating thing that
people can just show you a little images
there world.
Hey,
this is me at the grammy's take way more
interesting than it really is really
cultivated,
you know,
make it look like they're really in
vacationing all the time.
And they have the least close and they
go to the best parties and meet them in
a live in studio city with four
roommates in the studio.
Puppet.
Yeah.
We all want everybody to think that
we're doing better than we are.
Right.
Why is that?
What's that about?
Because if people think you're doing
better than it makes you feel better
because they treat you like you're
doing.
They treat you like you're at the level
that you're fixed fictitiously
portraying.
Right?
Right.
So,
you know what I mean?
So you get better treatment based on a
life you don't really live.
Right?
So if you become insta famous,
like what do you get out of that?
You could see you could make a living
off of that.
We'll see comics doing it all the time.
Yeah.
There's a comics or kyle done again.
Dude.
Carl Dunnigan blew up because of those
little videos that he puts on his.
Do you ever see that?
No.
Fuck you.
Hilarious.
Does face swaps with Kim Kardashian and
Donald Trump?
You never seen it?
Oh my God.
Please go back to the one where,
uh,
bruce is telling them he's pregnant.
See if you could see if he could find
that one.
Dude,
he's genius.
Really?
He does Solo.
Dude.
It is the funniest page on the Internet.
I'm not bullshitting.
Kyle Dot Higgins.
Instagram pages.
The funniest page on the Internet.
Okay.
That's saying a lot.
Dude.
I swear to God I,
because I have yet to seen a really.
Well,
I've seen a few,
but then they kind of just fizzled out.
I cry.
I showed the one with the Kim
Kardashians.
The washing machine,
the dishwasher or the,
uh,
the,
the clothes washing machine.
The one where she's lost in the house.
Dude.
Here it goes.
The buildup.
Whereas it,
it can.
I'm a loft in my house.
Oh Shit.
Look at your surroundings.
What do you Shay?
There's this white box.
White box.
I don't know.
I put north and died three.
Oh,
you're such a great thing.
All right.
Let me get Connie on the phone.
He said Jane Yesh.
Yeah.
Called Kanye and Kanye again.
You know what?
That white box behind
do.
Deeds don't know my girls.
Space Rock
captured
grandma too.
He'll save you from outside.
Shit,
it's so silly.
He's so silly that he's talking to
Donald Trump.
No,
he's got a shitload of a man.
You got to go to his page.
I got to follow all of his pain.
There's nothing like a regular person on
his page,
right?
There's nothing like,
here's me at the fixtures.
Have Dinner.
Go look at this sunset.
No,
there's none of that shit.
His page is basically like a channel.
Oh Shit.
He's at 300,
$4,000.
He deserves it.
He had done a good man.
I'm telling you that this is the
funniest page on the Internet.
I got to follow it.
Oh my God.
Kills me.
It's such an interesting.
People use it,
right?
Some people use instagram correctly,
people it,
but more importantly,
this is like a new thing.
He's able to put his,
like his use his mouth and use other
people's faces for the first time.
Like when has anybody ever been able to
do that without some great giant studio
behind you?
The fact that he can do all this shit on
his phone.
Progressive.
This is a new feature.
You can do it on your phone.
You can download that.
No,
no.
I know you can do it,
but I'm saying that now it opens up this
whole new kind of comedy.
That's a new kind of comedy.
I love it.
We,
I mean,
we know he's not those people,
but he's doing those people.
It's like a ultra hilarious impressions.
It's his own snl on his phone.
You got to see him do bill Maher,
find the bill Maher one.
His Bill Marwan is fucking genius.
He sounds exactly like Bill Maher and
then he's got bill Maher's face.
Shit is so funny man.
He's so good.
This is just like a new thing.
People.
People get this,
uh,
this new opportunity to do shit on.
You know,
the Internet is so interesting in that
way.
Just as some new thing opens up and some
comics.
Oh look at that.
It's my space.
Was that twitter?
Was that?
Yeah.
Facebook was that.
Well,
I had seen people do like little things.
Here it is.
Look at this.
Here's,
Oh really?
A cow jumped over the moon.
It took NASA astronauts going 17,000
miles an hour wait to get to the moon,
which is bullshit.
I cow couldn't jump over one of you
stupid idiots during nap time.
Okay.
Oh,
you're crying now.
I'm on page two.
Buckle up.
Asshole
impression.
Come on man.
That impression is fucking genius.
That was great.
He's so good.
Dude.
That was great.
And it's the face swap thing makes it
100 times better.
Like that shit would be funny on its
own,
but with him doing that face swap to
follow kyle.
Yeah.
Or you found them right now on live on
the podcast.
Gentlemen.
He's fallen countdown again.
Kyle did again.
One Tony Rock.
You are one of the comics in this world
that does not get the credit that you
deserve.
One of those guys.
Thank you.
And I agree.
I think you're one of the funniest guys
alive.
You and I agree.
I watched you do a set.
I guess it was last month when we did
Tripoli's a show with the store,
right?
That's how long ago was that?
About two months maybe.
Something like that.
Yeah,
Dude.
Fuck that.
You're funny as fuck.
It's,
it's fun to watch.
You got a lot of energy to man.
You powerful.
Thank you brother.
That was a.
That was a thing.
Like a couple guys after your set.
Willard.
Whew.
That was some heavy hitters on that one.
That night.
It was a.
That was a fun show.
I forgot who it was.
Billy on that Mobile Bill Barnett with.
I don't remember.
I mean he's been on a bunch of um,
aaa throw some amazing shows.
We did Montreal,
new faces together.
So every time I see trip I'm like,
hey,
you know,
were linked forever man.
We did new faces together.
Wow.
New faces.
Did I remember those days?
Yeah.
Meet the needs of hope me trip.
Uh,
corey holcomb.
Oh Shit.
Korean.
Well Mike Young on same year we were
like,
it was a great class.
We show.
He speaks very highly of corey holcomb.
Super Funny.
Joey.
Joey Diaz.
I will always love because Joey Diaz
shot the movie,
a longest yard with my brother and he
says he sees me at the comedy.
So.
Hey man,
day one,
you know I don't waste no time.
I see your brother day one.
I'm like,
why the fuck is your brother not in this
movie?
He can throw a football.
You can run faster than you guys.
I love you forever,
man.
I fucking love you.
This is bullshit.
He does not play games.
There will be no injustices around bad
guy.
Go eat a sandwich.
Shit,
whatever.
I'm around them.
Sometimes we get too high and I just
don't want to get them mad about it.
You never know what to say what not to
say.
You could mention the wrong band or the
wrong food or the clothes.
He's gone and you're just getting a big
town to switch.
He just explodes.
You gotta know days when he's actually
dangerous.
You gotta catch them after Jujitsu.
Joey,
Joey Diaz.
Wow.
All the time,
man.
Really?
Yeah.
He's lost a ton of weight to Joey's
down.
I think I got to say more than 50
pounds.
Oh,
I haven't seen him in a while.
I kinda.
I want to know.
I want to know how much he's lost.
He's lost quite a bit of weight and he's
going to just on a regular basis.
Yeah,
he gets into it.
He still,
he's doing more time now too,
is doing kickboxing classes.
Joey Diaz,
kickboxing.
Joey Diaz gets down and I didn't want to
make it seem like it was so shocking
when joy to everybody we know.
You know,
he used to be a lot bigger man,
but he's a,
he's become much more disciplined,
you know,
he's really a discipline.
Is Diet and women a woman in his life
health scare?
No,
he had a kid,
he had a kid a few years back and that
started the shift and then he's just
been.
He's also just been more aware,
you know,
as you get older,
like you really do have to take care of
your body or it's going to fail and it
might fail.
Even if you take care of it,
you know,
it's just like you're hedging your bets.
You're making it stronger.
True.
You know,
it's just,
you gotta,
you gotTa watch all the,
all the warning signs,
you know,
obviously a lot of excess weight is a
giant comics.
It's like we just don't sleep and
there's a lot of drinking late nights
and there's the travel,
the distresses dude,
as you get older too,
that don't sleep and shit just does not
fly.
Your body's like,
fuck you man.
We'll get sand bodies.
Like,
I'm going to sleep.
You can do what pitch.
I will give you a cold.
I will give you a cold and then you'll
have to lie down.
You can fuck.
I'll give you a fucking the three day
migraine.
It's a weird thing,
right?
That balance that you have to have,
like the moment someone figures out
something that you could do where you
don't ever need sleep.
We're going to have a weird world just
coming.
It's coming.
You think some kind of pill or something
will come in and probably right.
I mean,
if they have pills that make you,
uh,
make you go to sleep,
why wouldn't have pills?
They just figure out,
oh,
well this just counteracts all the
biochemical responses that your brain
creates,
what it needs.
Sleep your brain into thinking you're,
you're actively,
you know,
in the meantime we've actually found
through independent studies is that it
improves your recovery.
You actually live better with Chris Ryan
just posted some shit yesterday that I
read,
tweeted about how they were doctors and
scientists were encouraging women to
breastfeed and they were going to do it
nationally,
but it got sideswiped by the formula
industry.
Is that disturbing shit?
That's.
I believe that 100 percent because
there's always the other side where
we're going to not make money if this
thing gets through that,
but that one right there.
That is terrible.
That's a terrible idea.
It is.
That's your,
your.
You're deciding to give babies less
nutrition.
You're making a decision for profit,
profit over baby's nutrition.
You'll lying to moms.
It's like big tobacco was big tobacco's.
You know,
backhoe isn't targeting babies.
I know and I know there's no,
like there's no supporting big tobacco.
These,
you know,
how many people have died from fucking
cigarettes,
right?
Imagine if that was from something else.
So many of the product like diet coke,
we have diet coke,
just killing people left.
Do you think it is?
Of course.
I'm not sure about that.
I'm not sure it was not killing people
like cigarettes,
but I think it's not good for you,
but as far as anybody ever get like
cigarette it out.
Nobody's doing commercials with the
thing and the next day and I drink too
much diet coke,
but.
But if you,
I guess if you drink and all the
chemicals in it and all the different
things and all that.
Caffeine,
if you drank them,
nothing but diet cokes all day,
like 15,
$20.
Then you see it was a v,
like a youtube video where they put
stuff in Coca Cola,
left for days and how it dissolves,
it destroys.
It felt like a brick and a coca cola and
it just dissolves.
The brick blocks just crashed.
I used to.
But if you're eating a mountain dew,
like it was no fat,
juicy cheeseburger and a Dr Pepper or
cold Dr. pepper on ice.
Oh my goodness.
It tastes so good.
Why?
Why is it the things that tastes good?
So most things that are bad for you.
Yeah,
most things.
That's the.
But that's like so many things and
that's how they get you.
That's how they get how to get you.
That's how life gets.
Snickers is delicious.
Yeah.
Way Too much sugar.
How much will you indulge that part of
your brain?
How much will you let that part of your
brain run your life?
That's the thing.
You have to control that part of your
brain.
Self-Discipline.
Yeah.
But God damn man,
if you're in front of an ice cream
Sundae,
you're just looking at that thing.
Self discipline.
But goddamn the hardest thing in the
world.
If it's in front of me,
eight times out of 10,
I just go,
fuck it.
I just do good.
Most of the time we talking food or bad
stuff in general.
Mostly.
Mostly it's good for you.
Delicious food.
Like if I'm.
If I'm holding strong on my diet and
somebody pushing some Lasagna in front
of me and I'm like,
oh my God,
I tried to do the no dairy until I try
to do no dairy until I get off a plane
in New York City and I'm like,
there's no way.
I'm not having a whole pizza right from
Fulton street deed count pizzas,
dairy,
because of the doe.
Yeah.
Oh Jeez.
Right.
Yeah,
that's right.
Cheese.
Yeah.
Dairy's a weird one of the people,
right?
Yeah.
They say that you,
uh,
if you eat that raw cheese that your
body has a much easier time digesting
it.
Raw Cheese.
Yeah.
Man.
They have raw milk cheese.
That cheese is made with raw milk as
opposed to cheese.
It's made with homogenized and
pasteurized milk.
I had this friend who was a surgeon from
France,
really smart guy,
and he was explaining this to me once
and he had to smuggle cheese over from
Europe to America and they were
terrified they were going to get caught
in the,
as a cancer surgeon because the cheese
is just because it's.
Yeah.
Because it's illegal to have because
they want you to have the bad stuff
here.
Well,
they want it to be safe.
See,
there's no bad guy here.
It's kind of like a double bad guy
because what,
you know,
what they're trying to do is prevent
diseases.
They want milk to be able to stay on the
shelf because like all of our surplus
and all this stuff that we have in terms
of like green and food and stuff like
that,
like if we didn't have it and something
went wrong,
it would be kind of sketchy and that's
what happened somewhere around world war
two.
That's why we created all this stuff in
the first place.
That's where things started getting
really weird in terms of stacking things
up and surpluses and.
But milk can't stay raw on a shelf.
Very long man.
He would lose so much money because
things get transported and if it's milk,
it's got to be local.
It's got to be pretty fresh,
but damn,
if she can get it,
if you can get it from like a real good,
like a whole foods market or one of
those sprouts sometimes has raw milk.
It tastes better.
Well,
whole foods now has stuff that's like
just as normal as Ralph's.
Yeah.
It's like wholefoods.
The Myth is has been,
you know,
exposed well it's also the other places
like Ralphs and vons,
they're becoming more like diverse with
their food choices.
Right?
They're trying to compete and hopefully
they'll put in grass fed meat in there
and stuff like that.
And organic vegetables.
Yeah,
they're all because that's the other
ones.
What does it all?
So it's like weird granola and so you
know what I mean?
Those is like a weird granola aisle.
Like who's buying this shit?
Weird Chenwa section.
This is an empty section man.
Tumbleweeds tried off with the first
time was good a couple of months ago.
It's a very good grain.
I tried Kale for first time,
but you never had kale.
Dude.
Trying to eat healthy.
I'll make you a kale shake.
You'll freak out.
It feels like you're on drugs.
Really?
Oh Man.
It just gets you so fired up so much
nutrients.
Just get jolted into your system.
We got to try this.
Use Kale,
a giant thumb sized chunk of ginger for
garlic,
cloves,
a pair and celery.
Yes.
And run through the wall.
Like dude,
when you're drinking this stuff,
your whole body's going,
why in the fuck is all this?
Because it's blended down.
You don't even have to chew it to absorb
it.
This is going
right in there and getting broken down.
You feel great,
but then you better be close to a
bathroom,
so it's not to say that I feel great,
but it's cleaning you out quickly.
Like a fucking tsunami siren.
It's coming at your butthole door when
it.
When it goes.
Especially if you put.
Oh,
that's the other thing I forgot to add.
You need either coconut oil or mct oil.
What's MCT?
Medium chain triglyceride oil.
It's essentially an aspect of coconut
oil that they extract and it's just a
really strong healthy oil and a lot of
people put it in coffee and stuff and
different,
different things,
but it's a.
it's a good dietary aid,
but you have to put it in there because
apparently at least as it's been
explained to me,
the nutrients absorb in the body better
if there's fat mixed in with them so
that healthy mct oil or coconut oil.
When you put all that stuff in there,
then it allows your body to process
those nutrients better,
but dude,
you better be clear like a sprint or was
this the cleansing shake?
It just tastes good.
The key,
the key is don't put too much mct oil.
That's the key.
That seems to be the difference between
make it into the bathroom and having a
dreadful result and calling for help
from Laurel Canyon.
He might have to call for help.
Do you eat healthy?
I try.
You know,
I have the Vegan friends and I have
friends that like to cook and eat and
foodies,
so I'm trying to walk the fine line.
You know,
it's hard when you're on the road,
right?
It is very hard to eat healthy on the
road.
I try to do.
I go to whole foods,
I'll try to get some soup and some chips
or whatever for the room,
but I had to attend tonight.
It shows up at midnight,
you know,
hanging around and take pictures with
people and now it's 1:00 and I'm
starving and there's nothing open.
Then I can get a healthy meal from.
Yeah.
I always bring protein bars everywhere.
I go out to him to bring almonds and
protein bars.
Those are two good things to bring.
I should start doing it.
Yeah.
It's like it's an easy thing,
like if you just use it,
just trying to get some nutrition just
just to fill your stomach.
You're hungry.
Just let me just so I'm not hungry
anymore.
Almonds are great because.
Just a couple of elements.
I can't.
I can't do the homework.
Well,
don't listen to you that I'm allergic to
almonds.
Fucked.
How'd you get allergic to almonds?
I don't know.
I'm allergic to almonds.
Pecans.
I believe walnuts,
but not peanuts because peanuts is not
really.
Peanut grows in the ground.
Almonds,
pecans.
Grow on trees.
So something like something weird.
There were whoa.
Peanuts grow in the ground.
I did not know that.
Did you know that a peanut is not?
Jamie didn't know it either.
Peanuts.
All Day.
All my life.
I've never thought about a peanut tree.
Like what the fuck's a peanut tree?
Looked like?
I've never thought about that one.
Even though Jimmy Carter,
I remember it was a peanut farmer in
Georgia.
That was like a big thing.
That was his brother.
Wasn't that his brother?
No,
he was a peanut farmer.
Oh,
Jimmy Carter was.
He was his family.
He was peanuts all day.
Yeah man.
But I never knew what a fucking peanut
looked like,
like in the ground.
I thought it was a tree.
No,
but I never even saw like I could see an
art.
If you said a picture,
an orange tree.
I could see it.
Picture a peanut tree.
What?
What the fuck?
How does that thing look like?
Meanwhile,
I've had way more peanuts that I've had
oranges free full of squirrels will look
like.
Right.
You always picture it scrolls with
peanuts.
So you look,
that's what it looks like.
So they pulled that out of the ground.
Yeah.
Whoa.
So that's Kinda.
It kinda grows like that on top of the
grant right there.
Yeah.
Wow.
It grows on top of the ground.
Pick them.
Yeah.
You Go.
I remember picking them with my
grandmother back in South Carolina back
in the day.
It really is a trip like that.
Some food,
some of these plants are incredibly
nutritious to your body and some of
these plants will kill the fuck out of
you instantly and nature made people
figure it out.
He had to figure it out by trial and
error.
Trial and error.
You imagine what it was like.
Blowfish.
That guy.
The first guy.
Hey,
it's the fish.
We can we eat fish.
Bang.
Gone ahead.
Yeah.
How about those assholes is still
decided to make Sushi out of it.
If you.
If you cut it an inch to the left is the
right.
You're dead.
Like,
why?
Why not just not eating.
No,
no,
no.
Like why not just skip that one?
Danger that that probably doesn't make
it taste better.
He got those chopsticks and you're
bringing it up to your lips.
You don't like this guy.
Fuck,
this guy's getting old.
Maybe it's visions going bad.
His want to say anything because he
wants to keep his job.
I don't know this fucking guy.
And wait.
Yeah,
like blowfish,
Sushi.
That's like the.
The wing suit of Sushi.
You know those crazy people that jumped
my friend Andy Stumpf,
they jump off cliffs wing suits.
That's what that is for Sushi eaters I
saw was it was a guy that went through a
a whole.
Yeah.
I saw that.
It was like if he misses,
he's,
he's dead instantly.
Dead death.
There's a lot of videos.
Those guys dying.
There was a video of a guy hitting a
bridge going like 100 plus miles an
hour.
Hit this bridge.
It was awful.
I mean fuck line.
Yeah.
Bungee jumping on said,
you know,
we'll split this bungee jumping,
but did you see this video will smith?
He,
he,
he posted a video on his instagram.
Who under the guy that has a great
instagram posted a video about how fear
I know amazing things or right on the
other side of fear.
Yeah,
so he's been doing this thing where he's
just conquering all those fears and he's
has a group of guys that,
that professional bungee jump was that
bungee jumping on his birthday,
his 50th birthday out of a helicopter
over the Grand Canyon.
Jesus,
this I got to see.
That seems like a terrible idea.
We did a bunch of that kind of shit on
fear factor,
man.
We did it in the last season.
The last season we did a couple of them
that really had me freaked out,
but one of them they hook people up to
these bungee cords and they were had him
tied to like a post or something or a
tree or something.
I forget what it was.
They were shackled thing.
It was a post and the person had to
release them,
like figuring out which key goes into
which lock and it was like a race to do
it and as soon as you released they shot
through the air because there was a
helicopter holding onto a bungee cord
behind them.
Wow.
And then they were just dangling over
this canyon,
like bouncing up and down and I watched
the first one,
like they did a test one and I watched
and I was like,
yeah,
they know what they're doing.
I guess they know what they're doing.
These guys are like professional stunt
guys.
But I was like,
I would not want to be that person
attached to that Bungee cord was the
person that came up with these things.
Like I would watch the show.
I didn't mind the dangerous stuff like
that.
Just the eating like every time I'm
like,
how did you know you could eat that?
Yeah.
They had a whole team that,
you know,
that won't kill you.
They know they would do toxicology
examinations on certain bugs,
had grind them up and find out what,
you know,
what,
what's bad for you,
what's not,
who's that guy?
A lot of those people that ate food,
men that they shouldn't have had to eat.
Like they would do it with interns,
poor interns,
nice kids too.
Scarred for life.
Well,
there were,
there were working on production or
they're not interested or I'm sorry,
they were pas production assistance and
they would have to uh,
do like these really fucking difficult
eating challenges.
If they did it,
they'd want a certain amount of money.
They'd get a certain amount of money.
I would always give them whatever I had
in my pocket too.
They won't eat anything other than a
peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
Oh,
this poor kids like the.
Yeah.
I was just.
Some of it was ridiculous.
So there's some things you just can't
eat.
Just can't chew it down enough.
Right?
Like smell.
You'd be like,
yeah,
it's coming up.
Yeah,
but that didn't scare me.
What scares me is like the bungee cords
under the helicopters type shit.
That was like,
how do you know that that's gonna work
out.
Right?
Every time.
I don't know.
I would take a Bungee cord over the
helicopter,
the helicopter before bull nuts and all
that stuff.
No,
really to nuts or just just meat.
I just eat it.
That's one of the easiest ones.
Bull nuts would be super easy.
People love those things.
They call them rocky mountain oysters.
I've heard that.
I've seen it.
One of those cooking shows and they fry
them hollering like a fried pork rinds
and when.
Oh,
is that what you do with them?
It looks like pork.
Yeah.
They slice it and fry it up hard.
Oh Wow.
I hadn't seen that.
I'd seen a sauteed and I'd see that
where they breaded them,
they like a breaded bulled nut bread
them and fry them.
Yeah.
It's apparently people love them.
They are.
They chop those up.
Rocky Mountain Oysters.
Fried cauliflower.
Yeah.
Man's dominion tells you that's
cauliflower.
You eat it or they say it's cauliflower,
you eat it,
and then your friend is like,
no,
I'm kidding.
It was bold nuts.
See,
really bothers you that it's bull nuts.
Yeah,
Kinda doesn't bother me at all.
I think in,
if you're going to eat the whole animal
and you might as well use balls to just
out of respect.
I mean
the,
you know,
the whole thing about castrating them as
strange too and they only cast rate and
because they want them to be a.
that's how you get a steer,
right?
Like when they make a steak,
You get it out of a steer.
That means it doesn't breed.
Took a bolded.
They snipped right.
That's kind of crazy.
That's kind of crazy sad.
It's just how they did it for the bull.
Sad life.
Unfortunate.
So like did they,
they must do that with grass fed beef to
right?
Probably.
Yeah.
So what's the one they put in the world
is veal,
right?
They put the.
Oh that's in the box.
Oh yeah.
If that doesn't bother you,
what kind of person?
You know,
what are you doing?
Tip of the cap.
Is that what it is?
They put the half in a box so he can't
grow.
Yeah.
And they keep them in the dark and keeps
that,
keeps the meat tender or something like
that.
Who's the person that came up with that
one?
That guy was an ass guy,
was an asshole.
It was.
Put it in a dark box and for years it
didn't meet.
Will be.
Yeah.
Well here's the thing that I've found
from eating wild meat specifically,
and I know that everybody can't eat wild
meat.
I'm very aware of that argument,
but that none of those animals,
I like that they're,
they're living,
they're living this buck wild nature
life.
They're out there in the woods with
predators and their survival for years
in the mountains.
There's mountain lions out there and
bears out there.
And these fucking things and figured out
a way to get away from them and survive.
There are wired and alive.
And if you eat one of those,
it's just a different thing than eaten
these prisoners.
You know,
we're eating prisoners.
That's,
that seems bad to be out in the wild,
living your life.
You're an elk or a.
and then a human walks into this forum
that doesn't belong.
He's the outsider and blows your fucking
head off.
True.
Unless you like to eat elk,
then it's awesome.
That's exactly what you were looking
for.
You know?
I mean we could decide all day like
who's land is whose land?
It's their land.
This is where the elk club,
this is their home.
They will walk right through your
fucking living room and stump your kid
to death.
Okay?
Don't get it twisted.
I don't think it was coming to my living
room.
But if they wanted to,
like they're,
they're not respecting our,
our property because they love us.
And you know,
we have a mutual agreement.
No they,
they're not really dangerous.
But Moose,
our Moose will fuck you up.
I've never seen.
I've heard,
I've heard mostly like gigantic.
If you find a moose in your backyard,
get the fuck back in your house because
the Moose might fuck you.
Really?
Oh yeah.
Especially if you come near a Mama.
It's a mama and her calves.
I've never seen them.
Little slap the fuck live.
They're so big.
Dude.
Didn't even look real.
When you see them,
they're so big.
They're so big.
They're like 20 deer.
Damn.
Really moves.
Like what?
North America?
Canada?
Yeah.
Like I'm probably
north the loose in Carolina.
In this Moose in Colorado.
There's Moose in Canada.
There's a lot of moose in certain parts
of Canada.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
There's a moose in Alaska.
Oh yeah.
Moose.
Moose is delicious,
but they're so big.
You can't believe how big they are when
you see them.
You've eaten multiples.
Yeah.
Ain't moves before.
Wow.
Yeah,
it's really good.
It's delicious.
You get a lot of stuff in.
Yeah,
but it's.
I just,
I don't know,
I like it.
It's better for you.
But the whole point was this whole thing
like,
you know,
I don't want that.
Like that is not like,
that's not.
You don't have to eat that,
like why do you even want it that
tender?
Like what are you doing?
Because he does it hurt when you chew.
Fuck you doing.
I don't get it,
man.
You scared of children.
I just want good tasting foods to be
softer in that.
Where it's like,
oh,
it's so tender.
We're so lazy.
We don't even want to work out when we
eat.
We'll go through it.
You Lazy Ass.
Get it off the bone.
Just chew it.
You fuck.
No,
Nah.
I'd rather keep this little baby cow
hostage.
All Hog tied to is horrible.
It is horrible.
That's one of the more horrible things
about farming,
right?
They,
I guess they have free range veal too,
which is basically just free range is
still on in prison,
in autofarm.
Free range chickens.
Like they,
they still.
They know what they see.
They don't want a farm.
That's true.
But free range chickens are the
exception because freeway and chickens,
they don't get anywhere.
If you have a chicken house,
okay.
And you have a yard.
You don't ever have to fence the
chickens in.
The only reason why you fence the
chickens in is protecting them from
other things.
They go right in there.
Chicken house at night,
like we leave the door,
I have chickens,
we have the door open.
At the end of the day,
they just go into their little chicken
coop and climb up into their seats.
They know what do like that.
That's their house.
They lived there like I they.
They have some weird relationship with
me.
They know I bring food,
so when I come around they get excited
and they follow me around,
but they may know where they live.
They're not prisoners like they want to
be there.
You have free range chicken?
Yeah,
they're free range in the sense that I
let them out all the time,
but the thing about it as data,
they're not going to go to another state
with chicken.
Chickens hang around where they're going
to be fedex.
They're wild animals.
They know they a yard.
We get fed here.
We.
This guy comes out and throws green on
the ground twice a day,
so we are going to stay here.
Well,
it's not even that.
When you let them out,
they go looking for bugs.
That's all they're doing.
They wander around the yard.
They fuck every bug up.
Every bugs dead,
every mouse debt,
anything.
Oh,
they eat the fuck out of mice.
Chickens eat mice.
Jamie,
I think we need to play off played clip
for Mr. Rock.
Yeah.
Dude.
These I didn't know either until I got
them.
They eat mice.
The mice down in a ferocious manner.
To the point where cats please pull it
up.
Here's a fantastic video of a cat
playing with a mouse.
And a chicken comes over and shows them
how the fuck it's done.
So here's one where they're going to put
a mouse in this chicken's gonna.
Grab it from this.
That's not as impressive.
Jamie,
give me the one where the um,
the.
Give me the one with the cat.
The chicken steals the mouse from the
cat says chicken.
Eat mice.
Do they eat?
People have had these questions.
Uh,
we,
uh,
we had a mouse get into the chicken coop
once,
just to,
just randomly.
This is it.
Watch this.
Look at this chicken.
Or look at this cat.
Cat's thinking about getting the mouse.
So chickens like,
bitch,
give me that.
Look at this.
Did you fucking know?
Ferocious Dude.
Just consuming it.
See cats killed.
The cat didn't even try to get it in.
The cat was like this guy.
He's taking his time.
Was having to try to get it from the
chicken.
Chicken.
No,
chickens are too crazy.
Wow.
Okay.
Learn something new everyday.
Chicken eat chicken.
Eat Nice wild little fuckers.
So they uh,
they just go around my yard,
Jack and everything that moves.
How many chickens you got?
Thirteen days.
I lost a roost of them.
Lost a bunch of them to coyotes.
Yeah.
Uh,
no.
Rooster.
That's as an asshole move.
Why?
Every movers?
Yeah.
I was in Tampa.
You've done a Tampa Improv.
You see chickens all around Ebola?
Yeah.
Chickens.
Five in the morning.
What the fuck man?
I used to have a gardener that uh,
had he kept roosters,
like fighting roosters and when I went
over his house for something and uh,
he lived in Super Mexican neighborhood
or like everything was in Spanish.
All the signs are in Spanish.
Every that I was like,
wow.
I mean,
is it like almost like visiting a super,
Super Mexican?
Nothing was in English.
Everything was in Spanish,
but it was just Super Mexican,
right?
Where everybody in his little area had
boxes of chicken coops in the backyard.
Just stack fighting,
fighting chickens.
Dude.
I mean like five houses on this one
block.
That's a cultural thing,
right?
Fighting chickens.
So like people fight dogs and then
everybody's.
What the fuck is it?
A cultural thing.
Also a disclaimer.
I don't fight dogs.
I don't even own the dog.
I get it.
We make a distinction between chickens
and dogs because we eat chickens because
we eat chickens and because you never
really form a bond with a chicken.
Like chickens are always.
They never really there for you.
Right.
You know,
like my dogs there for me,
I come home,
I'm like,
my man,
he gets happy.
I go,
what are you doing?
How are you sir?
He gets,
gives me kisses.
Both of those bags.
As a family member.
Yeah.
Chicken is a meal.
And he,
he listens to me.
He's,
he's,
he's uh,
he's patient,
he's,
you're smart,
smart.
You can't train shit with a chicken.
You could teach them where the food is.
That's it.
No,
you just make the noise and they know
when they hear that when you get sued
assistant,
whatever you say it is.
We have a box of dried worms and we
shake this box of dried meal worms and
they come right here that they come
running and they love those things.
The little fish,
when you put your hand over it just of
dropped.
You can drop some food on him.
Yeah.
You can train them that much.
But.
So we make a distinction.
So when someone's like forest and dogs
to kill each other,
that's like forcing like a family member
that's making two friends fight to the
death.
Yeah.
Like if you have a family member who
can't read,
he trick them into fighting to the
death.
Tell them you love them the most.
If he does it,
hey dude,
if you fight it,
I would love you the most that you have
to win.
For me,
he's just smart for like a plant smart
for like,
you know,
like a but not smart for a person,
he's not crying,
but you can talk them into just asking
the question.
I don't want anybody to get upset and
say,
I said anything about fighting dogs.
I know how sensitive some people are due
today.
You can't riff anymore.
You can't just talk off the top of your
head.
Right.
You know,
like sometimes you,
you say some shit where you just
exploring it.
Like why?
Why can't I come up with chickens and
with dog and you might actually be only.
You might be the only reasonable way to
do that was to say it's fucked up with
chickens too.
That's the reasonable way.
But people would always misinterpret it
and go with the worst way is to say
what's wrong with fighting dogs,
which is not going to hear what they
want to hear about,
but you were really saying,
why should you be able to fight check
shit.
And we love chickens just as much.
That's what we eat them because they're
delicious shit and they get the nod
because they're delicious.
I went to an ashram once and this lady
who was there,
she and I were having a conversation and
I noticed that she had ant spray and I
said,
what do you do with the ant spray?
She goes,
well,
it's unfortunate,
but we have to use it because the answer
been getting to the garbage.
I go,
what?
you guys are murderers.
You guys are killing the ants.
And she started laughing.
She thought it was kind of funny.
She's like,
eh,
but she wrote a line.
That's one thing about Buddhists,
like a lot of Buddhists,
they don't take themselves too seriously
to the point where they can't like crack
out.
A little joke about that,
but the hypocrisy of the fact they're
using bug spray and this is very good
death spray.
You're killing all these organisms.
We just did,
but we decide that that's okay.
Whereas like if she was in her backyard
was invaded by house cats.
She just went out shotgun,
right?
You can't do that.
You can't do that,
but you could spray the fuck out of
these little bugs.
You've got to kill them.
It's like when things are a little,
we're like,
can't be bothered worrying about you too
little for this.
You would think though.
They would.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
You would think that they would,
uh,
figure out a better way to keep those
ants out.
They're lazy.
They wanted to kill him.
Buddhist are lazy.
Well,
that one was,
we just learned today.
Well,
don't you think?
Like,
do you think there could have been a way
to clean them up with water not killed
them?
Is that.
No.
You'd still kill some.
You'd still have to sweep them out.
Like you're a Buddhist outside,
but even then you're,
you're murdering dozens and dozens of
advance.
If you just had a broom and you started
hitting those ants.
Get an ant eater.
If you're a Buddhist,
because now circle of life type shit.
You know what I mean?
Maybe get a burger,
get a chicken.
Chicken,
chicken needs to eat.
Yeah.
Then you get chicken shit all over your
kitchen,
but you sweep that up.
That's not going to kill anybody.
That's true.
Maybe that's the mood for.
For a Buddhist.
They should have chickens outside
knowledge.
We've refined it answers here.
We get the answers,
but get down to the bottom.
I wonder if they try to make their
chickens vegetarian here.
What does it say here?
If you have an infestation,
use your vacuum to quickly get rid of
the invaders.
Then immediately entered the vacuum bag
in the outdoor compost pile or at some
distance from your house.
Do not use ant bait or poison like
sprays,
like rate that continued to.
They continue in the toxic waste stream
from their point of manufacturer to
their ultimate destination in landfills
via runoff or sue or 12.
That's very conscious of them,
so they're saying,
don't,
don't use bug spray.
Just use a vacuum cleaner.
You're still going to kill some
guaranteed.
You suck in those little tiny things
into a huge metal tube.
What could go wrong?
Get a chicken man.
If you imagine.
If somebody like assume that you would
be okay and they use something that's
proportionate size to suck you off,
the earth will be fine,
they'll be fine.
You land on a pile of other people,
people you'll get sucked up at the same
time.
When you get smashed into each other,
you're broken arms and shoulders.
I think that's ridiculous.
What would you do if there wasn't a
vacuum cleaner?
Mr Buddhists answer,
man.
Huh?
What if there's no vacuum cleaner?
Would you use a broom?
A vacuum cleaner is gonna.
Fuck those ants say chicken.
Chicken eats the ants.
Yeah,
I think I like when you're doing.
I think that's a smart way of thinking
and eater even further,
but I think he was just like to get to a
mound of dirt and just go to town.
I don't know if I need to like hunt
them.
They stick their tongues in the ant
hole.
Right,
right,
right.
And just,
yeah,
tongues like sticky.
So it's just like it just eaten for
days.
But what if they wiped them out real
quick and then you got to fucking ant
eater that you have to feed.
And you've got to bring in and see like
what kind of an asshole.
My Isa Ido.
What eats the Amperes fucking Jaguar
black bear cycle.
Buddhists do.
There is a crazy video that I tweeted of
these tourists walking through the woods
and they're walking down a trail and
they run into a fucking gigantic.
Grizzly bear is a terrifying video.
Wow.
I,
I tweeted it.
Yeah.
It's not on it.
I didn't put it on instagram.
Dude.
This thing is so big.
And now I called right back up.
Back Up.
They got to wake up.
Yeah,
I got away.
Did you see the video of the poachers
that went to kill the rhino and they
killer video of it.
It's A.
I saw a picture,
I suppose still.
Oh,
okay.
Yeah.
I didn't know if they got a video,
but yeah,
that's fucked up.
That's fucking few.
Dude got jacked,
right?
Tuna and sweet.
That's the lions.
And we even look at this.
Turn up the volume,
Jamie,
to use my best.
I don't want to use my bear spray.
He's a good boy.
That's a good boy too.
He's coming around.
That's good.
Can you come forward?
Yeah,
motherfuckers.
It's following them.
It's circling them around.
Yeah.
He's the thing is circling him,
man.
It's going towards him.
That's a good boy.
That thing is really the thing is coming
way too close to him and it's like,
oh crap.
He's huge.
Hell No.
Yeah,
they got lucky that I would've been
gone.
The scary thing about that is that bear
could have just decided randomly through
some firing of his bear synopsis to take
a left instead of a.
You go at him.
He just,
he could have easily decided that,
oh,
things crazy.
Scared the shit out of me.
You know why man?
We don't believe in things we don't see.
We don't believe in them.
What do you mean you don't believe in
things you don't see?
You know it's real,
but you don't believe danger.
No,
you don't believe in it.
It's not a real thing in your world.
Right?
If you were outside and you saw that,
if you will,
with those people in Australia,
you Billard oh Jesus Christ.
If I was there,
I would know that.
That's the reality.
That's really my world.
Does it evolve?
Does it involve being somewhere near
that close to a bear?
So to see it in my world would be what?
The.
I wouldn't be real.
Not like,
Holy Shit,
this can't be happening,
but if you were with those people,
if you went on that trip with the I'd
be.
That would be fucking fellow.
One of the craziest things you get out
with you.
Your whole existence gets down to the
chance that this thing makes a decision
to go one way or another.
Otherwise it's just going to run you
down.
Just like life.
If you go a certain scenarios you like
bite,
this shit can get real real fast,
real fast.
You know?
That's one of them,
man,
that his life,
any inner city life is just like,
holy shit is this is a of a pop off in
here,
right?
Like how many people died in Chicago
last week?
Some insane number.
There was a there reporting on the lack
of attention that the murders in Chicago
or getting in the national news and how
crazy it is.
I've been to Chicago several times.
The one thing that sticks out to me
every time I go to this house,
segregated into this.
Yeah,
I've never gone anywhere of a major city
like New York is like we're all piled up
together for killed.
Twenty four wounded and weekend
shootings.
God,
28 people got shot.
Dude,
that is crazy.
Twenty eight again in the afternoon and
said,
fuck standing on the sidewalk.
Jesus opened fire Jesus Christ,
but there is a.
There is a war going on in Chicago
that's way more deadly than most of the
wars were engaging in overseas.
You don't hear about
that.
Many soldiers dying every day.
Now that's another.
That's another scenario how we said
like,
that's real.
Yeah,
that's real,
but here's your work outside and
Chicago.
That is a real fear that you should have
and this is what's the number of people
in Chicago this year passes 1400.
1,400 people shot.
Now how many people do we know?
How many people got shot?
Like doing tours of Afghanistan?
That's a good question.
What does this.
This is the over the year.
Just this year.
Okay,
so let's Google.
How many soldiers were shot overseas?
This here?
You know the.
That's a weird thing,
man.
We got a war going on.
If that was Mexicans invading North
Dakota and shooting people now,
many people were dying every day we
would be taking action,
but because it's happening to people is
1400 and a hundred of them were white
people.
It would be an issue.
Oh yeah,
it was 1300 black people in 100 white
people.
It'd be now you really right?
This is,
I mean it's something that people don't
talk about.
$300.
Let me.
It's like a crazy.
That's a weird statistic.
It's a terrible situation like
culturally to have something like this
and with 1400 people being shot,
that means.
And people don't want to realize this
is,
you know,
post traumatic stress disorder is a real
thing in the ghetto as well as in the
hills of Afghanistan.
It's real of course.
So when you see something that when
people are like,
why these guys have guns on them,
it's like,
dude,
1400 people got shot.
I'm just trying to get to school and
back.
Yeah.
I'm trying to get to work in back.
Of course it's,
you know,
we're not protecting those people.
It's exactly.
If they were stuck somewhere overseas
and some in the middle of some war,
you know,
and they were American citizens,
please help get us out like we gotta get
these guts.
If there was a place that had like
statistically the numbers of the south
side of Chicago where all these murders
going down there a place to typically in
another part of the world,
we would be set those numbers anywhere
else and it's a.
it's a crisis.
If we had,
let's say Hawaii,
let's say if we had just moved into
Hawaii,
just just took over Hawaii and then
we're in an area where people started
getting shot and killed by local site
that we would want to read.
Want to extract those people from
Hawaii.
We'd scoop him up from an island.
We would think they'd be shooting at the
helicopter says we rested.
Right,
right.
Well,
you just look at the real numbers,
just the raw number.
That's a crazy number of people getting
shot.
And this year,
this is July,
July.
Just started.
How many soldiers got shot trying to
find the wounded.
I can only find a death.
Okay.
What's the death?
It's only like 1500 total since like
2011.
Since 2001 man or this is since January.
Seems weird saying only I know what
you're saying.
You're saying in comparison to the other
number since January.
Yeah.
That's insane.
That's crazy.
That is insane.
And that's happening right here in the
good old us of a,
in one of the biggest cities in the
world.
Chicago's giant.
Awesome city and is happening in other
cities also that people don't know about
[inaudible],
but Chicago is the most glaring because
I don't travel around there so I don't
know what happened or why it happened,
why they have this segregation there and
what it was all about.
Go to Chicago,
man.
It's like black people all the way over
there.
Then is downtown where it's nice and
everybody's,
you know,
Detroit has that too,
right?
It's right as well.
Yes.
Yeah,
yeah.
Um,
man.
Then you go down south.
It's like that.
Go to Louisiana.
That's crazy.
You were the king or the president?
Tony Rock.
I was the president,
how do you fix this?
Uh,
you have to fix this.
It's a process first.
I always say number one is education,
right?
Education is number one.
If you're just,
if you're getting a better education
than you just avoid the pitfalls
naturally because you just know that
certain things are wrong.
And,
and by getting a to see a better
education,
I mean you have opportunities to do,
you know,
you have a music appreciation,
you have the arts,
you have sports,
you have things to occupy you during
school hours and afterschool hours.
There's no type of any type of extra
curricular,
extra curricular activities for these
kids in Chicago.
There's gang life which you are born
into what you are expected to go into
once you are a certain age,
you alright,
you're a man.
Now here's the gun.
We don't like those guys.
Those guys don't like us.
You don't even question it.
It's like my father has been this way.
My grandfather has been this way.
My uncles a display,
my big brother.
So this way you don't even if you're
born right into it,
you don't want it in a war zone.
You all right and you don't question,
and it's a war zone where you sleep and
your family lives right,
not just a war zone with soldiers,
but a war zone with fabrics and another
thing better education you.
You're more worldly.
If you see the world,
you realize how small that,
how small your neighborhood is and
there's a bigger world out there and you
want to go places and see things.
Then you realize like what are we doing
here?
But these are people that I guarantee
probably never left Chicago for.
Probably never went on vacation to the
south to visit grandparents and realized
Danner South is nice and quiet and the
people are friendly and they've never
been to the zoo and saw animal and went
home and googled the mating rituals of
this.
Open your mind,
open your mind,
you see the world.
The stuff that you're involved in
becomes just so small.
This guy,
I don't like Scott because he has read
and I have on blue.
I don't get it.
So the education,
that tiny little area,
you know,
uh,
the,
that he operates in with his living his
life,
he does matter that your reality is
what's around you.
Yeah.
So you get a good scope of a bigger
world.
Like I grew up in the hood,
I grew up in bed Stuy,
Brooklyn,
but one of the wildest neighborhoods
when I was going up there,
but my vision was passed it.
My vision was,
yeah,
this is going on outside,
but I'm going to be there one day.
What do you attribute the,
having the ability to do that to a,
having a mom and a dad?
Pops.
My father worked two full time jobs my
whole childhood.
My father literally worked 80 hours a
week 80.
So just to see him go everyday,
like damn this dude,
this dude works hard,
man.
Wow.
Didn't have a lot to show for it and
made sure his kids had mom was a
teacher.
Education was,
you know,
she made an emphasis on it.
Wow.
You know,
it was,
it was like my friends,
my,
one of my best friends down the block
know dad,
my friend across the street.
No Dad,
my friend.
Two doors down.
No Dad.
Then crack came and that was everything
fucked up.
Everything started.
Just the neighborhood started just to,
you know.
Yeah.
That was like crack was people that
are alive today or young kids today.
They don't remember the eighties.
Yeah.
There was a like a plague,
a plague hit.
Everybody knew somebody that got hit and
so many people's lives were gone.
Done,
done over.
People who are doing fine and then all
of a sudden.
Yep,
Yep.
I remember it.
I remember it well.
Yeah.
It was a weird.
And I started losing friends.
That's what I,
that's what happened.
I started losing friends.
I,
I saw like people don't.
It was crazy man.
Like shit man.
This shit we saw.
I saw a friend get shot in the head,
like talk to them on the corner.
Engage.
What's up,
man?
Yeah.
We're going to play ball later.
You wouldn't play ball.
All right,
cool.
I'll hit you later.
Turned to walk down the block,
look maybe you know,
a thousand feet away and looked back to
like just,
you know,
looking around the neighborhood and saw
a guy just kind of like he was.
He looked like,
have you ever seen an old like big daddy
kane album?
He had the flat top and a bunch of
jewelry on,
on the corner on the payphone.
This was beeper days and you got to turn
and the guy ran up on him while he was
returning a beat and just tried to rob
him.
And then he went for his gun and the guy
just boom right in his head,
right on the corner of my block,
rised right on the corner of my block.
And I went home and my parents were
there and I was like,
this is crazy man.
And that's where I grew up.
But my vision was not confined to where
I was.
It was going to be,
you know,
fortunately I get outta here.
I'm going to do this and once I leave
here I'm going to.
You're very fortunate to have those
kinds of examples.
You know,
if your dad who worked out that you.
I'm very fortunate.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
man,
it's hard for some people if they didn't
get the break that you got in that
regard.
That's why I don't,
I have not missed on me.
Like I realized like if I didn't get
that,
I didn't catch that last Chapa
good for you man.
That's uh,
but that's,
that's where character comes from.
Two means having someone like that as an
example.
Like how like someone who can work two
full time jobs
and that is a force of will.
Most people struggle with one man.
One is hard eight hours a day.
And my dad's rule was everybody had to
have a job at 14.
13 was your last summer.
Enjoy yourself at the ball,
do whatever you wanna do.
14 you get in the job.
Wow.
Yep.
No,
he didn't play at all.
14 job.
He's.
The thing is man,
that's a bitter pill to swallow when
you're young,
but damn,
the dudes who go through that always
seemed like they have an extra gear.
You know,
I know a lot of dudes who went through
like bootcamp type dads,
they did not like it,
but they can do some shit.
Like I'll just a little bit more shit
that other people could do.
You know,
they might not have liked the fact that
dad was always telling him what to do,
but these motherfuckers can hike 20
miles and not complaining.
My Dad wasn't bootcamp,
but it was like,
you're going to work.
That's not even a question.
You're gonna work.
And then I have so many siblings that
his rule was,
you know,
we all had to take care of each other.
So my oldest brother,
of course,
he turns 14 first he's working,
he gets paid.
You have to give everybody $5.
You get paid today.
Give all your siblings $5.
Wow.
Next brother gets a job.
Now it's two brothers working.
Give everybody $5.
Wow.
We all had.
It was like a socialism.
Yeah.
My Dad just made sure it all worked.
That's cool.
That's very generous to.
That's like everybody that's forcing
everybody to be in it together.
Right.
That's smart.
And take a minute,
and then it was,
the rule was it was a,
if your brother is in a fight,
you're in a fight.
So then it became don't fuck with the
rock brothers because there's so many of
them.
You have to fight all of them.
So that kind of kept us safe during this
whole,
you know,
wow,
that's awesome.
And what a,
it's a bad situation to be in.
But uh,
a great place to develop characters were
opportunities,
different character.
You know,
who you are,
you know what you're,
you know that you know,
you develop a sense of a goal and get it
work hard.
No excuses,
nobody's doing it for you,
nobody's coming to save you.
You're responsible for you.
Yeah man,
we all need to have a little bit more of
that in our life.
And then also a little bit more
community to absolutely know that.
Right?
And we grew up in a time where it was
next door neighbor could spank you.
Lady across the street could grab you
and make you sit down on the stupid
ticket.
Mother came home,
the guy in the Bodega at the corner
would tell you to sit inside into your
mother.
Came home.
Yeah.
People would,
uh,
they would police the neighborhood
police we live in,
we live in.
Don't talk to my kid,
don't touch my kid out.
Right.
Get off my son.
Don't touch my child.
You know,
there's a lot of that.
Well,
it's because somebody,
man,
that's the weird balance.
I've talked about this recently,
but my cousin I saw my cousin gets
smacked by some lady once when we were
both,
like my cousin is a year younger than
me,
so I might have been six and she
might've been five somewhere around
there.
It wasn't any older than that.
And this lady cuffed her right in the
face,
man,
she fell.
This lady fell on the ice and my cousin
just happened be there and she
was looking at her on the ground and she
did not laugh at her,
but the lady said she laughed and she,
the lady got up and she was just angry
that she fell and hurt herself.
She got up and smack my cousin right in
the face.
My cousin fell down,
I remember seeing it and realizing I
couldn't do anything about it to save
her,
to help her,
you know,
I was a little kid too.
And being terrified that this grownup
person just smack this little kid in the
head for something that wasn't even
real.
Like you don't want that either.
Right?
It's like,
don't touch my kid.
It's probably better.
Well,
that's not long run crazy people.
That's not helping raise a child.
That's been as adult.
That's just a crazy.
She was a crazy lady that lived in our
building.
That was always thing about living in
apartment buildings.
Right?
There's always,
there's always somebody died,
right?
Somebody's always died and you will be
walking by that apartment going,
what the fuck is that?
What is that smell?
Smell.
Dead Body.
When somebody,
uh,
somebody died in the house,
dude,
it is crazy how bad it smells.
It's so bad.
People smell so bad when they die.
It's insane.
I go,
thank God I never spoke.
The entire floor smelled like a body.
It was so gross.
Even after the body was going through,
it took a while.
I'm sure for them to clean it.
I hardly remember.
I just remember there was a terrible,
terrible smell in the hallway and then
they realized that this lady had died in
her,
in her apartment,
so then they go in to get the body,
but I don't remember how long it took
for them to clean up the smell.
The smell was unbelievably bad and then
somebody moves in and all the neighbors
like,
you know,
somebody died in their.
Yeah.
They don't tell you shit.
Tell you that's the dead.
Now you will pass the dead house.
Don't they have to tell you now?
Like if someone got murdered in the
house,
I think that's a law.
That wasn't a law before.
I don't think it was.
I think in some places maybe it was a
law that's not a law.
They just sell you a house with like,
hey,
whatever.
And figuring out what happened to him.
Nothing but good times.
Enjoy your house.
Fuck up.
Nothing but good times there.
Bullet holes in the wall.
Hey,
you bought it.
people get crazy in this neighborhood.
They like to celebrate New Year's Eve.
Fourth of July.
I don't know man.
You should probably know.
Do you believe in haunted houses and not
really.
No,
not really.
I haven't experienced.
Right,
so I don't.
I don't,
I don't give it much thought.
I put it that way.
I don't believe in ghosts,
but I don't not believe in ghosts.
Have you experienced now normal?
Nope.
But imagine you're out in the desert and
all the sudden you see an apparition
walk towards you in the desert and then
this happened to you.
Just imagine.
Okay.
I'm in the desert and it's nighttime and
looks right at you and it looks like a
teacher that you knew from like seventh
graders.
This is that night,
that night,
and then it vanishes.
It vanishes right in front of you.
Detail people.
Uh,
yeah.
What do you tell him?
My fucking seventh grade teachers just
popped up in people like,
oh,
Tony,
we got to get you to a doctor.
Tony rocks gone crazy.
No,
you know what you would do if you,
the people you trust.
Even if the people you trust,
they'd be like you.
Okay,
let me feel your head that never
experienced that.
I would put you on a kid.
I would put you in a category.
Oh,
Tony Rock might be crazy.
You'd have to go into that category.
Then I'd have to accumulate more data.
I'd have to say.
Well,
every time I talked to him,
it seems reasonable and intelligent.
He's really funny guy.
I don't think he's crazy.
I think I was out there by myself.
It was nighttime.
You know,
today I was talking to the student once
it pulls out his phone and starts
showing me pictures of clouds,
like,
what does that do?
Here's another one.
Look at this one.
Here.
I go,
what is it?
He goes,
look at this one here.
I see them everywhere.
I go,
what do you see?
And he goes,
flying saucers.
These just.
These are clearly ships from outer space
and you during the clouds,
they're inside the cloud.
Yeah,
he's got pictures.
His phone was like,
remember when Jack Nicholson in the
shining all work?
No.
Play makes jack a dull boy.
Just types it over and over again.
This dude,
his whole phone was just clouds.
He shows me the pictures on his phone.
I was like,
oh,
wow.
Yeah,
that's a little different duty Ed.
Hundreds of pictures of clouds and
what'd you say?
Know what to say.
It's grown man older than me.
Was I going to say I'm okay?
I usually.
That's what I usually say.
Okay.
There's nothing to say.
You think those are spaceships?
I'm looking at clouds and you think
they're spaceship.
Something's wrong here.
I don't want to be mean.
It seems like a nice guy.
Okay.
It's probably okay.
Best Bet.
Yeah.
What do you say?
Yeah,
you're right.
Hey man,
maybe he's right.
Maybe he has some.
They live glasses that I don't have to
remember that movie with.
I can see he's.
He's looking at those photos and he sees
some shit that my puny brain can't see.
That's possible too.
What if people can see stuff like that?
What do people can see some stuff and we
should be so clear and onsite.
I think it's entirely possible that
people have sensors that can detect
things and feel things.
The real question is how many of those
people are being honest about it and how
often is it really happened?
Because people.
The problem is there's a tendency.
This is the tendency.
People love to pretend they have some
psychic power or they have some
paranormal gift or they're different and
exceptional in some way without earning
it from everybody else.
People love to do that.
Like I just have a sense.
I have a sense because they liked the
attention.
Yeah,
I just know.
I just know man,
I just have a fucking instinct that I
always go on my gut that that doesn't
mean you're always right.
So you gotta wonder like how many people
really do feel like something's wrong
when something's wrong.
Right?
And how many people really do like know
not to go to a place like something is
telling them not to go like something
strong and how many people were just
full of Shit and how many people.
I think that the fact pretend they had a
voice that told them not to do it.
I don't know about the voice,
but I know that that's real.
That's an instinct to say,
hey,
don't go there.
Yeah.
A lot of times has been times in my life
where I just followed the instinct and
ended up,
you know,
I couldn't.
I'm the one time something happened to
my brother Brian,
my favorite brother in the whole world.
Everybody knows the other brother's a
mad,
right?
Everybody know.
Everybody knows Brian's my favorite.
Brian got a guy,
tried to rob Bryan in the neighborhood.
One day he got in a fight with a guy
that got cut his face and he went to the
hospital and I was at work and my
brothers called me.
Like this guy tried to rob Bryan and,
and I didn't know where the hospital
was.
I jumped on the train.
I took the train a few stops.
I jumped off,
I jumped on another train,
took it a few stops.
I'm like,
fuck.
I jumped on another like,
you know,
you had transferred in New York,
the subway,
jump on third train and take it a few
stops and get off and come up to the
street.
And I asked the guy walking,
hey man,
do you know where Kings County hospital
is?
And he says right there,
and I had no idea.
I just fucking felt that like I gotta
get to my brother.
Wow.
And I literally,
hey man,
where's he's like right there.
And I just was,
I just felt like I got to find my
brother and that's all I was thinking
about.
Wow.
Yeah,
I believe you.
I believe that's real.
I know for a fact,
but I don't know about,
you know,
say that they live glasses.
I don't know.
No,
I don't think that's real.
But I,
I know there's something that happens
sometimes when you're thinking about
someone and they call you because
sometimes it happens where this person
is like so far out of your memory,
right?
Like you haven't talked to them in a
year and a half and you're like,
dude,
how the fuck did you know?
It was just,
I was just thinking of you like,
man,
I was just thinking about you just call
them check and see what the wave is.
So something.
Yet you put a frequency distro strong in
the air that I think there's something
to that.
Wait,
what is this ghostbusters laws?
Many states pass legislation in the 19
eighties in early 19 nineties to protect
sellers and real estate brokers from
buyers claiming they were damaged by the
sellers failure to disclose the presence
of ghosts.
Wow.
This is good.
These laws became known as ghost buster
laws after the 19 eighties era movie
comedy,
Connecticut Ghostbusters Law first
appeared in 1990.
Wow.
Psychological impact is a thing.
The psychological impact became in
nonmaterial.
Huh?
Nonmaterial fact concerning real
property.
The overhaul also replaced the reference
to HIV with a reference to the
commissioner of public health list of
reportable diseases.
Reportable diseases.
Huh?
Wow Man.
This is all the.
Yeah,
I mean I guess they have to do that,
right?
They have to do that.
I mean,
you don't want someone to know that.
Like there was a house that I saw in
boulder that was for sale is the house
where Jon Benet Ramsey was killed and
they couldn't sell it.
I think they even changed the name of
the street or something crazy like tile
and they still couldn't sell it and it
was like a really nice house.
People would just like,
no thanks.
Wow.
That house.
It's just poison.
That's like a Bundy right?
Monday.
Damn.
Who?
Oh,
Jay's house.
Oh yeah,
it was.
It wasn't.
What was it called?
A rocky.
Rockingham tore down some fucking
psycho.
Could move there.
You know,
want to live where the king lived.
Partment though.
Are the Condo is still there?
Keto Keto still lives there now.
Audrey's house was gone.
But uh,
Nicole,
the murder scene is still.
Oh really?
Wow.
Why would you as a.
That is a.
Why would they tear down old jays and.
Well,
somebody just made a call that said,
yeah,
that's,
that was one of the ghostbusters law.
I want to.
Oh my God.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
I'm wondering whether you know,
your honor,
we're going to go back to a refresh
reference.
Ghostbusters law number one,
they usually say ray Parker Jr as a
character with this.
I don't think in court they ever used
those names.
Right?
They just use like the docket number
statute.
You got to say go fuck.
They allowed to say in court.
You got to come in and play.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
Do something new.
Have you ever been a place where it felt
weird?
We found out that someone died there.
You ever been in a place where,
you know,
I've been in places that felt weird
because you know,
some violence was going to pop off and I
knew it.
I was like,
let's get the fuck out of here.
Right.
As you can tell that's you.
You can feel that somebody's dying.
No.
I was at a concert once in a brawl broke
out and I quit.
I was a security guard and I was a neil
young concert,
ran it.
It broke out and I put a Hoodie on.
I zipped it up.
A covered my security outfit.
I'd walk right the fuck out of there.
You out of your fucking mind jumping
into this fray and getting clocked in
the head by somebody like people were
fighting and they canceled the show and
kicked everybody out.
People are lighting fires.
I was at a.
What was it,
this not this boards when Dr Dre got
jumped in in a young buck,
stabbed the guy.
Oh,
I was there and I was doing a show for
upn.
This was back when upn was still a
network and one of the execs from upn
was there with her young son.
He will who wanted to see all the
rappers and he's sitting at the table
with us and I saw like the Gi unit group
come in.
Then I of death row guys come in and I
saw Andres Group and I'm sitting there
and I tell,
I forgot the lady's name.
I said,
hey,
you might want to get your kid out of
here.
Something's about to go down.
She's like,
what do you mean?
I'm like,
it's about to about to go.
And she's like,
he's so excited.
He wanted to see dre and he loves fifty
cent them.
Listen,
get this kid.
It was a little white kid to.
I'm like,
oh my God,
there's.
Can I go say hi and I'm like,
you get them out of here and as the
second time I said like,
Yo,
you might want to really get them out of
it.
It's gonna pop off.
Boom.
Dre gets punched in the face.
Malay young buck stabs guy and I'm like
told you Jesus.
And like two days later on set,
she's just like,
how did you know that?
Like,
I know that I know the energy in the
room.
I could feel it.
I've been around it too many times.
That's a crazy feeling to when people
are about to do ridiculous.
Yeah.
You see the,
you see the walk,
you see the look,
you know,
it's like,
it's sad,
but it's true.
Like when you grow up in the hood,
you have that instinct.
You have that,
that look,
you look at a guy walked past you at one
time and you look at,
look around the room and okay,
it's about to go.
It's about to go.
Yeah.
People that have never experienced that
probably wouldn't know what to do.
Right?
They wouldn't.
They would think nothing of it like that
lady.
Like she'd never seen those signs
before.
I've been on the road,
uh,
this was recently,
like maybe three months,
four months ago.
I had a,
my feature feature comic with me.
He's from Chicago actually,
and we're in a club after the show and
there's a couple guys talking in the
corner and I said something to a girl,
she's like,
Hey,
Tony Rock and have little small talk.
And she walks over to the group of guys
and one guy walks over and stands at the
end of the bar here and one guy stands
in the ball here and I turned to my
friend Dave and I go,
Yo,
you ever been a fight in a ball before?
And he said,
no.
I said,
get ready motherfucker.
Are you about to be in one?
Because I saw it.
And then the third guy comes over.
So funny that comes up.
And he's like,
Oh shit,
you are a comedian?
And I said,
yeah.
He said,
I thought that was you.
He was able to talk.
And I was like,
I thought that was a comedian guy and
psychotic a picture of it.
And I took a picture of them in these
calls that the guy.
But like,
yeah,
it was great.
It wasn't him that he kinda just
squashed it because he,
I guess they didn't know who I was.
Oh,
I was gonna go.
But because I said something to the
girl.
Oh No,
it was the comedian is hit.
And I'm like,
hey fellows,
what's up now?
I know I turned into the comedian like,
what's up guys?
How y'all doing?
Y'All all right.
What'd you guys need to drink?
Let's do a round of shots.
You know,
Dave's like,
that's just.
How did you know that?
I'm like,
I know motherfuckers going to go.
Yeah,
if you ain't never been around violent
people,
you probably don't smell that vibe.
Right?
You smell that vibe.
That's a valuable tool to have.
If you're in those places,
especially if you own the road in
cities,
you know,
catch yourself on the road,
you know?
Maybe have a local friends like to let
me take you to my friend's club.
We went to meet you someplace you like.
How do I get out of here?
Where are we going?
Hey,
my boys having a party at his house and
I'm like,
Oh,
you're up in the hill somewhere.
He couldn't even know how to drop the
car off the reference.
I was like,
I don't know.
The craziest ones are the ones that have
to take you in a shuttle.
You have to park your car here.
Sorry.
Are you fucking kidding me?
You're going into a shuttle to a party.
The worst.
I was in Iowa one time.
This is a true story.
I was in Iowa.
I was in a De Moines,
Iowa.
Did the show.
There's not very many black people was
so shows up a group of white guys like,
hey bro,
you super funny man.
Let's go get a drink.
Let's go to the bar right down the
street.
I'm a New Yorker right down the street
is literally right down the street,
right?
They get in a truck that he pulls the
truck around,
he pulls up,
he pulls a pickup truck,
one of those four door pickup trucks,
big ones,
and it's two guys in the front and
they're like,
hey,
jump in man.
And I'm like,
oh Jesus.
Fuck,
are we going right down the street and
that would drive in for maybe 10
minutes.
Oh.
And he's trying to get a point of
reference.
If I got to jump out the truck.
It's Iowa is nothing as far as you can
see.
Right or left of the truck.
Just highway and grass.
Right?
So there's nothing like my jump out.
Which way?
I don't know.
This is how girls have to feel every.
Yes.
That feeling.
So we pull up at a barn,
a barn and the two guys are excited.
They jump out and they run around the
other side of the ball.
Like,
hey bro,
come on in this way.
And they.
And they turn and I can't see them now.
I don't know.
And I say to myself like,
Holy Shit,
this is,
this is how it's going to end.
This is it right here.
And I turned the corner and I see the
neon light that says girls,
girls,
girls.
I had never been so excited to see the
ugliest strippers and was like,
yes,
yes I would have left.
There's this build the vcs what?
All the dances because I thought I was
going to die.
Five seconds.
Oh my God.
You thought they were taking you.
You go back behind there.
There's chains hanging.
Exactly.
Oh my God.
That shit's happened before.
That's the crazy thing about people like
the worst thing you know,
I'm watching the show vikings.
You ever watched Jamie got to binge.
So good God damn show.
I think I'm on season three or four.
I can't remember,
but it's a good fucking show,
but it just shows you how brutal people
were back then.
Like every day someone's getting fucked
up on that show.
That shows a guarantee.
People are going to die every app to
check it out.
People getting drowned,
people holding them underwater.
People.
Little kids are killing people with
access.
Like it's crazy.
That show is fucking crazy.
Every day people getting jacked and
murdered and killed.
You sound like you're like,
that's fucking good show.
I enjoy it,
but the point is like these people were
like,
this was.
This was life for these fucking people,
right?
That that was a real world.
Real world reality.
Reality is what your reality is.
It's like people are like people that
don't understand your reality,
well,
you're not from this world.
This is,
this is a real thing to us to know how a
going gonna pop off to know when a guy
strapped to know when this is all
reality.
What's crazy is that we like to think
that that doesn't exist anymore and that
that viking style of living doesn't
exist,
but it does.
They just used guns now.
Right.
Just happened in like that with guns.
That's all it is.
It's basically that same kind of like a
conqueror survivor mentality,
bullets and fuck you and fuck him and
the guys that run into the drugstore and
smashed the glass.
That's pillaging Lynn wandering past.
It's as old as time.
It's just confined to certain areas now.
It's not spreading out like the vikings
did in giant boats and getting on the C
and they're not doing it like the
Vikings did it.
Some aspect of it was just,
you know,
trying to discover new lands,
you know?
Yeah.
They were trying to farm and chip does
meet over here or there's gold here now.
They just do it because it's like,
I have to eat them,
you know,
I want those sneakers,
man.
I wish I could see what it was really
liked back then because it's like you
watch the show and the show is really
cool,
but you know,
they're actors and they're doing a great
job and everything,
but you still know they're actors and
you're watching them do things and
everything's really well done.
It's a really well done show,
but still you like,
man,
I wish I could see it in real life to
just be where,
where,
where was happening in real life.
Do you imagine?
Just being alive back then when the best
clothes were made out of fucking animal
hides.
He just draped in buffalo skins and she
killed the buffalo.
You ate the village eight,
the Buffalo.
Every.
You're used every piece of it.
So they lived in,
was closed.
It would take their boats out and catch
fish and bring them into.
People will be waiting on the dock,
see if they're going to eat tonight.
And it was only like 200 people in the
town.
So for plague hit,
half the people would be dead,
woman would have a baby right in front
of you.
Wrap it in a blanket.
And that was.
That was it.
That's how people lived forever.
People live like that and they lived and
they lived.
They didn't.
They,
they actually live.
They thrived.
Right?
But wouldn't you take this over that?
I would take this.
Yes,
they would.
They be like,
you fucking asshole.
You want to be a viking?
I want to drive a cadillac.
I would take,
I would take the bottle of water.
Yeah.
They'll be like,
no,
fuck riding a horse,
dude.
I drove in the escalate today.
That shit is so smooth.
It's comfortable to see this,
but it's cool in here.
I played music.
The music wirelessly charged my phone
right there on the site.
They would be like,
you're an asshole if you want to live
like us campers.
And then somebody doesn't have any of
that.
Fucking opened your door with a gun and
he.
Now he's the Viking.
Exactly.
I need this.
Yeah.
And if you don't take care of that
problem,
this is the thing that could never gets
better.
It's like a part of.
It's like if you,
if you are a person and you had like a
thing that was wrong with you,
like a big cancerous legion on your leg
and you just ignored it,
fuck it.
Whatever.
Right?
Keep on trucking,
right?
Yeah.
That is exactly what any sort of crime
infested area is.
It's a problem that if you don't address
is not going to get any better.
That's always going to get worse if
people don't address the problems in
society until it affects them.
What do you think they could do though?
Like how,
besides just education,
how do you stop as much crime?
How do you give people like counseling?
You can get the guns out of Chicago,
you can get the guns out anyway if you
want to.
You think so?
How would they get it?
Would get most of the guns out right?
And get.
You can get most of the guns out.
You can do that.
But do you run the risk of taking guns
away from people that could defend
themselves in a really dangerous area
that's filled with guns by taking by,
by taking the guns out.
Like what about people that are also.
So like,
who are you going to take the guns away
from?
You're going to take the guns away from
the lady who runs the bakery,
who carries a lot of cash.
So lady under the lady that runs the
bakery keeps our gun lady that runs the
bakery that has a,
that has a business that provides goods
and services for the neighborhood that
wants to protect that.
Once protection keeps her gun.
Did you see that recent video?
There's a crazy video of these two gals
behind the
stove and one lady took it yesterday and
got punched her in again.
It comes back in Wales or in the head.
And then the other girl pulls a gun out.
He keeps our gun.
Yeah.
That she keeps her gun because shit like
that might happen.
But that guy.
Now imagine if he had a gun,
that's a good thing for people to see.
This is why.
And I'm not saying everybody should have
guns.
It's a good thing for people to see
because you only hear the other side.
You only hear guns being dangerous and
killing people.
You don't hear people like that lady
that just saved herself.
I'm getting the fuck beat out of her
with a gun.
I know.
I saw,
I saw that video.
And then I saw the other video.
Was a guy in a jewelry store?
Yeah,
it comes in two,
three,
two or three guys.
Hoodies on.
Mask on.
You see the guys coming through the
door,
pulling their mass down.
It's like on the camera.
And then you see a guy walk away from
the jewelry display.
He walks in the camera shooting this
way.
So he walks out of range of the camera
and when the guys come in and he comes
back blasting full.
Whoa.
That guy keeps his gun.
Jesus.
He just started shooting.
Soon as they came in,
guns out.
Oh Jesus.
Yeah.
So what happened?
It was,
it was customers in it too.
So I know he hit one.
He first guy.
Yeah.
And other two ran out.
And you see the guy running out of
camera range,
he imagined being in a fucking jewelry
store trying to buy a watch for your
wife in a gunfight breaks easement ring.
You just like,
I'm so in love.
Me and my girl are going to get an.
A guy just comes in and you think this
could be it.
This is how I'm going to go.
Like my kids.
You know what?
This is a sign we shouldn't get married.
But she was scary.
I just have too much ptsd to get married
right now.
That is hilarious.
Yeah.
But she.
You run a business,
you keep your.
To keep your gun.
Yeah.
He's just a guy on the corner of 20 guys
on the corner.
Cops stopped him for his.
Okay.
Taking these guns,
it's going to be hard to get 'em all
man.
And the problem is defining who gets to
keep one and who doesn't get to keep on
this very sketchy.
Let's have that argument later.
Let's get the guns verse.
Well guys,
you're never going to get them back.
Like if once you take them away,
whoever got the guns taken away,
they're never getting their guns,
but I know that you've got to take the
guns and then you have to,
there has to be more to just that you've
got to take the guns and it has to be an
increased police presence.
You have to take the guns,
have to be something to do with school,
lets out,
you have to take the guns and they have
to be a counseling for drug offenders
and you take the guns and there has to
be jobs in the neighborhood.
You know,
it's a lot of steps that have to cope.
But,
but you can,
it can be done.
Yeah.
Um,
you definitely get the illegal guns,
right?
If you could somehow or another get
access to them,
the illegal guns,
the legal ones are going to be real
tough because if someone has a gun
legally and they haven't committed a
crime,
it's going to be real hard to take that
gun away from that.
But I don't think if they did the
numbers,
the guys with legal guns aren't the guys
that are committing crimes,
right?
The guy with a legal gun,
I'm pretty sure it isn't
the guy that drove past this particular
shot up.
Then you've got to worry about the
people with legal guns getting robbed
for their guns.
Right.
You know,
um,
if guns become a shortage,
the whole thing is very,
it's a,
it's a real problem.
And it's very,
um,
it's very complicated I think to try to
completely solve it.
And how do you get these people that are
in that life that are every day involved
in gang violence?
And I don't think I could be wrong.
I don't think everybody that's in gang
life wants to be there.
I think you're right.
No,
I think you're definitely right.
I think they just like,
what the fuck else is there to do in
this neighborhood.
I,
right.
You're right.
I think if they had an opportunity to,
you know,
I think they got the kid that is a very
good basketball player,
that his uncle was it,
like I said,
his family lineage,
his gang life.
If he had a chance to go play basketball
somewhere,
he would take that chance.
I think you're totally right and I think
in the absence of any other chances
that's when it becomes something that's
an option.
Right?
Yeah,
and I think it's all about the same
feeling that people get when they're
joining gangs or when they're like a
staunch right winger or a staunch left
winger.
I think it's all the same thing.
It's like people have a desire to belong
to something.
Absolutely.
To make something that makes your life
have more meaning.
I feel like it has more meaning and then
when you don't have that,
you'll get behind anything you get
behind anything.
Like I say on instagram all the time,
it's like I told my little brother just
yesterday.
It's the reason why they call them
followers because they just want to get
behind shit.
They don't even understand.
Yeah.
If you like,
I get my instagram is hilarious because
I get a lot of people like I'll get
girls that are like,
Hey,
I love what you're doing.
I saw your shows.
Then I get the random guy.
I was like,
your shit.
You just Chris's brother,
you ain't shit.
And it's like,
dude,
that's what you like.
You think that's gonna hurt me,
but if you just want it to be involved
in this,
you just want it to be a part of it.
You didn't.
You wanted my attention.
You didn't know how to get it.
Well,
the problem is the desire to do that in
the first place.
So who the fuck are you?
Like,
why would you want to do that?
Why did you want to make somebody feel
bad for no reason for what we want to be
involved in.
In some capacity?
Yeah.
Here's a tip to anybody that thinks like
that.
There's no way.
You're not a loser.
It's impossible.
There's not a single winner alive that
would write something like that.
Absolutely.
Do you think like maybe like Michael
Jordan goes trolling through instagram
accounts,
looking for shit,
Yay.
Shit.
Without your brother keep badgering,
you had to sign with the Lakers,
beat the fuck out of here.
That's what it loses it.
Winners and losers always have an excuse
for why you're not winters.
It's weird,
you know,
and I think it's a lot of it is people
not having good examples around them
when the grown up getting fucked over
being in a bad situation.
It's like we're just developing shitty
people or at least people that have
shitty ideas in these cycles where it
just doesn't ever get better in certain
spots.
I agree.
I think we're making more shitty people
now.
It's more shitty people that before I
agree with,
but I feel like we can put a curb on
that.
I feel like slow it down.
How do we curb.
People have to change the way they think
about shit.
It's this,
it's this time is too short to be
shitty.
You know,
when everybody's been shading.
I've been shitty before.
I'm sure you've been told Jamie shitty
the other day.
Remember,
I'm just kidding.
We all have been,
you know,
it's just people have to figure out a
way to do that.
Less and resist the urge to do it.
That urge to do it as a batter or it
doesn't help anybody.
You just.
You just feel good because you've made
somebody feel bad.
Like for what?
You don't even know Tony Rock.
Why you talking shit to him.
Like what is that dude?
Fuck you in Bro.
But that's the reason why I know about
him in the first place.
He was Fuckin Loci or no,
but that's like a fake that that's like
a fake,
a sense of feeling better about yourself
because it doesn't really make you feel
better,
but it doesn't at all and if it does,
it clearly doesn't affect me.
It doesn't hurt me one bit.
It also defines you to yourself because
you know you're not a winner because
it's impossible.
You think Elon Musk goes in and trolls
on twitter and says means shit to
people.
Talks about girls assets.
He doesn't have the time for that.
Right?
He's a winner.
He's busy rescue in that they got those
kids out of the cave and Thailand.
Yeah.
That's one of those baby in a well type
things.
Every few years,
like a little kid falls into a,
well,
why does that happen?
I don't know,
man.
We need to fix.
Or that shit should not be an option
year.
That's when his pinky finger off on the
July.
Fourth happens every year.
You would think people would learn,
oh,
that's probably happening all year round
Texas places we can go to Mexico real
quick.
Sneak over there and by firing every.
Every fourth of July in Brooklyn is like
Mike lost his finger.
I bet if they had a video across
America,
you know how they have those time lapse
videos and you could see every kid ever
documented that lost a finger in a
firecracker accident,
like hands are at war with a
firecracker.
You can just look across the country and
see from.
From California to New Jersey and just
see every movie like,
Oh my God,
that one pocket,
which is every year,
every year.
What did you see?
The NFL player.
They've posted a picture of his hand.
People,
Jason,
Jason Pfo show it to me.
It's like,
to me it's like,
oh no.
Yeah,
it's bad.
Oh Shit.
What happened?
That was July fourth,
last year,
two years ago.
Two years ago.
He blew up his hand.
He's a basketball player.
Oh my God.
Him Eighty in his hand.
So he lost fingers.
Millions of dollars.
So that was it.
He played again.
So he came back and played with a cast
on his hand,
but he.
Was He still playing?
He got traded to the Tampa Bay.
He can play football as a defense.
He has.
Oh,
okay.
He's defense.
Stewed.
What in the fuck though?
He blew his thumb off man.
And it's,
we're a pointer.
Finger Index.
Finger
fingers on.
I don't know what that is.
That's the middle finger.
Middle Finger.
Middle Finger ring and Pinky.
Jesus.
Fuck man.
That is terrifying.
Wow.
He shared that on the fourth video was
like be careful in the fourth and I just
had good for him.
Good for him.
Yeah.
Fuck those things man.
They're too easy to get in some spots.
You know,
like if you're on a border city just
sneak over to Juarez.
We wouldn't even see him in Brooklyn
until around around the fourth.
And they disappeared after I took a
drive to Tijuana.
Once we're working in San Diego,
La Jolla La Jolla comedy store.
We took a drive right down to Tijuana
and see.
There's a weird feeling you get with.
This was in the nineties.
Men.
This is like when it was still want to
come back.
Now people go there for cheap dental
work.
They do.
People cross the border to go to a
dentist to go to a dentist.
Dentists really super cheap.
Yeah.
Holy Shit.
No cost of living over there.
This is in Beverly Hills.
You want that dude to play prime real
estate.
You need to get paid.
You want to.
Yeah.
You want a dentist?
It's like really hustling.
Not a dentist.
It's easier if women go down into the
butt injections also down they go to do
that.
I think it fake titties.
And what injections.
Really?
Nah Man in hotel rooms go to a hotel.
What is that?
The map is.
Here's the border and there's all the
dentist right on my street,
right on the main street.
Right off the border.
Isn't that crazy?
So you pick who's the first guy right
there.
Central?
Yeah.
That you want a clinic for cosmetic
dentistry.
Holla at your boy when it gets pearly
white son.
I'm tired of these marijuana and coffee
stain choppers.
I'm going down there.
I'm going to come back pretty.
I'm not going to say Shit Jamie.
I'm just going to disappear.
I've been to on them and I'll tell you
I'm going on a hunting trip and then
I'll strike out and then I'll come back
with some shiny.
The limited doing.
They're going to Miami for the weekend.
They come back from Tijuana was tied and
the other one fake tits are weird one
man because we'd never accept anything
like that on a dude.
But I grew up with like take it like if
a guy like fake traps.
I just liked the look guys just put fake
trap thing because they filed the girls
like traps.
If there was a one thing like that,
but there was nothing that a guy could
not even close it.
Nothing's even close.
So we were like,
I'll take it,
I'll take it.
We don't care where so much easier than
them.
That's what it is.
That's why.
That's why we have so many.
You Got Youtube site fake.
Have a fake ass guys like you right
there.
Don't care guys with a fake ass.
You imagine if a girl was like you,
your book is so big,
you must be upheld.
Jumped so high.
I think I was like,
no,
I have my blood done last year.
Girl.
Be like,
why did you.
What did you guys don't care?
And then he said,
ready?
He said,
I got my butt done.
That's what he said.
I got my nickname.
They'd have a negative often,
but on guys don't care.
We just like.
My cousin used to have a joke.
He said,
I don't give a fuck what's in your
titties?
Just fuck me.
No,
Whoa,
that guy's aggressive.
That's funny.
Yeah.
Well,
if women can hear the ridiculous shit
that men say when they're not all the
time,
all the shit that makes us laugh.
That's the gross is people try to
pretend that we mean everything we say
too,
especially common with men in comics,
but right now men in comedy,
men in Compton.
Right,
right.
That's the problem.
Just like sometimes some of this stuff
was just joking,
you know,
like stop being so serious.
We most of it will.
Just joking.
Yeah.
Do you find that this is a more
sensitive time for comedy?
That's what I'm being told and that's
what I see in the news,
but I refuse to change anything I do
kind of can't write.
I'm not doing it.
I'm not saying jokes and having to issue
a statement later.
It's like I was saying in joke,
man,
if you didn't take it,
if you didn't take it the way I
interpreted it,
if you interpreted it the wrong way,
that's on you.
I'm not doing it.
Yeah.
It's just supposed to be funny.
Stupid.
Right.
It was funny to somebody.
You know,
it's weird that it's okay to do in a
movie.
Like you could have some ridiculous
scenes in the movie,
but when you have a ridiculous thing
that you're saying,
like people take it as a fact because
not even because.
Yeah,
right.
Yeah.
There's no acting.
It's like you said it.
Rogan believes this,
this thinks that.
Yeah.
It's interesting.
I think this is a,
like a very unique time in communication
for people.
It's one of the reasons why stand up is
a little bit more challenging right now,
but I think that's all good thing,
man.
Challenging is good.
Good.
It's good.
Make for a better product.
Yeah.
It's all good.
It's all interesting what you been
working mostly these days.
I'm on the first quarter.
I was a on what Mike Epps?
Mike Epps.
Uh,
we went out from January to like march,
April,
and then I do my own thing.
You went on tour tour?
Yeah.
The real deal.
Every week.
Mike brings him out,
man,
like 10,000,
12,000.
Jesus Christ credible.
And when you do a tour like that,
man,
and you're doing how many nights a week?
Uh,
we do Friday and Saturday.
If it's three.
If it's a three day weekend,
which was Sunday.
Oh,
so every week,
Friday,
Saturday,
Saturday.
And then are you working in the city at
all?
Are you working in here?
I'm always working in the city.
I'm always working with you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's a.
That gets you sharp as fuck.
Right?
Right.
And then I do that and then from there I
do 20,
maybe 25 minutes with Mike.
Then when that leg is done,
I do from April,
May to October,
September,
October.
Funny Bones,
Improv comedy clubs,
more intimate settings with the guys I
bring out.
Yeah.
And we do that until,
you know,
Ellie needs me,
I'll be on the road and now we just,
they just added more dates for Mike for
the fourth quarter.
So we doing west coast now we're doing
Portland in San Fran and Oakland and San
Diego in California and Phoenix.
And it's going to be incredible,
man.
You're one of those guys where I'm like,
what the fuck is going on?
Like how come people have caught on the
fact that Tony Rocks one of the funniest
guys alive?
Yeah,
I,
I've had it,
the lady at the show the other night,
she said,
I think the whole world is sleeping on
it,
and I said that's the fucking best
compliment I ever had.
Like his man,
you've been under the radar but getting
better.
Like I remember I got.
That's all that matters.
As long as I'm getting better,
I'll pop up on your radar at some point.
I don't remember how long ago this
conversation was,
how long you been doing comedy now?
Ninety eight.
So I think we had this conversation more
around the year,
2000 ish.
It was,
it was fairly recent in like you started
doing standup.
We were talking at the laugh factory and
I remember coming up to you and go,
dude,
you got good.
Like you got good like you,
you really made a big jump and Damon and
you were saying,
I'm working man.
I'm out here working every day.
And uh,
I remember watching that set and
thinking,
I don't remember what year this was,
but I want to say it was like 2002 or
three or something like that.
Watch this settles,
like,
Oh dude,
this guy is about to pop.
Nice.
Yeah,
I'll,
I'll be under the radar until I'm the
man.
That's the thing.
Every time I see you getting better that
that radar is a good thing and then
people will say,
oh,
he blew up.
But not knowing that.
Like you said,
it was 2000.
We had this conversation.
It's a fucking grind baby you to be,
you gotta be in it.
So a lot of guys,
a lot of guys I work with at the laugh
factory,
you know,
I see them all the time.
Ron Rubin,
Paul,
goofball.
Sure.
I.
Ruben Paul,
he's working.
I see a,
I see a hello everybody.
I can't think.
Think of the names of most of Nathan's
Rubin I see all the time.
He does his own room there now and he
has a Tuesday night show that he does.
It's like we,
we,
we in the trenches,
man,
we work in.
That's how to do it.
It's the only way to.
It's the only way in this crazy
business.
It's a weird businessman and it's just,
you know,
if you stayed in that work mode,
so much stuff going on in the world,
on,
in the world,
this material out there,
you just describe it.
It's out there.
Yeah.
There's always something fucked up
going.
Right.
Especially today and then in your life
there's stuff going on.
You're like,
okay,
got gotta.
Put that down.
I mean this is one of the strangest
times I think ever to be a comedian.
Ooh,
where do I begin?
That's great.
That's a great intro.
Like,
fuck,
what do I start?
What do I do?
Where do I get?
The whole thing's a mess,
man.
We're buddying up with dictators,
knows what's happening.
We've got a TV star for a president and
he's actually.
The economy is doing well,
so no one knows what to say.
The whole thing is chaos.
First Lady was in playboy,
taught us,
lady was in playboy.
She is the very first hot as fuck first
lady,
right?
No doubt.
Well,
we haven't seen all the first lady,
so that's true.
She's the very first hot as fuck.
First lady was.
She was stylish,
stylish,
wasn't she shut down.
She was okay.
If melania walked in the room,
you start talking to Jackie.
No risk,
no disrespect,
no disrespect.
She was a beautiful lady.
She certainly was.
She was.
I'm sure,
wonderful woman,
but Melania is stunning.
She's like supermodel stunning.
Yeah.
Especially when she was younger.
She's stunning.
Do you ever see pictures of her young
Melania?
No.
Dude,
when?
When he first married and she's a
beautiful woman,
like undeniably.
Well,
you don't have to agree with him because
he's.
I see some attraction there,
but I don't know.
She's like,
Holy Shit.
I think view around her in a party.
And you both had a couple of cocktails.
Oh,
it might go down and she touched your
thigh.
Looked at you.
You'd be like,
Oh shit.
I just got light headed to her or we
pull it up.
Picked you up.
What are we doing?
What are you doing,
Jamie?
Playboy picks.
You know it.
Just just,
just take a.
just show a photo of Melania,
right?
Why can't we see the playbook?
Here we go.
Come on.
Oh,
that's not bad.
She's hot as fuck.
That's not that one on the left is not
bad.
Yeah.
That's her when she was younger,
but not much younger.
I mean,
I think it's just how she's wearing what
she's wearing.
She's dressed more conservative now.
If you look at her in the far right
pick,
you know,
she's more conservatively.
That's not bad.
There's not even a close second.
She knocked it out of the park.
That's a legitimate professional hot
chick.
Who's the first lady?
First Hour,
right?
Save your bickering.
Stopped this.
Michelle Obama was gorgeous.
That's true.
But a different way.
A different way.
What's this?
This is her.
When she was younger.
That was definitely a different.
Gorgeous.
This is a different thing,
so I'm looking at that body.
Sit on the couch.
Get the fuck out of dodge.
Alright,
you got it.
You got that.
It's like the beginning of that door
song coming.
Come on.
That was nice.
That's whew.
That is a top of the food chain right
there.
Apparently she isn't into looks as much.
Maybe she just likes the way he treats
her go.
It's a strange,
strange time.
Tony Rock,
you know,
strange.
I love being a human being.
As a comic.
You got to love it.
Like you said.
Um,
do you like living around here?
Uh,
you know what?
I like La.
I don't love it.
It's not like,
oh my God,
I'm such a New Yorker.
I just,
I'm used to that.
How long have you been living down here
now?
Ten years.
Ten years?
Yeah,
but like the first three I was,
I would go home every.
You,
I was here filming a TV show,
so every height this week I would go
home and when the show wrapped I would
go on tour.
So I wasn't here the whole time.
The people who like New York,
especially New York comics,
they say that New York comics,
it's more harsh.
Like it's more fun,
like people insult each other more.
Yeah.
There's like a,
there's a comradery to that.
That's way more comradery.
Way More.
I come to la,
it's like,
oh,
I didn't know we were enemies.
I didn't know we were all against each
other.
How do you feel that?
Yeah.
Really more so with black comics.
Oh,
more so black comics of course,
like,
you know,
that's unfortunate.
I got to.
Unfortunately I have the brother that
everybody's like,
you know,
he said,
oh,
he's the best and all this his brother.
Fuck that guy.
This guy's regarded as the best and
that's his brother.
Fuck him.
He's going to get passed along.
He doesn't have to work hard,
but you to have everything handed to
him.
That didn't happen with the Wayans
brothers like Keenan and Marlin or a
demon rather.
Why do you think that is?
I don't know.
Like they did stuff together.
Keenan,
ivory Wayans and Damon waynes.
Like when they were both.
They were both famous of the exact same
time.
Yeah.
People forget how funny.
Daymond was.
A monster still monster.
Still.
Most when I used to see him in the
nineties,
he had a last his last stand up,
I think he called it a three.
The last day.
He was like,
I'm done.
I'm never doing this again.
That shit is one of my all time favorite
specials.
Didn't grab,
grab,
grab a quick bite.
You hilarious.
Tommy hearns piece.
He is so funny,
my brother said,
uh,
Dave and told him a lot about how to
stand up.
Oh,
I'm sure.
Yeah,
it was,
it still the man he was,
he was a guy who would come in.
I'm do late night spots of the comedy
store.
He would just show up and you know,
they'd put them up whenever he got there
and he would just completely explore
ideas like he had no worry about,
like he wasn't concerned about getting a
laugh.
He was working it out on stage 100
percent have seen it.
He was a famous guy at the time.
This is after in living color.
I see dave do it all the time.
Whenever I see David's stage,
David's like,
fuck this room.
I'm trying to figure this shit out for
the show,
you know,
but you also want to entertain the room
because they are the show too.
Right.
So Dave is,
I think,
the best dancing through that line.
He knows how to create new material
better than I think anybody I've ever
seen.
Have you seen Mark Curry?
Yo,
yeah.
Mark will go on stage and say give me a
topic and make it a 10 minute bit.
Yeah.
Yeah,
and that shit is impressive.
He's such a nice guy.
I think he is so likable.
Like Mark Curry,
like one of the nicest fucking guys.
Like when he would come to the comedy
store,
everybody would light up.
It was just so nice.
Like always funny to do it.
I like real relax like him a lot.
Man.
Y'all see I saw him do a lot of sets
back then too.
Back when he was doing,
hanging with Mr Cooper.
He drop in and do that.
I haven't seen him in a long time.
I think he was on tour with a cat right
there.
He's got a sleeper Bronco.
I think he still has it.
We had this like 19 eighties black
Bronco,
but he had it all done up like Oj Bronco
and was like,
oh Jane Bronco.
But he a.
He had like a engine upgrade in it.
Suspension,
upgrade tires,
wheels,
the whole deal.
It was like an urban assault vehicle,
like a powerful Bronco that like.
It just looked like an older bronco.
Let somebody just has on the road,
but meanwhile this thing,
it's like tuned up.
Nice.
Yeah.
The classics man.
Yeah,
and he would drive around that thing.
He had a gang of cars.
I love cars.
Really Nice.
Funny Guy.
I gotta.
I gotta get some old schools.
I want to.
I want to train them.
That's what I was.
Ooh,
what?
The smokey and the bandit.
Trans and.
Yeah,
that's what I would.
What is this?
Oh,
that's right.
It died.
He got hit by a tree.
Fuck,
that's right.
Did he catch on fire?
No,
a man.
But that's the Bronco.
Yeah.
Damn.
The storm last year took mark curry's
Bronco.
He loved that thing,
man.
That was it.
It was a total sleeper.
That car was a sleeper.
Three smart dudes like him.
Man.
They good sleepers.
They like to drive around a no notice
car.
You gotta around like that to don't
bring too much attention.
Yeah.
You got to move around and go wherever
you want to go.
When you want to go,
you know,
that's a movement and no nonsense.
Bronco.
I need an old school.
What kind of A.
I liked the,
I liked the pickup trucks,
the old thirties or forties,
fifties.
The Chevy with the uh,
with the.
Like the bubble.
Oh yeah.
A tire covers what it was like.
Oh,
I don't know.
But I know what you're talking about.
There's one that a lot of people redo.
There's a very specific,
a chevy pickup truck that right there.
Oh,
I need that.
I need one of those 1950 chevy pickup.
Wow.
It's crazy what they can do to those
two.
I mean,
who would have ever saw if you looked at
one of those in the flesh in 1950 that
someone would have something like that
in 2018.
That looks like something from the
movie.
Fifty eight cars.
It costs $6,000 in 1950.
Did it even cost that much?
Let's guess.
How much did the pickup truck costs in
1950?
I say $1,500.
I'm going to say $3,500.
How much did it pickup?
Cost in 1950.
Here we go.
Drum roll please.
Nothing popped up off the top.
That gives me pricing for now too.
So I'm trying to.
Oh,
how did you write?
How much did it pickup?
Truck costs of in retail price in 1950.
Maybe that's it.
People listening to this support out of
their fucking mind right now.
Like,
do you really care?
Why?
Do you care what a pickup truck cost?
Nineteen 50 or they watch it live.
Some people.
Hey,
what's up people?
There's a slight delay.
Nice.
Oh,
for curses.
Because the Internet,
I think it's too late.
We already fucked it up.
How much do they cost?
12.
40 three.
1,200?
Yeah.
Twelve 43.
12.
Forty three.
One thousand.
Two hundred $43.
That's crazy.
Insane.
I tell current value of $30,000.
Nice or so?
Yeah.
I gotta get one.
That's what you want.
Why a pickup truck?
Not a muscle car.
No,
I wouldn't.
I want that.
I want that to hold that spoon.
We debated at first.
Oh yeah,
of course.
I wanted to.
Lincoln continental with the suicide.
Doors need that.
Wow.
Got To have that.
The smokey and the bandit.
You're gonna have the firebird on the
front end.
The Hood?
Yeah.
The same one I went to,
uh,
I want to
the Ford Mustang.
The Illinois.
Yes.
The in 60 seconds car than that.
That's one of the best looking cars of
all time.
Probably the.
Yeah,
probably the 66 corvette.
Beautiful car.
Those are great.
Gardasil car.
I have a [inaudible] 65 convertible.
Do you really love so you know.
Yeah,
they're great.
Beautiful piece of machinery.
It's crazy.
Look right there.
Look back.
The top comes off like you just did
right there.
That's one of the most beautiful cars
ever made.
Is that a 67,
jamie?
That's what it says.
God,
that is incredible.
Is it called Eleanor before that movie
or that come from it came from the
movie,
right?
Yeah.
No,
I think it means something.
I think eleanor,
when you say it backwards,
like whatever the acronym is,
the,
uh,
find it.
It's the.
I think that's what they did.
I think they took some kind of tuner
thing,
some someone's name and used it
backwards.
It's like Roanoke,
is that it?
I remember very vaguely the story how
they came up with the name eleanor.
Anyway,
see if you can find it.
Yeah,
definitely need that.
that right there to dope fucking car.
Super Dope.
Maybe I'm thinking the opposite.
Maybe what I'm thinking of is someone
made a car that's like eleanor,
but they spelled it backwards.
I think that might be it.
It just says eleanor is the only forward
one,
mach one in history to see if a car
title credit.
Take the word eleanor and spell it
backwards and Google that.
I think there's a car that they're
making where they spell eleanor
backwards.
I think this is where I'm getting at the
Hyundai rule of the age.
The new Hyundai.
Yeah.
What would be eleanor?
Two thousand five Ranell Mustang.
Oh,
see there it is.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
That's where I fucked up.
Yeah,
so there's a mustang that they were.
There were spelling eleanor backwards to
make a dope Mustang.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Not Bad.
Yeah,
not bad for a modern car for fun.
That's nice.
Those are like modern muscle cars.
Those cars like that year,
like a into the 2000,
15 and 16 is when they kept the.
They got rid of the live rear axle
somewhere around,
I want to say like pretty recently,
like 2012 or something like that.
When,
when was the,
the,
the latest Mustang released the latest
model Mustang.
Before that they used to have a solid
rear axle,
like a muscle car.
Right.
So it can handle terrible,
but it's.
But it was fun to go,
but you would stomp on the gas and
things would go sideways.
It would burn out everywhere.
It was really like having a modern
muscle car with like antilock brakes and
a stick shift and you buy it from the
factory with 550 horsepower.
Ridiculous car.
Then they got it all the way up to 700.
And the last models,
the last models of the GT,
500 or 700 horsepower.
Front wheel rear wheel drive.
Wow.
700 horsepower with a rear axle.
That's insane.
Yeah.
Big crazy rear axle bouncing all over
every.
Every pothole.
You hit the cargo sideways.
I don't,
but they apparently.
That's great though.
Those old school,
he muscle cars for grip and the ground.
There's something about having
everything all in one heel in the office
a little bit back.
Just those two black stripes on the
asphalt as it goes sideways.
I love it.
Dance.
What'd you say?
You have a 60,
65 core Corbett?
Yeah.
That's nice.
I love it.
It's an old rumble,
I believe from what I just read that
that car was only made made for maybe
even used in that original movie and the
guy that made it,
hb toby,
holyoake wrote,
starred and directed that movie.
No,
that's his car.
So,
but I think they made several versions
because I saw a video of them selling
one of them.
They're selling one of them online.
Yeah,
but there's a company called classic
recreation's.
They.
They make those now they'll.
They'll make you so you can get a frame.
No,
they do the whole thing from the
beginning out and they make you like a
brand new version of a 19,
67 mustang.
But with modern engine modern
suspension,
which is expensive as I could have,
I could have added.
But if you're some rich dude who just
you lucas,
one is the thing about this like
flossing,
right?
Like if you have a Lamborghini,
you like,
look at this guy's doors go up,
you know,
there's something about that,
right?
The lamborghini was made for philosophy.
Ferrari.
Same thing.
You pull up one on like look at this
motherfucker making it woo.
But if you pull up in one of those
things,
that's,
that's a different kind of enjoyment.
That's like you're driving around in a
art piece.
Exactly.
You know,
you.
That's the less attention.
Grab a storyteller that's,
that's like,
people are just going to stop you.
Yeah.
It's like an a plus in terms of the
impact it has on,
on guys in particularly.
Put girls don't care about that as much.
Like think a muscle car.
I think chicks would dig that one.
I think that one.
That one's so.
Dig The long ball,
man.
You thought that's the logo that is,
that's out of the house.
Like what is that like?
Hey,
come take a it.
Yeah,
pull up.
Pull that photo up again.
That's silver one.
That 1967 silver one that you just had
up.
Look at this again.
She's looking at you.
You pull that up in front of the club.
Yeah,
Jesus Christ.
That's pretty.
Do you know how much the one from the
movie sold for at auction?
Let me guess.
The one from the $700,000.
$4 million.
1 million.
Wow.
What the main one from John Wick or from
Al Ghanim?
Sixty seconds in John Wick.
That's what it was.
It wasn't the eleanor one.
I'm remembering wrong.
It was the.
They were selling one of the mustangs
and the movie John Wick.
He had a 69.
He had a.
It wasn't a Illinois,
but if he had a nice moment in the
movie,
right?
Hit a 69 that got stolen.
Got killed his dog and stole stolen car
and then he got a 70 Chevelle shipped.
That's another.
Everybody that's 70 shows that 70
Chevelles class.
That's a good one.
That's an impala.
I got to get an impala to Anita.
You know what's even more classic than
will look at that.
God Damn Man.
That's a [inaudible].
Sixty nine.
I think that's a mock one.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
Look at that time.
Uh,
it makes me faintest fucking pretty weak
in the legs and I see a car like that.
Like,
oh my goodness.
Look at that thing.
That is America.
It's like two pieces that I think it's
like the front.
Yeah.
They do not drive that good.
They do not because that looks pretty
stock.
They do not handle very well.
Nope.
Terrible.
It's another kind of.
Yeah.
If you had like a modern Honda accord,
you'll blow that thing off the road for
real.
You've written that's Goddamn Work of
art though.
Pull up in that thing.
You take the Honda accord.
I'll take that.
Look at that.
Look how pretty that is.
That might be one of the best looking
cars of all time.
Know that eleanor is.
Yeah.
Top three.
Go to that one in the upper right hand
corner.
Young Jamie.
Look at that fucking thing.
S 1969.
Mach one dude Hendricks who was alive
that his car was out.
That is a sexy vehicle right there.
Hendrix died in [inaudible].
Sixty nine.
Right?
You could,
you could have been on your way to a
Goddamn Hendrix concert in that car in
1969.
You would be.
The man can imagine you pick up your
girl Shit,
Hendrix concert net people,
you know.
People were just different than.
Nice.
Yeah.
Hendrix probably would pull up the
concert.
That right.
That'd be a car.
Hendrix or drive.
Kevin's a guitar in the passenger seat.
Yeah.
I found out there was a house.
It was for sale that Hendrix almost
bought.
I live in Topanga Canyon and I was like,
you don't count the count.
He just walk through it like,
Nah,
not this one.
He was apparently on his way to buying
it when he died.
What is this thing?
Right?
T top Sun damage.
That's Jimi Hendrix corvette.
Holy Shit.
See if you find any other pictures of
that thing.
That's.
That's the sexy car.
Should look like a shock.
God.
Jimmy Hendrix had a baby last night.
That's just a different one,
but yeah,
those are crazy looking.
Go to that other one.
That was just on that.
That this isn't right here.
That's.
So.
There's only a couple of pictures of the
car from the top two corvettes.
Damn.
He had two corvettes.
Are those both is back to back?
Is that what we're looking at?
Two different ones.
It's the same car.
Oh yeah.
Jimmy Hendrix knew how to live old
school man.
Dinosaur.
Beautiful.
Beautiful car.
Yeah.
What do you drive,
Tony?
I have a cadillac.
Ooh,
I like it.
I got a catalog.
Which one do you got?
I got the sts.
Is is old now.
I was actually going to buy a new car
like the next couple of months.
Kind of what?
I want to have a crazy new sedan coming
out.
Which ones?
Some something v,
some big four door.
Super powered.
Ultra comfortable waiting for.
Have you seen the El Mirage?
Can you pull up the Cadillac?
El Mirage,
Mirage e l m I r a J.
I've been waiting for years for this car
and every time I go to the auto show
they're like,
yeah,
it's coming next year.
So I wait,
wait,
wait.
That sounds like a superhero.
And a Robert Rodriguez movie.
The MRI Mirage.
Look at this motherfucker.
Woo,
four years Cadillac.
I've been waiting for this call.
Whoa.
Every auto show.
Yeah,
next year.
That is slick.
That's a two door.
Yes.
Holy Shit.
I've been waiting patiently for this
car.
You know,
when we were kids we thought about what
cars will look like in the future.
That's what they would look like in the
future.
Look at the front end of that thing,
like the headlights.
Those are crazy.
Look at that man.
That has such a futuristic,
like pause there for that picture and
make that a little bit bigger.
That has such a futuristic shaped to
look at the leather on the inside and
look at that grill.
Look on that.
Grill integrates with like,
this is how girls go with shoes.
Like,
oh my God.
Do you see how strappy they are?
And you say to your girl like,
I don't get it.
This is it right here.
You're not going to get it.
This.
It's so strappy.
For years I been waiting for this call.
Why are you such a Cadillac Dude?
My father drove a cadillac.
It's a tribute to my dad.
I like that last call.
My pops had before he passed away was a
Burgundy Cadillac and he,
I just remember he loved it so much and
I didn't know growing up growing up in
New York,
I didn't need a car.
When I moved to La I was like,
Oh shit,
I got to get a car to get around.
I'm like,
what am I going to get tribute to Dad
Cadillac.
I love it.
That's a good move.
Yeah.
They make some old school cars too that
you could actually get fixed up and
drive around some seventies.
Some of them are going to get an Oldie
and put it in the hands of the caretaker
and let them just fix it up.
Get you one of them.
Definitely gonna do that.
Two Door Eldorados.
Who?
What color?
I don't know.
Maybe like a money green.
Oh,
like,
um,
like the Bishop Don Juan.
Do you have a migraine than scratch
that?
Scratch that.
We'll go burgundy because I don't want
anybody to mistake me for the.
I don't want no girl running up and by
calling in and out Burger,
like I got your money daddy.
I liked the burgundy,
I like
burgundy liquid,
like a little bit of metallic flake to
it.
Oh yeah.
That would be nice.
That would make sense.
Yes.
All fresh chrome got to ride those
things,
man.
I mean you got to respect the fact that
it takes a long time to stop those
fuckers.
Convertible Eldorado.
Oh,
look at this.
We're looking at a 76 convertible
Eldorado oh my God.
What a shape.
Look at that.
What a shape that was back when they
didn't know what the fuck.
Aerodynamics was like.
What the old.
That's what we're talking about right
there.
Look at that thing.
Look at that.
What years that Jim?
Sixty seven.
Yeah.
God.
That's nice.
People just drove these enormous boats.
Look at the size of the trunk.
It's crazy.
That trunk couldn't fit like a smart
card.
Yeah.
You could easily sleep in that trunk.
No problem.
That's nice.
They just went through a period of time
where they were making these giant
boats,
like the suicide door.
Continental.
You talked about that time closet.
Yeah.
All time classic.
Got To love that.
Yeah.
That's another one.
Best call probably ever made,
you know,
it's another best car ever made that it
would never want to park anywhere.
Nineteen 68 charger.
I saw in 1968 charger all done up.
Dukes of hazard.
It's similar is that is that year 68 or
69?
One of those years.
He's one of those years.
His bad ass.
But those cars,
they were just like sharks,
like big long boats.
They weren't like in any like look at
that.
That's not in any way practical in terms
of its shape.
Like it's gotta be that winds got to go
into that grill in a weird way and
probably slows it down.
It's like having a little mini parachute
in front of your hood.
Obviously.
I don't know.
Shit.
I don't know about aerodynamic dynamics
back then.
Go back to that original picture,
man.
That original one was beautiful.
Look at that thing.
That's what I'm talking about.
Like that car just represents a
different world.
That's a fast and furious,
right?
Yeah.
He had those right or similar.
Something similar.
Similar years.
There's something about a in 1978 got
weird because then they put the bumper
all around the front,
like a big oval.
Who See?
You ever see that?
No.
This car pull up.
Nineteen 70 charger.
Nineteen 70.
Got Weird.
Like somebody got crafty.
Look at the front bumper.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
What did you just do?
Hey.
Come here.
That's like put it back.
Yeah.
What did you do?
Put it back.
You had one go to the black one right
above it.
Where the headlights.
Oh,
they roll up the roll up like a 69
Camaro.
You ever see a 69 community?
Yeah.
It flips.
Those things flip.
That was like the rage back then man.
People love roll up headlights.
That's a good picture jamie.
But the other ones better because you
could see the uh,
no.
The black one right next to it because
you could see the other blue.
Yeah.
That weren't there because you could see
the grill,
like make that a little bigger.
Like look how goofy that is.
Look how goofy that grill is.
The bumper and the grill
or like it's got a bumper and a down
bumper.
Like,
what are you doing?
Why'd you do that?
Don't do that.
You had it perfect.
You fuck.
Some guy was like,
you know,
but yet Alex.
Oh yeah.
Those people were on coke.
It was the seventies.
They were like,
you know,
fuck double bond.
Let's do it.
Double bumper,
bumper up,
top bumper.
The bottom.
It's my thing,
bro.
You're going to push that through to the
GM.
A.
Hey,
did you bring up my idea about the
double bumper on top?
On the bottom.
I'm telling you,
man,
it's a fucking move.
It's one that I look at that just
doesn't look as good.
It still looks bad ass.
It does.
It's still.
The original picture was the one.
Yeah.
Now go to a 1969.
Nineteen 69 is a sweet spot.
That's when they nailed it and then they
fucked it up.
They should have made the 1969 charger.
Ooh.
Yeah.
See it wasn't.
That was dukes of hazzard.
Look at that one.
That black one up on the upper left hand
corner right there.
Upper left.
Yeah,
right there.
Look at that.
Oh my goodness.
What a shape.
Those people just had a different way of
looking at automobiles.
They weren't confined by.
What's the spot?
Big Bob's big boy and bourbon when they
pass by.
I never stopped in one of those.
I've been to similar things.
I've been to the La auto show too.
It's pretty interesting,
but I guess those cars and coffees and
things he ever done one of those.
No,
I heard those are pretty bad ass people
like pull up with weird cars.
Jay Leno's always showing up.
Some Burbank people.
They have them all over the place.
They haven't been fucking Irvine and all
over the place.
People go to check it out.
Yeah.
I do show every year and I asked about
the El Mirage and they're like,
yeah,
next year you are just obsessed with
cadillacs.
Got To get it.
That's interesting to get it.
So no matter how big you get catalogs,
I'll have other cars,
but it's going to be a caddy,
but that's your main daily driver
probably is.
I've got to get it.
I like it,
man.
I like it.
It's a different,
it's a different kind of luxury car,
you know,
and they're really doing it right now
to,
you know what else doing it right.
The new Lincoln navigator.
See that thing gigantic.
The thing.
It's crazy big man.
I think it's big.
It's luck.
You like it?
Yes.
Yeah,
I've written them before.
They're amazing.
I got to test drive.
I haven't driven one,
but I've written in as a passenger in
one.
I was like,
this thing is bad ass.
Yeah.
I liked the new was foreign,
but that new BMW seven proof.
It's like a couch going down the street.
You just some insane amount of money.
$60,000.
So this is one version of it.
It's the most expensive bmw they've ever
made and it's supposed to be the most
technologically advanced.
And I liked the new,
uh,
the Porsche to the photo of a Panamera
man.
Yeah.
That's the difference between living
here and living in New York,
living in New York.
So many people don't have cars.
Just really don't even.
Like if you have a car in New York is a
luxury this,
then you thought you have to find pocket
and you go fuck this carbon.
My brother,
my brother Kenny had a cough for like a
summer.
It was like I gotta get up and move it
every morning and when I go into the
city I got a five pocket and he's like
fuck this.
And when you drive down the street and
you see ones with boots on them,
people don't.
They don't realize what you see.
The tickets just piled up because
they'll put a ticket on top of the
ticket.
Yup.
And La sometimes people will say,
hey,
if you already have a ticket,
they won't put another one.
I don't know.
In New York they don't.
They'll put a ticket on top of the
ticket.
So he was just like a summer at.
What did he have?
He had a,
that's a different kind of living,
living with no car,
live in liberty and a Ford thunderbird
like we're older.
One,
2004.
Those were weird about this call
tickets.
You know,
it's weird like that thunderbird didn't
really totally work,
but the challenge of work.
Perfect.
Yeah.
The new.
Yes.
Yeah.
People are like,
oh Jesus.
Yeah,
you nailed it.
You got it.
At the thunderbird people like,
what are we doing here?
Is this an old car?
It's in a new car.
We don't know who are we that they
stopped making that,
right?
Yep.
They don't make that anymore.
Yeah,
charges was great.
I don't think Ford makes anything other
than mustangs and trucks.
I think they gave up on every single car
they may bring in a bronco back.
I know that.
Yeah,
bringing the Bronco back,
but I think that was a move they made.
Would you say Jamie,
they haven't focused or they stopped
making it?
I think they decided recently.
We're not counting the Ford focus man.
My real cars.
I think recently they said they're going
to cancel every car except the Mustang
and they're just going to make trucks.
Really?
Yeah.
Somebody went fucking crazy.
Well,
I think they'd probably make that four
gt two and limited numbers,
but yeah,
I think the saline is that.
That's a different company that takes a
Mustang and then they put an aftermarket
kit on it.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That's Steve Saleens company.
They do corvettes and a bunch of other
shit to do a bunch of different.
It's like Hennessy.
You ever heard that?
Hennessy hennessy performance.
I've heard of Hennessy performance,
but are we talking about shelby take?
They take these cars and they'll say
like do it to Eldorado or not an
Eldorado way.
They'll do it to escalate.
They'll do it.
Two corvettes.
Mustangs.
They'll take a regular car and put a
thousand horsepower in it.
Oh Wow.
And sell it.
So it's.
But it's not.
I mean it's not just a corvette,
it's a hennessy corvette.
Now it's like,
you know,
like a saline Mustang is like,
it's like a shelby Mustang.
Kind of similar,
but shelby,
they sell from the Ford dealerships.
Some Ford dealerships sell St John's.
Some of them do that.
You can buy them a few of legitimate
drunk when I'm drunk.
And my performance on Hennessy Hennessy
hennessy performance for to stop making
all passenger cars except the Mustang
explorer.
Yeah.
So they're just doing trucks.
And the Bronco,
but that's a dope one car.
That's weird.
That's the bullet car.
That's the attribute to the Steve
McQueen movie.
That's what that green car is.
Look at that thing.
Damn,
that is gorgeous.
Great movie by the way.
Yeah,
it is a great movie.
They nailed it though.
See Ford nailed it with these mustangs.
They figured out a perfect way to make a
shape that makes you think about old
cars,
but it looks like a new car.
What do they call it?
An Ode to the past.
Yes or no to the past.
That's nice.
Young Tony Rock.
Tony are going to wrap this up.
We just talked about cars for the last
shit.
Sorry.
But people please go see Tony Rock.
No bullshit.
You one of the funniest guys alive.
I'm a big fan.
Kansas City Improv this weekend.
Is this live right?
So I'm in Kansas City and Broxton city
Improv this weekend.
Tony Rock Dot com.
Tony Rock comedy.com.
Tony Rock one.
Instagram,
instagram.
Whoever is camping on the Tony rock
named.
Give it up.
Is it a real.
Tony Rock is his name.
Tony Rock,
I doubt it.
New.
I think there's only one.
Alright.
Anyway,
man,
thanks so much.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.