Dream in here.
We've got 6,000 people on this
motherfucker.
30003000700 for really?
That's what I'm saying.
It takes a little while.
Hey,
and we're lively's gentlemen,
we're live and we're live.
This is the first time we've ever been
live while also being live on instagram
live.
I don't ever use this shit.
Do you ever use this?
I have.
I was for awhile and it was cool,
but it's one,
it's one way to get a lot of new
followers because if you go to top live,
which I'm sure you are,
so who's ever live,
it'll have top live with the most people
who are tuning in and so that's where
you are right now.
And so people who don't follow you,
we'll,
we'll see you on top live.
We have 760077007800 it's getting dark
and crazy in here.
Cameron hanes fresh back from Australian
outback where he's out there wrestling
crowd it.
See those reflexes.
Photo is good and he moves the table.
Didn't even come close.
That's a years of Jujitsu,
years of trying to keep people from
choking me,
my instincts.
I'll do a little too jumpy.
That's the problem.
Right?
Too much quick movement.
There's got to calm that shit down.
So the bonding,
oh,
right.
Well,
and he's the opposite.
He needed the opposite and steady baby
bow hunting is pretty much the opposite
way of thinking than Jujitsu.
Cause Jujitsu,
you gotta fucking,
you gotta keep you gotta constantly.
You've got to constantly be protecting
yourself and move in and trying to close
the deal.
Bowhunting is like steady.
Yeah.
Dude,
you're out there wrestling wallabies I
heard.
Yeah,
something like that.
Jamie's ready to go.
Jamie's he was saying that and he was
like,
I want to wrestle a fucking wall would
be,
I don't think you'll will be up.
We saw a dead one and it has caused
about that long.
Do they're real.
Yeah,
I mean,
so you can imagine and their legs are
just obviously balancing all the time,
their legs.
It just got to be jacked into those big
claws.
I mean what I would try to relate it to
is,
have you ever tried to hold down a cat,
a house cat that doesn't want to be half
a man.
Right.
So they have little tiny claws match.
Have a wall would be with those jack
legs and big claws could do.
Plus it's wild.
Wouldn't be good.
I just have a wild cat.
I had a feral cat.
Is that window?
Wow.
Your cute little fellow.
Yeah.
No.
Whoa.
That's not real.
Is that real?
That's really his teeth.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
I'll look at the clause on those things.
If I don't know if it'll show cause
ever.
I can't believe they have teeth like
that.
See those front?
Because what the hell is the wall beat?
I figured while B it was like eating
nuts and shitty.
No,
I think they're murderers.
Babies,
so it looks like a little kangaroo.
Yeah.
Oh,
they have a kangaroo tail and the whole
deal.
They're just,
they're very similar to Kangaroos.
It was not a real teeth though.
That wasn't photoshopped.
Google.
Well,
Google wallabies teeth because I just
have a feeling that was bullshit.
I just looked like a vampire there.
I feel like they're like the ugly
stepchild of Kangaroos because they're
kind of more hunched over.
I'm like,
damn,
we're losing viewers.
What?
Crazy.
We're top live
though.
We're losing viewers like crazy.
We're down to 5,000,
900.
We're dropping.
Maybe I'll turn it towards me.
Maybe that's a problem.
Probably when it's turned towards Cam.
Oh,
jumping back up.
So now we're up to 6,500.
It is,
it is your page.
That's after I,
that can't be real.
That's the one we're looking at right
now is like a vampire.
Be Deer.
I've seen those things before.
Those vampire deer.
That's a real thing.
Right?
But those deer with those crazy things.
I think so.
Yeah.
It's real.
But like,
why do they have things like that?
Like why does they're not predators.
Very strange.
Did you see that?
Uh,
they found for the first time ever a
deer eating a human carcass at deer.
Yeah.
The scientist.
See if you pull that story up,
it was yesterday.
All alright folks is very distracting.
Uh,
go to,
uh,
Joe rogan.live.
And you could see this whole thing.
I would read this,
but here's the thing about getting older
folks.
Your fucking eyes start to go,
cameron hanes eyes are still excellent
though.
I gotta tell you this motherfucker,
you know,
Shit.
He can see anything.
Conspiracy theory.
We're the same age.
We're the same age and his eyes,
I don't know why my sock,
but um,
it's just the way it goes,
but my dick is getting bigger.
I don't know what's going on with that
either.
No.
Imagine tit for tat.
People would trade in glasses for bigger
deck for sure.
Um,
show feet.
What is that?
People are so weird.
Some of the people put,
they put weird comments just to get you
to read them.
And he got me,
he got me this.
Fuck.
All right folks.
I'm going to shut this off and we're
going to,
uh,
just have a podcast.
Joe rogan.live.
You can watch for streaming on youtube
until we make this big deal with twitch.
So yeah,
Bam.
And live video.
Do I save it done?
Nope.
Didn't save it.
Fuck it.
You can save them as a little thing up
in the upper right hand corner.
But I didn't,
I saw it right.
I was,
I was pressing and mid press sounding
like what's the big deal?
You know?
Dunno.
I Dunno dude.
I'm so never before seen deer spotted
eating human bones.
Makes sense though.
Like they would just think it's like
calcium.
Same.
Yeah.
They don't know it's a bone.
It's not like they like fuck these
people.
So he's like finally deers Eaton beeble
now.
But we've showed videos before,
um,
of deer eating birds.
Like,
cause they eat birds all the time.
Oh they do?
Yeah.
Like literally actively going after
birds.
Like the fallen out of nests dear.
It's like following it and the birds
trying to chase the deer off and there's
like,
yeah,
whatever.
I'm eating that bird.
Look at this.
So this bar,
this deer is the other birds.
They're like,
get out of there,
get out of it.
It's a button buck.
He's got these little tiny nubs and he's
trying to get this ground nesting bird.
He's going to go through the past,
that tree and then the guy filming it.
See?
See the bird hopping around on the
ground.
So it's a bird that fell out of a nest.
Oh,
they don't have like the eat that?
Oh yeah.
100%.
Yeah.
It's kind of,
well he's,
he's chasing it.
I mean,
he's going after a purpose.
What a Predator is.
Look at the speed,
the speed that deer shows.
But it just shows you how opportunistic
live animals are.
Wild animals.
Like some,
something in that deer's body tells it
to eat that thing.
Hey,
there's no compassion out there for
animals.
No watch animal.
An animal.
He's eating it.
Oh,
it's dark.
Yeah.
That's what he goes.
Life.
It's life.
It's just weird to see a deer for some
reason.
Eat a bird and do it on purpose.
Like he's all excited.
It's like,
Oh yeah,
this is great.
He's good.
There is a,
um,
some sort of wildlife thing.
Uh,
they,
they were doing some sort of a survey
and the captured these birds with a net.
They had this net set up,
uh,
in this area where these birds fly just
so they could capture these particular
birds.
But the deer kept eating the birds and
they,
they couldn't figure it out.
They're like,
what is going on here?
And then they watched,
they had a video of these deer walking
up and picking them off the net and
eating these birds while the birds like
Jay's house.
I can't believe this is happening.
Getting eaten by a deer.
Yeah.
You don't see that every day?
No.
That I'm not surprised.
Yeah.
I'm not surprised either.
I've seen cows do it too.
This video is a cows doing it.
For the longest time,
people didn't think that they thought
that,
you know,
those are just herbivores.
But no,
they just,
nature's just set them up to be super
slow.
But if something really delicious is in
front of them,
I thought it was an Eddie Bravo thing.
Oh,
this conspiracy.
Yeah.
He came up with it.
No,
it's not an Eddie Bravo conspiracy.
Eddie Brow believes a lot of
conspiracies,
but he doesn't believe that.
What does this one,
oh,
what does that an Eagle Jack and a bunny
rabbit.
That's a deer.
Deer and eagles are so ruthless.
Oh look at that.
Bam.
We can do this all day folks.
You got back from the real wild man like
when you were the instagram stories.
So Cameron Hanes and our buddy Adam
Green tree and a few other fellows were
up there in the north country of
Australia and you guys took over the
under armour hunt page and uh,
it was epic man that the underarmour
hunt page.
Like the little instagram stories.
Yeah.
I don't like instagram stories.
You know why?
Cause they're only 15 seconds and the
old teases.
I want you guys to be like live
streaming from up there.
Yeah,
it would be nice.
Wouldn't it put up a super cool are you
guys were at it was terrifying.
Yeah.
Kept showing these brown snakes these.
The second most deadly snake in the
world.
Yeah,
that's what I'm told.
Yeah.
You sound like how many of them?
Uh,
four or five.
Yeah,
but it only takes one.
Yeah.
And you're dead,
right?
Like,
I'd already watched dead.
Well,
second most deadly.
Yes.
Doesn't sound good.
That's not good.
No,
no.
And then there's,
you know,
big old spiders and crocodiles.
Yeah.
You guys saw crocodiles.
You even filmed crocodiles.
They were right where we were,
you know,
super.
It was,
I mean,
this is still not even their summer,
but it's still very warm.
I mean,
where we were up,
uh,
hunting buffalo at the top man is what
they call,
which is out of Darwin.
It was 90 to a hundred degrees.
So there's some film of a,
now this is a freshwater crocodile,
which is not as big,
not as big or as aggressive as a
saltwater Croc,
but could still definitely do damage.
And this was,
you know,
a mere feet from where we were sleeping.
And this is the,
where we'd go and take baths and uh,
or just kind of cooled down during the
heat of the day.
That's where he was right there.
And how big is that guy?
Oh,
I dunno.
Six,
eight,
seven,
eight feet,
something like that.
You know,
he wasn't huge,
but he definitely do some damage and get
a hold of Ya.
Did you guys see any of the salt water
once while you're there?
No.
So when you were telling me about this a
one pond that was near you guys,
where you saw eyes at night and you
didn't think of that was,
that was,
it was right there.
So the,
the first night we saw the one,
just that one right there,
we went over there and videoed him and,
and checked him out.
And then the next night Adam went down
there to the creek and it was only about
maybe 15,
20 feet across,
just small,
just very shallow.
And uh,
he looked down and said there was like
six sets of eyes,
red eyes,
which is crocodile.
So,
and that was,
you know,
they'd moved in.
So have you ever seen a live salt water
one in the wild?
Um,
I think we did the last time I hunted
there,
but I'm trying to remember.
Or maybe it was,
I think when we were flying.
Yeah.
When,
when we were flying,
we saw him.
Oh,
we've,
cause so you have to take a flight from
where Adam lives.
Adam lives near Melbourne,
right?
Sydney,
New South Wales.
You fly four and a half hours to Darwin
toward these water buffalo are.
Yep.
And then w w last time we used a
helicopter to get out of Darwin to,
and that was four hours in the
helicopter.
Whoa.
And so this time we had a helicopter and
so we flew the country,
kind of look at it and we saw some
pretty big crocs from there on the river
system.
So how do you know like,
where to stop?
Like when your buffalo hunting,
how do you know where to go?
Um,
well I mean basically it's however far
you can walk,
you know,
I mean you kind of get,
we were walking,
I dunno,
I want to say at least 10 miles a day.
10 10 to I think Adam and his guys.
One time his camera guy walked 18 miles
one day.
So we were just,
you know,
we're always,
10,
12,
13 miles a day.
So just covering country.
It was,
it was hard hunting up there right now
because this is their wet season or the
tail end of their wet season.
And so the foliage was,
was really grown up really thick.
So it was very hard to see the buffalo
normally,
um,
later when we went,
Eh,
it's all burnt up because of summer and
said there's no foliage.
And,
uh,
you can see the buffalo from miles
basically.
But with this grass,
the grass is in some places,
eight,
eight feet tall.
I mean,
you'd have to be 50 yards away to see a
buffalo and they're,
you know,
1800,
1800 to 2000 pounds.
So it's,
it's makes it hard to find them.
And then it also makes it dangerous to
trail them,
you know,
if your blood trailing him or if you're,
even if you just surprise one,
um,
you know,
you,
you surprise an animal that close a wild
animal like that,
and who knows how they're gonna react.
Yeah.
That's a huge animal.
And,
and with that grass,
it just,
you know,
as you know,
Adam and I did a and the camera guys,
we did a podcast up there and we were
kind of talking about the challenges of
the hunt and uh,
that was a big part of it is um,
just not being able to see very much
country.
And so people never hunt buffalo this
time of year.
This is like,
people say,
why would you go,
you're not gonna,
you know,
nobody goes this time and we just want
to do,
they go,
they go later in the year,
you know,
when the,
when there's not so much foliage.
So they go like in their fall there.
Yeah.
It would be,
you know what,
last time I went is December,
which is just before the West season
starts.
This is the tail end of the wet season
right now.
So we were thinking about when we want
to take you up,
there would be around November,
October,
November.
Cause you don't want to get stuck in
with the wet season,
hit big rains.
But uh,
you,
you want it.
And,
and also it makes it easier to find the
animals because there's not water
everywhere right now.
There's water everywhere so they don't
have to be concentrated to get water.
But later in the year,
all those lot of the water sources have
dried up.
So if you've got a good water hole,
you know,
every,
every animal is coming there.
Well,
so these are for people who don't know.
Um,
this is an invasive species of water
buffalo and enormous Asian.
And what is it called?
It's just called Asian water buffalo.
Like what is the actual name of it?
Thank it.
Or yeah,
there might be an ah Ha,
I just call them Asian water buffaloes.
That seems like there's a c in there
somewhere.
Asiatic or something.
I Dunno.
Maybe Jamie can look at Jamie.
We'll look it up.
But uh,
it's uh,
such a wild,
cool looking animal.
Yeah.
They're big.
They're big in,
uh,
my bowl,
um,
it was a big old bowl on a,
uh,
we called him in using like a wounded
calf call.
Oh Wow.
Wow.
So this is,
this is what it looks like.
It's a female,
obviously stepped in Asian water buffalo
and yeah,
that's it.
That's what it looks like.
Yeah.
Um,
go to Cam's a instagram page and there's
a picture of the,
there's is there.
Yeah,
there it is.
Now that's Adams.
Oh,
that's how items,
yeah.
Then there's,
yours is in the upper right hand corner,
but you only see,
right?
Cisco the only see the skull.
Yeah.
And then that's a fucking head.
People don't want to see that.
What is he doing now,
folks?
That's how you make fine.
There's only one way.
There's another picture of it,
I think when it's coming in and when
he's coming in right there.
Right above that,
Jamie.
Right.
Uh,
right now
the one with the far left.
Yeah.
Right.
Right there.
That's a him at full draw or would the
that's looking through the riser of the
bow.
Yeah.
So that's that bowl coming in.
Aggressive.
He was,
you can see his eyes.
He was just pissed off and that's,
he was coming,
that's at under 20 yards and he's not
stopping.
And so I shot him there frontal through
the chest and uh,
had to,
is uh,
almost like self defense.
Wow.
So these are animals that if hunters
don't go up there and kill them,
they actually hire people to go up there
and killed him right there.
Yeah.
They,
I mean these things have,
has spread disease up there.
I mean they're,
uh,
a non native species and they,
any water source up there is ruined any
natural habitat has been ruined because
there's so many buffalo.
So they just want him killed basically.
They're like,
um,
it'd be like similar to coyotes here,
you know,
kind of 2000 pounds or yeah.
Yeah.
Predators either.
No,
there's nothing else to kill him.
And,
and maybe a CROC could kill a small one.
Right.
But,
uh,
they just need,
you know,
in Coyote's down here in North America,
don't ruin water sources and ruin
habitat like these things do these
things that are just wrecking machines
and there's,
there's hundreds of thousands of them up
there.
So they ruined Walsh water sources for
the native animals as well.
I call the free things.
Anything.
Yeah.
Cause they shit and Piss in the water.
Well it's an,
Australia is so strange and a as is New
Zealand in that all these people
imported animals,
they're in the 18 hundreds and a,
I guess even before was it,
when did they establish Australia and
New Zealand?
I'm not sure.
I forget when they these to see if you
could find out when they established,
we talked about this recently with Josh
Zaps,
didn't we?
But they um,
they brought in all these animals with
no game plan.
They just let them loose and then they
let the crowd,
Jesus.
So in New Zealand they have these
beautiful stags,
these incredible animals and at some
places they have to shoot them at of
helicopters just to control the
population,
which we're it for people in America,
it's like unheard of.
Like how could you do that?
Like that's that's,
that's like an elk,
like a majestic animal.
You're going to shoot him out of
helicopters to just leave them there to
die.
It's way different.
It's a,
you know,
up there,
there's just not enough hunters because
in all of Australia they say there's as
many people as there are in la,
the La area here in the whole country,
Saint New Zealand says it was a,
okay.
The first European explored a sight New
Zealand was able,
Jan's Zune,
what name Jan Zune Tasmin on the 13th of
December in 1642 but that's obviously
just a European people been there for a
long fucking time.
Oh yeah.
And Australia was 1788 and shortly
thereafter then they bringing in all
these
animals and the idea was that they were
going to make it like a European hunting
destination.
Right.
For,
for rich,
the rich,
uh,
w what Douche bags.
So they released all these animals but
with no predators.
Yeah.
And so people were going to come over
from Europe and they were going to go to
Australia and hot the rich people.
And so I think that,
and they told me that seems like it was
in 1985 they're going to wipe out all
the buffalo and they had some money
funded for it and they were going to try
to get rid of them and they got halfway
through and quit.
They killed like half of them.
Something like that.
Yeah.
Wow.
And then they quit.
And so now it was just as I was saying,
the whole country is about the size of
the United States.
You were telling me this,
but I did know that the whole country
has the same amount of people's live in
la here.
So there's just not that many hunters.
You know,
a small percentage of them are hunters.
So there's nobody to control all these
number of non native species.
And that's from a water buffalo to the
fallow deer that I was hunting to
stagger.
There's not as many stags is fallow
deer,
but um,
all these species just,
there's no measure for control really.
Yeah.
And they brought in a bunch of other non
native species to,
it's a,
it's an exercise in conservation gone
totally wrong because they brought in
Katz to take care of certain animals and
they brought in Fox and then the Fox and
the cats are out of control and they
kill all the ground nesting birds.
And now it's Kinda fucked up to us here
in America.
But people in Australia hunt cats,
they,
them the way in the hold 'em up.
Like,
look,
I got one and yeah,
it's a cat.
Yeah,
it's weird.
It's like,
that's fluffy with the fuck.
Yeah,
no,
I,
we saw a guy and uh,
he had a rifle and he's walking on the
road.
They're just to,
uh,
he lives there,
you know,
I mean,
that's,
his home has lived here his whole life,
I think.
And he was walking on the,
on the road.
I went down there,
I had my bowel and I,
you know,
I said,
hey,
what are you after?
And he's like,
aw,
man,
after,
uh,
a big black cat.
And I'm like,
uh,
like,
just a regular cat.
He's like,
yeah.
I said like,
just a feral,
you know,
wild cat.
He's like,
yeah,
it's a black one though.
He goes,
so there's a $10 bounty on it that the
property owners around their head,
if he'd make kill this black cat is 10
bucks,
but they don't think anything about it
because there's just wild cats
everywhere.
How weird is that?
Yeah.
It is bounty on a kitty cat.
Well,
people,
um,
that have researched it in America,
just in North America,
a cats kill somewhere in the
neighborhood of 3 billion birds a year.
Yeah.
Billion.
That when they found that out,
like apparently like scientists were
shocked.
The biologists were shocked is between
1.5 and three point something billion.
And that's not even counting like mice
and rabbits.
All the other shit.
They killed squirrels.
I'll never forget,
I had a cap.
They used to.
Um,
I used to live across street from this
park and uh,
I had this one male cat and he was just
a murderer.
And uh,
I'll never forget watching him walk
across this a park with a squirrel
between his legs.
So he was biting down the squirrels
neck,
the squirrels dead,
and the squirrel was his size
practically,
and it was in between his leg.
So He's straddling it and walking with
it,
dragging it along so you could show it
to me.
Oh,
he was super psyched.
That was awesome.
He was like,
Dude,
look what I got.
That's probably a large percentage of
his weight right there.
He was.
It was probably no bullshit.
At least three quarters the size of him.
Yes.
It wasn't a big cat and it was a fat
fucking squirrel.
Yeah.
That,
that probably would've been a nice
battle.
It's just weird.
The adverse squirrel cats are the
weirdest animals man,
because they're cool with us,
but they're straight killers.
I know.
But the only story I remember about a
cat,
I can't remember where I heard it or who
told me,
but that,
oh,
maybe it was one of my cop friends.
But anyway,
if,
uh,
like an old say it's an elderly person
that has a dog,
they die.
The dog is that people come and find the
body that,
and the dog's laying there with them.
You know,
just like a loyal whatever.
And uh,
if a cat,
if they have a cat and they die,
the cat eats our eyelids and,
and lips.
Yeah.
Right away.
If you stop feeding that cat,
the cat's like,
look,
I'm eating it looked like knits owner.
Yup.
Yeah,
yeah.
So that's really all you need to know
about a cat.
They eat each other too.
Um,
like crazy old people.
Uh,
there's this one lady who was a hoarder
and she had a bunch of dead cats.
She had so many cats in our house and
the cats had died and so she wasn't
feeding the cats.
The cats were eating the dead cat and
Whoa.
Yeah,
it's hard out there.
It's hard out there.
Cameron Hanes,
imagine be a cat living with a hoarder.
He liked his pitch.
Doesn't even let me go out,
let me out of it.
Kill some birds.
Oh yeah.
That animals just want to be out and
live this.
That's what we need to,
we need to be out in live.
I mean that,
that two and a half weeks I was in
Australia.
That was,
man,
I took two showers a whole time.
They'd be asleep bag and it must smell
good.
What a hey,
that's just how it goes.
That's what people are supposed to
smell.
I couldn't even tell.
We're just used to it.
Yeah.
So,
and I've just,
for the viewers,
I'm a clean pr.
I'd take a couple of hours a day.
But you know when you're hunting that's
just the way it goes.
But yeah,
we'll you wearing wool?
No I was no,
he's warm.
Oh right.
But like a thin layer merino actually
keeps it cool cause you sweating it and
he regularly teat really well,
yeah it was,
you know where we are hunting deer in
New South Wales,
which is outside of Sydney.
It was actually cold at night.
I mean you guys are walking on like
frozen glass.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There is covered with Frost.
But I mean it was night.
It was freezing,
you know,
I mean it was like 32
degrees.
So we were used to,
we thought we were going to be hunting
and 90 to a hundred degree weather.
So,
yeah,
I didn't,
you know,
when you're laying in a sleeping bag
that's only rated to 40 degrees in his
32 and sleeping on the ground,
it's rough.
It's rough.
As you're saying that those deer were
like super turned on to where like there
were tuned in,
like they were very skinny edge.
They've been hunted and uh,
you know,
they don't have lions like we have here,
which keeps the deer on edge,
you know,
cause we have lions are just killers,
but uh,
um,
they don't have a Predator like that,
but man,
it's an antelope specie and or it's a,
they can see so well and so fast
reacting.
It's just amazing.
What are they,
this is a fallow deer,
right?
Yeah.
And what do they relate it to?
Um,
for,
I just said it right there.
You said an antelope,
but I'm not sure if once I said it I'm
like,
are they so don't,
don't quote me on that.
We might have to look that one up too.
But all I know is the reason why I said
that is because they can see,
I mean antelope and a torres for having
amazing vision,
you know,
10 times what,
what humans have apparently.
And that's how these were,
I mean,
I don't know if the deer antelope or
whatever,
but they can see extremely well.
So they were seeing you from like a long
ways out.
Oh you couldn't,
I mean there was this one buck out of
stock and I had a cameraman with me and
that the key for stalking animals is
always staying in the shade.
If,
if you stay in the shade and you got
Cammo on,
especially if they're in the sun,
you know how it is looking,
looking into,
if you're in the sun,
he tried to look into a house you can't
see.
Right.
So it's the same thing with shadow.
So you always have mitch out of the,
well,
we were 330 yards away from this buck.
I was stocking,
he was feeding in this creek and we had
this small patch of sunlight to cross
330 yards away.
It's a long way away.
And I told the camera,
man,
I'm like,
we just got to get across here.
Just stay low and get,
you know,
hustle through there.
So we hunched over and got in seconds.
We were through there,
got to the shade,
looked over at the buck.
He standing there staring.
I'm like,
are you kidding me?
How He's already,
so we're in the shade.
So then for sure we weren't moving.
I'm like,
don't move.
And he's just staring,
staring,
staring and staring.
And I'm like,
don't move.
He's like,
I'm not,
I go,
don't move.
He's,
he's on.
He's just looking.
Anything is going to spook them.
He's like,
I'm not moving.
And he was crouched down on his knees.
And so finally the buck like took a few,
uh,
um,
bites or grass and I'm like,
okay,
he's feeding.
Next thing gone.
So all he did is took a couple bites of
grass for the road.
He's like,
no,
I already know about a year,
but I'm taking this with me.
And he was gone.
That was it.
Yeah,
they're smart.
That's long rifle range.
We had bows.
It's just a barely this.
So,
and we have to get close with a bow.
And so you can imagine it just if that,
that one example tells you what it was
like basically.
So we were talking about um,
different,
both setups,
like you had brought to both setups.
He brought one for deer and you bought
one for Buffalo.
So for people that don't understand,
there's two different ways that you were
going to approach this.
The buffalo is a giant heavy boned
animals.
He had a real heavy Arrow,
which is going to go slower and those
hours are just too slow for those deer.
And the deer would actually move out of
the way before the Arab.
Yeah.
Like Matrix,
it,
it Wa it was,
you know,
the,
the thing with penetration with an Arrow
is weight.
The way to the Arrow equates to more
penetration with heavy bone.
And you know that we talked about the
buffalo 1800 to 2000 pounds.
So you need something that hits hard.
Well,
when you have a heavier Arrow,
it's gonna fly slower.
So those were flying at 245 feet a
second out of my high poundage.
Bo and I thought,
well,
good enough.
I mean,
I didn't,
these will be all right.
And I was shooting it so well.
I'm so accurate,
you know,
practicing not to 90 yards all the time.
She didn't really well.
So I thought,
you know what?
I know it's supposed to be for Buffalo,
I'm just going to use it for deer.
So the first week there I tried it for
deer and it was just like these deer
were seemingly 10 yards away,
but having the Arrow got two minutes.
I'm not talking a long shots.
And I'm like,
okay,
maybe it was just a fluke,
just a flu.
They would see it,
hear it,
they would hear it and they would duck
out of the way or just be gone.
I mean,
just like be 10 yards away.
So they would move out of the way before
the area got to them.
Yeah.
And uh,
so the finally I thought,
well maybe it's just in a super calm.
They're so,
so quiet.
You know,
I don't know my bose or quiet a heavy
arrow.
It makes a bow even quieter,
you know,
it absorbs that sound.
And the energy.
So your limbs aren't just like that.
There is more of like an,
but it still makes an always on a super
calm windless day,
especially when it's cold,
you know?
I mean it's just that sound's going to
get across her.
So I thought,
well maybe it's just a fluke.
Maybe the deer were pick something up,
pickup some movement.
So they were just on me and is whatever.
And I'm not worried about it,
you know,
I'm not used to missing,
I'm used to be very disciplined on my
shots and taking high percentage shots
that relaxed animals.
If I do do my stock right,
my,
my goal is always to shoot an animal
that has no idea on there,
you know,
so it's relaxed.
And uh,
so that wasn't happening here and I
thought,
well maybe,
maybe it's just because they're high,
strong and,
and they were on me.
So what would the,
the,
the time where I decided,
okay,
these arrows aren't going to work,
was a wild boar.
Was out there,
big boar,
45 yards.
Okay,
this should be
slam dunk money.
And I co camera over my shoulder.
He had no idea.
We were there.
Drawback,
shoot.
And he had,
he was facing,
uh,
his head to the left and he was heading
back to the right probably a few feet
away by the time the Arrow got there.
Well,
I didn't even have to even,
I like shot and went,
Oh man,
are you kidding me?
Is that gone?
That fast spun and just gone.
And so then at that time I,
Mike,
okay,
these,
this is not going to work.
It's so crazy because although there's
no predators,
they're the hunters that are there are
out there all the time.
They don't have a season.
No,
there's no season sees.
Animals are just tuned in there hunting
every day.
Wow.
Yeah.
And so it mostly rifle.
So I mean,
they're used to,
if they see somebody that's like a
danger because they've been shot at
from,
you know,
hundreds of yards.
So it's just,
yeah,
it was,
it was challenging.
Um,
but,
so I,
I changed from those,
uh,
245 grain arrows and I thought,
well,
I need to shoot my,
uh,
or not 245,
245 feet per second.
That's 687 green arrow to a lighter
arrow.
And I thought,
well maybe this will do it.
And uh,
you know,
is it shooting 300 feet per second?
At that time did you change products?
Yup.
Did you go to the tow car?
No.
You step with the solids?
No,
I shot a with above flow.
And actually,
you know,
it's funny actually what I ended up
killing the deer with two was uh,
um,
what were the magnus stingers and I also
the,
but they expand.
I had that expandable head.
Do you remember that one that I used on
the bear?
It was a grave digger grave digger.
Yeah.
That'll ruthless name that head and
that,
that had flies so good.
Oh,
is money.
So use that as well.
Yep.
So when you're out there man,
like,
so you're around Sydney,
which is where people are.
There's,
there's those animals are hunted pretty,
pretty regularly,
but then you're taking that flight for
four and a half hours and then a
helicopter.
And when you're in the area where the
buffalo are,
there's nobody out there.
No,
it's remote.
That is a wild,
wild place.
When you think about the,
the size of Australia,
the size of North America with the same
amount of people as Los Angeles,
but the area where you're at,
it's like that is as wild as it gets.
Yeah.
I mean w w you fly those four and a half
hour from Sydney to Darwin and most of
that there you're looking down at
country with nothing.
Nothing,
no roads,
no nothing.
And,
and that's,
that's a large majority of Australia is
like that and it's just overrun with
Buffalo.
Yeah.
A lot of it is.
Yep.
And uh,
what's crazy punch.
Yeah.
And that we did find some,
uh,
you know,
some drawings up there too.
Um,
from the,
from,
yeah.
I mean
all the natives.
Yeah.
For the aborigines.
And did you,
did you know that those were there
before you went there to doubt them?
Know that there were the pilot,
the pilot?
No.
Yeah.
So we wanted to go see him.
Oh Wow.
So are they in a cave like where they're
on?
Um,
the,
for the,
whether or not to get to them,
it has to be on like the underside of a
rock where we went and we filmed under
there.
It was like,
you could imagine people getting out of
the rain there and they're huge boulders
and they're getting,
and it was just a perfect spot to stay
dry.
And so that's,
if the rain was,
if they drew on a part of the rock where
the rain was hitting,
obviously it was gone.
But in these,
these areas,
they were protected.
So drawings were still there.
Last Time Adam was here,
he talked about,
um,
some of the aborigines there and explain
some stuff.
But when we went back to my house,
we,
uh,
we had dinner and we sat around talking
and he told me some crazy stories about
the horrors if those people face and how
they had been wiped out.
Like they had been poisoned.
Like he went to this one cave and he
found bones all through this cave.
He's like,
this is crazy.
There's like human bones and he's like
children's bones.
You'd find children's bones.
And then he had heard this story from
one of the other aborigines that live
there,
that someone had brought food to all
these people,
all the aborigines there and just
poisoned the food and just killed them
all off.
Yeah.
It's,
it's fucking dark.
Yeah.
It's dark.
No,
I dunno.
So they don't know.
They don't know who made those
hieroglyphs are there or the cave
drawings or whatever.
They weren't.
Or when they did it either.
Now,
now they say,
uh,
I put it up on my instagram page and I
saw some comments there.
And they're saying that the more
brightly colored,
the older they are.
Huh.
But I don't know.
I think,
I think the pilot mentioned 10,000 years
old.
Maybe.
I was just guessing the Flexi.
No,
I have no idea.
I think you just threw that out there.
How would you know?
I mean it's just something,
I'm sure somebody knows.
I mean,
right.
That studies that,
I'm sure this is probably a few people.
It seems like when you think about the
actual numbers of how much land you're
talking about,
how few people live out there and how
many of those things are probably there.
And also one of the things that Adam was
telling me that's crazy as you could
have,
the way,
um,
they refer to themselves,
uh,
like a aborigines.
They call themselves a mob like,
and no,
instead of a tribe,
it's a mob and they're like,
there could be one mob.
And he said there could be a mob.
He goes full kilometers away and they
speak a totally different language.
Oh,
right.
Yeah.
Like what I go,
how many languages are there?
He goes,
oh,
hundreds what?
Yeah,
hundreds.
I go,
so they can't talk to each other.
He goes,
nope.
Yeah,
no written language.
Yeah.
They,
they have different expressions for
things.
Yeah.
I heard that too.
That's crazy.
I know what I mean.
It's really,
it's like a tribal society,
right?
I mean,
that's just the way it goes.
Well,
it's,
it is like a tribal society,
but it's also like you're,
you're,
I mean,
right now there's culture and there's a
civilization that is linked to who knows
how many hundreds,
if not thousands of years ago,
and it will go away because there won't
be people that understand it.
There's not,
no,
not someone who is studying it.
Yeah.
And there's so many different versions
of the way they communicate that it's
just like you're,
you're literally watching history
dissolve,
right?
Yeah.
In front of you.
I know.
It's a,
it's a Ma,
it was amazing to be in that country
walking in hunting in the same that,
that they have for,
you know,
however many years.
And what did they hunt back then?
Because this is obviously before the
buffalo came in,
before they brought the fallow deer,
I dunno.
Just whatever wallabies or while he's a
native thing.
Kangaroos and she,
yeah,
yeah.
Wow.
Yeah.
But it was,
it was cool
being under that rock and,
and envisioning them being there too.
Yeah.
You know,
that long ago doing the same thing we
were doing.
That's,
that's a,
that's a real mind blower man.
It's just so fascinating thinking about
that.
That particular continent of Australia
that no,
Europe used it as a prison colony in
England.
Brought a bunch of people over there and
go,
look,
you people are assholes.
Stay here.
Dell is on,
there's an island off of Australia,
right.
That they used for that.
Well they used Australia for that.
I thought,
Oh God,
what was that island?
I know we were doing an island as well
that they still do.
I think that's what they tell
immigrants.
Right?
Yeah.
And they have to live there for a
certain amount of time before they can
come over.
Yeah.
They have some weird immigration laws in
Australia,
Australia.
Like if people that are complaining
about trump wanting to build a wall,
listen clearly island way worse and it's
like a prison.
Yeah.
If,
if I understand it right,
it's like a prison,
then they have to stay there for,
you know,
like I said,
a certain amount of time before they're
a citizen.
Yeah.
See if you could find that Jimmy,
Josh zips actually brought it up to us
and he was explaining how brutal the
immigration laws are over there.
They don't want to anybody moving to
Australia,
they understand.
They have a good thing going on.
Yeah.
I mean if you haven't been to Australia,
it is lovely.
People there are fantastic.
They're super friendly.
They're really nice.
And again,
there's not that many of them.
It's expensive though.
Yeah.
Very.
You know,
I mean there was a,
um,
amen.
He,
I think his house was like a two bedroom
house,
four or $500,000.
Wow.
Yeah.
It makes sense though.
You got to bring shit over there,
right?
Yeah.
They were saying the guy,
uh,
when I was in Sydney,
um,
the guy who driving us,
I was telling us how much cars costs
over there.
They cost so much more money,
especially like people,
like a classic American muscle cars.
And the guy was talking about how much
like a 1968 mustang was worth.
And he's like,
it's probably worth twice what it's
worth in a merrily.
Yeah,
because they have to ship them over
there.
What they have over there,
which is sweet,
was a Toyota high lux diesel trucks.
Those are pretty sweet.
What is it?
It's just a Toyota Tundra as it like a
ton.
Like a,
it's like a,
they call it a ute.
That's a pickup.
Oh,
okay.
Utility vehicle.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I dunno.
I'm just trying to use it.
Learn the lingo.
But a ute is a pickup and it was a
Toyota high lux diesel.
And is this what Adam was driving around
in?
No,
I can't remember what his is.
I heard is right there,
Huh?
Yeah,
that's a,
okay,
so it's like a flat bed.
Yeah.
Hmm.
I'm not sure what happened.
Maybe Adam has that.
I can't remember now.
One of the things that I thought was
weird when I was there,
it was how many people have snorkels on
their trucks?
Yeah.
That one right there that's driving
through water.
Well,
it's not just water,
it's also dust.
Elderly chokes up your air filters.
So I have those things way up high so
that it a,
when the engine's getting the air,
like apparently it mitigates a lot of
the dust cause a lot of the dust is like
a headlight.
Hi.
Yeah.
When you're driving and that gets you a
little bit more clear air there.
Well that's out of my wheelhouse.
I know bow hunt down and running.
Well you knew the name of it.
No,
I just noticed because they're cool.
Well whenever you go to like Africa,
yeah.
Whenever we go someplace that's fucking
brutal.
You see a lot of toyotas.
Yeah.
Toyota's know how to,
they know how to make a car that lasts.
Do they do that?
They're not.
I mean here it's just like,
you know Ford,
Chevy,
you know.
I Dunno cause we were like American
stuff.
I guess so,
yeah.
But still you still see a lot of like
old land cruisers?
Yeah.
I mean how many Fj cruiser there where
we were on in the outback driving
around.
Everybody has those.
Yeah.
Every person has a truck set up like
that?
Well I guess you have to.
Yeah.
If you realize after time,
like this is the only thing that makes
it,
yeah,
cause Adam was saying when he drives
from Sydney to Darwin,
he know we took a four and a half hour
plane flight,
but it's three days.
So he have to have,
your rig has to be bulletproof
basically.
Yeah.
They have an expression.
You could take a range rover into the
bush,
but you need a land rover to get out of
the bush.
Is that right?
Okay.
Yeah.
They just,
those toyotas.
It's just,
it's kinda crazy how well they last and
when you really think about like for the
longest time America did a real shit job
of making cars that last,
there's was a period in American cars
from like the 1970s till I think till
probably like the late nineties a 2000
they finally got it right.
And now we make very dependable cars as
well.
But for the longest time we were making
dog shit.
Well,
I don't know about all that,
but I do know we're going to go up and
do that.
Hunter,
me,
you and Adam and we're going to do a
netflix special.
They don't,
Netflix has a plan.
Netflix doesn't know this yet.
Why?
Why,
why Netflix?
What?
What makes you a little,
well,
it's good move.
It's a good move.
I want to do something
on the Internet.
Yeah.
I want her to be like an hour long
documentary style fam hunting film,
giving back,
you know,
killing Buffalo,
taking the meat back to the community.
Does the natives.
Yeah.
To aborigines.
That's what I envision.
That sounds like a great idea.
It could be,
certainly it could be done on Netflix or
it could be done and you can just put it
online.
Yeah,
that,
that could be just as,
I mean Netflix is awesome for sure,
but there's some people that don't have
netflix.
Everybody has an online connection.
Yeah.
My,
my,
my goal is to sort of use you cause
people,
because I wanna I wanna I want hunting
to be shown and the light that I know it
to be,
which is hard work,
respect for the country and the animals
and giving back.
So with you involved more people care
about it.
Right.
And we want to have you involved because
we like hanging out with you and like,
well I was explaining this to Adam to
um,
when we did my podcast up there in the
bush is like,
ever since I,
I've hunted way back when Roy moved to
Alaska and I was left hunting a
wilderness on my own.
I loved it so much.
I kept wanting to find somebody who
would love it as much as I,
so I could say,
look how awesome this is.
Isn't this awesome?
And I kept taking people there and try
to convince them how awesome it was.
It wasn't awesome for them.
So it was like,
but you want to share something that
impacts you so much with other people
who appreciate it.
So that's why that's,
that's what I was saying when Adam I
were talking is that,
you know,
you love bow hunting and so that's when,
when you are so interested in invested
in something and have such a passion for
something,
there's nothing better when somebody's
then when somebody else shares that
passion.
Right.
Yeah.
So that,
that was,
that was why there's a few different
reasons why you were going to be
involved.
Thank you.
I'm excited about that.
I also think the difficulty factor is
what turns people off.
I don't think they expect it to be so
difficult.
No,
no,
no.
If you try to introduce bow hunting to
people,
first of all,
just shooting a bow,
people think,
oh well we'll see you pull the string
back.
You pointed the spot,
you'll let it go.
Good luck with all that.
It takes some fucking years.
It takes years to get competent with a
ball.
And,
uh,
I remember when you first started
showing me how to shoot when we first
shot in my backyard.
And I immediately recognized,
I think like after,
first of all you've got a 90 pound bow,
which I definitely shouldn't have been
pulling back.
My shoulder was fucking killing me after
the first hour.
Like this takes,
you got to build up to this God damn
thing.
But then I remember thinking like to be
accurate with this,
like I just went down a rabbit hole.
I'm like,
I just took my first step down a crazy
rabbit hole and who knows where it leads
because this is not easy and I'm a,
I have a very addictive yeah.
And I need to figure out ways to channel
that addiction in positive ways cause I
can get lost doing things that are not
good.
So bow hunting and archery itself.
To me it seemed like,
okay,
this is a discipline.
It's a worthy pursuit.
It's fascinating and I'm very,
very interested in it.
But for a lot of people I think it's
very daunting.
Like,
oh,
I don't think they realize it.
People think of hunting is like elmer
fudd.
Like you know,
you'd go out there or they see some
hunting scene in a movie where there's a
bunch of rednecks and they're fat and
they're was sitting in a tree stand or
something like that.
And they think it's easy and they think
it's a bunch of people that are just
killing animals and they don't care.
And then when you actually go out and do
it,
especially if you go do it with a person
like you,
you understand what this thing really
is.
And what it really is,
is this incredibly difficult pursuit
that takes immense amounts of hard work
and dedication and you gotta be in
fucking shape for it.
And this is something that people are
starting to realize now,
and I think you're a big part of this,
and over the last few years and all the
platforms that you've gone on to tell
your story is that people understand
that big game hunting in the West and
the western style hunting elk and mule
deer,
the type of stuff that you love to do is
very,
very difficult.
It is a combination of athletics,
of extreme endurance,
of hiking,
outdoorsmen ship survival skills,
and then the knowledge of hunting.
And then you have to be a good shot on
top of all that.
You have to know archery.
Yeah.
Then you have to be able to keep,
you know,
with that adrenaline hits all of a
sudden.
And that's what's hard is people have
invested so much into it and they've
been thinking about the,
the Mo,
the crunch time for so long that when it
happens it's too much.
Yeah.
So it's really hard when you've been
thinking about something for years
potentially,
or at least all year,
you know that,
oh,
here's my chance,
here's my chance.
And then you get it and you're not ready
yet because it's just too much to,
it's so hard to stay calm.
Well,
it's also something that you need to do
a bunch of times until you understand
it.
It's like,
I try to explain it to people about,
we were talking about fighting earlier.
We were talking about,
um,
when Pete,
if someone has never fought before and
never competed before,
the,
the scary thing is not really the,
what's nerve racking is not the actual
fighting itself.
Once the fighting starts,
you're actually kind of like just in the
zone and you're just doing it.
I mean,
you might be intimidated,
especially if you're fighting a guy like
Mike Tyson or Anderson Silva or
something like that.
You're going to be shitting your pants.
But the real terrifying stuff is the
buildup,
the lead up.
And that's kind of the same thing with
hunting.
It's the moment before the shot.
It's your adrenaline is pumping.
It's like if you had a shoot an eight
ball across the table,
long shot and your life was on the line,
it's almost like that.
And you don't get any warm up shots.
There's no warmup shots.
Just all of a sudden,
here's this one shot for all the marbles
and you've got to stay calm.
Okay.
Oh,
and the animals might be moving.
Yeah.
Like,
Oh fuck no.
I was saying that on this last hunt.
It was,
you know,
we had me,
Adam and remy warrant and supposedly
we're supposed to be pretty good hunter,
the best of the best and we were
struggling to get something killed.
And I was just like imagine how
frustrating this would be for somebody,
a new hunter.
I mean it's no wonder people try to bow
hunt and then just be like,
are you kidding me?
This is impossible.
And it's,
but it's,
it's that challenge.
Anyway,
it's that whole journey,
which is why I want to do that special
and I want,
I want to share all of us positive about
hunting it to as many people as you
know.
And we are reaching new people these
days.
You know what I mean?
Hunting,
it's,
it's in the cross hairs in some aspects
I guess.
But we're also other people are getting,
cause I get,
I mean I went to an archery shop up
there,
Benson's archery in Sydney and we just
had a few hours notice saying,
Hey Adam,
Adam and I are going to stop by swing
by,
and quite a few people came.
I mean,
it was,
it was surprising how many people showed
up,
but a lot of them were vegetarians,
you know,
six months ago,
listen to your show.
A lot of people told me,
Oh,
I found out about you from Joe Rogan or
I didn't hunt.
All right,
I didn't even eat meat.
And all these different stories,
all these different from all these
different areas.
So we are reaching new people and I want
to make sure our message,
the one of,
of,
of respect and reverence and awe and
appreciation for everything out there
and for survival and for just,
you know,
outside of the life outside of the city,
I want that shown in a way that I know
we would.
So that's why I'm selfishly want this to
be a big thing,
just because I'm sick of hunting,
you know,
the elmer fudd thing or um,
I see.
I was watching a movie the other day and
they showed a hunter and it was like the
girl was on there and she was,
oh,
what was that?
There's three girls that were kidnapped
and one of them had hunted as a,
as a younger girl.
And so she was like,
do you know what movie that is?
Anyway,
so she was had the upper hand,
she was tougher and she was more
prepared because she had been a hunter.
And I'm like,
oh,
that's cool.
But then they show her as a little girl
hunting and her perverted uncle had
molested her hunting,
drinking beer.
Oh God.
That movie split Split.
That's what it was.
So the hunter in there with some child
molester,
I'm like,
why is the most misunderstood and
misrepresented discipline?
I think,
uh,
that we have here in,
and it's,
it's so confusing to people because when
we think of a food,
we think of restaurants and we think a
supermarket.
Yeah.
We don't think of wild animals and the
connection that people feel like they
don't have what their food is.
One thing that comes up all the time
lately,
so people are constantly looking for
these farm to table places.
I visit a farm to table place out here,
um,
called a peddler's fork.
It's a really good place.
They have great eggs,
like you get the eggs,
they were like real dark yoke and the
food is all grass fed beef or from a
farm if they have a connection to and
they buy the meat from the farm.
And there's a lot of that,
these farm to table places where they,
these restaurants have a great
relationship with the people that
actually grow the food.
So everything's organic.
They know where it comes from and people
are super connected to that.
They love the idea that because factory
farming is kind of freaking people out.
And for the longest time it was
happening without us knowing.
You know,
I think during the eighties and the
nineties it was all going on and no one,
no one understood.
Yup.
So now people are becoming more aware
because of the Internet,
because of information and they're
becoming more aware of where their food
comes from.
And you're also seeing a higher number
of people that their response to this
factory farming thing is,
well,
hey,
I'll go vegetarian all,
I'll go vegan.
And Yeah,
before I hunted with Rinella,
that was my thought.
I was like,
I don't want to participate in factory
farming.
Yeah.
So what am I going to do?
I'm going to do one of two things.
I can either go hunting,
I'm going to hunt for my own food
because I knew there's something wrong.
I'm like,
it's too easy to just get a steak.
I would always like pick up a steak and
I go,
this isn't me an animal like a,
here I am at the supermarket now it's a
styrofoam container wrapped in Saran
wrap.
Like this is fucking weird.
It's weird that you could just do this.
So my thought was if I shoot an animal
and I hate it,
like I didn't know how it was going to
feel.
I never shy.
I've fished all my life.
I never,
but when I shot that deer and I was
like,
oh,
I can,
I get it.
Yeah.
I mean it was an extreme amount of
respect.
It's on video.
I mean,
you can see it on media or anybody who
wants to watch it.
You could watch it online.
The first time I ever shot a deer,
it was intense.
Yeah.
You know,
and,
and then cutting it up and eating it
that night.
I was like,
this makes sense.
This is a,
and then when you actually find out
that,
you know that these animals,
the money that co gum from hunting tags
and even from buying hunting gear,
there's a percentage of money that goes
towards conservation.
And this is all very carefully thought
out by people like you and by these
people that really respect and care for
these animals.
And you get deeper and deeper into this
and you understand what it really is.
And then you see this whole community of
these people like yourself and Remy
Warren and these hardcore hunters that
are also like deeply connected to the
land and conservation and deeply
appreciate these animals.
And this is how they get all their meat.
This is how they live.
And like that was extremely appealing to
me.
Yeah,
it's uh,
I think Steve or has done a great job
make getting that message out in a,
in a,
in a perfect way really.
I mean,
he's a great spokesman and,
and his show,
I used to watch his show before meteor.
Now,
I can't remember what it was called
within.
Is that what it was?
Yeah.
Okay.
And,
and I remember he had just something
about him that I'm like,
okay,
this is different.
I liked I was a hunter.
I,
you know,
I've been a hunter myself my whole life,
but his,
his portrayal was different than what
we'd seen before.
And so,
you know,
maybe the me and some of the other
people you've mentioned and,
and Adam have just carried that on and
tried to do a good job of educating
people who don't know any better.
And I just,
you know,
it's like,
I wish everybody could be out there.
I mean,
that last day we were up in the
mountains there,
um,
after I had killed my deer and we had a
back strap,
so we're picking up camp,
getting everything away.
But I had,
I had,
uh,
awesome fallow deer backstrap,
which is like the prime for people that
don't know as a prime cut.
And I cut it all up.
I cleaned it all off every piece of
anything that was on at hair.
If there's any tree bark,
anything that was on there was just a
perfect clean piece of meat.
I sliced it all up.
We got a green stick to put it on.
Um,
skewered it on,
on green,
um,
wood.
So if it's,
if it's dry wood that we'll just going
to burn.
And so,
you know,
you can't cook on that.
So it's gotta be green and we put it
over the fire there and it was,
we seasoned it,
it was so good.
It was probably some of the best meat
I've ever eaten.
And standing around the campfire,
just pulling that off,
that,
that stick that we had cooked it over
the open flame was,
I wish everybody could know what that
was like to know that that deer just
previous to that was alive in the woods.
We harvested them,
which is Aka killed him.
And then Adam and that's that circle of
life or whatever you want to call it or
just that moment that's,
I wish everybody could experience it
because I just think they'd have a
different take on,
on hunter hunting and hunters and uh,
being self sustaining.
It's very different.
Meat is very different when you've
tilled it yourself.
It's impossible to describe without
experiencing it.
I mean,
I could try,
I could give it my best shot,
but I'll,
I'll fall short.
But I remember eating that meat that we
ate,
uh,
when I was in Montana with Rinella,
the first hunt and uh,
it was so delicious and we're cooking
and over at Campfire and Steven brought
this little grill,
not,
not a grill,
like a great,
you know,
that we'd sat down over the fire and
[inaudible] and it's like,
like if you buy a steak and you cook it,
it's great.
Tastes good.
Or call this a good steak.
This is nice.
But there's no connection
there.
No,
none.
When you are eating an animal that you
killed yourself and it's difficult to do
when you,
you were hard hunting for many,
many days for you got that deer.
Yeah.
So there's this intense respect and
connection that I think we all,
I mean,
we,
we harp on about it so many times that
people listen to these podcasts,
that Jesus Christ,
you go stop talking about how awesome
hunting is,
is it's because it's impacted both of us
in a very,
very positive way.
In a very,
uh,
there's a primal genetic sort of a
ancestral thing that's happening when
you hunt.
Yeah.
There's,
there's a,
there's some lights that go off the,
you didn't even know where they're like,
oh,
I didn't even know there was a switch
over there and like,
oh,
this is a part of my brain that's lit up
that it was never lit up before.
And it's not,
it's not what everybody thinks that the
negative aspects,
it's not a barbaric thing.
It's not a cruelty thing.
It's a very respectful thing.
Yeah.
And I understand the people that have
bad feelings about it.
I understand the people that look at it
like animal cruelty.
Like you don't have to do that.
You can get food other ways.
You can eat beans and you don't need to
do this.
I understand how they're thinking,
but my thought process is very
different.
My thought process is what you're doing,
what I'm doing,
what all these people that do that hunt
is your entering into the wild and you
are for a small window a week or
whatever it is.
You're becoming a part of this crazy
cycle of nature.
You're taking something out of that and
leaving something as well.
You're spending a ton of money.
That money,
whether it's a the money for the
outfitters,
the money for the tags and money for the
gear,
all that stuff.
Percentage of that goes to make sure
that the habitat is maintained.
Make sure that the animal populations
maintained,
make sure that department of fishing
game is well staffed with biologists,
with people that are monitoring these
animals because guess what?
If that doesn't get done,
it's,
it's these animals are not going to be
there anymore,
right?
They're not going to be taken care of.
And North America has the best wildlife
management program or,
or management system of anywhere.
And that's why almost all the species
that we have here,
there's more now than there almost ever
has been.
And even with shrinking habitat,
because we're encroaching on,
on where they live,
but we're still the number still
flourish because we're not,
hunters aren't just,
Oh,
let's go kill life.
I'm all out.
I mean,
we're,
it's managed.
It's fishing game as managers are funded
by hunters.
And what we pay that with,
uh,
with the tags and license.
And so it's,
there's a system to it,
but at the end of the day,
like they're in Australia,
we were getting up in the morning out of
the sleeping bag,
grabbing her bow and taken off.
We're hunters as it and that,
that feels,
man,
it,
it feels,
like I said,
I wish people could know what it feels
like because I see people comment on my
social media and they saved the susans
of the 19th century anymore.
You don't have to be a neanderthal or
whatever,
but
it's just,
we,
we are hunters.
Yeah,
well most of those people of
cheeseburgers and their instagram pages,
which is fucking hilarious.
There's so much of that.
This one chick,
she posted something mean when I posted
a picture of some elk that I was cooking
and I said,
hey honey,
I go,
you got like call girls honey,
because it makes them feel like I'm a
sexist.
You got a,
you got to fucking blt on your page
sweetie.
And uh,
she's like,
well,
that was just from four months ago
before I was enlightened.
I like,
Oh,
you became enlightened.
It's always the most adamant vegans like
just became one of the most
proselytizing,
ruthlessly aggressive once I understand
where they're coming from.
And I think that's very important for,
to get our message across is that like
it went on animal haters.
This is not this.
And it's,
it's hard for people to understand that
someone could love animals and love the
idea of animals and love wildlife,
but still eat them.
Yeah.
You know,
I,
I always,
I climbed up in this tree there,
I found this place where the deer were
coming into this field.
And,
uh,
like I said,
this area had been hunted,
but I,
I,
I had figured nobody had ever a hundred
out of a tree there,
you know,
um,
not like a white tail back here,
you know,
in the,
in the east or in the south,
that Theresa 100 all the time.
So I'm like,
well,
I think I can get up in this tree,
these deer coming out in this area.
I probably have a pretty good chance.
So I was up there in the tree and,
uh,
these doughs and Fonz or out in the
field and they were running around
chasing each other plain.
I mean,
it was just like speeding all around in
circles and bumping into each other.
And,
uh,
it was cool to see.
And then this,
uh,
a doe and a spike,
a young buck came out right under my
tree.
This spike was 24,
25 yards away,
basically a chip shot with a bow,
especially had no idea.
I was there and I,
there was a thought that we were getting
low on meeting camp and,
uh,
I hadn't killed a deer.
So,
you know,
I had said before,
I'm like,
I'm killing any buck that comes out.
Um,
I'm,
I'm taking him.
And then I was watching him up there and
I'm just like,
I just,
you know,
for me,
uh,
it's gotta be the right animals,
not just like,
I'm not some blood thirsty,
you know,
I still watch the deer.
I still appreciate their beauty and
that,
you know,
they're frolicking about or whatever you
want to call it.
And it's still enjoyed that this,
this young buck was down and I had said
I was,
we're going to get meat for camp,
but I'm not some bloodthirsty guy.
So I just said,
well,
no,
I'm just going to watch him and you
know,
enjoy it.
And he was there.
And then the buck,
I ended up killing,
stepped out.
And uh,
you know,
an old Bach,
he was,
you could see his hip bones because he
was so run down from the ride and he was
getting older.
I could tell he was an older,
mature deer.
And that's,
that's what I want to take.
I want to take an animal past its prime
that has done his job for spreaders
genes for the health of the herd and
was,
that's the animals we want to take out.
And so he,
he was just a rundown
old Bach.
That's why I took,
yeah,
people don't they,
that's the problem is that people
associate someone who wants to take an
older big mature animal with trophy
hunting.
Like,
Oh,
you just want the antler.
So you just want a big,
but they don't understand that that is
actually the animal that you should
take.
Yeah.
And he's still a,
he's still great me.
Yeah,
sure.
Yeah.
But I mean that,
that's just,
you know,
for the health of the herd,
that's the one you want,
you know,
if you're doing it right,
right.
You know,
young ones,
then we'll get a chance to fill his
spot.
Right.
And that would be the natural position
if there was an,
this is the natural position.
If there's predators,
the natural position is the really young
ones,
like the Fonz get taken out and then the
really old ones start getting worn down.
They get taken out.
And then everything in the middle gets
to breed.
And then this guy who was eight years
old or whatever he is,
he's had plenty of opportunity to shed
spread his genetics.
And so his,
his offspring will be everywhere and
then they'll get a chance now.
And the thing is nobody makes it out.
Nobody makes the whole live there
either.
All by everybody.
We're all dying.
So I mean,
just so if I wouldn't have killed that
bucket,
it doesn't mean he's going to live
forever.
I mean,
he's going to die one way or another.
It's not going to become a ferry.
The fact that he died,
I shot him and he was dead within
seconds is guaranteed and people are
always talk shit about this is the very
best way he could go.
Yeah.
You don't want them starving to death or
you know,
dying because his teeth don't work
anymore and literally can't eat food.
You know this,
I've seen animals where you,
um,
you look at their teeth and they're
almost none left.
Yeah.
You get a,
like a really old buck.
This is buck teeth were flat in the
back.
So it was just when you can't eat,
they got to gum,
they can't gum enough.
Yeah.
They can't talk a doubt.
So it's uh,
you know,
and,
and Adam also found two bucks that had
fought and got stuck.
They were fighting,
an offense was in between them,
just a cattle fence.
They got stuck in the fence.
Died.
Yeah.
So it's just their life is,
I mean,
how many guys out here in the street,
you know,
fight and kill each other and gets stuck
together?
It doesn't happen.
It's life in the wild is,
I mean,
unless you're out there and you witness
things like that,
you just live in,
it's a,
it's not real.
I think the real problem is perspective,
you know,
I mean,
I think unless you're there,
unless you are experiencing the
wilderness itself,
like a,
I've talked about my experience on
Prince of Wales island that um,
you know,
Brian Cowen and Rinella and I,
uh,
we were up there for sec,
I guess.
I think we camped there for six days.
And you,
your,
your idea of what like life is,
is the only based on what your
perception is,
like what you're seeing on a daily
basis.
Well,
he,
you're seeing Ventura Boulevard and
you're seeing billboards and all new
movies coming out and keeping up with
the Kardashians.
Here's a new season.
And look at that new Audi.
Wow.
That's a sweet looking car.
Hey,
I got the new iphone.
All right,
and this is life.
And then you're out there and you go,
oh well this is life to total quiet like
this.
No.
Cell phone service.
Rain animals.
Yeah.
And then if you die,
no one's going to,
no,
no.
If you fall and break your neck and die
right there,
something will eat you.
No one will find you.
You're nuts.
That's normal.
You're trying to stay warm,
you're trying to get food.
And there's more spots that on this
planet,
more spots like that on this planet.
Then spots like Los Angeles.
Yeah.
It's uh,
it's weird.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's just,
it's,
but that connection,
I don't know,
I guess there's no,
there's no way to see it in,
in front of your computer.
No.
But I want if we can film it right and
share a right,
I think people will get it.
Getting it a little now get it more than
what
right now.
So,
I mean,
that's my goal with,
you know,
what we've been talking about and I
mean,
we talked about the difficulty.
I did remember,
I wanted to mention this.
Um,
that ha the hell was,
I mean I've been on a lot of haunts and
a lot of places over the years and uh,
I hadn't struggled like ahead on this
[inaudible] it was so difficult.
I was telling the guys back there,
I said,
I'm,
I'm questioning my life right now.
What,
what am I doing with my life?
And it was just because I'm like,
it's not going to happen.
I'm not going to get it done.
And the animals don't care about my
goals that they don't care about that.
Oh,
we're supposed to be making this great
film and portray hunting.
They're like,
now we're not,
has nothing to do.
They're just staying alive.
That was it.
So it was just like everything that
I've,
I felt like I want her to do or achieve
or my,
it was just like,
it's not going to happen.
And it felt like,
God,
have I lost it?
You know?
I mean,
I was,
it was just like,
this is hard,
but when it works and you do it right in
that shot happens,
then it's just like,
okay.
And I don't know,
it's just that doing something so
difficult,
um,
and being successful,
and I've said this before,
has made me who I am,
you know?
I mean,
without,
without a challenge like that,
I dunno.
I Dunno where I'd be right now.
So it's,
uh,
I dunno.
Sometimes you cuss it and then,
man,
you were just so appreciative of the
journey.
Yeah.
Well those difficult moments,
the only thing that makes success
worthwhile if success was easy,
if you woke up in the morning,
first day yawn,
have a cup of coffee,
step five steps,
there's the biggest deer that's ever
lived,
shoot one right through his heart.
You wouldn't even feel it.
It wouldn't,
it wouldn't be like,
oh no.
And I don't think people understand how
difficult it is to,
because they watch these TV shows.
Have you ever watched a hunting show?
There were half an hour long.
So you're watching 22 minutes without
commercials,
right?
Yeah,
and 22 minutes,
you know,
they usually build up for the first,
15 minutes when you know,
we came close to them but we
could not get a shot and then finally
they get a shot,
which you don't see is that these,
it takes days and days and days of 10 12
hours hike up and down mountains up and
down and up and down.
And when I met you,
the reason why I got in contact with you
and the reason why I met you was because
I was so confused as to why someone
would need to run ultra marathons or to
get ready for hunting.
I was like,
what the fuck is this guy doing?
Like why is he lifting weights and doing
all this shit for it?
I didn't get it.
I was like this.
I was just getting into it and I was
trying to figure out like I was,
I would start to watch things on
television though,
starting to read certain articles and
read certain books.
And I was like,
well,
what is this whole fitness connection to
hunting?
Like why do they need to be in shape?
I'm like,
I'm in pretty good shape.
Like what's the big deal?
Well,
I went with Rinella and when I went with
Grinnell,
one of the things I realized is like,
boy,
I got pretty winded going up these
fucking hills,
like hiking,
hiking,
tires,
you out,
especially high altitude.
And then I see your,
your videos online.
And I was like,
what the fuck is this guy into?
And then,
um,
as I go deeper and deeper into it,
I realized like,
oh,
this is like an extreme pursuit.
This is not just like something,
you just go out and do this.
It's something that's really hard to do.
And a lot of people there,
I've,
I've read this one article,
but there's one guy who was unsuccessful
12 years in a row,
elk hunting before he finally,
I shot an elk like 12 years.
Like how many times did this guy go out?
How many days did he camp and the
forest,
how many days did he try to stock and
get winded or snap on a twig at the last
minute or,
you know,
the,
the elk sees him and bolt it.
Most people are unsuccessful.
Yeah.
I mean,
nine out of 10 every year on successful.
I think it's more than that.
Hunting with archery,
it,
it's about,
it's about 10% is it 10% yeah.
So nine out of 10 are unsuccessful.
So people who don't hunt,
who see,
you know,
dead stuff all the time,
they think,
oh,
you just go out and kill an animal.
Right?
No.
Right.
Most 90% don't.
It is really hard.
And it's just like until you're out
there,
you got the bow in your hand and you're
trying to close in on that animal and
you're trying to do everything right
from a to z with.
And there's so many variables during
that whole path as like it,
it seems a possible sometimes,
you know,
even even for me after 30 years,
and this is a very strange connection
that you get with nature and forget
about even the fact that you're pursuing
these animals to hunt them and eat them.
But there's a very strange connection
that you get when you're out there in
that total quiet woods where they live,
you're in their world and you lock eyes
with them and you meet them and you see
them and you're in this place with no
cell phone reception with no people
anywhere near you for miles and miles.
Yeah.
It's a totally different feeling.
Life shows you,
uh,
another aspect of itself that you didn't
know existed.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And it's out there every day.
Yeah.
But we're just,
you know,
and living in our,
we're muted were very nice.
You did.
There's something about cities and this
existence.
I mean,
don't get me wrong,
I like it.
I like a lot of it.
I liked the fact that you can go to a
restaurant.
I like going to the movies.
I like the fact that if,
uh,
you know,
if your phone breaks,
you go to the fucking mom,
get a new cell phone,
all that stuff's wonderful.
It's not,
not bad,
but the other stuff is fantastic too and
we're disconnected.
A giant percentage of our population
lives in these urban environments that
have a complete and total disconnect
from the actual life on earth.
Like life on earth is not just urban
environments.
Life on earth has this broad spectrum of
different ways it manifests itself and
to experience all these different ones.
To be in Alberta and see black bears in
the wild to be,
you know,
in Colorado and see mule deer and being
in the woods and the mountains and to be
around these different animals,
it's a different,
it's a different understanding of the
actual existence that living things have
here on earth.
That living things that share the air
you breathe and the water you drink and
the earth itself.
How was it that was the best part of
that trip?
Cause we would split up,
uh,
Adam would go one way.
I would go another way in the morning.
I'd have mark womack with me.
He'd have a,
jamison was his camera man's name would
go with him.
And the best part was at the end of the
day,
hearing what everybody saw and not,
not,
not what if you killed something.
Cause we didn't care.
I mean,
were there a long time,
it didn't kill very much,
but just what everybody saw,
you know,
from the bucks being locked up that were
dead.
Two,
uh,
one morning we were up and a w heard
something,
a commotion up ahead of us and mark's
mark says,
oh,
it's a bug rubbing his antlers.
And I listen for a second.
I said,
no,
that's two bucks fighting.
So we took off up the hill and I got 25
yards away and these bucks,
we're just going at it,
just fighting,
pushing each other around.
And I,
I couldn't get a clear shot,
didn't get out there and time to do
that.
But that story.
And then Adam would say,
well he called in three Fox,
you know,
he did a varmint call on three Fox came
running in or he saw this many wild
boars or he was close to getting inside
a giant fallow Bach and however it
didn't work out.
And then I would share a story about
what I saw,
you know,
about another brown snake or something
like that.
And that was,
that was so fun just getting together
over the campfire.
Not talking about what we killed,
but just what we saw and experienced,
you know,
and it's,
I was flew home last night and just got
in this morning to La and I'm looking
around in the airport.
I was thinking about all the people,
I wonder how many actually would get me,
you know,
cause I feel like an outsider a little
bit,
especially coming back from the hunt and
I'm just looking at everybody thinking I
don't get them.
They probably don't get me,
but you'll at least understand what
they're doing.
I think,
you know,
I mean,
when I was checking my luggage in it,
I was flew virgin coming her back from
Sydney to La and you know,
the,
the lady there,
the check and she's like,
oh,
what's in that case?
And I said,
it's about a weapon.
I go,
could be,
yeah,
it's a bow and arrow.
What were you doing?
I said,
hunting.
She's in.
She goes,
what were you hunting?
Oh,
don't tell me.
Don't tell me.
She didn't want to hear it.
Like you have leather shoes on.
I was like,
I was hunting buffalo.
She's like,
there's buffalo here.
I said,
well,
not here,
but yeah,
there's,
there's a lot of buffalo in Australia.
And uh,
she's like,
well,
I don't think you can fly with a bow and
arrow.
And I'm like,
I know you can't.
Yeah you can.
I said,
it's just like I said,
it's not even like a firearm or weapon
type thing,
it's just,
you just check it in just normal.
But anyway,
I,
I was thinking,
I was like,
Whoa,
man.
That's,
how old was this lady?
Oh,
she wasn't old.
She was much younger than me probably.
I mean,
you can fly with a bone.
And what was she telling you that I
don't know.
She never looked into that.
I said,
I go,
well,
I ended up,
you didn't have to do anything.
She said,
you're going to have to sign all this
stuff because they're not allowed.
And I'm just like,
I said,
listen,
I fly with this all over the world as a
lady worked there.
Yeah,
no,
no.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
So she said there are way more strict,
which maybe they are verge.
I was most true.
That's where she said,
she goes.
I said,
well,
I've just flew quantis to Darwin and
back,
and nobody said a word.
I said it,
I've,
she goes,
have you ever been in Australia before
with it?
I said,
yeah.
I've listened.
I've been everywhere.
It's never an issue.
Trust me.
I'm not trying to blow.
I mean,
just trust me.
So anyway,
but yeah,
it's just,
there's times that I'm just like,
God,
am I the outsider or,
or what?
I don't know.
Well,
you know,
it's like
we were talking before this when we were
on the way over here about a show.
They wanted me to come on and talk about
guns,
but there's going to be like a large
audience and is going to be a bunch of
people on the panel and you talk for
seven minutes and you go to commercial
break and I'm like,
I'm not interested.
I'm not interested in doing that because
I think that it's a long conversation
that you have to have with someone and
it takes a while for you to understand
their point of view.
It takes a while for them to understand
your point of view.
It takes a while to establish the fact
that you're a very reasonable person and
this is a very nuanced conversation.
Much like when that guy in France ran
over a bunch of people with his truck,
I don't think the truck should be
outlawed.
And I think the real issue is human
beings that are capable of doing
horrible shit,
blind people,
right?
Why are they capable of doing that?
Let's get to the bottom of that and
let's stop ignoring all the factors and
just concentrating only on the weapon.
Right.
That kind of is a long
conversation that I think it takes hours
and hours and you still might not get to
the bottom of it.
That's how I feel about like you talking
to someone about hunting,
like if you came over here,
it's almost like,
I don't even want to tell them.
Like if someone says like the,
you have a boat,
like what's in the case?
I got to bow and Arrow.
What do you do?
I practice our tree.
Yeah.
It's easier that way.
I like to shoot at targets.
Oh,
you target shooting.
that's cool.
That's in the Olympics.
Yup.
I see New Olympics.
Yeah,
it's up my targets,
they move and they have antlers.
I nick.
Well,
they can't tell him that.
I think I'm just like,
it takes too long.
Yeah,
it does,
but I don't know.
I think I'm,
I just don't like hiding who I am,
basically.
So I'm always,
I just say,
Hey,
this is what I do.
So yeah.
She's like,
don't tell me.
I'm like,
I was hunting buffalo.
I'm telling you,
I don't care.
They're an invasive species.
They live there.
You're going to hear,
you're gonna hear what I was doing,
whether you like it or not.
Nobody wants to hear.
Well it's Kinda Kinda like with my,
with my social media,
I like putting up stuff that so I can do
weed the people out,
you know,
like holding,
holding the buffalo head in the water.
I'm like,
okay,
this is going to weed out so that people
who I really don't want here anyway,
they're going to get mad at you for
sure.
But they would get mad anyway.
And there's a lot of people that listen
to these conversations and they get a
perspective that they would have never
had.
Like there's a lot of people right now
that are listening,
that are in their car,
that are on there,
you know,
on the boss or whatever,
and they've got the headphones on and
they're thinking about this in a way
that they never thought about it before
because in their mind they've,
because of the fact they live in these
urban environments and they've never
been exposed to hunting and they get all
their meat from a store or from a
supermarket or from a restaurant,
they just never heard anybody talk about
it.
And this is a,
it's a weird part of our life.
It's a d,
it's a dangerous disconnect I think with
life and death,
the dangerous disconnect of restaurants
and supermarkets.
Well here's,
here's one thing,
I think people just get tuned in to what
they're interested in.
And that's it.
I mean,
even instagram does it.
So on the explore page or whatever that
is,
what comes up is what you look at.
So it comes up on my page is like a
hunting and fitness and that's,
so it's all that.
So whatever you're looking at,
whether it's gay guys are or cooking,
that's what's going.
That's what,
that's your world.
So that's sort of what our world is now
as we only,
we're only exposed to really what we
want to be exposed to,
you know?
And that's why I'm like,
no,
I'm hunting buffalo,
uh,
that lady be exposed to something
different.
Right,
right,
right.
So,
I dunno,
it's just,
um,
it's comparable.
Comparably know what my point is,
but it's,
what you're saying makes a whole lot of
sense is that people,
do they find these communities with
likeminded people and becomes an echo
chamber.
Yeah,
yeah.
If you're preaching to the choir,
and that goes all the way back to like a
million hours ago,
it feels like since we've been talking
about why that Netflix thing is so
appealing to me and having you involved,
it's just because we've reached so many
new people and hunting is so,
is so important to me.
And I think,
I mean,
just the,
just so people can understand what
motivates us and why it's important.
I just want that,
just want that shown.
Right.
You know,
it's shared.
Right.
But there's definitely a way to do it.
And I,
I know where we should go.
I mean,
whether it's the buffalo place or
somewhere else,
but I think it's a great idea to do.
No,
Steven Nellis show net is on Netflix.
Yeah.
Yep.
And it has one star.
Does people are so angry,
either they find it and if you shouldn't
have to eat me.
Yeah.
Anything you want from salary,
people get,
uh,
they get super,
super aggro.
You know,
you want to make people really angry.
Tell them,
tell them that there's a growing body of
science that shows it.
Plants are intelligent.
Yeah.
Glance thing.
They feel that the screen and all that
fucking freak out like babies or you
don't even have to say that this
justifies eating meat.
Just put that.
No,
when I put that on twitter,
just the,
the,
the data about that and people will
fucking go crazy and attack me for
hunting.
Yeah.
Or if you talk about all the animals
that die when they're one of their
salads been made,
you know,
I mean,
so it's different.
Whatever I,
they,
they put,
they prioritize or put different
importance on,
you know,
that we've talked about that too,
that they feel like they're doing a good
thing.
And they also,
in many ways,
look,
if you're,
if you're shooing factory farm,
you're avoiding factory farming and
eating more salads in evening,
uh,
you know,
farm to table vegetables instead,
you are definitely contributing to less
death and suffering.
100%.
Yeah,
but you can tip it into some,
they just are,
if you will,
grain.
If you eat grain,
you're contributing to a w for,
first of all,
what do you care about?
Do you care about insects?
Like where do you draw the line?
Because if you don't care about insects,
well then you're okay.
But if you do,
if you think that insects are life well,
there's pesticides,
they're fucking,
they're there.
It's a holocaust everyday out there
fucking bugs.
They're spraying those goddamn things
constantly.
I mean if you,
if you want to have a healthy crops,
there's a reason why they have these
pesticides cause they want to kill these
animals that are trying to eat the crops
to kill these little bugs.
And I don't know,
I just keep going back to this recent
trip just because I think about it and
it's just like,
here's another example.
So those are the Brown snakes up there
are second most deadly and we saw a
number of brown snakes in the road while
we were driving.
Adam swerves around them,
you know,
try to not kill him,
not kill him.
He wants him to stay alive while yeah,
big spider.
He had crawling on his face.
I saw that thing.
Why did you let that thing grow on his
face?
I Dunno,
cause he's Australian.
Just different.
Free to but not killing
it.
What's happened?
Is that on his instagram,
uh,
it was,
yeah,
it is somewhere.
So you got it.
Adam.
Dot.
Green Tree.
Bow Hunting.
Now he changed it to just Adam Green
tree.
Adam.
Dot.
Green Tree.
Why?
Oh,
I don't know.
The bow hunting park.
I think it was tutoring cruisy yeah,
maybe.
Um,
I don't think he's worried about that at
all.
I Dunno.
People,
boy,
that guy seemed immune to,
to hate.
Yeah.
It's,
uh,
um,
he's a great guy.
He's a,
but he,
he is sensitive to,
I mean he's,
it's not,
that's what I'm saying.
It's not like we're just cold blooded
killers.
Right.
You know what I mean?
There was one time we did,
we didn't have an argument,
but I didn't believe him about something
and he was so upset.
He's like,
I,
he goes,
I'm brutally honest,
you know,
and he's like mad that I didn't believe
him.
So it's like he's a warmhearted person.
He's not just a,
uh,
not running over snakes and kill a
robot.
No,
no,
no.
And so people think that we're just
these,
these cold blooded killers out there,
barbaric or whatever.
No,
no.
I feel like,
and I don't want to judge people who
aren't,
but I feel like we are just,
we understand the circle of life better.
Yeah.
I Dunno.
Well,
you definitely more accustomed to being
around it.
You're definitely exposed to more.
Yeah.
You know,
I think,
like I said,
I have friends that are vegans.
I know a lot of vegans and people think
that for some reason I hate vegans.
I mock a lot of things.
I make fun of things that are,
that are targets and a lot of like the
proselytizing nature of vegans in the
angry self,
righteous moral,
high ground stance that they take.
It's easy to mock.
It's right there.
It's easy.
And I think,
I think most of the people that do it,
they do it for good reasons.
Most of the,
the,
you know,
trying the lifestyle and eating that
way,
but there's also health problems with
it.
You know,
people don't like you saying that
either.
I know a lot of people that have tried
it and they give up after awhile because
it bought up my friend Sophie from the
comedy store.
She just started eating eggs again.
Yeah.
For the longest time she was just trying
to just go straight Vegan.
She kept getting her blood work back and
it wasn't healthy.
Or,
um,
actually she wasn't,
she wasn't a work.
Sam Harris was the blood car.
He went Vegan for a while,
but his blood work was all fucked up,
so he started eating fish and eggs and
yeah,
it's like there's people that buy
different bodies are more adaptable to
different kinds of diets and some people
just don't do well and are all plant
based diet and maybe they're not as
disciplined as some folks.
Maybe they're not doing it right.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's hard to say,
but everybody,
everybody's different.
But I don't think there's anything wrong
with going out and killing animals and
eating them.
And I think that's where we differ from
a lot of people that think that you
should not be allowed to do that.
You not be allowed because it's
barbaric.
I don't think it's barbaric.
I think it's spiritual and that's what
what freaks people out.
They get very angry if you say that.
Yeah.
But they,
but they wouldn't get angry if he talked
about native Americans doing it.
Yeah,
it's very interesting.
And the thing is is like the big
difference is I don't care if they don't
eat meat.
I don't judge them for not eating meat,
but they judge us for killing.
You know what I mean?
So it's,
it's pretty one sided as far as they
won't accept being a hunter and being
self sufficient while any hunter I know
isn't going on Vegan pages and talking
shit.
You know what I mean?
I mean,
so it's just weird how they're so
hateful and so one sided,
you know,
up on our soapbox and I don't feel like
we would do that.
I mean,
I know we'll do it.
I know there's going to be people that
say they're going to say,
oh,
first of all,
they can say,
how many times am I going to be on here
as many times as he can come.
Let's talk about podcast folks.
What's the record of the most people on
here for the most number of,
I dunno,
repeat guests,
somebody probably knows.
Probably Joey Diaz.
Callan's probably pushed challen.
Yeah,
account.
All the,
all the fight companions and everything
and he brought,
well,
oh that's true.
Yeah.
And then they'll say,
talking about more boring hunting shit.
That's fine.
I know you don't have to listen folks.
I do a lot of podcasts.
I've got one later today with Jordan
Peterson.
I guarantee you we're not going to be
talking about hunting.
Well it's,
who's that?
He's a professor at the University of
Toronto.
He might hut.
He might,
I don't think it does though.
Uh,
he hunts liberals,
but he,
one of the things is about,
um,
what we're talking about earlier that we
were saying that people sort of find
their area and it becomes like an echo
chamber.
And I think that's one of the issues
with,
whether it's veganism or even hunting,
is that I think that people,
they need to be had to have these
dialogues with people that don't
necessarily agree with that so they can
find out how the other person thinks.
And you know,
if you do,
if you are talking to a person who is a
hunter and you find out that they're
actually just a cruel psychopath,
like,
fuck man,
I wouldn't want to hang out with that
guy.
I mean,
I've,
I haven't experienced that,
but I know they must be out there.
So if you were sitting across him having
a freaks and everything and everything.
Yeah.
And you were having a conversation with
someone like that.
I mean it would be,
it would be disturbing,
but I think that most people that,
uh,
are,
especially people like yourself or a guy
like remy warren or Steve Rinella,
very well spoken,
who was also an advocate for
conservation,
loves wildlife.
If they sat down and had a long form
conversation like this with someone
who's a reasonable person who was a
Vegan for all the right reasons,
there's a vegan because they care about
life and cause they,
they want to be cruelty free and they
want to live life with his little
footprint as possible.
I think they'd be surprised at how much
common ground they find.
Yeah.
I mean if you,
if,
if anybody spent a day in the woods with
remy or Adam,
they'd be shocked at how much not
hunting.
They know just how much they know about
the environment,
about,
about where they're hunting about
different species,
about the animals and tendencies and in
foliage.
And I mean those guys are amazing.
Almost like we were talking about like
with the aborigines were kind of losing
their culture.
We're losing out on an understanding of
how these people live.
There's a little bit of that could be
said about the,
the,
the culture of hunting is that if it
goes away and if it w w there was a
trend about 10 maybe 1520 years ago,
where from what I've read at least,
obviously I'm pretty new to it.
I've only been hunting for five years,
but that they were considerably worried.
They were really worried.
There was a real thought that the next
few generations that hunting was going
to dwindle down to such a such a low
number that the hunters would not have
the same sort of impact in,
in terms of politically where they could
affect the retaining of public lands.
Yeah.
And,
which is a huge issue with,
with,
with Americans today and you're seeing
it with this trump administration where
you're seeing the erosion of the
environmental protection agency and the
erosion of the status that protected
status at some national monuments have
and perhaps public lands have people
were super nervous and you had a
conversation,
a long conversation with Jason Chaffetz,
Chaffetz Chaffetz Chaffetz who had a
very controversial bill that he had out
that was pulled back.
It was a bill to sell off public land
that was pulled back because of the
activism of hunters in the people care.
Yeah.
It was,
uh,
it was what they determine what they
were going to,
um,
determine was disposable.
Yeah.
3 million acres.
Disposable as well.
That was,
that was hr six 21 and then there's Hr
six 22 also said there's two of them
kind of back to back.
Different,
six 22 just took away the law
enforcement on public lands,
which at,
and t and they wanted to take it from
the,
the federal government,
um,
to give it to the state,
which people think that that's just a
way where the states can say,
well,
we can't afford it,
so we're going to have to sell this
public land because it's a resource.
And in the states have to,
the states have to balance our budget
every year.
Federal government doesn't.
So if the state has to balance its
budget and it's not penciling out and
they can sell x amount of acres and
that's going to help,
they're going to do that.
That's all there is to it.
So,
um,
yeah,
that is,
there's also wildfire protection.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean,
bunch of issue fighting wildfires is
all,
it's a federal issue,
but if it's private land,
if the state sells it all,
that shit's gone.
There's no more federal protection.
Yeah.
And you look at,
um,
I dunno,
it's a,
that's a big one.
And so sportsmen's really stepped up and
that was through social media,
how they can,
now we have more of a voice than we've
ever had.
You know,
before it was just these politicians
making decisions and you know,
the US little people didn't really have
a say.
Now we have a say.
I mean Jason Chaffetz,
you'd think,
well,
why would he care?
He'd look at his instagram page.
He might have,
you know,
I don't think he has 20,000 whereas we
have pretty big numbers,
especially you.
So if you mentioned something about it,
he gets overwhelmed with,
Hey,
are you looking out for us?
Are you doing the right thing by us?
Um,
we,
we won't vote you in next time.
And so then it makes those guys think,
Holy Shit.
Did you see his town hall meeting?
Yeah.
It's crazy.
It's all sportsmen and sportswomen
showed up and they all people that care
about public lands and they went crazy.
Yeah.
That I don't,
that was a kind of a goal.
I was,
yeah,
I was had mixed mixed feelings on that
because the yelling and stuff doesn't,
it least it sends a very clear message.
It did.
It doesn't accomplish much as far as
there,
but yeah,
it,
it sends a message for sure.
Yeah.
It's a dangerous and he's not going to
be a politician anymore.
No,
I nuns resign and I don't know.
I'm not sure.
I haven't,
you know,
I see every once in a while he likes
some of my stuff,
so it's like,
um,
I hear he's going into male
prostitution.
That's what I heard.
Is that true?
Jamie,
can you go google that?
I just made that up.
I know Jason,
if you're listening,
I'm a comedian and I'm sorry.
No,
don't.
So he,
he seemed like a super nice guy,
but it's,
it's a politician.
And I told him,
I said,
Lucy was,
I go,
listen,
you're the first politician I've ever
met.
And he's like,
Oh,
you've lived a charmed life puzzled by
representative Shavitz decision to quit
congress.
Ben Is that fucking deal going in that
town hall and have all those people
screaming.
I'm probably thinking,
what am I doing?
Well,
he's,
you know,
like I said,
he seemed nice,
but maybe that politicians have to be
personable.
That's how they get elected.
You know,
you ever watch house of cards now?
I had show,
she'll watch it freaking the fuck out if
it's really like you should be scared.
We should all be scared.
So I'd like to,
I'd like to learn more.
I haven't,
I haven't asked him,
you know,
what's going on or whatever.
But yeah,
I mean I was,
I liked the fact that he at least took
time out to talk about it,
you know,
instead of just,
and I'm not sure why he did,
but I appreciated the fact that he did.
Well,
it's,
he's an interesting guy because he saves
money for the people by sleeping in his
office.
He was a cot in his office that he
sleeps in to save money on hotel rooms
for the people.
So it's like,
yeah,
it's not like he's a total piece of
shit.
No.
You know,
he didn't get that feeling.
But,
um,
Rinella has a very bad opinion of him
based on his record with defending
public lands and Rinella thinks that he
does not understand the significance of
these decisions.
These decisions are,
they are a step in the wrong direction
that will snowball out of control and it
will eventually lead to privatizing
public lands and the loss of the access
to them by the American people that,
you know,
it was all set aside by Teddy Roosevelt
and all those people that had such great
insight and foresight back in the day.
And that's,
you know,
that was the worry with,
he says,
well,
no,
I'm just taking the law enforcement
away,
um,
from these lands and gay,
or not taking your way but giving it to
the state.
And like I said,
with the whole budget thing,
so people were thinking that when they
don't have enough money,
not just for the law enforcement,
but for,
uh,
enforcing illegal timber,
timber harvest and dumping trash.
And so when all that happens that that
lessens the value of the land.
So when the value of the land is lesson,
then it's just like,
okay,
whatever.
This is a garbage dump anyway,
so it makes it easier.
So they thought that was just a step in
the transition of moving,
taking that away from public land and
privatizing it is opinion and maybe,
maybe it was,
I don't know.
Well he seemed like Jason seem like a
very nice guy when you were interviewing
him.
I don't know enough about that
particular issue,
but when you talk to God like Brunello
who is deeply invested in it and very
well read on it,
he uh,
is of the opinion 100% that it's an
incredibly negative idea.
Hr has six 21 which has gone and six 22
which he thinks is equally negative and
he thinks it's essentially like a Trojan
horse.
Right.
And that's,
and I told him,
I said,
what I said too,
as I said,
you know,
sportsmen don't support six 22 either.
The girls get mad when you call it
sportsman probably.
Is there another word outdoors?
People towards,
people can't say sports people.
You're like,
what?
Lacrosse players sick of that.
Are you,
cause you're a man,
your male privilege is showing,
oh son of a bitch.
I thought it was white privilege that
too.
Oh,
you got to have it all.
American privilege.
White privilege.
CIS gender privilege.
Peanut butter,
jelly ratios,
peanut butter and jellies.
Racist Take Fletcher had that on.
I didn't even know what that was about.
All I saw was your post and the
headline,
just like I didn't surprise me though.
People think the peanut butter and Jelly
is racist.
This is how deep it gets because white
people eat peanut butter and Jelly,
whereas black people don't necessarily
eat peanut butter and jelly.
So to have peanut butter and jelly as a
food choice in school for our kids is
racist because other ethnic groups don't
necessarily eat peanut butter and jelly.
What in the fuck?
Well,
first of all,
who doesn't like peanut butter and
Jelly?
Uh,
some communists.
I think maybe Chinese folks.
Uh,
from of the stars.
Yeah.
Hunters probably don't.
Yeah,
that guy from that movie molested that
girl.
Um,
yeah.
Who North Koreans?
Maybe the most evil ones.
Maybe they don't like me to burn.
The only,
probably I don't,
that's ridiculous.
That's delicious food choice.
People are just working too hard to be
offended.
So you are exactly 100% correct right
there.
People are working too hard to be
offended.
Yeah.
There's a,
there's a lot of folks out there that
just looking for something to get ticked
off at.
It's uh,
it's too easy.
It's too easy to get by,
you know?
And I think that's also something that
happens when life is too fucking easy.
Yeah.
There's not enough struggle when we're
talking about kids and about putting
your kids through difficult things so
that they understand accomplishing goals
and they understand how things aren't
easy.
You have to struggle through stuff.
And how it's hard today because you
know,
you're doing well.
I'm doing well.
Our kids are fine.
You know,
they don't have to worry about where
food's coming from.
It's going to be there.
You open the fridge,
there's the food.
Yeah.
So you have to figure out like,
okay,
how do you get this kid to understand
and appreciate the value of a difficult
task?
Overcoming that difficult task and
feeling that good feeling that you have
of building character and of and
knowing,
yeah,
I can push through something like you
had to do during that tough hunt,
very difficult.
Questioning yourself.
Then finally success.
Ah,
and then you have that good feeling,
good feeling of success and of
accomplishment and of realizing that you
will fight those demons in your mind and
that you will stay the course and keep
hammering as it were,
get through on the other end with
success.
And you've done it before and even
though you've been doing it for fucking
decades,
those questions still come to your mind.
That's,
and that for me personally,
that's why work as hard as I do just
because you get wake up calls like that
and you're just like,
okay,
I gotta be on my a game.
Well,
it's one of the reasons why I like doing
really difficult things,
which leads me to what you've got me
into his running.
Yeah.
I've been fucking running lately.
I run all the time now.
One fucking hills.
It's crazy.
I run hills.
I put a backpack on with a weight played
on I fucking Walk Hills.
I'm like,
what am I doing?
How often are you running?
Several days a week.
Really?
Yeah.
Depending on whether or not I'm home,
like then route that we did.
Yep.
Okay.
I'll do that route and I also do that
steep hill near my house.
I do that a does a couple different
routes that I go.
How's it?
I mean is it easier than this year?
But it still sucks the fat Dick.
That's what was about to say.
That's like,
that's running.
Hey,
that could be a shirt running.
Sucks a fat Dick.
But I love it.
It's,
it's,
it's definitely slightly easier.
Yeah,
but they'll,
you remember that fucking steep,
Steep Hill once you get to the bottom
and then you go back up as awesome.
It is awesome.
But it is always hard.
It's never easy when I'm getting to the
top of that thing,
but I could make it all the way up to
the top.
Now.
I don't have to stop it.
Really?
Yeah,
I can make,
oh,
that's good.
Yeah.
That's awesome.
It's fucking brutal.
Yeah.
I made sure that I could get there.
Fuck,
it's hard.
But you,
you did mention that it has helped your
cardio on.
Oh Dude.
Well that's one thing that I noticed.
Like I didn't,
I didn't uh,
kickbox for couple of weeks because I've
been too busy doing other stuff and I
wanted to keep with the running because
I was getting some accomplishment.
I'm,
I was getting some um,
um,
progress out of it.
I was seeing progress and then,
uh,
I started,
going back into some of my other
workouts.
It didn't affect my weightlifting and
all my Catawba Kettlebell workouts at
all.
But man kickboxing,
it really affected it.
It affected it a real positive way cause
I'm doing all hills,
so I'm basically sprinting a lot jacked
spike.
And so when I was a,
I was doing rounds in the bag the other
day,
I was like,
she is,
I got a lot of wind.
It's kind of crazy.
That's awesome.
Yeah,
it was like deep into like the third and
fourth round and I was still slamming
the bag and I was like,
this is weird.
It's like I've got like an extra gear
here.
Did A,
have you dropped any weight?
Yeah,
I've dropped a few pounds.
Probably like somewhere between one 94
one 96 where I was,
I was hovering around 200 but I've
dropped down before just by my diet.
Gut shitty again,
got shitty again.
When I went to Mexico I gained like
eight pounds in a week in Mexico.
Yeah.
Be Year and Mexican food.
That's not good.
That's not good for weight control.
Where's definitely not taste good
though.
Yeah.
Well I haven't been doing Jujitsu very
much when I do Jujitsu a lot.
I fucking,
the weight just flies off.
Really need anything.
I could eat a horse,
but it's a Jujitsu just so calorie
intensive.
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah,
the way it burns.
Just fighting for your life.
Well,
let's know,
what's your running goal?
Um,
I don't have a running goal.
I just,
I'm definitely going to keep doing it
and keep getting in better shape.
And then if something,
if I decide,
okay,
I need something to strive for,
then here's my goal.
Okay,
I want to do the key.
Pam Ran Five K next year and fucking
kick ass at it instead of this year when
I did it where I was like,
oh Jesus,
this is hard.
Well,
the zero running.
How about this guy?
Almost 25 seconds short of the two hour
marathon barrier.
So crazy.
He did break the world record though.
It broke the world record.
Two hours and 20 seconds.
25 seconds I believe it was.
So he was only 25 seconds short of
breaking what people think is this
unattainable record.
That's insane.
He'll break it or someone like him would
break.
Somebody will.
Yeah,
but it's so close.
So in Nike's apparently lied to you will
invest.
Yeah,
I don't think so.
I'm not built like that guy.
They're all built the same way.
Like
popsicle sticks,
super humid.
When he was running this too,
it was like 70% humidity,
which isn't like ideal.
No hot water.
Oh,
that's high.
Well that probably could have been the
20 seconds.
Right?
Oh for sure.
Yeah.
Maybe they could do that in Seattle in
the winter.
The course is running on is in Milan.
I guess there's an article I just read
yesterday.
I think it was on tech crunch maybe or
wired.
Somebody like a for there was trying to
break a half marathon and he wanted to
see if he could break a 90 minute or
half marathon and was his first time
running on that course and he broke up
like two and a half minutes so that
there's something special about that
course to take a mile and a half track.
I don't know why you'd be able to run
faster necessarily there,
but punk can and those shoes they made
two or what is it?
What's the deal with the shoes?
Something spus super special training.
I don't know exactly.
You can't buy him yet.
You can like only when I'm off a raffle.
Maybe if you had under armor he would've
won.
That's it.
Maybe keep hammering.
Choose good under armour.
Keep hammering shoes that you could get
an underarmour.com can you get your key
hammering shoes?
Can you buy them anywhere?
I don't think so.
What the fuck under armour get on the
ball if you can't buy my,
my three five your shirt I always wear
either.
Yeah.
Well that's a rare thing.
Shirt with buttons.
She keep that away from the public.
That's super important.
We are,
I don't know what it's going to be
released,
but the Cameron hanes line is coming out
the Cameron Hanes,
underarmour UAA hunt.
Ron.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's awesome.
And you're going to have a say in how
it's designed.
It's awesome.
It's the boots are amazing.
Yeah.
Beautiful boots.
Uh,
Kamma shorts,
pants,
base layer,
hoodie jacket.
It's killer.
And when is this?
All this stuff.
You don't know when it's coming out now?
I don't know.
But they're in the in development stage
right now.
Yeah.
I think that they texted me when I was
in Australia and said they have samples.
And for me it was awesome when you took
over the UAE hunt page on instagram and
you'll do more of that now.
Right?
Because I talked to Brian,
you know,
Brian,
we're going to get on the ball with
this.
Yeah.
I mean when I took it over the week that
I took over there was,
so if you look at impressions on
Instragram it went up 3 million.
Well that seems like a good thing Brian
isn't I really wait,
we're waiting for response looking at
Brian off here.
Looking at him in the camera.
You can look at him up there.
Oh it's up.
Yeah.
So no,
and when Adam took it over,
when we're on that Australia hunt it,
it went up like they went from,
what was it,
a 493,000 to 502,000 followers.
So pretty good jump.
Yeah,
that's good jump.
I posted it on instagram too.
Yeah.
And it's just a matter of putting out
interesting content.
Yeah,
well that's what I was saying.
Like the instagram story was nice,
but I would have really loved it if you
guys were street.
If there was a way to stream like more
often,
like you had like very specific moments
where he's streaming and I think that as
technology advances especially,
did you see what a Ilan Musk is trying
to do?
He's trying to fill the world with one
gigabyte Internet and he's going to do
is launch satellites into the year
that's going to allow people to have one
gigabyte is fucking insane fast.
And if that happens you can stream live
from anywhere.
But say goodbye to privacy by the way.
It's going to be drones filming people
right outside their window.
It's going to get really crazy but live.
But what's going to be interesting is
you can in a place like
where you were and you could,
you know,
call people from your phone,
you can film things,
you could stream live and all that stuff
would be available and you would have
real Internet access in the,
in the bush.
And that's what people,
people like that,
I mean they're already asking wins a
film coming out,
you know,
we,
we filmed this,
mark womack with his company's sub
seven,
filmed it for under armour and we're
like,
we gotta turn this thing around fast.
And I saw under armour put out,
this can come out in the fall.
I'm like,
bullshit,
listen,
let's get this out.
Fucking may know people came.
People like,
I mean the chop chop,
people don't have patience anymore.
I don't have patience anymore.
I don't either.
I would like you to finish the sentence
quicker please.
I T I saw,
uh,
I saw mark womack,
we got off the plane together and in La
here and I'm like,
Hey,
you get that movie done or what?
He's,
he's on the plane.
He said he was working,
he had been editing.
So I'm like,
all right,
let's get that thing posted.
So I don't know.
I mean,
people are primed for right now.
They follow along and in our super
invested in it and it'd be,
it'd be awesome to get it up close.
And I'm your manager now,
so I'm going to make some calls.
We've already decided we're going to
make things happen quicker.
Yeah,
you got me running.
You got me doing a lot of shiny shit,
dude.
You gotta be do a lot of things I didn't
think I'd be doing.
Oh,
that's awesome.
So,
uh,
I oh yeah.
Well good.
So I want to make some cryo you to,
for,
uh,
for giving me this.
Just talk about landforms.
I really do think that it's made a big
impact.
And I think you and Rinella and Remy
Warren and Adam and the people that I've
had on it and Jim shockey and you know,
real representatives of the noble
pursuit,
the,
the real,
the real hardcore enthusiasts that truly
have a deep love of nature and they've
given these people,
this,
this platform and giving these people
this way to communicate these ideas.
I think the,
the millions and millions of people that
have listened to you guys,
it's changed perception.
And I think that that perception is,
there's a ripple effect and that
perception is going to lead people to
maybe read your book,
um,
or you know,
read maybe Rinella,
his book,
meat eater or maybe listen to some of
these books on tape or maybe,
you know,
look into Aldo leopold or looking to
some of these people that have really
been these huge figures in conservation
and the love of wildlife and hunting.
And they'll get a different
understanding of it than people have had
because of movies like that split movie
where the hunters or purse,
yeah,
the trade is a child molester.
It's like it right now,
you know that you said hunting was dying
or you know the one that was the fear
and now they're like in my instagram
page is 20 year old guys,
you know,
that are our intuit and our,
our buying bows and the bell rack back
home is packed and you know,
eva shockey and I will do appearances
and we have a line that goes for hours,
you know,
young girls waiting for her,
cause she's a,
you know,
and
her book coming out,
taking aim as about that lifestyle.
So I mean I feel like we're sort of
turning the corner maybe a little bit
and so we just keep that momentum going.
I think for sure it's turning the
corner.
I mean,
as far as what I see in the
communication that I get with people
online,
I mean the bowl rock,
is it,
are they experiencing an up jumping
sales?
Yeah,
I mean winked.
Yeah.
I mean,
Wayne the other day,
like,
I can't even remember what day it was,
but he sold something like 40 bows that
day in a day.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
For folks who don't know,
that's like 50,000 plus dollars in bows
in a day and bows or a specialized
thing.
It's not,
it's not something that people,
you know,
it's,
it's a very,
there's a steep learning curve to get
involved.
You know,
like we were talking about it,
about if there was a hoyt academy.
Yeah.
In California,
if there's a place to go,
there's not a whole lot of places to go.
Like when you took Scott Eastwood,
you went to that place down in
riverside,
our streets.
Is that what it was?
Yeah.
There's a few great places like that,
but there's 30 million people here and
it might be five of those spots.
Yeah.
You know,
I would love it if hoyt had a place
where our,
ideally they had more than one place.
You know,
where people could go and you would get
fitted.
They would find out what's your proper
draw length.
You know what,
how,
you know,
what weight should you start at?
What weight arrows should just start at.
Someone can teach you how,
what the proper form is,
how to release an arrow correctly and
really understand.
But just,
I mean,
even if there's someone never wants to
hunt,
just understand the,
the meditative and beautiful effect of
just launching an Arrow at a target and
have it hit that x,
the witchery of archery,
which re yeah.
Is At witchery.
That's a book.
Oh really?
Or the witchcraft of our county or zen
and the art of archery is a great book.
It's a book the witchcraft of archery.
Cause it looked that up.
Hmm.
I'm almost positive.
I read it.
Really.
Jamie,
come on.
Help me out.
You're leaving me hanging.
I definitely craft of archery.
Is it?
No.
Uh,
yes.
Nope.
Yes.
Come on.
It's probably a only one copy guy handed
to look at.
I wrote this.
Oh,
you don't believe him?
Wow.
It witchcraft of archery.
Here we go.
Which craft of our tree,
which craft posts?
Archery.
This is not looking good registry.
Which Klaff page pagan,
which splits in the which I'll work.
Hmm.
Um,
not looking good.
The witchcraft of archers according to
the famous thing like that.
All right,
interesting.
Okay.
Does,
can we edit this part out?
Nope.
Just kidding.
The sorcery of archery.
Yeah,
it's fun.
It's a beautiful discipline.
I mean even if someone never choose,
and honestly if
you really want to get into hunting,
just straight up hunting,
he'd probably just start with a rifle
anyway.
It's a far easier way to do it.
No,
no,
don't say that.
Or wear earplugs.
If you do do it,
you don't want to blow your ears out for
sure.
Another problem that I'm running into is
a lot of people have been hunting for a
good portion,
a portion of their life have bad
hearing.
I know my ears ring all the time for
when I rifle hunted.
That's crazy.
And it was just a kid cause I used to go
shoot my 300 winchester magnum up at the
rock pit bull.
I mean that's thing was so loud.
I used to love shooting and I was like,
Oh,
you're a pussy if you weren't.
I mean,
nobody wore here re hearing protection.
Not Crazy.
It's just like nobody wore bike helmets
either.
You know what I mean?
Right.
So it's the same type of thing.
But now my ears,
this ring all the time.
Yeah,
all the time.
It shows you tasted music.
That's why.
Why Toy?
Listen to some of your instagram
stories.
Listen to the music.
You're listening with Jesus Christ now
than it was raining when your ears are
ringing.
Sounds better.
What?
The country or the rapper?
Oh No,
the RAF is good.
Me and Adam,
listen,
we drove,
drove to Sydney for two hours.
I think we listen to a Kendrick Lamar,
uh,
his new song like probably 20 times.
Wow.
In a row.
Yes.
Did you guys like seeing the words
along?
It looks a word window if we still don't
really even know words.
Did you say the sing along with the n
word or do you guys get silent during
that part?
It just kind of does.
It's a funny thing,
man.
With white people.
Like what are we supposed to do it?
What are we supposed to do when it gets
to that part of the song?
It's called be humble.
Be Humble.
No,
that's a song.
Oh yeah.
Humboldt and then be humbled to when the
n word comes up,
just cause that realize it's actually be
humble bitch.
Be Humble.
Oh really?
Yeah.
It's a good one.
That's a mixed message.
Do you know that one?
Jamie?
I was going to ask you,
how'd they like that new album went down
in Australia with the Kendrick will?
Yeah.
He know about it until you brought it up
to him.
Well,
you know,
he made fun of me.
I always put in my instance,
my music on the instant story.
Rap a lot.
No,
a lot of rap though.
Yeah.
And country.
That's kind of what I listen to.
But then he had this song,
I'm like,
okay,
Hey,
where the hell do you think you learned
a song from?
From me.
And what did he say?
I don't know.
Made something out.
Yeah.
Who probably lied.
Are there any Australian wrappers?
I think there are.
I did not.
Not that anybody knows,
but I,
I remember they had,
we had the radio on down there and they,
there was some rap on there that had no
idea what it was.
So it has to be from there.
Well there's so many different rappers
now though.
There's no way you could know all that
stuff.
It's like we've reached a weird
saturation point with music where there
is no god.
I mean every year that coming out with
new music.
Yeah,
I know.
But I mean you get used to the certain
sounds or certain styles.
And this was like something I had never.
I've,
I've listened to a lot.
I was in Brazil.
You were in Brazil with me.
Yeah.
Uh,
but one time when I was in Brussels,
listen to some rap music,
some Brazilian rap,
I was like,
this is bad ass.
Yeah.
I hope what they're saying isn't stupid
cause it's,
I don't understand Portuguese,
but it sounds bad ass.
Yeah.
It's a great,
I think it would be great to work out
too.
Yeah.
You don't know what it's not as
distracting,
right?
Like if their lyrics are corny.
Yeah.
I Dunno.
I Dunno,
but I think there is Australian rap,
but it's not Kendrick Lamar.
Be Humble.
Eylea oh,
right now my dig is Elliot.
She's from,
she's from Australia.
She's white,
white privilege.
Black people over there.
They do.
Right.
But my ex pats,
American expats sneak over there.
Yeah,
I'm not sure.
Okay.
That's one of the few places I would
live outside of America.
Like if the shit hit,
that's nice there.
Canada and Australia.
Those are my spots.
Yeah,
it's cool.
I mean Sydney traffic is ridiculous
while they fucking drive on the wrong
side of the road.
They're all confused.
Yeah.
That's on the left.
Like what are you doing over here or
over there?
Go over there.
Let's switch this around everybody.
That's probably why it's all messed up.
Like look,
the roads are in place.
Everything.
They got roads in the right spot.
Traveling the inside.
Yeah.
Simple fix.
Yeah,
we'll fix.
How's Sydney?
So traffic filled.
I mean how many people live in Sydney?
5 million.
Whoa,
that's crazy.
Yeah.
If 5 million.
That's crazy.
No,
it took think of that because there's 30
million people in all of Australia or is
it less?
I think it's a little less,
probably less.
Okay.
Let's say it's 20 million,
so it's,
that would be like if there was 75
million in Los Angeles.
Yeah,
no more centered and more than that.
It'd be more be like 80 million,
80 million people just in Los Angeles.
Yeah.
There's only like,
like a few big city.
I mean Melbourne or,
I probably said it wrong.
23.7 million in all of Australia to five
or in Sydney.
Jesus Christ.
That's crazy.
25% of the entire population.
It's a beautiful city though.
I love it.
Sydney is really awesome.
Yeah,
no,
it's great.
It's just,
we were going to go to the boat shop and
I said,
you know,
I go to the butcher shops in Sydney,
right?
He's like,
yeah.
I said,
how long's it gonna take to get there?
So we did it on the map quest sang or
whatever,
an hour.
That's like I said,
this is like La.
This sucks hours in the same city.
I didn't expect that.
Everything is fine.
You don't have to worry about shit up
there.
You've got two lane roads and there's no
cars.
If you don't make it through one traffic
light cycle,
you're like,
what the hell is going on?
Wait,
this is bull shit.
Yeah.
Well you get used to a place like that
man.
You know,
and he life,
it's nice and calm and it feels
different.
Like life feels different in a small
town.
It's like there's a,
I feel like,
and this is some woo woo spiritual
bullshit that I have no,
uh,
no science behind whatsoever.
But I feel like people give off energy
and I feel like cities,
whether or not something's happening or
not,
the amount of humans in there,
there's a certain amount of energy that
you feel and when you're in a smaller
town,
you're calmer.
Yeah.
I really believe that.
I feel like there's less,
and I don't think it's just the
activity,
just this cars.
And I think it's the actual amount of
humans in an area.
Like there's some sort of a psychic
energy that they give off.
You're not,
Jamie's not buying it either.
Maybe the which we have our tree.
Ha Ha.
Maurice Thompson.
I knew it.
I had that book.
He teen 78.
Wow.
What is witchery?
Is that a real word I told you I was
right.
You were right.
I've redeemed five out of five stars in
Barnes and noble,
but it's a good book.
Wow.
So it's in Barnes and noble.
Yes.
Um,
can I get it on a kindle finder if I can
get it on kindle?
Yeah.
Witchery of archery.
It's speaking of a whole different,
um,
I dunno what you just said,
but I'm going to be it.
I'll be in Iq.
Look cubicle tomorrow.
No,
you want it.
You've got to quit that job,
dude today.
Yeah.
Should I just call right now?
Let me call for you.
Oh yeah.
You're my manager and your manager,
Kendall.
Nice.
Five 99.
I'm getting it.
Thank you.
On Jamie,
the witchery of archery and if my
fucking kindle and I tried to enter it
in,
he's like,
nope,
nothing exists.
I'm like,
listen bitch,
I've already gone through this.
All right.
Yeah.
It's so crazy that you keep a full time
job.
It's just a,
I don't understand how you do it.
And that's also where a lot of people
that get involved in hunting,
the amount of time that it takes,
like people don't have the time.
Like I was,
I was listening to Jason Carter on some
podcasts who's talking about pursuing
one individual buck for like two weeks
and I was like,
Oh fuck is two weeks ago after one
animal.
Like this is crazy.
Who's got that kind of time only like a
real,
like crazy before people pro type
character.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
That's it.
It takes time.
I mean,
it's just,
even just the dedication to,
to regular practice takes time for
archery,
but that's the next level.
There is no mean archery is,
uh,
it's,
it really is.
In terms of hunting,
it really is the ultimate pursuit,
the ultimate in difficulty.
But that's what I stopped at the
compound thing.
People go to troy,
traditional archery component or truce
for pussies settled down.
Yeah.
And that was enough fiber kill killer
with a rock.
How about you kill it with a rock layer?
Cake person did.
Oh,
you wearing shoes.
Pussy.
I always wanted to wear shoes.
I always want to drink.
Yeah,
I know.
I always wondered how anybody would kill
it.
The recurve where I was hunting,
because I said my 245 feet per second
bolus slow.
Right.
That'd be super fast for a traditional
bow.
Oh yeah.
So I mean,
I could imagine with this deer,
they'd just,
I dunno.
It'd be very tough.
Very tough here.
You probably could.
Oh wait,
you didn't know you were there.
Yeah.
But it sounds like the area you were in,
they were very unnaturally hyped up,
like unnaturally wired because there've
been hunted by so many people think
they're just normally wired,
but when people kill them is when
they're writing.
Um,
you know,
so you're distracted because there it's
a breeding season.
Yeah.
So this is post Rut.
Those bucks are not even with dose at
all.
And there,
you know,
just,
just tuned in.
But during the ride it would,
it would be easier just be like hunting
elk during the road as opposed to not,
or honey you do to the club with a
boner.
Right.
People get distracted.
I've never hunted a dude with a button.
I'm glad.
I'm glad to hear that.
I was wondering.
I have questions and sometimes I get,
I beat around the Bush to get to the
answer all I got.
I got what you're doing right then.
Yeah,
it is this,
this,
it's funny how these different animals
have like different seasons that they
come into.
Like the idea that only one time a year
they breed,
like there are a mammal.
It's not like a dog.
Like dogs want to fuck all the time,
but like deer one time a year.
Yeah.
Everything starts on hop in.
Nature says,
listen,
this is how it works.
You want to have a baby in the spring.
It's a way to do this.
You gotta do it in the fall.
Yeah.
Okay.
In the fall you got to get cracking and
then she's got take some time to cook up
that baby and dropped that baby in the
spring.
And then,
but it's bizarre.
Yeah.
There's actually some bucks that were,
they call it croaking,
which is grunting cause um,
they weren't really the full Rut,
but some doughs that didn't get bread
the first season.
If they don't get bread,
they come back into heat.
They,
we call them second cycle dose.
They were coming in.
So the bucks,
I mean they'll,
they'll do it whenever they just got to
wait for the female.
So the bucks were actually still sort of
writing a little bit.
We heard some croaking so that was full
on.
No,
there's just a few doughs that hadn't
been bred.
Well that's one of the coolest things
about elk hunting.
There's nothing like the Rut when you
hear elk screaming.
Like if the people have never
experienced that before,
even if you have no desire to hunt,
please go to a place where elk live
during the Rut.
Just to hear it.
Cause it is insane.
So wild.
Yeah,
there is so loud and the sound sounds
like something from the Lord of the
rings.
Yeah.
It doesn't even seem real.
And you're going to be in Utah this
year.
Ooh.
Yay.
Remember that?
I'm very excited.
Yeah.
Well,
we're definitely going to film some
stuff there.
We're definitely going to film some
stuff.
We'll do some instagram stories.
We'll,
we'll,
we'll definitely get some footage and
we're definitely,
and when we got some footage from last
year when you and I were into hone ranch
that I put up on Instagram,
some elk screaming,
we we're pretty far away or a couple of
hundred yards away and it's wide open.
Whereas Utah's a little bit more wooded
and we'll try to get a little bit
closer.
Yeah,
those bulls will be coming close.
I'm very excited.
I can't wait either.
I can't wait just to see you.
I can't wait.
Yeah.
I mean,
thanks for introducing me to this man.
It's changed my life.
Really has.
It's been,
it's been great to share it with you
and,
and it's been great to have you on to
share it with other people and just
share not just that,
but your entire disciplined approach to
this whole lifestyle that you live.
I think it's very inspiring to people
and think it's very important.
And,
uh,
you're a,
you're a shining beacon out there,
cameron Hanes,
so keep,
keep hammering as it were.
And your podcast,
keep hammering.
You've got a new episode that you just
gave to Jamie,
so it'll be up today.
Jamie's gonna post it today.
Young Jamie is on the ball.
Yes,
our ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be back at 1:30 PM with Jordan
Peterson and a,
I'm fixing to go check out the new
studio we got.
We're signing the lease today,
folks.
So popping.
I'm very excited.
I'm going to show camp too,
so we'll be back soon.
And uh,
yeah,
that's it.
See you soon.