Okay.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
boom, Sherlock luck. Boom bitches,
boom. Shakalaka like a Boob,
some left in the volcano.
That was real. That was real. That
was powerful. And it was real shit.
We got Sam Aaa on this, this volcano
as well. It's good to be here.
Sam Shipley tried to come to the fucking
Joe Rogan experience podcast talking
some crazy shit about,
he's been partying too much lately and
he wants to try this one sober. Yeah.
I wanted to like Sam [inaudible] dare you.
How dare you brother. We're old
school road dogging. Last respect to,
don't you know what you're saying?
You're trying to get things going and
trying to be all discipline and positive.
I feel your homie.
I'm trying Lee's jump.
We were sponsored by the flashlight
this weekend, every week.
And if you go to Joe rogan.net
and click on the link, you will,
you will save 15% type in the keyword
Rogan and you can get a discount.
Sam tripling your announcer voices
getting good. Perfect. So yeah,
you're really getting it
down and working on it now.
All you to do is start doing that quick
small talk like in the fine print and
you're going to be,
you know what I've been thinking about
doing is taking like just for purely for
educational purposes,
like a weekend Dj Strip club Gig,
just so I could work on my announcer voice
because I feel like if this ever does
blossom into a real radio show,
which it totally can because radio
is definitely on the comeback.
I mean that's what I want to hear
after I hear uncensored podcast.
I want to hear it.
A little short sound where they
can't say anything and they get,
you can't say retard or can
even say butthole, right?
I think there's three tonging can't
say retard. Dude. When I was in Boston,
we did a video that if you could watch
the video that we did and the most recent
one from Austin, Texas, we had,
we had to say we had to do it
over and over and over again.
Was it fucking terrible? They had a beep,
retard the Beep, retard like 20 times.
Hold on. Where did they do that in Austin
when you did your podcast there? Bb? No,
no, no, no, no, no. We did the radio show
there. That's crazy. Yeah, it's terrible.
But that's what's happening man.
And what's crazy about it is before
we even got into the radio station,
the person that drove us around
that worked for the comedy club,
she was talking about how that,
oh you just said the r word
like like it's a bad word.
We're like kind of thinking
like, yeah, exactly what?
And then we go into the radio station
and Joe was saying on the radio and got
caught out called out for saying retard
on the radio and it was just like, yeah,
there were totally serious. I'm trying,
I'm doing on it. It's just like nobody
calls people with special
needs retarded anymore. They,
they did this special need. You
call us assholes retarded. Exactly.
That dude's retarded asshole.
Yeah. They have down syndrome.
They have an actual name for the disease,
like calling someone a retard.
It's like you can't say idiot.
Well guess what?
That's what retards used to be when
you got, when you had down syndrome,
they used to call you a mongoloid idiot.
That was the actual medical definition
for what the fuck is wrong with you.
It's so much worse. Isn't that crazy?
They used to your baby's an idiot. Here,
take your baby home on the fucking
idiot. Well, you can say idiot,
but saying you can't say retard. Retard
is not some sort of a scientific thing.
It's not like you're, you're,
you're, you're 100% yeah.
It doesn't make any sense.
You can't say retarded. I
can say retard. You fucks.
It's like every year we go back
further and further what we calve.
I've cut faggot out of my vernacular.
The only time I say faggot now is when
I talk about the word faggot like right
now. And it feels good. You let it
go. Good to go back to my old friend,
like, let me just say about
the word faggot. I have,
I have more respect personally for the
gay community about that word than I do
for the black community and the word
nigger. Really. And I'll tell you why.
Because they call themselves
[inaudible] out on saying faggot too.
So at least there, there's not this weird
double standard, but they know though,
like Perez Hilton, that was how
he got in big trouble. Right.
He got in big trouble. Yeah, that's true.
You I knew. I see what you're saying.
You know what I'm saying? They're
gay. People will get this and saying,
oh there's this. Okay. We can say
we're taking it back. The only time,
and I was talking to on my podcast is
that the only time I think it's okay to
say the n word is in bed.
Like I love getting it all I do.
I love getting called the n word. I don't
know why you've already said nigger.
All right. After you say, I love it.
This was Bain, this Mexican chicken,
the back of my car. She was calling
you a nigger. Yeah, it was so,
it was so hot and I'm just like,
yeah, they just like, you know,
I got to get that place where I know
the girls cool. And then I'll be like,
can you call me that? They're like,
why did they call it? And they're like,
they just turn you asked you, we'll
call you. She started calling me.
She started calling you
later on with other chicks.
I know once I know of in
this cool place with them,
have them drop some n bombs on me.
Okay, so for the one check one check,
you just kind of got into it.
She just called me and but it,
then it became your thing. Yeah. Wow.
But that's how all fetish is start.
Like something happens accidentally
and you're like, hey, I like that.
You know what I'm saying? That's how
all weird shit start crazy one though.
Like you're banging this chick. And what,
what was the first reaction? I was like,
so tell me what to tell me how it
went down. I'm like, what? You know,
it's kind of like here in the
backseat of a car. Well, first of all,
rocking it old school. I appreciate
you still get low. How long this week?
Years and years and years ago. Years
and years and years ago. I just love,
first of all, I love car
sex. I just love this dirty,
like I'm looking for a car right
now and I'm literally thinking,
can I Bang a chick in
the back of this car?
Like that is one of the things I think
about when I'm thinking about purchasing
a car. Can Bang a chick in the backseat
of a Porsche, do it, can't do let Alexa.
So Econet should be their selling point.
Like that whole, uh, so practical. Yeah.
Hey, we're Cadillac. You can bang
in the back of your car. Yeah,
that you should do that.
Like how a thing where they go.
What are you saying back there?
Why not? That's the commercial
windows. Tinted windows in
the back. So always nice dude.
You've got to have tinted windows too.
But then what about the windshield, Bro?
Your windshield's not tent and people
just get to the front of your car.
Why don't you float with us?
The Sun visor thing that you pull out
with us for no one, you know my mom,
this is how crazy it was when
we used to go on vacations.
Like what road trips we go on road trips.
You'd put newspapers all around the
windows and would sleep at a rest stop.
And I'm thinking like how crazy.
You wouldn't do that nowadays. Yeah.
That's scary as fuck. Cause they know
there's people in sod. Yeah, yeah.
There's too many crazy, is it that
there's more crazy people now or is it,
we're aware of the crazy people
were aware of the crazy people.
Like some people think
everybody's getting dumber.
I personally think that they're just
getting oversaturated with useless
knowledge.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Like there's so much more useless
knowledge out there that's taking up your
brain space.
Like when you go home to let's say your
high school reunion and your buddy who
just got married and had kids and went
right to the mill. Right. He's like,
you remember nice going into that.
You're like, no, I don't remember that.
And he's like,
you remember this and be like,
cause you have all these
new things in your head.
You got to get rid of the old things.
Right. You know what I'm saying?
By Juno you're saying? Yeah.
So it's like, you know,
in the 18 hundreds like some peasant or
something isn't necessarily smarter than
that.
The idiots we have around now,
he just didn't have all this
like Kim Kardashian who's
going to get her pregnant.
All this crazy shit in her head.
You know what I'm saying?
That totally makes sense. I mean,
you only have so much room in your,
your hard drive, you know, I don't
know if people are getting dumber.
I think collectively,
uh, there's what it is,
is the people that are smarter are fucking
really smart. Yeah. The really, really,
really smart.
But the people that are dumb,
it's so easy to just get
by and be a moron now.
It's so easy.
You know,
everything is set up for you between
cell phones and easy jobs and it's like,
what do you have to do?
Like all you have to do is just show up
and do what someone tells you and you
don't have to think at all. And then
you get off work. What do you do?
You drink or you go home
and watch reality TV,
which makes you even fucking dumber.
It's all and it reinforces like dumb shit.
Like you start thinking there's
nothing wrong with you because hey man,
that's how they are on reality TV.
That's driving me crazy.
Cause I watched the sneaky
given an interview and she's
acting like she's regal
now. She's sitting there like this
with good posture. Like she, you know,
would you rather like pick her
teeth and play with her pussy? Yeah,
because that's her. That's why we like her
because she's a, you know, a black elk,
Cox Zombie. We let that Shit, you know
what I'm saying? Like we like that.
That's what we want.
But you don't act like you're not that Pr.
I W you know if you came in right,
you'd be like Joe Rogan, UFC announcer,
comedian.
That's what you,
you've done like they should introduce
these people as like what they've done.
Like Kim Kardashian and she got peed on
by a third rate wrapper and or video.
That's the intro. Kiana? Yeah.
Really? Yeah. I didn't know that.
He talks about man. Yeah, she got heat on.
Whoa, whoa. We, I think is cool. Hold on.
We need to look at the
items that we cannot,
we cannot keep spreading disinformation.
We have in the past,
unfortunately all the bath salts thing,
it's this information or no,
and the other one I said,
this is what I said, no, the
bath salts, it's not fake. No,
no. I guess you're talking about the gun,
the gun shooting the kids. It's fake.
Yeah, that's for sure.
Well, we'll talk about,
we'll talk about your struggle with
at first anyway, the bath salts,
there's a drug called bath salts.
Okay.
And what it is is they're selling it as
bath salts so that they can sell it in
stores and so that it's unregulated
because what this stuff is,
it's like a type of,
you know,
at some sort of a cousin to crystal
meth and it's really, really dangerous.
They're selling it as legal cocaine in
head shops and they also sell it online
and sell it in some stores and convenience
stores and they're selling it as bath
salts. And what it is is an intense,
like really, really bad drug and super,
super predictive. Not just
addictive, but a terrible experience.
Like not even a good time
and you get addicted to it.
It's a bad experience and it's super,
isn't it? The original use of it's
supposed to be like for insects or plants,
fertilizer or something like that.
No,
but they're also selling it.
They're also selling it as a plant food.
All right,
so that that video,
I went home and watched it cause when
you were talking about yesterday,
I never saw it.
And a of the,
what it was is a video of
these two skateboarder kids
and this guy comes out of
their house and then getting
some kind of confrontation.
The guy goes back and then
the house gets a gun there.
The skateboarder guys run away and they
shoot him. Copied on the can. Production?
No, I didn't think so because I
live over there. I looked Roma
black. Did you watch a porn? No. Well, I
watched parts of it, but I just was here.
The deal,
apparently the golden shower scene
was cut out of the vivid entertainment
release of the second tape.
Allegedly,
Kim was always denied
that ray peed on her.
Although she denied the existence
of the tape for a while too.
So it's in the air. I want to say, you
know the guy who does the sex tapes? Yeah.
I want to say it's real.
Yeah. He said it's real.
We're going to get to the guy who
does the sex tapes in one minute.
So you think the good that the key when
we're talking about his two kids are
skateboarding in front
of this guy's house.
There's some sort of an altercation
guy comes out and shoots them.
All right. So the date on
the tape was recently? Yeah,
it was just like last week or something
like that. So first I went through, uh,
put in Google, spent like an hour, hour
and a half looking from news articles,
looking for anything. There
was nothing that had in any
news or, right. Especially,
uh, so then you go to the tape and you
started looking at the tape itself.
If you look at the tape,
there's a big flashing record light on it,
which is usually used for,
if you're in looking through a view
finder of a camera and not a home security
system, it doesn't record a
flashing record light on it.
So I immediately know good ones
do none that I've ever seen but,
but as a video editor there,
I know that that's fake shit.
That's like what you see on
TV, right? They put on it
again how when you're in a movie and a
guy gets a cell phone and he looks at the
text on his phone and you know that's
not the graphics of the phone. Right?
You're like,
this is like some animated bullshit.
It's like so big and stupid looking
like and it takes you out of the movie,
right? Like they show
cheaters, they'll do that.
Like here's our undercover
it and then that cross hair.
Oh you can't say crosshairs
anymore either. Yeah.
And then then if you
look at the gun itself,
at first I thought it was like a shotgun.
Cause like how the he shot both of the
kids at the exact same time got hit like
meaning one kid did a barrel roll and the
other kid just kind of fell laid down.
It looked like he kind of laid down fell.
So all these things are to me are
like all right something's not right.
So then I started doing more looking
online looking at align found went to live
leak and there was like
12 pages of people.
Live leak is mostly military based people.
1212 pages of people
saying it's fake and like
is every single one that has like
the really bad videos. Like a Sassy.
Yeah they have like middle mostly
military stuff like planes shooting down
people and like kind of more
like real crazy. You guys are
going deep in my is great. I love,
I told Jim Norton about it but I said
daily motion so I have to email daily
motion might have it too. That's
kind of hear of forge. Chen.
Have you ever heard Chan of course love
four Chan Four Chan is the best skid
marks of the Internet.
No they are not. They are
great. Our stupid Sam trip.
Well what they do is they go after
they go after shit heads like a a not,
they go after a Scientology,
they go after the people that were
prosecuting Julian Assange's for the Wiki
leaks thing.
You know they go after hypocrites.
They have a certain amount of morals.
I mean yeah there's some psychos
on their stuff. They're definitely
what was leaked that was so bad about us
that we're like oh I can't believe this
get out. Or you know, it makes me think
we leaked it out. It's like Oh my God,
look at all this stuff. Cause it's all
the, I was watching Msnbc the other day,
which is the progressive side,
the argument.
So they'll call out the government
in anything and they're like,
it didn't really make us look that bad.
If you really take a look at it, sort of,
but it see, it confirmed a lot of things
that people had already suspected.
Like first of all that they
do that the United Nations,
like Hillary Clinton did one thing where
she was trying to collect biometric
data on the United Nations. And this is
like a real email. Well, that's spying.
That's illegal.
That's against international law.
You're not allowed to spy on the
fucking members of UN. But they were,
there's some shit like that.
But the video of the gunship of the,
um,
the helicopter shooting down those, those
reporters in Iraq, that was the big one.
That was pretty bad. That was really bad.
That it was crazy because then there's,
there's kids in the scene too,
and one of the guys says he should,
they shouldn't have brought their kids.
You shouldn't have bought their kids.
Like that's your reaction to just shooting
50 millimeter rounds onto a car full
of kids. You shouldn't have
brought your kids. It's,
and it shows you what kind of attitude
gets developed when you're in wards wars,
the most unhealthy fucking thing possible.
Man.
There's no way to do it and to
come out of it healthy, you know,
there's no way to just,
well,
I'll just put that in the past
now and move on with my life. No,
you've been gunning people
down for five fucking,
that shit is to haunt your
memory eventually. It's good.
It's terrible for your fucking, your,
your, your mind and your thinking and,
and you know, people develop
justifications and they
get used to certain things.
People can get used to anything and
they get used to killing people.
And that's one of the things
you see in that video.
This callous disregard for life
sucks. It's hard. And you know what,
those guys,
they probably not even bad guys.
They're just fucking guys who got into
the military and then as time went on,
that's the attitude they have.
And they say a lot of shit like that to
each other to sort of reaffirm, you know,
like, Hey, I should have brought
their kids fucking right. You know,
they'll say shit like, yeah, we're crazy.
We're the craziest, you know, like,
and it's almost like they're saying
these things and you know, like,
let me get them letting gum got down.
It's almost like to reinforce each other
because they all know they're doing
something insane. Did you ever hear
the theory, the story that I'm in,
like World War II,
they did us,
the government did a study and they found
that like most soldiers couldn't shoot
and kill somebody. It just wasn't
in them. So that's the whole thing.
That's when you start seeing in movies
like, uh, more gunplay, more guns,
shooting people to kind of get people
used to the idea of actually shooting
somebody. Wow. Yeah. I did
some, uh, because back then
it was just so rare. Yeah.
I did some USO tours and one the guy
who took me on was telling me that story
that like in World War One,
they found that the majority of soldiers
could not pull the trigger to kill
somebody. Wow. So we really have become
desensitized by movies and TV shows.
100%. Dude, I, I, uh, was
driving back from Vegas one time.
I saw the most horrific crash
I've ever seen in my life,
and I pulled over to
see if everybody's okay.
There's dead bodies all over the
place. Not even affected, you know,
because I've seen so
much that on television,
I mean this car had fallen on
top of this woman's head. Whoa.
And I was this and the girl was
like his grandma Ken. I'm like,
do not tell her anything. Then he
wanted to see, it was like really,
really weird, but it wasn't.
The weirdest part was my,
I didn't have any reaction to seeing the
dead people. I wasn't like God and I,
that really stuck with me.
Why? I don't know, man. I
would still feel that I didn't,
I didn't. I didn't. I wasn't like, wow,
this is going to still fill it out too.
I don't know, man. It wasn't,
well, I'm not saying I didn't
feel something for them.
Someone's fucking crazy.
No, I didn't say it.
I'm not saying I didn't feel for them,
but it wasn't like this incredible
like insane mode. You get a hard on.
Awesome. I started playing
myself, Jill matching.
If you know your grandma got
trapped underneath the car
and someone's back there,
is she okay? Yeah, I think
she's going to be all right.
Just stay back and you
go around the corner in,
the guy's beating off on your grandma's
dead head. Oh, come on dude, that's crazy.
Somebody out there that would do it.
If you can just think that up like I
just did for sure someone would do it.
Could you imagine if grandma
dies in a car accident?
The first guy that pulls over
is beaten off on her head.
Does that the whole Sam Canson story.
Grandma car accident fleshlight right.
That like back in the day they were
partying in a news guy who had a more who
like was ran a morgue or something like
that and like the thing was that, yeah,
the homosexual necrophilia picker.
I thought you were talking about his
car accident story. No, that, yeah,
they guys would pay him to come.
Crazy thing, you know, he died.
A drunk driver hit him.
How crazy.
That is crazy to do all this
material about drinking and driving.
He used to do all these things.
We're gonna drag and we're gonna drive.
We're going to pull it off. You know why?
Because we get weighed, every fucking
had that whole bit about it. And it
was, you know, wasn't even funny.
It was like cheerleading for losers,
you know,
that was like the dark
years of Kennison comedy.
Like Kennison when he first
came out was the best.
I'd say the Kennison of 1986
who's better than that ever?
Who's ever been better than that?
You could love Bill Hicks all you want.
And I do. But Bill Hicks was
never that funny. Just no,
no one was ever that funny.
That fucking homosexual necrophiliac bid
all the shit about Jesus and the cross.
And you know, you know why? Because
I was married for two fucking years.
All that was the best shit ever.
But then he got famous and when he got
famous and he's doing blow every night,
and that's what's going to kill you.
Banging tens maybe had those.
It's that Maliki chick
that was always with him.
That was his girlfriend and she
was a fucking 10. I be like, man,
this guy's a troll and he's
got a 10 fame is sexy. Yeah.
And so he got big, he got famous
and he was partying all the time.
And I read his book, his brother's book
called the brother Sam. Interesting book.
And that's what he said in the
book that Sam just stop writing.
Just was partying all the time.
So then it was just coming up with stuff,
cheerleading for those dishes that
would come to Sam, you know? Yeah.
That was one of them. I mean, I still
loved him. No Man. But yeah, dude,
that's crazy managers.
And now how do you get into that? How do
you know that that's what you're into?
The guy who goes to the morgue and
beats off on the, how do you get there?
That's my whole question.
How do more guys who been busted
fucking bodies many times,
especially fresh ones. That's
happened many, many, many,
many times. Cause I think,
you know,
if you're some guy and you're sexually
attracted to women and this is a woman
that you could never possibly get
ahold of and no one could stop you from
touching her. There's no one around man,
you're in a quiet room with no windows.
And you know, she's on a pan and if you
want to, you can just start fingering her.
And some guys not, not only finger,
they fuck them. You know, I mean, it's,
that's happened so many times. He
says, look man, you get desensitized.
You're desensitized to those dead bodies
there really dis desensitized to dead
bodies when you see dead
bodies every fucking day of
your life. You know, I mean,
that's gotta be weird as
fuck has to be weird voice.
He had a couple dead bodies ever.
Man. It's always a very strange thing.
It the strange, but I wasn't like
freaked out. That was the whole, well,
maybe you were just trying to be strong.
What's weird is when he sees the
body's like stacked, like I went to a,
my grandfather died,
they were getting chairs out of this
room and I think it was a crowded day for
the funeral home. And, um,
I'm just kind of walking around like
thinking about things and the door opens
and there's my grandfather and like five
other dead people just sitting there in
this room with all these
chairs. And I was just like, Eh,
just the creepiest look and feel
and just was he, was he lying down,
he's laying down like you know,
just like there was a bunch of other
people that it's just like, like in slabs,
slabs right next to each other.
Like, like they're just, you know,
just like they were in a storage room,
you know,
like with all these
chairs and extra stuff.
Like like why are they just
wheeling it out in the storage room?
If you think about it,
it's amazing that we can go as like,
we've been so insulated by our complex
society that we can go like our whole
lives and never see a dead body.
Like a lot of people will go their
whole lives and never see a dead body.
Whereas back in caveman days, man,
you've saw some fucking bodies, man.
Everybody saw bodies in the Roman
days cause you knew you. Yeah Dude,
I always say that's why like it was so
much easier to get married back in the
day cause you knew you were going to
die quicker. You know what I'm saying?
Death do us part was so much easier
because the w there was more violence out
there. Yes. As like the life
expectancy gets longer and longer.
People going to take that shit more
and more for granted. You know,
back then like you, you gotta get your
living in in 30 fucking years. Yeah. How,
how old are you now? I'm 38 he'd be
dad, dude, Yad for sure mean by mommy.
I'd be long dead. And if I was
alive I would look like an old man.
Poor nutrition and no
fucking weightlifting.
I would look like shit out of gray hair.
You know,
I'd probably be taken no vitamins.
I just be eating porridge or whatever
the fuck village elder. Yeah. Whatever.
Whatever food that we killed that
day, you know. Horridge. Yeah,
man,
I was,
I've been watching the show the wild
within it's fucking good show man.
Some new show and a travel channel
with this dude goes and he,
he hunts a all over the world and he
hunts like out like uh, Lewis and Clark,
he went on this a one little expedition
where he took the same route that Lewis
and Clark took with a bunch of his
boys and they were shooting things with
muskets. They didn't shoot anything.
They couldn't shoot a fucking,
these guys have experienced hunter
and it never got close enough.
They caught Kotlow a couple of
fish and they barely survived.
One of the things that they
got was somebody had shot
a deer and left the deer.
All they took was like some of the
meat from the back of the deer,
which is like really common. Like guys
take the, what's called the backstrap.
It's like the lowing,
the Strip loin that goes against the
logic though the meat against your spine
and that's the only food that they found.
If it wasn't for that,
some hunter leaving a body behind,
you know,
they scavenged it and they're all
talking shit about this hunter the but me
malls. How many would have eaten
it too? If it wasn't all them,
it would have been a coyote.
It's not like it's going to go to waste.
It's in the fucking jungle, you
know? What do you think the crew,
the film crew's going through? I like, are
they big MACs by, they're like starving.
You know,
it's pretty crazy because last night I
watched one episode where he hunted a pig
with a knife.
They there in Hawaii and the way they
hunt pigs in Hawaii is you use pit bulls
and use two different types of dogs.
One type of dog goes and finds the pig
and they're they, they're the bang dogs.
So that tracking dogs,
they have the best sense of smell and
they can find hogs like miles away.
They can find old tracks and track them
down. So these dogs are barking. Row, row,
row, row. They let him know
and then the pit bulls come in,
the pit bulls come running in
and their armored pit bulls,
they have collars around their neck,
that protector next and they have Kevlar
vests on so the pigs can't bite through
their body. And it's because
pigs are nasty mouth fast.
And they have giant tusks.
Pigs are a weird animal man. When a
pig is in a, in a pigsty and you're,
you're on a farm and they're
all pink and cute and shit.
Pigs are the only animal that we know
of that morphs once it becomes feral.
So when you put pigs is
quickly as three weeks.
When pigs exist in the wild in
three weeks there for changes,
their tusks grow longer. Like they
literally become a different animal.
It's a fucking transformed. That's
why I like wild pigs have black hair,
that black crazy hair,
but like domestic pigs on,
most of them have like white hair.
Well there's something happens
to them when you let them free.
There's something about pigs going wild.
It actually forces like a
biological change. Survival. Micah.
Delicious Butterfly. So anyway,
this guy is out there and um, the,
the dogs are holding the pig down
and there's two different pigs.
So they have to stop both of them.
And so one of them they had to do without
the pit bulls had to do with a bang
dogs. And he's at this pig is fucking
these dogs up, man. Pick, pick,
keeps biting and biting the shit out
his dogs to putting holes in these dogs.
Really?
Yeah.
And the guy runs over and just stabs
the pig in the heart and it's all in a
river, you know? So it's like the whole
scene is like really fucking primal man.
Like he dives in the water and they're
fighting in the pigs trying to bite him
and he has to jump out of the way.
And then the dogs get in place and
then when the dogs are in place,
the pig bites a dog and the guy just runs
over and slams the fucking blade right
between the ribs. Wow. Right
into the heart. It's dark dude.
And you gotta think like that,
some real hunting man.
You're hunting up pig with a knife.
Yep. And that's how they do it.
The dog's hold them down, be apparently
that's the easiest way to do it.
I don't know why that makes any sense
at all. Why you wouldn't just fuck it.
I guess the only way to find them is
with the dogs and once you find them,
the dogs are buying them. You can't
shoot them because the dogs are there.
So it gets tricky.
So then you have to go and stab them
because apparently pigs are pretty fucking
smart and pigs, they see people come
in and they just get ghost. It's like,
you know, it's not as easy to track
them down as it is to like track a deer.
They're intelligent. They're
more intelligent than dogs. What,
what comedians do without like
discovery channel or any of that?
I mean like how much material comes from
the discovery and the travel channel,
all that stuff.
There's some crazy shit out.
That's where all the freakouts come
from, man. If it wasn't for that shit,
I probably have a much saner
life, you know, wasn't,
wasn't from totally my world.
What is, where's my
worries? Where's the why?
It was the super volcano
is not really in my world,
but it is in my world because
I'm on fucking, you know,
on TV at two o'clock in the
morning watching some crazy signs,
channel special battle. We're all
gonna die. Hey, did you see the, uh,
on the Huffington post? A green blob in
the middle of deep. How crazy is that?
So what is it? What did they
think it is? I don't know.
They are seeing it creates stars.
Yeah. That's some crazy shit.
Stellar nursery. Yeah. The
colors are not delicate.
Keller's correct of the car's careering.
No, it said something about, yeah,
they embellish the colors. Like it's
not really a scope. Yeah, but man,
I mean it's six,
640 million light years away.
One light years. A trillion years.
She's trillion miles. Excuse me.
How crazy is that would be cool if we
found a star factory where we figured out
how to make planets and stars and be like,
start sewing
planets. Like, no way, dude. I don't
happen to know where we do that.
You can buy a star and you and 900
people on that same star. Well, yeah,
yeah. I bought you a star, honey. Yeah.
Shut the fuck up. You don't own that star,
that star. Yeah, like you can name a star.
That becomes a real though and we all
become space travelers and like we ended
up like, no, you own that star
now and you can live on, you can,
if you become a Mormon brother,
you can have your own planet and your
own people and you make your own rules.
That's right.
They're supposed to be some new discovery
that was found today by the Hubble
telescope. I can't seem to find
it here. I'll find it eventually.
But just space itself, man. It's too
big. It's too virtual. Often mean.
Think about it. Do you ever try to think
about eternity and your brain just like,
nope, tap out. I tend to really go
on forever. That's the way it does,
but it's really tricky.
So what,
what happens is it goes to a certain
point and then you come back.
It's like a geometric design. It's
like, like it's, it's a shape.
Like the universe apparently is a shape.
It's a curved wall. There's, that's,
that's where it gets crazy. There's,
this doesn't make any sense,
but what they think is
that there's, like, we,
we think of the universe is everything,
but apparently it's not just as our
solar system isn't everything just as our
galaxy is and everything. At first
it was a solar system. First of all,
we thought that our solar system was, this
is it, this is all there is out there.
And then we realize, oh no,
no, we're part of a galaxy.
And the galaxy is all there is out
there. Oh No, no, no. The galaxies,
a part of many galaxies,
which is part of the universe.
Well now they think that inside every
galaxy is a supermassive black hole that
contains, and another universe.
And inside that universe is,
could be exactly like our universe or
a could have some completely different
structure.
I can't even understand. They can't
understand it. It's like when you look up,
we're, we're looking little ants
trying to, I mean, not even, you know,
you break it down.
Yeah,
we're mites on an ant's ass trying to
figure out fucking how Google works.
We were talking about last night,
the comedy club about whether, um,
you think people boned up on like
the space station they must have,
cause they put laws saying that they
can't do it. Yeah. That's so funny.
But that's why they want the Russians
there. So then bang some Russian chicks,
something that one, a astronaut who
drove cross state and their diaper.
I mean that's how crazy that chicken, so
you know, they're into some freaky stuff,
which I like.
I like
smart freaky chicks.
There's something very attractive about
getting a very smart girl and having her
sane degrading shit. It just,
it's very fun for the beginning.
The problem with smart sex is I find that
most a smart chicks that really liked
me are fucking crazy.
And did you just play some music?
It sounded like it though.
I think it did. I think the,
the drum beats sort of going off anyway.
So I,
you know like the really smart ones
that are like kind of like, like,
like snarky and a lot of them are crazy.
You know,
and a lot of them like being a
smart chick is fucking hardest shit.
Cause a lot of dudes don't
care if you're smart,
they just want to stick your Dick.
They're dead inside you. They,
they want a fleshlight, you know, and
then they want love and relationship.
But most importantly you got to,
you got to feed this fucking addiction
that you have in your deck now you'd have
to get rid of some loads. So it's,
it's hard being a smart chick. I think.
I love it. And when they deal
with Douchebag, douchebag,
they just assume that you're
going to be a Douche bag too.
And so it's hard being a
girl, bro. It's can't be easy.
Can Be good to take care of babies.
And you got to assume that the dude's
going to help you out like you were.
You were going to completely
change your whole world.
You're going to grow a human inside of
you and then you're not going to be able
to work cause you're gonna be able to
have to take care of this human or you
bring it to daycare and your kid gets
sick every fucking day of its life.
I have a buddy who as this kid in
daycare and he's like so sad about it,
he just can't afford to not
have his kid in daycare,
can afford to have his wife not work.
And you know,
actually they just broke up because
of all this. Now they're divorced.
But he's like, my kids always
say cause like it's horrible.
They're always confidence needs. And
he goes and he crushes my heart. Oh,
because it's like there's so many germs
over there. No, he's like a producer,
but he can't, he's not like a high level
producer so he can't get shit going, man.
It's fucking, you know when
in Hollywood man, when the,
when the recession hits
or hits for everybody.
So he was not making good
money and she's fucked.
He's like picks up jobs here and there
and they're sporadic and in between he's
got a little live off unemployment. It's
horrible. Yeah, it's a grind, dude. So,
you know, my point is
for a chick man, it's,
it's a way more difficult situation just
simply by the virtue of the fact that
you have a growing human
being inside of you.
You can make a baby and then you
have to take care of this baby,
that baby completely vulnerable
for many, many, many years.
Whereas a man can just shoot loads and
women all over town and have a fucking
gang of these chicks watching after
his kids. You know, you can just like,
who's done that? John's what's on
night guys named the football player,
the Bass basketball player that has a
fucking 80 killed Sean camp. Sean camp.
There you go. How many kids does that
guy have? I was reading this book.
I think he has eight kids. Damn.
There's one football lawyer.
They had 10 kids all over
the place too, right?
He couldn't stop smoking weed. So he lost,
he basically got kicked out of the NFL.
Now you're screwed. Whoa. He got kicked
out of the NFL because of we, yeah,
he had three violations. Who's
that? What's his not Ricky Williams.
He used to run for Buffalo, then he
got traded to Denver. I don't know man.
How crazy. They trying to keep football
players from smoking weed. Yeah.
One Time Charles Oakley said that
that like 80% of the MBA smoked.
We, yeah they can't, they can't have,
that's part of their contract negotiations
that they don't test for weed cause
weed it for basketball and for
pool for anything involving balls.
This is all I know for anything involving
feel and I don't mean balls like
you're nuts.
I mean anything involving orbs where
you're judging distances and it's like
these are like subtle feely things. You
know, weed makes you more sensitive.
So if you're more sensitive,
you're going to play basketball better,
you're going to play pool better.
You know you're going to fuck better.
And I think it also takes you out of
you so you don't overthink the moment.
And like sometimes if you watch basketball
guy will be so wide open and he'll
totally clink it cause he's too open. You
know, like this shit. Oh God, I'm so open.
I hope I hit this
thing. Yeah. Yeah. You let that other
thing talk to you. Don't fuck this up.
The little hat, the little boy and
get to talk to you when you're high.
You know when you're in the
groove in the zone, you know.
That's why I'm not in the VIP list.
He can't get into the club that night.
Going on stage. Stone is the best. I
can't do it. You can do it. I can't.
You have done it. Why are you lying? I
can't lie to him because we're Joe's.
Most comics say that
they can't do it like,
like you're one of the very
few people that I think can do,
but like I know for a fact
that I can't do it. All right.
It's so you can go to stoned.
You can definitely get two stone.
Especially if you eat something like
I fucked up at city walk and guy.
He gave me this fucking cookie. I was an
idiot. I was like, Hey, he's a nice guy.
I'll just take a cookie.
I would more,
I would've given you special gloves and
a fucking aluminum briefcase if I had
that cookie inside of,
if I knew how strong that cookie was,
I'd have that thing attached to electrodes
and if it moves to a gland goes off.
It was ridiculously strong
cause they make them with Hash,
they don't make them with weed so they,
these guys just go the professional
stoners, those assholes,
they want to get blitzkrieg.
They don't want to think about things.
They just want to get so high that
it's like an amusement park ride.
Like you just feel like you're in like
yeah. That's how I felt when I would,
when I did, Ralphie may gave
me a pot Brownie and I just,
this next thing I know I'm like I'm naked
watching Ph one celebrity rehab cause
I couldn't get porn.
So that's the closest I can get to it.
What have you been watching the camp
at this time?
I didn't have access.
I didn't have my computer with,
I hadn't had gotten a Mac at that time.
If a cell phone? No, this was like, oh,
three years ago I didn't have that.
You didn't have a cell phone? Yeah,
I didn't have a cell phone.
The mid videos,
I guess I had [inaudible] three years ago.
Calculator t three one
eight zero zero eight.
What does that boobies turn it
upside and shut the fuck up?
You fucking child.
You could draw a porn before I would
watch the celebrity reality. You Call
Jason? I don't like sex. Celebrity
Rehab. I like drug celebrity. Rhea.
Is there a sexual library where yeah,
there was. Who was on that one? Um,
they had a couple porn stars. Earl's?
Yeah. Is there any guys on that? Yeah,
there was a fill Verone was on that was
that he was a guy who was like, dude,
this is so funny. He's the drummer
of, uh, I forgot what the band is.
A camera. He was a drummer and some
eighties band and he get on there and he,
it's like he said he's addicted
to sex. Yeah. Poor guy.
But then the girls are talking and then
you can get addicted to anything. I know,
I know dudes who are so hung up on sex
that it's like they're not even horny and
they're trying to like keep racking up
scores. Yeah. It's like it consumes you.
I know guys whose careers
have been derailed because
there's such pussy hounds.
Yeah, that's true. Well it
becomes a massive distraction too.
Like if you have a lot of pressure,
you know you can distract yourself
with things like gambling,
addictions and stuff like
that where it's real.
What it really you're trying to do is
you're trying to avoid the pressure of
your career you're portraying to
avoid the, the hard work and all
the things that you really
need to get done. And you know,
I find myself like I have instant.
That's why the war of art
book is so fucking good.
If your rent it great book because
it deals with that deals with the
distractions and it, you know, calls it
resistance and that's really what it is,
man. You, you know, when, when
life gives you a lot of pressure,
people go towards something to
distract him from them. Yeah.
Cause they don't want to deal with it.
They don't want to think about it
so they get obsessed with something.
It could be pussy, it could be
gambling, the gambling end pussy,
it could be a drug thing.
I think some people are also afraid
to make it too in some weird way.
They don't want to,
they like,
they kind of just enjoyed the not having
the pressure of having to produce and
it kind of sabotage
themselves in a weird way.
Success is very hard and difficult.
I think a lot of people
sabotage themselves and are
afraid of success and those
are by the way,
the same people that are always talking
shit about other people that are
successful.
They're always like going after them
and pointing fingers at them and like,
you know,
I mean if you look at like anytime you
watch like you go to like TMZ or anytime
there's some celebrity story
and go look in the comments.
All the venom in the fight comments,
it was common.
Youtube is the worst. I
can't stand that shit. It's,
but I guarantee you that every single
person that it's fixating on Charlie Sheen
and you know whoever the fuck it is,
tiger woods, all the venom and venom,
those people are not paying this much
focus on their own life. They're just not.
If you're on youtube and you're getting
into a fucking three page flame war with
some other asshole that's
like Eh, you know, SRC seven,
seven on Prom,
you know that's his name and you're
going back and forth and you're trying to
win and that's is a distraction.
You're not thinking about
your life for it for sure.
There's some shit that
you need to get done.
There's some papers you need to fill
out or some bills you need to send in.
You're not doing everything you need
to do your, your, that's an addiction.
Just like anything else,
just like porn,
just so they can do whatever they
want because there's no repercussions.
Like there's no who's going to kick in
their door, in their mom's basement,
punch him in the face or say mean
shit they ever happened. He used to,
even when you sent an email or a letter,
rather, it had a return address. Right,
right. 100%. I remember one time, uh,
it was Kathy Griffin just
started hosting the, uh,
the New Year's Eve thing on CNN and she
was getting heckled and she said, well,
I'm coming to your job and kick the
dicks out of your mouth bump bump. Right.
Which is, you know, a thousand years old.
Jesus used that when he had a bad set.
You know what I'm saying?
I used that the last time I used that,
I shook my own head and I was like, what
the fuck did you do that? But anyways,
I'm just got to do it.
I went on Youtube,
I just want to see what the comments
were. And they're like, she's so fast.
She's so crazy. It's so fun. I
go, you guys, I mean, she's good,
but that's the like the oldest line. And
they just started coming at me, right.
And this one guy just started really
trying to give me, and I'm like,
who is this guy? And he's like, and
everyone's like, yeah. To him. Keep going.
I'm like, really? Yeah. So I go to
his page, all of his videos lit,
and this is a guy,
all of his videos are like high school
boys dancing around with no shirts on.
Right. And I go, whoa. And I go
back. I go, okay everybody, Eve,
you really cheered for him. Go and take
a look at all of his videos. I save boom.
Didn't hear from him again cause it
was like he actually got hit when he
normally could just say whatever he
wants. There's no repercussion. Right.
You've found his page was
is actually him. Yeah. Wow.
Wow.
Yeah.
People that when people are used
to being able to say something,
but getting a response to someone,
this is the first time ever you've been
able to just anonymously attack people
and then people start websites
about people and go after people.
People that don't even know
they have no, no. You know,
no real relationship with them. But they
fixate on them. Yeah, he got to let it go,
man. It's never easy. I get, and here's
the funny, the funniest comment is,
oh that's so gay.
Like you could do a video of,
you make an hour with the hottest chicken
world and there'll be some guy goes
video ever. It's like it's not gay. It's
like I'm making out with some chick.
What are you talking about? I get
murdered all the time on my Facebook page.
The worst is when someone puts a video
up for you that you can't control and so
the comments there and
you can't really like,
I don't mind if you say
I don't like to fixate.
Do you fix it and comments
and the [inaudible] I do
like to a while. It's nice,
they have a good point and be like,
you know what? That's a good point.
You can keep that up there. If they're
just saying some stupid ass shit,
I'll be like, ya'll either hit
them or delete the comment.
So you actually had gotten arguments with
these people on your like youtube page
and shit, you know once I want
you do? No, but I've seen it.
Have you seen him what it is on Facebook
or maybe it was a youtube or something
like that.
I still would go on Facebook one where I
got in a fight with a chick because she
called, I did a video called I love
black people. Oh, that was good. And I,
it's basically was a base off of when
we were in Canada and we didn't see any
black people. I'm like, you
know, I Ms. Black people.
So I decided to do a video called
I love black people. And I'm like,
and I would tell them I love black
people and we'd hug and I'd list all the
reasons I love them. And this girl's
like, you're so racist. I'm like,
the video's called,
I love black people.
I'm hugging Black Cape
Board around Hanky grades,
finding black people in hugging him.
That's how is that racist? Yeah.
And we just went made in the video after
we did that Canada to, yeah, yeah, yeah.
We went to weird parts of Canada too,
right?
We were like in grand prairie
and loved it is Saskatoon.
We were like way up there,
man.
Canadian girls are the white
versions of Mexican girls. Yeah.
That they're there. What do you mean
they're gray? Your nigger? Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, I'd love it. But
they're great in bed. They at,
they have this amazing ability to be
both a freakin bed and it like a good
girlfriend. You know what I'm saying?
Right. Like the white girls in America,
they can't, it's either one or the
other. What do you think that is?
You think that just were
repressed here and there?
Not because they don't have a much more
European sexual attitude in Canada,
especially Montreal. I think they
can have that though. Uh, yeah,
I think it is a little repression cause
if you talked to anybody, you're like,
you know,
where's the greatest groupies or this?
They'll always say like Utah because those
girls have like one shot at greatness,
if you know what I'm
saying. Oh really? So like,
I'm like bands say that like the
greatest groupies are in Utah. Yeah,
I like it that who told you that? Ah, I
was, I talked to a couple of porn stars.
I said were the craziest people.
They're like Mormons, Utah,
real gene Simmons said when he
ranked like we're the best groupies.
They said Utah. Wow. Yeah. I remember
when I did some with Vince Vaughn,
I went on a tour and we were on this bus
and it's the closest I'll ever get to
be in a beetle.
Right.
I just like driving this huge buzz and
people going crazy and we were driving
around and we just stopped somewhere and
this girl's walking with her boyfriend.
She just jumps on the bus and leaves
with us. He jumps in, his car,
falls us and I'm like, if
I doubt followed you. Yeah.
What would you do though? We
get rid of that bitch. Yeah,
no, I've seen that before.
I've seen,
I've been at shows where there's a guy
with a girl and the girl is just like got
her hands on my chest and asking me
where we're going after this show. Yeah.
And you want to just go,
go to the dude, dude, dude,
you got to get out of this relationship
man. This shit will rot your years.
Cause if you're a fucking dude, and
especially if she's hot. Oh yeah.
Fucking trapped.
I've met a lot of dudes that were like,
they really shouldn't be banging that
check. And all of a sudden they are,
and you know, and you're stuck in
someplace like some small town somewhere.
You know,
you're in Louisville,
Kentucky or something with this crazy
bitch and there's not a lot of, you know,
selection. Everybody wants to fuck her,
so you don't want to let her go. Yeah,
well that's the trap because you can
go into somewhere, you can go into,
some were killed in this
gorgeous girls coming on you.
She's not going to tell you they're
crazy as boyfriend's over there.
That's what happened to Mick young
when we had a, yeah, Mike Young though,
you can't really rely on his
stories whether I was there.
One is hang on a girl and a guy
beat him up. No, no, no, no, no, no.
This is what happened.
We were just walking around and he picks
up this chick asked her to come to our
show. She comes to show we're hanging out
the club. I'm not, this is true story.
Hey, out of the club, I go
down on the dance floor.
This dude just walks in the club,
just doesn't even say,
just walks up and just
fucking starts throwing bombs.
I'm Mike Young and all the sudden
I hear screaming, I look up,
Mike Young sends up, he's like triple. He
watches her face just bleeding. I'm like,
dude,
so I run up but I run this way.
The guy runs this way so I run
this way. See what's up. He's gone.
I couldn't even find him.
And then so the guy just ran up,
punched him a couple times and then
ran that. Just drop haymakers on them.
10 Mike had never spoken
to this guy. No War. No.
I saw the whole thing from the guy.
I know who Mike was cause
he knew who the girl was.
So Mike was sitting next to the girl.
So she just,
he just walked up and started blasting.
Yeah, that was his girlfriend.
That's Mike Young's Karma Bro.
Relative to that guy gets lethal dude,
that guy.
And that's the craziest thing.
I was dancing with some chick and he
got to take Mike on here by the way,
just cause we talked about
him so much and was like,
who the fuck is Mike Young Chick? I was
hooking up with Mike Young. How dare you,
he's friends with Leonardo Dicaprio.
My shot on entourage.
You ever hear that one? I'm watching.
All of a sudden it's like blah blah blah.
And Mike Young, I'm like, they did
not just say Mike Young name Larry.
That's hilarious. Some of his other
buddies. Right on that. So, um, so what,
what were just in the middle of
something? The Mike Young Ram. Yeah.
Yeah that's what happened to him
almost having to Rick Ingram too.
I heard that too. Like he's in Alaska
and he went to some bar with some chick
and uh,
they walk in the bar,
the girl's boyfriend's there and her
boyfriend's friend just surrounding me was
like, I didn't know. Boom, I'm
gone. And that's the biggest thing.
It's due to get mad at other dudes because
of their girlfriends. A whore. Well,
Jesus Christ, that is the dumbest
shit ever. Like, listen man,
if your girl is a good girl,
if she was down with you,
she would not be here with Mike Young.
You fuck just give up. You do it.
No problem. You just got an emotional
issue that you need to fucking sort out.
You're not good enough to get a good
girl. You fuck, he's crazy. So anyways,
I'm like, Mike, this
chick knows that dude.
There's no reason that guy would come
up to you and just start blasting you.
And she's like, I didn't know him.
And then we just kept prodding.
Here's how crazy Mike youngest just guys
buck kicked for hanging out with a hot
chick.
I'm sitting in the Er of the hospital in
walks the hottest blonde I've ever seen
in my life. She's like,
where's Mike Young? I'm like,
you're gotta be kidding me dude.
He's guy, girl. Meet him at the Er.
She was so hot.
Why would he have a girl meet him at the
Er cus she's hot and I might get a scum
bag. I'm like, I wonder if I can
bang this chick at the hospital.
Steal her from like,
I mean,
I just wanted to hit it like I want to
cross it off my list. Oh, that's funny.
Would Mike Young be pissed?
I think he had bigger problems at that.
His face is they're putting it together
like Mr Potato head at that point. Yeah.
Came back. Better looking. That's just
a guy like John likes girls. He does.
I wanted to do this whole a show where
I take like Mike Young, Brian Kaylin,
uh,
Steve Byrne and Sergio love and then Mike
Black and we go on a tour and it's who
can tap the most ass. But once you
get an STD, you're off the show.
Brian Cowan is married and he doesn't
do that anymore. No, I know that I'm,
this was years ago, that store off
that show. Okay. I'm taking them off.
Let me put it online.
That's not fair because he's going to,
he would beat all of them.
No, he wouldn't. Yeah, that's
the whole thing at the end.
It's Mike Black [inaudible]
who would just fuck anything.
He'll just take the other ones.
It's the right place.
Some cheetahs only get to to eat what
they can catch when the leopards and
hyenas aren't around. Right.
That's just how it goes. You know,
if a cheetah take something down,
the hyenas go,
I'll take that bitch and they come in and
the cheetahs have to run away was just,
I have no problems with that part of
the game. I have no problems of that.
Is Mike blacks parents have photos of
themselves on this? That'd be hilarious.
That would be you go to it like there.
How does,
I mean my black is a comic that does.
I'd known for always having a
photo of himself on his shirt.
Every time you see him for years,
he wears the exact same shirt. Oh,
picture of himself on. Okay, so your
sensor, do his parents are the same crime.
He so devoted to the fuck. Would they
know what you're talking about? Yeah. Why?
Just explain it. You had to,
you get stuck. Mike Young books,
a bunch of commercials are, he's on
fire right now. A commercial art.
He's always doing commercials.
He's become more successful for
commercials and anything else.
He is a such a good actor.
He booked a subway commercial.
Doesn't look like in any way he'd ever
do work at subway unless he was like
their accountant.
You know what I'm saying?
Like he does not look like he's making
like sandwiches or some shit like that.
He doesn't do you,
does he look like a fast food employee?
The you really pull it off.
Yeah. Where's the homeless look?
He's got that. He's got one of
those. I could be anywhere. Looks,
I've never seen a a fast food employee
cause we live in Los Angeles and they're
all Mexican. Yeah, that's
what we were saying.
I just want to kill like Indian
casinos, brother. Really?
I'm the champ of the Indian cause
you do a lot of Indian cuisine.
I love them too. They're like the new
cat skills. You know what I'm saying?
Just you're just rocking India.
I just did my first two hour
set and you did two hours.
Where in Oklahoma, man, I did this
place called the Fire Lake. Best time.
The people that are so cool.
Really? And I'm like, oh
dude, it's the funniest thing.
I love going in the places and I just
start interviewing people because I just
like to get to know,
like,
it's almost like quantum leap where you
like jump in somewhere and you're like,
okay, what are the rules of
this place? What's going on?
How am I going to solve this problem?
So I just start interviewing
people and I'm like,
so you guys got any Mexicans here?
He's like, Eh, down south, you know,
a little father down south and
this is true. I go, how about Jews?
You got any juice? He's like,
oh, we don't do that here.
I'm like, what? How? He goes,
Whoa, we don't do that here. Wow.
And he starts telling me how,
like he's had the Klan knock on his
door and give him applications to join.
He's like, I won't do a shit
ton. I'm asking if you ever
hook up with the Mexican.
He's like, oh, no, no, no. I'm like, how
black chick? Not My family would hate me.
I'm like, really? It's 2011 wow.
You're not banging fucking minorities.
I love that shit.
[inaudible] Blake Griffin style.
You know what I'm saying?
That's pretty crazy that they do that, but
nicest crowd, two hours, just crushing.
Wow. Here's another joke. I'm
done. Why Pat? Pat? Bam. So yeah,
you think now because of the Internet
will obviously these people aren't the
coolest if they're talking
all this crazy racist shit,
but do you think that they'll use
a nice guy though? I mean like,
I know that sounds nuts. Well he wasn't.
He's just, he's stuck in this. Yes.
I think it's, yeah. Hmm.
That's an interesting argument,
but I think if you're
connected to the Internet,
and this was what going to be my point,
at a certain point in time,
you realize like,
you know,
you can find the right information and
the right people to hang out with and
people can get access to information in
places where they never could before.
Like if you were stuck in some small
town in Oklahoma back in the day,
that's where your environment, that's like
those, that's how you grew up. You know?
I mean you had to get the fuck out of
there and go to college in New York or
something to really break out of it.
Right. 100 but a lot of people did,
but now you don't because
of the Internet you're,
you're always getting access to all
kinds of shit online. Like look,
my message board, Twitter, all kinds of
shit. There's always new information,
new intelligent discussions, maybe
discussions you can't have in your town,
but you can have them on, on, you know,
on a message board. You go for it,
you go, you searched his
stuff. I find that people,
most people don't want to do that
and I think most of the damage gets,
everyone hates Fox News
and all that stuff.
I really think like most of the damage
in terms of misinformation is done on the
local news level. Have you ever
watched local news is it's brutal,
crazy Google stuff that
they're saying you're like,
that is so far from the truth, but
nobody has any, they don't know that.
I watched this one on marijuana,
this local new show that
were talking about marijuana.
This is new strain of marijuana.
Like it's like it's so
strong it's actually causing
people to go insane and they
were like real serious and reading
their notes and I was like,
why you can't just say that.
It's information and the local level.
That's where it was.
The other thing it said and possibly could
be deadly like constantly like in the
realm of the only way we
can be deadly as if someone,
he ties together some like 50 pound
bundles and throws him out of one of those
fucking drug plans and they land on
your head. That's the only way we'd,
his deadline,
unless it's some kind of,
we were there that was deadly about is
there stuff added to it like you know
like where people put cocaine on weed,
why people did it.
When you can do to be so strong you think
you might die. I've been there like,
oh dude,
this is it.
I got Chris Mcguire high once and he
swore that it was, it was, he was laced.
He didn't know. He had never had some
of that real strong California medical.
We'd especially like a see a real
strong sativa. Most guys like,
well people don't know is you know, most
of the weedy get all across the country.
If you're not in a medical program,
you're usually getting into,
cause it's easier and cheaper to grow.
But the sativa is a totally different
kind of high and when you give it to
someone like choir, it's not
just Chris regards, a very
funny comic, but he's just,
he doesn't get stoned a lot.
And we got him baked one night in the
back area of the comedy store and we were
a blitzkrieg so it was
me and him and Joe Diaz.
So he's trying to keep up with me and
Joe does keep up with Joe does, you know?
And that he was convinced.
It was convinced.
He was convinced he was on some drugs.
Now there's something in this,
something in this. I'm like, yeah,
it's called good. We'd sign. Yeah,
that sounds like a girl before too. It
sounds like a girl who liked d gets drunk,
does some stuff in the next day. It's
like, oh, I wouldn't have done it.
Someone had to slip me something.
No, you guys got a little crazy.
You know what I think it is?
A lot of people use their bowls like
especially when you're out in a place and
you're like, you want to hit
this and you're like, okay,
but what they don't tell you is like,
oh last night I smoked
hash and that you know,
and there's Hash and that bowl or cause
I smoked a hit off of somebody the other
day and it tastes like
Poper read and attune to.
That reminds me of like when I
used to smoke opium and I'm like,
that tastes like opium. And I wonder
if this guy had opiate and that bowl.
You've flats. Whoa, you were smoking
opium like fucking Wyatt Earp and shit.
Chinese 10 like what was that?
How is that high opium and it
was pretty sweet. It was mellow.
Just mellow. Hi Character. I
mean that's basically heroin man.
It's fucking see babies crawling
on the ceiling or anything.
Well you don't see that on heroin, right?
Heroin is on a hallucinogen heroin.
I don't like needles. I
don't think so. The movie.
Trainspotting was all
about the hallucinogens.
It depends on how long you've been doing
it. You know, it's like if you do math,
you're not going to be like terror,
you know, painting the House.
But if you do it like for
like two weeks straight,
you're probably gonna think
your house needs to get painted.
I thought for sure heroin was Eddie Bravo
always dated a bunch of pitches that
were hooked on speed and he used to tell
me that like he had like
all these like rules,
like how you could tell
when chicks your date,
we're on speed and one of them was,
their fucking house is spotless,
their house is spotless and they're
always cleaning and like these pitchers
never eat and they're always tough.
They're never tired who never eating
and they never tired. And he was like,
the best thing about them is that you
could fuck them in the ass because there
was never any poop in there.
That's hilarious.
That sounds like survival guide.
The banging meth heads.
That's hilarious dude.
I always taught the sham wow guy was on
math because if you ever listened to the
commercial,
he's always like,
well how would you spend it on cleaning
supplies month? They're like 60 $70.
It's like who's doing that much cleaning
pro? Unless your meth out of your mind.
He's definitely doing something cause
he had a fight with a prostitute with a
prostitute, bit his tongue. So
he tongue kissing a prostitute.
She bit down on his tongue and
he punched her in the face.
Is that new movie that came out?
It's going to move in. Yeah.
He's like producing movies now. And how
much money do you make off that channel?
Millions.
He actually did that old movie that
the New York Times gave zero stars too.
You ever hear about what someone was
like Bobby, Leonid and wheels per Reezy.
Do you remember that movie? Didn't
they make that in Mexico? Yeah,
it's like Joe Dns.
We're supposed to be on that movie.
But something happened like there were,
there were supposed to send him like
money in advance or something like that
cause he thought it was shady and
he didn't go. That's the sham. Wow.
Guy made this. But that's funny because
the new one has like Lindsay Lohan,
there's a part in it and stuff like
that. Well guys, maybe she was high.
Where's Lindsey?
But the movie like cracked out Lindsey
Cause I got a shot with cracked out
Lindsey. Jesus Freak Lindsay,
she's thanking us for mine,
was banging her buddy of mine who's in
a band. It was a really crazy story man.
He was a real good dude man.
And um,
I've never seen anybody get hooked on
drugs more clearly. Like, you know,
like you hang out with someone once and
then you see them again like six months
later.
Like I hung out with him once and he was
like super cool and friendly and happy
and he'd been really doing a lot of
yoga and he's like, man, you know,
I just found out when I exercise,
like you're going to think clearer.
I'm really into that lately.
And I kinda like just cut way back in
the party and I don't know what the fuck
happened to him,
but then I saw him six months later and
he was like trying to sell me a stereo
or something. Yeah, just jacked
out and shaking. And it was,
it was warm out,
but this mother fucker was freezing and
he was like covering himself with his
jacket. What? He was talking to me and
it was like so horrible. It was like, I,
I watched it like a dude who had gotten a,
you know, he's like, he's been infected.
She by the Stereo. No, no sir. I
love disc cracked discounts, Bro.
I had a fat TV for awhile, for 20 bucks.
Was Real kid sold it to me. I'm like,
you're moving right? Oh yeah.
Yeah. I'm moving. I got a
it, but I'm like, okay, cool.
Any Bucks? Nice television. It's that
amazing that they need it so bad.
They're willing to give you a TV for 20
bucks. What is that evolutionary step?
The fuck is, I don't give a shit. Is
it stolen? It might be there as bro.
A lot of people before
they start stealing,
they start selling their own shit really
cheap because that's the only shit.
I mean if they can,
if it's different than you waiting six
hours of getting 200 bucks or selling it
right now and getting 20 and
then getting high right away.
A lot of guys will just take that 20 yeah.
I don't know if its evolution.
I just think people,
we've gotten so away
from our primal roles.
Do you know what I'm saying?
That people are Borden.
I mean they don't know what to do with
themselves because we're, you know,
it's back to where I'm meant to
be hunting. They're meant to be.
Women are meant to be raising babies and
you know the way I've always described
it as that we have this ancient hardware,
these ancient bodies that are you still
like a certain amount that we need a
certain amount of input.
We're designed to like,
like the reason why people need
human touch. We need camaraderie.
Like if you don't have human touch,
it doesn't seem like you should.
That should like 100% of babies
can die if human 100% Oh,
I mean it's like it's a real needy. The
Emmys, it's a need. It's not, you know,
so where did that evolve from?
Will that evolve from the fact that we
need to stay together as tribes and this
is the way we bond together.
Like we literally need each other and if
we're separated from each other for any
long lengths of time, we feel
terrible. I don't get sick.
You never read a book called, why do
beautiful people have more daughters?
I think I might talk to you about that.
They talk about how like human beings,
we're still wired like cavemen,
we have very primal drives inside us.
And then he,
they say it takes 10,000 years for some
thing to either leave us or a new way of
thinking. It takes that long to
cycle out. It makes sense. I mean,
how else could it do it quickly? But the
world is changing so fast that, you know,
I mean it's,
it's just,
it's a completely different
environment than 10,000 years ago.
Every single aspect of it
from gathering food. You know,
I was thinking about this the other day.
I pulled into a Wendy's.
I was hungry and I've got a cheeseburger
and I'm sitting there in my car,
he and his cheeseburger. I'm like,
how did I get meat so quick? You know,
literally like it was a minute between
the time that I talked in this speaker to
the time I'm biting down his cheeseburger.
It was one minute.
It was so god damn fast. I pulled up, I
gave him the money to God gave me a bag.
I'm like, really? This is it.
And then I sit there and I'm eating
this cheeseburger and then I'm like,
this is so I want some Wendy's.
I want to be amazed by fast
food that's being baked.
But I was thinking,
it's so incredible that I have a piece
of a dead animal that's cooked already
and it's in my mouth and it's
one crazy, right? I mean,
it's fast food is really
a motherfucker because we,
we all these other things
that we think are important,
like we've got to rush around
and get this and get that done.
That's not really what's important.
What's important is sustenance.
You have to be able to feed yourself.
You've got to be able to clothe yourself.
You've got to have loved ones around.
You got to have a good time.
That's what's really important,
but all of it's fucking shit.
I've got a meeting at five and I got to
get here and I got to make this happen.
The meeting meeting is going to make
sure that my career moves forward in a
certain direction.
Then I'm going to work more hours and
I don't have time for food, you know?
But Shit, man, what are you doing
this for? Like where's this going?
What happens at the end?
You get up fucking bag of gold and you
get to run off to Leprechaun land or yeah,
we'll just get a fucking
heart attack and and shit.
Your pants and your bed while you're
clutching onto your chest. You know,
you die in a puddle of your own diarrhea.
Would a fucking busted open heart
raising because you've been,
because you've been on a diet,
pill, fucking freight train. That was
my diarrhea sound. That was the sound.
That was great with the heart
attack sound. What was it?
Hard tax.
So how do you make a hard
Brian still rocking the cigarettes, man.
He was, are you talking about health?
I smoke cigarettes because my
grandpa's smoked cigarettes forever.
Yeah, I need my, my
grandpa like cigarettes,
but he smoked pipe tobacco like out
of pipes are actually good for you.
It's done. Bam. Oh yeah. But it's not a
huge blow out. More smoking a cigarette,
but you don't inhale that. You
don't inhale, that doesn't fuck.
Your lungs are amazed when
I hear people still smoke.
It just blows my mind because the
backhoe in medical doesn't taste good.
What is he? Yeah, well tobacco
is actually been shown medically.
Nicotine rather has been shown medically
to actually have a beneficial aid to a
lot of different things. You know,
nicotine is actually not that bad for you,
especially in like small doses.
Nicotine is not what's really dangerous.
What's really dangerous as probably the
509 on the additives in cigarettes and
they're designed to make you remember that
Russell Crowe movie the insider. Yeah.
Went over all the shit that date,
that carbon dioxide to right.
It's not good for either being anything.
Smoke is bad and that's why we're
hitting the vaporizer. Right, right.
I feel way better after
using the vaporizer. Then
I'd do smoking joints stoned.
Really? Yeah. I don't feel stoned at
all right now let's go back in there.
So that's what I'm saying. I just seems
like vaporizers to me, for the most part,
it's waste. We'd like that much
weed that you put in there.
You could have had a joint and we
got all been fucking blown out.
It's a health thing. That's the
reason why it's there. I mean,
if you have a joint a day, who gives
a fuck, that's not that bad for you.
If you're doing Joey Diaz tight smoking
where you're just nonstop joints or
against bad. Yeah. But Joe
d is self medicating you.
You guys talk amongst yourself.
Want to get some weed?
So Sam you have the 90 showed them
morrow right at the end of frog.
Very excited about it. Um, who's
Doug Benson is on it right then sin.
Jenna Hays. Joe Hays is nice. Yeah
we got some fun people coming down.
Jeff Richards going to be playing drunk
girl. No Way. That's kind of cool.
I actually,
that was one of the few characters from
the old Saturday night lights I used to
actually enjoy watching was Jeff.
Richard says the drunk girl but now he's,
that's considered old super blue dream
lesion. Gentlemen, soother blue dream.
Ari's a full on a stoner now.
I,
I guess I didn't realize on
tour with them I'm like wow.
When I first moved out to California,
Dunkin in Ra were like my two first
friends and we would like always like film
videos. Like Duncan was always trying
to be famous with his little Hobo,
a video guy. So it would make
little videos for him. And,
and one time I got stoned in Ari's like
didn't smoke weed. And I was like, dude,
just smoke it. This is actually the
shittiest weed you could possibly buy.
Meanwhile, it's like the, it
was the best we'd ever, I just,
so he fills up the bond grind.
I know. Well, you know, it's
just like you, you, you,
you hang out with comics
that you will benefit from
wheat and you're like, dude, come on.
You will, you'll like this. Chill out.
You need to take it. I'm going to push
us. So anyways, he fills the bong up,
fucking coughs a long out fucking
crazy stone. And then he goes,
oh, you're gonna need to tell people
why that makes you crazy stones. Uh,
because it opens up your,
supposedly when you cough,
it opens up the air or in
the blood vessels in your
lungs that makes more THC go
into your grinding.
The marijuana to put it inside of
the label was your fancy grinders.
You cough when you cough, you get
off. Where's your fancy grinder, Joe?
Where's that tee shirt? Uh, so anyways,
but what's crazy is after he did all this,
I thought he was hanging out
for a while. He goes, damn,
I'm away for my audition
or something like that.
I got a jet and I lived in Calabasas
and he was going to Hollywood,
which is like a good 30 minutes away.
And so I supposedly, he was so stoned,
he was driving like so
slow on the highway.
He was sitting at green light's not
knowing to go. He was fucked up.
That's why like most times when you
talk to people, like, yeah, I got,
I got high once. It really didn't feel
that because you're always really light.
Oh, just a little hit. Just a little
hit. Make them go for it. Yeah.
Now he's smokes 80 times more than me.
You know,
like I'm one of those guys that I'll take
a good one or two hits here and there
during the day when I'm
working or doing something. Uh,
but he's one of those guys that just
wakes up and smokes and eats and just
everything we'd nonstop
now he loves the weed.
I just can't I I get
paranoid a little bit. Yeah.
Well you should be paranoid,
bitch.
I stopped and I haven't been
getting paranoid anymore.
I don't know if that's just over.
It's called not.
Yeah, so tomorrow night's naughty
should every night about. Dude,
if you've never seen it before,
it's not just a comedy show.
It's a comedy show with a
bunch of sketches and all
kinds of other crazy shit.
You still tossing my fucking my boy.
Brian is Exxon stage.
She hasn't done, she hasn't been
thought she did a something in Vegas.
He's bang more girls in my show than I
have. I've banked none. He's bankable.
That's good for you.
That shows your character and
your dedication to a fine show.
Someone needs to pick this fucking show
up. Vegas people, you people at the palms,
you want it. You want to show, look at
a brain picker. Land over at hard rock.
You people to hard rock. Fuck the
palms. I wouldn't say fuck the pumps.
I love the poms. Poms is
cool man. It's cool too.
Why do you want to do the
hardrock and other pumps?
Because courts at the palms and that's
his house and he's my friend and I would
never do anything wrong to have a way.
What the fuck?
That's more of a party anyway. You
remember that? Used to have that.
Have you been by the cosmetology
cosmopolitan? Is that what's causing that?
It's the new hotel dude. It is nuts.
I couldn't believe. I'm like, wow,
this is crazy. Yeah, it will be the next
weekend. Next weekend is a Mandalay bay.
I'm so jealous you guys down on
down. I like to come watch, man.
I liked that weekend, dude. That's
going to be such a great Jon Jones.
Six Oh seven brother. That's my home
area cough. Hello. Hello. It's actually,
he's Binghamton. I'm Cortland.
We're just outside Syracuse man.
Six Oh seven says you. Do you feel
like you're, he's representing. Yeah.
All do I get so I get such pride that
Armenians and Fred's a great fight.
That's going to be a good fight.
It seders very dangerous.
Anderson Silva is going to be a good fight
to Anderson Silva versus [inaudible].
But he changed like training. Pardon?
Uh, training. Uh, Anderson did? No.
A Belford I read changes. A training
manager? No, no, no, no, no. He just,
he had, Sean Tompkins was
one of his striking coaches
and he worked with him for,
he's been working on for a while.
He stopped going with him and
he's working with Ray Sefo now.
That shit to race sophos a US
a bad motherfucker. I'm sure.
I just get worried when he
started changing trainers.
Raped beef like a week before the
fight. That's kind of weird. Or not.
How many weeks has been, I dunno,
I'm excited for that fight.
I like both those guys man.
And they're both those guys that get in
the octagon and have that like that like
worldclass scare you like factor,
you know, you're like, oh man,
look who's across the way. He talks so
fast, man. He, he could catch anybody,
you know, but Anderson so smart and so
technical, you know, it's like, you know,
a lot of people are saying,
well Anderson had a problem with
shell son and stand up. Totally true.
But I don't think he
was anticipated as much.
I think he was anticipating child to
try to take him down. Whereas with Vito,
he's definitely going to be
thinking about vittores standup.
It's a very interesting fight.
I can't wait man. I can't wait.
It's like finally selling is not
intimidated. They're both intimidators.
I think that's a big thing and it sees,
I mean to be that successful in
the octagon is crazy for that long.
Since 2006 you're going to have to do your
own UFC drunk crass at night. Ah, yeah.
Brian's going to be there live you guys,
by the way.
The nightly show podcast number two is
now up on iTunes. Thank you. I'm good.
Good, good. Maybe just take
one hit. Donk can trust him.
That was a fake hit like a girl.
That was it.
But now he's like, girl, what
a girl is known for fake kits.
What about that even mean?
I don't even know.
So I was reading online and some people
were upset at you because of that.
You got to kick out of a girl calling
you a nigger. Can you believe that?
They're mad at me.
Why did they think it's racist?
They don't understand context and they
don't understand that you have opened
yourself up and you're communicating
with all these folks online.
Honestly as if they were friends.
We see we are all friends here and we've
been friends for many years and you're
treating us and you're treating these
people online the same as the same as you
trying to free them. That's
what I'm doing. I'm like,
cause I feel like sex is like the
thing that defines you the most.
And sometimes if you're in a weird shit
you like hide it and that's how you know,
you end up hanging yourself in a fucking
closet. You know what I'm saying?
Jerking off.
Well people think to something,
there's something wrong with you
because you liked that and that's,
that's a strange thing, man, that did.
Someone would judge you for liking that.
I don't care man. You know, not saying
not a racist at all. I mean I'm not,
I love people.
I've known Sam for more than a decade
and he's never showed any prejudice
towards anything. I love that.
Or women or gays or you know
everybody on an individual
basis. Absolutely. You.
You are 100% across the board like that,
but you know there's something about
you that likes naughty shit. Yeah,
I mean that's why you have this show
called the naughty show them a little
messed up. If you're banging a
chicken, she's calling you a nigger.
It's like there's something about that.
It's like dude, you know what I'm saying?
Cause it's like tab boo man.
That's what everybody liked.
People on liars such fucking knuckleheads.
If for whatever reason they're turned
off by this late don't understood way to
alienate a crowd, you know good
way to alienate your audience.
Like what are you saying by being honest,
he's not calling people
niggers in matter of fact,
he's not even calling the girl that
he's banging. Yeah, I'm getting called.
He's getting called it dude. Have you ever
been called the n word by a black guy?
It's the greatest feeling ever.
I loved that.
He goes all use use it. You Ain't white
homie use Armenian. You's a Nigga.
I was like oh those you're
going to find out someday Homie,
you Nigga Yo Nigga Yo Nigga would
whiter skin. Okay. Yo Nigga,
it's just so interesting. Like
racism used to be Joe. Ah,
you can't go here. You can't do this.
You can't date them. You can't work here.
You can't eat here right now.
It's like,
could you don't agree with the context
of the joke? It's a racist joke. It's,
there's nothing race.
Nobody's being held back.
No one's being forced into something.
It's true.
It's the slippery slope because for
awhile there you couldn't question it.
It's so good. You're racist. You're like,
okay, hey dude, dude, let's not get crazy.
It's like 1989 slash 90 week
girls will say, you hate
women. Yeah. You know, if you,
if you think there are cons like you hate
women, Brian posted is the best line.
He goes, cause a girl actually said
that to him. He goes, yeah, you know,
here's a funny thing. Every girl
had said that to me. I hate. Yeah,
that's a great line.
It's a great line like the idea that
you stand for everyone with a vagina.
That's completely ridiculous because
we're in an argument and I disagree with
you. All of a sudden I have issues with
all women now that's like a, a weakening,
it's a trick that they use on you to like
to try to get you to submit and it's,
it's about trying to stop the conversation
because they have no more get the
label. You're a racist.
That's what racism used to be.
If I called you racist like 10 years
ago, that was the death blow. Hey,
settle down Bob. No, Hey, that's how
long, just gender, race all like, c'mon,
let's not get crazy. It's like, Whoa,
you're getting good. Putting a labels.
It's a funny thing man. I, you know, I
have joke about it like that. You know,
I never said the word nigger unless
I'm on stage or unless I know for sure
there's no white people around, but I
don't, I don't say it like, like, hey,
there's a bunch of niggers.
I say it like your friend walks up,
there's no white people. Be like, what's
up? Yeah. You give each other a pound.
And it's also so interesting how the rule
applies to like who to applies to who
doesn't apply to like I've heard comedians
all the time yet saying the n word on
stage.
No,
I've heard white guy saying
only if they're using it
in like saying that someone
said it. Like I saw Norton this weekend
and he was doing a bit on Mel Gibson.
Hilarious. By the way. Jim
Norton was fucking, he's very
fun. He was hilarious dude.
I laughed hard. It was the first
time that I had got the scene,
like a guide do like a real
headline set in a long time. Anyway,
he was doing a thing about
Mel Gibson where he was, you
know, saying the word, you know,
like Meg's Mel Gibson say I hope
you get raped by a pack of niggers.
And you know, it was, it was really funny,
but he had to say that word because it
was in that contract he was in. This is,
he's repeating what Mel gives said.
So if he said the n word,
it would have sounded awkward,
you know. So Mel Gibson said,
I hope you get attacked
by a pack of Edwards. No.
[inaudible] just going to repeat what
he said. Right. You have to say it.
I always felt Mel Gibson wasn't,
it didn't mean it in a racist kind of way.
He just meant he's in a interracial
Gangbang porn and he just want to see his
girl get gang by black guys. He's
an asshole. No, he is an asshole.
He is an ass and I'm calling, you know,
it's a different, when I was at and I got,
people gave me shit about that joke,
like about even saying it in that joke
in saying that I would call my friend and
Nigger, but I would say that I would
never do it. There's black people around.
Like I don't want black
people to get offended.
I don't want anybody's feelings to
be hurt by the words that I say,
but what's so what's so?
Isn't it supposed to be all about intense?
I don't get why people want to keep
taking things away. I understand.
Why hates we have jobs bro.
And they have to work and when people
have to work and you're in that sort of
environment where everybody's like super
proper and you can't say certain things
and they want to keep
taking more things away,
you know it's like it used to be
able to call retards in the office.
I'm sure you spell,
it'd be if you work,
if you're like a boss and you have a
bunch of employees and you start throwing
around the word retard and
this fucking dope, you know,
you start talking like that or you can
get sued. Yeah, 100% sue you and they'll,
they'll like, you know, you,
you'll have to like pay out your employees
because you're subjecting them to
like Erin stand that.
But like in terms of art,
like art is meant to stimulate, whether
it's positive or negative. It's you.
Is that true though? I mean, yeah, this
is expression, right? It's expression.
It's an expression.
And if someone would like violently
disagrees with your expression,
they violently violently disagree with
the thought behind it. So it feels like,
you know,
if you have a racist bit and it's clearly
a real racist bit and even though you
think it's really funny and a lot of
racist people think it's really funny.
For some people it'll be like, whoa,
Whoa, Whoa, like this is a bad expression.
I want to stop this right where it is.
Right. I see what you're doing here.
I totally agree with that. But I
mean personally meant I love America.
I love like the southern cal is the
greatest thing because there's so much
diversity here. There's lot more
else should go. There's nothing,
and I know there's like part of England
and France and Germany are very diverse,
but no one has the Latin American like
population that we have and it's like
that's what makes America amazing.
And then you go to somewhere like
Canada where it's all white people.
It's like just a weird kind of like,
but they're also super fun and friendly
and know they are, they are crime.
They are like, you know,
it's like what do you want?
You want all the flavor and the crime
or do you want like less flavor?
Nice people? It's a tricky
thing. I mean a lot of,
that's why a lot of people have moved to
Colorado after they live in California
as well. One of the reasons why I did it
was like people are different. They're,
they're a little more relaxed,
there's less crime is less bullshit
as well as angst. You know,
I liked the diversity. I
like it too, but I don't,
I don't like all the goddamn traffic.
And now that is one thing.
But I like diversity.
I like different,
I like how everybody's different.
So used to it now. Like I, at
first it was kind of scary I guess.
Cause I mean it really
is like where I live,
I'm one white person on a block almost,
you know, just everywhere I look it's,
you know, not white people. So
at first it was kind of scary,
but now it's like if you feel used to
it almost like it feels like, oh no, no,
I'm kind of Mexican.
Oh he's great.
You can get in with it.
Like a Armenian taxi driver take you
to a hip hop club to dance to hip hop,
stop the diversity. That's the
problem. It's the overpopulation.
It's too many people.
And when you have too many people,
for sure there's going to be a bunch
of crime. It's just the way it is.
So there's only so many resources and
some people got to take resources that
aren't readily available. Well there's
that. Yeah. And then there's also just,
this is all going to be in more bad apples
cause there's more humans. You know,
if one person out of a million is doing
fucked up shit that's gonna make the
news. And there was no one I haven't heard
anymore. If you make it to the party,
you can stay at the party.
You know what I'm saying?
You can't fix them and you can't kill him.
So what do you got to do?
You've got to lock them in boxes.
I also think that, you know,
I mean in terms of racism,
I think there's something about,
and you seen in la La is like people
like to believe there's some shadow group
out there holding them down. You
know, and that's across the board.
Like there's some people who like to
act like it's 1950s and like they're
oppressed.
And I'm not saying one certain group,
but you see certain people saying that
like female comics make me laugh because
they're always talking about how
hard is it to be a female comic.
But usually they're,
what they're bitching about is the
same thing male comics have to do.
I think it's harder to be a chick
man. I think it is to, I don't,
I think you move very quickly. I
think, I think there used to be,
but now you see these girls who are,
who are hitting quicker and they're,
they're learning comedy on the fly.
If they kind of a ratio,
it gets success before they get success
in signed up. They get TV success. Yeah.
They get everything. So the alert
they're making, they're having a career,
why they're learning. So I think
like it's in that sense it's, I,
I think if you show a
little bit of like skill,
you get moved up quicker in my opinion.
Well I think they're looking for
funny checks because they're so rare.
So when you see one,
they're so rare that that's why you think
that they get moved up quicker because
there's guys that are getting moved up
at the same rate, but there's more guys.
So it's like, you know, it's, it's, it's,
it's harder for each individual guy,
but for, I think it's the same amount
of chicks get success as gods and it's,
I think it's harder.
I think their subject matters limited.
They can't talk anything about politics.
I don't wanna hear politics
out of some chick's mouth.
The fuck you to be running
this country. Ochre, you know,
guys will hear a woman talk about politics
and instinctually want to think the
opposite.
They want to like calm cause they're
trying to combat this woman from taking
over. Like it's like natural tribal monkey
instincts that you have to suppress in
order to let a woman talk.
So you've got this woman who's
talking and she's on an onstage,
in front of a crowd with a microphone
and a spotlight and you're a man,
you're a man and she's
commanded the attention.
Well just your caveman instincts are like,
there's something wrong with this dynamic.
I don't know man.
I just like some like a Lisa Lampanelli
feel that she's able to say things
because of how she looks and who
she is and she's, no Diaz isn't.
It's the same thing man. People suddenly
people can rock it harder. You know why?
Because they're ugly.
Right?
Or there's something that's a weapon when
you're a comic being ugly and fat and
fucked up is a weapon.
You know you use that shit like this
motherfucker's funny already. Why?
Because in real life we've
come to associate ugly fat,
fucked up people with the guys
who were the most reckless.
They say the craziest shit. They're the
ones who get hammered probably fine.
Right?
Probably not develop a good personality
cause chicks worn into him cause he had
a gut. You know those guys are,
a lot of times they have them.
More comedy comes from because
it's a defense mechanism.
But for what I'm saying is for a
woman who's a normal looking woman,
you're a normal looking man, you
know, a normal looking woman.
I think it's harder for her than it is
for you to go onstage and to, I don't,
I think it's harder for them. I think
their subject matters more limited,
especially if it's a regular looking girl.
Like there's a lot more dirty
girl comics now that are good.
I think because of Sarah Silverman,
like they saw that she had,
she was successful and then there's
a lot of pervert chicks out there,
but they were like holding
that back. Right. You know?
And so now I think they recognize
that that's a viable option and people
actually like it.
They like that kind of common for
funerals except that cause it's paradigms.
That's my opinion. But it'd be like it
dirty. They're like, Oh man, you know,
all great frat boy comedy. If a girl gets
dirty, it girls are almost like, yeah,
you're representing us because if it's
not dumb. I think Sarah was the first.
Sarah. Sylvan was the first like
really good female. Very, very funny.
She's really, rivers was
phenomenal. She was good. I mean,
when she was not dirty like Sarah
Silverman though. Sarah Silvermans brutal.
I mean, maybe Joan Rivers
is Saucy, you know?
But Sarah Silverman tags love taking
shits and elevators and then she's fucking
funny man. And then leave rock. Nellie
came through and she's really dirty too.
Yeah, there's, there's,
there's many more of those now,
but I think Sarah was like the
first one that was like really good.
Chandler does Chelsea, she's,
she's a party girl. You know,
she's like more acceptable. Yeah.
That's all I'm trying to say.
I'm just saying it's still harder for
the chick, man. It's harder to beat.
You're more nervous. You have no physical
confidence. Here's another thing, man. I,
you know,
it's like,
and then recently it was a leaving the
Improv and I saw this female comic who
used to just get blackout crazy
drunk at the comedy store.
I remember name by used to watch it
go and that girl is a train wreck.
I walked by, I see her, she's like, hey.
I'm like, Hey, what's up? She's like,
got married and then he's
driving this fat Lexus Suv,
so I always feel like as a female comic
you have an out, you have a backup plan,
my backup plan file,
make case valley on me.
You can't find some gay guy and
suck his dick. You know? Listen Bro,
you could find some sugar mama if she's
got some ugly dude that she's banging,
you can find some ugly chick divorced
if you really want to do that,
you could do that,
but how many girls want to be under
the control of some math for money?
You're saying that that it's
like a viable option that would,
well if you're going to drop the standards
that low and assume that women will
do that and get married
to some do just for money,
like all of them have that in the bag,
like as an escape clause.
You could say that for
Youtube because you're,
you're making an assumption chick's
you'd be willing to do that.
They would all be willing to do that.
No,
that's not what I'm not saying all of
them. I'm saying that is a, is an option,
but it's not for an option
for all of them. First of all,
it's not an option because
they don't want that.
They don't want some dude that they're
not in love with the just there with the
money, you know? So a lot of them,
there's no option you're assuming
high right now. I can't remember.
I had a rebuttal to that, but I just,
I just, I think it triggered on every,
my point being everybody has
the same kind of like, uh,
problems in comedy is just
a hard business. You know
what I'm saying? It's easy,
it's hard, but like the actual business
is not the easiest thing in the world.
I think that applies to everybody.
And sometimes people want to make it
up like they have a harder time than
everybody else.
Do you know what I'm saying?
I agree with you 100%
people definitely do that.
And then when I see like some 20 year
old kid on Youtube bitching about racism,
I'm like, you're late. It's a different
time. People are getting along better.
Everyone's boning, you know, it's also,
but it's in his, it's in his perspective,
he still sees an injustice and
even though it's like you're like,
well it's not the 1950s where they
can't use the same water fountain.
So there's no injustice, like lighten
the fuck up. But he still sees something.
They're still saying,
it's like everyone believes is
this person holding them down.
That is a problem man.
The self defeating sort of a attitude
that some people have that it's like,
you know, hey man, it's so stacked
against me. You know, there's,
there's some guys that the world is
always fucking stack 100% 100% Nick Depalo
love him to death. One of the funniest
fucking guys out there. But I got nick,
he played the part of my brother on
Newsradio and nick is just always used to
everybody being a cunt
had he's fucking quiz.
He's fucking Cock sock has
these motherfuckers fucking
with me. He's always,
you know, he's always like,
someone's always an asshole.
This guy's a Douche bag and
this, you know, whatever.
So it's like Nick Dipaolo is like
always get this negative vibe. So he,
worst case scenario,
that casting lady was a poon
hound or a male version,
the female version of a male
Poon Hound love dudes. Right.
And now I'm not saying she
did anything with these dudes,
but she loved to have them as friends.
She was, it was so big for her.
She loved it.
And she had all these guy buddy friends
that she'd hooked him up with parts and
sometimes they weren't very fucking good.
They weren't good actors,
but they were pals with her. So they
got cast for these roles. Well, when we,
when we wrote this script,
you know, there was two,
I had three brothers and two brothers
were going to be played by my friends.
Brian Cowen played one
brother and Nick Dipaolo.
Britt played the other Bri and we had
already worked it out with the producers
and this is exactly what we wanted.
They knew these guys,
the guys had come in like they, they knew
they'd been familiar with their work.
Like this is perfect.
This, it'd be really funny.
Well that my friend goes in to meet the
casting lady and it's supposed to be
like prearranged and she decides that
she's going to put like some other
boyfriend of hers in. So
she, she cuts him off,
she cuts to Paulo off and he like
does something with the paperwork.
I don't know what the fuck she did.
I know how she finagled it,
but all of a sudden she made it as look
as if he couldn't do it and this guy's
doing it. So I called nick up and I
go, what happened? He goes, I don't,
what the fuck happened? You know, I went
down there, I talked to the guy. So I go,
hold on a second,
I'm going to fix it. I'll call you
right back. So we had to tell the girl,
now this,
this part was already given to this guy.
And so nick couldn't believe it
when he came back on the set,
when he was on the side. He's
like, it's real. I'm really sorry.
Just waiting for someone to fuck it up
and boom, somebody fucked it up for him.
You know,
it's a self fulfilling prophecies man.
That goes back to what you were
saying that he's really negative.
But I mean for me it was really funny
that it just like, he's always that way.
He's always negative but that's why it's
fucking comedy. So funny. Very funny.
I worked with them at the Riviera Oh
many years ago. It was a lot of fun.
He's very nice guy.
Did to Nick Dipaolo is a killer.
When I saw him back in Boston,
he was like, he was like,
I was an open mic or I was just
starting out and he was like,
oh a real pro by then
like maybe two years in.
So he was like doing a lot of road
gigs, middling for people, you know,
he was like super active and I remember
watching him on stage once it stitches
just fucking light the place up for
20 minutes. And I was like, wow,
like can I do that someday?
You know?
It's like some of my favorite jokes
are so vicious. Vicious was material.
Matt,
his son about AIDS awareness thing.
Who does Nobel aid dogs
fuck with condoms now.
He's so funny. It sounds totally
like at Nick Depaulo lies so funny,
man.
Fucking that's that watching that whole
casting agent thing was so fascinating,
man.
This woman's like the male version of,
you know a guy who uses the casting couch
and if it was a guy that was doing it,
he would be a piece of shit.
If there was a guy that
was a podcast podcast,
here is what the casting couch is like,
you know to some people.
Okay.
Anyway,
what I was saying was it just
with this woman was the mail,
but I know it's not,
what I'm saying is it's like a casting
couch is the new version of the Comcast
casting. Is that your grades? No, no.
I'm not bringing anybody on
this show that my band is.
He is a little blade. That totally
fucking joking. You're not joking.
There's no one else thought that.
That isn't even in the back of my head,
but your head, it's in
the four now. That's the,
that's the in millions of people's heads.
You know like you have girls bombing on
you because of this podcast? No, not, no,
not because of this podcast. I'm saying
podcasting. Podcasting is the new,
the the couch like, hey, you want a
podcast? We can hook you up with a pod.
You're saying this,
you're saying this is ridiculous.
No one else is saying that too.
This is not like a common theme. No,
that's what I am saying that like the new
version of the casting couch nowadays.
You silly fucking here's why. Because
you're not auditioning people for a part.
You don't have them come in and maybe
I like you and maybe I like you.
The reason why these people have like
this, these weird relationships is they,
they, they get the person,
whoever's acting, you know,
whoever wants these parts thinking that,
look,
there's a thousand people
trying out for this.
Who's going to be my best friend who's
going to be clogged? Yeah, definitely.
You see it all the time, dude. I've seen
some. They would cast for some things.
You would see a big fucking
line of people and this power,
this ultimate power over the people
that come in casting people.
Some of the fucking creepiest people
have very nice ones. Don't get me wrong,
I've met a bunch of very, very nice
ones. Some of them, you know, they,
they don't take advantage of the
power and they're just, you know,
they're just friendly people and they're
just trying to have a good time and
everyone's nice to them because
everybody wants to be on a show.
So for the most part the job is
pretty positive is, and they look,
they got this guy like the guy who
got me fear factor Jeff, I'm sorry,
I don't remember his name, his last
name. He was a great guy, super,
super friendly guy.
Like no negativity at all.
And he was a casting guy but he was a
guy who genuinely loved productions and
loved good work and loved like
putting together a TV shows and shit.
And he had cast a bunch of like really
good shows. So it was a positive,
but a lot of them,
man,
they just fucking feed off that power
corrupts just creepy fucking shitty dumb
ass opinions.
And I remember being in a fucking a
casting agent room with this chick and she
was like Chubby and unattractive, but
very confident, which is always odd,
right? You know, and why wildfire
has the best line. He goes,
never put a fat chicken power because she
has too many axes to grind. It's true.
It's true.
And so this one,
she sits down with me and it's
like she sits down and you know,
she's like judging me and
breaking me down. You know,
I'm this young guy and you know,
she's probably like 40 and
kind of creepy and you know,
just something predatory about it,
right?
So she starts talking about where
you're from. And I said, well,
I was born in New Jersey, but I grew
up in Boston. And she goes, well,
I'm from Jersey too. But I
don't tell anybody. I tell
them I'm from New York. I go,
why would you tell them that
you're from New York? And she goes,
I don't want people knowing I'm from New
Jersey. I go, that's ridiculous. I go,
so you're telling me that like you,
you define people by what state
they tell you they're from.
And she just looks at me and she goes,
would you like to start reading
like right there? And then I'm like,
what have I done? And then there's
a part in his fucking this,
this audition and it's really
embarrassing audition. Okay.
Because I have to pretend that this
cow is now my girlfriend, you know,
and that I love her and then I have to
leave her and at one point in time I have
to sing a song to her so I have to sing
this fucking delirious Bruce Springsteen
song. That tape would
be gone. My God to this,
she is looking at me like with a
half an eyebrow raised and like,
you're wasting your time. I'm never
going to give you this part anyway,
but you have to do it because I told
you to do it. So here's your audition.
Scared Person. Oh, it was death.
It was just a on to your eyes,
dog shit logs coming out of my mouth.
I was trying to get him out.
It was like I had a hundred logs of dry
dog shit in my mouth. I'm just trying to,
I got to get them out one at a time or
I can't wait to get them out and then
finally got it out and I got
to leave and that's hilarious.
Ever heard from my hate auditioning man.
Some of the Times it's, it's brutal.
It's the worst thing about acting. It's
like here, you know we want you to be,
we want to know that you can
pretend to be someone else.
So we're going to give you,
you know,
a totally alien environment
where he's sitting there,
there's a cam quarter on you assistance,
everyone's got their arms crossed
and in and you're going to read.
And one time I was,
I got annoyed once cause I was doing
this audition and I was reading with this
assistant and this fucking
dude couldn't read man.
It was like you're supposed to be like
reading with them like some like listen
Mike, if we don't get back there by
six o'clock, we've got a real problem.
You have to be able to at least say
that this guy was like, listen, if
Mike Listen, if you don't get back
there by 10 o'clock we have a real,
I'm not kidding, this guy fucked up every
line. He was like super, super nervous.
He, everything that came out of his
mouth was like a jumble and I'm like,
you shot her and fuck.
This is a movie audition.
I remember auditioning for this really,
really bad sitcom,
not a sitcom comedy movie and I
didn't want to go on the audition,
but I was told, I was like, I don't want
to do this movie. If I ever do this move,
I'll be unhappy in. My agent's
like, listen, sometimes
it's better to get things.
Then you turn them down. Then more
people want to beat when I'm like, oh,
that doesn't make any sense, but
all right, you got me. I'm there.
So I go and I auditioned for it
and it's brutal. It's so bad.
It's like this and I'm supposed to play
this guy who's like really happy about
being married and I'm trying to
convince my friend that, you know,
you could be married to man, this
a marriage is amazing. It's so bad.
I have no idea. So anyway, there's this
horrible English director, you know,
he's got this like you're like a really
powerful English accent and he's,
he wants me to Ad Lib so
I just get done with this,
these awful awful words.
I mean the,
the dialogue was just wooden and
stupid and he's like, all right,
this is a next thing when I want you to
do is I want you to take this piece of
paper and I want you to write on
shots. Married Joel, very excited.
You K you're going to let him
know, you know, just married.
And I stopped and I said,
you know what? I go,
if this guy was an actor and
we run a set and I was already,
I already had the part,
I might ad Lib something and I could
probably come up with something.
I'd sit down and you know,
figuring out some good lines for them,
but this is an audition and this guy's
an assistant and I don't want to do that.
I can't. So I said, I actually
said that like, these are my words.
I don't want to do that. And
they go, okay, well thank
you. Thank you for coming in.
Okay. And I leave and my agent
calls me up fucking furious.
What did you say to them?
You know you can't do that.
You're going to get black balled. You
understand? I go, do I understand? I go,
what did I say? I, I was honest.
I said, this is a, this is bad.
There's a assistant here who can't read
and you want me to Ad Lib to some Shitty
fucking movie. What am I supposed to
do there? But yeah, this, this, this.
I don't think that what I did was rude.
I think I let them know that I didn't
want to do their movie. You have to have,
you did, you got put your foot down once
in a while. This town respects that.
You can't say, come here,
read this for the first town,
now write your own shit and
put it in there. Well, okay.
Which will probably end up in the
movie though. That's great line Zap.
Judah did that exam. Judah apparently
was doing this movie with some guy,
and I don't want to say the guy's name,
but it rhymes with Eddie Murphy
and he was uh, he was doing,
he would say like really funny
lines and then a box and that Zap,
Zap Judah, Judah, Jesus Christ.
The fuck is wrong with me. Jude
is all together. Yeah. Wow.
The boxers and a movie. Yeah. Thank
you for noticing that. That shit would,
it went on the Internet.
Oops. Too late. Anyway,
so is doing this movie and Judah has
all these great ad libs and in the next
scene, like in the next take, like Eddie
Murphy's got the Ad Libs now of Judas,
Judas, like an unpaid writer.
Like he's writing all these
great line. He'd get out.
Eddie Murphy, just Jackson. That's
horrible. Well, it's like I,
you know, what can you do? I
totally get what they're doing.
They're trying to find the best person
for the job. I get it, I get it,
but Goddamn, it was dumb. You know
who's on set? That's always cool.
Universally makeup girls, everyone else
that they're always the nicest people.
They always have a cool vibe.
I knew one of those crazy,
a new one that was completely
insane. So yeah, I met one early on.
It was just out of her fucking head and
saying was she attractive at all because
she's not attractive to
show them Draco Whoa,
who's this Unicorn you found awfulness
or I don't know. She's a nice person.
It's just a crazy person.
Yeah, I knew one that
was a, that does both.
Like movies ambitious also does porn sets.
She lives in a van and it's a
sweet vantage. It's like, you know,
like you go in and they have
couches and he could smoke weed,
but I think she lives in it.
What is it
like to go from Columbus,
Ohio,
like where you grew up and all of a sudden
you're in La and you're like intwined
in the porn business for
a brief period of time.
We were like hanging around
with all these people and like,
are you loved or you like, are they
like, do what's wrong with you?
It's,
it was interesting.
It was interesting seeing what that was
all about very quickly and understanding
how it works and how, you know, the
whole game of it. That was interesting.
What did you get out of it? Like, you
know, did you, did you get a lot of it,
like more of an understanding for
those girls who do that? Well,
I think the best thing was is
that you get what I call it.
I don't know what it'd be like a brother,
no second cousin aids test, which is,
you know,
cause they,
every time they shoot they get an aids
test and then if they don't have A's and
you don't have it,
do you know?
So I love [inaudible] so I don't have
any aids tests looking for a pussy.
Just super resistant to it. But your
Dick is just her boss who's like rubber,
but it's better than
the job fuck so much.
The inside of his completely calloused
to the point where nothing can get in.
There's no open skin. But, but
meanwhile it's like this, you know,
this leather pouch that contains
aids loads and you're singing,
you're sticking your Dick in there.
Well, I mean most guys,
I don't know about you.
I never wouldn't hit a bit of Goo nudes,
toast. You know, I never really do
dude.
I got an ace test when I was,
when I got health insurance when
I was 24 25 and I was terrified.
Really? Absolutely. Completely hard.
I was like thinking about all the times
I had sex without condoms and I was like,
for sure one of those girls has aids
and now I have aids. Like, you know,
I was already 25 and I was stupid.
And you know,
you don't even think about what you're
doing. You're 25 if somebody gives you a,
you know, an open and you
throw the pitch, boom. No, it's
in the glove. Bam. You know,
it's
like Peter and even believe she's
letting you fucker in the first place.
It is truly amazing. You last thing to
do is throw a condom on half the time,
you know,
it's like you don't wear condoms until
you like have like an a one pregnancy
scare and then you girlfriends like
you got to wear a condom this time.
You're like, okay, I'll wear
a condom anyway. Will we
ever get to the technology?
Condoms feel good. Do you
think? No, I don't think they
can do that. I mean, what a,
what is it going to be? How's it gonna
feel as good as no sac as good as sex?
Maybe. I mean, who knows, who knows? I
mean, what the fuck do I know? I'm, I,
I can't control what kind of inventions
come out of podcast. Got No power.
I got no power. But um, you
know, so anyway, when I was,
like I said when I was 25 did a lot
of stupid shit or I made a lot of bad
decisions, I wasn't a mature thinking
adult. I was a child living on my own.
So when that aids test came,
I was fucking petrified.
I was positive that I had HIV.
It was just thinking I'll every dirty
skank than I ever banked all would flash
back and fall that Emory and I get sick.
That's sick feeling that you get,
especially when you're,
when you're a kid,
you don't even realize you have to find
out from all your friends being honest
about the same situation,
but nobody teaches you when
you're a young boy like Sun,
one day you're going to have a hard on
and that hard on is going to betray you.
Okay? I just want to let you know you're
going to fuck a girl that you don't even
like.
You don't want to be around her and
you're going to promise her you love her.
You're going to talk to her.
You mean it.
You're going to talk to her about having
kids with her just because you want to
stick your dick inside of her. And as
much as the hard is, you try to do it.
That's the exact opposite, how bad
you're going to feel when it's over.
When you have an orgasm and you
just have that fucking terrible,
horrible feeling of regret.
Eddie Bravo cause it PostNet syndrome.
That's hilarious. The minute leaves to my
friend used to do two crazy wild party.
I used to do a bit about it,
about being stuck on a bus.
And then it's like when you,
when you have a heart on,
it feels like your Dick is driving
the bus and you're in the back seat.
You're sitting in the back
side of it, you're watching
life play out. You're like,
what do you even do in up there?
Do you know where you're going?
Like you barely driving your life,
but that when, as soon as you orgasm,
all of a sudden you're
at the front of the bus,
hold onto the wheel and you're like, how
did I get here? What am I doing here?
I don't even know how to get home. Who's
that? Yeah. What the fuck? And you know,
could you just cuddle and be tender
B tender? What are you talking about?
I gotta go, I gotta go, I gotta go.
I got Glen. Yeah. And it's, it's,
you really did mean everything
you said an hour ago.
You really meant all that shit. It's like,
it's so strange. The difference between,
you know how when you're horny and
when you're trying to have sex,
like how passionate you could be into
someone and then as soon as the orgasm
goes away, all their qualities that you
found attractive. Now we're annoying.
Did you did simply try to sue the guy
for that, like they lean? Yeah, sure.
Reception or something like she
that you know to get her in bed.
He said one thing and then afterwards he
was like, it didn't happen. She's like,
that's a breach of contract
almost. Yeah. I would imagine.
I doubted holds up in court though.
Yeah. Anything that you say,
well you have a hard on, should not hold
up in court. I think that is the ruling.
This should be ridiculous.
It's like he's in a compromised state
very clearly. Did he have a hard on? Yeah.
What do you do? What did you expect? Yes.
You asked him he was willing to marry you.
His Dick was a quarter of an inch from
your wet vagina. It was going to say yes.
Okay, I'll marry you up.
What did I say? Yeah. Ah,
it's really like witchcraft.
No wonder why dudes would be like burn
chicks for witchcraft back in the day.
They probably really believed that it
was witchcraft. You know that a pump,
a woman put a spell on you.
Oh, it didn't make sense.
Like how can I be so enchanted by her?
She's how rich and then the other fat
chicks in the fucking community come
storming with torches and light that
bitch on fire. Like the, uh, like, uh,
it's always the fat chick.
Like those two in my stories it is.
Do you know the North
Carolina a football team,
the panthers to their cheerleaders got
busted going at it in a bathroom stall at
a restaurant. Whoa. And then the, uh,
one of the waitresses called the cops and
had them arrested. I'm like, you know,
she's just some Chunky Moomoo that just
fucking was player hating on these two
hotties going out. I don't know,
man. If I was a regular chicken,
I was working in some skanks. You just
assholes in the fucking both. I might go,
Hey,
get the fuck outta here with your dirty
ass hole table where a French fry could
fall down a little kink in pick it up
like in the bathroom at a restaurant and
two guys are having sex and licking
each other's ass holes. Would you go to,
you set a booth. Okay. I said
bathroom. Did I say that?
I think you said I'm in a bathroom.
Stall. Bathrooms. You confuse the shit.
You confuse the shit out of me. It's just
the wrong word. We got confused. Okay,
so I, I get your point. Yeah. If
they were banging in the bathroom,
I probably let it go.
If I came in the bathroom and two chicks
are fingering each other, I'd be like,
oh, whoops. Sorry.
Gotta go and probably just told a
manager and the manager called the cops,
you know, or something like, yeah, she
ratted her in America. They shouldn't,
you shouldn't rat someone out
for eating box in a, in a toilet.
Who's getting hurt there?
Who's the victim?
If you came in and she was giving her
a massage, would you call the police?
She was like, oh, right there, it
hurts. Oh, that's good. That's good.
And Gel like you were giving
her what she needed physically.
You given her a physical sensation.
What your fingers.
How's that different from Eaton box in
a toilet stall. And that's my point,
I believe. I bet in Europe it can
fly. And Europe, you're probably,
they have like special seats in there.
If you want to take a shit, sit here.
If you wanna get your Dick sucked set
up here. Hey, they have a porn. Uh,
they have a porn bookstore in a
German airport. Oh really? Yeah.
They sell porn at airports.
Holy Shit. This A, I forget,
I think it was Iceland or some the,
they have the like a lesbian prime
minister and she outlawed strip bars.
Whoa. Yeah. That's interesting. How
can you outlaw that? How can mean that?
Seems like that's like communist shit.
You can't tell because
there have been women look,
a lot of women that get into stripping.
Yes. A lot of them have been molested,
but there happened women that they just
needed money and this was a way to make
a ton of money and it puts them, they
actually put themselves through school.
I mean, it's the big Cliche, right? You
know, like who had a Mike, Joe, Mike,
a young a,
a joke about
how do you ever notice that all strippers
are going to college like some year,
one day? It's kind of, it's like there's
going to be a whole graduating class,
a genius strippers. It was really
funny. He can't chance. Yeah,
exactly. Right. Yeah. Yeah.
There's the jug. I mean, but
they should have that option.
If you want to stick your ass
on some guy's face and you know,
and make 1000 bucks a night,
he should be allowed to because
is that less humiliating,
the working at Denny's for 100 bucks a
night? I don't think it is. Oh by the way,
I think if you want to work with fucking,
if you're a hot check and you got a nice
body and you want to work five hours
and you want to stick your, if you're
cool with somebody, we can pussy. Wow.
I always wanted to be financial consultant
to the strippers because they have so
much money and they do nothing with it.
If you're like,
let me invest for you silly
so you're not a good investor.
Fuck you talking about. I didn't mix
yourself. Nonsense. He's talking,
trying to control some strippers.
Monies is called pimp inside
and I've been there, done that.
I know what you're doing,
but it's like they don't even have cars.
Half these girls.
Why not like invested in the stock market
trying to make some money because the
stock market's unpredictable.
They should save some money.
Let's do they should do. Puts
squirrels some away. The problem is,
you know when all sudden you're making
1000 bucks a night and you're doing a job,
that sucks. If you don't want
to be there all the time,
you know you'll start spending money
just to kind of placate yourself. Right?
A lot of people that have their boyfriends
spends it on Xbox or some shit like
that. That's true too. They
support men too. That's the other,
the weirdest relationship with strippers
is a lot of them have like super loser
boyfriends that just cannot get jobs,
you know,
and that's why these guys
are willing to accept it.
There girl will climb on guys' laps
every night and stick their tits and guys
like Dan, not into it, man. Most of
them aren't. They're just weak men.
And this girl needs a man and needs a
man to like be serious with her and live
with her and,
and still allow her to work this job.
And most guys are not going to
be down with that, but losers,
guys who have like shitty jobs are guys
who are just really lazy and they're,
they don't have a problem with
a girl taking care of them.
They got no problem with that. So
they're like, you know, go ahead,
go ahead and work up. Some guys
are just into that like, yeah,
their whole stock holding thing
and all that. Cuckold Holden. Yeah.
There's a few that are into that, but most
of them are just losers. Most of them.
That's why you know,
they beat the girl up eventually or get
mad at her or something and you're not
even in fucking man.
You'd have in a job you fuckin whore.
You know there's always,
always something, you know it's
be their investor,
aim high,
go for those strippers. Thousand dollars
a month invested that shit. It's a good,
it's a good move.
I think I liked the way strippers thing.
Just make a shit load of money and
just spend it on drugs and drinking and
sheers. You like that and shoot. Is that
what you would do if you're a stripper?
Probably. You wouldn't be
starting your own business.
I wouldn't be thinking about
it. I'm fucking working
nights. Single gas station.
I one of the sleeping in strippers
have to sleep in. You know,
you're out till 5:00 AM every
day. Yeah. It's a lot of work.
Best part of the invite the economy being
bad as hot chicks working at Denny's
now, have you noticed that? Yeah. I was
in Phoenix and I went to this Denny's
and these chicks were hot. Really?
Yeah. Wow. I guess he got to take what
you got to take. I think it's awesome.
I chicks and bad situations.
Brother allowed you love. Yeah,
I do like when you look, just
keep one. Are y'all? Yeah.
When they're driving like shitty cars.
You like that or riding the bus ls.
You'll drive by. You see like some
hot chicken getting ready for the bus.
You're like, how easy could it be?
The be the knight in shining armor.
You know what I'm saying? I got, we'll
get you where you got to go. Yeah, dude,
I love bad situations. Hot chicks
and bad situations. My favorite shit.
There's more of that happening now than
ever before. That's for flux. Sure.
Especially in la where they just
moved there. It's like, yeah.
What happens when you're a chicken?
You've got a sugar daddy and your sugar
daddy goes bankrupt. Oh, that's good.
Imagine that Shit, man. Then also
we've got to get a job. Oh Fuck,
I've been fucking, it's fat cock sucker
for five years. That's my job. You know,
she's like, I gotta join the workforce
now. Or when they do, you know,
you get married then after a couple of
months and get divorced just to get that
cash. Do you think that it's, how
many girls take that path that you do?
You described earlier about your comedian
friend that all of a sudden she's
driving a nice car.
How many girls do that?
I think there's a lot and
I don't see it as the,
I don't think necessarily being
attracted to a guy cause he has wealth is
necessarily a bad thing. Well it
is a, it is a feature, you know,
it's like a big Dick is
going to be nice to me.
You know I liked that big Dick
because he does he have a strong body?
Strong body can protect me. Is he
handsome? Yeah, I'll find him attractive.
These are all rewards. What
about the money? He's broke.
Fuck this broke ass. Yeah.
Well that makes sense. That Kanye West
Song. Alright, so and she's a gold digger.
Look, that's just the way it is, man.
It's like it's, it's a part of nature.
You know, someone providing
is an attractive feature.
It's all well and good.
If you work hard and you're not as man,
but if you're still making five bucks an
hour, you might be retarded and retard.
I don't need your raising my
kids on 20 bucks a week. Okay?
I need to find more money. You fuck.
That's what they're supposed to do. Yeah.
There's a game going on.
You're playing the game.
The game's called capitalism and you
don't have any chips. You got no chips.
You're out there. You're, you're
humping just like everybody else.
I know you're being
noble and all that shit,
but we got to come to a realization that
this world runs on certain principles.
I've got to get that payment.
My baby needs resources.
Got I got that paper. Yeah.
Babies need resources,
man.
You can't be running around
with babies with some broke ass.
It's a pain in the ass,
ma'am.
100% as we make this trek into this new
stage of existence where fucking robots
are going to be doing everything
retards are doing now,
it's going to be very strange.
It's going to be just like Iraq war when
the soldiers come home and they were
like, now what? That's
what's going to happen.
All these retards are going to
get kicked out of, you know, any,
any like mindless job is all going to
be eventually done by robots. Yeah.
Whether they do, what do they do?
Man? Robots don't have to sleep.
They can work 24 hours a day and once
they can handle delicate measures and do
things and then once it's economically
feasible, which eventually it must be,
it's like everything becomes cheaper
and faster and easier as time goes on.
So eventually there's
going to be some sort of,
robots are going to virtually
everything that people do.
When you charge people's, you know,
people get paid $7 an hour, any,
any fast food jobs and all that shit's
going to be handled by robots. Yeah,
I fucked some people can't
be doctors or lawyers.
They don't have that meant they're not
built like that. They're more hands on.
So you know, they're meant
to be like working, you know,
building cars or whatever.
You know, they're more like, well that's
all good shit too. I mean that's not a,
that's not a mindless thing. That's,
I'm not saying that the line was,
I'm saying what I mean is you're
saying a word dumb labor jobs. Yeah.
I was in someone's like written to making
cars and the craftsman stuff sort of
thing. They could find the other
things. Like people are always,
our lots are building all the jobs.
Cars are art, you know, like a car,
like a hot rod or something that someone
who fabricates a car. Let me just say,
I wasn't saying that
that was a mindless job.
I'm saying like these people
aren't built to, because I need,
I know what you're saying. Eventually
robots are gonna take over those parts.
So where do they go? Because they
can't become doctors. Lawyers.
Cause that's not really what their,
their wheelhouses I guess.
Do you know what I'm saying? Just have
to figure out something else. You know,
I mean if you don't have,
if the job doesn't exist anymore,
the universe is not sweating that, all
right, you got to deal with that shit.
Right.
And if you're smart enough to get to that
point where you're good at one thing,
you're going to have to figure out how to,
you know,
use what skills you have to
get better at something else.
Because obviously that that part
doesn't exist in society anymore.
You're just going to have to
face up to that adapt or die.
It's really that simple.
It's like,
well we can't nerf the world for people
that they can't catch up nerf the world.
I like just going to be
some spots where it's rocky.
There's going to be some spots where
people had banked on something being
successful forever and then it's not.
And what are we do?
We're going to keep it alive.
You know,
just for the sake of these folks
now these folks have to fucking,
they have to figure out what's next for
them because this thing is going to die
off and then a new thing. It's got to
come. Right. I totally agree with that.
Do you ever wonder or worry that there's
going to get to a point where there's
all these people out there with no
place? Yeah, so I'm saying like we're,
you know, it's like we keep
talking about creating jobs.
I mean like they're all fucking,
and they're all making babies.
Look at redbox and blockbuster video.
There's no need to have
blockbuster videos anymore.
You can just throw up a machine at every
corner now and that just takes out the
whole entire store and all those
employees, you know, it's crazy. Yeah.
Well there's that. Yeah.
Yeah. They figured out how
to cut the middleman, right.
The fuck out of the picture. And see
DVDs are so easy to burn. You know?
It's so easy to make DVDs, so many fucking
steels wanting. You can replace it so,
so hard. You could do one in your own
home computer. One are ridiculous.
Is that he could make where they got
damn DVD on your home computer. Yeah.
Where do they go? That's my hope.
We're a society than it go, you know,
because we keep inventing
crazier and crazier things.
Like it's so funny if you go back and
look at like the pioneer days when they
crossed the, I was watching the show,
the one I was talking about earlier,
the wild within the uh,
the,
the hunting show while I was watching
that and he tried to do what Lewis and
Clark did, they were like, they
made like boats out of like, um,
buffalo skin and sticks and shit.
It was like craziness.
Like they tipped over in the water.
It was ridiculous.
And I was thinking about it like them
living back there like that was just
accepted.
Yeah,
we're happy you had a gun and you would
link back to member of the old days when
folks had a kill things with spears and
you thought they were idiots. Right. Well,
how are the power people are going to
be looking at us just in a few years?
Just in 20 years. Yeah. When I
see a new baby, I think, man,
this kid's can be around
for like a hundred years.
Madge and what's going to be going
on in a hundred years from now? Dude,
it's just saying we're a hundred
years ago. What was going on?
It's happening so quick too.
It's like maybe it's not even a hundred.
Maybe it's like five or 10,
whatever the fuck.
What's it like every year our knowledge
doubles or something that it's like some
crazy number or it's just,
it's going so fast and Japan's
even farther ahead than us.
Here's an awesome quote and I can't
remember what the fuck it was,
but it was about, uh, gigabytes. It
was about how many gigabytes up from,
I think it was like everything that
human d, the entire stored, um,
results of all human writing and
knowledge and everything that's ever been
written by people up until like,
I think it was like 1996
or something like that.
It was like the date that they calculated
this was only like a certain amount of
gigabytes. Like ever, like a very, very
small, really? Yeah, very small round.
But from then to now,
we generate that every two days.
Wow. Holy Cow. Yeah,
it's insane. And forgive me if I don't
exactly have the numbers correct.
It might've been 2001 it might not have
been 1996 this is all pulled off the top
of my head, but they were talking
about how insane just the, uh,
the output of text and, and
information in ones and Zeros and, and,
and just writing that people do now with
blogs and newspapers and news sites and
this and that.
Everything you read all day and photos
and Twitter and Facebook and constantly,
you're constantly like putting out
gigabytes and gigabytes and gigabytes of
information. It's an a, the internet.
Is there any possibility of fills up
or she could just go, let us expand.
It was this new internet they keep
talking about well to Internet two. Yeah.
I think right now it's just from,
for,
it's either just for educational purposes
or just military purposes. Prett way,
just faster. Pretty much. That's
all it is. It's not, well,
we shouldn't really ever talking about
her. We don't really understand it.
I don't even know what the intern,
and I'm pretty sure what Internet two is.
Just using a different form of,
it's faster, it's faster. Will we?
So we'll never fill up internet one
where it's like there's no more,
no more websites. Yeah, I
think it's not going to change.
I think it's going to
be the same internet,
just different speeds for most
US advanced network consortium.
That's what they're calling
is a, everybody's still
mad at me about the n word.
I guess it's an education thing.
It says led by the research and education
community since 1996 Internet two
promotes the missions of its members
by providing leading edge network
capabilities and unique
partnership opportunities together,
facilitate the development deployment
and use our revolutionary internet
technologies. You just said a whole
lot of nothing there, dude. Okay.
You know what you said?
You said this is some elite shit
that regular people can't get. Yeah.
That's why I'm thinking
when when this Zombie
apocalypse happened,
these fiber optics will be underground
and we'll still be able to communicate
with each other,
but your AOL account will be dead.
That's why I'm taking Samurai
classes. Really? You haven't taken,
so just started your, but you've
become one of your own jokes now.
Cause you said always look out
for a dude who has a sword. Yeah,
that dude's shame. I am
shading. I like shady shit. My
friends are shady. So query,
where are you taking
these Samurai classes? Uh,
it's in century city and
it's an all like a scent.
Yeah. Century city. It's the what
do you do? Well, I just started,
I've only taken a couple classes
so we learn us striking and the,
and then I'm about to take my first
sword class. I'm very excited.
So you learned striking weapons.
Jamraya weapon tree.
So you weren't striking like karate, like
punching and kicking too. Yeah. So what,
what made you want to be a Samurai? Um,
something to do. Just a dream. I'm like,
you know what? That's the dream. Yeah.
I just taken acting classes and then
they make me miserable. Great teachers.
But I was just miserable. So I'm
like, why do I want to do that?
I want to do something I've always
wanted to do. Wow. Take Samurai class.
You were taking acting classes.
You didn't like it.
You decided to take Samurai
classes. Dude, that's funny man.
How was your manager feel about
this? I don't know. Who knows?
I don't care anymore. I'm so over.
I just want to like have fun.
You know what I'm saying? Are you
over it? Yeah. I'm just Kinda, I just,
I enjoy it and I love doing what I do
and I'm happy with who I am as and now I
just want to learn how the fuck can wield
a sword. I'm saying that's what I want.
You know? It's when you come to a certain
point in your life where you're like,
you realize that you're, you're making a
good living, doing what you want to do.
Like you as a standup comedian in me,
you headline all over the country.
Now I'm blessed. You have,
you have checks coming in.
Once you get that freedom you
like, I can keep doing this, man.
I can keep doing it. You can't stop
me from being funny. And then you go,
I just want to be myself.
One day I just said no more bad gigs,
not doing gigs. I don't want to
do. I'm just like, you know, I,
I stopped the day job because
I hated being at the day job.
I started doing comedy because I wanted
that freedom and that's kind of like
what I'm doing now. So I'm just rocking
Indian casinos. You know what I'm saying?
Live your life and have some
fun. Why not? That is really bad.
And what it's all about
in the end, what, what,
what you have down as your
accomplishments is all nonsense.
It's like how did you affect people
when that you came in contact with,
how much fun did you have? Do you have
a good time? Did you spread a positive,
you know,
overwhelmingly positive or overwhelmingly
negative message and you know,
dispersion of energy while you were here?
Yeah,
I mean like to do two hour set was so
much fun just to have it and see what was
working there and what
didn't work and you know,
I was getting applause breaks on stuff.
I like,
if I like political material that you'd
totally wouldn't think I got an unique
casino in Oklahoma. Well that's
what I was talking about with bill,
with the Internet.
It's like people have access in these
places and these rural communities now to
virtually everything that you have.
When I was living in Colorado, man,
I didn't feel disconnected when
I was in a town of, you know,
a few hundred people on the
top of a mountain. Yeah.
It definitely keeps everybody close to
the front man too. It's a different,
we live in,
Oh yeah.
You know what else he really thinks help
comedy to South Park and I think that's
because people are used to just fucked up.
You know, I was doing the show
the other day and it's like, oh,
they're really young. They tend to
be more, I always thought they were,
they were fun to do kind of dirty
jokes for but more risque stuff.
They sometimes cringed and I was doing
it and they were just gone with them.
I'm like, wow, that's so crazy. And
I was talking to them, they're like,
well these kids all grew up on
south park. You know, they all,
they all through snow.
Like they get this weird sense of humor
that's not necessarily like you're being
better than garbage pail kids
and the shit that, you know,
we grew 100% when I used to do
colleges back when I was young.
Then when I lived in New York,
I did a bunch of them.
There was one point where I did a whole
string where I would do like colleges
for like you just months and months
at a time. Cause it was really,
really good money, like way more money
than I could ever make doing in clubs.
But I would go in front of these kids
and he would talk about sex and there was
so many virgins in the audience who was
so many people that would look back and
forth at each other and they didn't have
a fucking clue what I was talking about.
And I would say,
I would say it like it took me a couple
of shows where till eventually went,
how many you guys have
never had sex before?
Just kind of just give me a
little clap under the table.
And they started laughing like it was.
So what they were thinking of
like it killed me saying that.
How many guys have never had sex before?
Ah,
you knows
Mike. Wow. You are like children now.
They're doing math and fucking each
other in bathrooms and watching porn.
These kids have all grown up watching
like ass to mouth porn or hearing over and
over.
Funny.
I know like a virgin who have lost their
virginity later in life and the girls
were like, I couldn't believe
he's actually good in bed.
And I like that would
be trained. Right. Well,
these guys have been watching game
film for like the last 10 years.
It's like if you had to watch
10 years of footage of football,
you would know the play and
you just got that one time.
I'd say like he actually knew to play
new as a throw it when he's opening.
It's the same thing,
man.
That's probably like a lot of guys
watch the UFC and think they know how to
choke somebody, Bro. I know how to do it,
bro. You got to get your hooks in. Well,
it should be easier though in
a weird way to like explain,
oh this is the blah blah control. You're
like, oh. So I knew what that looks like.
So it's probably a little easier
than when there was nothing.
Or if you were in a fight with somebody
and you had no martial arts experience
whatsoever,
but you are a huge UFC fan and all of a
sudden in a scramble you wound up on top
of this guy. He'd be like, okay, I'm in
the mountain now. What? I do one truck,
I've got to drop some bombs
and you hear your voice.
Oh,
he's definitely hurt.
Does a dude that we were hanging out
with in front of the Improv one night and
he came to one of the shows and he said
he got beat up by these dudes and while
he was getting beat up,
one guy was doing me,
he was doing an impression of me while
the other guy was hitting him and he said
he was getting his ass kicked and
while he's getting his ass kicked,
he thought it was fucking hilarious.
He was laughing and I'm like,
I'm sorry that it happened to you, dude.
That sucks. Yeah, dude, that's crazy.
Was the, had a great sense of humor about
it. I submitted it a video about it,
didn't we? In front of the Improv,
there's only youtube somewhere to do that.
Great personality that you
could tell it dudes personality,
but how he takes an ass kicking
some guys a story. Yeah. Like what?
What made him get his ass? Katie tell you
that. Because he seems like a nice guy.
I think some guys just jumped him.
I think some douchebag.
Why wouldn't he flipped a store? A standup
comic too? Yes, he was a standup comedy,
open mics with him.
Who is this just some guy that you use?
I think he works for Lynn
or something like that.
He was doing open mikes briefly and then
you just stopped doing it or he moved
on to somewhere else. He decided
he wanted to be happy. Right.
There's a lot of guys that just
can't take it anymore. The pressure,
the pressure of constantly trying
to come up with new material.
The pressure of performing, the pressure
of, I'm trying to advance so I like,
I love writing and I'm,
oh I'm blessed.
You know that I can write a lot but
sometimes I just get, I love standup.
I just hate the businesses.
Sandy, don't you find it?
The writing is all just a matter of
sitting around and doing it though.
A lot of it is just forcing yourself to
do it and talk to myself all day lights.
That's how I like to write. Do
you write on paper? Sometimes,
but mostly it's just like me turning bits
in the thing cause I know I'm going to
go up, so I'm just thinking of different
ideas and where I could fit this.
And does it ever drive you
fucking crazy when you,
you have an idea in your head and someone
just won't stop talking to you and
you're like, want to run away and you're
like, hold on a second, hold a second. No,
no, no. But this guy was
like, don't talk right now.
And like you have the slip reest of
grips on this brilliant fucking bit.
And that's the cray you feel like
switching. Yeah. Right. It's terrible.
But you feel like an antisocial douche
bag for go and shop tops, tops top.
But meanwhile they're like stomping over
your beautiful collection. Like you,
you've got some beautiful painting that
you're making but it's invisible and
they're running in which shit on their
shoes. Just stamping all over. Oh yeah,
it happened to me.
I do that because what happened the
day I thought of something while I was
plugging in to an outlet in my bedroom,
I was plugging something in and I
thought of like this bit and I was like,
I gotta write this down.
I got her dead.
So I'm running to the living room and my
friend is like talking to me and I, no,
no, no, stop, stop, stop. And
then he was like, wouldn't
stop like be quiet. I'm like,
wait, I need to write something down.
And then like I tried to get like my,
my whatever, my iPad on and it
was trying to type it and it,
while I was typing it slowly they kept
start talking again. I'm like, no, no.
And I'm like, all right, I
forget the main part, whatever.
It's the worst because it's,
you could be an have a,
I'd like of this slippery grip on the
most brilliant idea you like, fuck yes,
this is awesome. And for whatever
reason you barely have it. The Mat,
the, your, your, your whole
on creativity and imagination.
It's so requires like a shirt
and frequency in your brain.
It's so requires like a certain
focus and when someone comes in,
Hey Bang, Bang, Bang and
pants together, come on,
let's go outside to drink. All of
a sudden it's gone. You're out.
Other than Saran second. I never think
about just saying it out loud either.
Like I never go. Okay. Uh, yeah, that
moon is a pie. Moon is a pie. You know,
they that would it be it
shut up. Shut up. Shut up.
Moon is a pie yet maybe if you
said it, maybe it would work. Yeah,
maybe they would get someone.
Stop talking myself.
I do that all the time. You do
that? Did I do that all the time?
Well I just use the notepad feature in
the iPhone. The Oh, notepad features.
Awesome. I have, I have a droid. We'll get
rid of that piece of shit. I'm waiting.
I'm waiting till I know that iPhone is
not gonna be as good. Pi knows a bit.
It's funny. Fight Story. Funny fight
story on my channel. Pull this shit up.
Yeah.
Have you ever done a bit and you were
about to give it up and all of a sudden it
catches fire.
I had this,
I do this bit about crimes of awesomeness
and I was started at when I was in
Australia and it just was eating
it. But I'm like, that's so funny.
And I got back to the states
and I remember, I'm like,
I'm just going to try it because it
eight dogs, Dick fucking Australia.
And I went there and again on state
and the place goes Ooh. And I'm like,
I knew that was funny.
It was so interesting.
So was it the Australians
didn't think it was funny. Yeah.
So it's just their sense of humors.
Just maybe it was just word play
that they didn't understand.
Maybe I call it a homeless shelter,
but you know,
maybe they didn't know what that was and
they call it something else over there.
But I, I, I didn't care enough about
the ass anybody at that point. Hey,
what do you guys call? We call
it a day, ah, homeless loft.
There's some shit like that.
You know what I'm saying?
So maybe if I tweaked it on in that way,
he could just be the sense of humor too.
It's so funny how people in
other countries just have
completely defensible dude.
Like you ever watch like English stand
up and they're laughing and shit and he
like, I don't understand what
they're saying. I don't get this. Oh,
I love the British House of Commons.
That's comedy. Did that, what does that,
he ever watched that? No,
the British House of Commons,
like it's basically it's congress
meets a your Mama's competition.
Why show? No, it's, they're a parliament.
It's a real, the real Paul. Yeah, Dude.
It is the best man use watch.
A guy gets up there and he'll give a
speech and people start heckling the shit
out of him. Really? Yeah. Well they
were gonna send George Bush and,
but they're like, no, he can't
go in because they were going to,
it's like trying to do the
Apollo, you know? Really? Yeah.
It's like a white people's Apollos.
So awesome dude.
I love watching it and like they get
snarky back and they kill hecklers.
It's so much fun when you
watch this on a cspan. Whoa.
Not Worth it. I don't know, man. It
sounds pretty fascinating. I love this.
I love almost everything British too.
Did dish people or it's fun.
It's a fun place to party.
England's awesome. I always
love performing in England.
The people are cool as fuck.
We went here, this video. Yeah.
Play that video real quick.
This is the kid who was talking
about getting his ass kicked.
Yeah.
I was living in Chicago and uh,
I was walking to work one morning
and these two kids out of nowhere,
you're not going anywhere. You're
not going anywhere. I'm like,
I have to go to fucking work. Right. It
kept fucking hits me right in the jaw.
It was swollen like shit. And the
kid goes, he's rocked, he's rocked.
And I watched fucking this guy
doing commentary and I'm like,
I know where that came. And that was my
first thought. Instead of, Oh my God,
I'm in trouble. My first thought is
this guy's quoting Joe Rogan, man.
I'm fucking like all swollen up and shit
sitting there at the doctor. And, uh,
my girl,
what happened?
Say email me, baggy on it.
It made my day, honestly,
like is the only positive thing
from that story. But it made my day.
Oh, that's what it is.
He emailed me the story,
then I emailed him back and then
I came to show Larry a story.
That's hilarious.
You're the, you're in the vernacular
brother. That's ridiculous. Rocked.
Is it ever now I'm so conscious
of not saying it now because it's,
sometimes it just comes out, you
know? But sometimes I say, man,
I shouldn't say that shit
so often because people,
there's like the actual drinking game.
I say it so much.
This is a drinking game where someone,
when I say rock dudes do shots, you know,
and sometimes sometimes they'll get
the fucked up though, man. Yeah.
That's a big car.
You know,
I get a Frankie Edgar fight alone
could give you alcohol poisoning, dude.
Have you ever been told like,
Hey,
if you say you've been
dude or a mountain dude,
you'd get $10,000 or like started
switching up your year commentary. Terry,
with some sponsors.
Do they do that?
Like,
hey commentators to say like [inaudible]
you been snapped and do a slim Jim.
Well there's certain things that they
have for the show. Like you know this,
this clock is sponsored by call of duty
or something like that. Yeah. But the,
he can't just fucking in the middle of
your commentary. He's big captain crunch.
It's funny cause I just said fucking right
there and I caught myself as I said I
was Ooh I swore. Oh okay.
I'm not doing commentary,
I'm just talking on the podcast like
just thinking about commentary because I
have a very clear commentary
state of mind. Like it's very,
because it's very difficult for me to
talk for five hours and not swear. Yeah.
You know that's the hardest part about
it because when someone gets in I want to
go, oh shit. It's like natural.
So I have Doug like constantly be zen
and make sure that I saw like just then
really just saying fucking there
was a part of me that went oops.
Cause it's like commentary state
of mind. Right. Well it's tricky.
Sometimes I get book place with it like
cause I need the cash. There'll be like,
you can't swear. And I don't know why,
but when I'm told that I can do it,
but my natural thing is f bombs and
all this stuff that right to say,
I just like, that's who I
am. But for some reason,
like when I go and like they say
to do stand up on television,
I was watching a burns last night.
He had a really good set and Lopez
attorney see the part where the, okay,
there we go. Oh, you're so much
louder. Yeah, they a really good part.
He did really well on Lopez.
Let's do this. Yeah. And um,
he dropped a beat to mom something I can,
I think he said Shit.
I'm not sure if you could say that,
but they beat them on that.
Tbs is a cable station, right?
Is it FCC regulated? I don't see,
that's the whole weird,
I think it's not so much about regulation,
but it's more about not pissing off
sponsors. Right. Right. Right. Now. So he,
he got a beep on that and I was like,
oh,
I wonder if they're letting them do that.
But what I'm told,
I can't swear for some
reason it's easy for me,
right? Like you just go into that mode.
Yeah. The clean mode and you know,
there's a box that you're operating in.
We're just going to operate
in the clean mode box.
When you're doing standup does ever
happen to you where you're talking and
you're thinking, it's almost like
it's almost two different things.
Do you know what I'm saying it a bit,
but I'm going to, what am I doing here?
And you're like, okay, where's this going?
What's going on over there? You know,
it's like,
it's not autopilot,
but it's just an interesting thing
where you're like literally like,
like multitasking.
That's why it's the most annoying thing
when there's a whole table full of
people talking really loud
while you're doing a bit.
Because while you're in the groove,
instead of just thinking about,
here's the bit I'm doing and this
is what I'm going to do next,
it's the bit I'm doing this,
what I'm gonna do next.
And what the fuck is going on over here
and some all this annoyance and Andy,
there's bad crowd. These bad people or
audience members that are not, you know,
not following by the audience member,
comedian relationship,
100% we're just ignoring it. They're just
being douche bag. So when you call it,
that's the worst.
When you called him on it,
what did we do? And we didn't do anything
when they're doing anything wrong. Yeah.
After you kill them, that's like
when you're no, a heckler war. Okay.
And we'll go back and forth, but once I
own you and it's done, it's time to go.
It's like let's, that's the only time I
really get mad. It's like you've lost,
you know it, you need a, you got
served tagline then or sorry, I,
you know,
I'm just,
the worst to me is when someone needs to
be kicked out and they don't get kicked
out. And then the, the people
want to keep them there,
like the clubs trying to keep them
there and you got to go, look man,
this is not going to, you got a table
full of drunk people yelling shit, Shit.
Divert taking chip bouncer story. A
chick bouncer. Well she bounced this,
another chick bounce and other
chick. What did I have? No,
I have not told you this. So anyways,
um, and if I told you you can stop me,
maybe you did.
And I don't remember doing it halfway.
And I go to the comedy store,
I pull in and I'm,
I'm next Brody Stevens is on stage and
he's got this crazy drunk Australian girl
on there and I could
tell it's not going good.
No one's laughing and it's
just weird energy in a room.
And I walk in and he sees me. He goes,
Sam, do you want me to leave her on stage?
I like no, get her off.
The place goes crazy.
So automatically right there I noticed
she's, the crowd doesn't like this girl,
right? So anyways, Brody kicks her off,
he brings me on stage and we have this,
have this weird kind of
exchange and it's like we're,
we're having fun with each other, but
we're kind of zingy each other. Yeah.
So he's walking out, we're
zinging each other. She just,
this drunk girl comes off the Strunk
Australian girl comes up and just starts
screaming at me, get off stage.
You're not funny. And I'm like,
and I'm just zinging I'm killing her now.
She's walked all the
way to the front of the,
or she's in the front row pointing at me
standing up, you've got funny, get the,
and then she's now she's getting nasty
cause I'm just killing her in the place
is going nuts, kill, kill,
kill again. And she's like, Oh,
you're not funny. And then I'm like, okay,
where are the bouncers at this moment?
Okay. It's because they have
like, uh, like, um, like
emos over there working, you know guys
who look like they're in like catch cabs,
QT bands, you know what I'm saying? Like
playing keyboards and shit. And I'm like,
where are nothing? Nothing, nothing.
She screaming at me all
the sudden out of nowhere,
this like five foot six Italian girl
walks up and I think she's with her cause
she walks up to the girl,
grabs her look, spins around,
smacks around the ass, spends
her background, picks her up,
carries her out fireman style.
Holy Shit. Holy Shit. I'm like,
what is going on?
Brings her outside,
basically gets her face
so don't go back inside.
Bitch walks back up and I'm like, Holy
Shit. She didn't know her. I'm like,
did you know her? She goes, no,
she's fucking annoying. I'm like,
did you just regular holy shit that the
craziest Shit I've ever wish you had
that on video man. It is literally the
bullying, the best heckles stories ever.
It takes too much time to get the video.
Does should be a special button on
your phone where you have to press.
It's really hard to press but the video
camera instantly comes on, you know,
so it's a one one press button.
Just you could just a fucked up situation
button you can do that. I found,
I think you program the buttons a
home button to launch an application,
can't you? You can do that. You are
so light years ahead of me, dude.
I have no clue. But that's ridiculous
because if your phone's on on,
on standby and you press it,
you first of all,
you have to put it in your fucking
code first. And I get these time. Well,
I mean if you had it could have
deactivate your code, right?
So you'd have to wonder why don't around
town hoping that you don't drop your
phone and people don't get all
your cock pictures. What I mean?
I mean I'm just saying, I mean I don't
have any coq pictures on my phone,
nothing about that.
But that would be the shit though.
If there was some way you can just
press it in instantly immediately starts
videotaping shit, you know,
light on go go gadget. I'm like,
where's my camera? Why didn't I have
that moment? How long ago was this?
I'd say about a year ago. So you could
have had that on your phone. Yeah,
mother fucker.
That would be funny.
I should record all my sets cause she
hadn't touched that crazy bitch I've had.
She's just doing it.
The girls all the time and he grow.
Does that once the ass was the best part,
it was like I own you smack, I own you.
I own you smack from a chick. Did
you get turned on at all? Yeah,
I find that stuff hot. I find chicks
who kick ass crazy bitches like that.
There's something about you wanting them
to give into you and accept your yeah,
I'm telling Ya. That's what
I love. Really smart chicks.
It's just fun to like make them say
like really crazy weird degrading shit.
Oh yes. Was smart tricks or the
promise smartsocks are though.
They're smart and you can't get away
with everything that you can with dumb
chicks and you, you have to, you know
they all again, arguments and shit.
The investigator know they the,
the government wishes they had the rights
that women had where they could just
go through all your emails and all
that Shit. There's a woman that,
it was a dating this guy and it was
another one. It was a hot woman.
There was dating a guy who was an
ugly dude and she, uh, she wasn't,
she was even open about it.
She was telling people at the supermarket.
I heard her telling
people about, uh, about, uh,
how she had been planning it.
I think it was at the supermarket,
might be disinformation. Anyway,
she'd planned it like months in advance
and she was going through all of his
finances to make sure that he wasn't
hiding things. And Oh my God, that's,
that's the thing that drives me every,
every nickel.
This guy made down to a science as threats
chapel a lot out how much she can get.
And it was terrible. Women do that, man.
They'll also lap relationships. They seem,
one's going down. They'll ra
hell let it go. Somebody said,
I don't remember who the fuck it was.
It might've been Patrice O'Neal,
but it's really funny. I don't remember
who it was. It might've been me.
I don't even know. But anyway,
that chicks, when they're
swinging, you know, they'll,
they're like monkeys.
They want to make sure there's another
branch there to catch it. They don't know.
They don't, they don't want to be
walking out in the plains by themselves.
They don't like to have, they don't like
to have downtime to get to know them.
So you got to take care of yourself
and by your own meals, you know,
especially girls who
get into that situation.
You get into a situation where you
dating someone who's got some cash,
you know he'd ever been in a situation
where there's a girl who just got done
dating a guy with cash and you're broke
and you're like, what the fuck? Yeah,
that sucks. Worst. You feel
so like dehumanize. Yeah.
Well Mike and I used to go on vacations
and I know you can't afford that,
so it's no big deal. They're just, yeah,
just keeping the bed warm places.
That's the mother fuckers. Mike,
what they use to take you on Vicodin.
I know.
Like always wanting to go on vacations
nonstop. That's, yeah, because that's,
girls want to be pampered.
They want to go,
let's go to the spa and then that vision,
they love visuals of new
places. Like, Ooh, look at this.
It's also that they want to go on
vacation because it represents opulence.
It represents they're being taken
care of. You know? Here we are.
We're on a vacation. Yay. You took
me on Zoloft, primal man vacation.
Saw that. That's evolutionary
psychology, man. That is all primal shit.
You can't hate the chicks were wanting
that any more than they can hate you for
wanting a nice juicy ass and I knew
juicy ass every once in a while.
Oh Sam tripling opened up.
Deadbox sorry about that.
It's hard to keep it together, isn't
it? As we try my best, it's so hard.
Monkey DNA wants to spread.
Whoo. Whoo, whoo, whoo.
I think that's it. That's the
end of this fucking show. Jesus.
When you said you're an animal sounds,
it's time to end the show.
Brian's animal sound will be the final
Straw. Thank you to the fleshlight.
Yeah.
Okay Dude, thank you to the flashlight
for sponsoring us. Go Joe rogan.net.
Click the link and you get a 15% off.
Just type in the word Rogan this weekend.
Ari Shaffir and I will be at the West
Palm Beach Improv. That is the 28th,
29th and the 30th come on down bitches.
It's going to be a party.
Very excited about getting back there.
Also next week, next weekend, Friday,
February 4th at the Mandalay Bay theater.
It's the big fat fucked up show with me.
Joey Diaz and Ari Shaffir at
the Big Ass Lion King Theater.
And it's going to be fun as shit fired
up about that one. And Sam Tripoli.
What's going on with you man?
Where can people catch you?
Naughty show night at the Melrose Improv.
Are Tickets still available tomorrow
night? Naughty show Improv. And if I,
you can check out my youtube page,
man.
That's why I'm pushing right now to
youtube the uh, naughty show comedy page.
It's, that's it. How do they find it? Uh,
just you put in Youtube
Naddie show comedy,
Naughty show comedy page and
it says tickets is, yeah.
If you don't have tickets to
tomorrow night, you want to go,
you got to get them now because
the fucker will sell out.
It sells out every single time.
And the fucking show is hilarious.
And like I said,
it's not just a comedy show,
it's a comedy show and they have videos
and they have like games they play with
the audience and it's all like fast and
it keeps moving and all the comics or
add theater. But it's total add
theater. It's fun. It's a fun show.
The naughty shows us
solid cause like I said,
it really should be like one
of those casinos in Vegas.
It would be a great show.
Like if someone picked it up and put it
out, you want to go for the hard rock,
you know? And that's where they
had Beecher's madhouse too,
which is a very sort of similar zone here.
Now is he out here now?
He's at the Roosevelt. Well
that thing that he had, the uh,
in the hard rock was really successful.
They would sell that out all
the time and he's a great,
but it was more of a nightmare for comics.
So comics would do that and they have
harsh always war gig. After that,
I was like,
you would go to battle with a bunch of
psychos and swatching you'd walk into
sound. It was a wall of sound. You
could feel the sound on your skin.
It was so loud and you just throw
to the darkness and you just all,
you didn't want to get booed.
And I remember I had to file Paris
Hilton one time there. Did you ever,
did I ever tell you this story will
end on this? We'll end on this.
I had the fall, Paris Hilton. They're
like, we got surprise guests and uh,
she just has to go up real quick. And I'm
like her. She's like, yeah, it's parasail.
And I'm like, oh no. And then dude,
she's going up there and you knew
what was going to happen. She's,
they're going nuts for her nuts. And
I'm like, ah, good. Not good or bad.
Great. Love her. They love her.
Like, you know, like royalty,
Nelson Mandela entering
like the World Cup arena.
Like there's are all knuckleheads from
Idaho that are on vacation loving her and
they can't believe they're seeing royalty.
And it just goes,
and then they're like,
okay, thank you know,
and barely even says it's
comedian Sam Tripoli.
And I walk out and dude, I started
thrown. All of a sudden, boom, boom,
boom.
I started hearing a couple.
Now I'm like Bruce Lee in the movie when
he tastes his own blood and his crazy
eyes happens, gets that.
And I just locked down dude.
And I turned the booze because the key
to that room was getting the girls on
your side. Once you've got them on
your side, you could start killing.
So start out booing at the end. I got
a standing o everybody there was like,
I've never seen that before. You turn
them around. I turned them around.
I just stayed in the pocket sun. You
know, that's comedy store for you, dude.
That's the thing about the comedy store.
You're so used to taking care of
your own crowd because there's no,
you get in the Improv with someone yells,
there's a big guy who comes over and puts
his hands on the guy's shoulder goes,
bro, you gotta shut the fuck up or
leave. It's really sounding. Yep.
And they stopped it and they,
it keeps a nice friendly show.
But the problem with that is you don't
develop those combat comedy skills.
You gotta have those combat comedy skills
and that's come through is my over a
decade at the comedy store, man, you
learn. And I had thrown at me in that
place. I've never had a glass above.
I've had water bottles thrown at
me. People are savages, you know,
and more,
more like disenfranchise people go to
that club than any other club in the
country. And He, like you said,
emo bouncers, the whole thing.
It's God damn nightmare. You're bouncing.
Shouldn't have sweater vests. That's all.
I guess that's the, the
outfit. The hipster outfit,
right? Yeah. Sweater vests.
I don't know how having bad
eyesight as hip now too.
Maybe that's me just getting old.
It's some weird, creepy thing.
Like you want to look like your mom's dad.
Yeah. It's, you know, when he was young,
whatever. Bitches. That's it. That's it
for the show this week. Um, next week,
uh,
Bobby Lee is going to be on Tuesday,
so fired up about that and we're
probably going mad to get, uh,
everyone tweet him so he won't
back down like nonstop tweeting.
They can't ways or a bit flaky.
But who isn't? Comics are,
I mean that's one of the things
about Sam triply. That's an unusual,
you're very funny yet. You're very
disciplined. Very sure you get on,
you're always on time for shit. And
some Keno Comics, he never sleeps.
The funny ones are crazy. Joe
Diaz is crazy. You know, crazy.
Noro people are entertaining. This
is something of a, we're not perfect.
We're fucked up humans. But um, uh,
so next week Bobby Lee and hopefully
we're going to get Jody as an Ari Shaffir
in studio because we've got a studio
now. Bitches. That's what I'm calling it.
I love it. And it seems like a studio.
It's nice to be, yeah, because a,
we're doing that show a, which is next
Friday night at Mandalay bay. Okay.
We love you bitches and uh, we'll see
you next week. Thanks for tuning in.
As always, much appreciated.
Much love. Much good things,
positive energy, your way.
You do not have to be to you that you
were all your life. You know how to do it.
Rock it out, do it, do it right.
Just do it.