Five,
four,
three,
two,
one d Brennan Shab.
What's up doe that texting people?
No,
I'm reposting your posts,
man.
People didn't talk about that,
bro.
You gotta be on top of
that social media count,
Bro.
I'm trying man.
What's up?
How are you brother?
I'm good man.
This is a big weekend.
Big Ufc weekend.
Each weekend that just engaging and Eddie
Alvarez fight first team all violence.
Yeah.
That's like a,
that's the one I'm thinking about.
Maybe more than even the title fight.
Uh,
yes.
There's a few more than the title
fight that it's exciting to me though.
Is it?
Yeah,
it's,
I know it's not that much to you.
I like it.
It's not that I don't like it.
I like,
I like it,
but I love Francis and over him.
Yeah.
And I love gay g Alvarez.
I agree.
You don't,
Alvarez is an underdog.
I like his shot as an underdog.
Wow.
Cause I think it's incredible.
As much as I love gauging,
I should root for more.
I do root for them
because we were from the,
you know,
from Daenerys word,
my old team,
stuff like that.
I've trained a ton with
them back in the day.
I just feel like at a certain level that
stand in Bang Leonard Garcia type of
style it at the upper echelons,
it can get you in trouble.
And if Eddie Alvarez
wants to play that game,
he's going to lose.
But he has the skill set to,
you know,
to win by decision.
Outsmart them,
not play that meathead game.
See,
ah,
this is where I disagree.
I don't think that Justin kg
really plays a meathead game.
I think he plays a will game.
I think he's skillful.
But when,
when there's an opportunity to get
someone to do a battle of wills,
he's more confident in his will.
And I think at the upper echelon,
you can't play that game because think
about the other guy's at 55 play that
game with Tony Ferguson could be running
on it goes to play that game with Ed
Barboza.
Mm.
Yeah.
But I want to see that.
No,
don't get me wrong.
no,
no.
He's a fan favorite for sure.
I love gauging.
Absolutely love them.
I think at a certain level
you can't play that Chin down.
So filling those boats or you can
name a guy who's done it successfully.
Well it's all can we can't say Santina no.
So it's only him and he
hasn't faced the top guys yet.
Correct.
We're going to see what he's capable of
doing or whether or not he's capable of
switching it up if he has to.
But he's been able to survive 18
professional fist fights in world.
First of all,
17 of those are in world
series of fighting.
It's true.
Well first,
right?
The count a little.
You can not compare to the UFC.
No,
the Michael Johnson fight was the first
big that one counted and he got tagged
in that fight.
He got tagged.
You get lit up a little bit.
He got tagged and Michael Johnson,
uh,
eventually succumbed to the
violence cause he played his game.
Yeah.
Well at some point talking so much
shit to each other before that fight.
It was so like gates,
you just dragged him into a war.
What gate fee and I don't think a lot of
people realize is he's an all American
wrestler,
north,
northern Colorado.
Like that dude can wrestle
and he's athletic too.
Yeah,
we just,
he's this guy.
I'm good man.
He just wants to start an animal.
He refuse to go backwards.
That's sole thing.
It's an ego thing.
He doesn't want to take a step back,
which can get you in trouble I
think at only at a certain levels.
Again,
getting in trouble.
It's made them,
this got them this far
and he's a fan favorite.
But I think at the upper echelon you,
it's going to be tough,
but we're going to see how he adjusts.
Save.
He's in there with an Ensign Barboza book.
By the way.
They did Barboza and Habib
Bet your ass they did cheat.
Is that the Vegas fine?
Is that December 30th the whole
cards yet Holly Cyborg on the cards.
Nasty,
nasty car.
But that Barboza fight is so fascinating
to me because Barboza is so god damn
fast.
He's so fast.
He fucks people up with that.
Standup is standup is so crisp.
Norwin one Barboza fought
Anthony Pettis and you Mike Woo.
Yes.
You realize like,
wow,
this is some next level striking,
but you know he's vulnerable to cal by
cracked him with a jab member and cowboy
choked him out.
Yeah,
he's lost some kind of key
fights so he hasn't really had,
you know,
if dad Habib shows up
though looking like that,
you know,
he's just got to keep his weight down.
That's,
that's really the main thing.
Like I hope what Daniel
Cormier you said it's true.
Daniel Cormier,
he said that he's got a new nutritionist
and he's got them on point and he's in
the one seventies now.
It's,
which is way lighter than
he's ever been before.
You know,
this many weeks out of a fight,
I swear to God,
if Tiramisu ruins that,
I'm going to freak the fuck out.
What you really have to be concerned with,
and take this with a grain of salt,
because clearly I'm not a doctor,
but I would imagine that if you've had
not one but two instances where your body
shuts down from cutting weight too.
He had it with the Michael Johnson fight
and then he had it again in the fight
with Tony Ferguson where
we had to pull out.
But they said it was similar
to what happened in the
Michael Johnson weight cut.
Even worse.
Yeah.
But even worse.
Well he came in too heavy and he's
trying to drain too much water.
I mean it's as simple as that.
I think how bad it was
if you're from Russia,
from Russia,
he wrote,
fought with one leg and he got so bad
he had to check in with the doctor.
They brought him to the hospital.
I mean he was in,
his liver was shutting down and yeah,
he was,
he's kidneys.
Sorry.
Yeah,
it's not good.
Whatever it is.
I thought it was his liver to maybe,
maybe it wasn't kidneys.
Um,
but I'd read liver,
but I think I'd read it
from like a teammate talking
about it cause it might not
have been like that has
to do with weight cutting.
It's the kid.
Right.
And that's what fails people right
when they have like real issues.
Okay.
So,
Ooh,
smaller meal meat.
That is this weekend.
See,
this is a fight that people
aren't fucking talking about it.
No,
no.
The hooch salons on December
30th December 3rd meal.
Meek.
It can't make it right because
visa is he out first of all,
a meal.
Meeks.
First team.
All body.
How Savvis snitch needs
to snoop around Norway.
Yeah,
he's in the red.
It's all straight viking though.
It's get viking DNA that's like,
no,
he's just a natural freak.
Yeah,
this caught but so Zeus,
mine.
That's why he's a skinny guy.
Terrifying.
No one wants to fight them.
Nobody.
And no one's talking about him.
This is like Taz,
Dan.
Tell does.
Yeah.
Anybody.
So exciting to have him around.
I know he was a sleeper.
He said no one.
I feel,
I feel like this card though has been
kind of under the radar a little bit.
Little bit,
yeah.
A little bit like I
teach on Monday went bro.
You know Francis and Overeem fight
this weekend or day this weekend.
I totally forgot.
Did you see Francis break the
world record for the hardest punch?
I've skeptical hip eyes on that.
Oh,
I knew you were.
I'm just saying how many
guys have punch that thing?
Have you punched it?
I said thousands of punched it.
Oh,
I saw that company.
He responds.
Saint Joe's Twitter,
tweeter.
It's actually a competition.
They do it all over the world.
Did you question the thing?
Oh,
okay,
good.
Well we were like how many people have
done it and we found out the tire on
spawn came in second and then has market
and hit her with a left hook to cro.
Cop kick it.
It's a hearts punch.
Okay.
I don't think cro cop's
kicked it the hardest kick,
right?
Yeah,
but I'd like to see if Mark Hunt
hit that bitch with a left hook.
Right,
right.
I just need to see some of that stuff.
Like what other heavyweights
hit it because of course,
right.
This is huge,
but he might be the hardest
hitting heavyweight alive.
That's possible too.
I'd like to get car when on that thing.
Car went in his prime.
Even calling right now straight.
Yeah.
She seemed Mitchell and called
out carbon for steroids.
No,
she owns talking crazy shit.
Of course.
Matt does.
His name out there.
Yeah,
he is cause for the belt or
a heavyweight tournament.
You Know Matt spite and Roy.
Yeah.
And then they go,
you know,
shut a car,
went ass coker to be
an alternate on there.
So he gets hurt and then they
asked Matt about it and he's like,
I mean they need a test
that that fricking guy,
there's no way he's clean and just
one about this whole business.
Like anyone who I fight has to be clean.
I doubt Kerwin is so now
Carlin's calling out Matt now.
Careful what you ask for a Maddie.
Ooh.
Yeah.
Because even if he's clean it,
good luck.
Those are the owns.
Let's get some just
caveman bone structure.
A lot of anger built up.
You don't want that put back to France.
Break that record.
I need to see who,
what other heavyweights hit
that thing before I celebrate,
right?
Yeah.
Yeah man.
How many fucking great guys have
backs given out on in their prime?
That's a big one.
I mean,
Keynes.
Yeah,
it should be one chain's a big one.
Those two guys alone.
So the rumor was Kane fighting at UFC
two 20 in Boston against Cain and steep
bay.
Yeah.
That's not happening.
Not Happening.
How do you know?
What do you know?
Tell us.
Tell close sources.
It's not what came.
Won't be ready.
Not Happening.
Steve.
Steve Bay of fight.
The winner if it,
depending if the good of Francis over him.
So what is the sort of,
what's,
what's the issue that's holding them back?
I'm not sure.
I just know you won't be ready to
buy some sort of recovery issue.
Some injury thing.
Something.
I'm just not ready.
Say No bullshit.
Wow.
They chose to,
they have a fight for
that January 20th not yet.
That's really soon.
Yeah.
January 20th yeah.
Isn't that seem soon?
Pretty soon.
Yeah,
definitely sooner.
Two months you,
especially if it's a
heavyweight title fight.
Yeah,
it's less than two months.
That's soon.
Yeah.
And I'm hoping for a big
fight announcement cause
I'm at the Wilbur the night
before.
Sir.
What else is on that card already?
Wow.
It's really a well really light.
Really well there.
They're getting around to Urbino Boston,
this Dane,
his hometown.
So He's not going to disappoint.
Glace and t bow back in the
house after a pest and hot.
What is he going to look like?
Not like that.
What do you think is going to look like?
Cause he's the freakiest of
the freaks at 155 pounds.
He was,
those days are over,
dude.
He would come into the Octagon,
oh my God.
On fight night.
And you're like,
how the fuck are you 155 in the world?
How the fuck are you?
Not a middle weight.
He's a middle weight.
I mean,
I'm not exaggerating.
He looked like a fucking middleweight.
He looked like Paul Harris when
Paul Harris was the middle weight.
He looked like glaze and t ball.
It looks when he's,
yeah,
so jacked and skillful.
Hell yeah.
You know he's gonna Bounce bounced.
He's a fucking animal.
So he's got everything going.
But I was disappointed that steeping
Cain wasn't going to go down because I
think if Steve Bay beats cane,
then there's argument for steep pays
the best heavyweight of all time.
If we were to beat Cain,
well if he beats Cain healthy cane,
that's,
see the thing is what we
really need is time machine.
We need to fucking take primetime cane
and stick them in pride with primetime
fader.
Let's find out.
And you got to do it in pride
too because with no commissions,
I don't know what the fuck
they were doing over there,
but I know the result,
if I'm just looking at the result
as a person who's an analyst,
I got to look at prime time fade or as
number one prime time fade or throwing
bombs on Nogueira when he's pinned
against the fucking ring apron Trevor,
that garrison the corner
faders on top of them,
just dropping those casting punches,
those crazy Russian
punches to come like this.
I am just,
Ooh.
That's why it's,
it's difficult when [inaudible]
who's the best of all time?
It's like all right,
well we go on off pre snitch or are we
going snitch here cause we go golden
snitch.
You got steeper yet.
But even if you don't know
who the golden snitches is,
Jeff says Devinsky and again,
that's not a,
it's not a bad time.
He's coming on the podcast.
We're working date out
right now and I'm a fan.
I liked the guy he's doing.
Yeah,
I'm not,
when I say Golden Snitch,
I'm just playing around with four.
Used to be who had the best cheater,
who had the best chemists,
who had the best doctors,
the best doctor who had the best guy
that could make you test positive or test
clean rather after the way in.
That's all you had to do
except for looking at him.
He's a guy,
you know,
find this weekend where you,
obviously he's done some stuff,
some guarantees life,
and he's been,
he's tested hot and just paid the price
and then the golden snitch comes in and
his team goes,
I dude,
you can't just rely on power.
You'll start using a
technique which you have.
So let's focus on it.
He's doing pretty damn well.
Pretty damn well.
He had that one loss before.
It's that loss.
Stevie,
he was smoking dudes.
His lost a steep bay.
Wasn't that bad cause he had
steep in a lot of trouble.
Definitely.
We actually thought,
you know,
in the post fight kicked,
kicked me us,
they choked him out.
He tap that myrtle thing.
Guys were stunned.
That was a close fight though.
Very close.
And then he goes on,
you know,
beats,
we're doomed.
His last fight and now he's
fighting Francis where you know,
that's not obviously it's France.
Tough fight fray Frances,
the favorite,
but dude over him was the best striker,
most decorated striker of all time,
the heavyweight division like
over and can win that fight.
You know,
I broke down in my podcast how many
times over it's been stopped on the last
podcast,
last MMA podcasts.
It's crazy in 19 I don't mind,
I think it's like 13 and MMA or somewhere
between 11 and 13 and MMA and an
additional three or four and kickboxing.
A lot of stoppage losses.
It's a lot.
But tink,
he's been fighting more than anyone to,
yeah.
But if you look at the last few years,
there's an exorbitant amount
of losses by stoppage.
For over him.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's quite a few number of things,
right.
It's the all the,
all the wear and tear in the ring.
Then also not being able to do gear.
See,
look,
Ben Rothwell,
Travis Browne,
the big foot silver one
that all of those have,
hold on.
Don't let her go back.
Um,
those,
all of those happen inside
of a couple of years.
Man,
it's one year,
but also one year from February of 2013
literally to September of 2014 that's
not much time and he's been brutally
knocked out three times in that time.
Well at least two of them are really
brutal to Ben Rothwell fight was like,
he got cracked with a big shot and
dropped and then they stopped the fight.
I think at a good time.
It could happen to anybody
that could happen to anybody,
but the big foot fight that wasn't a
regular k o that was goddamn ruthless.
Travis Brown and got him pretty bad
to that front kick to the grill.
Big Foot fight was so interesting
though because it was so obviously post
snitch.
Yup.
It was just,
he didn't figure it out yet.
Ooh.
Burrim when he beat Brock Lesner
that was the ubering Securus man.
Never entered an doctor.
Ever Naf fight.
When you look across the octagon to 65
maybe 10% body fat jack to the tits check
please.
I'm a health and best
kick boxer to ever fight.
How about Oh Jesus,
what does it,
what are you going to do now man?
And then he figures it out though.
You have that.
And then he figured out and
junior dos Santos fight.
Yeah,
but and now he'll before backhoe Uber
ream up when his ubering before the golden
snitch.
Good luck back in that dude,
that dude,
you're paying the price now I'm a fucking
will turn his back and run out and go
right on and it works.
Hey,
just get the fuck out of
there by any means necessary.
I wonder if he would ever be,
you know,
that was one of the things that
your own brought about Joe Silva.
He said that Joe Silva told him that he
got a small ring or that it was going to
be a large ring when he fought
Roy big country and it wasn't.
It was a small ring,
so he was,
he said that he was upset about that.
I've had that happen before too though.
But again,
I'm not defending.
Joe Silva have worked
a ton with Joe Silva,
obviously all over the years.
It doesn't really work like that.
It really doesn't work.
You can make demands on the cage and
and asked for this and asked for that.
It is what it is and you
might prefer something.
They're like,
yeah,
maybe.
But Joe Silva's dealing with
so many different dynamics,
the cage,
he goes,
hey,
what's the case?
So am I go,
it's a 24 foot.
All right,
cool.
Yeah,
it gets the bigger cage.
You want to fight or not man,
like there's so much going on.
I don't think he purposely
lied to Matt and was like,
it's a big cage.
Take the fight.
But I'm wonder like what fights would
be like if the cage is much smaller,
less technique.
You're going to get a
bunch of gates he fights,
which is in a bad thing.
But if you're a technical guy,
like mitre owned with has,
who's crazy athletic with footwork
or a Barboza or Conor McGregor,
you don't want that small cage.
It limits your resources
and your abilities.
You get smothered and it cuts all your
angles short everything off the off the
exchange.
Like if you're too close to a cage and
anything off have to exchange a cut and
short,
like you're gonna run into the cage.
So now you can't go back that way because
you won't get out of the way the shot
and you can't go back that way.
So you have like limited
amount of movements that
you can make it the gracilis
paradise.
Yeah.
Well it's also a brawlers paradise.
Right?
So those two things can be good if,
if,
if the fight was done in a
smaller outdoor and could be,
would never lose.
Yeah.
I think.
Yeah,
for sure.
But I think also one thing that I would
favor is like real high level Muay Thai
guys cause they're clincher.
Yeah.
They're always clinching.
And,
and,
and going after each other.
You know,
and I think that that style,
like the Muy Thai style is not like
a Wonderboy style with their slide.
Now the way of everything,
they're standing right in front of you
and checking things and attacking clinch.
I don't think it would
be better for the sport.
Maybe not better for the sport,
but it would be interesting to
see how it favors certain styles.
And I think that it would favor a
good wrestler with real good Moitai.
I think it would ever be a
real good environment for them.
You think if,
let's say Francis were to just start
over in which listen over to music,
watch his p's and q's or 15 minutes,
you need to use this technique
run when you have to.
Even even if people don't like it,
you win by decision.
Great man.
But if he doesn't watch the p's
and q's and gets starts by Francis,
you think Francis deserves
a shot right away.
It's Francis Starches and Francis is
the hottest commodity in the heavyweight
division.
So he deserves a shot.
Yeah.
I think Overeem is ranked number one.
No,
he's number one canes.
Not Number one.
No.
Okay.
So He's number one is,
which is crazy for him to take this
fight and for dooms number two.
So no one knows.
And that's really,
that's really nuts.
Cause that fight like that the,
those two had,
boy that was as close to fight as you
can get and most people thought that for
doing one.
Yeah.
I think for doom,
doom,
heroin got robbed.
No one got robbed,
but it was,
she'll fight for doom.
Heard him and over him.
Never really hurt for doing.
Not,
not the same way.
At least I'm sure he hit him hard,
I thought were doing when the fight
I've taught for doing one to fight too.
I thought that one brown where
he rocked him and hurt him.
That should have been,
that was the most significant
moment of the fight for sure.
So how do you not make Francis go
through for doom to get to steepen?
That's interesting.
It's a very good question because
that's a tougher matchup for Francis.
Then over him.
It's a very,
something mother felt.
I don't know what's
going on with Steve Bay.
Why don't they have a
challenger for Steve Bay?
Like why is that heavy weight division?
It's a bunch of dinosaurs.
Right,
but is that what it is?
I mean,
cause I had heard that there
was some contract negotiations.
Shit going on.
There's,
there's that.
Yeah,
I've heard that.
I know where that Penn's
been sucking on that pen.
It's just not,
I just put it here.
I don't suck on it and I will suck on it.
I'll put on my lip.
I won't suck on a tall Nah man.
Just the tip will suck on it though.
Um,
I lived on the outside.
I know,
I know Steve Bay's ready
to go for February.
Yes.
Yeah.
So they just don't have a car.
They don't have an opponent for him.
Maybe they'll try to do
it for January for Boston.
They're,
they're,
they're hoping that,
you know,
Francis in this over him thing work out.
Yeah,
because listen,
I was very mad.
It's too soon.
A rematch with Steve Bay for over him.
It's a very interesting fight.
It's very interesting.
Can sell it.
Especially if he beats Francis who
everyone is so high and mighty on.
Yeah.
If you were to get by him,
how can you deny it?
Yeah,
it's true.
Frances is just,
whew.
Whew.
Whew,
whew.
I'm not on board yet.
I'm terrified.
Have you seen him fight live?
Uh,
no.
Nope.
I have not.
Should be illegal and foot
easy.
It's have you seen over in fight?
Have you seen him?
Me fucking Mark Kahn Indo.
The Brock Lesnar fight was probably
the scariest one because I was like,
this guy is the greatest
heavyweight of all time,
but he smashed Rockledge.
Only time I'm like,
oh my God.
What if he could do that to Cain
was a superhero where it's like,
ah,
fuck,
I don't have the resources
to get on the same shit.
But now that he's off
the shit and he flatline,
Mark Hunt,
that's scary to meet.
If they had,
I know,
right?
What did,
they had no testing though.
None.
Zero like he able to make like the,
the testing requirements is
minimal as they were back then.
He able,
he pulled it off.
He tested clean gay day.
Imagine if there was,
God bless.
No fucking Desi.
Like he had a cycle off.
Yeah.
Like what if he's looked
like that cycling?
It looks like that,
but think about this.
Francis is as natural as
fucking coconut water.
That mother fuckers all natural.
Now imagine if he could take something.
Okay,
then what do we do?
No problem.
We've got a real problem.
Shred city hits harder than anyone
now and eating fricking plantation.
There's Overeem in the Uber theme days.
Bom Bom browns is no pump though.
Bring up Francis that fine mode.
The skin prime.
Ooh,
Brene versus prime tank Abbott.
Who takes it?
I get the fuck out of
hilarious Sally dear.
You're so silly.
Yeah,
he doesn't look the same,
but he doesn't look bad.
Like if he was just a heavyweight fighter
and he was built the way he's built
now you would say he's a powerful guy.
I mean if you see him in his last fight,
pull up the last fight
with him versus Mark Hunt.
I mean,
he definitely doesn't
look like a small guy.
He's still somewhere around
the two 50 something range.
Everyone's body's luge guy.
Literally everyone's
bodies look different.
Yeah.
Everybody's,
they look different.
Eric Silva was a big one
that people kept bringing up.
Like he looks,
he's ladies time piece.
Yeah.
And then it just all changed.
You have a see like you look at Alister,
they're like,
he's just got more body fat,
more stomach fat,
less muscle is a little bit of a guy.
Like he has almost a dad bod
that worked out on the weekend.
I wouldn't say that you said that.
Not me.
Well,
the fit dad bought though.
You know what I'm saying?
Like an active dad.
Yeah.
I mean he's just,
but what's interesting is that he's
such a fighter that gear or no gear.
I mean he comes to fucking fight.
He comes to kill you because he is the
best technique to look at that fucking
chaos.
Oh my gosh.
Flatline mark.
You know,
Mark Cup flew to Vegas to get all this
stuff checked off the brain scan all
that.
And what did they say about it?
I'm not sure but,
but he at least made the effort to fly
from Australia to there so he can clear
this up.
You get back in the cage because again,
I think for Francis it,
unless he does an argument,
you know,
if he just goes out there and
starches over him in 10 seconds,
like all right,
well we've got to figure
out what he's worth.
Let's give him steeper.
But if he doesn't,
man,
you could give a mark con that's a great
fight and give them for doom cause you
gotta walk to do some fire cause look at
the fire Steve Bay walked through to be
the heavyweight.
It's a good point.
And you know,
he really is only beaten our Lawsky.
It's just where we're looking at,
um,
at the,
the magnitude of his performances
against guys that were in,
in his league.
You know,
it's like you just see the
magnitude of his impact.
Like he's,
he's a guy that you'd go woo,
who the fuck's gonna stop that?
But they're all favorable.
Matchups Yup.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like your favorite baseball player.
He's only hitting off the pitcher who
we know he can hit home run off of.
When you give them a guy who actually
can so some junk and he's not as good,
you know,
or if he hits that guy,
I think he is what he's worth.
Well prime time came when
it showed us what was up,
you know,
a prime time came versus him
where you can get them down,
hold him down,
beat him mind time cane,
you know I,
you know,
I also think Steve Bay right now,
he might,
you know he's in his prime,
might be at the end of his prime,
but he's going to,
he's in his prime.
Yeah.
Things.
I don't think Steve Bay's at
the end of his prime at all.
I think Steve Bay's right in there.
He's in the,
he's right there where he
could get Francis and he's,
I want to see Francis Wrestle.
That's all going to see.
But again from sources they said I'm a,
he's a nightmare to take down.
I believe it.
I mean it looks so God damn
strong and the way he hits,
I mean he hits your,
your,
your window of opening is so little
and your mistakes are so costly.
Anytime you make a mistake with him,
you just get bombed on so hard.
You're like no buck.
But when you got a guy like
Cain or steep it where they go,
I know he got power,
I'll put my chest in your
fricking chess for 25 minutes.
I put my head straight and your
chest good like firing off man.
Oh,
when you do fire off,
I'm gonna take you down.
At least keep you busy so you can't
just fire off and not deal with that
combinations on you with constant barrage.
Stop and strikes.
Keith,
Keith haring you over and over again.
Ammar fis,
elbows,
punches,
punches.
You never get tired of.
Francis is similar to me as a jds.
He similar,
similar where,
you know,
decent footwork.
I don't think he's athletic as Jds,
but good footwork,
power puncher.
But when you get a guy like Steve Bear
Cain who don't play that game on the
outside with the,
I just want to get dirty.
You're in some trouble,
man.
Well it's going to be interesting to
see if he's in some trouble because you
know if he could stop the take down,
if he can keep those guys
standing up with them,
then you're going to see some nightmares
because he's getting better all the
time.
The thing about Francis,
he hasn't even really
been fighting that long.
He doesn't have this long crazy record.
No,
not at all.
In the UFC was like,
you might be something special.
Let's come to Vegas and you just
worked out in this sports center.
We inject this bane supplement and
you whatever the fuck it is you,
you don't even want him
to use protein powder.
He's worried about testing hot.
Wow.
He takes nothing good.
Perfect.
We needed to see what the fuck's possible.
I agree.
What kind of genetics are there out there?
He's like,
you know what?
We were talking yesterday
about a Bo Jackson Callen
and I were going on about Bo
Jackson.
But there's certain athletes
that in their prime,
they just like were just a
notch above everything else,
like just out of the womb.
It was on just a different animal.
They didn't all start at
the same starting line.
Herschel Walker,
another good example like freak.
What's that?
Now see my prom,
you,
we can't put France and
that discussion yet.
Not yet.
Not even close,
not even close to there yet.
Some work to do,
not in this as far as
greatness and accomplishments,
freakish,
but as far as like physical freak.
Yeah.
I don't know either,
but Francis scares the shit out of me.
When you watch him hit people,
it's boom.
You see them go,
oh Jesus.
He's just so big and so powerful and so
undeniable when he comes moving in for
the kill is undeniable.
It very scary guy.
But you're totally right.
He's gotta be tested.
We've seen many,
many guys like him go bust.
Overeem is,
uh,
he,
he's a test but Overeem's
a guy where for 15 minutes,
if Francis lands that fricking bomb of
his and you know over and is probably
going out because it's
Chin's not the same.
He's been in so many up and down wars,
you know,
and he's um,
for instance is a naturally bigger man.
I mean you gotta remember Alster fought
a two oh five before he fought chuck at
two Oh five used to be real skinny.
That's right.
Francis is a big motherfucker.
He's big.
I mean he is,
he's a natural 265 pound man thick dude.
Yeah,
that's a dangerous guy because
if in the beginning of the fight,
especially he's,
it'd be pushed pressure and he moves
forward and puts pressure and he's like
real explosive and fast.
But something gets in there,
something gets in there.
Here,
here's the x factor is
over him in the clinch.
There's no one better than
the heavyweight division.
It's true.
We haven't seen Frances in the clinch
with a worldclass guy like over him.
Cause again over and we've,
we forget cause the demolition
man has been around so long,
he gets in that clinch,
those elbows,
those knees best needs in
that a fucking division.
God.
Yeah.
I mean yeah,
that's Fujita one.
Yeah.
Those,
that was horrifying.
Yeah.
It was killed a guy who's that
other guy that kickboxer to share?
I think the kickboxer that'd be fought
over and k one where they decided to uh,
make it so he could only hold one hand
behind the head cause Alster would get
two hands by in your head.
And that was 99.
Demolition man.
Just dropped those knees on your chin.
The funnest file in the car to me.
Francis over him.
Just where they go,
the career path,
stuff like that.
I say,
um,
the Gagey Alvarez one is,
but they're both right up there.
They're either one.
Look,
there's three giant fights in his card.
The Aldo Holloway fight
is a giant fight for me.
I want that fine.
I want to see it.
I liked the fight just if we're going
off all those words saying he did have
issues with his legs.
That's why he wasn't kicking before.
I don't buy it.
I really don't buy it.
And if for that,
if that was true,
I don't but kept because in his
previous sites and fights after that,
he hasn't been using all of his tools.
Well,
I think there's a
strategy for that though.
The Frankie Edgar fight,
I'm really believed that he didn't use
his kicks because I think he felt like
Frankie was training for those kicks and
he was training to kick take them down
off the leg kicks.
Everyone kicks though.
We know all that,
but he's got damn good at.
He didn't write.
He just pleased to me.
He's become very fundamental
in just boxing plant his feet.
He's gotten away from what
got them to the dance.
Maybe.
Maybe or we can go,
he was hurt if we,
yeah,
if we're basing it on those two
fights and if you have to believe him,
and I'm just going to believe I'm
just for the sake of believing him.
If he says his leg was hurt,
it makes sense.
It also makes sense how he
was getting tired quick.
You got tired pretty quick
in that fight and they did,
which if he had a leg
injury it would make sense.
You wouldn't be able to
push as hard and camp.
And he was,
he was winning those early rounds.
There was a huge speed advantage for
all Aldona early in those rounds.
And then Max Hollywood took over.
Yeah.
Well Max Holloway measures you,
you know,
he doesn't burn himself out early
and he's got tremendous endurance.
He measures you and he
starts putting it on you,
putting it on you.
What Max is really good
at is distance control,
really good at movement and distance
control and just not being there.
It's also adding speaking long.
Yup.
And the kill does it in the cut doesn't
kill him for one 45 he's very tall,
very physically striking.
Mack truck hits like a truck and
he's just got that thing his,
you're savage champion warriors spirit.
You're going to have to kill
him and get him out of the man.
And he's just,
he's a fascinating guy.
Cause he's like Hawaiian to the bone.
Yes or no.
And you go over to Hawaii,
man,
and he has the next shot
at being like the new Bj,
Bj Penn.
Bj Penn is a legend and he's a legend
from the early days and he's alleged and
when he went up to heavyweight,
fought Leo Machida,
Bj was up fucking monster.
And his favorite people.
Yeah,
a monster.
So it's going to be a while before
max gets into those lofty grounds,
but he's on his way.
He's on his way.
And what's interesting is Bj and Max
are to the nicest guys in the world.
Super Nice.
They both have that in common.
And the both from Hawaii.
Both monsters.
No,
Matt Max could,
especially at one 45 because he,
the Conners never going back there for,
for Max.
He could,
he could be a Bj Penn type.
Yeah.
I wonder if he challenges Connor.
No.
If child,
if Connor comes back,
who knows?
What did Conor do?
Did you just get in a brawl in a bar?
Is that real?
Oh,
it's so,
you know,
in Dana White Scrim,
he goes,
listen,
if it was that big,
there'd be more video of it.
Dan Goes,
I,
I'm Dana's basically saying I'm
skeptical hip that happened.
People that I know in Dublin and
that are blowing me up or saying,
dude,
it's real colors,
a bit of trouble.
Cause he has a friend from one area of
Ireland that's in this mafia and that got
beat up by these guys.
Connor finds out the guys who beat
up his friend are in this bar.
It's kind of comes in and
beats the hell out of that guy.
Well that guy's associated with this,
you know,
pretty intense mafia family over there.
So now there's a hit out on Connor's,
what they're saying what?
Yes,
for 900 gram.
What now?
How much is that?
It's true.
How much of it is speculation?
I'm not sure.
Holy Shit.
And cause on my podcast I was like,
you know,
I don't know.
It sounds like a bunch of Hoopla people
just want to be associated then I've so
many people in the middle going,
bro,
here's the background of the guys that
he's messing with and they've done some
gnarly shit.
Like there's a a boxing,
a promotion that they just came in
dressed as like mass men and shut up the
whole thing.
They're like,
he's dealing with gnarly dudes.
Whoa.
But then again,
I guess in Dublin especially
kind of being who he is,
you're going to have these associations
with this underground world,
stuff like that.
We're trying to say about Dublin,
Bro.
It's awesome.
My favorite place I've ever been,
man,
that is terrible.
That's a terrible scene.
I don't know what to believe.
I don't know the ins and outs of it.
I don't,
you know,
in,
in Dana,
you against it.
This then is scrum.
It's always fascinating and it does
those scrums because it's all hearsay,
stuff like that.
But then they go,
you know what's next for county?
You've got to fight for me.
He goes,
listen man,
guys,
$100 million in the bank fighting socks.
I don't know if he's ever gonna
get punched in the face again.
Here's $100 million.
So legit point to totally legit point,
but $100 million can go a lot faster
than you think if you'd like to ball.
Because here's the thing,
you don't really get $100 million.
You get $100 million,
but then you got to pay taxes,
you got to pay your trainer fee,
you've got to pay whatever
you pay your manager CSF,
Andy,
he wouldn't have 17 after times.
Yup.
Nope,
nope,
nope.
So legs,
hundred Erica in America,
if you make a hundred I mean like
realistically I think it's everything over
$250,000 a year is taxed 30
35% 8% or something like that.
And then you know,
you've got to think he's got managers and
trainers and agents and when you make,
here's a question that I
should know the answer to,
but I do not.
When you make money,
if you're from Ireland,
you make money in America.
Do you have to pay taxes in America?
Because I know you have to do that.
If you make money in Canada
can make money in Canada,
like you'd do gigs Canada,
you have to pay taxes,
taxes in Dublin and in
England and Australia when
they come to also have to pay
those taxes.
When you get home,
you have to pay your own taxes.
Yeah.
So I don't know if you get double taxed,
but there's ways around it.
So let's say,
let's say make 60 let's get to six.
I'm going to say 40.
Okay,
cool.
Let's be cool.
But that's just based off of the fight.
Now think about as endorsed peaking,
go through $40 million in three years.
If you're a complete,
who's Amania fucking moron?
If you the same type of
guy that is Conor McGregor.
I don't know about that
because said we're,
we're basing off his Instagram,
which is a persona of him.
Right?
So you,
so you see the royals Royces,
these watches a lot of the stuff.
You're married a lot of those
Rolls Royce's people give to them.
They donated,
he's renting this cause he
was standing on one of them.
Yeah.
They're like,
Bro,
this day you're shitting on a Rolex.
But um,
or Rolls Royce.
Yeah.
So I think,
I don't know if he's that
stupid with his money.
Hmm.
That's interesting.
Well,
if that's the case,
if he's not really completely balling
out of control and all those Bentley
photos and everything like that is
all just for show and it's part of the
persona and part of the act.
That makes sense.
Well,
if that's the case and he just
wants to live like a fairly large,
he's loving Lord,
don't get me wrong,
he's living,
but he's not Mike Tyson,
stupid John Jones.
He's a private jet.
Stupid.
Right?
And he's like,
can a law that can be borrowed?
Yeah,
it could be.
I mean,
not even saying private jets to,
but if you've got $100 million to
do whatever the fuck you wants,
or what I'm saying is if you want it
to last for the rest of your days,
well if you just invest it right,
you're,
you're straight.
See,
the other thing is that the amount
of possibility for him to make money,
it's so staggering right now that I don't
see that this is going to be the end
of his career.
I just do not agree with anybody that
thinks he's not going to fight again.
I think you're crazy.
I think he's going to get bored.
I think he's going to want a challenge.
I think he's going to realize there's a
tremendous amount of money out there to
be made.
I'm not crazy.
Dana White's crazy cause I
think he's going to fight.
Dana said he doesn't think he's going
to fight against fighting sucks though.
Those aren't my words.
I actually think he's going to fight again
for cause I think he's more than just
about money.
I think he's more about his
legacy and what what is,
you know kind of foot mark in the sport
is and I think he knows he has to defend
that 155 pound title but
then he also knows many pack,
y'all called him out and he
can go make a quick whatever,
50 60 million fighting Pacquiao.
Yeah.
So there's a lot of opportunities there
but I also know for a fact he has a shit
load of opportunities
in Hollywood as well.
Nonstop.
Damn.
So for,
he's going to be fine either way.
As long as he doesn't get
shot by a Dublin gangster,
he should be fine.
Yeah.
Fuck.
The other thing is,
is GSPs not fighting Whitaker,
gs.
Ps,
the rumor mill from what I hear is he
might want to see if you can cut to 50 f
to cut to 70 see if he can still get to
70 and do a super fight with Conor that
Conor.
See that's what I said.
I'd said that Connor versus just p
would be the biggest financial boom.
If I was WME,
I'd be like come,
that's what they want to do.
That's in a,
in a dream situation.
That's what all sides would want to have
happen in GSP is taking time off now,
but I know he's going to see if he can
cut the 70 to possibly make that happen.
They should be able to do it.
When you think or is he get he is to
thicker than the three musketeers right
now.
He was thick city and that Bisping fight.
He was pretty jacked.
It's a lot of uh,
Lou must be doing well on the
strength and conditioning.
Yeah.
Fucking,
I mean,
he's a muscular dude.
He's getting older too.
So the way it comes on,
you know,
but I wonder what he's doing for
like his weightlifting routine.
You just have to get super strict also.
I bet.
I bet he could do it.
Switch at 70,
if you know,
he realizes the possibilities on,
on super fight like Connor because have
you seen the numbers on his fight with
Brisbane?
No.
Uh,
I think uh,
it came in at about eight 65.
That's not bad.
Not Great though.
It's not as good as he could do.
Well it's not,
it's not as good as the,
the paper view.
Blockbuster stars.
No,
but it's not what can
happen for four years.
See,
the thing is,
and you and I were talking about this,
is that we both agreed like there's a
lot of fans that are fans now the dental
have a fucking clue who he is,
at least didn't it before that fight?
No,
they came in was Rhonda
Post Rhonda and Post Conner.
I think Rhonda brought a gigantic group
in and then Connor brought another even
more gigantic group in.
And especially the kids
today that are like 18,
19 2021 they have no fucking idea.
No clue.
You have to be hardcore
to know who GSPS correct.
But now they know.
Now they know he's the
middle weight champ.
Holy Shit.
He came back.
People will talk and it'll build it up
and then the next one will be bigger.
I think.
See,
I even if he fought Whitaker,
I don't think it breaks a million.
Even now think you're,
um,
you're probably in the ballpark.
I think it's calmed down.
It'd be close to a million.
I think he does fine
around eight 50 to 900.
Again,
it's,
it might be a little better.
Maybe it's an Australia for paper view.
I think he has to have a,
a partner,
a dance partner like
Connor to break a million.
Hmm.
Well,
the Conor fight would be
a million of Connor fall.
My Mom,
let me get that straight up.
Yeah.
Know if Kotler and Jamie Fun
and 2 million and 2 million.
Especially now.
Yeah.
Anything he does after that.
Floyd Mayweather,
there's so much,
you know,
just hype.
Everyone sees next move.
It's going to,
it's going to be biggest UFC of all time.
Yeah.
Just for that boy.
There's not a lot of like giant matchups
right now that are looming that make me
excited more than that one does.
Connor versus GSP is like,
whoa.
That's like a,
like,
I want to sit down and think
about that one for a while,
but we'll see.
I have thought down and
thought about it and it's,
it's not a s a great fight for Conor
said 70 is not where Connor belongs.
A Smashley with the greatest
welterweight of all time.
Who can grapple his balls off apple,
his balls off.
He gets you to the ground.
He's gonna fuck you up.
Fuck you up.
He's so much stronger.
George is so big now.
When I put my arm around him,
when I was doing the interviews
with them until the Wayans,
I was like,
what in the fuck?
And this is like Wade in rehydrated all
day and then I get to it at like six
o'clock,
which is what they're doing now,
which is kind of interesting.
But I was like,
wow,
he's like 200 pounds plus he's a big boy.
Yeah,
he's way bigger than it used to be.
And they're like,
everybody thought that Bisping was going
to have this big advantage over them
size wise.
But when you see George George
also has a very long style,
keeps his weight legs wide,
bounces around a lot in and out.
And so he,
he accomplishes a lot with his,
like his distance and his ability to
close the distance until I though the size
and reach advantage that Bisping
had just didn't play in it.
All that being said though,
Biz,
I mean not Bisbing.
Um,
GSP has no business being in the middle.
Wait,
that's not the land for him.
Um,
Robert Whitaker's dangerous
fight for him at one 85 it,
but it's really the only fight grant.
He's the champ that's the
size isn't that big of a deal.
The problem is he's in his prime,
he's young,
hits like a Mack truck and he,
oh,
he's good at everything.
He's good at everything.
And He fires fucking bombs at your face.
Like he's trying to take you back there.
Yeah,
he's,
he's tactical striking just
to the opening is there,
it's very interesting with a Whitaker
because he's the smaller guy at 85 in the
land of the dinosaurs right now in the
land of the giants with Brock cold,
you got a Uol jock gray,
all these monsters Weidman's a big boy.
The of all those lots losses.
Then you have a guy like GSP who's your
interim champion and then you got Kelvin
that people are talking about.
We're Kelvin's done undersized guy to
where GSPs on the interim champion.
He's a legit champion.
Whitaker's the interim champion.
That's true.
Which is such bullshit.
It's kind of crazy,
right?
Yeah.
So,
so you have two champions,
right?
But I'm doing such bullshit.
Is it though?
Yeah,
it's bullshit.
It's bullshit about it.
Let's take four years off.
You jump the queue.
You fight a guy that's perfect matchup
for you and you when they got Whitaker
who've walked through
fucking monster land.
But in his defense he
couldn't fight that he,
he's injured.
I know I'm just saying.
Right.
But they,
they,
if they could not have made the Whittaker
versus Bisping fight any earlier cause
Whitaker's need was fucked up.
I mean he had a PR so there was no
fight to be made other than this in the
middleweight division.
Unless you wanted to have EOL just
fought for the title and last fight.
Bisping for the real title after
he lost for the interim title.
That doesn't necessarily make sense.
Everyone forbid we should wait.
Well,
I think heaven forbid,
let's rush it.
Didn't you enjoy the GSP fight?
Yeah,
it did.
So while I'm not a hitter,
what's the,
uh,
objecting Da.
There's no object and I'm
just saying as far as,
to me,
a real,
the real champion,
85 would be Whitaker.
I don't see him.
I don't give GSP that title.
I do because he knocked out Bisping rot,
knocked out.
Rockhold it's really simple.
Rockhold was absolutely
the world champion.
This plant based thing
absolutely knocked him out.
Correct.
And then he beat Dan Henderson,
which is,
there's an argument there is a little bit,
aren't we like it as guys
who are Dan Harris fans?
But let's be real.
It's perceived the the number one guy
in world at that time to fight from
[inaudible] to give
Bisbing what he wanted,
which is a shot at redemption.
Yeah.
But he can't fight.
He won the fight.
Although Dan thought he won.
You know,
I could see Dan definitely
heard it more like God.
How about Biz means chance.
Yeah.
Incredible.
And what Dan said after the fight,
I wished they judge fights on how
the other guy looks after the fight.
That's hilarious.
Because he didn't have a scratch on him.
His business should go down as the top
three middle weights of all time just
based off doing this with
one fucking eye poodle.
He has one.
I'm man.
What he's doing is insane.
Yeah.
He's got oil in his right eye.
Right.
To keep his resumes.
Man.
He's one of the best of all time.
To me,
retinas are scary shit man.
Scary Shit.
When that stuff starts calling Shane,
if you look at what Whitaker
has done to become champions,
it's a little more impressive to,
well it's a little more impressive
because he'd beat you over Romero and he'd
beat Yoel Romero and I'm fucking
tough fight any beat him after you.
Well we're Merrill hyper extends his
leg and blew his knee out in the first
round and before that he starts Jock,
Ara,
starched starch,
the starch.
So it's like,
you know,
he's walked through the fire.
This same thing with Francisca.
No.
You know like you got to walk through
that fireman to me to get there.
I agree.
So,
but that's not the world we live in.
But what you got to
make the Bisping fight.
If I was a,
the UFC automate that fight.
GSP says he wants to come back
and fight Bisbing Bisbing he says,
I want to get that big payday too.
I go,
let's make this me too.
I'm with Ya.
I make the fight too.
And what's interesting
is you have these small,
the,
you know the of the smaller guy being
the champion and for Kelvin he doesn't
match up great with anyone fricking six
through one but it does match up great
with the champ.
So he had to decide what you want to
do with them cause Kelvin can be world
champion 70 not at 85
unless he fights with,
hold on,
hold on.
You don't think that
Calvin could beat GSP?
GSP is not fighting 85 day,
but he's the champ.
He did.
It doesn't matter.
Esp though,
isn't he beat Matt Hughes?
We should have that conversation
because GSP is going to fight it.
But wait a minute.
No,
but she sp is the one 85 pound champ is
competing at one 85 but that's what it
is.
What do you got here?
Oh the orders wears Calvin
nine down at number nine.
Yeah,
I think he should be a little higher.
He just knocked out the former champ.
Michael Bisping who's number two.
That doesn't make any sense.
I don't care if this was coming
off of a tough fight with GSP.
It's me.
Definitely probably
hampered his performance.
He should be at seven there's no way
Calvin should be at nine in Bisbing.
Is it too?
That doesn't make any sense.
Maybe they didn't update it pulled up,
but you're saying Kelvin's
should be at two that's crazy.
No,
no,
no.
That's not what I'm saying.
Know what I'm saying is there's
no way that Bisping should be too.
If Calvin just knocked him out and
Calvin's nine that doesn't make sense.
What's the point in having ranking?
Kelvin's should be nine
but he [inaudible] be too.
He should be passed.
Bisping who?
That's tough.
What about some body of war
and we just knocked him out?
It doesn't matter.
The ranking is where are you at right now?
If a guy beats you in
basketball tournament,
right,
isn't he?
Doesn't he move forward?
I hate in a wrestling tournament.
It doesn't.
He move forward yet we don't
look at someone's past and say,
this is who you are forever.
We look at your present performance.
The last performance and Michael
Bisping hat was against Calvin Gaslin.
Kelvin beat him in a decisive,
very clear and dominating way.
He moves ahead.
Was that tire.
Doesn't matter.
He's ranked higher.
We all we can go on is the contest itself.
The contest itself was very obviously
one by Calvin in a spectacular way,
but bang,
he drops that right jab in and that
straight left hand Asti amazing performer.
Amazing.
He's ahead of Bisbing facts.
Okay.
Anybody says differently?
That's fine.
You can cry that.
You can put them ahead of Brisbane.
However you can't put it at number
two middleweight in the world.
No,
I wouldn't because I think
Weidman's in the mix.
Yoel Romero.
Yes.
Jock raise a bad matchup.
Luke Rockhold is a
monster of that division.
Luke Rockhold w if I had
to put money on somebody,
Luke Rockhold,
Jimmy the champion,
that division,
he could be.
He very well could be or David
Branch almost took him out.
Remember that?
Any branch heard them?
Luke Rockhold.
He had him hurt.
Not that bad.
I think he had a murder.
I think he had him hurt,
but Rockhold showed what a fucking
animal he is and came through it.
But what happens if someone like
Yoel Romero catches him like that?
What happens if someone
like Robert Whitaker catches
him like that with running?
My thing is Rockhold is a beast,
but anything can happen in that
division when these guys are that good.
Even David Branch,
what I'm saying,
who's not?
If it was a very good fighter and
hadn't lost like five years world series
again.
Yeah.
Again,
but gave until he got tired,
gave Rockhold a very tough experience.
He came down like,
yes,
he came out and it wasn't
like Rockhold the fight.
Remember Rockwell had a long ass layoff.
He's doing the modeling thing.
If he wanted this sort of matched what
we wanted to sort of money and then that
long ass left.
Then you fight this what the middleweight
champion light heavyweight champ,
the world series and he,
it's his biggest fight of all time.
He brings us towards Rockhold record,
weathered the storm that just
took over when the storm took,
took him down smash,
smash,
smash them.
Henzel Gracie black.
My point is that that absolutely he did.
He definitely warm down to,
he was like,
it was exhausted by the space.
You have to,
how long?
About 14 months off,
which you know,
now he's one of the most underrated guys,
especially at getting you
down and holding you down.
Look what he did.
A little Yoda Machita look what he did
to Weidman and look what he did to David
Branch.
Those guys are all very good at the
ground and he smashes and he'd go back to
the Strikeforce days is his,
uh,
jock ray fights Tim Kenny,
you know,
he's the best of the best,
but it's definitely been a
savage his entire career.
But still,
you still have to realize
Bisbing did knock him out.
And you know what man?
You're in a division where you're
talking about aton of psychos.
Like you've got Robert Whitaker,
Yoel Romero,
Chris Weidman,
you got GSP.
If he decides to stay in the division,
but you don't think it will better.
Okay,
he's a champ,
but you got it Christa Champ.
You got,
you got these killers and then Luke
Rockhold might be the best out of all of
them.
Yes,
but he might not be.
We really don't know.
I mean,
I'm excited about that.
I'm excited about them.
I'm excited about.
You look at him on paper.
You Go,
yeah,
Rockhold might be the best of the bunch,
but God damn,
it's hard to root against Whitaker.
It's hard to bet against that guy.
They all,
I'm done.
Then it gets Whitaker,
especially after he stuffed
all the fucking take downs
from Yolo Ramiro with one
knee on that Whittaker train.
Just like I'm in the deer and tilt train.
Yeah.
80 85 70 of 55 and the
UFC is so goddamn good.
Right?
So competitive.
It's the best it's ever been.
Light heavyweight,
the worst it's ever been.
Heavyweight land of the dinosaurs.
But 55 70 85 pull up data.
[inaudible] Kumar Uzman fight.
We should find out that
fights actually been canceled.
It hasn't been canceled.
He's trying to get as a visa.
He hasn't fucking Donald
Trump let them in.
I know you got to do is Jesus Christ.
He's the Viking cause your people.
Yeah,
I'm a music fan to that
70 good luck at 70 yeah,
good luck.
Get seven.
That's where we're just saying [inaudible]
is fucking terrifying and no one's
even talking about them cause
there's so many killers and that,
here we go.
Amil Meek explained status of two 19
fight with Camacho Guzman visa issues.
So he's just hoping the hope
and they could sort it out.
But that must be tough
going through training camp,
either a 10 day thing or take six
months or anything in between.
That's all.
Doc Office just told me to have patients.
The question is not about if
I'm going to get it or not,
it's just when I get it and
if I can get it in time,
I hope it can.
You know that's uh,
I mean it feels like you don't have Susan.
I'm some fucking power
and I'm saying can we get,
can we just want to make some calls?
Take somebody out to my boy,
me into the Goddamn states.
Unrelated but also news.
What does this,
oh,
we have tried to get this shake.
Carlin retired.
Oh Wow.
It seems like their nose.
No.
Interesting fights and
I'm not getting younger.
Let me explain.
Let me just lay my gloves
down right here on.
Oh,
he did it on Reddit.
Wow.
Wait.
Why is he done though?
Thank you to each and every one of you.
It's odd to be healthy and unable to
compete yet able to compete when so
unhealthy.
I guess we end.
I don't know what that means.
I think you've made a mistake
there with never an oh,
I guess we end with never
knowing what could have been
somber would be the best
bay to describe the emotion.
Thank you all for the love,
the insults and the great times.
I will sync back into the mode of being
a redditor and my quest to become a mod
here.
He was here.
He started making a little joke there.
I am also on the hunt for a large fedora.
I'm like an eight and a
half and half ass Shane.
Seriously.
Thank you.
Often bottom of my heart for being an
amazing if for being amazing and for
making this sport amazing.
I thought he was retired.
He was coming back up.
Try and fight.
Did Bell towards just
tell him no or something?
Yeah,
I think he just put his name in the hat.
You just called out mitre own.
He lived like two days ago.
He just said he wanted
to fight as the old.
Here's what it's weird.
It says it's odd to be
healthy and unable to compete,
yet able to compete when so unhealthy
mean it's odd that he's healthy now and he
can't get a fight.
Did they?
That the commissioner,
maybe someone told him he can't
fight or maybe belt or was like,
now we're good son.
Well,
I would never say he couldn't fight in
terms of like the punishment he's taken.
I mean there's like the junior dos
Santos fight was tough to watch.
That was a tough one.
That was a tough one to watch.
He's had some tough fights,
but I mean a lot of guys have,
if you're going to let Overeem fight,
how could you not let Shane Carwyn fight?
Unless it's like the spinal surgery stuff.
Yeah.
I'm not sure what's going on that but,
but also he could fight and rise again.
I would imagine that they would take care.
Bye Amy Buddy.
You know that they had an issue with
him where he was getting divorced and he
had some personal issues.
I apparently they were saying and he had
to pull out of their tournament member.
Yeah.
He ended up fighting.
They were very upset.
They were very upset at
all that he backed out.
Yeah.
And they said,
they said some things about him,
you know,
not having a warrior spirit
or some crazy shit like that.
Relax rides and shit happen.
Yeah.
I mean,
not only that,
you don't even have so
many fucking heavyweights.
Yeah.
You're also writing and so it's relaxed
and have Shane Kerwin back the half.
Shane car went over there
and alarm call courage.
I [inaudible] him.
Currcomm wild west
golden snitch.
Yeah.
Just full on Mexican.
Stop.
What spins?
Let the party role mix it up.
Especially,
I mean chains in his forties right.
How old is shame?
Hell yeah.
He's in his forties
let it roll.
Let it roll.
[inaudible] the spot.
I mean,
look,
we should have a steroid league.
We should have a league where some
people are not Daniel Cormier essays for
faces.
Volk on owes Demir at
UFC two 20 and Boston.
Ooh.
Ooh,
wow.
Breaking news folks.
Breaking news old's Demir scary,
but there's a,
there's a guy who's got the
quickest rise to the top ever.
This is my face for that fight.
You don't care.
I care.
I'm lukewarm on it with those DC.
I love DC and I wish she was a bigger
star and he should be a bigger star and I,
but you know he's going to be phenomenal
as a commentator and I think he flies
through those the minute.
Do you really?
Yes.
Easily Think,
oh Zumiez dangerous for anybody,
man.
Anybody good luck dealing with DC
when he gets you in there clinch.
It's true.
DC's a monster light
heavyweight of all time.
Not named John Jones.
Whoa.
Strong words.
Who's better?
Nobody.
He was the heavyweight champion twice.
Yeah,
twice beat Guthman.
He was the head of state
champion Grand Prix.
Then then think about the
people in that Grand Prix.
Yeah.
When we did the Josh Barnett,
Judge Brennan had a broken hand,
but throw them up in the air and
we did the port Dan Henderson.
How,
by the way DC,
how dare you treat our legend like that.
How dare you take an old,
whether Dan Henderson
spike him on his head.
You son of a dog.
I mean he ragdolled.
I love DC men.
I liked that fight for DC.
I'm a owes them air fan.
I think it'd be hilarious
if he has champions.
It's 700 Twitter followers,
but I think that TC is going
to mop the floor with them.
Interesting.
Unless it's a bar in Florida
then it's different story.
I'm just interested in
seeing what happens if um,
if he gets hit because owes Demir is
very fast and hits very hard and has a
shocking reaction.
It hit hard.
Oh for sure.
Rumble,
rumble,
rock them.
Rock the rocks and that overhand
right in the first fight in the head.
Kicked him in the second week.
Yeah.
Be really sat him down cause he popped up.
Yeah,
I'll beat DC is a monster.
No doubt.
I'm just interested because I think owes
Demir really does have special power.
You,
you'll,
you'll see him hit people,
you like cheeses and according to
everybody that watched him and rumbled
trained,
like he was the guy that trained
with rumble all the time.
It's one of the few guys
that want to spar with,
probably say about it.
So they went to war.
Really?
Hud Watch that.
Watch that.
I would watch it and who to have said,
that's one of the reasons
why those to me are so good.
So it always the like
train with the wrong.
He was like,
everybody's carrying around ball.
How do not be scared about it?
They're not just knock
each other out every day.
I think they're smart.
They hit each other just hard enough to
like let each other know they're hitting
each other.
And look,
you want a valuable sparring partner.
I mean if you take your toys,
yeah,
look,
it's benefiting the both of them.
Obviously.
Here's one for you.
How about rumble ones?
Come back at heavyweight rumble.
Steep pay for the curve ball.
Here's the thing,
you can't really do that because he just
fought as a light every way and then
quit and said,
I don't want to do this anymore.
And then he comes back and finds
that a heavyweight and he's back,
bro.
He said he doesn't like fighting.
Says
there's a lot the rest of that a man.
What he say,
I don't like blood but I'm back.
I mean what happened was that
retirement life ain't fun,
is it?
It's not.
It's boring.
Right.
And he knows he can be championed too.
Like he really does have
championship skills,
you know what I mean?
He's got,
now he does for sure.
Unquestionably has enough power
to knock out any human being.
And P if DC and Jon Jones are out,
yeah,
he's the guy.
If DC got hit with that upper cut,
that glow over got hit with,
he goes night,
night to night.
But those guys are too smart for that.
They don't fight that style.
Well,
they didn't.
Yeah.
Glover was too easy to hit for him.
But I think he realizes
that anybody in the world,
I mean he literally,
he might have to have a hundred percent
chance to beat anybody in the world,
but he might have,
no,
not a hundred percent chance.
Do you know anybody in the world?
But I'm saying he might
have like a 60% chance,
like in any fight with anybody,
he could connect with a bomb
and put your fucking lights out.
He's that powerful.
So that alone in his head means like
if he fought Jon Jones 60% of the time,
he might be able to catch John Jones.
It might be if he caught
John Jones or anybody,
he hits so fucking hard,
but he definitely froze up
against DC in the second fight.
He did not look like a guy
who was there to do or die.
Did he hit that path that
they keep jacking off to?
Did he hit the,
I would like to see that.
I'd like to see that.
I think he hits harder than in Ghana.
Ghana was a lot bigger than him,
man.
Yeah.
But Anthony Johnson is filled up more.
He's more explosive.
Especially with you.
You put Anthony Johnson on that healthy
diet and he's the two 40 empty Johnson.
He's going to hit like a Mack truck.
Very interesting.
Cm and heavy.
Where ansys rumble Johnson
black on black power.
Kaepernick could show up for that bitch.
You got would be rumbles going to have
[inaudible] fight in heavyweight fights.
Just docile.
Oh my God.
He's ready to go.
No,
no,
no.
You get them.
That Russian dude that
looks to choke people
who lets people now,
now he's a heavyweight.
He's,
yeah,
you get him.
That'd be Brown.
And that poor soul to put
the Russian has no idea.
I fight black men and
just fucking get starched.
Yeah,
that'll be interesting.
It's an interesting guy.
Let's see what happened guy.
I want to see what happens.
Give him that guy.
Give him somebody who's,
you know,
can we get it?
Encourages mounts.
I can get a joke.
The guy's going to come after him.
The guy's gonna come after him.
Alexi.
Holiness.
Powerful LEXI.
Yeah.
Deep in his forties
same hairlines Brian Cowen,
52 and 11 he's been through the fucking
door ring or you think he gives a fuck
about how hard rumble hits now?
He'll take that fight.
You know,
like I'd take foot to the
all day until stricter.
Fucking write the Boa.
Yeah,
that would be a fun fight.
You mean beat my hip for heavy weight,
man?
Who the fuck knows what
if he gets rumbled down?
What if he gets rumbled down?
We see him in side mount.
We're going on a rear
naked choke from the side.
You have run in troll.
That motherfucker gets hold of your neck.
Rumbles in trouble if
you get mount on him,
man.
He,
that guy's a monster.
He's a monster from the bottom.
I'm sure he choked that dude
out from his back mounted.
He gave it to him.
Crazy.
Yeah,
he's a,
he's a squeezer.
There's certain dudes to just can squeeze
your neck and a rum on the first round
might be the most dangerous man.
Oh yeah.
I wonder maybe.
Look,
I mean,
I don't know how much weight he was
cutting to make two oh five but if he's
really walking around at two 32 35
and that doesn't have to cut anything,
he might be better at heavyweight.
So I'm saying let's give
them on that punch meter.
Got Francis.
Just give them a good fight
of her doom from overdose.
We're doing like kill your dreams man.
Who's a mother fucker?
Who was a mother fuck is beacon
strike that's on the world.
On the ground.
She's huge and me give a fuck about
the golden snitch cause he never been
caught.
That doesn't take anything.
He had some issues for doom comes hunting
for you and that Jujitsu is just on
another planet.
Dude.
How about,
how about,
how about when,
what fight was that that backed out?
Oh,
the black beast.
We were supposed to
fight Derrick Lewis Fan.
We were talking about Derrick Lewis,
social media.
I just had the best.
Might be the best fucking
his instinct fighter.
Hilarious.
Hilarious,
hilarious.
Shout out to Dick Lewis.
Shout out to the black beans.
Some hilarious shit.
Fight soon.
But remember,
Derek,
who's supposed to fight for doomed
and the like hours for the fight,
that guy,
he can't do.
So this filled in random homeboy
and he was just happy to be there.
Walt Harris Harris Business Lock and
just fucking beautiful transition when
it took us back and then took the arm off
the bat.
He's teaching his students and
then it's about the arm to show.
It's fucking easy.
I'll show you how it was so easy for him.
Uh,
there's a payday then fights
that rush and goes five rounds.
That's why he won't be ready
to fight Steve Bay in Boston.
I wonder if he would,
he might.
Yes.
Five rounds.
I don't know.
See to Bora caught him a few times,
but it never got rocked.
[inaudible] was outclassed.
Yeah.
He's just not that level yet.
Never got hurt.
No.
And uh,
you know,
if we're doing one,
if he didn't get injured,
Boston has January,
who knows.
Talk to him in a couple of weeks.
How are you feeling bro?
Especially for a title shot.
Yeah.
How are you feeling?
Most probably down.
No,
he won't fight for the title for this
monster Francis that we're not sure about.
Yeah,
it all depends on how much
damage he took in that fight.
He did get leg kicked a few times.
Didn't get down though,
man.
Yeah.
You know he is.
But did he get hurt?
Like is there anything
fucked up in his wrist?
His elbow.
Okay.
You know little shit that happens in
a fight that nobody even knows about.
Training camps.
Yeah.
And during a fight as well.
Right.
So what else is going on this weekend?
There's those,
those fights.
This Holloway Edgar,
which is very interesting.
There is gagey versus Eddie Alvarez.
That's a,
that's,
that's the one that I'm most
excited to sit udo pedis.
So who'd,
oh,
it's,
that's the one I wanted to talk about.
That's another one.
And Paul Felder and Charles
Olivera for the fs one prelims.
That's another very interesting one
because all of era just got done.
He was,
he's fine in 45 to draining
45 and just choked out.
Bill Brooks remember that?
Yes.
We'll Brooks having a tough time.
Tough time in the UFC.
I thought it was gonna do really
well too with spiders caught him.
[inaudible] he's had a
tough go over in the EOC.
Yeah.
Um,
look man,
this is the highest level
of the game for sure.
It's weird cause Brooke,
some tough time you'll see in a lot of
the UFC guys are having a tough time in
Bella toward the different divisions
I think is probably the strongest over
there.
And Bella [inaudible] 70 right now,
especially with Rory Mcdonald there
I think is as strong as it gets.
I think you've got Douglas Lema.
You got Rory Macdonald.
You,
you got like,
like a vinegarette Larkin.
You got Michael Venom page.
You got Paul Daley who just
knocked out Lorens Larkin.
You got to have a gang
of fucking assassins.
Uh,
Paul's the most limited
because of his ground game.
Yes.
You know,
when a guy like Rory gets you down
like he showed how to Pete Paul,
you know,
um,
that's just,
but if you stand with Paul,
he's got a chance to idea.
He's got a chance against anybody
in the world are doing daily.
Verse Marco Been In page
the arguing each other.
Hate each other.
Hate each are going to do that.
Yeah.
That's a great fight.
That's a crazy fight.
Great fight.
And you know Roy McDonald wants to
be an alternate and the heavyweight,
he's out of his fucking mind.
Crazy tell to him verse,
you know,
fucking mitre own or something like that.
Yeah.
Those guys are huge.
The huge,
he's more technical alone but point
doesn't matter how much does he weigh?
Roy's maybe one 90 95 maybe a
lot of fucking Krispy Kreme.
Yeah.
It's just a bad idea.
Don't so gangster though.
Yeah he is.
But there's some gorillas
in that division.
Well think if they let Shane and the
thing melts shameless Chael Sonnen.
Who's going to sanction that?
Fine.
Yeah,
he's fine to rampage rampage.
That seems kind of crazy too.
It does it.
That makes more sense to me.
At least.
Rampage is at light
heavyweight and are similar.
That's true.
But you know,
I dunno,
I don't know why they made
Matt and Roy on the same,
the first round I would've,
I would've put them on opposite sites
around cause we've seen that show.
See I'll put them on opposite sides.
Well,
I think they wanted that fight to happen.
They wanted that rematch to happen,
you know,
and I think Mitre on,
right?
Like if I was,
if I was in the fate or camp,
who's fade or fighting first?
Frank Mir,
that's a dangerous fight.
Hell yeah.
It's a dangerous fight.
Dangerous fight song.
That's dangerous fight.
Then he got King Mo,
Ryan Bader especially under non snitch,
like testing well that,
that,
that whole,
that whole tournament.
Yeah.
It's non snitch like Oh hold up.
So well,
okay,
so he got Quinton rampage,
Jackson Shale stone that's at the forum.
So that's the law.
That's the California Commission
and the strictest fuck.
But the Mohegan Sun arena,
mitre and Roy Nelson suspect
and then all state arena.
What city is that in?
Use All state.
But if I was,
if I was fade or I'd only want to do it
in the middle of the Indian reservation.
Yeah.
We're doing to be as
far from the outskirts,
you know,
possible.
We fight and inclusive casino.
We're going to move to the virtual center,
but uh,
but,
uh,
juiced up frank or so juiced up.
Fado that's a dream match.
Where's that a Allstate arena?
Chicago.
They got a good athletic
commission might be fucked.
They've got to get those doctors
that they brought in for that Acre.
It's moving out of all out
of all the God damn fights.
How does Metro and Roy,
the two guys who've never tested
hot end up in Mohegan Sun?
Maybe because they knew they didn't
have to worry about them testing.
Yeah.
No,
but you put fade or in frank and Mohegan.
But what?
They don't want them to be able to,
to go fucking hardcore.
All right then.
You don't want to have fun.
That's fine.
All right,
Scott,
do your thing,
man.
Do your thing,
Scott.
You know,
I love you.
Do your thing,
man.
I would have had that inclusive casino.
Choose to the Gills all day.
Pride days.
Whole days.
Right?
And how's Bobby latching
on that tournament?
That's true.
Could I get white check congas on it?
A little boring.
Bobby Lashley is the one they go age.
Just,
um,
we just can't,
Bobby,
come on.
Just come on.
Nobody thinks you clean.
Nobody.
He's never failed.
Never Mama.
Dude,
what do you think?
Am I clean?
Boy,
you know you ain't call
dude bought.
I would watch Bobby fader,
Bobby Roy Nelson be sick.
Leave.
Decided on dude,
I don't know.
I know,
I know.
He's got great genetics.
I know he works hard.
He's skilled as a motherfucker.
A motherfucker bought stripey
latch snap was a grappling beast,
but one of the best
wrestlers I've ever seen.
But that is the body of a man
who's been to the Mexican pharmacy.
How dare you,
or had someone go for him.
How dare you?
Or bought it from a dude who went there.
He got it at the gym.
I mean,
that's just,
that's just steroid,
but he's never failed.
Oh my God.
Fuck ass man.
That's not even that looks
checkouts guys from promethium,
those dudes from Promethian said that
those ridiculous bodies that brought the
DNA to earth to make new people,
those John,
it did pull up one of them dudes for
promethium and put it right by the side of
him.
By the way.
I love that movie.
Put them right beside him.
The Prometheans Jack Dude,
where it looks like the new
teenage mutant Ninja Turtles.
That image he like literally had the body
of one of those Prometheans guys like
right there with the
shirt off by the ocean.
Bang.
Make that larger.
Yeah,
it looks identical.
He loves beer.
He's thicker.
For sure.
Jack.
Let's go.
Come on son.
Jesus Christ.
Look at the size of him.
Well,
come on.
He's bigger.
I would say Bobby Lashley.
Steamrolls that dude from Promeo,
those guys for jibs huge though,
bro.
Steamrolls difference.
If he's the same size as that guy,
go one more Bobby.
Lashley fucked.
Fuck.
Ugh.
That's,
but that's a real human.
But all the other guys,
not Bobby Lashley college pick.
He's always been Jack.
Oh,
I believe it.
I mean,
he's definitely got phenomenal genetics,
but the idea that there
ain't nothing going on,
but the rent,
you're out of your fucking
out of your fucking mind.
You're out of your fucking mind.
Yeah.
I don't know,
man.
I talked to Jimmy Smith about
where they have him fight.
Yeah,
no,
I know where they have him fight.
Yeah.
I just,
I'm giving the guy a break.
I think he's awesome,
but I think there's a reality to pride
that made it exciting and made it fun.
Correct.
You know,
and we're,
I would like to see one
of those things today,
whether it's rising or took the size.
I,
dude,
I mean,
again,
phenomenal genetics.
Maybe he really is taken gamma labs,
but in the live,
but there's part of me that goes,
I want to go back to the
old Arsenio hall days.
Things would make you go,
well,
if the size of him up there,
elbow straps above the left,
I don't care.
Go go large on that picture
was more Joe Timmer,
Bob Sapp.
Oh my God.
Pops up and it's Prime Bob Sapp and
his prime was not even a human being.
He was a science project,
a full on science pain.
He's been Bob savage versus Nogueira.
Look at the size of Bobby Ashley.
Go to Bob Sapp versus Nogueira.
There's a time where the beginning of
fight Noguera is standing there ready to
find Bob Sapp is standing there.
And Bob's habs gloves look like miniature
gloves because his body is this wide
and he's like,
cartoon moves in.
Khartoum my only thing with Bobby,
last few years I've seen guys in the
NFL who aren't hot that looked like him.
Oh yeah.
It's possible.
It's totally possible.
Bobby last,
she's also 40 right,
isn't he?
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh yeah.
Wrestled blue in the middle of them.
I just let it go.
Let it happen for the first round.
Like watch it comes out.
Look at the fucking size of the spine.
Girls Snack.
Yeah.
He was so big.
He was at one point in time,
I think he was 300 plus pounds.
400 Oh,
I don't know about that.
Was He?
He was 300 plus pounds with abs
like three 50 or three 75 with that.
Oh my God.
They don't teach you that
at any gym in the world.
Ooh,
that's so bad for your neck.
Oh dude,
that no girl was had to retire because
of that really is the worse injuries ever
sustained.
So what happened to his neck?
A disc bulging disc.
He had to have surgery.
Like that's,
that's one of the things that
really fucked them gear up.
It's amazing that he's still
fought and won and won.
Amazing God.
No,
Kara Mann,
one of the fucking savage man,
he almost got taken out because
of a fucking head spike.
You know,
fader was not willing to fight him fader.
I was like,
no thanks.
Like you are allowed to throw those crazy
kicks from when you were on your back.
Then you could kick to the face like he,
I forgot he got reversed.
Remember that?
Think of that monster on top of you.
Jesus.
That much of a bad ass Nokia
is cause you know what?
Off Fight fricking Bob Sapp,
even though he's juice to the Gills,
Bob sat on top of him.
He has his back and
punched him and rock him,
smashing him.
Smash city,
Eh crazy.
I for struggle city for
big hug right there.
What about this?
You forget about this fight.
You forget how big of an old my God,
look at that.
That's a grizzly bear.
Oof Jesus Christ.
But if you hit him when he
hit the bully in the face,
they go away.
Look at this.
Remember he almost had him in a triangle.
You've got slammed.
Yeah.
It's a bad idea to do that.
The Triangle Slam,
the Ricardo Arona,
rampage Jackson Triangle Slam should
be shown to every kid who wants to hold
onto a triangle.
Ever.
I need to watch this because this is real.
Two bonds that some of
the best ever broke.
The leg locks and everything.
Look at this.
I forgot.
He went to leg loss.
They fought from the best ever.
Not beat.
This was a nutty fight.
And again,
this was a fight that
fate or wouldn't take,
but fader was like,
Nah,
I don't care.
What do I shy?
Understand what he's thinking.
Yeah.
Even in,
even though when they won,
they won a no gear.
Do the rematch.
He's like,
dude was spiking.
I can't with my neck,
man.
It's too much.
And he was sending to my life,
my career.
Look at him.
Yeah,
he was battered.
But how entertaining is amazing.
Like,
well,
it's amazing.
But now,
and he,
I love with this.
When he hit him with the Granby roll,
Woo whoop on your backside.
And when one,
when he won,
I remember watching it.
We were going crazy.
Look at me and Eddie were fucking
screaming at this without an arm bar.
Beautiful.
Lemme know when he straightens
it out and Bob taps.
It's like no fucking way.
But this is not just Jujitsu.
This is lily.
That tap,
tap,
tap.
Tap is not just Jujitsu with no Gary.
It's just toughness and just animal spirit
and the toughest kids is his warrior
heart that allowed him to get through
getting spiked on his head like that and
battered and nuts is 350 pound juggernaut
on top of you dropping bombs on you.
Legend still gets Rushmore.
Rushmore.
Fuck man.
What a crazy time.
Those pride days where flanking.
What a great plaintiff
was that hockey Bono?
Yeah.
Do you know hoists?
Hoy Speed Aki.
Bono with an armbar.
How bad ass?
His voice fucking crazy.
Oh my God.
Hoists Gracie fought Aki.
Bono with the pants on.
He fought like with g pants I can ride.
He did got Aki bono arm bar.
Look at this size of occupied
Pono Jesus Christ said,
fuck your Kido.
Who,
that dude is thick.
This is a Bob Sapp though that
has started to lose his physique.
Like this is a,
into his career where
he had been fighting,
you know,
like you'd only like the levels of juice
that he was on during those days of
glory.
Like when he fought Nogueira.
Those are just not sustainable.
No,
he also hated fighting.
I,
I have a friend that,
uh,
that shows on those fighter with him
and he used to train with Bob and said
towards end of his career,
he wouldn't barely train it all.
You just do it for the payday.
He just walked in the,
yeah,
and he would tap whenever he got hurt.
He was smart about it.
He like,
he knew he could make money.
He would go places they'd want to
see people beat Bob Sapp and see.
He would go and he would
not take much of a beating.
Did in Tokyo.
He was like on the fucking
Wheaties box and stuff.
Used to sell,
like call sorts of merchandise.
Look at this shit,
stain undies and stuff.
But do you know what happened?
Do you know the whole story?
No,
something happened with k one
where he had a contract that,
um,
he was supposed to go out and fight,
but they hadn't given him the contract.
And he's like,
I'm not signing,
I mean,
I'm not fighting without
a fucking contract.
I need my money.
Legit point.
And wound up leaving.
There was some sort of a contract dispute
and wound up leaving before the main
event just dipped out as dipped out.
I said,
fuck this.
I'm out.
I'm not fighting.
And you know,
they're like,
oh,
what?
That's the year is over.
Like you're done.
You're done.
I am.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
And um,
I guess you know,
whether or not,
I don't know whose stories correct.
And all I know is a story that I've read
and the store that I had read was that,
you know,
he was upset.
They hadn't given him the contract yet
and they wanted him to just fight and
deal with it later.
Yeah.
Come on,
Bro.
Listen,
if they can get you to do something,
it's specially right before I got,
dammit.
All right.
Boom.
Yeah.
Well when I talked to people that are
Japanese about the way they would do
business over there,
he says really interesting.
He's like,
one of the things that like when
the UFC was talking to pride,
it was really interesting because they
would have these meetings and they would
talk about selling it,
you know,
but they really didn't want to sell it.
They just wanted you to say
that you wanted to buy it.
They're like,
okay,
good.
See you later.
Just nearly stopped.
But then it also pumped up pride.
Like everybody in the UFC tarted talking
about Vandelay was going to fight chuck
and they are bringing together,
but these Japanese business,
when would they were playing
like super high level,
sophisticated dimensional chess,
very tight move.
And then here's the
tightest of tight move.
I'm not happy that they did this,
but they essentially,
she sold the UFC $60
million worth of nothing.
They got a,
they got a fucking video library of
fights and they got pride to be out of
business.
That's what they got for 60 whatever
million dollars they paid because a lot of
the contracts were no good.
Yup.
That's why fade or it
was never in the UFC.
I mean,
and the Mark Hunt thing,
they were willing to pay Mark Hunt out
there like we were willing to give you
your money.
He's ended up fuck that.
I want to fight.
Yeah.
UFC didn't want work to fight.
I remember when mark first got the UFC,
it wasn't pretty days.
No.
Humans get submitted by Chris Tuscher.
Yeah.
He had some rough days.
Had some rough days.
Yeah.
We'll fight and flight by somebody.
Like in his first Sean.
Oh,
uh,
corcal yes.
Sean McCorkle caught him in
the Camorra from his back.
His first fight in the
first fight in the UFC.
Submitted them,
submitted them.
Huge upset.
And then he had the mccorkells
a funny fucking guy.
He says some ridiculous Shit Online.
I don't know.
Is he still alive?
I haven't heard from him.
It was a funny guy.
He's was funny at the time.
Him and met,
used to train together.
I think they had to show,
but um,
yeah,
mark struggled for a little bit there.
And then he had the walk off home
run knocked out of Chris Duchscherer.
Yeah.
That horrible fight.
And Denver.
Oh yeah.
Fuck dead.
Rothwell Rothwell cause they both
got so tired because the altitude.
Yeah.
And then I was asking Joe Silva's,
Dude,
let me fight my hometown.
He's like,
we will never do heavyweights
in Denver again because of that.
Meanwhile,
they have Ken fight for doom or they have,
um,
a Mexican Cain fight for
doom and Mexico City,
which is 2000 feet higher.
Bad idea.
The ridiculous.
So what else is going on in this card?
Is that it?
Should we just wrap this up?
I think I've got kind of got fleas.
Hillary.
Yeah,
you kind of got it covered.
We kind of got the card covered.
Oh,
the Paul Felder,
Charles Olivera fight it.
Felder's a fucking beast,
man fit,
you know,
filters.
Another guy who,
uh,
and I'm,
I'm interested to see.
I'm not hating on you.
I'm not saying they can't do it.
Amisha see,
you know,
I'll see DC DC's been able to do it.
Um,
Dominick Cruz,
he got injured but he
was supposed to fight.
He's out of the fight now.
But guys who were working as analysts
and fighters at a certain level,
are you going to be able to continue
at the highest level and compete?
But he's not doing the
animal analysis and not for,
I think it's going to find
hurt him and I think in,
in fact it's enough.
So it probably takes his mind
off the training a little bit,
let them relax and let
some analyze fights.
I don't think it's that big of a deal.
And when he did do the commentary,
he was really good at it.
That's my thing.
He's really good.
It's really good.
I was really good at it.
He has a future in it for sure.
Once he decides to retire.
Paul could be an amazing commentator.
I still think he's in his prime.
I think it's potentials in commentating,
I think was a hypertension commentating
that he does be in the world champion in
the UFC.
I'm not willing to sign them off yet.
I'm not signing them off.
He's a phenomenal fighter.
I don't know if he's world champion,
but he's phenomenal fight.
How crazy would he be versus
Gagey that's a fun fight.
That's a fun fucking fight.
He's an animal.
Fleets hail are versus gagey would be
maybe like a perfect style matchup.
Never mad when Cooper fights.
Now I'm a,
I'm excited about this fight,
um,
because all of air is very technical
on his feet all over this side,
the underground,
he's super technical and he,
you know,
he,
he's sneaky on the ground,
but he just can't get over that hump yet.
So much prompts.
He's just going to go over that hump.
We can't be telling Derek Silva where
there's so much promise and we thought
they're going to be this and
just has an aligned for him.
The so Hutto pedes fights
a very important fight to,
very important.
When you look at Pseudo Huda,
when he came off of that
fight with a Wilson Hayes,
he looked amazing sensation.
But also what screwed,
not screwed on me.
It was a good experience.
But when you fought,
Demetrius Johnson had no seven fight,
mixed martial arts flight sim fight.
He should not been in
there with Demetrius.
John is just not ready now we
see a little more well rounded.
He's a phenomenal power puncher offset.
You'll ridiculous wrestler a for pedes it.
It's a tough one for him to take on here.
Very tough.
And he's a young kid,
you know,
pedes is only 24 I think.
He's very young.
He's,
he's,
he's out of his brother's
shadow now for sure.
He's at his brother's shadow.
Well with a few wins.
His brother's still a
former world champion,
both in strike force and in the UFC.
He's brother just lost again though.
He's lost a bunch.
He's fighting at a way higher
level up until this fight.
At least this fight is a,
this is like a world
class level for for pedes.
This is like the most difficult fight,
I think.
100% it's a little too much too soon
I think for pedes and that David Tamer
dude,
he's fighting against your car
clothes that fuck you see Tamer fight.
He was the one that
fought Landover not ass.
Ooh,
he's nasty.
He's a monster.
He's a fucking savage.
Savage.
Kickboxer man there.
That's going to be a following year.
Fucking go.
Cons out of the fight out.
I'm not sure he got hurt.
That's a bomber and it is a bummer.
How about Holly a?
I'm sure it will for
Holly Cyborg tat time.
It's interesting.
I'll tell you what,
nobody has more composed or composure.
Nobody has more composure in
their Instagram videos than Holly.
She's the most composure.
She's like,
when she says professional,
Cyborg's been saying that.
I haven't been tested.
She's a politician.
I'd actually,
I'd been tested nine times.
She's been tested heat times.
So some of us are out here training
and not worrying about who's fantastic.
It's so like,
thank you.
Thank you and have a good thank you.
I'm ready to head kick a pitch.
I love following such in direct
contrast to her fucking back flips.
She's a politician.
Head kicks and shit.
It's like a politician,
right?
Smart man.
Very calm and smooth and,
and she's like a real all American girl.
Like you look at Holly Holm.
I mean she got freckles and shit.
She's pretty,
she like an all American head
kicker and beat Cyborg in the tough.
If it's tough,
if she beats Cyborg to me,
she's number one of all time that she'd
beat Ron and her prime right now should
beat Cyborg in her prime.
What are we doing?
I know she had those rough logs.
Shelter where you should take.
I know.
Listen,
Misha Tate strangled her and she was
still punching in the air while she was
going unconscious.
Yeah.
That's how savage Holly Holm as I know
and such a great matchup we should take.
Did get her and Nisha got her
in the fifth round of a fight.
She was losing.
Losing took her back and put
it asleep on should tape fans.
Ooh.
Yeah.
Fan.
But she's retired.
Yup.
She want to do anything
about Holly sideboard.
Yeah,
but it's that Holly Cyborg.
Yeah.
I wonder what kind of numbers
that does cause that's,
that's your headline on there right now.
Because you know,
dump cruises off.
Well,
it's going to show you the
power of a like top flight,
women's MMA fights and then there's the,
you know,
there's the cyborg aspect.
Like people tune in,
she's like a cultural
icon sort of a thing.
Like people would tune in to see
you like all that cyborg check.
She's scared.
Yeah.
Does it scares either
and it's scary being me.
Not physically scary,
too scary.
The way she destroys violent,
very violent and very technical.
Her last fight wasn't that violent,
but she wanted to show most
for was fighting a crazy,
I mean Zam Zam Zam Tonya evenger.
She's,
she,
she didn't give a fuck.
She was throwing me mom,
I don't know.
I call it my mom.
She's tough as fuck and mom
bod and also would not go away.
Like that's that.
If you were watching
like a youtube or a law,
it wouldn't even be on youtube.
They pull it from youtube,
like a live leak outside
of a bar and Kentucky,
I think worse.
She saw him.
Chick gets up,
puts her fucking cigarette
down and rolls up the sleeves.
Flannel shirt,
probably wearing your shirt.
The very shirt you're wearing and just
throws haymakers on some check and she's
got her by the Gal and she's fucking
drop and Moitai elbows on her,
but she keeps getting wrong.
She'd be like the Kimbo slice
of soccer moms in the backyard.
Brawler she's a tough,
tough woman.
She's as tough as the same animal.
I enjoyed that fight because of her.
I agree.
She made the phone.
She made the fire chief.
She fucking had some whistling
shots swinging by Cyborgs Chin.
She didn't let him get all for it.
She took it.
She took it and she was going for it.
That's off.
Took a fight.
Did a lot of people didn't want,
no one wants that fight.
Yeah.
I mean,
look at fucking Germane to random.
He said,
Nah,
I'm good.
You can keep your title.
Shuck fighting her if she's
done steroids before it yet,
but she tests clean now.
I don't care.
I'm,
I'm not.
Not recently enough.
Nope.
No.
You got to get her to test her again like
10 years to every day for 10 years and
then we'll draw me said,
fuck this.
I love that Cyborg fight though.
I do too.
But I want you to see what number
is it does see Germane to random.
He is a very tactical Stryker.
That's why I thought her versus
Cyborg would be interesting.
I mean Jermaine,
Jermaine to random,
he fought a man.
That's how crazy scary Cyborg is.
Germane fought a man and k owed
him this video of you can watch it.
She's like,
I'll fight a man,
but I don't know if
I just,
I'm off to do randomly just
when you give up the belly,
say not fuck it.
She just,
she's too much.
Well I'm,
I'm a,
I'm a fan of her talent.
She's a very talented fighter.
She shouldn't have been
shared in the first place.
I agree.
Holly beat her and I think she
should have been penalized for sure.
For at least one of those.
After the bell shot 100%.
She landed two after the bell shots.
One of them was devastating.
Like she really rocked Holly,
beat her.
I think Holly beat her.
I think uh,
you got to take into consideration how,
what scoring system they
were using back then.
Because I do not think that they were
using the new MMA school is also New York,
his early Day New York.
When I say early
[inaudible] six months ago,
I think the refereeing,
I mean I think the refereeing could
have been better because I do think she
should have been penalized for those
shots after the bill and when Holly head
kicked her,
that was one of the most
significant moments in the fight.
The other most significant moment of
the fighters and Holly dropped it with a
straight left hand.
Yeah.
So those are two giant moments in the
fight and they were both on Holly side and
then there was the two
shots after the bell,
which you could conceivably penalize
her for at least one you have to do for
one.
And that's what I thought.
Hold won the fight.
Yeah,
I would agree.
I would agree with you.
I would agree with you
because other than that,
Holly did the most damage
in the fight for sure.
But during demanding Germain,
de Randamie was controlling the action,
the beginning of the
fight until Holly Landa,
that question Mark Kick
Funko a question mark.
It cause a beautiful kick.
It's just a beautiful kick.
You know,
if you're good at it,
if you get that over the top,
like rock holds beautiful at that.
He's really good at it.
No one does better than Donald,
but yeah.
Dollar kind of beautiful.
I feel like Donald,
when he kind of made that
his thing in the UFC,
yes.
Per head kick.
Kaos um,
question mark kicks.
There's been some other ones in the past.
I'm trying to remember that video.
I think Justin wren posted,
but ESPN blast it that the wheel kick
that land and knocked that dude out.
The heel landed right on the dude's chin.
It's so gnarly.
Oh,
the one with the dude ducks
down and throws an up.
We'll kick.
The guy's throwing a head kick.
There's a black guy in a white guy
and that guy throws her head yes.
And the dude ducks down like almost
like a cartwheel kick and throws like a,
yeah,
we'll kick up and the shield goes,
oh,
perfect shot.
My God,
the way he threw it.
You know what the video is?
Capitol Eric?
Yes.
Well it's almost like that.
But what it's like is like he just knew
where they do its chin was going to be
and duct himself.
So you know you bend your body,
but it's just very rare that you
see someone landed at that angle.
Especially with the heel.
Yeah.
Was He,
did it look at this boom.
Crazy.
It's almost like it's hard to know whether
or not that was like perfectly placed
or just crazy lucky timing.
I think you'll like watch this,
watch it again.
So you see him here,
he's going to give it up.
See,
but that's not the way did it.
So it's not a normal path.
It's really amazing.
Almost like he almost adapt to
do it when it's straight up.
Once he,
yeah,
he knew he had was going to be,
I mean it really,
you'd have to see him fight more to
see how good he is with his kicks,
but that shit is perfect.
Let's see that warranty mass the
more time because it's crazy.
Luckily the look,
the title amateur MMA fighter,
it's starch.
His opponents.
He right here,
like a taekwondo guy would see the
shifting of the hips and then the shoulder
moves toward the left and so see that?
Yeah,
I see that right there.
You see that right there?
That is absolutely.
He's about to spend.
See the right leg moves
the right leg slides back.
You're showing your cards
that you don't see it.
Wonderboy is not going
to shock you to see that.
Now he's showing us
these flashing his aces,
but he's also doing it in
timing with this left high kick,
which is so brilliant.
So the the left kick is coming.
He sees the left kick and he's like,
yeah,
check this out brow.
I ain't there to the head killed Mrs this.
And then it goes and you know
what I think you did on purpose?
100% percent.
Oh,
I mean he either improvised in the
moment or he did it exactly like this on
purpose,
like saw it common.
But either way it's just a perfect shot.
Two to dodge that kick and land
this he kick skillful shit.
Amazing is a head kick and landed a
perfect like crazy 90 degree angle.
We'll kick to the mug
amateur fight I've seen.
Okay,
that's crazy.
It's crazy how he saw the
left high kick to like boom,
fucking a BSPN as an
amateur fight in an ESPN.
I know right now you gotta
you gotta make up for that,
that you got to carry that with you.
Everybody's looking for the head kick.
The next ones you can't be grounded.
Pounded so first thing now.
Yeah,
she's getting married to
a thing really early on.
Right.
Becomes a real problem because real
problem Helia like you're known as like if
gates,
he just decides tomorrow to
fight like Tyron Woodley.
I just move around a lot and
get the fuck out of dies.
There's middle riot.
People would go so crazy.
Like what if gauge,
you got a title shot against Tyron
Woodley and they both looked mirrored each
other.
We both like like,
like what the fuck is going?
Wait,
wait,
wait.
Oh wait,
wait,
wait.
Have you seen how hard your boy,
Colby Covington's getting going
in the paint on Instagram Woodley?
Oh my God.
Have you seen his recent
one with the sandals?
He did a black Friday sale.
They sandals mockin and Woodley.
Wow.
You got to see it.
I don't care how he's
mocking Woodley was handles.
You'll see it.
Okay.
They're not real sandals.
He's just like,
Hey,
make sure you get your sitting
to your sandals this Friday.
And it's the sandals of
Woodley saying one thing.
Why he'll fight Nate Diaz,
but saying another thing,
life won't fight Colby.
There it is.
The aerial GSP has duck me.
He just wants money.
Fights.
Ariel,
I'm not ducking Colby
or anyone that wants 70.
I want to fight Nate
because it's a money fight.
Um,
he just seems like he's
saying the same thing.
Yes.
Yeah,
I get it.
Yeah.
And he just keeps,
he just wants some money.
Fight.
I wanna fight nape cause
it's a money fight.
Yeah,
I get it.
What do you do with Woodley?
Good question.
You offer him a big fight?
You know,
I mean that's what I,
I'm almost positive it.
Make sure I'm right on this before
I get destroyed on the underground.
But um,
I'm,
I think Dan goes,
we never offered Woodley the Diaz fight.
Oh.
So he's just trying to get it pretty sure.
Look,
the real Diaz fight as the other Diaz.
That's the real key.
Is it nick suspended though?
Let them pay that fucking money back.
Ah,
Tyron Woodley response to claim.
Nate Diaz fight was
never offered delusional.
Dana constantly demotes me as a fighter.
Whoa.
In regards to what though Jamie?
Cause is the claim that Nate Diaz
fight was never offered to him.
Delusional.
Dana did Dana say it constantly demotes
me as a fighter when the job is,
when the job is to promote his fighters,
especially champions.
Woodley said,
why would I get in camp?
Why would Nate give a $15 million
purse request if there was no fight?
It's obvious they haven't found
their blockbuster headliner yet.
This was a reality and they know it.
The inability to come to financial
terms with Nate killed it.
Oh,
there's,
but there's data going.
One of our attorneys here
started playing matchmaker,
which is weird.
He said he has a good rapport with the
Diaz brothers and he basically said to
Nate,
what if you could fight Woodley?
Me and Sean Shelby.
We're like,
how does he deserve to fight Woodley?
There's no effing list of guys that are
waiting to fight time willy and this
gives a fuck.
Oh,
there is.
There's a fucking,
what are you guys?
There you go.
Yeah.
Okay,
so the attorney went out of his way.
The attorney,
the attorney fucked up.
Who's this attorney kind of slap Dick
Attorney tries play in these games.
That's what I would do.
You.
I've seen them.
A bunch of fake attorney,
quitter Twitter accounts.
I'm an attorney with you.
I've seen it.
I'm interested to know,
would you be interested
in this last grant?
I know you say you're
retired but not retired.
Are you?
Get back at me,
dude,
that can ask it on the podcast.
Fuck yes,
dude.
To me,
his career is a sad story.
It is the guy that never was,
well they,
for whatever reason,
they couldn't work it out
with him and the UFC and Dana,
they had their disagreements
and also his fighting style.
But for him never to compete.
They're fighting style is court.
And Man,
if you're a fan of fighting,
that style is important because Ben
aspirins shuts motherfuckers down and he
shuts good guys like Lima and Bowel memo.
We've shut Lima down like
Korotkov shot him the fuck.
Shut them down.
Those are world class
guys shot his ass down.
Such a bummer.
He never gotten the EOC.
And you know what I gotta be honest.
I think if that same GSP showed up,
that fight Bisbing shows up to
fight astron African beats on Whoa.
I know.
Crazy right?
To me asking.
It's a sad story.
It's a sad,
sad story.
I agree.
He's um,
my,
if I had one wish to get a guy in
the UFC that's never been in the UFC,
he'd be the guy let me to fade.
Or it's like you already getting the
same in Beltour but he was on just
[inaudible].
You know,
I get it,
but not this stage.
At this stage I would say,
uh,
without doubt it was aspirin.
I would use my golden ticket if I had
one with Dana to get askern and yeah,
I would too.
But you know he called Dana
like a fat bald steroid monkey,
but shit.
But he's funny.
But does that mean how many
things has Dana said about guys?
It's a style thing too.
They're worried that his style is boring.
I understand that they are
in the business of fighting,
but I mean I kind of am,
but I've kind of not,
I'm in the business of,
I'm a fan of fighting and I'm
not just a fan of fighting.
Like I like to watch fights.
I want to see what the
fuck really works the best.
And when a guy can do what Ben aspirins
been able to do time and time again in
his career to world class fighters,
take them down,
smother them,
beat the shit out of him.
That's entertaining.
It's not just entertaining.
It's important for the,
for the art form.
I agree to adapt to that style that you've
got to know that a guy can do that to
a guy like Lima or it got like course
correct but also been asking can he speaks
well?
Yes.
You can hype the fight up on social media.
He speaks very well.
Yes.
Olympian.
He's also an Olympian.
And how about this?
Floyd Mayweather does not win
fights because this is exciting
to see him lose cause
he's a good trash talker.
We should start our own promotion.
We really should.
What should we co in a football field.
God Damn it,
don't you and Eddie,
you're doing that.
I don't do football fields.
Freak party fighting productions.
I think that crazy as he is the
matchmaker and it would definitely be the
matchmaker.
But first you have to
listen to a 45 minutes,
seven on the lake in the flatter,
latest uh,
false flags.
Come on man.
If we had a sitcom though,
seriously?
Like think about how crazy
different we all are.
If we had a sitcom where there
was like all these characters,
you would want to have
the crazy conspiracy guy.
Oh,
he doesn't call.
So one of the best Jujitsu
instructors in the war.
Correct.
Wizard.
Well validates it wizard guy.
So he's like,
oh all about operation mockingbird.
He's successful so you
can take what he says.
Pretty serious.
But it's also bat shit crazy.
Batshit crazy and tell you I'm crazy.
I'm crazy.
I know.
It's crazy.
I'm crazy.
But all I'm saying is look into it
then you got Callen.
He's out of his fucking mind.
It's a weird,
weird group of people.
This is the best dynamic man.
Oh Man.
We haven't done a fight
in painting in a while.
I know.
We need to do a good one.
I'm the,
with our big giant ass screen.
We did one with the big giant ass green.
Right.
Just you,
me and eddy though.
What?
Um,
what fights are coming up that we might,
there's one everyone we want.
You got here year's show
me what we got here.
Young Dreamer.
We have a,
there's one
right after that.
That's what cubs Watson.
Ooh.
And or Tayga.
Brian TC,
Te City Ortega.
Triangle city.
He's a bad motherfucker.
I love that guy.
I love his guard man.
He has one of the best guards.
That's the one.
That's the one sign.
Don't sign.
Geosyn Lawler.
Oh boy.
December 16 mother fucker.
I'm in Buffalo.
Everyone's on it.
You're in Vegas.
Shit.
Why are you in Vegas?
I'm not.
Oh No,
I'm in Vegas.
Uh,
two weeks ago.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I'm out of town to that day.
We're all out of town.
But what's up with that?
December the December 9th one.
MMM.
When's that Saturday.
December night.
I'm working.
Dammit.
No comedy.
Yeah,
I'm in like long beach or some shit.
Long Beach.
Yeah.
Let me tell you exact where I'm at.
Um,
while you're the long
beach terrace theater.
Tears stayed in Long Beach.
Guess who's going to be in Boston at the
Wilbur theater on January 19th the day
before UFC two 20 I heard
it's apprenticeship.
Oh,
that's right,
brother in Boston.
Man.
We're going to be there together.
Yes.
I'm excited.
I'm excited too,
man.
It's going to be fun.
Weekend tickets just went on sale.
We'll receive this beautiful place too,
man.
You were very funny last night.
Thanks for killing it.
Killing it.
Thanks for working out it too.
Yeah.
Let's wrap this up cause I got piss.
Um,
see you guys.
Bye everybody.
See you.