Bor.
All right,
we'll live Brett.
First of all,
thanks for doing this.
Appreciate it,
man.
All right,
glad to be here.
He looked great.
Despite all this pressure you're smiling
is,
uh,
for people that don't know what's going
on,
let's lay out all of,
uh,
all the events that have transpired.
Essentially,
you are being asked to step away from
your college for a day.
Is that what it was?
Is it one day?
Well,
this goes back farther than that.
Let's lay out the whole thing.
Okay.
So we couldn't possibly lay out the
whole thing,
but let's just,
for people that have no idea what's
going on right there listening right
now,
and they're like,
who's this Bret Weinstein guy?
So the core of it surrounds a tradition
that we have at evergreen called day of
absence in this tradition.
Stretches back long before I was ever at
the college.
I've been there 15 years.
This tradition stretches back into,
I think the early seventies.
And it's a,
it's built around a play written by
Douglas Turner Ward,
a black playwright and the play,
um,
portrays events in a fictional town
where the black population decides not
to show up one day,
um,
in order to emphasize their,
their roles in the town that the white
population is unaware of.
Um,
and as you would imagine,
all hell breaks list.
So anyway,
that's a,
it's an excellent play.
And,
uh,
some early faculty at our college
decided that we should have a day that
mirror and this event and that,
uh,
originally black faculty and students
and then later with people of color
would leave campus for a day to
emphasize the role that they play in our
community.
And then they would later the,
um,
the tradition was amended and had a day
of presence,
attitude at where people would come back
to campus.
And this has been going on.
Uh,
as I said,
since the 70s and the whole time I've
been there.
And then this year it was announced by
the organizing committee that the,
uh,
the situation would be reversed and they
asked white students,
staff and faculty not to come to campus.
And,
uh,
that did not at all sit well with me.
Um,
as I said in my letter to the,
uh,
the person who had announced this,
Rashida,
who I should say a staff and I,
she has ended up at the center of this
controversy,
I think wrongly just because my letter
and response is addressed to her.
And then it was made public by our
school paper.
So her name has been dragged front and
center.
But in any case,
uh,
my letter,
I said that there was all the difference
in the world between a population
deciding to absent themselves from a
shared space in order to highlight their
role and a population deciding to absent
another population from a shared space,
which I find unacceptable as as a
person,
as somebody devoted to the gains of the
civil rights movement.
Uh,
I just,
I and I should also probably say as a
Jew and when people start telling me
where I can and cannot,
um,
yet it rings alarm bells.
Um,
so that,
that's the gist of the story.
And the letter caused quite a stir
amongst,
uh,
students,
staff and faculty who responded.
Many of them quite angrily,
privately.
Of course people were much more divided
on the matter and there were plenty of
people who agreed with my letter,
but publicly speaking,
there was condemnation of the letter.
But the,
uh,
the event itself,
they have absence was mostly uneventful.
I,
I did go to campus,
as I said I would in my letter.
And,
um,
I actually,
uh,
it's neither here nor there.
It was accidental.
But while I was on campus,
I ran into a student that I know very
well actually student that my wife and I
were abroad in Ecuador with last year.
We were teaching abroad and,
uh,
we had 30 students with us.
And so one of the students who had
traveled with us to Ecuador,
happened to be on campus to,
this is a student of color.
I'm going to stop this
cause too much banging around in here.
Sorry.
That's all right.
That was going to go on and I was going
to drive me crazy.
I understand.
Keep going.
So I ran into this student that I,
I know well and care about quite a bit
and we had a very nice conversation.
Mostly not about day of absence.
As a matter of fact,
I can't even remember if we did a talk
about day of absence,
but there was something poignant to me
about the fact that while I was being
condemned for,
uh,
re refusing to accept this new
formulation,
that I was able to meet with a student
who is important to me and thee neither
of our racial backgrounds is fun,
is primary in our relationship.
We know each other as people.
And that's really how I would like to
see all of us interacting on campus.
We all have our backgrounds,
they matter to us,
but it can't,
it cannot become the primary interface
between us.
Let,
let,
let me stop you here and let me try to
understand,
um,
what the reaction was because you
rightly said that you think there's a
huge problem with asking people to not
show up simply based on their color of
their skin.
Exactly.
And what was the argument against that?
Like when,
when you said that,
and I read your letter and your letter
didn't sound racist at all,
it sounded very well thought out.
It's a,
it made a very good point.
But the response,
the inflammatory response to your letter
was so disturbing and shocking.
Was there anyone who had reasonable
debate with you about this?
Was there anyone who said,
well,
we should take into consideration why
they're asking us to do this.
We should sit down with them.
We should talk through this.
Was there,
was there anything reasonable or was it
just dig your heels in the sand and let
the insults and the white privilege and
all these accusations fly?
Well.
Um,
like I said,
there's a huge difference that you can't
see unless you're at the center of one
of these things between the public
discussion and the private discussion
privately,
I had very interesting discussions with
many people that was not absent,
but if you were to look in on the
discussion at the public level,
it looked as if there was consensus
united against me.
Now when you say public and private,
are the same people making contradictory
statements in public that are,
that are commiserating with you in
private or is it just different people?
Well,
a few of them do that.
The act that actually is the thing I
find most surprising is that sometimes
people will privately say one thing to
you and then publicly do another.
Uh,
mostly it's different people.
And I should say the people who,
um,
have talked to me privately and
expressed concerns are actually quite a
diverse group.
So it's not as if white folks are
disturbed by this and people of color
are united.
It's not at all like that.
But the part of the,
the hidden story here is that in order
to invent advanced certain policy
proposals,
it has to appear that the community is
united behind them and that anybody who
stands against them is standing against
them for illegitimate reasons.
So that means that the number of people
who are willing to express any sort of
nuance about what's taking place has to
be small and they have to be
dismissible.
So what they did is they called me a
racist,
which is ironic because I'm an
antiracist.
I really,
I've,
I've gone out of my way to first of all
study the question of why racism occurs.
And uh,
I've,
I believe been pretty courageous in
fighting against it where I've run into
it.
So to challenge me with that particular
epithet was a mistake on their part.
It was a strategic mistake and I kept
trying to tell them all this was still
internally being discussed in the
college.
I kept trying to tell them that they
should really check the concept that I'm
a racist.
They should ask because if they did,
they would discover that they were
actually way off the mark and then they
would have an interesting puzzle on
their hands.
Then they would have to explain to
themselves why they had found themselves
hurling.
This most poisonous a term at somebody
who not only isn't a racist but is
pretty nearly the opposite.
Well it's,
it's a standard maneuver when someone
wants to silence someone,
when someone wants to put someone in a
category that's instantly recognizable,
one of the best ones is racist.
Oh,
absolutely.
And,
and what I found is that,
um,
people simply could not figure out what
they would do if that term was applied
to them.
Right.
They were able to preview in their minds
what that would be like.
And so many people could see that there
was no escape for them.
Right.
So
it's like being called a rapist almost.
It's like even if you are exonerated,
there's still that cloud hanging hanging
above you.
Yes.
But this also actually points to
something pretty important.
And for anybody who travels this ground
themselves,
they're going to discover this,
that many of the terms that are being
used have been redefined,
but they haven't been fully redefined.
So one of the things that I've seen in
several places is that a term like
racist has been redefined so that the
bar for being a racist is so low that
you couldn't possibly help but trip over
it.
But then once you've tripped over it and
you have accepted that you are a racist,
then the stigma goes back to the
original definition.
So it is the dodging and weaving between
the two definitions that actually does
the heavy lifting.
Well,
there's also a really disturbing idea
that's being bounced around lately,
that it's impossible to be racist if
you're anything other than white.
Right.
Which is ridiculous.
It's preposterous.
Um,
anybody who looks up the actual
definition of racism will discover that
that's preposterous.
Um,
but yes,
that does pass in certain places as
logical.
Yeah.
And just,
it's parroted and this very bizarre way
that's supposed to be on challenged.
And this is a very recent thing.
I mean,
this is not something that existed two
decades ago.
Right.
I agree.
And uh,
the pace at which it's moving in the
last few years is very surprising.
It is surprising,
but it kind of makes sense because you
get into these roots groups of people,
they have this confirmation bias,
they lumped up together and they all
reinforce their ideas in this echo
chamber and they all do it inside the
colleges.
And then when it gets out to the rest of
the world,
as we're seeing with your case at
Evergreen,
it,
the,
the rest of the world is like,
what is going on over here?
Like what is happening in school and
people who are sending their children
off to school are very concerned with
the indoctrination of these ideas and
the,
the adopting these very rigid mindsets
that the rest of the world just simply
could pick apart pretty quickly.
Well,
this is the most shocking thing because
I'm,
you know,
I haven't been censured I haven't been
suspended.
I'm still on the email distribution
list.
So I'm watching the traffic inside of my
college and I'm able to compare it to
the huge flood of stuff that I'm seeing
from the outside world as they get wind
of what's going on at Evergreen.
And the difference is a million miles
inside of evergreen.
Actually we are descending further into
madness.
The,
the faculty,
um,
are uh,
blaming the fact that the campus had to
be suddenly closed due to a threat from
the outside yesterday,
uh,
on me for having talked about this in
the outside world specifically for
hilarious.
I can't see,
I can't use that term yet.
Hopefully some day.
I hope it's soon.
And you know,
I must say one thing that I don't know,
we haven't even talked about where this
uh,
where I got thrust into the spotlight
here,
which your
listeners are going to have to know in
order to understand why I'm even sitting
here.
But,
um,
but the,
uh,
the intensity and the,
um,
out of touch nature of the discussion
inside the college simply reinforces
the,
uh,
the impression that something is
desperately off that,
that what we really have is a filter
bubble that is so,
so strong that even when the world sends
very clear evidence that you've missed
something somewhere and it's time to
rethink what you've been doing.
They're not waking up and I love this
college,
this college,
we maybe we'll get to talk about it,
but the structuring of this college is
so unusual and what one can do as a
professor at Evergreen,
uh,
if you're really dedicated to teaching,
it is the place to be because you have
unparalleled pedagogical freedom,
more freedom than you'd have as a
tenured professor at Harvard.
And you also have room to teach
individually to students because our
students take one program at a time,
they're full time in one program and the
professors teach one program at a time
full time and they can go on for a full
year.
So imagine you've got 25 students and
you have him for a year full time.
You really know every student in your
class individually,
not just by name,
but you know how they think,
you know,
their backgrounds,
um,
their blind spots and that allows for a
kind of teaching that can't be done
anywhere else.
So I am quite distressed at the fact
that evergreen is now endangered by
what's going on.
Um,
and I really would like to see it wake
up and rescue itself because it is worth
rescuing.
Okay.
I watched the,
is it the president of the school who
gave the speech addressing all these
issues?
George Bridges?
Yes.
Looked like a hostage negotiation.
It looked like he had a gun to his head.
He was literally Austin.
It was so bizarre.
And kids are yelling things at him like,
what the fuck are you going to do?
And,
and,
and he just has to take it.
It's so strange.
It's such a bizarro world to view it
from the outside and to view these
preposterous allegations that these kids
are throwing at him of being racist and
everyone's being racist and no one's
doing anything to protect them.
And everyone's acting like they're in
danger.
And their ideas are in danger and their,
their minds are in danger.
It's just so,
there's so much grandstanding.
It's so preposterous.
Like what is it?
Well,
first of all,
did you see the video in which a Dr.
Bridges our president is being
challenged for his hand gestures and the
protesters are actually policing his
hand gestures.
That's,
oh,
it's,
it's fun with his hand gestures.
He's not doing this as he,
no,
it wasn't any friend.
Thank you.
Can't even go like this to a friend
because they'll pause you.
Right.
You right there in the middle.
No,
I think he's,
I mean,
I don't want to caricature this because
I really think it's very important.
As preposterous as what's going on is I
think it's very important that we
understand it.
It's very easy to dismiss it because
it's so strange.
Um,
but it's very important that we get it
right.
I think the complaint about the hand
gestures was that they represented,
um,
microaggressions,
if you will.
I don't know for sure that that was the
complaint,
but I can't make heads or tails of it
otherwise.
What was he doing?
I give you,
can you move your hands and you think he
was kind of gesturing like a person to,
that's fine to talk with emotional and
so I do think there's a,
there's a translation which is this can
be portrayed as a microaggression in
some way.
You're speaking it isn't,
well we should talk about whether
microaggression is even a good category,
but let's just say the protesters had
enough control over him that he
gestured.
They didn't like it.
They told him not to.
He capitulated and she's been doing the
entire time.
So I would say there's a huge amount of
what's going on at Evergreen.
That is what I would call a show of
force.
Is he afraid of losing his job?
Is he afraid of losing the support of
the students?
What is he afraid of?
Well,
if you had to guess.
I think he is afraid of,
he's old enough.
He doesn't need another job.
He didn't need to take the job at
evergreen,
what she took two years ago.
I think he is afraid that this is going
to be the capstone of his career.
A scandal in which he is allowed the
campus to get out of control,
which he did.
But
here's the crazy thing.
It's a non scandal.
You're a non-racist who's been accused
of being a racist.
All you did was say,
Hey,
I don't think he should be able to tell
people they can't show up for work if
they're white.
They can't show up for school if they're
white.
It seems kind of crazy.
And now hand gestures,
this is how far we've sunk that.
We're not at Kent State.
This is not the national guard shooting
students.
It's this moving your hands around while
you're talking with emotion.
That's a micro aggression.
His guys afraid of losing his job
because of his hand motions.
Well,
it,
it goes beyond that.
So when George came to the college,
he,
he studied us,
which I can't hold him responsible for
that.
That was a good move.
If he was well intentioned,
he would have done that.
But he studied us very carefully.
He had a friend to interview,
uh,
hundreds of us to figure out what was
going on at the college.
But then he set in motion,
um,
policy proposals and committees that
were empowered in a way that was
completely at odds with the way the
school has run traditionally.
How so?
Well,
so among the many unique features of
evergreen is the fact that the co,
the college is in large measure governed
by the faculty.
And even the administration,
all of the deans are faculty members who
have come from the faculty.
And when they're done being deans,
they go back to the faculty.
So the faculty has control over the
college in a way that I don't,
there's another college in the country
that runs that way.
So what that means is that if you want
to advance a policy proposal,
the faculty has to agree to it.
And George wanted to do some things that
the faculty would not have agreed to.
So I've told you about these full time
programs where students get this really
personally tailored education and they,
they join a community that everybody
knows each other.
He wanted to take those apart.
Why?
I can't imagine,
I can't imagine why you would,
I mean I,
I can,
the most generous thing to say is that
he did not understand what,
uh,
an important part of the evergreen
model.
Those programs are whatever his reason,
it was a terrible error and the only way
to do it is to advance the uh,
the idea as an equity enhancing idea.
In other words,
you can say that,
um,
that the full time programs are anti,
they are anti equity in the sense that
if you are disadvantaged you are less
likely to be able to dedicate yourself
full time to a program because you may
be going to school while you have a
family and you have a job.
And so,
you know,
no doubt there's some truth to that,
but it doesn't,
you know,
how many colleges in the country do we
have that do for credit programs and we
don't need another,
we have one college in the country that
does full time programs.
And even if it is inconvenient for many
people,
for reasons that are beyond their
control,
the real question is can we get enough
people for whom that's exactly the right
model through the door.
And you know,
there are a lot,
you know,
it's also the college is very
inconvenient for people who live in
Colorado by virtue of the fact that it's
hundreds of miles away.
So anyway,
so if you want it to advance that
proposal,
it had to be dressed up as equity
enhancing.
And once it was equity enhancing,
it became very hard to challenge it
because of course if you did challenge
it then you were anti equity.
Boy,
that's convoluted.
You're telling me.
So he wants to sorta disassemble this
very unique and very beneficial model
that you guys are operating under.
So this is just one part of it.
Now,
how does this get to this one suggestion
that white people step down?
Oh,
it doesn't.
Um,
the two are connected in the following
sense.
The president empowered he,
he chose people to be on what's called
the Equity Council.
The council has changed its name several
times.
So,
I'm not even sure what the current name
is.
I think it's the equity and inclusion
council.
But,
um,
but in any case,
he chose this council.
The council is,
uh,
if you count the two deans that are on
it,
it's only a third faculty members.
So it's mostly students,
staff and less than half faculty.
And he empowered them to propose
modifications to the college that would
be equity,
enhance it.
And the thing that they,
the,
uh,
strategic equity plan is extremely
densely written.
So it's hard to read.
And most of the people on our campus
have not read it.
Um,
most of the people in the faculty have
not read it.
In fact,
when it was released,
it was pretty clear that most of the
people on the Equity Council hadn't read
it because it was so full of errors,
spelling errors and other things that
would have been caught if people had
gone through it.
But in any case,
um,
my wife,
who also teaches at evergreen and I,
and several others did read it carefully
and were very alarmed at what was in it.
So there were,
there were features of the document that
would,
for example,
completely reorient our hiring.
So our hiring process,
I would be up to see it revised and made
better too.
Cause I don't,
I don't think we do it very well.
I think it's one of the things we were
weak about.
But um,
but anyway,
the proposal that they advanced was
that,
for example,
every single hire would have to be
justified on the basis that it was
equity enhancing,
meaning racially equity,
equity enhancing.
So imagine racially equity enhance,
right?
So not just,
uh,
not just a policy of hiring all kinds of
people and not being racially
discriminatory but being discriminatory
in looking for certain people,
people of certain colors,
like he's a little harmony aiming
towards.
I think beyond that,
beyond that,
when I read that,
I thought,
how exactly do you hire a physical
chemist and justify that this is
racially equity enhancing.
So you would
look towards like say if you had 10
chemists,
you would try to only hire the ones that
were of color.
Yes.
And that in the,
yes,
I think so.
I mean,
as I said,
the document is so densely written that
it's hard to know.
It really is set up,
I think to be dismissed so that it can
be instituted.
And then,
uh,
we can find out what it really means.
But think about the,
the model that I described about how we
teach at Evergreen.
That is not a model that anybody trains
to teach in.
And the people who do it well are very
unusual.
So there we're not looking for the same
professors that are,
you know,
that would be best at Berkeley,
for example,
we're looking for unusual people who
will take full time programs and total
pedagogical autonomy.
Meaning we actually literally are free
to teach anything we want in any way we
want.
So that freedom is a marvelous thing.
If you have a particular appetite for
figuring out how teaching should be
done,
that it's never been done anywhere else
before and you're willing to try it out
and learn from the experience and
advanced that way.
So we're looking for very unusual people
who find that an appealing challenge
rather than somebody who wants to get a
textbook and deliver the right the
regular stuff.
If we're now going to prioritize race
over everything else in hiring,
then finding those needles in a haystack
who are actually well built to deal with
that much pedagogical freedom and that
much contact with the students is going
to be that much harder because sometimes
the right person for the job just simply
isn't going to be dark skinned or who
knows.
So anyway,
I found the proposal as did as did other
people I talked to who had read it quite
alarming at the level of hiring in
particular.
So is it meant to give the impression of
diversity just by simply like,
look,
we've got our boxes checked,
here's a brown woman,
here's an Asian man,
here is,
I mean,
is that what they're trying to do?
Like look,
we've got all our bases covered.
This school is diverse.
Well,
I'd like to put a place holder on Asian
man because,
um,
during day of absence there was actually
a,
I guess you would call it a seminar held
on a how Asians might just be part of
the problem here.
Yes.
Asians and,
and a problem.
Yes.
Did you air quote when he said the
problem?
I did and I'm not even sure if I should.
And I,
you know,
the,
the world has become so bizarre.
Surrounded Asians are part of what
problem?
Well,
I think,
I think the translation is that,
um,
because um,
Asians are a population,
I don't know that is succeeding in a
particular way,
at least from the perception of those
who are deciding what these seminars
look like,
that they actually,
I don't know,
have special obligations in this.
And I might say everything I've just
said about Asians,
uh,
could be repeated for women,
especially white women who are playing a
special role in this equity battle on
our campus too.
Um,
so white women might be a part of the
problem as well as Asian men quite
clearly.
And so,
right.
So the idea,
I think,
I mean I have my own hypothesis about
this and that's really all it is,
but it does fit everything I've seen so
far is that there are entities within
the,
you know,
10 years ago the phrase women in
minorities was a very common phrase.
And what it meant was people who had
faced historical oppression.
Um,
in the current context,
that's too many people in order to,
uh,
to utilize these structures to um,
to feed a certain set of populations,
you can't very well have all women
included.
And so what's happened is people who are
perceived as yes,
having been historically disadvantaged
in some way,
but also at the moment being successful
in some sense,
uh,
are being shoved out of the coalition.
And then if they feel a loss,
a sense of loss in having been shoved
out,
the mechanism to get back in is to take
on the role of what is ironically called
allyship in this case,
which is not allyship at all.
It's an abuse of the concept of
allyship.
Allyship is really a sum symmetrical
concept.
And this is subordination in is
subordination than we hear that a lot
with a male feminist community.
The male feminists are supposed to be
allies to women.
And we,
I haven't read a paper that was a,
or an article rather that was a telling
white people,
if you truly want to be allies,
you should not take high paying jobs and
you should only leave them to
minorities.
Yes.
My,
my brother could ally.
Yeah.
That's what a good,
a good ally subordinates and that means
stepping away from a job,
et cetera.
So it's not an ally at all.
No.
It has nothing to do with ally.
And in fact,
this is the thing that is most troubling
to me about my personal situation is
that if they really wanted,
you know,
mind you,
we're going to have to fill in what they
means.
But if this coalition really wanted,
uh,
an ally for a quest for real equity,
I would be an ally.
Right?
I really equate reelect.
Right.
That's not what they want.
And so
what do you think that means then?
If they don't want real equity?
What they want is a,
a special advantage given to people of
color,
a special advantage giving to people
that were historically oppressed?
Well,
let's put it this way.
Um,
I believe so.
I believe that in general at the moment,
coalitions are unholy alliances between
two things.
And in this case you have the real
equity movement,
which are people who wish to end
oppression.
And then you have a nother movement that
wishes to reverse oppression and they
don't know that they're different
because until you reach equity,
they're pointing in the same direction.
I say.
So
one is trying to balance it out by,
in some way,
pushing down against white people.
And people who have historically had
privilege to trying to,
trying to reduce their role,
they're trying to literally oppress.
Think about the,
the,
the story we were just talking about
where the president of the college is
being told how to move his hand with his
hands.
That's not so unlike,
um,
a black person,
a black man,
let's say,
being told that he's not allowed to look
a white woman in the eye.
Right?
It's that kind of thing,
having been reversed.
This is people of color telling the
president of our college how to move his
hands.
So it was people of color that were
telling them to do this with his hands
that,
uh,
again,
I've gotta be really careful because,
you know,
I've seen the video only once and I'm
trying to remember if the people who are
doing the asking are even on the screen.
So I don't want to,
I don't want to project something that I
don't know for sure,
but it was definitely,
uh,
this,
the protesters which were protesting on,
some of them were white protesting on
behalf of people of color.
And some of them,
many of them were people of color.
But even there,
we're in trouble with the complexity
because the people of color coalition
that is protesting is not synonymous
with people of color at evergreen.
There are many people of color at
evergreen who are,
um,
either just simply bewildered by what's
going on or very troubled by it.
Because you can imagine,
I mean,
I've just put yourself in the shoes of a
person of color who came to evergreen to
get a really interesting education and
didn't want to tell the president how to
move his hands,
and then you see this happening in your
name.
What exactly are you supposed to do
then?
Well,
there's also the problem,
the very real problem with the mob
mentality,
and it is a,
a common thing with human beings and
they get together in large groups and
people started chanting and screaming
and they feel very justified and they
always want to escalate.
It's,
it's very weird.
it's a strange reaction that,
that human beings have in large groups
acting together where they just want to
ramp things up.
They want to take it to the next level.
They want to shut this motherfucker
down.
They,
it's,
it's a weird thing that people do it,
but I was watching it in your videos
where people were saying,
you should resign.
Like you need to resign.
Like,
wow,
you need to apologize to that woman for
communicating with her the way you did.
Right.
And very respectful and intelligent
manner.
Like it's,
they want to bull you around,
they want to push you around.
They want to take that professor,
that guy who has been allowed to be the
one who's talking and distributing all
the information and they want to shut
you down.
It's flat out bullying.
Yeah.
And what I'm,
what I'm seeing is that almost nobody
seems to know what to do about bullies,
especially when they're armed with a
super weapon.
Like the accusation that you're a
racist.
Nobody understands that capitulating to
bullies may solve your problem in the
moment,
but it makes the problem vastly worse
over time.
And so anyway,
all I've done is apply that piece of
knowledge that when a,
when a bully challenges you,
um,
not capitulating is just a prerequisite
to getting anywhere.
Ideally you want the bullied,
um,
to pay enough of a price that they don't
continue what they're doing.
Well,
ideally you would like to have a
rational conversation with these people
and get them to see your perspective and
they should be able to consider it and
say,
okay,
he's not racist.
Well,
yeah,
it is kind of ridiculous that we're
asking people who didn't have a say in
what color they were born to step away
from something or to we're,
we're literally discriminating in under
the guise of being anti discriminatory.
We're discriminating.
Right.
I mean that's,
and it's not even,
it wouldn't even be hard to have that
conversation one on one even I do it 20
on one.
But don't you think that that's what
happened?
They just start screaming and,
well,
I mean a,
you,
you have to get used to the fact that
you don't get there all at once.
You plant a seed that's enough to cause
them to know something about what we're
saying couldn't possibly be right or we
wouldn't be seeing what we're seeing.
Um,
the problem here is that the,
the mob that we're talking about is so
large that even,
you know,
in a couple cases on last Tuesday and
not this last year,
so I guess it was two tuesdays ago now.
Um,
the couple of times that I was faced
with a group that was,
you know,
somewhere below a hundred,
I actually do think I made some
progress,
but I thought it was not durable at all
because as soon as the event was over,
whatever progress was made got
overwritten by whatever discussion
happened next.
Yeah.
So it is possible to have these
discussions,
but there's something about the momentum
that is in play here that makes it
impossible to make any durable progress.
Durable progress is a very interesting
description.
Durable progress.
Yup.
Yeah.
Cause you're,
you're fighting against is this current
movement,
uh,
of a ridiculous ideas that that's going
on through schools.
And we saw with Yale,
we saw it with those students screaming
at,
um,
what was it?
The professor was at a professor who was
the guy that was,
they were screaming at that was a trying
to defend his wife's.
Yes.
Email about Halloween costumes.
Yes,
maybe we should allow people to wear
ridiculous Halloween costumes because
that's part of like the fun of
Halloween.
People were acting like you were saying
that we should be lynching people.
Well,
so first of all he did reach out to me.
Uh,
and his point was what you are going
through is eerily reminiscent he's
watched the videos and he was just
pointing out how shocking it was.
I mean,
even to the point of,
um,
my wife having been dragged in here
oddly,
uh,
in this discussion where she wrote an
email internal to our,
uh,
our distribution list asking the college
why they were not protecting me and my
students who were being actively stocked
on our campus harassed doxed which
students,
uh,
my current students.
But why,
why your current students being
harassed?
My current students,
like almost all of my former students
know that this charge is completely
baseless and so they have been
supportive.
So in defending you then they're being
attacked absolute like their little
soldiers in some sort of a strange
ideological battle.
They are being penalized for not falling
in line.
Wow.
That's scary.
That's real scary.
Bullying.
When someone says,
Hey,
he's a good guy.
And then someone comes after them and
said,
this is where this person lives,
let's find them that that is actually
literally happened.
And uh,
what has happened to the students once
they do find them?
Well,
so the students have been,
I think the idea is intimidation.
So I've,
uh,
I've had students followed in the woods
and that I've had students visited at
home.
Um,
it's very scary and I should say,
just in terms of putting the context
here,
as the college was pretending that
nothing serious was going on,
the police called me up on the
Wednesday,
just after the Tuesday in which I had
been challenged in my class and asked
me,
are you on campus?
And I didn't have class.
I said,
no,
I'm not on campus.
So they said,
don't come to campus.
And I said,
why?
And they said,
because,
um,
the protesters are searching car to car
for what they describe as an individual
and we think it's you and the college
has told us to stand down.
We can't protect you.
What I know,
college has told the police to not
protect you.
The college told the police to stand
down,
which means the police were literally
barricaded in the police station despite
their sense that they very much needed
to be actively protecting people outside
of the police station.
The police were left with no choice but
to barricade themselves in the police
station because they answered to the
college administration,
which told them not to act,
I think because it wished to prevent,
um,
a,
uh,
a new story.
But this meant people engage in these
protests were roving freely about the
campus,
looking for people following them.
They,
you know,
that's so incredibly aggressive,
like looking for individuals in a car
and to do what?
Well,
that's the question.
I,
my guests would be even,
they don't know,
let's say that it was me that they were
looking for,
which would make sense.
I would imagine that they would have had
the idea of,
I don't know,
taking me somewhere and getting me to
acknowledge something that they think
sort of a hostage situation.
Right.
But suppose I didn't want to acknowledge
whatever it is that they wanted me to
acknowledge,
just as I didn't want to resign when
they said I should resign.
I don't,
I don't know if they had a backup plan.
And it worries me that one of the things
that unfolded on the campus was that
people who had a very clear idea of how
things should go were they were
literally,
uh,
I mean there were barricaded in the
president's office with the president
and a bunch of faculty members and
staff.
And the story is that the president
wanted to go to the bathroom and he was
not even allowed to go privately to the
bathroom.
He had to be escorted by two people who
president of the college.
But who are the people?
Protestors,
protestors had to go with him to the
bathroom.
Right.
So that to me sounds like literally get
an APP.
It's just stunning that he agreed to
that.
It,
it is,
it is stunning.
I can't believe I'm seeing it.
Well,
this is pc gone a muck.
I mean,
this is what everybody's been worried
about.
This,
is that what you are right now is the
year that tip of the spear
we are previewing where this goes.
Taken to its logical.
Yeah.
I mean,
and could have been worse.
Had you not been contacted by the
police,
had you been in one of those cars?
Had you been pulled out?
Have you been pulled into some sort of a
hostage situation where they're trying
tell you you can't
go to the bathroom without us like they
did to the fucking president and he
agreed to it?
Yup.
I mean,
this is madness.
I mean that's like,
people should go to jail for that.
Well,
so,
okay.
That's kidnapping,
kidnapping.
I do think,
um,
that the administration and certain
faculty members have a lot of
responsibility here.
So I think in some sense,
yes,
it's literal kidnapping.
The students,
however,
I believe have become tools of something
that they don't really understand tools
of what though?
Of their own making.
I mean,
is it an ideology,
an ideology outside of the school that
they subscribed to or is it their own?
I mean,
what is it?
Well,
I believe
it is a,
um,
a militant belief structure.
And,
uh,
I do think based on what we've seen on
our campus,
it is emanating from a subset of the
black population.
Okay.
So I'm not saying that this is black
people doing this,
but I'm saying that the people who are
at the forefront of it happened to be in
that part of the coalition of people of
color and that they are advancing a set
of assumptions and beliefs that they
seem to imagine,
uh,
describe some future world that they
would like to reach.
And it's a future road.
I mean,
it's preposterous.
It will never happen because what is the
future world where the 400 years of
oppression of black people in North
America results in a,
uh,
a reversal of roles?
I think,
I mean,
I can't imagine having that thought and
following it through and not realizing
that this can't possibly be anything
like a way forward.
I also see something that they've
described this reversal roles.
Well,
they would like to come to this
conclusion.
So I would imagine that your listeners
having heard me just say what I said,
have to be wondering a little bit about
me and,
and where,
where am I sympathies really lie.
But what I've seen,
and if,
and if your listeners go looking at the
videos that came out of evergreen over
the last 10 days posted by the
protesters,
I should point out videos that they
thought they had them look good.
Um,
they will find many instances in which
the official order of things says,
um,
well,
let's say there's a four o'clock meeting
on the Tuesday in which I was challenged
in the morning four o'clock meeting.
That became very dangerous.
Um,
and the meeting began with an
announcement that the chairs and the
food,
we're for people of color and that white
people shouldn't use them.
Uh,
yes,
I know
the chairs and the food.
We're only for people of color.
Correct.
White people have to be hungry.
Right?
You can't sit down.
Right.
And I've also seen,
you know,
I don't remember where I saw it and I
probably have a of it,
but I saw something where,
uh,
some activists,
put out a message,
a broadcast message that said a person
of color needed a power adapter for a
computer.
Where there any white people who could
fetch one or something like that.
I mean,
the thing is that it's preposterous,
but it is also putting in danger the
actual vision of a world in which race
ceases to provide advantage.
Right?
Um,
so anyway,
it's jeopardizing that.
It should be reversed.
It's just so crazy.
Like we should press now like,
no,
does she be none?
Right?
We should get past this,
right?
We should be anti supremacist 100%.
This idea.
I mean,
can you imagine if there was a college
in North America that suggested that
white people only should eat and white
people only should be able to take the
seats?
Is that what's going to happen 300
years?
So what if black people are pressed for
the next 300 then white people come back
and say,
hey,
we're going to have to turn this around
again.
I mean,
isn't the idea that a hundred years from
now white people are going to be a
minority in America because the rates of
birth is with Latinos and black folks
that w w we'll it,
there won't be a this minority group
anymore that they will be.
In fact,
a majority.
All I can say is it's so obviously a
wrong path just in terms of a,
it's not an honorable objective.
It's racist.
It's race.
It's absolutely racist.
I mean it's not even,
it's not even difficult to see that.
It just simply is racist.
But if you say that on my campus at the
moment you're the racist for not
understanding why this is logic.
So how do people react when someone says
a person of color and needs a power
adapter?
Can a white person go fetch it?
Are these white air quote allies?
Exactly.
Running these Beta males and just
running to go grab a white power adapter
and give it to this person of color.
Is that what's happening?
That's the literal description of it.
Jesus Christ.
And then they have to,
in a few years,
they're going to have to go out into the
workforce.
Well,
and that's the thing that,
well this is a whole other side of the
puzzle.
What this is really about,
and not just at Evergreen,
but this movement which has taken over
so many campuses and shut down.
So many people who spoke with positions
that were not,
um,
somehow sanctioned,
uh,
is really a battle between two
incompatible worldviews,
uh,
within the academy.
So on the one hand you have the sciences
and all of the things that function on
the same assumptions that the sciences
do about how you figure out what's true.
And then you have these postmodern
disciplines,
which basically argue that the tools
that the science claim are about
figuring out what's true are actually
tools of oppression themselves.
And so,
you know,
another video.
Damn.
Rulers.
Yeah,
exactly.
Um,
so there's this video in the middle of,
of the Tuesday,
the first Tuesday of these protests
where the president barricaded with
these protesters is talking to them and
uh,
the protesters actually flat out say,
in referring to my email that I
mentioned the word phenotype,
and that that inherently tells you that
I must be a racist to even be thinking
about a scientific term in the context
of this,
which I find horrifying because these
very students stand to gain a tremendous
amount.
They will be most powerful in the world
in pursuing equity.
Among other things,
they will be most powerful in the world
if they are armed with a scientific tool
kit with an analytical tool kit that
allows them to,
to be forceful rather than to be
preposterous.
What was the context you used the word
phenotype again,
I,
I forget.
Oh,
I said,
um,
that I would like us in my challenge to
the new day of absence formulation.
I said I would like us to put phenotype
aside,
right?
But phenotype aside,
meaning that I did not want us
discussing equity as teams,
as different teams broken up by stem
color.
Um,
and so the very fact that I said
phenotype and that I suggested that I
would be willing to give a lecture to
anybody who wanted to come about what I
understand to be the evolutionary
context of racism.
And they did not want the lecture.
They assumed that if I said evolution
and racism that I was going to give a
eugenics lecture or something like that.
Um,
and so it's,
it's preposterous.
The way the way this works is they shut
down the conversation before you can
have it so that they don't actually know
what you're going to say and therefore
don't need to address it.
Oh God.
Yeah.
It's quite frightening.
Well,
it's,
it's bizarre because it's,
it's primarily occurring in
universities.
It's not happening really in high
school's very much.
It's sort of bubbles up in high schools.
It appears by people that I talked to
that have been in high school and gone
into universities that you see echoes of
it.
You see the beginnings.
And then when it gets to college,
you're away from your parents.
You're in some new place.
They,
everyone gathers in groups,
they dig their heels in the sand and
they go fucking crazy.
Well,
I mean there is something about college
and you know,
and we all did,
she dump stuff in college.
Um,
but I also think there's a hidden reason
for being colleges,
which is that there is real inequity in
civilization that needs to be dealt
with.
I would say the thing that I find most
troubling is the skew in policing and in
the courts that results in
disproportionate fractions of some
populations being incarcerated,
which has a terrifically destabilizing
impact on this community.
So I think that that is a very real harm
that would be hard to overstate and that
absolutely has to be addressed,
uh,
just,
just to even make any claim on being a
fair society.
That said,
it is very hard to attack the,
um,
the private prison complex,
for example.
Right.
It's a,
it's a difficult challenge.
On the other hand,
the universities are a soft target.
They can't defend themselves and they
already have sympathies in the direction
of,
you know,
a view of a radically different enhanced
world.
So in effect,
I think we're being challenged on the
basis that the inequities on our
campuses are completely intolerable and
that that is largely a fiction.
And that what really is happening is
that this is displaced anger over a
system that is fair,
that's been pointed at something that
can't defend it
itself.
That's fascinating.
So this is a reaction to the actual real
inequities of the outside world,
the systemic racism in places like
Baltimore and what we're finding out
about places where they literally would
not sell homes to black people,
communities that have just had
generation after generation of
impoverished people that are fighting
off crime ridden neighborhoods.
Right.
Or water you can't drink because it has
red in it went right.
Exactly.
So what the universities,
what,
what's happening in the universities is
a sort of a misguided reaction to all
the real inequity in the way
world.
I would say not misguidance ms direct Mr
wreck.
He just pointed at the wrong thing.
And the reason it's pointed at the
colleges and universities is that they
simply can't defend themselves.
That's fascinating.
And so,
um,
this is occurring in universities all
over the country and at a rate that's
according to people that I know that
teach pretty unprecedented at,
this wasn't the case 20 years ago,
that you would have dissent,
you would have debate,
you'd have discussion,
but you wouldn't have these full blown
ideological mobs.
Yeah.
I think the thing is it hadn't been
operationalized yet.
The thought process that led to this was
postmodernism has been,
um,
has been around for decades.
And so there were places you could go if
you want it to have an absurd
discussion.
You could go,
for example,
to cultural anthropology.
Cultural anthropology was captured by
postmodernism 30 years ago.
And so if you want it to hear people say
really crazy things about what's true,
cultural anthropology was a place you
could do it.
If you step next door to physical
anthropology,
it was just fine.
Um,
and so anyway,
that's been in the university and what's
happened is it has been,
um,
how would one put it?
It has been operationalized or activated
so that it is now,
um,
it is now,
it forms the core of a vision that
college students are trying to bring
about.
Not all of them,
but enough of them that you can't run a
college without either deciding to
capitulate or figuring out how you're
going to fight back.
What,
was there a way that this could have
been stopped or nipped in the bud in the
years past or zero that this could have
been sort of planned for?
Was there a lack of lack of foresight?
Yeah.
Um,
this is exactly what I was talking about
a few minutes ago.
If you,
um,
if you give in to the bully,
the bully comes back stronger.
Um,
we've been given into the postmodern
bully for decades and it's now come back
in a form that nobody knows what to do
with it.
Um,
so what was the original reason to give
in when it was a more mild argument?
Well,
because it was an abstraction.
Hmm.
So
originally the idea that,
um,
that certain,
that based on their history,
certain people who had been,
for example,
largely shut out of the sciences,
we're entitled to think without having
to deal with the structures that had
been built around,
let's say a man and most mostly white
men over the course of western
scientific history.
So the idea that women may be needed a
place to discuss what was true that was
not structured by men.
I get that.
And in fact,
there's a very good example in my own
field where the difference between the
way men and women,
I don't mean every man and every woman,
but the difference on average,
I think played a decisive and very
positive role when Louis Leakey
empowered three women to go study the
three great apes in order to figure out
what's going on with them.
And so Jane Goodall to figured out what
was going on with the chimps because she
was,
uh,
because she was female and because she
didn't subscribe to the rules that men
had written down about how you study
these creatures.
And so it is a case where something
about the way men look at the world had
prevented people like George Shaller,
uh,
who had,
made his mark studying lions.
He didn't do so well with gorillas.
Um,
so anyway,
Jane Goodall's female approach worked
and it,
it is largely the reason that we
understand chimps today.
On the other hand,
Jane Goodall took the scientific toolkit
and throughout the rules that had been
biased,
rather than rejecting the scientific
toolkit,
which is what the postmoderns are doing,
which I think is just tragic,
what we should be doing is arming
everybody who goes to college.
And frankly,
we should be arming everybody who can't
go to college with a scientific toolkit
that lets them figure out what's true,
especially now because science is the
ultimate bullshit detector.
And you know,
this era is,
you know,
hopefully this is peak bullshit,
but they need the ultimate bullshit
detector.
It
does seem like people share.
Right?
And it seems like that that's one of the
reasons why it's so important for you to
stand your ground is that you,
you are,
you're being very clear in what,
what you perceive the situation to be.
And you,
you're doing it in a very logical and a
very rational,
well thought out and,
and clearly way you're
showing everyone what's wrong with this.
It is a scientific approach and you are
literally using the very tools that
you're trying to empower these young
children,
young children feel like they are.
Yeah.
He's kid because that kid,
yeah.
That works.
Yeah.
Youthful exuberance.
A human beings.
Millennials.
Yeah.
I hate those words.
Eight,
those generational terms.
But you're,
you're,
you're literally using your,
you're dealing with a dilemma and you're
using the very tools that you would like
them to learn from this university and
take forth into the world.
I mean,
it is a very scientific approach.
You're,
you're,
you're saying like,
well,
the,
no,
this is not,
that's not racism.
This is racism.
And what you're doing here is actually
racism.
Right.
And in fact,
you know,
the irony is,
um,
so my students and really my students,
many of them are both my students and my
wife's students.
We both teach you evolutionary biology
and students bounce back and forth
between our programs.
So,
you know,
we have people in our community who are,
uh,
empowered by having an understanding of
how things function evolutionarily.
That gives them a window into all sorts
of things including,
you know,
human social dynamics and other things
that affect us all,
um,
all the time.
Uh,
so anyway,
yes,
there,
there is a way of thinking about,
um,
virtually any of the issues that most
people care about using scientific
rationality,
which does not mean that you put aside
your humanity,
but it means that you give your humanity
a tool to understand what is going on
before you figure out how you feel about
it and whether something ought to be
done.
How does this university survive this?
How does the community survive this?
How do these students come out of this
with a new understanding of what went
wrong and in some way that allows them
to save face and still be a viable part
of the community at is a beautiful
question.
Thank you for asking it.
I really hope it works.
I got three things and I'm afraid I'm
gonna forget one of them.
But first of all,
there's one clear first step.
The president of the college has to step
down and there are two reasons he has to
step down.
One,
this is how things work.
I don't like are you moving?
Your hands were talking to,
I'm sorry John microaggressions that
um,
so he's got to step down because a,
when something has gone as crazy as
we've seen things go on evergreens
campus,
there is an expectation that somebody
will take responsibility.
So he has to,
he has to step down to signal to the
world that somebody is taking
responsibility.
But in this case,
he also absolutely must step down
because this is his responsibility.
He set this in motion and he made this
happen.
And so it is not an injustice at all
that he should have to step down.
And I frankly am flabbergasted that it
hasn't happened yet.
I do not understand how the board of
trustees could allow him to maintain
that position as long as he,
but first thing is he has to step down
at the point he steps down.
That's going to flip a switch.
Suddenly the question is,
okay,
what now?
The next thing that would have to happen
is the faculty of my college would have
to evidence that they actually got
something out of this rather than
feeling that they had been wrongly
portrayed in the media or something like
that.
If the faculty,
and there are many good faculty who do
understand what's going on.
So,
um,
they have been quiet because frankly
they're afraid of what happens to them
if they're not.
But um,
but George has to step down or be fired
and the faculty have to rally and
evidence that they learned something.
And then the third thing,
and in some ways,
this is the one that is,
I think the toughest.
They came after me.
They came after two other people,
the chief of police of our police force,
Stacey Brown,
who they have been attempt,
she is a,
um,
utterly professional,
extremely good police officer who is
also an evergreen graduate and
interested in cleaning up policing.
She wants feet,
she's aware of what bad policing is and
what the campus police,
campus police we,
so it's independent of the the region.
Right.
Which is why they were stood down
because they are part of the
administration is,
is it has control over them.
But the chief of police was demonized.
And uh,
I mean in the most disgusting way,
it's posters of her wearing a kkk outfit
in some sort of,
I dunno why sexed up garb was
distributed on like,
this is a mother of three.
Right.
And what,
what was,
what was the logic behind it?
Well,
no lie,
I hate to say it,
but the logic I think was this saying
that,
um,
circulates all cops are bad.
So she was literally her,
uh,
her,
swearing in was protested.
So at the very moment she took the job,
she was already persona non grata.
Um,
they want no police.
Well,
I knew,
in fact they advocated for that.
There was in the middle of this protest,
there was a,
uh,
something like,
police community review board.
I'm not sure exactly what it's called,
but there was some sort of a gathering
where suggestions about better policing
were advanced and the protesters
actually advanced not only the idea that
the police be moved off campus,
that they'd be disarmed.
Um,
but that in fact that campus policing be
turned over to what they call community
policing.
So at the very same moment that you have
protestors,
uh,
as judge,
jury and executioner searching cars for
people stalking them,
they're telling us that actually they
want official control over the policing
of the campus.
It couldn't,
it couldn't be more ironic.
Well,
so how do they plan to handle sexual
assault,
violence,
anything along those lines?
Funny,
you mentioned sexual assault because the
third,
which in addition to me and the chief of
police was at,
is our grievance officer.
Um,
our grievance officer,
Andy Siebert,
um,
is also an excellent human being who is
very dedicated to her job and very
dedicated to evergreen and has been
there for a very long time.
And one of the things that she's been
accused of is not being sensitive to,
um,
allegations of sexual assault.
Now,
what she has not said in her own defense
fees.
So I'm interested in protecting the
college from its own worst instincts
that which she has not said in her own
defense is that she runs a summer camp
for girls who have been sexually
assaulted.
This is the,
and I think she funds it out of her own
pocket.
So in all three cases,
in my case,
I'm accused of being a racist in Stacy
Brown,
the police chiefs case,
she's accused of being a brutal biased
cop and an Andy sieberts case fuse
accused of being insensitive to people
who have been assaulted in all three
cases.
Not only are these things wrong,
they are the opposite of right.
And so,
uh,
I was just going to say,
the third thing that I wanted to say
was,
George has to step down.
The faculty has to wake up and then
everybody needs to take a look at the
fact that three for three,
they've gone after people in classic
witch hunting style.
And the person in question was the exact
opposite of what they were saying at the
point.
You discover that you've been hunting
witches and then it turns out the people
in question are innocent.
You have to step back and ask yourself
how you got there.
How did that happen to you that you
ended up hunting innocent people?
That should be a wake up call for
everybody involved.
Well,
as soon as you start talking about
searching for cars and searching for
individuals,
my mind immediately escalates to
violence.
That's,
that's how my mind goes when I know mobs
and I know people and I,
and I'm,
I'm,
I just have far too much experience with
violence.
And I know what happens when people ramp
up ideas without a real predetermined
goal.
They don't have,
uh,
like what we'd like to do is get Brett
and talk to them one on one and,
well,
it's want to invite him to have a
debate,
a one on one debate with someone without
an audience so they could sit down and
hash out these ideas of,
hey,
you're working with something.
Well,
how do we find them?
maybe he's in one of these cars like
that.
That's not what they're doing right now.
They go,
we're going to find him,
but they don't have a step after they're
going to find you.
Unless they do.
And it might be fucking barbaric.
I mean,
it might be,
you know,
we're going to kidnap him.
We're gonna,
we're gonna force him to read this
letter.
You know what I mean?
W W it's really hostage.
Shit.
I,
I agree.
And I do think,
you know,
I don't,
I don't know.
I'm not an expert on what happens when
mobs ultimately do something.
You know,
like I think it's my shawl con,
uh,
who was,
killed by,
by a mob over,
suppose it blasphemy,
uh,
I guess last month,
but um,
was that in Turkey?
I thought it was in Pakistan,
but wasn't in Turkey.
Okay.
Um,
all right.
I'm sorry.
I should,
that's all right.
But um,
that's a different,
but in any case,
the world and different,
it's a different world.
But nonetheless,
the point is a mob,
a mob thinks that it's on the right
track and it's so convinced of what it
believes that uh,
it ends up doing something that it
doesn't know it's capable of.
And there's also a diffusion of
responsibility in the large group.
They're allowed to do much more horrific
things.
You would ever do one on one to an
individual,
100%.
So I don't think that anyone intends
that,
but I'm not sure that they ever do.
Well,
the ramping up of things is what
terrifies me.
I just,
I've just seen it too many times where
people get together in large groups of
people and things escalate and no one
knows why.
And then all of a sudden it's chaos and
there's an a literal feeling in the air
that violence could erupt.
And I don't know if there's,
maybe you would be able to tell me,
is there some evolutionary echo of that
from back in the day when we would get
invaded by large groups of people and we
had to switch over immediately to some
sort of a warlike mindset.
I don't know what it is,
but there's something really bizarre
that happens to people in large groups.
And if you've ever been in a concert
where a riot breaks out or a stampede
where things go crazy,
it's scary,
it's terrifying.
But you're absolutely right about the
evolutionary roots that these are
programs that exist in us for
circumstances.
And one of the things,
you know,
if I had been able to give the lecture
that I proposed in the letter that got
me in so much trouble with people.
Um,
one of the things that I would say is
that the most dangerous thing is that we
have these latent programs that are
waiting for evidence that it is the
moment to do x,
y,
or Z.
And because we haven't been in those
circumstances until the moment,
those programs are triggered,
we don't even,
we're not even aware that human beings
are capable of some of the things
they're capable of.
So we have to guard against these things
at all costs if we really,
you know,
never again is a very important concept.
And if never again is to mean anything,
we have to understand why it happens in
the first place so that we can,
um,
repair the world.
So it becomes impossible.
Yes.
Instead of giving into the influence of
these ancient programs,
understanding that they're there and
recognizing them when they go live.
Exactly.
In fact,
maybe the thing that,
um,
would be worth remembering is what
happens to a drowning person when a
person drowns.
They're very dangerous,
right?
Because they,
their body switches on a drowning
program that basically looks for
anything that can be pushed down so you
can get up to where are the areas,
which means that somebody can drown,
you know,
their closest kin by accident because a
drowning program that they've never seen
active until the first time they face
drowning is suddenly online.
Right.
And so that's
a simple one.
But there are other ones too.
There are ones for,
for tyranny and I,
I believe things like genocide where
populations that have successfully
eliminated other populations have done
well.
And so knowing that human beings are
actually wired for genocide under
certain circumstances is,
um,
well it's a sobering responsibility,
but it's also hopeful to me because if
you know that it's there,
you can figure out what triggers that
and you can,
I think we can rule it out by raising
people in an environment where awareness
of that program allows us to teach them
in such a way that that program is
deactivated.
And that might be the only way to be
you.
You must be aware of the fact that there
is a potential to disassociate and
decide that this is the,
that this group of people as the other
and that they are not you and you could
do horrific things to them.
And that this is literally a part of how
human beings evolved to 2017.
How we got through all the horrific
things that have taken place in the
past.
And if you think about,
um,
the,
uh,
the religious innovations that have
occurred in the history of most of the
populations on earth today,
they involve a recognition at some point
where,
um,
the definition of self gets broadened to
a larger group.
So if you think about,
for example,
um,
the golden rule,
the golden rule has,
uh,
has progenitors in the hillel tradition.
Um,
um,
but it is basically somebody saying that
some large entity needs to be treated as
some extension of self.
And really,
um,
this may sound funny to people,
but if we are to survive the next
century as a,
as a species,
it's going to have to be through the
recognition that actually all human
beings are trapped on one tiny little
planet and we're in severe jeopardy.
And really we have to start treating
each other not as other because we will,
you know,
we will be fighting each other as the
whole experiment goes to hell.
Um,
we have to recognize that we actually
face a common enemy,
which is the unintended consequences of
the system we've built.
I never liked flipped.
Bring up Ronald Reagan as the voice of
reason,
but he had a,
a fantastic quote way back in the day
and one of his speeches during the cold
war where he was talking about how we
would bond together if we were
approached by some alien life form from
another planet that threatened us.
How we would all realize that we are,
we are all in this together.
I had no idea that he said that it was a
great speech cause the conspiracy
theorist went crazy and they're like,
there's aliens man.
Well
I think this is totally right and here's
the,
here's the even better part I think,
which is,
yeah,
if there was an alien race that came to
invade the Earth,
we'd rally,
um,
if there was an asteroid that we had
enough time to know that was coming and
that we would have to rally together to
do something about it,
we do something about it.
And so it is perfectly possible for the
mechanisms that evolution built into us
to fight each other.
That caused us to cooperate,
to fight other groups,
to be re targeted at things that aren't
other groups that are problems.
And so what frustrates me more than I
think anything else is right now we do
face a common enemy.
And that common enemy is,
you know,
let's say climate change would be one
facet of it,
but it's the system that's set climate
change in motion,
which has also given us nuclear reactors
that are unstable and difficult to
control.
It's given us,
um,
economic policies that are going to
cause us to destabilize as a result of
the concentration of wellbeing and power
in a small number of hands.
Those are common enemies.
And if we allowed the circuitry that is
in us to be triggered,
that allows us to fight a common enemy,
actually we would be quite united at the
moment and for a good cause,
which is one of the more disturbing
things about trump pulling out of the
Paris climate agreement.
Is that what,
what it says is that we're not in this
together.
I mean,
even more so than it says that these
guys are,
I mean,
he has advisors in this Epa guy is a
very dangerous character.
That's a climate change denier and
there's so much anti science going on in
this administration.
You could,
you wouldn't even know where to begin,
right?
But what are the real problems is that
we're moving away from this group of
people that's trying to figure out what
to do about emissions,
what,
what do we do about all this garbage?
What do we do about all this ways?
And it's not even necessarily just about
climate change,
it's about sustainability.
It's about what are we doing with the
biproduct of civilization?
If there's one thing that should cut
across political lines,
it's that question,
what do we do about the things that
jeopardize us all together?
And if it's one thing that should
disturb us about capitalism,
the number one thing is putting profit
ahead of the environment that we
literally need to sustain life.
And that's something they're trying to
do with bringing back fucking Cole Cole
of all things.
And they have these coal miners on TV
and they don't even agree with it.
They had that,
they interviewed a bunch of coal miners
today that were president trump
supporters that were at happy.
They voted for trump because he's going
to bring back coal and they're like,
well,
I don't know about this.
Why is he stepping away from the climate
change thing though?
Like even people in the coal mining
industry or torn on this.
I mean this is a very dark time in that
way.
Very dark.
And you know,
and ironic too,
because I mean we're now behind the
eight ball because we've put this off
for so long.
We should have started doing this 25 or
30 years ago,
but even now it is actually not as hard
as people think to figure out how the
world might function that didn't create
this jeopardy.
As a matter of byproducts of everyday
activity.
It's actually not that difficult,
but the system is built to frustrated.
So you know,
in the same sense if you step back from
the last presidential election and you
think about how is it that we ended up
with two such lousy candidates for this
position with such power,
some something in the system has to be
off that we don't end up with any viable
candidates for that office.
Um,
and it's the same.
It's the same problem we are,
we are caught in loops that prevent
proper solution making.
It's not that solution making isn't
possible.
It's that solution making is not
someplace we can go from here because of
a mundane reasons in our system that are
ultimately going to kill us if we're not
careful.
Well,
it's also such a complicated structure
that outside of completely radical
change,
like restructuring everything from the
bottom up,
like tearing it down literally to the
foundation and rebuilding it.
How else are you going to fix this thing
with lobbyists and special interest
groups and congressmen,
a representative government.
It's like there's so many different
areas that allow for the possibility of
corruption and an influence and just
cronyism.
It's just,
it's such a dark and twisted corridor
that you enter into if you're
considering any kind of reform,
well,
it can't be reformed and it's not going.
We can't tear it down either.
I mean,
uh,
well what we do,
well,
that's an interesting question and I
must say it's something that,
um,
a number of friends of mine and I have
been working on for some time.
There are answers which five,
seven years ago I wouldn't have thought
possible that I now believe actually are
possible.
And so what we're really talking about,
we,
we can't have revolution.
We can't afford it,
nor will it work.
The power arrayed against revolution is
so immense that it's inconceivable that
it could,
it could function.
We also can't afford a disruption,
massive enough to cause the system to
restructure on its own if for no other
reason than the fact that we've got more
than 400 nuclear reactors on earth today
that require constant inputs of power or
they melt down and spill not only the
contents of the reactors,
but the contents of the spent fuel pools
where we've stored decades worth of
spent material.
So basically we have to restructure the
system without letting it collapse and
without confronting it in the
traditional way.
So we need effectively revolutionary
change without revolution.
However,
notice that,
um,
your life today doesn't look all that
much like your life 30 years ago from
the point of view of how you go about
things,
how you navigate around the world,
things sweep across civilization,
um,
in a market system based on utility.
And,
uh,
that model can also be used to replace
the system that we have currently.
Um,
so in essence,
if you think forward is what is the
World gonna look like 20 years from now?
It's very hard to know because you know
how much change has come in the last 20
years.
So there will be revolutionary change at
the moment.
It will be dictated by a market and it
will basically give us more of what we
think we want rather than what we
actually need.
However,
the same mechanism that causes,
um,
technologies to sweep across
civilization can be utilized to have
meaningful change in the way we
interrelate with each other and the way
we govern ourselves,
sweep across civilization.
So that's the project that we've been
working on behind the scenes.
So what is the project like?
How does it work?
Well,
it involves different people with
different expertise and,
uh,
there are those who are expert in the
technological aspects.
In other words,
identifying those technologies that
actually stand a good chance of
replacing the dangerous stuff that runs
civilization.
Now,
there are those of us who are involved
in the game theoretic aspects of what it
is that keeps the current system
stabilized as it is and what would have
to change in order to,
um,
replace it.
Uh,
so anyway,
it's,
it's a complicated effort,
but it is not,
I am hopeful in a way that I wasn't,
um,
Mac during occupy,
let's say,
uh,
because I no longer think that the only
route forward is one of the traditional
modes that we've seen.
So do you think it's going to be a slow
integration of technology into people's
lives,
to the point where it's going to affect
the system itself?
To the point where the current system,
the way it works just won't operate?
The wid does?
No,
not really.
What are you saying specifically?
What I'm saying specifically is that
people have been shut out of the gains
of civilization and they have been fed a
small portion of the phony growth that
our system generates to placate them.
They've also been threatened with
austerity,
which is largely a false threat.
In other words,
they've been told,
yes we could do something different,
but you're going to have to give up most
of the things that you value.
So how about it?
And in fact the world could be a very
exciting place to transform.
Um,
if we,
uh,
work to recognize the real landscape
that we face rather than the story that
has been portrayed that has told us that
we really don't have any good options.
Um,
it seems that there,
there is still time though,
frankly the clock is ticking.
So like what would be the steps?
It would be taken in order to make this
a reality?
Well,
I'm,
the question is,
do I want to say that out loud here?
Um,
where the entities that want to oppose
it and know exactly what it is before it
comes.
I don't know how as that is,
what I will say is that there are a good
number of us working on the puzzle.
We're serious about it.
And um,
we are,
uh,
the things that would typically be used
to dismiss us a ought not be,
we're not looking to,
um,
to be the head of some system that
enriches us.
We're looking to make the planet
function in a way that serves everyone.
So do you think there's some sort of
conspiracy to stop this?
Like if you actually bring it up,
you think that there would actually be
people that would make or take active
measures in order to hold it off at the
pass?
I don't think it's exactly like that.
I think,
um,
there is a structure that has emerged
that exists,
um,
administrations come and go,
but there's a structure that doesn't,
and it seems to have a central principle
behind it,
which is it doesn't like change that it
can't control changes.
One thing change happens,
but it's not interested in change that
could upend it.
So anyway,
the reason that we ended up with a
battle between,
um,
you know,
uh,
non-viable Republican and a non-viable
Democrat is that they have passed a test
in which they do not threaten the
fundamental structures underneath.
In fact,
trump may actually be a violation of
that.
He may actually threaten those
structures and they may be trying to
figure out what to do about them.
Um,
but,
uh,
but in general,
what we have is a system that filters on
the way towards the levers of power such
that anybody who gets their wouldn't use
them in a dusty,
they stabilizing fashion,
which is why we saw the DNC conspiring
against Bernie Sanders.
Absolutely.
We saw them conspire in the most direct
terms.
And then we've seen them in court defend
it by saying that had every right to do
it rather than denying it.
Yeah.
Um,
so anyway,
I,
I'm not,
you know,
it's too easy to say conspiracy.
And it is too,
it's too simplistic because it implies
that people got together in a room and
said things out loud.
And that does happen sometimes,
but it also happens through another
mechanism,
a mechanism of,
uh,
but scientifically we would call
emergence where those structures that
frustrate change outcompete structures
that allow change.
So it may be that what we have,
our forces that resist change
reflexively without knowing what they're
doing the same way,
you know,
a tree grows towards the light without
knowing what it's doing.
Oh,
okay.
Don't you think though,
that there'd be some benefit to
discussing these potential solutions to
these issues out loud and then people
would sort of like pick it up and act on
it,
especially given this enormous platform?
I do.
Um,
so it's not that I don't want to talk
about them.
I mean,
in fact,
we've,
we held,
uh,
what's called an unconference in Palo
Alto.
Uh,
several months ago.
So it's not that we don't talk about
them out loud.
What I'm concerned about is that a,
I'm only one of the people involved.
And so,
you know,
I have my area of expertise in,
in this group.
Um,
but there are many others are areas of
expertise that I can't speak to as
directly.
Um,
so anyway,
I'm,
I'm concerned about unearthing the thing
in a place where it will be a cartoon
version of something that's actually
more sophisticated than that.
I understand.
I'm not,
I'm not averse to,
to answering questions.
If you got them.
Um,
what would be the first step?
Well,
the first step would probably involve,
um,
a blockchain currency that had strengths
connected to it that made it,
um,
competitively superior to something like
the dollar.
In other words,
the dollar is a flawed entity in
multiple regards,
but the dollar depends on our valuing
it.
And the thing about blockchain
currencies is that blockchain currencies
can be exchanged between entities that
have an agreement about,
um,
preferring them.
So,
for example,
a group of people could decide to pay
each other in a,
in blockchain currency of some kind,
uh,
based on ideals that are not the same
ones on which,
uh,
you know,
our,
our nation for example,
is founded.
So you could agree to a higher set of
standards for something and agreed to
prefer,
uh,
each other in the context of business.
So you would,
you would do business with those who had
also agreed to the same higher set of
principles and that currency could
therefore,
um,
displace something like the dollar.
Well,
it'd be fascinating to see.
I mean,
I know that bitcoin and blockchain it a
lot,
a lot of these different
cryptocurrencies are gaining momentum
and in fact,
bitcoin weren't we just talking about
this is higher now than it has been like
literally in years.
Ever,
ever.
Yeah.
So there's some momentum in that regard.
It'd be nice to see them use side by
side,
you know,
to see if it could be possible that to
gain more momentum to get to the point
where it's you right now,
you bring up,
I'm going to buy something with bitcoin.
People think you're a freak,
right?
I got my friend and Andreas Antonopoulos
who's a big in the bitcoin movement.
I've had them on the podcast a few
times.
He's written books on it and he does
everything in bitcoins paid in bitcoin.
He buys his airline tickets and bitcoin
pays his rent in bitcoin.
I mean he's,
he's deep,
but it's maybe blood is one of a
thousand people in the world that might
do that.
Right?
Um,
although you know,
everything transformative starts in a
small minority of people doing it
somewhere.
So what I would say is that the
cryptocurrency isn't enough in and of
itself.
You have to couple it with the
structures that are capable of the other
problems of civilization.
So someone figuring out what to do with
nuclear waste,
that would be a nice one.
That's a Biggie,
right?
That's a big,
and it's a high on my list of,
of let's say fears,
is that those nuclear reactors are so
dangerous by virtue of what it is that
keeps them stable day in and day out.
That really if people understood the
danger they faced based on those
reactors and the spent fuel that they,
um,
they have,
uh,
people would be alarmed.
Well,
if people just paid attention to
Mishima,
I mean,
just look at what's happening and know
how many of those there are.
And here's the other issue.
You know,
I've talked to people before and there's
a this,
I mean it's,
it's,
it's really funny how when you
subscribed a certain ideology,
whether it's a liberal ideology or
whether it's conservative ideology,
you immediately immediately adopt a
series of beliefs that go along with
that.
And one of them,
and on the right is a,
that nuclear power is clean energy.
You know,
and my argument to that has always been,
we've only had it for 60 years.
And look how many places you can't even
go anymore.
I mean,
Fukushima,
Chernobyl,
what does it,
three mile island [inaudible] island,
I don't know.
Three lounds if can you go there now?
Uh,
I wouldn't go there.
It'd be the best of those three.
But we also have the wip project in New
Mexico.
Yeah.
They're the number of places on earth
you can just simply no longer go is
growing.
And it's places in Nevada where they
just bury the waste or they just bury
the waste.
Hanford,
uh,
just had a huge collapse.
Um,
so let's put it this way.
We now know how dangerous this
technology is and we also know that what
we were told when it was invented,
I mean everything we were told,
we were told electricity too cheap to
meter.
For one thing,
we were also told we'll figure out what
to do with the waste and know and not
true,
not true.
And here's what's really terrifying.
I mean,
every now and then we,
you know,
they're digging in Mexico City and they
find some ancient Aztec ruins and they
have to stop construction because they
didn't know it was there.
What the fuck happens if a hundred years
from now they dig into the Nevada desert
and just tap,
right?
Yeah.
To a chamber of spent fuel rods and kill
everybody.
In fact,
that's one of the problems that they've
tried to solve is how do you,
how do you make a sign for people,
you know,
a thousand years in the future and a
hundred years.
We have no idea how you would warn them
off.
Um,
nor are these things stable.
I mean,
the thing about the whip project in New
Mexico is that,
you know,
this was supposed to be stable for
thousands of years and we had this
explosion that leaked plutonium,
um,
you know,
after decades the thing was not stable
the way we were told it was.
And uh,
so anyway,
we have this terrible problem and what
to do with the waste we've already got
is obviously a huge issue.
Not Making more of it would be a really
good idea.
Yeah.
And um,
there have been some solutions that
someone,
uh,
there,
there was
a,
a really young kid,
I believe that came out with some
radical proposal for taking the nuclear
waste and converting it into energy that
could power cities for thousands of
years.
Whether or not it's viable,
you know,
but I mean it's totally possible.
I mean,
look,
if we've couldn't come,
if someone can come up with nuclear
energy in the first place,
the ability to split an atom and power a
city,
maybe it is possible that someone could
figure out what to do with that way.
Some new sort of radical approach to
looking at it but can't just leave it.
No,
you can't just keep doing what we're
doing over and over again and hope that
we don't make more spots where you can't
live.
Well,
I mean the first thing is there is one
thing we can do with it that's better
that we already have the technology to
do and there's no excuse for not doing
it,
which is that all of the stuff that's
sitting in pools that has to be actively
cooled after something like five years.
It can be put in dry cask storage,
which ain't perfect,
but at least it doesn't require some
system to actively keep it from boiling
over and doesn't need electricity in
order to cool it.
Exactly.
The issue that happened in Fukushima,
and that's strictly a matter of money,
right?
We could do that tomorrow.
We can just require it and we should
because it's vastly safer.
Um,
we could also potentially,
there are ways to take the spent fuel
and to burn it down.
That does involve other kinds of
reactors,
but ultimately,
ultimately,
I can't understand why we have not made
an immense investment in fusion power
where we to discover the ability to make
viable fusion power,
which I believe we know is possible.
Um,
we not only would be able to power
civilization without warming the
climate,
but we would also be able to pull carbon
out of the atmosphere if it turns out
that we need to do that.
If you have effectively an unlimited
source of power,
you can take carbon out of the
atmosphere and you could turn it into
building materials that were stable for
thousands of years.
Um,
and the tiny amount that we spend on a
fusion research is inexplicably to me.
Yeah,
we're
gotten way away from the original
subject,
but I think this is all very important
stuff.
But I wanted to talk to you about
evolutionary biology.
All right.
And being a,
someone who teaches that and being as
that's your discipline and um,
seeing all of these,
I mean,
what did,
what is it like being a professor and
being someone who's studying this stuff
and then seeing all these weird traits
and all these weird personality aspects
demonstrate themselves in these times of
crisis?
Like seeing these,
these situations
you're talking about people?
Yes.
Um,
well that's an interesting question.
I have become fascinated.
I didn't start out studying people,
but the,
um,
the longer I proceed in evolutionary
biology,
the more interested I am in people.
And um,
let's put it this way.
Something is surprising,
but in general,
if you have the right tools to
understand people at an evolutionary
level,
things make a certain amount of sense.
They are,
I have something I say to students
frequently,
which is if a situation is confusing
with people,
very often it makes more sense if you
turn the sound all the way down so you
can't hear what they're actually saying.
Because very often what's being enacted
between people isn't really about the
content of what they're saying.
It's about something else.
And so let's take for example,
um,
my first project when I was an
undergraduate,
I was studying with,
uh,
a very famous evolutionary biologist
named Bob Trevor's.
And,
uh,
I wrote a paper for,
for his class.
Um,
and it was about the Holocaust.
It was about the really,
I was testing the question at the time.
It was relatively commonplace to hear
that Hitler was insane.
And something about that didn't ring
true to me.
And I wanted to know,
evolutionarily speaking,
was he insane?
And in studying that question,
it became very clear that insane was the
wrong description,
that he was a monster,
but he was a rational monster from the
point of view of advancing,
um,
German jeans.
And that was a very troubling discovery
to me that,
um,
in effect what he was doing was,
uh,
I mean it's the worst thing imaginable,
but from the point of view of genes that
are attempting to spread across the
globe and exclude alternative genes from
access to resources,
it was perfectly reasonable.
Not only what he did to,
to Jews and homosexuals and Jehovah's
Witnesses,
but,
um,
the military plan,
the future of Germany lies in Russia.
The idea was that this was actually a
sophisticated plan that would have,
um,
advanced the cause of spreading German
jeans a spectacularly had,
frankly,
so many million Russians not been ready
to give their lives to turn the German
war machine around.
So what I'm saying this,
this has to be dealt with carefully
because people hear you say that and
they think that you're justifying it.
But you know,
I'm of course a,
do you know whose ancestors were from
Europe?
I,
there's,
there's no part of me that is an Nh
anyway,
okay.
With what happened.
Quite the opposite.
But understanding that even though the
Darwinism that Hitler was deploying was
deformed and not,
not accurate and defensible in a logical
sense,
um,
the plan he was advancing was German
jeans attempting to take over a larger
fraction of the resources the planet
earth has to offer then they had
available to them,
uh,
at that point in the 30s.
So,
um,
anyway,
what I'm trying to say is that
there's something that we,
we often teach students first when we
get to them,
which is called the naturalistic
fallacy.
It means that just because something is
true doesn't mean it's good that it
ought to be trail.
And so discovering the nature of
something like the Holocaust is very
important in the sense that it allows
you to grapple with it logically.
But as you're grappling with it
logically,
people want to imagine that you're
saying it was okay.
And that's the opposite.
There are many things that are true for
evolutionary reasons that are completely
unacceptable and understanding what
those things are,
um,
gives you a pretty good shot at
preventing them from,
from unfolding.
It is,
it also really is a problem when
something becomes taboo to even consider
or two to look at.
Like you,
you,
you can't look at the idea that he
wasn't insane and that he was in fact
rational in rationalizing his horrific
acts and that there was some sort of a
plan to it all.
And you would say that even by enacting
that plan,
you'd be insane in terms of how you
think of the world.
And I think of the world,
like if,
uh,
we found out that Jamie over here,
I was thinking about starting a master
race and killing everybody off,
we would go,
oh,
Jamie's con sane.
I mean,
that's like the end to say no,
he's not insane.
He has a rational plan.
Like immediately people would want to
justify any horrific thing that could
say about you.
Yeah.
Just to be clear though,
Jamie's not doing that right,
Jamie got guy.
Fair enough.
I like sports.
How to take over,
he's into um,
but it,
but having taboo subjects or having
things you cannot consider,
even if you're clearly not a racist
person,
even if you're clearing not a person who
advocates genocide,
the,
the idea that intellectual discussions
cannot be pursued about specific topics.
Well,
uh,
the first thing,
if you're going to go into evolutionary
biology,
especially if you're going to get
anywhere near human beings,
you have to really put aside the idea of
taboo in intellectual space.
You have to be able to consider
everything because I'm so much of the
story is,
you know,
it goes from bizarre to horrifying,
and there's also great beauty.
I mean,
one of the important things to remember
is that the evolutionary,
the adaptive process,
the adaptive evolutionary process gave
us not only our worst characteristics,
our tendency to war and to genocide and
to oppression,
but it gave us our best characteristics
to our capacity,
to love,
to empathize,
to be compassionate,
to sacrifice for others.
So all of those things are evolutionary
products.
And you know,
the,
the message I try to convey to people
when I talk about this is that we have
to pick and choose which of the
evolutionary prod products we want to
honor and preserve,
and which of them we wish to bar from
the landscape.
And this is really what civilization is
about.
Civilization is about
taking the whole spectrum of things that
we're capable of and,
um,
providing a landscape for the ones that
are honorable and good,
and making the ones that aren't
honorable and good,
so expensive that nobody would consider
engaging in them.
Now when you're in the middle of this
crazy scenario that you find yourself
in,
um,
and you,
what,
you know,
what you know about evolutionary biology
and about,
uh,
the,
the mechanisms behind human behavior and
how do you,
uh,
how do you get back to work?
Well,
I'm lucky in that the freedom than
evergreen offers me to teach what I
want,
how I want to,
you can teach outside of the school.
Well,
I mean,
you'd be surprised.
My contract doesn't even mention
biology.
I can teach what I want.
So you could teach like football scores.
I could teach dance.
I mean,
I really,
I'm not not a good dancer,
so I can't,
but um,
but I could teach pottery doesn't
matter.
Now what,
so what that means from my perspective
is that I'm able to take the stuff I'm
intellectually interested in and I'm
able to make it my teaching life as
well.
And that has worked beautifully.
I've really had a great time,
uh,
bringing students in on what I think is
the cutting edge of evolutionary theory
and many of them have rallied.
So,
you know,
it's a lot like having graduate students
who are deeply interested in the same
material and are able to play ball
because you know,
they,
they take on the toolkit,
they learn to use it.
And so anyway,
but my intellectual life is quite rich
and it,
um,
it involves undergraduate students,
which is a pretty unusual,
pretty unusual thing.
But it does work pretty well.
Um,
how do you get back to work at your
school though?
Oh,
is that what you're asking?
Yeah,
I mean,
how does,
does that even happen?
I,
it's a tough question.
I have to say,
you were confronted with the very real
possibility that your days at evergreen
might be over.
Well,
there's a practical question.
I don't think they can fire me because I
haven't done anything wrong.
Right.
So that means I can go back to work in
the fall and uh,
I don't have another plan.
I'm on the other hand.
You're saying in the fall like this,
your,
your school,
how much longer does this semester have?
Well my you had in June or July,
I unfortunately have a conference that I
have to,
I mean,
it's not unfortunate that I have it,
but I have a conference that
unfortunately interfaces with the end of
the quarter such that I had to wrap my
program up early and I met with my
program for the last time yesterday
after the campus had closed.
We met in the park again.
Um,
and in the park,
well,
we weren't safe to be on campus,
so we started doing that as an
alternative.
How many students?
I am supposed to have 25.
I have 32.
So who are the extra ones?
Uh,
people who begged to get into the
program and I couldn't turn him away.
Ah,
you're a sweetie.
So now you meet in the park.
Are you worried that someone's going to
find out where your meeting and you
won't be saved there?
Um,
you know what I mean?
I,
I don't go anywhere without thinking
about it.
So yes,
I'm concerned about that.
So it's really gotten that,
that crazy and you in your mind that
you,
you have to worry if you will
going to the supermarket or you have to
worry if you're,
I never know what I'm going to encounter
and uh,
you know,
I'm not a big worrier on that front.
I'm more or less feel like if I
encounter somebody,
they're probably going to be upset and
especially if there aren't a large
number of them,
actually I could probably talk to them
and get somewhere,
on the other hand,
given what people think is true about me
and what they think the rules are with
respect to what they are therefore
entitled to do,
I don't know.
I really don't know what could happen.
Wow.
Well what,
what can be done or what should be done
about some of the,
I don't want to use the term crazy,
but some of the more rambunctious
students that are a part of this,
I mean,
it doesn't seem like they're going to
just change their behavior and,
and go back to just being a normal,
inquisitive young person trying to
figure out the world.
It's like there's so embroiled in this
ideology it seems,
and they've given them so much ground.
It's like,
how do you stop this?
And when you,
when you've held the fucking president
hostage and told him he can't go to the
bathroom without representatives of your
militant group watching and p where does
it go from there?
Well,
um,
I should say,
I what I said,
uh,
I don't know,
five,
10 minutes ago probably sounded a little
utopian.
I'm not a utopian,
I'm quite,
I think utopia might be the worst idea
humans ever had.
So what I'm saying should be under
arrest or court costs.
Well,
I mean the Holocaust was utopian.
I guess it was right.
That was the idea.
Uh,
so,
so yes,
that I think,
but most people think of Utopian is like
some moment in time where we all sort of
like,
oh,
what are we doing?
Let's work together.
Let's all be nice.
Right.
Well people,
I mean,
you know,
utopia,
utopian ideas of utopia.
Yes.
Well they very practical ideas.
They think they a,
they think they know enough about the
way things work to describe a good state
for things to,
to reach and they tend to focus on one
thing that they want to make better and
ignore all of the harms that will come
if they engage in it.
So,
um,
anyway,
I,
I'm not,
I'm not a Utopian and what I'm about to
say about what could happen at evergreen
is not Utopian in nature,
but I do think evergreen was,
as you described earlier,
is really the tip of something.
What happened at Evergreen is so extreme
and the way it looks to the world is so
preposterous that I do think,
I do hope that,
that the academy is hitting bottom,
that in seeing this little preview of
where these things go,
if they are allowed to,
to evolve their own accord,
that people will wake up and they will
realize actually as hard as it is to
challenge the stuff,
we have to do it.
Because if we don't,
this is what happens.
Um,
now that said on our campus if,
um,
if we get rid of,
a few bad actors starting with the
president,
uh,
and we recognize that we have ended up
in some new landscape where up is down,
it is also possible that we could find,
uh,
we could find a new comp kind of common
ground.
So,
um,
do you think you could find a new common
ground with these students that are
screaming in the streets?
Hey,
hey Ho Ho these racist teachers have got
to go.
I know this is going to sound crazy and
some people are not going to understand
why when you know,
my family and students have been
threatened.
I would,
I would even talk like this and to be
honest,
I understand why they would say that,
but um,
but the difference is can you talk to
them in a small group of people where
they could be reached because indeed
many of them are reachable or do you
have to talk to the entire mob?
In which case,
yes.
It's absolutely impossible,
isn't it also a problem in that when
people dig their heels into the sand and
they decided this is how things are,
and then even when confronted with the
possibility that they may have been
incorrect or wrong or acted
irrationally,
it's very difficult for people to admit
that and reconcile and step back and
maybe just self assess.
Um,
somebody has to blaze the trail.
In other words,
I find myself accidentally in the
position of blazing a particular trail
of how do you stare down a,
an accusation of racism.
So someone from that side has to blaze a
trail.
Somebody from realize,
hey brad,
it is the opposite of racist.
We're being silly here.
We all have a common enemy and the
common enemy is real racism.
Ah,
good.
And I mean,
this is why I said recognizing that you
have been involved in a witch hunt,
that's the moment at which you know you,
you're either level up or you don't.
When you realize you've been engaged in
a witch hunt,
that's the moment at which you can
discover there's something fundamental
that's wrong in my program.
Somewhere that allowed that to happen.
Maybe that would be a subject someone
could teach as a course.
You know,
like how campus ideology goes amuck.
Absolutely.
How things go amuck.
I mean,
in fact,
uh,
it's not exactly that and it was planned
long before this protest erupted,
but I'm scheduled next spring to teach,
uh,
with another professor,
a program on essentially the
evolutionary origins of human violence.
Wow.
So when,
when you think about everything coming,
do you have like a vision in your mind
about how everything would,
sort of,
the dust will settle and this president,
hopefully we'll either resign or be
forced out.
And then what do you do with these
students that you looked at in the end
they were screaming at you,
calling you a racist,
telling you to resign.
Like how do you deal with that when you
go back to school?
Well,
I mean,
if they were willing to listen,
I could deal with it.
I,
the,
the thing that is I think,
hard to appreciate from the outside a
little bit is that because,
uh,
I know that there's nothing to the
accusation and because so many students
know that there's nothing to the
accusation,
it doesn't hurt in the same way that it
would if I had serious doubts about
myself in this regard.
So if they were to come around,
um,
you know,
we,
we could make it happen.
Um,
that said,
that's not the direction things are
going as of this morning.
The,
the internal list of the,
uh,
the faculty and staff was headed in
exactly the wrong direction.
What is the list like what are they,
what are they trying to do?
Well,
they imagined that this entire
catastrophe,
including the closing of the campus
yesterday and today is the result of
the,
I think it was six minutes I spent on
Tucker Carlson.
Yeah.
He got on Fox News.
You summon the demon.
I mean,
those airwaves are immoral.
Yeah.
So have they literally said that,
that you should not have gone on Fox
News?
Oh,
that's beyond that.
Their point is,
what is this?
Here we go ever to evergreen state
faculty demand punishment of white
professor who refused to leave on anti
white day.
Oh,
it's anti white day.
That's even more interesting.
Yeah.
Wow.
Today I might've came out since we
started the podcast too.
I'm not sure when this hit.
What is it?
The college,
fixed.com this is describing what's in
the letter at the contents of the letter
right here.
Uh,
I've been tweeted a few times to make
that a little larger for me.
Okay.
We acknowledge that all of us have power
within the institution.
Oh.
Who have power within the institution,
share responsibility for the racist
actions of others.
Furthermore,
there's those of us who are white bear,
particularly large share of that
responsibility.
Oh God.
We acknowledge that we have a great deal
of work to do in order to honor and live
up to the demands made by the student
leaders.
The all the students are leaders.
They're leaders.
Like how in Yale,
the students that stare the
professor and physically threatened him,
they,
they were,
they were actually,
they were given awards where they
wasn't.
One of them,
like given some sort of a,
an acknowledgement of like being a
leader.
Some people will find that Jameel find
that,
but we acknowledge we have a great deal
of work to do in order to honor and live
up to the demands made by the student
leaders.
During last week's protests,
we acknowledged that students of color
and others who are underrepresented and
underserved had been voicing their
demands to us for some time through the
students of color focus groups of 2014
through their participation in anchoring
the strategic equity plan for November
in Cooper Point Journal and blah,
blah,
blah.
And we have not yet truly listened and
acted.
We acknowledge the students' right to
protest and affirm president bridges.
Recent decision not to use the misguided
language of the current student contact.
What does that current student conduct
code to punish the the protesters?
What is the language of the current
student conduct code?
Uh,
a hell if I know,
but b,
I believe what they're talking about as
the president said that,
um,
that students would not be held
accountable for disrupting my class.
And then I believe he,
uh,
agreed to their demand for student
authority over any changes to the
conduct code.
So they have students who are engaged in
this.
I hope this is right.
I don't want to say something that's
untrue,
but my understanding was that he agreed
to that demand.
We vehemently reject the claim.
The students have been violent simply
because they have been loud and
emphatic.
There is a difference between exercise
and the right to freely voice and
opinion and inciting violence.
And that difference has nothing to do
with the volume of forcefulness.
That's not true because they were,
they were upset that he was moving his
hands.
Right.
We're calling that aggression and now
they're saying that on the other hand,
she children can scream,
I'm calling children from now on.
We support the demands made by students
and honor the positive institutional
change they have already achieved
through their protest.
That's hilarious.
Are Most urgent demands below center on
the safety of those individuals who are
currently most at risk?
At the same,
I mean like the professor.
At the same time,
we acknowledge that in weeks and months
to come our attention,
we'll need to turn to the larger
structural issues students have
identified in solidarity with students.
We commit ourselves to participating
actively and self critically.
And the annual mandatory trainings
specified in the memorandum of
understanding recently signed by the U F
was UFE staff Flyer.
That's how union United Faculty of
Evergreen and management bargaining
teams holding each other accountable
when we act in racist ways against our
colleagues or our students.
Okay,
well then why don't you hold yourself
accountable that you act.
We asked to a fucking anti white day
that's racist,
right?
But,
but what's going to happen here is
there,
this is going to be intolerable
reeducation by people who frankly,
I,
it pains me to say it,
but they're the most racist people on
the campus.
I mean,
that's what this is.
This is racism.
It just happens to be in an unfamiliar
direction,
but it's racism.
And they also are going to be in charge
of,
uh,
of sensitivity training here,
which to me is the height of insanity.
So scroll up a little bit.
In solidarity with students,
we call for the evergreen this way,
administration to center student
perspectives in a persistent media
approach was gobbly Gook to camp
approach to the counter that all right.
Narratives that are demonizing
evergreen.
Okay.
Do you have an alt right movement?
Oh,
evergreen.
If I read that correctly,
I am now in the alt right.
Oh,
you're an ot writer I guess.
So are demonizing evergreen and day of
absences specifically.
Wow.
Persistent media approach.
What is the process that you go in on
Tucker Carlson Nets.
That must be it.
Yeah,
so we have to break this down like it's
code.
Like we're not even speaking English.
We're reading fucking hieroglyphs here.
Persistent media approach.
Persistent media pro.
Yeah.
Am I all right?
I might be.
You are now.
People think I am because of it had
outright people onto these to sa or,
but then conveniently when I have
liberals on,
I'm a fucking raging liberal.
God dammit.
Take seriously the threats made to the
individual community members.
Oh,
aren't you an individual community might
think you're about to get to me here.
Use available institutional resources to
protect them.
Demonstrate Accountability by pursuing a
disciplinary investigation against Bret
Weinstein according to guidelines and
the social contract con contact contract
rather,
and faculty handbook.
Weinstein has endangered faculty staffs
and students making them targets of
white supremacists backlash by
promulgating misinformation in public
emails on national television and news
outlets and on social media.
That is a very,
very broad,
you should sue.
That's a hell of a bullet point,
Huh?
You should sue just for that.
Yep.
You have endangered faculty staff and
students.
We see the problem with that statement
is someone can just read that now and
and and use that as a quote and just
start saying that as if it's fact.
Well,
let,
let's just lift his deal with this for a
second.
Can we?
Okay,
so that is a very interesting bullet
point.
The fact is,
I have gone on,
media media has come to me.
What I have done is I have pointed to
videos of the protesters themselves put
up that caused the world to say,
what the hell is going on in evergreen
and this has resulted,
the entire thing has unfolded.
I've been fighting this for a year to
point out to
my colleagues that they were making
terrible errors.
This is all the result of reforms put in
motion by president bridges.
So they are now blaming me and I should
say,
I do think there is jeopardy on the
campus.
We had a threat yesterday from somebody.
You have no idea how serious it was,
but I do believe that there's jeopardy
to people on our campus.
What specifically was a threat?
It was it a threat from a white
supremacist group was a threat from uh,
uh,
a pro protestor group.
Like it wasn't specific,
but w so what I,
all I can say is that I got,
what I was told was a transcript of the
call.
I cannot vouch for it because I don't
have access to,
you know,
somebody could be promulgating a hoax.
I don't know.
Right.
What it said was that they were coming
to campus,
I think with a magnum and they were
going to kill as many as they could is
what they said.
Um,
they do,
we can play the audio.
Yeah.
Okay.
Put your headphones on.
Let's listen.
Let's hear it fast.
Hello.
Dispatch can help you.
Uh,
yes,
I'm on my way to evergreen university
now with a 44 magnum.
I am going to execute as many people on
that campus.
If I can get ahold of you.
Have that.
What's going on here?
You've communist scum bag pounds.
I need a murder.
As many people on our campus is like,
Hey sir,
just keep it,
just keep,
just keep your eyes open someday.
Okay.
First of all,
hey,
that guy's full of shit.
And he's and amateur,
right?
Because a 44 magnum only hold six
rounds.
Mostly.
Maybe five might even be five rounds.
Or is that a desert eagle?
Is that guy's a bullshit artist,
a 44 magnum.
You don't specify the round or you're
going to use,
nor does that weapon make any sense,
but yeah,
but nonetheless,
the point is he's dirty Harry.
He thinks so.
Yeah.
Right.
Um,
but you know,
I don't want to belittle people's
jeopardy.
I have to say,
you might have been crazy and that he
might have actually been really wanting
to do that and he could have done it
right.
And it could happen for sure.
Um,
I,
I think the jeopardy to people on campus
campuses real and I live right adjacent
to campus and I must tell you,
uh,
I brought my family with me because I
don't feel that they are safe there at
the moment.
The question is how is it that we have
reached the point of deciding that this
jeopardy is from me?
The horrific,
what they've done is so irresponsible in
releasing that and making it public.
It's so irresponsible and,
and,
and so,
so,
so silly that they don't realize that
other people are going to see through
that so clearly.
Well,
many of the information and like what
misinformation,
what specifically they should be very
specific when they accuse you of
misinformation.
They should be very specific if they're
going so far as to say that you are in
somehow or another summoning outright
and making misinformation public on mass
media.
What is that misinformation?
Well,
I know because I've been watching the,
the email traffic,
right?
So their claim,
uh,
is that white people were not asked to
leave campus,
that there were only 200 spaces in the
venue off campus and therefore this was
just supposed to be for a small subset
of people,
which is nonsense.
Um,
there were only 200 spaces if you want
it to go to the particular seminars that
they were holding.
For example,
the one about why Asians were part of
the problem.
So they had a seminar on Asians being a
problem or a presentation of some kind
that is really racist I believe.
So.
Um,
but in any case,
they are conflating the 200 spaces off
campus with what was actually expected
of us.
And it was quite clear.
In fact,
one of my uh,
staff colleagues,
uh,
put out an email,
boy time has gone into some weird thing,
but I think it was last night in which
he detailed the several emails that we
had seen in which the school did ask
white people to leave for that day.
So they are,
they are promoting false hoods
themselves designed to obscure what's
going on.
I think because they finally understood
that the world doesn't get what they
were doing.
Well,
do they not understand that this is a
trail that's going to be released like
that,
that this is actual data and that this
data,
when they accuse you of misinformation
and then you have all this data and then
you could just like release it to
everybody,
like,
Hey,
this is the actual emails.
Clearly this contradicts what you're
saying.
It makes you a liar.
Right?
Several people,
in fact,
many people have now started to refer to
what's going on in the staff faculty
zone here as a cult.
And I think,
you know,
on the one hand that could be tongue and
cheek.
On the other hand,
the mechanisms at work that have people
doubling down on absurdities rather than
trying to get on the right side of
history as quickly as possible.
It is very cold like,
and um,
again,
you know,
the,
you asked me what would have to happen
for us to,
to right the ship.
The second one is that my faculty
colleagues have to wake up to the fact
that their belief structure is,
um,
has become bizarre and unrecognizable
from any normal position.
Very dangerous from the perspective of
an educator.
If this is what an educated person who
has gone through the entire system and
now has a job in educating young people,
if this is how you view the world,
this is how you view facts and this is
how you distort them and then
disseminate them to the rest of these
likeminded folks.
And it's very bizarre.
Echo chamber that's being rejected.
It was like almost universally outside
of the,
the college.
I mean it's not just Fox News,
it's rejecting.
It's The Washington Post is the New York
Times,
Hey,
people are freaking out about your
situation and recognize very clearly and
very rightly that you are absolutely not
a racist.
Right?
And this is,
they've been,
this is kind of a lot of what I've said
to Jordan Peterson when I had him on,
like they fucked with the wrong person
again.
They fucked with the wrong person.
And this is one of the most horrific
things about what I find so troubling
about what I think of as a used to think
of myself as a progressive.
But what I prompt would I have a problem
with all of this,
is that the left is attacking itself
now.
It's like it's,
it's,
there's no one who's progressive enough.
No one,
like every single thing you do as a
microaggression,
every single thing you do is based on
white privilege and therefore you're
racist.
And in less,
you somehow or another give up all your
money and give up all your jobs.
And there are people who are asking to
do that too,
by the way,
because people asking people to give
their money and put them in black banks,
get them to black people.
I mean,
we're going crazy.
This is,
this is literally,
it's not an individual psychosis,
but it's a collective psychosis that
we're watching.
And I believe that in literal terms,
we are watching a kind of group
insanity.
Is this a problem with language?
Is in some ways is this,
is this a problem with influence and
charisma and people's ability to sort of
change the way others view the world
with dramatic interpretations of events
and,
and things like emails where this is not
a one on one debate.
There's a real problem with blogs and
emails and I've,
I've talked about this several times,
but it's,
it's worth repeating.
There's a real problem when someone
writes something like that specifically
about another person like you and just
writes it,
but you're not there to respond.
So they can write as much stuff that's
not true and they could put it all down
and then it's there and then someone has
to refute it,
but it's still there.
So you don't even get to refute the
actual document.
You write your own and then someone has
to go and read that at a different
location.
It's a real weird way to distribute
information and it's contrary to the way
human beings rationally discuss and
debate ideas.
Well,
I would say there are many rules that
are written into the way we interact now
that make it possible for this to
happen.
Um,
so there was an instance where a faculty
member,
um,
accused those that were challenging any
of these equity proposals as being part
of a racist backlash.
And she was clearly talking about me
because I'm the most,
um,
the most prominent,
uh,
person objects as faculty member,
a white person and no.
Um,
so anyway,
she says in a faculty meeting that,
uh,
this is a racist backlash.
And I said to her in front of this
faculty meeting,
I said,
somebody might want to check on the
question of whether or not I'm a racist,
because if you do check on it,
um,
you will discover I'm not,
and if you don't,
this is going to blow up on you.
And the,
um,
chair of the faculty told me that the
faculty meeting was not the place to
defend myself against accusations of
racism.
I said to her,
that's fine.
Where is not the place to level,
to level the accusations.
But I said,
where is the place?
And then the faculty member who had made
the accusations said,
you should not expect there to be a
venue in which to defend yourself.
You should just get used to these
accusations.
In a separate case,
I was told who said that a white guy or
it's the same faculty member who made
the accusation,
wait a minute,
the person said that you should just
accept these untrue accusations.
Yes.
Um,
yeah.
I mean,
was your reaction to that?
That this is not a place for you to
defend yourself against racist
accusations?
This is a place for you to just eat
shit,
right?
You just have to accept these ideas on a
separate occasion.
We were also told that,
um,
that to question,
uh,
an allegation of racism is racist.
Oh,
so convenient.
Yeah.
We'll try to wrap your mind around that.
One question and accusation of racism is
racist,
right?
We have an obligation to believe them.
Wow.
I know.
Wait a minute.
How that is crazy.
That is like,
that is such stupid back afterwards
thinking
it,
uh,
you know,
it's,
it's what the cult mentality sounds like
inside.
It doesn't understand that when you say
that to an outsider,
you know,
it simply doesn't add up
or it's creating a structure that makes
it impossible to defend yourself because
these accusations is so preposterous
that they realize that they have to have
some sort of a bizarro world structure.
Absolutely.
Oh my God.
So what does this person tea,
um,
they teach media.
So they teach how ironic,
right.
They teach media.
Um,
they are currently running a program
where she's teaching students to make
documentaries and that program,
one of the students in the program filed
a public records request.
Since we are a public college,
you can request the emails of uh,
faculty and staff,
um,
if you want them.
And so she had a student file,
a public records request from my email
to make a documentary in her program.
So you've got one faculty member
searching and other faculties members
email through a student looking for
evidence of,
I don't know what,
but um,
evidence of racism.
Well,
presumably God,
yes.
What little half of a sentence.
And she's going to cut out a contest
with a few dot dogs afterwards.
I mean,
in fact,
if you can separate my letters from each
other and reorganize them,
I could have said all kinds of things.
Well,
I think you should have a student ask
for,
uh,
the emails that came from her.
I bet they'd be wonderful.
They could be very interesting.
Oh,
I bet they'd be wonderful if she's
telling you that you shouldn't have a
venue to defend yourself and you should
just accept the fact that you're going
to be called a rate,
that the idea that she can call you a
racist in a meeting,
but you defending yourself against
racism is not,
it's not the place for that.
It's not the place for it.
Um,
and in fact,
this whole exchange took place with the
president of the college and the provost
sitting there silently,
silently didn't say a word.
He move his hands.
That's really,
really good question.
Um,
I don't remember him moving his hands.
I do remember him not releasing an email
after that meeting saying that in fact,
uh,
on,
accusations of racism without evidence
will not be tolerated.
He never
pretty God damn important.
It's really pretty goddamned report.
And then you just can't just w there's,
there are certain hot topics that you
just got to leave alone.
When someone levels an accusation.
This is the,
this is the current progressive mindset.
The current like pc gone awry mindset.
Yeah.
It's fucking crazy.
We're all even,
we're all human.
That's it.
I don't give a shit where you're from.
I don't care if you're from your
ancestors are from one part of the
planet or right next door.
It does not matter.
It's who you are and as soon as you try
to gain some sort of a leverage position
because of the fact that you think that
you have suffered more oppression in
your family's ancestral history,
we're,
we're way off track.
We're way off track.
The track should be equality today.
That should be where we're all on this
and as soon as someone says you're a
racist but you can't defend yourself,
well then we don't have a quality
anymore,
man.
You're trying to have an anti inequality
in order to bring equality to people
that have been treated unethically.
Is that what it is?
You're absolutely right.
It's structural inequity,
which is the irony of the whole thing is
that people who were wrapped in the flag
of equity,
um,
I challenged them because I believe in
actual equity and I was accused of being
a racist for doing it.
But it also sounds like intellectual
poverty too.
It's like the,
the,
the actual structure of the thoughts
that they're presenting are so poorly
worded and so it's,
it's so poorly thought out and you're
not allowed to defend against it.
Well,
that's the,
that's what I was saying about the,
um,
the difference in assumptions and
beliefs between the postmodern
disciplines.
And uh,
dare I say the actual disciplines in the
postmodern disciplines,
the illogic of those arguments doesn't
matter because logic isn't a thing.
It's a tool of oppression.
The,
well,
that's cute way to just,
yeah,
throw a monkey wrench into the gears.
Could client,
that's exactly what it is.
And what do they want to achieve out of
this?
They just want to achieve all black
professors and all white people on their
knees as slaves.
I mean,
what the,
what is the ultimate
goal?
You know,
just people running around fetching
power adapters.
Um,
yeah.
I mean I have to,
again,
I want to be really careful of the most,
most people of color,
most black people hold no truck with
this.
Right?
They don't want this,
but a tiny number who do want this or
maybe think they wanted until they see
what it looks like.
Um,
are writing the narrative and that can't
be,
they're going to undo.
They were going to undo the civil rights
movement and that can't be allowed.
Well,
not only that,
the real problem with any of this really
crazy shit is that it gives fuel to
actual racists and then it makes actual
racist.
Think that these people that are
involved in these protests as a
misguided as they are,
it makes them think that sleek.
Look,
we told you that these people are bad.
See,
look,
we told you that there's a reason why
they're inferior and it just as soon as
you,
as soon as you open the door to that,
I give real problems.
Yeah.
This plays right into the cartoonish
fantasies of the absurd left than the
right believes in,
which is a tragedy.
It is a tragedy.
But I will say there's a,
there's a positive outgrowth of this I
think,
which is if I look in my various inboxes
at the stuff that's coming in from
people that I've never heard of before,
this wake up call is uniting people
across every known fault line.
So I'm getting letters from religious
people,
from very conservative people,
from very progressive people.
Every known fault line is cut by this
and people are,
uh,
they are galvanized by seeing something
that doesn't fit any narrative they've
seen before.
That is to say staring down an
accusation like this is not common.
Watching it stared down and,
um,
the world not fall apart is,
uh,
is encouraging.
And then,
you know,
you mentioned it yourself to have the
Wall Street Journal and the New York
Times on the same page about this.
That's pretty interesting.
So I do hope that what emerges from this
is that all of the coalitions that
exist,
we'll look at themselves and will
recognize that they have,
you know,
maybe not every coalition has a noble
park,
but all of the ones that have a Nobel
part will understand that it's paired
with something that isn't noble.
And I'm hoping that people who find
themselves ill served by the narrative
will join together and that basically,
you know,
a coalition of the reasonable might
emerge.
Well,
that's a beautiful hope.
And uh,
I share that hope with you.
I mean,
I really hope that what's happening is
that in these insulated environments of
these universities and colleges where
things just get crazy,
that when word leaks out that they get
crazy.
It's very much like cults.
When you hear about Jones town,
you're like,
hey man,
don't drink the fucking Koolaid.
Something's going on down there.
But these group mindsets that people
fall into,
you know,
oftentimes when you're,
you,
when you're in the hive and you're in
the middle of it,
it can all be very,
very confusing.
My hope is that as more people find out
about the preposterous behavior that's
going on in these universities and
colleges and how people are,
I mean these are young people that don't
have a fully formed frontal cortex and
are about to enter into the world and
they're,
they're doing this with this ridiculous
momentum of these silly ideas and
there's people that want to enforce that
more and more and that these people,
some of them are actually professors at
the very college where this is going on.
I mean that to me is one of the weirder
aspects of it and one of the things that
scares people a lot is the idea that
these people are going to live in these
insulated environments and then they're
going to go and get their graduate
degree and then they're going to start
teaching and then they're gonna go right
back with these same ideas in this
insulated environment and never really
go out into the world where the
marketplace of ideas is roundly
rejected.
A lot of these notions that they're
trying to pass off through logic and
debate and actual discourse,
not through shutting people down because
of the color of their skin or lack of,
or,
you know,
excess amount of Melanin.
I mean,
that's not,
that's not how human beings should be
behaving in 2017.
It's just not.
So when you see it so evident and so
prominent and so,
so commonplace in universities and
colleges,
there's so many people on the outside
looking back,
looking in at this rather are baffled
and for the first time enraged.
Huh?
Well,
I think what you just described is
exactly how this happened.
The fact that the,
um,
the critical race theorists and the
postmodernist are,
you know,
third generation by now.
And so this has matured into a movement
that wishes to reformulate the world
according to what it thinks it
understands.
But it's so confused about the nature of
reality that,
um,
that it's just,
uh,
it's,
it's hard to even describe how
preposterous it looks as it,
as it tries to emerge
because they go from t being at the
university to eventually teaching at
that same university.
Well,
it doesn't have to be the same one,
but yeah,
they come,
they come to maturity inside a field
where these things sound reasonable and
then they go on to teach them to
students.
And so,
you know,
the intensity and absurdity grows with,
with each of those generations.
And I think,
um,
had,
had they been exposed to the real world
in the context of having to make sense
in order to make a living,
which,
you know,
I'm not,
I'm not a big fan of capitalism,
but nonetheless,
just even having to interface with the
and make enough sense
to get by would enforce a kind of mental
discipline that is not evident here.
Yeah.
Mental discipline as a good way to
describe it too.
I mean,
it just,
it seems like,
like the,
the idea that not only should there not
be 11 level playing field but the,
you should force a playing field that's
not level permanently not like,
yeah,
it's,
it's crazy.
And obviously the world agrees or a good
percentage of it is not even,
I mean,
I'm sure there's some bias in who writes
and who doesn't,
but I would actually imagine there'd be
some pressure if you were really angry
with me out in the world to write to me.
And um,
I don't know.
I must have a thousand highly supportive
emails.
Um,
all kinds of emails from amazing,
interesting people all over the world
now.
Um,
and a few angry emails and I think,
uh,
I don't know if it's three or four angry
emails and two of them come from inside
the college.
Yeah,
I'm sure some of them must be.
Some of the professors that realize that
this is a fucking sinking ship that's on
fire.
Like you can't keep doing it.
Like this is not going to end well.
You can't double down.
That's what they keep doing.
Well,
they keep doubledown what,
what,
so what happens now?
Like what,
what,
how do you just wait for the dust to
settle?
Do you,
um,
I don't know.
Uh,
I'm,
this has never happened to you before.
So this is a very unique moment in your
life completely.
I mean,
I'm 48.
So your whole life,
well,
essentially we should be careful there.
They've actually been a number.
Nothing like this has ever happened.
This is the intensity of this.
The national nature of it is all
completely unprecedented and uh,
it's pushing both me and my wife to our
absolute limit of what we can do.
Just even fielding all of the stuff that
is coming across our desks.
And all that said,
there is a,
um,
a precedent,
uh,
when I was in a freshman and a in
college.
Um,
and I've,
you know,
I've,
I've had battles inside of my field and
so at what I would say is that when,
um,
when one has deep principles and one act
based on those principles,
irrespective of the,
I guess what would be called optics,
you find yourself,
um,
the one against the many repeatedly just
by virtue of the way the world works.
And so this is without precedent in
terms of the magnitude of it,
but it's not the first time that I've
found that just simply proceeding from
principals that I'm pretty sure are
right based on careful work has resulted
in,
um,
something boiling over in some amazing
fashion.
Have you explored the possibility of
teaching outside of a university or
college
structure?
Have you explored the possibility of
using new media,
whether it's a online video,
audio text,
and in terms of like publishing things
and maybe having a patrion page or
something along those lines?
Well,
I would love to do it actually,
because at the moment,
you know,
the,
the college has been a great place to do
this because of the,
um,
the unusual teaching model.
But it's becoming less fun.
I mean,
even if I wasn't at the center of this
firestorm,
um,
the,
the rules that are being instituted and
you know,
diversity,
uh,
sensitivity training that's coming and
all of those lives that,
what did they make you do buy?
They haven't done it yet.
We need to learn how to not be racist.
Right?
So they have to assume that you have
these issues in the first place.
Right?
So they,
first of all,
why would they ever hire you if they
thought that you were discriminatory?
And then second,
what is going to be done?
Has it ever been proven ever that you
can change people through compulsive
Tori or compulsory re mapping of their
brain and antiracist
some sort of a,
what is it like it's like a two day
seminar thing.
Like what do they like that?
Well,
the thing is,
none of this makes any sense because
let's say this,
let's say that all white people pick up
racism from their environment
developmentally.
The can't help it.
Um,
so we know you're a racist.
Wow.
Okay.
Well,
if we know you're a racist,
then what's the remedy?
Okay.
The remedy is going to be some sort of a
sensitivity training.
Well,
but if sensitivity training works,
then how do you know,
I haven't already had experiences that
have done this for me.
How do you know?
Right,
right.
Um,
so the,
the whole thing is illogical and frankly
I think it's punitive.
I think,
I think the real purpose is we would
like to lecture you and,
um,
so like that,
in answer to your question about have I
considered working,
uh,
outside the college system,
I've considered it the real question is
how to operationalize it so that I don't
strand my family because Evergreen,
um,
provides a very high quality of life.
We live well in a beautiful setting,
but it doesn't pay well.
So we haven't accumulated the resources
where I can just cut the umbilical cord
and go take this stuff to a different
audience.
So,
um,
I would love to find a different way to
do it.
I think are way to do it in the
meanwhile.
Like you don't have to leave one to do
the other.
Well that's certainly true and I
wouldn't,
I wouldn't be averse to starting
something like that a while teaching at
Evergreen.
Um,
I really hope you do
cause I think you have some really
interesting ideas and you're a very
smart guy and obviously your heart and
your mind is in the right place.
And it seems like before all this boiled
over with this new president,
things were going the way you would
enjoy them going this individualized
attention,
the,
the freedom to teach anything you,
I mean it sounds wonderful in the hands
of the right person and you seem to be
the right person is beautiful.
No,
I just feel like the whole idea of going
to a place and learning,
I mean it's,
it,
it sounds like a great idea back when
that was how it had to be done,
but it doesn't take into account the
wonderful Internet that we all have.
I mean the,
the ability that you have now with this
platform,
with the amount of attention that's on
you right now to launch something is
really,
you're never going to have anything like
this ever again in your life.
Hopefully.
Yeah.
From your mouth to God's ear,
you know?
Um,
yeah.
Okay.
Well,
uh,
I will take that as a piece of advice.
This is the moment to launch such a
thing.
Listen,
do it.
I'll help you.
I'll,
I'll promote it.
I'll tweet it.
I'll,
I'll put it on instagram.
I'll put it on facebook.
I'll let people know.
Wow.
Thank you.
Yeah.
It's just,
I think that's the future.
I think the future is people educating
anybody.
Like anybody who wants it,
whether you're,
you know,
here or there or do,
you don't have to be in a specific
location.
And,
and I think that maybe a lot of this can
be overcome if we don't have these,
these groups of people that like live in
these echo chambers and constantly
circulating these same groups that
reinforce these opinions and,
and,
and experience all this confirmation
bias that makes them believe that this
is,
this is all correct.
And the,
the,
the rest of the world is just
misinformed and don't understand,
but clearly by that email,
I think that's a big problem is the
staff itself.
Okay.
Yeah.
I don't want to say the staff.
It's the whoever,
the administrator and a and then some
faculty,
they're crazy.
They're crazy
calling you.
All right are saying this is all right
and that you're racist and
misinformation.
I mean,
that is,
that's slander.
I mean,
it really is.
Yeah.
Well it's slander.
It's,
it's also,
I think it's just worth pointing out
kind of funny.
Yeah.
I mean,
they should have something to back those
claims up.
Those are just empty claims.
They're beyond empty claims.
I mean,
you know.
Yeah.
I'm a,
I'm a Bernie Sanders voter.
Okay.
If I'm all right.
Where are they?
Yeah.
Talk across and tried to say you were a
hillary supporter.
You like growing.
I was like,
no,
no.
What did you just say about me man?
It just,
have you thought about contacting an
attorney?
Uh,
I am getting offers and people are
contacting me saying I should,
you should.
As long as they keep that guy as
president,
you should definitely contact an
attorney and if they're going to put
shit like that on the Internet,
because for every person like me who
reads it and goes,
this is nonsense,
there's going to be a possibility of
someone reading it and go,
oh,
that Bret Weinstein guy's a racist.
Oh,
that Bret Weinstein guys all outright,
oh,
he uses misinformation and in the media
and he's actively sought out this
attention and he's doing this to damage
the relationship with the schools.
He's doing this out of spite because he
was called out for being a racist.
And we have this professor who says he's
a racist,
and she said it to his face and
he didn't defend himself.
I mean,
all that kind of shit.
That's how it boils over.
Yup.
No,
I mean it's clearly,
it's clearly justified and they won't
listen to anything else.
I've tried everything else,
so maybe that's just simply the answer.
I really hope you do something
alternative.
I really do.
Because I think if someone like you who
has this unprecedented platform where
you,
you have been launched into the public
eye because so many people are outraged
about this.
And I know you were on my friend Dave
Ruben show and uh,
you know,
I'm sure there's going to be a thousand
other request after people hear this as
well.
People,
people don't want this to be the case
anymore and they want to do whatever
they can to stop that.
And they also want to support people
that are brilliant people like yourself
that have wonderful ideas that we would
like our kids to learn if they do go to
college somewhere.
We'd like people to be educated in these
unique facets of the world and,
and,
and to have a platform where you could
teach evolutionary biology and uninjured
unshackled by this fucking nonsense that
you're dealing with our bridge.
Um,
yeah,
well it's a great idea and uh,
you know,
I don't know,
it may be that the unity university
system is so in crusted with this stuff
at this point that it can't be freed.
That's what Jordan Peterson,
thanks.
I talked to quite a few other professors
to think that as well.
Um,
Gad Saad,
he believes that as well.
I believe it's like there's just a
certain amount of time left in this
system where it's just,
it's so caked up.
Then maybe the only way to deal with it
is to abandon it.
Well then,
and then,
then we would have to reformulate it.
Yeah.
Which would be,
you know,
unlike civilization,
the university system could be
reformulated.
We could start with a fresh sheet of
paper and it's probably very dangerous
to not have a university system.
Can't not have it right after.
It's the,
it's the way we figure out what's true.
Right.
And there's gotta be a way to save it
while cutting out all these cancers,
aspects of it,
or started a fresh,
you know,
we could,
uh,
leave the carcass to the postmodernist
and build something that works outside
where we don't have to let them in.
Then there'll be a whole group of people
just talk about what a piece of shit you
are.
The locked in some classroom somewhere
demonstrating all the different terrible
things that you've done.
Bring horrible things upon the college.
It's just,
boy,
it's such a strange world you're in
right now.
Uh,
it is really,
it's,
it's almost more dreamlike than dreams.
Are you sleeping?
And that's a good question.
I usually,
I sleep pretty well.
This one,
uh,
I mean,
partly it's just the number of hours
trying to field everything means I go to
bed late and then,
you know,
by the time the sun comes up,
the question is how much more stuff is
accumulated.
So less than I might.
I don't.
MMM.
I guess the thing is I'm worried about
what's going on.
I'm worried about the danger to my
family that gets in the road of sleep.
I,
I know that what I'm makes sense,
even if my colleagues don't understand
that.
Um,
so I'm not getting enough sleep,
that's for sure.
But I'm also not ripped apart by doubt.
It's what you've done.
Nothing wrong.
So you don't have that blanket of guilt.
Like,
why did I do that?
What could I have done differently?
Right.
You know,
you're not,
you're not Kathy Griffin right now.
No.
You know what I mean?
It's so I just,
I really hope this works out well for
you.
And A,
I'll be paying attention every step of
the way and if my offer is real,
if you need some help,
if you decided to put something together
and you need some help promoting it,
I'd be more than happy to.
And I'm sure there's been a lot of
people listening to this and would love
to hear your ideas on things.
Great.
Well,
thank you so much.
Thanks,
man.
Thanks for coming in here.
All right.
Really appreciate it.
Yeah,
me too.
That's it,
folks.
We're done for today.
We'll see you next week.
Bye.
Hmm.
Okay.