Hey everybody,
this episode of the podcast is brought
to you by stamps.com summer is here,
ladies and gentlemen, and you want to
have as much free time as possible,
so don't let go into the post office, cut
into your barbecuing and partying time.
Ladies and gentlemen,
use stamps.com instead with stamps.com
you can print postage right from your
desk, from your home computer, from
your work computer at the office.
Super easy to do just with a regular
computer and irregular printer.
You can print out official us postage
and you will never have to go to the post
office again.
You don't have to find parking,
you don't have to wait your turn and
long stupid line filled with people that
don't want to be there just like you
with stamps.com you could do it all from
your computer.
Oh look at that.
Print everything from stamps to
shipping labels whenever you need it,
and then just hand it to
your mailman and you're done.
And with our special offer.
If you type in j r e the Promo Code,
click on the microphone in
the upper right hand corner,
type in Jre and you will
get a free no risk trial,
which is $110 bonus offer that includes
a digital scale and up to $55 worth of
free postage. You use that digital
scale, you measure out your packages,
you print all your postal, whatever
you call it, what would you call it?
US postage, all the labels. He'd do
it all completely from your computer.
If anything changes,
like if postal rates change,
stamps.com automatically updates
everything. Super easy to do.
You do it all from there,
handed to your post man and you're done.
So go to stamps.com before
you do anything else,
click
on the
microphone@thetopofthehomepageandtypeinjrethatstamps.com
and
enter
in j r e we were also
brought to you by legal zoom.
Legal Zoom is the best way to handle
a lot of legal things that you would
normally have to do in a legal office.
Go to a law firm, make an appointment,
sit down, talk to a lawyer, pay
an exorbitant amount of money.
A lot of that shit you can do at home
and legal zoom this month celebrates
innovation by helping
you launch your dream.
Apply for a patent to secure an invention.
Register a trademark to protect
your products and services.
You can incorporate or form
an LLC to start your business.
Just call or visit legal zoom.com and
they'll provide the personal attention you
need and help take care of the details.
Over the past 14 years,
they've helped over a million
businesses get started, right,
and they also have an a plus rating
from the better business bureau,
not an a, not an a minus,
not a B plus and a plus.
Pretty sweet.
So celebrate innovation with legal
zoom through the end of June and get a
special price on trademark,
copyright or provisional patent
applications by using the referral code,
the referral code, I can't even say that
referral code use the referral code.
Rogan checkout,
is that your phone man and seeing the
way it does know how to use vibrate.
Here it is.
Legal Zoom provides legal help through
independent attorneys and self and self
help,
but they are not a law firm.
They can connect you with an in an
independent attorney though if you panic,
if you were in the middle of doing all
this stuff and filling out your forms and
you're like, you know what, I
don't know if this is right.
They will connect you with a
third party independent attorney,
but you probably won't need it. Everyone
that I know that's used did Brian,
red bands used it. Aubrey
Marcus used it, the form on it.
They did it all by themselves. Um,
super easy to do. Go to legal zoom.com.
Use the code word Rogan.
We're also brought to you by on it.com.
That's o n n I t on it is a
human optimization website.
We sell all of the best shit that we
can find that helps physical performance
helps proper proper performance.
What's wrong with my fucking mouth today?
Yesterday too.
Something about a little something
about being up in Canada for too long.
They got me those fucks. Um, we, we,
we find everything that can weather
it can help cognitive performance,
whether it can help your endurance.
Anything that we find that's great for
as far as strength and conditioning
equipment,
we try to sell it at on it,
including our kettle bell series.
My favorite exercise as far as strength
and conditioning without a doubt is
kettle bells.
I think they're incredibly versatile.
There's so many different exercises
you can do with them. And uh,
we sell a wide variety
of sizes and weights.
We have weights that go,
we have a bunch of different packages.
If you go to the kettle bell section,
you could see the men's beginner
kettlebell section, which has a 20,
a 16 and a 12 kilobytes kilobytes,
kilogram key low.
That's how they say it in those other
countries that use the metric system.
But we're like over here in
America, we're like, no, no, no,
we're gonna stick with pounds and inches.
Some stupid shit that doesn't make any
sense while the rest of the world use
kilos.
When you go over to Canada,
they have kilometers on the mile and you
just look at the, you're going, I'm like,
we're not going a hundred miles an hour.
No, we're going a hundred kilometers.
Well, what the fuck is that? Oh, it's 50
Celsius today. What are you even saying?
What does that mean? It's not 50
degrees outside. No, no, no. 50 Celsius.
Take a liter of gas. Yeah, liter of gas.
But the fuck is that. This is nonsense.
Um, bunch of packages including the,
uh, advanced kettlebell package,
which has a 20, at 24 and at 28. Um,
and all the way up to, it's a pretty
heavy ones too. We have a 40 kilogram,
which is I think 90 pounds.
That's 40, 90 pounds,
something like that.
It's like 2.2 pounds per kilogram.
Let's find out what that
is. 40 kilograms. 40 kilos.
I'd say it's 90, 96. Is it 96
times 2.2? Yeah. Yeah. Hey, do you know
that right? Because you live in Japan,
in Japan, these kilograms, right? Yeah.
What the fuck is wrong with America?
I don't know, man. Why? Why don't you know
they tried that shit when I was a kid.
I remember when I was a kid,
there was, there was a, um,
a whole push to get everybody to
you use the metric system. 88, 88.
That's what it is. Okay. 88, 88.184,
nine pounds is 40 kilograms. Um,
essentially pretty close to 90 pounds.
Um, so we have basically, if you
can work out with those killer,
if you could work out with two 40
pound or two 40 kilo kettlebells,
you're a fucking monster.
I mean,
that's like a heavyweight would work out
with two 40 pound kilos and 40 pounds.
What the fuck is wrong with me? 40 Kilo
kettlebells and get an awesome workout.
I've got to talk like a moron. I can't
free ball this early in the morning.
It just doesn't work. Um,
we also sell battle ropes,
weight vests.
Basically anything that you'd need for a
comprehensive strength and conditioning
program. You never need to go to a gym
again. You could buy all your shit on it.
If you do do it though,
please.
If you can't find someone who's a personal
trainer that can guide you and show
you the correct form and technique
for exercises, please start light.
Take it slow and look at a video online
and try to do it with a very lightweight
and get the form down.
First form is one of the most important
things when it comes to any strength and
conditioning program
that involves weights.
You can do it and do it healthily and do
it safely and work out and get in great
shape. But if you do a goofy,
you will fucking hurt yourself.
If you throw it around big heavy iron
cannonballs with handles on them,
it's very possible you're
going to fuck yourself up.
So don't be a macho meathead
like me and start off slow.
Start off light and learn the proper form.
Um,
if you want a good workout DVD to
follow, we have an excellent one. It's,
it's Keith.
I'm Keith Weber's extreme
kettlebell cardio workout series.
They're fantastic. I use
them all the time. Um,
they're like one of my best as far as
like getting a good workout in 20 minutes.
You can get,
if you use Keith Weber series,
you can get a workout that will give you
a fucking heart attack with a 45 pound
kettle bell and you could do it in
a half an hour and I'm not kidding.
It will break you down even if
you were in really good shape.
He has a two excellent ones,
extreme kettle bell to a cardio workout
DVD and one and we have a ton of other
ones that are available at on it including
fitness function, a Kettlebell DVD.
We have ones for women,
the Bell Babe Kettlebell
DVD with Donica Storino.
I would change the name of that
Bell Bay please. Seriously,
she has pink kettle bells to
what a cutie. Um, and anyway,
all that information is available as well
as a lot of inspirational stuff add on
it.com. Um, our, our co, our goal,
our quest to inspire and to become the
best human optimization website on the
Internet is let us to fill these pages.
Especially if you go to
the Onnit academy section,
all sorts of different free
workouts that are available. Um,
showing form,
showing all the different benefits that
you can get from whether it's Kettlebell
workouts, whether it's body
weight conditioning, steel
mace workouts, and even uh,
some diet stuff as well.
We work hand in hand with Mike Dolce
who's a famous for working with mixed
martial arts fighters.
He provides us with a lot of a
diet and nutrition advice and uh,
as well as advice on some of the foods
that we sound like the earth grown
nutrients or the hemp force
protein powder. Anyway,
all this good stuff is available
at [inaudible] dot com.
That's o n n I t used the Codeword Rogan
and you will save 10% off any an all
supplements. All Right, ladies and
gentlemen, without further ado, ensign.
Anyways here,
why fuck around play the music
Rogan experience my day.
Joe Rogan podcast all day,
way, way, way, way back in. I think it was
1998 I first got to meet ensign when you
aren't barred. Nice. Seven. They said,
wow,
you onboard Royce Alger and Royce Alger
was the one of the latest and greatest
of the wrestlers.
It was entering into the UFC and they
were going to take the place like mark,
there was a Mark Coleman era when Mark
Coleman was smashing everybody and it was
255 pounds solid muscle. Kevin
Jackson beat John Lewis then to yeah,
put that thing closer to
your face that we can pay.
You can move it around a little bit.
Yeah. Yeah. Kevin Jackson beat John Lewis.
We had like,
there was like some serious wrestlers
back in that day that we're just starting.
Like Kenny Monday was entering into MMA.
Did he do,
did he do extreme combat or
[inaudible] and then he did, um,
one of the member they had, um, the same
people. They data submission only thing.
We're frank shamrock took on Dan Henderson
and I'm going to heal ankle lock.
You remember that? Yeah. There was a
lot of that going on, man. It was a lot.
All these,
uh,
these high level wrestlers were just
starting to find their way into MMA.
They're like, oh, this is
finally an opportunity to, uh,
to use a wrestling skills
and try to tell him.
I saw though wrestlers fight always,
always said it.
They don't understand numbers. It's
true. Yeah. You had a wicked one man.
You're one of the few guys
to ever submit Randy couture.
You submitted Randy coture with an arm
bar and before you caught him with that
arm bar,
man,
you've landed some of the most devastating
kicks from the butt scoot position
I've ever seen.
Because everybody used to just throw
straight kicks to kick guys off from the
butts goop.
But you figured out a way to Torque your
hips from the ground you would land.
It's a little late kick. Yeah. And
the nasty leg kick from the ground.
It's kind of interesting because
you don't see that from other dudes.
And even to this day,
that's a rare, you don't,
I think that fight your fight with
Randy coture might've been like the most
effective application of those low leg
kicks on the ground I've ever seen. Yeah.
So you all just wanted to,
my whole objective in that fight
was just to keep pressing forward.
Just pressure him all the way. Yeah,
that was a, there it is right there.
That was a great fight,
man. That was a great fight.
That was a really interesting fight,
man. You are a wild motherfucker dude.
You're one of my all time
favorite fighters to watch
because of that. And your,
uh, your style of fighting man was
always, you know, balls to the wall,
do or die and die. You know a lot
of people talk that, but you did it.
You did it in every single fight,
man. And you for without a doubt,
you have one of the most exciting
mixed martial arts careers ever.
And despite your, you know, your wild,
crazy style, you've got through it,
you're fine man. You all those
years of fighting and you know,
can not stuttering too
much. Not at all, man.
How did you manage to pull that off?
Make him all short and fast, man. Yeah,
this is, yeah, this was
the, the butts goop thing.
You were doing something
totally different because you,
you snuck up on him
like he scooted forward.
Randy was standing right in front of you
but you were blasting them with these
like kid, you know, my ankles and my
shins. I had like a whole roll of like,
Oh yeah, you, you really taped it up.
Hard, hard to let it, let us do it.
So I was like,
why not like castle my legs?
Oh the men when they used to let
everybody fight with wrestling shoes on,
that was a big thing too.
They used to kick guys in the
face with wrestling shoes,
which I thought maybe okay with
the top of the wrestling shoe,
but if you do shit like wheel kicks
and like sidekicks to the face,
you could scratch the fuck out of
someone's I like with the bottom,
the texture rubber part of the shoe.
Know that's a, that's a weird thing.
When they were the transitionary time
of MMA when they were four sort of first
sorting out the rules.
But this was a big fight because this is,
Randy had left the UFC and a Randy
was one of the elite guys in the UFC.
This is after he had beat v Tour and CPV.
Yeah.
And Randy was known as like one
of the best guys in the world,
but all slapped on that
armbar son and that's it.
And an anyway is a motherfucker.
Ladies and gentlemen,
are you a still training
guys now over in Japan? Um,
more doing stuff up north there, up
north and my bracelets that said, yeah,
popping in the gym here and there,
but you're still working with the
people near the nuclear plant as you do.
It's still doing that.
Going up to the temporary housing,
what is that situation like up
there for everybody here? You know,
you hear a lot of hysteria and you
hear everyone's kind of scared because
they're afraid the radiation is getting
into the water and it's coming over to
America. What I've read from scientists
that have actually been off the coast of
Fukushima who have,
uh,
analyze the fish is that it's
not something to worry about yet.
They've caught fish
directly off the coast that live there,
that are like not migrating fish and
they say those fissures safe to eat.
It depends on where, where he's talking
with you talking with the power plant. Um,
as of right now,
there's not much of a worry,
but it all depends on what's going to
happen like that because they're getting
too much radioactive waste storage.
You can't store it anymore. Yeah, yeah.
They're doing this crazy thing when they
have a pit and they're surrounding the
pit with frozen rods,
so they're going to freeze the ground and
turn this pit into this like temporary
housing for all this radioactive water.
When they're getting too much, they can't,
they can't supply it anymore.
They got these big bins of their,
I'm holding a minute. They're
cracking though. So yes.
As far as up by the plant, it's a
lot of radiation. But as far as, um,
the people who were displaced from the
tsunami or from the radiation there,
Darren, like a hopeless situation because
they're, they have temporary housing,
which is the box is smaller than this
room and they have to live there with
their families in the true, the winter.
It's like just a small wall that you can,
you can hear the rain hit the
roofs. Yeah. Wow. So it's a,
that has been extended.
It was supposed to be a two year thing.
They extended it for another three.
So that's five and they're still not
going to be able to move on from then.
The government is not helping them.
So why isn't the government helping him?
I don't think they can afford it. Yeah.
Right now, why isn't the world helping?
I mean that's a world issue.
That's a,
I feel like any sort of a
cataclysmic disaster like that,
that is a time where the world
has to show a world community,
forget about all the borders and
nations and all the nonsense.
If there's money that can be donated,
if this people that can be helped,
that's a time to help. I mean that's a
real cluster fuck of a situation do. Yeah.
I've been up there a 29 times.
Yeah. Wow. That's amazing.
Still going to continue you.
It's um,
it's kind of shocking how quick
that whole thing went bad.
Like everybody thought that when
you see nuclear power plants,
you u s assume they have some sort of
a backup plan. Like if it goes bad,
I didn't know until this,
this event, that power plants,
you can't shut them down. Like I didn't
know that either. Isn't that crazy?
Like what do you mean?
You have to keep them operating?
Like what are you talking about?
Like you have to keep them going to
keep them cool. And if you don't,
they burn through the
containment and they, you know,
they melt the meltdown and go into the
earth and they don't know what the fuck
happened. But then Fukushima
was just, uh, just the,
the size of the earthquake and then the
timing of the tsunami coming in so fast
and so hard.
Yeah.
But it's weird that that's also one of
the things that they do with nuclear
power plants,
that they put them near the ocean to keep
them cool so they could use the water,
but it's just like, oh,
what the fuck? Really? Yeah.
I learned a lot about nuclear
power plants from that,
from just paying attention
to it because before that I,
I didn't even know what they did.
I thought like the nuclear energy
somehow or another made electricity,
but it's really just make steam.
Yeah, I know that either. Yeah. Yeah.
Like that's still like some
old school method of, you know,
using steam power to create
electricity and you just say,
just do it through as it clears out
a lot of them all over the world.
Asking a scarier, when you have an
easy job to San Diego down the coast,
you see them and you're like,
oh Jesus,
that's a fucking nuclear power plant
right there. That fucker could go bad to,
all they have to do is get hit
with the wrong natural disasters.
I think the one in Fukushima
though needed to be updated. Right.
It was like an old system,
like they didn't have the the right
amount of backup and redundancy as far as
the generators and stuff.
The headline of all reports on it prior
to it and didn't do anything of Bartlett.
So now it's a situation
where the government just
doesn't have enough money to
fix everything.
Yeah, there's too much. Uh, see,
the thing is is that they
have a 2020 kilometer radius.
Now that is a exclusive zone where
people can go in and out because of the
radiation.
But in actuality it's supposed to be 30
because when I went in there with my guy
or Connor,
I fall in hot spots higher than ones
10 kilometers from the plant and 30
kilometers one day said they can't,
they won't do that because they
can't displace that much more people.
They can't afford it.
And I'm like, I'm like,
so you got to let people
live in radiation.
It's kind of crazy sometimes weird birth
defects with like rabbits and shit are
born with no ears, which is, yeah.
Which is to a human is going to happen in
the next one, eight, seven, eight years.
Right. You see about 10 years and before
you start releasing the fix to it.
Oh Wow. Yeah. Yeah. It's a real wake
up call for people and you know,
it's, there's not a whole lot of options
as far as like how to generate power.
Nuclear power when you get to large
cities is one of the most effective way to
generate power. Yeah. Like people are
protesting to shut them down, man.
What's going to happen if
you shut them down? Yeah,
well I think there's a way that they,
if they have like a
plan to shut them down,
there's a way to maintain it. I'm talking
completely out of my ass by the way,
but from what I've read,
it's,
they can do it much better than if it
just shuts down because of a natural
disaster and they can't plan for it, which
is the situation that they're in now.
You know what's crazy is la, because it's
never rainy here, but there's no solar.
Anything like you talk about
like not using a resource.
Every fucking building in la
should be covered in solar panels.
They should get all of their electricity
from the sucks big business I guess.
Huh? It should. Someone should bring
that in because it's all over Hawaii.
I'm doing it at my house and I have a,
my neighbor doesn't have
electrical bills anymore. He,
everything he gets is
from the sun. Yeah. His,
no electricity doesn't pay
for electricity at all.
These like some maintenance and like the,
apparently the batteries lose a certain
amount of effectiveness every year.
I have very slight amount and over a
course of like 10 years, it could be like,
you know, come a certain percentage
and then it becomes noticeable.
But then you just replace the batteries.
My house in Hawaii we got like,
I think 70% of the roof is covered
with really? Yeah, cos it a lot.
But I heard it brings on your
electric bill. Yeah. Big Time. Yeah.
Well in Hawaii you could also
collect rainwater to, and who know,
I know a lot of people that do that.
I knew a dude who lived up in, um,
he lived up on Mauna Loa and
he had a whole system set up.
Like you just lived up there.
He had a solar electricity,
he had a rain water that they collected
in a bin because it rains up there.
He was in the, the, this is,
if you've been to the big
island, the big island you,
I'm sure you've had.
But for folks who haven't,
the big island has like a bunch of
different ecosystems. It's like desert,
like arid, dry climate. And
then you go to another place,
it's like near Hilo is like a
God damn rain forest. It's crazy.
It's like a Polynesian tropical rain
forest and that's where this dude lived.
And he collected rainwater up there and
that's how he got all of his water and
all electricity just for mother earth
girls on food and his garden. Crazy.
Just lived up there. You know, you're, um,
the island itself, it's like one of
the most magical places on earth,
you know. I mean, all the Hawaiian
islands are pretty God damn magical, but,
but the big island itself, it's just
incredible. That's active volcano.
Yes. Constantly getting
bigger. Give a fly over.
You do the helicopter tour.
Um, no, I never did that.
I went and saw the at the
observatory though. Oh, the,
yeah, the the, the way. Uh,
yeah, the um, um,
the helicopter tours pretty dope
because you get to see the lava actually
pouring into the ocean. Oh really? Yeah.
You see the big island Grotzia hitting
bigger. Yeah. You can see a grill.
It's wild.
It's just all steam.
Like you can see the red lava going into
the ocean and then you see the steam
coming off and you literally
watching the island grow. Oh Wow.
Yeah, it's pretty
intense. It's pretty cool.
And also on the big island,
they have all these areas where you
could see like photos of houses that were
lost when the lava came down and just
wiped out certain towns that were just a
little freaky thing that you,
you have a house and you see the
love of coming out about what?
Like a mile per hour. Not even though
and you just can't do nothing about it.
Nothing. There's nothing you can do
to stop it. Nothing but just watching.
I mean the think the big dig a big
hole debts or pour water on it.
It was just hard in it.
Now there's nothing you can do
and it just, cause it's slowly,
well it's amazing is, it's so beautiful
there. People don't give a shit.
They're like, so what? We'll rebuild.
But that's still better than living on
the mainland. When you lived in Hawaii,
did you get a, did you get island fever?
What do you mean? When I was away,
I missed it. No island fever, like living
there. Were you like, it's too small.
Like you feel like you've got to
get never did. Now I love the ocean.
That's why so a lot of diving, a
lot of surfing and I was good. I,
I missed it whenever I went away though.
Isn't your brothers like some
crazy free diving champion? Ryan,
we can hold this [inaudible]
seven minutes. He's a surfer now.
How long can he hold his
breath for? I don't know. He
used to go on deep. Does this
go into deep blue? That was
beyond, that was after my time.
We used to just free dive night dive,
but that thing about going down a hundred
feet and that kind of stuff is crazy.
Yeah. He had a ridiculous ability
to hold a breath. Yeah. Yeah.
If a lot of people don't know your
brother was a badass mixed martial arts
fighter to this. A lot of stuff.
Man. Paul Champion, whatever he does,
he does good. Yeah. Racquetball Chap
who, um, Shih Tzu did him in May.
He was going to go into dentistry.
He, he had his massage license.
Wow. He was a pharmacist.
Pharmaceutical Rep for Merck. Wow.
What's he doing now? He's
doing a bootcamp. No. Oh,
like a bootcamp training.
I think he'd take everyday man.
He's up at five in the morning teaching
classes. Wow. And why? Yeah. And uh,
which uh, Honolulu in Honolulu right near
it. Right in town or I didn't tell him.
So he has a, he, I think he has
three or four locations now and the,
the most crowded class have is 5:00 AM
5:00 AM what people would want to get fit
before they go to work I guess.
Yeah. Oh fuck man. You know,
if you get used to doing that.
I've been doing that over
the last couple of months.
I get up in the morning and
first thing I'd do is work out.
I'd never used to do that.
I used to eat breakfast and lay around,
but now I force myself to workout
first thing in the morning.
It makes a whole day a
different experience.
He gets out of the way to get that in
there. How much you trained in these days?
Not much. When I go there, I
try to do bootcamp. Um, I met,
I met, sure. Kiya and all them one, I
was doing bracelets like 12 hours a day.
So I don't want to go to boot Kevin and
get a little tired in the day and have
to be working. These bracelets that you,
or one that you're wearing right now,
these are, you sent me some and I gave
them to my daughters. They love him.
Right. Um, what, what is the significance
behind these bracelets? Well,
in Japan they believed that the
bracelets protect you. Yeah.
So if a brace it breaks,
it's actually a good thing because it's
taking something that was supposed to
come to you.
And that's the real main reason why I
started wearing them and was interested in
him. And later on down the line
someone told me, Oh, you know, they're,
you know that there's parcels,
there are real gems. And I'm like,
what do you mean there's crystals?
I know Crystal's, okay, cool.
But what did you mean whether gems?
And they told me,
you know what the r next to have the
citrine and it's all different properties
for different things. And
I'm like, really? And it's
crazy because, um, you know,
there's, there's one for every
ailment, there's one for depression,
there's one for diabetes, you
know, and, and for me, I, I made,
I make the braces. I'm not a stone expert.
Right. And I love the bracelets tonight.
When I started making them for color, I
realized I was choosing different stones.
And then we started reading up on that.
And now it's like sometimes you get
people coming in to make a bracelet for
arthritis.
And I'm the one making the braces,
but I'm not a stone expert and I'm not
this glue that's pushing power stones.
I'm pushing bracelets and it
just happens to be parcels.
And so they want to line up for
arthritis. So I get all my,
you know, a little book and
Ocu arthritis stones. Okay.
Calcite.
I line up the calcite,
get a good look at and something nice
and something that's for their ailment.
And two days later, and this happened
numerous times, they'll walk in and see,
you know, my hands aren't tight
when I wake up in the morning.
Do you believe that though? Yes. See the
thing is I'm supposed to be like, well,
I'm supposed to be like, yeah, I know,
but then for me, it's still new to me,
so I'm like, no way. Really.
I'm super skeptical at this 0.5 because
I've just seen so much bullshit,
but I think that if you
tell someone that a a,
a rock can help some part of their
life, then it actually can. Yeah.
The placebo effect is real
and I don't understand it,
but you can give people sugar pills and
tell them that it's medicine and their
body thinking that it's medicine starts
to relax and concentrate on here,
Huh. Yeah. A lot of it
is just people were,
I think there's a lot of ailments that
fall upon people because of stress and
because they're imbalanced and they
can be somewhat alleviated by placebos.
We just don't understand
how the mind works. What,
what frequency are you tuning into when
you're taking in a placebo that you
think is medicine that allows you to get
better? We don't know. We have no idea,
but we do know that it's a real fat. Yeah,
it does. Yeah. It's pretty cool, Huh?
So that's probably what it is. I don't
think that a rock can cure diabetes,
but what the fuck do I know?
I don't know.
You know the works and then it
might be that placebo thing. Yeah,
it's gotta be whatever it is,
man. It's working. I think.
What do you remember when everybody was
wearing those Hologram risk bracelets?
Those rubber ones, like a lot of athletes
are wearing them. Balanced ones. Yeah,
they got sued for like a hundred
million bucks and it's all bullshit.
It's 100% bullshit. But I swear to God,
people were telling me that it worked.
Like, like real athletes like Shane
Carwyn, Shane Carlton was telling me,
he's like,
dude,
I'm telling you I put this thing on
and it changed my life and I was like,
it's up to Siebel must via 100% it's 100%
but placebo somehow it's real.
It's like there's this dude that I know
who's a chiropractor who does it shit
called zone healing and it's a weird shit.
Like they're like they press down and
certain parts of your back and claims it
can help. The digestion and help
all sorts of areas of your body.
But when you press him about it, like
how's this stuff work? How's it work?
It's essentially he's providing you
have an avenue for the placebo effect to
work. Like by telling you that this
is helping you in certain areas,
it actually can help people in certain
areas. So you've got to believe it. Yeah.
But if you're smart enough, you know it's
bullshit and then you can't believe it.
So you're robbed of the placebo
effect by being too smart. Yeah,
it's fucked. It's weird. Right?
It's almost like you can be too smart
for your own good. Yeah. Something that,
that situation is not good to be
two sworn though. In that situation,
what is like,
like I had a conversation with
someone once and when it came to
religion and fighting and they were like,
why do so many fights at why so many
fighters religious? And I said, well,
it's probably the same reason why so many
like people at war religious, you know,
there's an old expression,
there's no atheists in a foxhole.
It's like when you need
to believe in something,
a lot of times people fall on religion
and that it can help like this.
People that have a real true belief in
God and that true belief in God does
benefit them substantially.
It's real that what the effect of that
belief is real and it doesn't necessarily
mean that what they believe in is real,
but the fact that they believe in it and
they give themselves to it can actually
benefit them. So it becomes real.
Yeah, it does. No, it does. Yeah.
I've seen people like that where you know
it's God's will and they accept
things easier because of that. Yeah,
it's actually beneficial
for a lot of people.
It's very beneficial and
in a sense sometimes being
an atheist or being someone
who doubts everything can kind of fuck you
because I've always said that
like I wished that someone
could come along with a
cult that I truly believed in. Like
something has a really good, really well,
like I just not think about all this shit.
You guys got it all explained out.
Oh right, good. And just d, Let me
look at it a little bit. All right.
It seems like you've got
your bases covered now.
I don't have to think about these
things. Well this is what is, uh,
being a atheist can screw you. You know,
it's being too religious can also too,
yeah.
Well it's,
especially if you're too religious
in like a hypocritical sort of a way,
which is a lot of times people,
they pick and choose what they believe
and when it comes to religion, you know,
this is a lot of Christians that are
like angry people and they know the angry
about people that are non Christians,
are angry about people that don't follow
aspects of the Bible that they believe
in and it gets, uh, it
gets kind of squirrely.
But the near the nature of it, I think
all, I think the nature of all religions,
the best aspects of all religions and
aren't tainted by man are the lessons that
people learn over a life of trial and
error and wisdom and sharing ideas.
And he kind of learned that to be a
good person you have to do good things.
And to be a happy person,
you have to help others.
And you know when you treat each other
like they're your brothers and sisters
out there in the world, you truly
have a better life and you live in a,
in a way that makes you more connected
and it makes you in their eyes more
connected to God.
And in a big sense that's what you're
doing with your life these days.
All your work helping all
these people in Fukushima,
like you're not a guy who just kind of
like does charity because it's a public
thing and it makes you look good.
Like you feel very dedicated to these
causes and it's very admirable because you
go out there and you risk your
health and safety. You go to the,
I've seen the photos that
you put up online, man, you
are in the fucking hot zone.
Yeah, we went up to three
times. Yeah. What is that
like? I probably say like this,
right? It doesn't feel like raising
nothing. You can't feel nothing.
You don't get hot, you don't
feel itchy. There's nothing man.
The radiation's a scary thing man.
And all you see is the guy
you're or growing up on the couch
just scares you just so watching
that thing go up. Yeah. How,
what is like a normal
radiation level? Um, well,
well when I went into Shima the most
high God and the one time was a 25,000
microsieverts so as far as if you to to
put into relation 65,000 microsieverts
within a year we'll change your
blood chemistry. Whoa. Yeah.
So I got 25,000. I think I got a
little more after that, but nothing,
I kind of stopped at about halfway.
So he says he safe.
They say that you're supposed
to take iodine, iodine tablets.
What does I die on? Tavis helps to, um,
contracted, but it's mostly for the Tyro,
thyroid cancer, which is one
of the most common cancers. Oh,
so it just works on a tie. Well, yeah.
And there's all kinds of stuff they
said we eat, see lead, you know,
seaweeds go see we strong and I are done.
I asked to see lead
helps with the radiation.
What if you get seaweed
that's contaminated with
radiation? One of mine. Got It.
You're fucked. Yeah. Yeah.
They said that they've,
they've started catching tuna that show
a 3% increase in radiation and everybody
started freaking out. But they say that
that's still negligible still there.
No. The thing that I always wonder
know is since cause she was,
everyone's been testing everything though.
I don't,
have they been doing that before?
Have you caught before she,
their car like tuna and
tested for radiation? I don't
think they've done that.
You know,
I think they probably must have
otherwise he wouldn't have a base level.
Oh, I can pay this. The
grace. Oh, I see. I see.
I read a thing recently about grand
central station in New York City is
radioactive because it's made
out of granite and granite is,
it has natural radioactive properties.
So in actuality,
when you walk them through Grand Central
Station is more radioactive than is
required, uh, for a nuclear
power plant to be below,
like nuclear power plants have,
like when you're working at a power plant,
it has to be below a
certain amount of radiation.
Grand Central Station is higher than
that just because of natural granite.
It's fucking crazy. That's the people to
understand. There's radiation all over.
Yeah.
Like once on antifreeze Shayma when the
winds were blowing the right direction
from me, I got 16. Microsieverts
I fall, I fall on the plane,
went round trip to um, New York. I
got 19. I had the same guard kroner.
So it's like you write in their plane,
you're getting,
you're getting a mediation to the CMN
outside going to the car and radiation
bouncing off the concrete
and you get radiation.
You're getting reation we're getting
reached right now from, I'm freaking out.
Computers.
Yeah. Well that's what they
say about cell phones. Right?
Like that they're going to see a bunch
of people that have brain tumors later on
because they're holding phones
up to their ears all the time.
So it's something that's
really misunderstood right now.
The plane thing is a
big one. Yeah, please.
That's why I think it's higher risk yet.
It'd be a flight attendant.
A lot of flight attendants can work
too long. Yeah. Yeah. It's, um,
it's like getting,
apparently a round trip flight is
like getting a bunch of x rays. Yeah.
Chest x rays.
We talked about it before.
I tried to figure out what the actual
number was, but when you get an x ray,
when you go to the dentist,
that chick hits that button from behind
a fucking concrete blast barrier.
You know,
they cover,
you would lead and then they run out of
the room and hit that button and then
come back in.
But meanwhile you're getting that same
kind of exposure every time you get on a
flight. Fly to London, fly
as you can. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But flight attendants, I don't hear about
them getting sick all the time. Well,
my friend had a flight. It didn't told
me there's a lot of them think of cancer.
What kind of cancer? I Dunno.
Yeah. I wonder if there's some,
like if the iodine thing
protects you from thyroid cancer,
if there's other shit that protects
you from other cancers, it probably is,
but we don't know about it yet.
It's probably antioxidants, green,
leafy vegetables, things like
that. I mean, isn't that,
but I don't truly totally
understand the process of evolution,
but from what I understand,
a lot of it is from random mutations
that are caused by radiation. Like yeah.
Random mutations that
prove to be advantageous.
Those are the ones that are capped, you
know, she's just getting off a plane. Oh,
maybe that's why I'm so stupid today.
That's why I can't talk so good. Yeah,
there's certain days you wonder. Yeah. Um,
but rocks granted like a lot of
different things just give off natural
radiation. Yeah. What are
they going to do? Um, to,
to try to contain that area
there? They have a long term. No,
there's a, um, I have a friend that
she went to a tech sheet trying to,
he has a machine that will actually melt
down radiation off glass, out of water.
And it's in the testing stage right now,
almost in a final testing seats.
So if that getting that kind of get
accepted, it's going to be a big thing.
It can melt down Riyadh.
The heat goes so high that it
can melt down militate though.
Off Water. Off Glass. Whoa. Yeah,
it's so it's takes glass that's
radioactive and it melted down.
But where's the radiation go?
And he goes, yeah, I know.
I don't need to have this conversation.
Even the,
even like the problem is she wants
to like the call Shit. Oh yeah.
He said they have tons of that and that
it can melt that down and then it turns
it into like dry wall so he could actually
use the cow shit is radioactive. Yeah.
This is great.
As it cost you,
they have tons of and didn't
know what to do with it.
It's the fine radioactive cow shit
that you could turn it into dry wall.
Wow. People are weird. What a weird world
we live in. Yeah. I know.
There was some kid who, um,
I had figured out some sort of a way to
take radioactive waste and to reprocess
it and turn it into fuel again. Wow.
Yeah. Because most radioactive waste,
you know,
they have to store it in the ground.
Like there's places in Nevada where
they have these, did you see Godzilla?
The new Godzilla? No, I didn't.
It is. Okay. It's kind of stupid.
But what one of the things is the monsters
go after the radioactive waste that's
stored in near Las Vegas.
Like way out deep in the desert.
Apparently they have these,
these vaults where they,
they take radioactive waste from nuclear
power plants and they bury it deep into
the ground. The monsters went after
that cause they eat radiation. Oh Wow.
Pretty fucking it. Yeah. But this
kid who is invented this, uh,
this process believes that in the future
that they'll be able to take all of
this radioactive quote unquote
waste and that it's not waste.
It's just that they don't completely
understand the process of converting it
back to fuel yet.
But once that process is understood,
there will be no
radioactive waste anymore.
There'll be able to convert
that back to fuel. Wow. Yeah.
Pretty interesting. Right?
Yeah.
Crazy shit going on that.
Well that's an interesting thing about
when we fuck up because when human beings
fucked up, we fucked up so many
different things. But when we fuck up,
our backs get pushed against the wall
and then we're forced to innovate like a,
there's a 19 year old kid and figured
out a machine that can take the plastic
out of that Pacific garbage patch.
You know about that garbage patch?
It's in the ocean, you know about all
of that? No. Oh that's a crazy thing.
There's an area in the ocean,
enormous area,
this bigger than the size of Texas
that is all plastic from the world,
from all over the countries of the world.
People that have littered things
that have fallen off of boats,
things that have got picked up from
the beach. And they've all swirled,
cause you know,
there's um,
there's currents in the ocean and
his currents create pass and inside,
yeah.
Inside these paths in these areas where
all this stuff has sort of congealed and
congested, um, that those
aren't the right words.
But it's formed this like floating patch
of garbage and it's really fucked up
because it's in the Wa there's, there's
an image of it, but they've, um,
they've done all these missions to go
out and try to figure out how big exactly
is. The problem is a lot of
it is suspended underneath
the water and it's being
broken down slowly by the water. So
fish are eating it, ingesting it,
and getting sick.
Birds are taking the plastic back
and feeding it to their children,
to their babies because the birds don't
understand what the fuck it is. So they,
there's islands that they
find where these birds,
these baby birds are dead and their
stomachs are filled with plastic bits that
their mothers have given them because
their mothers don't know what the fuck
they are. Their mothers think that it's
fish or food or something like that. Wow.
Yeah, it's pretty crazy. So this kid has
figured out a way to take this gigantic,
see this machine, it's skims the, uh, the,
the ocean and it's going to suck all
the plastic out of the ocean and cleaned
the whole thing. Whoa. Yeah.
Incredible. Your kid. Yeah.
And then they've also said,
well, you know, hey, you know,
we're going to all these
problems with the ocean and the,
there's these dead zones is lack of
oxygen and pollution in the ocean.
They figured out a way to throw iron
to take iron scrap and poured into the
ocean and that iron scrap, we'll
create algae and create, uh,
different, uh, environments
for fish to live in.
And it'll re oxygenate
the water while yes,
it's weird like when people get their back
pushed up again, the, on both of those,
I don't even,
I shouldn't even be allowed to talk
about it too fucking stupid to explain it
correctly, but it's, it's
fascinating. There's this kid event,
this a giant ocean garbage patch skimmer
and that's this machine that he's,
he's invented and I believe
he's only 19 too, but in,
within a few years time,
he did a Ted talk on it.
Within a few years time they're going to
be able to clean up that patch if this
invention, uh, pants out. Yeah.
That's the weird thing about people.
We fuck everything up,
but when we fuck everything up,
someone smarter comes along,
goes, okay. Okay. Okay. That's
amazing. That's amazing.
That's amazing. Well, we were doing right
and a lot of labor. Wasn't that like us,
man, you still primitive days,
man. Cave man days yet. Well,
I'm glad there's people like
us too though. You know?
That's the Yin and the Yang,
right? That's the great, the great
balance of life can all be eggheads.
There has to be all sorts of different
people to make this world so interesting.
But yeah, if it was just up to you and
me, I don't think there'd be an internet.
We wouldn't really be having a podcast.
We wouldn't be taught through
the fuck knows how this works.
How's this microphone work? I
have no clue. I rely on these.
I have no idea how they were true.
I don't have a clue.
I couldn't even draw you a fucking like
a crude schematic of what's inside of a
microphone, you know? But it's
important. Yeah, the knee.
That's the beauty of being human is that
we all sort of contribute in one sort
of a way.
We're all like one piece of a gigantic
organism that's kind of doing all these
things and occasionally part of
the organism fucks up like, ah,
we didn't have a backup
on a power plant shit.
And then the world has to sort of scramble
and right now I'm sure there's people
far more intelligent than you or I,
and they're trying to figure out a way
to fix things like Fukushima. Yeah,
I bet there's a lot of
them. We got to, yeah,
that thing that they're doing with
the w the ice is pretty crazy.
These giant pipes in the
ground and they're trying
to freeze the ground to turn
it into a giant containment wall,
like a big pot, like a big pool.
Huge swimming pool filled with
radioactive waste in real fucked.
I mean, isn't there a better way
to do it? It sounds so ridiculous.
It sounds like something a
little Kibin advent, you know,
but I don't think there is.
What is the government of Japan?
Did they have a financial problem right
now? I don't know man. But they're not,
you're
just not reimbursing the people. They're
not helping the people. You know,
like if you,
if you're going to take a land and
a house away from a family who's,
who's worked hard for it to
work for it all their lives,
because a company that's run by the
government, which is Tepco, the,
the nuclear plant is run by
the government. If you're,
your client is going to fuck up,
you're going to take responsibility
and relocate them to an equal amount of
things that they had.
Instead of putting them in a little box,
how much money would that cost?
How many Neil? 100,000 of them.
So that's why they can afford it.
Over a hundred.
100,000 and you'd have to spend at least
a hundred thousand probably on each one
of them do. Yeah. Well a lot of them
were helped out by Red Cross. Oh yeah.
Yeah. So I don't think government's
doing, yeah. Fuck. Well,
you figured the government didn't tell
the people what was really happening with
the radiation?
Well,
that was one of the few times I think
that I can recall where I talked to,
you know, Japanese people are
very orderly and very polite.
It's a very different society.
When I was in Japan,
what was fascinating because it was
only about a year after the Fukushima
incident and I was talking
to this guy and uh,
he was very reluctant to talk
negatively about the government,
but he was trying to hedge his
words and basically said was,
I don't think they've been
entirely honest. That was like,
that's the worst he could have said yes.
He didn't want to say like different,
the Japanese culture,
like for Americans who are,
everybody in America wants a
pill to lose weight. You know,
they want a quick fix for everything.
I don't think they totally
understand the Japanese culture.
That's why like a doc. Did you see the
documentary Jiro Dreams of Sushi? No.
It's fascinating,
fascinating documentary.
It's about this guy who has a small Sushi
place in a Tokyo subway and this small
Sushi place he's been working at for
decades and he works 16 hours a day,
every day and we'll work
like for years and years,
just develop this one dish and has all
these apprentices and that this one
apprentice, they thought I was working
for years on this particular egg dish.
And then finally he got it right and
the guy said, you got it right finally.
And the guy was crying cause
it some fucking egg dish.
Whoa. Some egg dishes. It's,
this is a, that's Jiro. It's
an interesting documentary.
Apparently has the best Sushi in uh,
in Japan is incredible.
The delicious Sushi and it's like a 10
seat restaurant. Really? Yeah. Yeah.
And before the documentary came out,
it was booked for months in advance.
But now that documentaries
out who knows me,
it might be impossible
to get in there earlier,
but because of the fact that he keeps
the place so small and he doesn't have
that many people working
for him, like he, his,
he's not really concerned with branching
out like you've used an American,
they were like, we're going to sell
our brand, our businesses, our brand.
And what we're
going to do now is going to spread
out of the malls all across America.
Jiro dreams of Sushi stores.
Nope,
this cat has one place and he's humble.
He's hardworking.
He's fucking 80 years old.
He had a quit smoking cigarettes cause
he had a heart attack, but you know,
healed back up, stop smoking
cigarettes, jumped right back in.
Still working 16 hours a day. Wow,
that's neat. And I should check that out.
It's, it's admirable. Right. But
isn't that, that's the Sushi place.
Tiny little place man.
But isn't that sort of indicative about
the differences between Japanese culture
and Americans? A lot of differences. Yeah.
Extreme differences in the way of thinking
in the way of doing things. Yeah. Well,
that's where you,
you know,
you are known for not just being,
uh,
one of the pioneers of MMA,
but you're known for that expression
Yamato [inaudible] that you have always,
you've always promoted that ideal,
this,
this Samurai spirit and this,
this spirit of Japan, this way of,
of doing things wholeheartedly.
And you know,
you've talked openly that
you freely give yourself,
like when you would go to fight
and you'd be ready to die. Yes.
And not just saying that like you, you
would really reconciled it in your mind.
You would say goodbye to your friends.
Say Goodbye to your family
letters.
I wrote letters to people that I
wanted to say goodbye to every fight.
Yeah. That's some deep shit. You
know, it was the thing too is I'm
fighting to die flying to die.
You're going to train
with the will to die too,
so you can measure them as good
training I got in. Yeah. I mean,
I'm training every day before the fight,
so I won't die in the fight.
I'm planning, I'm okay.
I'm accepting the fact
that I might die there,
but I know that the better I can be is
the less chance to me dying in the ring.
So you know,
I'm not going to get up in the morning
and because I'm sore I'm not going to
miss training because I'm tired or
I'm lazy because it'll might be the
difference in me living and
dying in the room. So you know,
it helped me out a lot. And then the
training aspect and you know the dining,
I mean I want to eat,
I want to drink a coke,
but I'm trying to eat only good things
on my before my fight. And it's,
it's a lot easier to do that when you're
in to that level. It can't hurt you,
you know,
to plan to die in the ring to,
to believe that and to train and to walk
that life for that three months while
training for the fight it,
they can't hurt you.
Is it difficult for you because you
earnestly embraced that thought process?
Is it difficult for you when you see
guys that are kind of dabbling in MMA,
that kind of like half asking it,
not training hard enough.
Maybe they have some talent,
but they don't really put their
will and heart into it. Well,
it's a whole new era now because
back in the day we didn't get
paid good. We weren't, we weren't,
weren't that worried about, you
know, losing a sponsor here, right.
Being cut by the UFC,
you know,
that kind of stuff didn't because there
was all these little association with
fighting for so little bit money.
The objective and the whole movement
of that error was different. Yeah.
So you know,
when fighters start getting lazy
or they don't fight as hard or the
tap out a little sooner, you know,
I understand that because it's a whole
new era because you're fighting for a
different reason though. They're fighting
for money, they're fighting for living,
they're fighting for sponsors if
wanting to look good. You know?
So it's easier when you're
fighting for those reasons.
I mean there's only so much
money will make you do,
but if you're fighting for your honor
and you're fighting for your life,
it's a whole different level.
Yeah,
it's interesting too because in this day
and age it's a real business as well.
So it's almost like you have to have a
little bit of both to be the elite of the
elite, you almost have to have the
attitude that you had, but in order to be,
to maximize your profits, you have to
kind of think about it in a different way.
And after like avoid certain fights
or pick and choose your opponents,
but then once you have
an opponent locked in,
it's almost like the best of both
worlds seems to be like the answer.
Well I think, yeah,
you have to have a good
balance here because if you just look a
fighter like me wouldn't make it today.
I mean I probably wouldn't
have that much wins.
I probably would have three with losses
in a role and I'd probably be losing way.
My job at the UFC, you know,
there's, it's, it's when
people ask me a lot, you know,
are you disappointed at the, wait,
what happened to the fight game?
And they, they, you know,
I always say, you know,
a lot of times now in the fight game
where the worrier we'll start is where the
fight ends now. I mean, right where his
heart is going to kick in right now. Okay.
This is
wanna see if this guy has
it in his heart or not.
That's when the ref stops the fight
because it's getting dangerous, you know?
Did you see, um, this past
weekend's fights? Yeah, I did.
Did you see Jason High and
Rafael dos Anjos yeah. Did you,
what'd you think about that, that
situation? Do you know what happened?
He pushed the right, that should
never happen. Never happened.
It should never happen. If you
don't know what happened. Um,
Dosantos cracked Jason High, hit him
with a real good shot, had them down.
I thought it was a premature stoppage.
He was, he was getting hit, but he was,
he was moving into position,
but Dosantos did that thing that guys
do where they look at the referee,
the hitting them,
and then they look at the referee there
aren't you gonna stop that and then the
referee comes in and stops that,
which is kind of fucking manipulative
that guys do that all the time.
This was hard about the refereeing job
is split second can change a good stop.
It's too shitty softening.
And if he stopped at like a second earlier
when I'd read Jason High got dropped
and it was kind of a little bit out of it.
After the flurry,
it would have been a good stoppage.
But he waited and Jason,
I actually got his posture and
I started like coming up again.
It was a little premature.
But do you think that it's better
to be premature than it is to be,
to have guys take too many shots?
Like what are you thoughts on that
in the day today? Today's MMA? Yes,
definitely. Today's I'm going
to stop the fights her. Yeah.
You got to kind of let
the guys getting hurt.
But the MMA of your era pride was such
a completely different animal because
there was stomps and
soccer kicks and there was,
the rule system was completely different.
It was just a completely
different kind of finds.
Any pins and you're fighting for you
right now in the UFC. It's a sport,
it's a sport, it's a, it's a huge
sport now you can get sponsored,
you can make a living with it. It's
huge. You're fighting for a sport and to,
to be a huge sport as you need
immediate need to sponsors.
You can't have guys getting hurt. You
can't make it too brutal, you know?
So in this day and age you should be more
cautious than anything in stopping the
face. I grew with that. But back in the
day when you're fighting for honor, no,
I mean if that fight was not televised
and you don't need to worry about
sponsors and you know, and people getting
hurt and suits and everything, I would,
if I, in my day I would prefer the
fight not to have stoppages. Well,
like perfect example in my opinion is
Frankie Edgar and like Frankie Edgar and
gray Maynard lot of referees would've
stopped to have those fights in the first
round. A lot of referees. But
Frankie Edgar came back to uh,
to have a draw and one of those fights
where it looked like gray Maynard had him.
Yeah, he was solid. I
mean, it was ridiculous.
A lot of people would have stopped
that fight and waved it off.
But Frankie Edgar came back to win the
second round and then start winning
enough, you know, rounds and make
it close enough. So that was a draw.
And then the second fight or
the fight after that same thing,
he gets tagged and hurt real bad and the
first round and then came back to knock
gray Maynard out later in the fight.
It's, it's hard. It's, it's uh,
in everybody's different. Some guys
can take a shot, some guys just can't,
some guys get hurt and they never come
back. Some guys are known for coming back.
The thing I think about that is, you know,
if the stuff is just weren't so soon,
you know how many unbelievable
inspirational moments
we'd have in fighting.
But that's a sacrifice we make four
for it to be such a big sport. No.
Yeah, the butt part. It's
a big, big part. Yeah.
It's a weird thing because there's no
absolute correct moment in a fight to call
a fight. Like one person's call,
like the guys had a punishment.
Another referee may disagree.
It's so subjective. Yeah. Ice.
It's a real hard thing. If I'm
like, you know, it's, I mean,
I wouldn't say I could be the
same fighter if I fought today.
Now when you say that,
like when you say that you would
have three losses in a row,
like what would be the difference between
the way you fought and the way like
say, modern MMA fighters
fight? I'm, for me,
the win isn't getting my hand raised.
Yeah.
The wind is hitting the fears that I
have head on and growing as a person.
If I, it's, it's really,
sometimes it really contracts each
other because for Igor, Volvo Chante,
when I fought him,
the best thing for me to do was
to take him down and get on top.
But the best thing for me to,
to grow as a man,
as a person is to hit that fearful
stage of throwing total total it, Igor.
You know what I mean?
Ego Of,
of [inaudible] for folks who don't know,
when you were finding him was one of the
most devastating strikers in the sport
at the time. He was brutal knockout
artists and he was a small guy,
but he fucked up Mark Kerr
when Mark Carr was big,
he remember he caught Mark Harwood Harwell
bomb standing up and me ego was only
like five, 10 right. It wasn't a, yeah,
he looked like a guy that should have
probably been way bigger and longer,
but someone like chopped
his arms off at the end,
not for fists,
like in the middle of his,
and he was just this ball of muscle
and bone. That guy could crack.
Yeah.
For me to win the fight and to win the
battle in my heart to be a stronger
person.
It's two different things.
So the,
when the fight is was to use your
Jujitsu to take him to the ground just a
minute, but to overcome your fear was to
bite down your mouthpiece and just wing.
Yes and fuck. Did you ever
man, that was some crazy shit.
I remember I was watching it at my
house with Eddie Bravo and we were just
screaming. The whole like beginning
of that fight was oh shit. Oh Shit.
Cause you just did exactly what,
like a coil,
like a Greg Jackson would tell you not to
do. They would say, they would say, okay,
I want you to avoid, avoid his punches,
which is what we're going to do.
We're going to kick the legs,
we're going to move around a lot.
When you see the opening,
we see the punches calm.
You're going to shoot
him for the take down
when they are bit down that
mouthpiece and you were,
that was one of the wildest opening
exchanges I can remember from the day.
You know what
cirrhotic thing about that fight is?
It was my worst beating that ever took,
but it was the best fight for me.
I've learned so much about
myself in that fight.
I learned about my heart and
that actually solidified that,
you know, living the Yarmouth, Llama
wait, you know, a lot of people, you know,
you can say it, you can have
these kind of sorta hard fights,
but that fight kind of showed
that I'm actually living it.
So it was the worst beating physically
Vic as far as getting the results as far
as the victory, that was probably
the worst fight in my career.
But as far as me growing as a
person and as far as, you know,
something that was a reputation that was
to me forever, it was the best fight.
Do you have a fight that like you look,
you look back and your member is like
a proud moment or one of your proudest
moments?
Oh, that fight would probably be
it, but not at the moment. Yeah,
because at the moment I didn't think I
was that bad. I, uh, at the moment when,
um, when I was getting hit, the biggest,
I remember getting hit some shots
that really rocked me and I,
I remember thinking in my head,
the thing that I thought was,
I can't let them know it hurt.
And I remember looking at my corner
and looking at them and just saying,
I'm okay.
It didn't ask me,
but I just did it on purpose because
I knew he'd be see me doing nearly,
what the fuck's wrong with this
guy. Just hit him so hard. What,
what blue they'll just knock people out
with and he skies look in his corner so
I'm okay. And then you know that that's
the kind of stuff. And I, when the,
when the fight was stopped
and I was screaming, no,
it wasn't because I
was trying to be tough.
I just just felt in that
moment and time I felt, okay,
I got two minutes between Rollins,
why are you coming in at 30
seconds and seeing the fights over.
And the second thing I'm thinking too is
you guys don't know the training that I
went through for this. This is nothing
compared to what I did every day. I said,
I mean, I felt like, let me go on.
And I also felt that this is the
time right here. This is the time,
my breaking moment in.
This is a time where I can show
myself that I can still go on.
But I didn't realize that, you
know, my, my, my year was preferred.
It's so bad that I had my
equilibrium was off on my,
didn't realize that I needed, you know, I
was saying, I was saying the doctor, no,
I still got two minutes, you know,
I'm thinking about two minutes.
Don't check me now,
but I actually should have been yelling.
I give me three months. I didn't
realize how bad it was. Yeah.
Wow. So how long did it
take for you to recover?
Three months to recover from that. Wow.
So I had a periphery to your drum. Um,
I had a broken jaw,
broken finger,
and I had a swollen brain and the,
that,
that was a big worry for the doctors.
Doug, the other big brewer was a kidney.
The kidney levels rose
2000 times a normal person.
The kidney levels.
Do you see what he,
what the doctor explained to me was when
your muscles get any type of trauma,
even if it's just one area of your body,
your muscles all act together as a team
and they'll pull it off toxins that will
affect your kidneys apparently.
So the,
the breakdown of the muscle tissue was
processed by the kidneys and the kidneys
had a deal with a lot of tissues.
Sins, yeah. Tissue Trauma.
And so it was a lot of types of,
something of what the kidney levels,
if they go too high, the
kidneys are shut down. Well,
it's also probably the effort that you
put forth to cause it was such a crazy,
crazy fight. You know, that,
that issue that a lot of crossfitters
have that rhabdomyolysis.
You hear about that? No, it's a
big issue that's going on with a,
a lot of these crossfit competitions,
they push themselves so far,
they push themselves to the
brink of your total body failure.
And this rhabdomyolysis is very
common amongst crossfitters.
I know a guy whose wife got it,
uh,
from just training crossfit because they
push themselves so fucking hard that
they have like kidney failure,
their body starts breaking down.
It's really common. I mean, anytime
when someone overtrained that's a,
it's a,
it's a big issue.
So a fight at post fight like a fight
like that and especially pull up, uh,
Ego Volv changin versus Francisco
Bueno. Yeah, I saw that.
Z. See what this guy was like back in
the day of the fight that actually got me
intrigued to fight Igor. Yeah.
When I saw that, that, that,
that devastation was like something like,
well,
can you manage stepping in that zone,
knowing that that could
happen to you at any moment.
But standing there in that
zone, fighting that, you know,
this is when I fought marker was
right after he beat up Google Dorothy.
Ah, you know, so I was looking at fights
to grow as a person, not to get
a win win loss record. You know,
that's why I'm saying Encino of today
wouldn't make it right because it wasn't
looking, it wasn't very good
from a career. You fought
some big fucking guys too,
and you weren't like, like you fought
Randy who's a heavyweight, you know,
and like, here's a here's ego of, of
channeling versus Francisco [inaudible].
And this was Igor at his
prime. Who has guys built,
look at this. Ding, Ding, Ding.
He caught him three times
as he out on the way down.
Yeah, that was, he was out for a long
time too. Oh yeah, dude. He got flatlined.
We're sitting, I was sitting ringside
and there was this, I guess a girl,
his girlfriend.
But she was going crazy screaming man,
like she was.
He didn't wake up for a while,
but that was a brutal, brutal, brutal
Kayo. And that was Igor at his very best.
And look at this again. Look at
the way this guy's belt. I mean,
he really does look like
a guy who is way bigger.
Cause I had to cut off the ends
of his body. Look at us clink.
And he had those crazy punches to
those casting punches he threw.
He was one of the first
guys to throw like a,
the way fate Dar was known for throwing
those punches where it's almost like
your,
your hand is a perpendicular with the
ground instead of a horizontal with it.
They would throw,
he would throw a lot of his punches
like this in a very unorthodox way of
casting punches. Those are
the days, the glory days.
When you look back,
man, and you thankfully,
you know from the 1997 your
fright with Royce Alger.
Did they have gloves on back then?
That was the last CFC that
they gave us an option.
So I opted to not have
gloves because they always,
always want to have to try that.
Yeah. Wow. So that was the,
you were one in the last UFC where you
didn't have to work a lot with gene was
the last one that they made it an option.
Why is it that it was a rule
that you have? So I, I feel
like I just made it. Yes.
Well for a grappler too, you
know, that's a big advantage.
So sneaky and chokes and
the way they tape the,
they didn't allow you to tape the hands
and they taped it for me and it was like
it cut. Like here is like just,
just pretty much the risk.
So nothing on this at all to
protect your hand, Huh? Yeah.
What do you think now about these new,
like there's a lot of issues
these days with guys I pokes,
but it wasn't a big issue back then,
which is weird to me that there was
not nearly as much of an
issue in those early days.
Like you didn't see a lot of I
pokes. Yeah. You know, and you,
you didn't see a lot in pride and I,
Tim Kennedy was on the podcast.
We have these pride gloves. There was a
bunch of them like the last year of Sia.
Oh, there's a lot of them a lot
lately. But these pride gloves,
Tim Kennedy believes are superior to
the UFC gloves because they naturally
promote a curved fist.
Whereas the UFC gloves have much
more of a straight line to them.
Everlast has a new glove that they're
using with the Bella tour. And, um,
it's a much more curved
fist and it's also,
there's more panning across the
top to, uh, to reinforce the,
the metacarpals when you,
when you're hitting.
And they apparently stopped a lot of
bone breaks because that all really,
but I almost feel like the same thing
I feel like with football that like
everybody is concerned about
head trauma and football,
but no one wants to look at,
there's a lot of people who have a
now analyzed football. They say, well,
there's the best way to stop his head.
Trauma is probably to make people
play football with no helmets.
Because if you play
football with no helmets,
you're gonna play it totally different.
You cannot go head to head in,
clash into each other if
you have no fucking element.
And the only real way to control the
way these guys do this is to make it so
that it's impossible to you.
I mean,
they're spiking each other with
helmets on and shoulder pads and shit.
They're saying if you
really want to do it,
look at rugby and look at Australian
rules. Football, less had trauma,
less instances of a traumatic brain
injury and they're there fighting with no
pads.
I mean that's probably,
and I think that might be the
way to do with MMA to man,
because I get that people think that it's
brutal to punch people with no gloves
on. But guess what? You're kicking
people with nothing on your feet.
Your foot is way fucking stronger. You're,
he'll never gets hurt. I mean, you could,
he'll kick someone in the face all day
and it's never going to hurt you or heal.
I mean, I've seen people,
we'll kick people full clip,
slamming of their face. They walk off
fine. You never see them like, ow my foot,
you know, it doesn't hurt your foot,
your heel, you can stomp on the ground.
You know, you can do things with your
foot. You could never do with your hands.
I think they should
probably go bare knuckle.
I think that might be the way the gloves
are actually just to protect the hens
ivy. Yeah. Yeah. And maybe stop some cuts.
Elbows, elbows, cows. So it's
probably, we could have an elbow here.
What do you think about that?
Because some people think that elbows
actually stop a lot of good fights because
it cuts. Asking a guy who
didn't, I didn't want,
I wanted growing shots allowed.
Right.
I mean everything and even I ecology,
you know,
I really don't because I believe that the,
see all the people that get hurt in the
eyes because you can't do it so you're
not expecting it. If we
were professionals, I
mean your, your to to stop
all the joint locks, all the different
chokes. Who'd your training to,
to stop being in bad
positions. If you, if,
if you're allowed to have
growing shots, you'd be, you,
you train not to get hit in the groin.
I think if you got to allow our gouges
you've got a real problem. Yeah.
I mean this, I mean even, you know, biting
his only thing that I would be for you,
but biting is good if you get side
control and bites him and then he would
actually change a flight. You know
what else? Oh, biting the ear. Yeah.
I mean, look how Holly feel reacted
to Mike Tyson. A chunk of his ear off.
Yeah. I think I gouges or
that's a dangerous problem.
You've got a bunch of guys like Alan
Belcher's careers in jeopardy because of
detached retinas. Michael Bisping
had to have several eyes surgery.
He's got a real problem now.
One of his eyes looked weird,
like he's got the thumbing
air. My accident. Yeah. I'm
talking about grappling.
When you try and dice, it's hard if
the guy's going to defend from that.
You know nick, how Yuki losses.
I was, because I believe a big,
a big thing was you,
you're allowing these dirty fighters to
get away with it because it's not in the
rules. Right. So he's not
expecting it. Yeah. Right.
So I figured a professional
expecting it would would,
that would not have happened if Nikai
knew that it was in the rules. Hmm.
Yeah. That was, he fought Gerard
Gardot. Yeah. That was big. Yeah.
Big Karate Guide. That was shameful.
Yeah. That was shameful. It was, yeah.
He lost his eye because of
that. Yeah. He's one of the few,
but there's quite a few guys have had
a text. Right. And I was like, yeah,
that's really common these days,
man. Really common. I just,
I don't know what they could do about it.
I almost feel like there's a way to
cover the tips of the fingers though.
I wonder. Yeah, I wonder how much it
will affect the Groppe Linville yeah.
I wonder if it's a small,
like a thin piece of like a,
a thin leather that it may be even enhance
the grappling because it'll give you
more grip and when your hands are sweaty,
you know when you clamp down,
like maybe someone's working on it right
now probably. Huh? I'm sure there is.
These are the Bella tore gloves
you could see up on that thing.
See the bell toward glove is on the left.
Where's the UFC style glove is on the
right and the bell tower glove has a a
more padding on the metacarpal
and it's curved more. Uh Huh.
I don't know what they,
what they have shown though.
Belterra has had far less handbrakes
because of that. Oh really? Yeah.
But then again,
it goes back to the football thing,
like maybe you're better off knowing
that you can't just tee off on someone's
head without breaking your hand.
I mean,
if guys had to be more
conservative with their punches,
maybe we would see more kicks.
Maybe we'd see more grappling and
maybe MMA would be more realistic.
And that's true, man. That's true. I don't
know. I don't know what the answer is.
Yeah, I tickets. We have a bunch
of issues in MMA right now.
The judging issues. A tremendous
man. What's going on with that man?
You see the Diego Sanchez, Ross
Pearson, five crazy fucking ridiculous.
Crazy ridiculous.
I haven't seen one person that
thought Diego Sanchez won that fight,
other than Diego Diego's family
know. And I love Diego. I'd think,
you know, it's not Diego's fault that
they scored it wrong, but God damn,
that was a bad decision. It was very bad.
Yeah. I mean, Diego's got a lot of heart.
You can't, you can't take it
away from him. He's that guy.
He's a Yamato Dimasi right?
He is. He's a motherfucker.
Diego Sanchez comes to watching the
guy from one of my all time favorites.
He's a wild man.
Yeah.
He's one of the few guys today that's
still fights with complete total reckless
abandon, you know, especially when
he starts getting hurt. Oh yeah.
It's face could be hanging up.
When he fought Martin Kampmann and that
third round, his face was hanging off,
hanging off of his skull and he's
charging like a wild beast with rabies.
He's a crazy dude, man. He's
fun to watch fight. He's pure,
pure aggression. That guy. Pure aggression
and heart. I like that guy. Yeah,
love watching him fight man. I just
don't think he won that decision. Yeah,
I don't think so either. What do you think
about the way the UFC has rounds too?
Cause one of the things I really loved
about pride was that first 10 minute
round that really separated
like the people that had real,
true endurance and knew
how to pace yourself.
There's one thing pacing yourself
on a five minute round is one thing.
Patient yourself on a 10 minute round as
an entirely different proposition when
it comes to conditioning. Yeah. Well,
again, he goes to the question, you know,
the reason why am amazed being changed
in the way it is for the sponsors and for
the,
for the audience.
And I think it's depending on the
fighter can you mentioned, you know,
you have those boring fights where
they get to the ground and you exist.
Why don't you stand up?
But they're doing enough that they don't
get broken up and you're like, damn,
five minutes is that that bad?
But he can't imagine that happening
for 10 minutes. Yeah, that's true.
That's the thing. That's, I think that's
the thing that really works for the,
the sport now because they're
shorter rounds for the audience.
I agree. But there's a purist in
me that I don't like stand ups.
I don't think you should be stood up.
Yeah.
I think if the guys on the bottom and
you don't like the fact that the guy's
holding you down,
you got to get better at getting up.
You got to get better at sweeping
them. You've got to get better at. Uh,
it's just trying to
attack from the bottom,
attacking to try to get a better position
to stand back up or to try to finish
him from your back.
I just don't think it's realistic for a
guy just to hang on and let the referee
standing back up again. Which is a
strategy. You see it all the time. Well,
it's a sport. No. Yeah, yeah. If you're
looking at it as a fight, you know,
that's why he's a good MMA fighter.
What he's, I mean like a street fighter.
It's a whole different thing.
Right. But even as a sport,
I think if you're going to look at the
sport, it's still the sport of fighting.
And if a guy can hold you down,
he's holding you down.
Like you can't just stand them up.
Like she worked hard to get that guy down
and the guy on the bottom doesn't want
to be there. So the guy in
the bottom technique. Yeah,
he's just knocking his hands
and just holding them. Yeah.
Just to get a better position stood up
again. That's what a lot of guys do.
They just wait to get stood back up. I
think that's kind of crazy. Yeah, it,
I don't like that either. I to see a guy
like, you know, you know Charles Olivera,
you know that kid.
I like watching that guy fight because
he's so dangerous off of his back because
he's,
he's real aggressive standing up and one
of the reasons why he's so aggressive
standing up, he's not worried about
being taken down because if he,
he's taken down,
it's tax a tax,
a tax right away off of his back arm
bars triangle. Like this is no picnic.
Taking that guy on the ground,
you take him down to the ground,
you just did another different type
of account is constantly attack. Yeah,
I like that. That's good. Yeah. When
the guys have one dimensional games,
that's when getting taken down becomes a
problem because they get taken down and
then the guy can hold them there, but
you can't hold some guys, you know,
there's guys that have wicked guards.
You take them down and man,
you're in a fucking new world,
a shit.
You're just running into another sort of
a situation where you can get submitted
or lose the fight.
I think that that's the best way for MMA.
The be the best way is not standing guys
up because then why not even just why
have it MMA then?
Why not just fight kickboxing?
If you just want to fight standing up
then where there's no threat of takedowns,
then you could do some wild shit,
you know?
But you have a different sport then
if you're going to have takedowns.
I don't think you should have standups.
I really don't. Yeah, true. But stem,
can you imagine the sponsor's wouldn't
like that TV would be baseball,
man. How do they watch
baseball? I way more boring.
They will watch it. True. You look at
that then they should not break them.
That's not that boring I to look
at that. It's not even close. Well,
even football man. What do you think?
Two on ones and stuff. I don't like that.
You don't like that man? No.
The team fighting shit. Oh,
not the team fighting like two on one.
Even two on one.
I think the deal strategy man,
I think two one one would be interesting
if it's like a guy like you versus to
non trained guys. Would that
be funny? That'd be exciting.
Exciting non train big guys.
Yes. Non trained guys though.
But with train guys.
No that's like a circus.
But like say if you had a guy like John
Jones versus to like football players
that don't really know how to fight, that
would be exciting. Exciting. It would,
that would be exciting.
But a guy like John Jones versus
two John Jones's? No. Yeah,
no way. I don't want to see
that. I mean for me I always,
I always felt that there was one of the
things I wanted to try and do two on one
ace fight two guys at one time and see
because there's a hole in your fear live
in. Yeah. Oh yeah. Fuck yeah.
So there's that fear element is what I
was kinda intrigued to try and experience.
Would you want to fight two guys
at the same size as you know,
but like say if I'm,
if I'm too,
I'm too 30 like guys that
are like 180 or 200 pounds,
just have a little bit of
advantage of size and then yeah,
the issues would be different now.
Yeah. Yeah. Well that's what I'm saying.
Like two untrained guys,
you get like too rough,
tough fucking football players, you know,
they don't really know how to fight,
give him like a couple of weeks to fucking
hit or whatever. Just a little bit,
you know, just a couple of weeks to
do some fight training. But the real,
the reality is a guy like you versus a
football player that has no martial arts
experience, he would need years just
to be able to survive on his own.
But two of them, they have that, you
know, the gangster fights. Yeah. Yeah.
And it's a,
it's actually pretty semi trained.
All of them are semi train and that
you didn't even like gangster fights.
You're talking about the Russian?
No one's in Japan that the
Yakuza is fine and stuff,
but really they have one guy and Liza Lou.
You guys are a little bit
smaller and this, it's crazy.
Some of the fights man.
So it's one guy versus two guys.
One guy versus two guys. And the the,
the two guys are a little bit smaller.
A little bit smaller. Just a little
bit. Yeah. And the Yakuza sets these up.
There's a, there's a fights that are
run by them. Yeah. Is it organized? Yes.
Organized is, we're organized.
They call it though. It's um,
they call it a Chica cock.
Togi Chica is underground and Cocteau
gears fighting Chica. Cocteau Ogee yeah.
So underground fight weight.
If you're in Japan when they have one,
I'll take you to fuck. Yeah,
hazy. Then you know, the fun,
the good thing about it is a lot of
these guys don't have that much skill and
they just did this a bra.
Wow.
Now do they have like a doctor standing
by for these things or they have a ring
doctors, they have referees,
they have everything.
And you could get away with that
in Japan because of the Yakuza has,
it's a different sort of a scenario then
like say the mafia in America. So yeah,
it's a little bit different. Yeah. I guess
much more accepted. Right? Yes it is.
It's, it's, it's something inside
of people know that's around. Wow.
But it's not something that you
want to be public about, Huh? Yeah.
They made me cover up my tattoos.
We've talked about this the last
time we were on the podcast,
I was in a gym and they made
me put on a long sleeve shirt.
You come back and you can't
probably can't shower here. Yeah.
Because shower my room. Um,
so, but the Yakuza is just,
is not talked about, but it's
everywhere. It's everywhere.
You can see them a wrong, there's nice
guys that are, cause there's assholes.
There's this, a whole bunch of, I've,
I've had a lot of stuff with them. Yeah.
We talked about a little bit about that
last time. You were here on the podcast.
We had a smack the shit out of some
guy. It's all in the book too. Okay.
Now tell me about the book and when is
it out? This is the one for you, man.
Beautiful. Oh, awesome.
Beautiful. Yeah, it's uh,
I think four years in the making
them live as a man, die as a man,
become a man.
And do you understand that saying yes.
Do you know that? You know, do
you know what I think? Well,
I don't know if we talked about it before,
but you know,
the middle line is to die when
everyone thinks that that's the end.
So everyone thinks that the normal
reading would be to live as a man,
become a man and
a man. But I believe that
until you faced it more,
most fearful tests of dying, you don't
know how strong you actually are.
Hmm. So you live your life with all these
little tests in life or little's trials
that you have to build your strength
and build your heart to the last test of
the dying.
And the way you die is going to determine
whether you've passed that test or not.
So that's why I like that
title. Yeah. That's a,
in today's Day and age,
this strange,
soft pussified society that we live in.
You know,
and there's a lot of good things about
the pussified society. Don't get me wrong,
there's a lot of good things about people
being civil with each other and about
having laws and about having,
you know,
being able to get your food from grocery
store. All those things are good,
but what's bad about all these things,
and it's not bad about these things,
but the,
the,
the repercussions of them is
that men don't develop character.
And a lot of men fold under
pressure because they've
never experienced pressure.
They don't know themselves.
They don't know what they're capable
of because they've never had to face
adversity, true adversity. When you
were really worried about your life,
when you're really worried
about your safety, when you are,
your back is up against the wall and
you either rise to the occasion or your
dwarfed by the moment. And so many
people that have never faced adversity,
they just immediately fall
apart. They panicked, they fold,
they don't know what to do. Yeah.
That's what you were fighting against.
Yeah. And um, the,
a lot of it is in the book is a lot of
the stuff that I've went through and it's
not like me being a big hero and being
flying with bright colors in every
experience.
Sometimes there's experiences where
I really just fucked up and I just,
and some of those fuckups you're
actually really taught me about like, uh,
there was, uh, the book starts off with
this story about my friend that, uh,
was when we were,
when I was little and like 12 years old,
I watched a friend get beat up by bigger
guys and I didn't do anything about it.
I was so scared.
I was frozen,
I didn't know what to do and I just
watched it and I was afraid of getting
involved and getting hurt, physically
hurt, you know, beaten, beaten up,
possibly go in the hospital,
possibly a broken bone and I
didn't do anything about it.
And Wow.
The thing about that now is if I did
something about it and say I got a broken
arm, broken leg, they broke my
by orbital, I'd be here today,
probably healed up because the body
heals. But to this day, even that,
even if that episode was 30 something
years ago, I still hurt from that insight.
Thinking about that, wishing I could
rewind and do something about it,
wishing I could see that my friend
again and tell him, I'm sorry.
What'd we see my friend
and telling him, man, fuck,
I don't know why it didn't help you.
You know?
I never saw the guy again after
that. The Ma. Yeah, and it was,
it's something that just is even just
talking about it right now, it's just it,
it, I, I heard about it. I
hurt, I hurt. I in my heart.
I heard thinking about it.
Yeah. Do you think that those
moments when you have these, the,
these moments,
those are to s to make the wrong decision
and to feel the repercussions of that
wrong decision?
That's an integral part of the learning
process because when something comes up
in the future,
you've experienced the pain of the wrong
decision and then the right decision
becomes the only decision. Yeah. That's
probably the best way to learn. Yeah.
Trial and error. It's the only way I
think to really truly understand it.
You can learn a little bit from
other people's mistakes. You know,
you can sort of internalized
their mistakes and you put
it in into your category
or your or your catalog
rather of knowledge.
But I think to truly have a
a real lesson in your head,
yeah,
you almost have to fuck it up yourself.
Well,
that one experience has helped me make
the right decisions and a lot of other
things that came later in my life,
but still that, just that one,
that one just still hurts, man.
30 something years later, man.
Wow. Any bone that was broken would
have been healed by that. Wow.
That's the true thing also about
losses is that everybody wants to win.
Winning is everything when he's the
only thing, it's not everything.
It's the only thing. People always
say that there are no second place,
first loser,
you know,
but the reality is those losses and that
awful feeling of those losses are so
fucking important for the growing process.
If you don't realize what it's like to
drop your hands and get cracked by a
counter shot, you don't
realize how important it is
to really keep your hands up.
You you won't. No, you
won't internalize it,
but when you've been cracked and
rocked and you wind up losing a fight,
you're like fuck.
Then when you're in that fight again or
in another fight that those lessons are
concrete, those lessons are
tangible. Those lessons are
a part of who you are now.
I suppose it depends on
what level. Are you going to
look at wins and losses at? Yeah,
because if after you fight, if someone
asks me after I fought, how'd you do?
I mean if you're talking
about the way I think,
I don't know yet cause I'm going to know
if I won or lost that fight in my next
fight. If I become a better
fighter because of that experience,
I'm a better fighter. I won because I
gained and I got better. So you know,
losses are determined on what you're
going to do after the law. Awesome.
Yeah.
There's oftentimes wins that fuck a
fighter up more than a loss does because
like say maybe you catch a guy with one
punch and you knock them out and then
you just decide that you're a knockout
puncher now instead of being 10 Finkel
instead of using a comprehensive game,
you just kind of a striker.
All of a sudden, a lot of guys,
man, a lot of guys who are Jujitsu,
black belts all the sudden started
getting in these kickboxing matches and
getting fucked up and it was so
frustrating for me to watch, like,
I understand that you like to strike
however you are fucking wizard on the
ground and you're not even attempting.
She use these skills because
you had in this one thing,
so they decided they were a striker. A
lot of the game is the mind, right? Yeah.
The book covers every fight.
Exactly how I was thinking from when I
got the fight to when I was preparing for
the fight during the fight.
It's going to be interesting because a
lot of people think that I'm just the
almost the dom mushy guy that has no
fears and just comes out and has this iron
type of thinking.
But it kind of tells you exactly
what I'm thinking during the fight,
what happened, what I thought
after the fight. And it's, it's,
it's straight up real stuff.
I mean,
well, you know, custom motto, the
Guy, the long time trained Mike Tyson,
famous guy who was really what his,
his take wasn't just the
technical aspects of boxing,
but also the psychology behind boxing.
And one of the things that
he ingrained in Mike Tyson,
he said that a coward and the
hero feel the exact same thing.
It's just that the hero chooses to act.
Why the coward falls apart
is what you'd do at fury.
It's what you do with the fear. And his
other thing was that fear is like fire.
It can, it can cook your food
for you, it can keep you warm,
or if you lose control of it, it can burn
your house down and kill you. Yeah. Yeah.
That's so real. Yeah.
Yeah. It's like it's your,
your impressive performances are more
impressive knowing that you were scared
knowing that you had all the
fears that everybody else has,
but you decided anyway to still
clamped down your mouthpiece and,
and fucking throw led at equal vote.
Shanshan yeah,
that's, that's what I was fighting
for this Yamanto Dimasi and you know,
eastern eastern philosophy,
which is very different in a lot
of ways than western philosophy.
The philosophy that a lot of
people associate with martial arts,
the respect and honor,
integrity and warrior spirit.
A lot of that is kind of missing in some,
some MMA camps.
And it's almost like they become
jocks and athletes and not,
not as much martial artists.
What do you think about
that? I think it's, uh,
it's something that's people are losing.
It is true that there's a benefit in
having that right. Well, indefinitely.
Because what happens when you run your
gym and you fight in that mentality,
you're, once you done with Emma,
you can't fight forever. Right?
And when you're done with
it, it, it'll carry you.
It'll carry on with you as a person.
If you're just being a jock and doing
just Emon man, you're just doing that.
Once you're done with that,
you're going to,
you're going to go into the real world,
the person that you were
when you started fighting.
Not only that,
you'll probably be one
of those motherfuckers to
those boring ass glory day
stories. They keep talking
about that Glenn. Yeah.
Back when you won the Olympic
trials for wrestling and you know,
it was doing great until I blew that disk.
You know,
if you train with that
honor and discipline and
you develop that during your
fighting career,
you're going to definitely be a better
man when you finish your fighting career.
Well, I got real lucky when
I first started, uh, doing
martial arts is that my,
my taekwondo instructor was very into the,
the,
the aspects of martial arts
that we consider like the
philosophy and the mindset
and the warrior code,
indomitable spirit,
like all these different things was
we're promoted very heavily and promoted
that. One of the big ones was
that martial arts or just a ve,
a vehicle for developing your human
potential and that this is even when you
can't kick and even when you can't
punch and even when your body's old,
you're still doing martial
arts because this, this,
this path that you are on this path of,
of learning this path of testing yourself
and this path of trying to overcome
resistance.
This will stay with you forever in life.
Yeah. Well, yeah, I believe martial
arts for me was a steer in my life, uh,
stared at,
I had to climb to become a better person.
Do you think that it would,
I think it would stop a lot of bullying
if martial arts were mandatory in school.
Yeah, I think so. Yeah. It would, it
would stop a lot of them crazy. You know,
being tough fights in the school.
Yeah.
Test.
If guys could test each other and guys
could test themselves and guys can push
themselves like in the gym and also just
develop confidence because you actually
know how to fight instead of like
pretending you know how to find,
try to scare people off
because you're insecure,
which is what the bottom have those
though. No matter what. Less of it though,
don't you think you'd have less
of it? Yeah, for sure. I mean,
you have bullies in the gym.
There's always going to be
problems with guys in the gym.
Beat up on lesser talented guys,
hurt guys when they're sparring and
supposed to be going 50% and they go 100%
you're always going to have that goes
to have gym wars or one guy elevates a
little bit and the young guy catches up
to him and then the other guy takes it
to another level and next thing you know
they're in a full on fight. Yeah. Yeah.
When you were training
for, um, for MMA fights,
how did you structure your training?
Like when you,
when you said about like say if you have,
if you were about to fight
mark her for example,
and you have eight weeks
to prepare for your fight,
how did you structure your training camp?
Did you do it all yourself?
Did you have someone help
you design your programs?
Um, I did a lot, um, work with Egan.
Egan would help me out with a strategy.
We'd helped me with a game
plan and then we'd set our,
or our training in correspondence
to the game plan. Yeah,
like mark curve for me.
I didn't think I could get strong and
big enough to match and powerful par.
So I thought no getting
stamina and moving faster.
So I think I was like 94 kilos in
that fight. Yeah. What does 94 kilos?
94 kilos,
I don't know.
Let's find out two or tools
to a seven to eight maybe.
Let's see how many pounds is 94 kilos?
It is two oh seven two seven
was like two 62
65 town muscle. Yeah,
he was fucking gigantic.
And he was saying that he was
going to throw total toy at me,
so I was working my striking
when I actually went to, um,
more Reese's Jim Murray Smith. Oh
really? And worked there with him.
How did that fight go down?
I don't,
I don't want to tell her that
fine tacos here. We thought,
I thought we're going to throw it down.
And he tackled me and I was like,
God damn.
And he held me and just kind of chipped
away and he was good enough that I
couldn't finish them, but he wasn't
good enough to pass my guard.
But he was good enough that I couldn't
our embargo and we got broken once and
that was when pride had those 10 minute
rounds or broken once and then dumb me
the second time I thought, okay,
we're going to stand though.
And boom, he shot for a tackle.
Yeah. Yeah. That was frustrating.
He was an interesting case because he
was one of those guys that sort of tested
this.
We were in the beginning of MMA when
people would watch the various styles and
the various strategies that people would
be successful with inside the octagon,
they would try to figure
out what is the best way.
Is it the best way to be a big wrestler?
Well No,
if you fight Maury Smith Cause Maury
Smith figured out how to be a smaller guy.
Chip away at the legs of Mark Coleman.
Take it into the later rounds
and that's how he won the title.
He won the title with stamina
and with his striking. Yeah.
But then you see a guy like Mark Kerr
and who was like the very like as far as
you could go with like the big steroid
it up muscular frame and wrestling.
I pull up a picture of Mark Carr.
Mark Kerr in his prime was his nickname
was the smashing machine and the
specimen. Huh? I got the specimen
smashing machine and he was a,
a big wrestler who didn't have like a
lot of skills as far as like submissions.
Like he submitted a guy
what a can opener wants.
Probably the only guy I ever late.
There was Jesus fucking Christ
that is barely human. He was
fucking gigantic, man. Yeah.
That's the one I fought.
He submitted a guy,
he submitted a Dan Babish by
putting his chin in his eyeball.
He talked to his chin into Bobas wishes,
eyeball and fucking and crushed his,
his head into his own chin.
It's like he pulled his chin into the,
like the guy's eyeball and tapped him I
think in mountain him and did that stuck
his chin and his face. Wrong.
Strongest fuck I bet. Right? Yeah.
So the strongest guys I fit.
Yeah.
He was as big as you could get and
still do MMA. That was like that.
He was the s like that example, like
for example, the big strong wrestler,
he was the most extreme version. It was
real successful in the beginning. Oh yeah.
Real successful. But it seemed like the
wheel started to come off after a while.
No fighting. No, no. He did
a few fights afterwards,
but after the smashing machine documentary
came out and the folks have never
seen that documentary.
That is,
he's got an incredible amount of courage
for letting people into that world
because mark had a significant problem
with painkillers and with drugs and
showed it all in all of its,
they,
they started that documentary wanting
to do a documentary to follow one of the
best mixed martial arts fighter in
the world, the smashing machine,
the guy who a lot of people thought was
the heavyweight to wash and along the
way they,
they caught it at the perfect time where
he was starting to unravel and they got
to see a guy whose life was just
sort of falling apart. That was,
that was pretty crazy. This
is trends. It came out and
shoot himself up all the time
with all these painkillers,
painkillers or a motherfucker, man. Yeah.
That's a big thing, huh? Oh yeah. Yeah.
Their opiates, very addicting.
Never tried them at all. No.
No painkillers at all.
I never tried any drugs that marijuana.
Did you ever like have a
surgery or anything like
that? No. No surgeries at all?
Nothing. No. No knee surgery? Nothing? No.
How the hell did you manage
to go through an Lma career?
With no surgeries or luck.
I love you man. The worst.
I had to think it was the orbit of
crack from the Oit Royce Alger fight for
Royce Alger fight. Horrible. Okay. That's
what happened. That fight. You don't,
when you interviewed me I was fine and
it went to the back and I felt my nose
was bleeding, so I blew my nose
in it. Just whoa, that's crazy.
And it just filled my eye up with air.
And then the doctor came in and said,
you can't fight. And I was like, no,
no, I'm fine. Please let me fight.
I still can see. That was the who?
Tito Tito. It took your place.
Wow.
Historical Shit.
You know Tito Ortiz was molten.
It historical shit.
What did you think about Tito Ortiz
fight in Beltour? That little guy,
he fought flamenco.
Well,
I was hoping he did beat
the guy up because I was
thinking of that guy shouldn't
be calling on every week
class. It's ridiculous. And I,
I didn't know what he was
thinking. Yeah, I'm glad.
And he even knew what he passed
them all. He knocked the wall. Yeah.
Put him to sleep that was wanting
to see what the head and arm choke.
That was nice to see. Yeah. Tito's got
a really underrated submission game.
A lot of people don't give
him enough credit for a
submission game. You know, he,
he's big too. Fucking huge. Yeah. He's
like my weight class and I, when I,
I just saw them the other time at one
of the events, he was a guest then.
He's huge. He's enormous. Yeah.
It's hard to believe he even makes two
oh five when you look at the drops,
good weight.
Manko is like my size.
He had no business being in the
cage with Tita and Tito. He called,
he's the one who called Tito out.
Right. I don't know what that's about.
And Tito's sort of sponsored him too,
which is a lot of people thought like
some fuckery was afoot foot. They're like,
wait a minute. Cause Tito like teen
punishment. He represents team punishment.
Really? Oh, that's
weird. Huh? I don't know.
I mean maybe they just said they can
make some money. Let's just do it.
And she'll Manka wanted to test himself.
Uh, I don't know. You know, but,
but when you see the two of them
inside the cage at the same time,
at least they look,
it's like a giant is fighting a little
mat and Tito got him to the ground.
Man.
You just saw that weight and pressure
and just submitted them pretty quickly.
Like we have the difference in the size
there. Yeah, I get that. This is crazy,
but good for Tito. Get that
wind back man. You know,
that's one thing that bums
me out is that people don't,
I mean I guess Tito kind of brings it on
himself sometimes cause he says a bunch
of crazy shit, but that guy
doesn't get enough credit. He,
a lot of people disrespect him. Tito's or
real. He's a real pioneer. Yeah, he is.
Oh yeah, for sure. He,
their bag with you in 97 and really
Tang Abby. That's the time. Yup.
Yup. Yeah. I mean that's when tank
Abbott was the Huntington beach.
Bad boy does sort of became bad
boy somewhere along the line.
Right. Wow. Yeah, he was a
part of tank average crew.
He said he learned a lot from tank Abbott.
And it's interesting because what
you say about attitude and about,
you know about the,
the mindset of fighting,
that's what he said that he
learned from [inaudible] Tang.
You learned from tag out.
But how did you go in there and fuck
somebody up and they'll just go in there
and kick somebody's fucking ass.
And that's what tank Abbott used to
do to say whatever you want about tank
Abbott. That motherfucker never
passed on a fight would fight anybody.
And with an hour's notice and you know,
you could, you could literally call him,
he'll be on a bar stool,
he'd be on a flight the next day headed
to wherever the fuck you wanted him to
fight drunk. And he would win a
lot of those fights. Hard puncher.
Cause he had that attitude.
He was just ready to get in there and
fuck somebody up. If you're there,
it is Tito right next to him. Oh
yeah, yeah. Oh it's a Odi tank.
Habits like God damn classic.
He's a classic guy.
He was some wild fucking fights
inside the octagon. So crazy knockout.
So, yeah, I don't remember. I
don't know the last time he fought,
but I have a feeling it was like,
I want to say it was fairly
recently tank out of it or, yeah.
Somebody told me that he bought recently.
And let me see here.
Let's look up on Wikipedia. They'll
tell us one of the last time he fought,
because I want to say that he
fought fairly recently. Yeah.
I fought in 2013.
Whoa.
He lost to a Reuben hurricane Villareal.
That's the same guy that boss route and
fought on one of his last fights too.
And he beat Mike Bork in 2009.
So he took a,
took four years off,
came back and lost and King of the cage.
Wow. That wasn't even, was that even
though it wasn't a hyped up at all? No.
It was kind of crazy. King of
the cage fighting legends. Wow.
That was 2013. Oh, to watch that cab. You
probably didn't even know about it. Yeah,
that's the problem. Sure. Yeah. It's
kind of crazy that it was so, uh,
you know,
low profile before the ad.
He fought a Kimbo slice in 2008 yeah.
In Miami.
That was before Kimbo when to the,
he fought Yoshida,
Yoshida and pride.
And he got a, he got choked. Yeah.
It's a lot of fights. A lot of fights.
Yeah. I mean if you look at his career
and there's a lot of losses in the air,
but God damn classic fights. Yeah.
They are classic toys and went to his,
that was his first fight.
His very first fight.
And then Paul varlands remember that
fight? It was another great fight.
There it is.
Can you the cage legends.
Oh Wow. Tank. Gambit gray beard now.
Still slinging led.
King of the cage is a place where a lot
of guys had their start, right? Yeah.
King of the cage. Where did you have your
first fight? Uh, mine was in a shoot.
Don't shoot. Oh yeah.
Did you find Super Bra?
Was that Egon funds first Superbowl
once? Yeah. You fought at once.
Would you find it over there?
Uh,
Tommy saw her and super ball was a
almost like old school valley Tuto style,
right? Yeah. Different rules.
Hawaii had a different different set of
rules that you are allowed to compete
under. Like what is it? What
was the rules of Superbowl? Um,
at that time was more just like pride,
pride rules.
When I fall soccer kicks knees to
the head on the ground ground. Yeah.
I like those rules.
Do you think that that the MMA
in its current form right now,
like if you, if you could change any
of the rules and still keep it a sport,
I think that first of all, 12 to six
elbows that that's got to come back.
I think 12 to six elbows as it is
a ridiculous thing to have band,
but I think needs, needs to have grounded
opponent. We change a lot of shit too.
Yeah. Even soccer ball kicks. I
think he's okay. Really? Yeah.
You're fucking crazy. I think
those, I would like those to be in.
The only thing I have a problem
with the soccer kicks is the cage.
I liked the soccer kicks in a ring
because you can move your head away,
but the fact that you're trapped and you
can get kicked and stomped when you're
trapped up against the cage,
that's the only time that I think that
it would be a problem because the guy
can't really defend himself because of
the environment as opposed to because
he's out. That would be just one more
danger in a cage. There's a lot of that.
That's true. That's true. That's true.
The people would be keeping their head
away from the cage a little more. Yeah.
When you look back, I mean your
first fight in the UFC 1997, um,
what was your first actual
mixed martial arts fight?
Shoot it and I need 10 96
96 daddy's the early days,
man, that was right after
Hickson and came to Japan.
Hixon fought in the Japan valley that
maybe you want to fight you. Really? Yeah.
Wow. That was incredible, man.
Those are incredible times.
And when you look back at that
and now you see the guys of today,
you see like the Demetrius mighty mouse
Johnson's and you see the John Jones is
and these high level guys, the pound
for pound best guys at today, man,
it's just like a totally different thing.
Yes it is this, there's, there's actual
fighters that are called
mixed martial artists now.
Yeah. Full mixed martial art can do
everything. It's not a karate guy.
Back in the day
that your fighter was either a striker
arrester or ground guy and it was always
a real straight up strategy to
fight in those. But now man,
they can get everything nowadays.
I mean I see the, you know,
the younger fighters coming
up nowadays and you know, the,
some people tell me like, ah, when you
fought there was no money. There was,
it was so small and shit and it wouldn't
you don't you wish your grandfather
this day and age and I'm thinking
to myself, I don't know man. He,
Ken's a fighter's nowadays,
man, there's full me shed.
They can their black blackbelt Jujitsu's
that are professional kickboxers and
wrestles, it can fight
boxing. You know what I mean?
It's like wrestlers would blackbelt
Jujitsu. It's unbelievable.
And it's getting better. Yeah. It
seems to me that it's getting better.
I mean it seems to me that the
level keeps rising the levels.
Just wait Tj Dillashaw what the fuck?
What the fuck like kid comes
out of nowhere. I mean,
I thought that was going to be a real
difficult fight for him. I thought like,
man, Hanan Barao is a killer, one of the
best pound for pound guys in the world.
And then Tj Dillashaw just goes in there.
One's a clinic on one's a clinic on him.
That was unbelievable and there's more
of those come out at then head kicks him
in the fifth round and didn't ever fight
like he was ahead. Dude, never fight.
Always trying to finish crazy.
It's good fighter, man. Fuck yeah.
Great fighters that there's going to
be a rematch them that I hope so. Yeah,
it should be. Man, I hope so. Well,
there's a lot of great fights
at one 55 there's so many. Oh,
Dominick Cruz, you know. [inaudible] never
had that division before. It was crazy.
Yeah. Before it was just the
heavier guys. Yeah. Well,
I think they're probably
going to have a one 15 to,
they're going to have a straw weight.
Well,
there's a lot of great
fighters in other countries,
especially a lot of great Japanese guys.
One 15 a lot of Brazilian guys.
One 15 I think that in a few more women,
weight classes would be good too.
You know?
I think they're going to do a one 25
women's weight class maybe at one 15 as
well. Yeah, that'd be big.
That's good. Yeah. It's amazing.
Time in exciting. Do you have
pride when you look back and you,
you think that you were like,
I mean,
you were one of the real pioneers of
the fastest growing sport the world has
ever seen.
There's never been a time in my lifetime.
There's never been a time where a sport
was introduced and became this gigantic
thing over a matter of a decade,
two decades, and groom viewable.
How fast it grew and grew the
way the UFC has grown under row.
There's nothing like that.
Yeah, it's amazing, dude.
You look back on that and go,
wow, I was, you know, I was
in a special time in life.
I looked back at that and see, yeah,
I love what's happening. I mean,
my life has made by him in me and I just,
I appreciate all the things, you know,
Dana's doing the people who making it big.
And you asked me if I have pride in that.
No,
not really because I don't feel like I can
help. I'm the one who did all this. No,
I don't.
I just feel it was the lucky person to
be the person that was actually there in
the beginning to see what it was like
in meeting when it was banned in states
and every window, whenever someone
heard you or mixed martial arts fighter,
they say, well, see, beat people up for
living all human cockfighting. You know,
back in that day when it was like,
it's frowned upon now. It's like,
it's a cool thing now is
so nice to see that change.
Yeah. It is nice to see that change.
When I first was working, uh,
on a Sitcom,
I was on a sitcom news radio and it
was when I first started doing the post
fight interviews back when
I interviewed you. Yeah.
It's one of the first events I was a
second event I ever worked at. Oh Wow.
And um, I would tell people that I
was going, you know, it was like,
where were we at? Augusta,
Georgia or something like that.
Where did you find Georgia? Yeah. And uh,
I remember telling people that I was
going to go work for the UFC interviewing
fighters after their matches and they'd
looked at me like I was fucking crazy.
Like I was involved in dog fighting
or something. That's what it was like,
like I was involved in porn or something
like that. Something. Yeah. Yeah.
It was like that. Yeah. Now, you
know, people say, what do you do it?
So I do commentary for the
UFC. They go, Ooh, I love that.
My husband,
I,
well, I see that change though. It's
amazing. Yeah. When I, when I see that,
I mean think that I'm a,
you know, I was back in,
I was lucky enough to be a part of that.
That's what I feel. Yeah. Back in the day,
man,
I can only imagine from your position,
so from my position I feel very lucky,
but obviously I'm an outsider
watching and commenting on it.
You were like in the, in the, in
the heat of the battle itself.
Are we on the UFC one one 75 on 25 yeah.
Was In 13 huh?
It's crazy. 13 well not only
that, you were not just at one,
I think the position that you
were at UFC 12 I think the,
in my opinion, the support changed
radically around UFC 12 because of detour.
I think when [inaudible]
entered into the cage,
won that tournament at 19 years old,
at UFC 12 the whole game changed because
you've got to see really high level
striking from a Jujitsu black
belt. And he was, he was light,
but he was fast.
He was a tall total new specimen.
I mean it wasn't the v tour
that fought Randy coture.
I think that veto got too big to like
two months for 204 days just to jacked.
But when he fought,
yeah,
he was like two oh five UFC 12 shredded,
strong explosive fuck Sam.
And we first saw him when he's
first couple of fights, man.
It was just like this was a new athlete,
completely new person that we'd never
seen like a skill level like that as far
as his hand speed, the boxing
combinations that he put together.
Nobody had seen that before.
Yeah. Yeah. You know,
I think that you came at that time,
you came as a sport was just exponentially
and you were starting to see like
real world class athletes.
I think when time,
when we look in the future and
they look back at this era,
like the era between 1993
in 2008, I really, uh,
not only around today,
but still finding it the highest level.
Which brings up another point.
How do you feel about all this
testosterone replacement shit?
Um, I wouldn't do it. If I was
fighting, I wouldn't do it.
Um, I just, uh, I don't know if
I'm for it or against it. I mean,
if some of fighter wants to do it,
I wouldn't have a problem with my,
my opponent did it, you wouldn't have
a problem with your opponent doing it,
but you wouldn't do it. Yeah, I
wouldn't do it. Why wouldn't you do it?
Uh,
I guess I wouldn't know if it would, I
don't know the really real effects to it.
Yeah. And I feel like I can get, I can,
I could get in shape enough
to fight without it. Yeah.
John Fitch said something real interesting
once I talked to him about it and he
said, well, I get older. He said,
I would definitely take
hormone replacement therapy,
but not when I'm fighting.
He said, I want to know that everything
I did, I did because I did it.
I did with my hard work. I did
with my mind, you know, and that,
that was fitches attitude. I thought that
was very admirable. You know, he's a,
he's a real man, you know, Fitch
lives by the sword dies by the sword.
And that attitude that wasn't just
some talk and bullshit. I mean,
he's never been popped for PDS. It
doesn't look like he's doing. Um, yeah,
it looks the same.
He's just a tough motherfucker,
a hard nose wrestler who became a
great mixed martial arts fighter.
But that attitude was, you know, he wanted
to know that he did it all themselves.
We see guys like, you know,
[inaudible] it's a perfect
example. We tore, got on TRT,
got on testosterone replacement
therapy and became this it.
He had this resurgence where you
saw detour from the old days,
the trade Talbmen fight. He was
19 years old. He was a phenom,
but Vituro f a lot of folks don't know
post the Randy coture fight after Randy
coture beat him, he went
into a dark period where he
wasn't very good for awhile.
Soccer rob a, beat him up. A lot of guys
beat him. Alistair Overeem submitted him.
He wasn't the same guy anymore. He lost
his confidence. For whatever reason,
they just,
Dan Henderson beat him and
then he fought in the UFC,
had some good fights,
but it didn't look like the same guy.
Didn't look shred,
got on testosterone replacement and then
all the sudden shot through the fucking
roof and became this motherfucker again.
So I could see both.
See that's uh,
the one on the left is him
pre testosterone in the
one on the right is post
testosterone. I mean I could see, well
this is the way in his photos, by the way,
these guys are completely
dehydrated. They don't look, yeah,
there's sick mean when
you're weighing in your,
your body's completely dried out. They
lose over the, like Vito probably lose 10,
15 pounds easily just to make weight.
But the resurgence
when you saw him fight Michael Bisping,
Luke Rockhold and,
and then the rematch with Dan
Henderson, he was so fucking good. Yeah.
And it makes you wonder like, what is it?
Is that testosterone, is it hard work?
Is that the testosterone that
allows them to work hard?
Like where is a kind of gray area?
Like where do you draw the line?
Would hard work? Definitely Ken just
take talks to it and get good. He, yeah,
it allows you to work harder I think.
Exactly.
Definitely hard work and definitely
talent. And definitely his mind. Yeah.
Confidence.
Yeah.
But that's the thing about
the testosterone and allows
you to get that crazy
gorilla confidence. It changes the
game. Right. And it does. But you know,
the thing is,
you know,
as much as people that are against it
and that kind of cool to see him. Oh,
the of the fights you put out cause
he's on it. That's a good point.
It's like bodybuilding, yet people
like says fuck steroids and stuff.
But when they go to watch body of,
you think the,
they are at the muscle tone
in the size and it's like,
now I might get steroids,
but you go there and you
love the bodybuilding and
I say it's like a give and
take. Yeah. Yeah. Well
bodybuilding without steroids,
it's almost not nonexistent to that. True.
None of those guys are clean. You can't,
you can't get that big. Yeah. And be
clean. Be cleaned for the last year.
Do they even test? I don't know what
the test they do with bodybuilding,
but it's gotta be a Horse Shit.
You know,
if somebody tests positive in
a bodybuilding competition,
it's probably because they pissed off
the promoter and they said to test that
motherfucker for real,
for real.
This time and pride. Did they test you
at all on pride? No. They had a, I mean,
do you get, he didn't know that they had
a clause in the contract. What clause?
They had a clause that
said what to test for. Oh.
And they don't test for star test for, um,
the historic we'd the test for cocaine.
They had a whole list and not only did,
did the steroids did not,
wasn't on that list.
They had a sentence after that saying,
we do not test for steroids. Wow. Yeah.
So it was, that was kind of crazy.
Jason Chambers, you know, Jason Chambers,
he was a show, a human weapon. He fought,
fought MMA a bunch of times. He's a
friend of mine, but he, um, he was, uh,
they were trying to get him to fight in
pride and they want him to fight at one
85. And uh, he was like, but I
weigh one 70. And I was like,
yeah, just to steroids. And
they were telling them to
do steroids and he was like,
what
you were telling him we think you
should because he's a handsome guy.
They were like, we should find that
one 85 and he's like, wait, what?
They wanted him to juice up and look
big and muscular five [inaudible] five.
And he was like, I'm not
wanting any five guys. You know,
I heard a lot of stories about that.
How pride used to like really
bullied the fighters are yeah.
You never know. Days
Kiss my ass man. Really?
It was weird cause I remember mark
cursing saying something about how all
rampage was caught up like one
week before the soccer arba fight.
And if he didn't take it,
they told him something that you'd
never find Japan again or something like
walking him around Linkedin and the
same people that are bullying him
around at the people that I see.
And I can't even imagine that
side of the character from them
do think it's an exaggeration. Like maybe
not getting the full story from them.
Um, I think it's a play of
those to Japanese. Yeah. Oh,
they would know what they can do
either. You like, you know, like a dogs.
Your dogs are mostly medium dark to you.
But then when your
friend takes care of him,
he's pissing all over the place
and barking and shit. You know,
I think it's the same thing. They didn't
know what they can get away with. Yeah.
My friend, uh, Eddie Bravo was over my
house once and he was scared of my dog.
And so my dog attack the cat in front
of them because he knew that Eddie was
scared of the dog.
He's like a head.
He just decided that he's
the boss because the dog,
cause I was just taking a shit.
He freaked out and he starts screaming
and I had a run in and rescue the cat,
but he just decided that Eddie was a punk
because Eddie was scared of him and he
could feel it. So he decided I've been
wanting to bite this fucking cat say way.
But it was a clear example of that
because Eddie Eddie wasn't used to being
around big dogs. He didn't know
how to handle them and you know,
he didn't know that.
You just got to be friendly with the dog
and just establish said he was like, oh,
she was always like this
around the dogs and dogs.
Like this motherfucker's stairs a thing.
I'm running shit here.
But it was a clear example,
but he would never do that in front of me.
Never attack the cat in front of me.
But in front of Eddie, he just decided
that's a good example. I think it's
perfect example. So they bullied.
Those guys are owning these guys.
Would you, do you remember the guy,
the Guy Minster incident with me?
What happened with guy?
He fought Egan and then we had a little
thing in the ring with him. Yeah.
What happened? Well,
he was supposed to, um,
or apparently this is what he said was
he was supposed to call me out in a bad
way. I just retired. Right. And he,
he beat Egan and they told
him to call it to do that.
And they told him that I knew about it.
So six some purchasing bullshit
thing by I not know nothing about it.
So I'm here, I go into the ring
after Egan losers and I'm just going,
you know how you go check on your
fighter? Yeah, I checked on you. Okay,
everything's okay. Guy Walks up
to me and says, it's not personal.
And like, what's not personal?
You'd beat up my brother. Of course,
it's not personal, Hugh,
congratulations. He goes, no,
no, no. What I would have to do,
that's what are you talking about?
And if you see the video,
I'm shaking his hand and he's telling me
the other shake his hand and I'm like,
I don't let go of his hand.
And the weird I'm there were like,
I'm guiding them into the
corner. Like, what do you
mean? What are you going to do?
And he goes, I got to call you
out. I said, well, yeah, you
know, I'm retired. He goes,
yeah, but it's in my contract. I said,
no, no, fuck you. I said, I told him,
if you don't want it, do it. Don't
fucking do it. And it was answered.
I got to do it. And I said, don't
fucking do it if you don't want to do it.
And then I then I realized that the way
pride plays that shit with the creditors
and I realized that, you know, guy
was in this position that, you know,
he really couldn't do anything about.
And so I was like, you know, guys,
not guys deal, you know, guys, not
the bad guy here. And he's like,
so he turned around and he did
it different. No, he didn't.
He didn't be a dick about it. He kind of
went in, she said, uh, something about,
yeah, the, the better fight would have
been with his younger brother and son.
But after that,
it's all in the book too.
But after that it went in the locker
room. And I guess, I dunno, I think I'm,
Gary Glitter's is in my locker room.
Igor was in the locker room.
Those spiders all saw this happened.
But I went on a rampage to calling for
the president of the pride to come in and
see me right now because that's bullshit.
It's purchasing bullshit doesn't work.
Wow. And they wouldn't bring
them. So I would always, you know,
the little staff guys that year,
I was kicking them around and tell him,
get the president and the one of the
guys come in, this guy called Kawasaki,
he was a matchmaker for pride.
And I got on a mid term on the ground
[inaudible] really as a huge thing.
You throw him on the ground
when they grind them all in him.
And then Egan stopped me and then,
and then I told him,
I don't want to see you on a seat,
Morty still the prison.
That's when he was alive.
And of course in the middle of the events
you can think prison just can't come
in. But the vice president comes in
and then he sits me down and he says,
you know, are, we didn't know nothing
will get to the bottom of this.
But according to guy,
that's the guy he talked to.
So it was in the contract that he was
supposed to call you and Meagan the,
and then the president wound up dead and
strangled in like he hung himself on a
fucking shower rod or something.
Yeah, that's a weird one, Huh?
Yeah. Cause I talked to him a week before
that and he, he told me that, um, um,
or if he telling me that he,
he likes the way I fight and he
wants fighters to fight more like me.
I remember him telling you that and he
had a big image about changing the fight
game into a more of aggressive fighters
but wasn't that the death was very
controversial. Yeah. It
was uh, it wasn't suicide.
Yeah.
It didn't seem like,
it seems like it's really hard to do
a chin up from a shower curtain. Yeah,
he did. I mean, how can you, those
rods are not that strong. Yeah.
How's that? How can you even hang
yourself with one loss? Can you,
he did the wrong keys.
He pissed off the wrong people allegedly.
Yeah. Allegedly. Allegedly. Let's leave
it at that. What was it like in the,
in that day,
like dealing with that
aspect of mixed martial arts?
Like it wasn't just mixed martial arts
like it is in the UFC where it's a
business and there's promoters
and there's, you know,
they have an agenda to try to promote
to the fans and try to make money.
But you are dealing with a very intense
organized crime mass spec to it.
What was that like? It was
good. Good. That me? Yeah.
Because of who I was in the record,
the respect that I have from the other
people in Japan, it helped me to it.
So I didn't take me wrong and
everything was straight up.
Did they support Japanese fighters more?
They're like, what are they excited?
Their jar? Yes. They wanted the Japanese
first to win. Guys like Yoshida.
Well back in our day with some more
Sakuraba, some short g Matsui, you know,
dog fighters.
They wanted to promote those guys so they
when they're Takada Takotna was a pro
wrestler. That was an
interesting situation too. Pussy.
Well he was a weird one because he was
one of the few guys that was in a very
obvious fixed fight.
His fight with Mark Coleman.
I pull up that pull up to
Catia versus mark homer.
Cause this is one of the few fights
that I love Mark Coleman and,
but Mark Coleman never admitted
that he, he, he did that.
But I'm sure that that's what happened.
Mark would never lose to icon.
Well not that way either.
I mean the way tap to the heel hook,
it was total pro wrestling. I was like,
no, I don't want to, I don't want to tap.
Tap. Yeah. Yeah, I saw that.
Yeah. It was like a movie.
It was a weird, well TACAN does a fag.
He really, yeah, he's straight up.
He's a fake. What is his background?
He's just a wrestler just but does,
he has marks on him on the street.
I saw him in, in a street incident.
He fagged out.
What happened?
I was in a club and my friend was
a white students who were Ricky.
Ricky Fukuda was, uh, the,
the um, security there.
Sit here and he's like [inaudible]
like he's like punching him in the leg.
You can see his punches.
Coleman sits at all in these punches.
But then when he's not, it's the arm
punches. It's barely, barely punched him.
And this was like back when Coleman
had won the heavyweight Grand Prix,
right leg.
Like what is that about?
These leg punches I come on man.
Mark Holman was not
about little bets if it,
if you did put the leg it'd be heavy
punches. Everything he did was heavy.
He was the godfather or ground and pound.
And so he gets on top of him and he
gives up his leg here and look at this.
I mean he has given up the leg here.
He rolls with a little bit
and he see he is first of all to God is
not even, that's not even a heel hook.
He's not even turning it. I mean
look at that. He taps but that,
that you'll, it was a terrible
healer who wasn't even turning it.
He was just holding it.
He was like,
it didn't like the end
and a 10 step process.
He got to eight and then
just hung on at eight colon.
Had a task screwed up cause
I'm not against purchasing,
but I am against purchasing being done
in the mixed martial arts or ring,
well wasn't that a weird
part of pride with that?
There was a lot of pro wrestling
guys that fought in pride,
but a lot of them legit
guys whose diet butcher.
What was that? Uh, yeah,
that was tough. Top.
Yeah. Very tough. And started
out as a pro wrestler. Yeah.
And what was diet butcher?
What was that thing?
The thing that he always had
on his pants that was his,
like his nickname I think.
Yeah.
But it was the pro wrestling guys.
We're the guys that had
brought a lot of fans,
sort of like Brock Lesnar that
brought a lot of fans to watch fight.
Exactly. Yeah, that's true.
And Takotna was one of those
guys, right? He's a fake. So
what was the, the street situation?
Well, Ricky, Ricky for Kudo is, uh,
I was training with
him at the time and he,
I got him a job at a security
at a club that we hung out at.
So we went to the club and I remember at
the Caudal was there at the club and he
said hi to me and stuff, you know, kind
of like this, like, Hey, what's up?
And that's it. And then I heard there
was like a big writer at the top.
So I'm worried about Ricky
making sure that he's okay.
So I went upstairs to check on
it and it was just huge mob.
They almost like a bs moving across
the street. And I was also who, uh,
who's fighting, I don't know who's
fighting someone, what's going on,
what's going on.
And I noticed some of the guys as a group
called the [inaudible] angle in Japan,
this is like a gang,
they're not yakuza,
but there aren't like the gang of kids
that don't give a fuck and they just get
into the beat people up.
I mean with bats and all kinds of stuff.
But I noticed a couple of them, I knew
who they are. So I went and followed the,
the thing to make sure that
everything was okay with Ricky Rick,
he's not involved in and everything.
And I went there and in the beehive,
when we get to the back,
one guy breaks free and it's a,
it's this a rugby player and he's running
down when his face is all fucked up
already and he's running down the street
and Takata's is running after him and
the kind of cc me and he goes hands and
help, they're going to kill us, help,
help and cause not touched his,
no scratches,
not a bruise on his face. And then
those guys, those guys ran by man,
I'm, I'm still wondering what's
going on. Like whoa, shit, something.
And they ran by me and they caught
up to the rugby guy, tackled them,
these gangsters tackle this rugby guy
had him and started working on again,
kicking him in the face, flower
pot on the head, everything.
And you know what the is
doing. He standing on the
side screaming his lungs off,
stop it, stop it, stop it and not doing
anything about it. And he's fucking huge,
giant dude not grabbing anybody.
He's not physically stopping in.
And he refused to physically get
involved and he sees me coming.
He goes ends and stop, stop. I'll stop
them and like do this your friend. So I,
I click in my head thinking I can,
you know,
I can plague killed two
birds with one stone.
I can help to Catia and I can
help these guys cause this,
this fight was going on for like
eight minutes or it, you know,
and the cops are probably on the way.
So think he's,
you guys got to guys get to get out
of here because the cops are coming.
So I'm grabbing these guys,
throwing them in their van and as
I'm getting another guy, that guy,
that guy's coming out, it
was like ridiculous. Let's,
let's try to get them in the car.
Five him got him in the car, got away.
That got away right when the police
are coming. High speed chase,
they actually got caught up the street,
put in prison and nothing from Takada.
Not a thank you. Not a what's
up? Nothing from Tacoma.
And I've had,
I haven't talked to him since that day.
What does that got to do now? I don't
know. He does some acting. He acts.
That's good. He's probably better
at that than fighting. He was
doing that in the ring was a little
bit of that. Yeah. So yeah, so I,
I have no respect for Takata at all.
And if he comes up to me in
Japan and tried to shake my hand,
I'm not going to shake his hand.
I'll tell before I shake your hand.
You just didn't. You have
somebody who say to me, cause he,
I saved them on that and he's just,
he's such a pussy and you know,
real upsetting for me to see him in the
ring at the pride in looking at Sylvan
sing. Are you a man looking at
rapids? Are you a man? Are you a man?
Sing them like Xojane.
Yeah, he said in Japanese,
he'll sing it like it was
about the tournament, I
think. Oh Man. Are you a man?
So the big theme was being
a man and I think God,
this is the biggest pussy asking
people if they're men. You know,
I remember when he fought Hickson,
Hickson just fucking worked
them. Yeah. That was,
I mean everyone who knew
how shitty Tacarla was new.
That ticks it was going to kick his ass.
But for the Japanese people it was huge
cause Takado was this to be a hero? Yeah,
that was Hixon in the special time
to six and fought in the UFC. Man,
he's one of my biggest regrets.
One of my biggest regrets is a fan is
that Hixon in his prime didn't fight all
the top guys like, oh, I would've
loved to seen Hixon vs Coleman.
I would love to see in
Hixson versus a marked car.
I would have loved to seen
him versus a lot of guys. Man.
It could have been some amazing fights.
I mean we got to see him versus food.
Knocky who was legit for Nakia
was digital was the jet. Yeah.
That was a good fight in Hickson got hurt.
He got a ruptured a orbital fractures.
Orbital in that fight. I swole up and
then he had to finish for Nakia for knock.
He just went to sleep and even tap
out and retired right after that.
I respect the shit out of that.
Yeah,
I mean Hixon got on top of them and a
member he gift wrap that arm across and
he's holding onto his arm and just beat
him down and took his back and choked in
the sleep. That was an intense fight
and it was a real fucking fight. Yeah.
That was for Nike is good.
There was Hickson's last
fight too. Oh, was it? Yeah.
That was coliseum in 2000 2014 years ago.
14 years ago. And Hickson was still
talking about fighting years later when,
um, when fader was a, the
champ of pride, um, they,
they x and wanted a lot of fucking money,
but he's still wanting to fight.
He wanted to fight the best guys, but for
whatever reason, it never happened. Yeah.
Because,
uh,
I went to dinner with Hickson and his
wife and his family and his wife didn't
want him to do it. She didn't want him to
do it. But, uh, if they're separated, no.
Yeah. But Hickson was like, ah, that's
the guy I would want to fight. Yeah.
This is the end.
This is when Hickson was at his best and
I think Hickson was probably around 40
then. Yeah, he was. Yeah.
And he was, you know,
still at his best. And he was big
too for this fight. He got muscular,
probably the most muscular and the
strongest he got for any fight.
Cause Funai was no fucking joke man.
But he got his back and here it is,
got that rear naked on and boom for Naca.
Just did you see him right there?
He's out.
He's just sitting there out fucking cold.
Yeah. Okay. Actually kicks him off.
Okay.
Yeah. And he's not an easy guy to
be choke out to fiction living.
They made it look so easy and we
saw something special. I mean,
when you talk to all the different Jujitsu
practitioners that have trained picks
and they, none of them come
away and go, yeah, yeah,
it's a lot of hype and none of
them, no, not a single one. Yeah.
Every single one would talk about
Hixon saying he's the best. Yeah.
Unbelievable. Yeah. You know, I,
I got to hang out with them one
night and talk positions with them.
And strategy and stuff like
that. Fascinating. Fascinating.
Fascinating. Watching a breakdown
fights too. I mean, we did tell him,
watching him fight,
watching them watch fights with top guys
like Mario Sperry and stuff like that,
but just showing all
the holes in their game,
really showing all the things
they're doing wrong. Yeah.
Six set up an elite of the elites,
you know,
I would've loved to got a chance
to roll with him, man. I got to,
but I was a white belt,
so yeah, everyone asks me,
did you get to road weeks of a yeah,
kind of. Yeah. Well, no you don't.
He's saying I was a white belt
and he was, he was, uh, you know,
his kicks in and of course she's not
going to go hard on the white belt,
so he kind of just roll with
us and beat us up and yeah.
So I didn't really get to feel
Hixson Hixson so I actually
in a way, kind of, no,
not really. I did, but no, not really.
Yeah. Yeah. Even if I did, it would,
might as well be me being a white belt.
It's the same thing.
That's what's really crazy. It's like I
try to tell people like there's a law,
there's levels of black belt,
like it could be a black belt and
then you roll it Marcello Garcia,
and you could treat it like a white belt.
It's you're still going to get strangled.
Yeah. There's guys that are just,
he lines up all the black belts in
Brazil and submit some will Hixon. Yeah,
so I heard he'd used to do every year,
I don't know about now,
but back in the day.
Yeah.
He used to go to Brazil and line up
all the black belts and actually submit
everyone one by one. Yeah,
he used to do that for sure.
He's got back problems now
though. Oh really? Yeah. He
looks good though, yet. Oh,
he's works out still and still
does yoga and he surfs a lot,
but he can't really train anymore.
It doesn't do Jujitsu. Yeah.
Crone was on the podcast and he said
that his dad has something like seven
herniated discs.
Yeah.
Does the issue, would you just two
guys, same thing with Brown. Yeah.
Ricardo Laborio. He's got like
seven herniated disc too. Yeah.
All of them are holding out, sticking in
world spots of his body. Like Ricardo,
when you sit him see him standing there,
he's like, he's always in pain. Really?
He never fought MMA. Yeah,
he did. He did. Yeah.
Ricardo I think had one or two MMA
fights and looked fucking great.
You want me to see it? Won't pull it off.
Ricardo Laborio I remember seeing him,
uh,
he did you doing Jujitsu seminars?
I would thought this guy would
be so good in him and me.
He's a fucking beast is back
in the day, man. He was, yeah,
he had one fight and it was a
draw one fight. He fought me.
Noah [inaudible] Noah. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
And
he just defended a lot.
Yeah, I think so. Yeah.
And it just a three round fight
went to a draw and that's it.
I Dunno. I Dunno. I don't
remember much of that fight,
but I just remember that at the time
a lot of people put him in the same
category as Hickson and he's like,
look,
we're caught and this is 2001 he had
that fight and the Barrio was very,
very highly respected
amongst Jujitsu guys.
Like a lot of the guys that roll with
them. So he was just unbelievably good,
very tactical, very strong
technicals, bigs to solid guy.
If you saw him back in the Minoa,
he, he's fucking pull that fight up.
Ricardo laborio versus Minoa.
Yeah.
You could see how he looked at the
time. Oh, he's in incredible shape,
but he's got a bunch of back problems
too, man. Wow. Really? Yeah. Yep.
Well he's still rose with all those guys.
You know,
he's the Co founder and the
head instructor at American
top team. So you know,
he's always there on a regular basis,
but he's still rolls with all those guys.
Wow. I think they had a, a,
a super fight of grappling Superfight
planned between him and Mario Sperry,
but I don't know if that's
still going to take place.
But I had his back problems.
Well, I don't know.
I think he was still going to do
it even despite his back problems.
How is Marsh Berry Day?
It's a good question.
I mean he was the head coach of the black
zillions and then for whatever reason
they had a falling out and he,
he wound up leaving the black zillions.
I Dunno what the fuck happened.
So I don't know where he is now.
But he was an interesting, uh,
he was an interesting coach.
They cleaned the Zanda they call
them, does that machines and yeah, uh,
when I was first starting out,
I started out at crossings
place in 1996. And, um,
Mario Sperry was there and Myra Sperry
was talking about how he got really good
at triangles by making his girlfriend
sit in his guard and he would just slap a
triangle on, on each side over
and over again. And she's like,
I don't want to do this anymore.
It's like,
shut up and just catch triangular
over and over and over again.
And he's just Kinda fucked up.
But he used her as a grappling dummies.
Yeah. Here it is right here. Ricardo
Laboriel and Manila shaved his head.
That's right.
Yeah.
This is way back in the day in 2001
and Minoa still fucking fighting.
Minoa is still going at it, but
no, it was fun. A lot of guys, man,
huge bias as the big circus thing,
uh,
attacking each other here.
It's interesting how there was a lot
of dudes that were heavy favorites,
like going into MMA and everybody
thought that Bob, these,
this is going to be the next motherfucker
in MMA and like solid Libero,
solid Houbara. A lot of people thought
like he was going to be the next Hickson.
He's going to go into MMA and dominate
cause he was so good at Jujitsu,
but it never quite panned
out. You know, that's the end.
Even in Japan, uh, the judo
guy said go into it. Yeah. She
was one of the most successful,
but there was one after him that came
out. He, Hey, he keef on it here.
I think he trained in Vegas.
Which guy? What's his name?
He was like a gold medalist.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I know he lost to Yoshida later.
He came back in Japan in font.
She didn't last, but not, not Maura. Um
hmm.
Big Boy man. Let me see. I'll
pull up your sheet as career.
And he was raw aggressive in judo too.
That's why they thought he was
going to be the next big thing.
Nakamura now Nakamura, he
lost too. He lost he sheet.
Um, he's a he fought an Astra, Huh?
No, it wasn't Ogawa. Oh God. I not
going out ago. It's new kid man.
He didn't really do much, but
he was uh, he was up here.
I think he traded with Baroni
to, hmm. I Dunno. I'm looking
at his record. I forget.
Is She, is she, I think, Oh,
is she? Yeah, he, she is, um,
that's where I said till she is she, yeah,
that was the, in Japan that was like,
he was going to be the next huge
MMA guy, but never pans out. Well,
he fought him too young.
He was just starting to get in
the MFS too many striking skills.
I remember Yoshida fought tank Abbott
and head kicked him. Remember that? Yeah.
Shana was pretty good.
Strike through don with Silva too.
It's a strong mother fucker, man.
He was a strong mother fucker. Yeah,
he sent some good fights. I was supposed
to be like the next big thing in Japan.
Them in May, but never turned
out. Yeah. Uh, is she, uh,
I think, I think that was
pretty cool in the states.
I think he's training in the states
though, you know? Yeah. No, I think he is.
He's a, I think he still has a,
he's still fighting MMA. Yeah.
I think he's still fighting. Yeah. Well
he fought in April. He fought, he won.
He beat, filled the freeze
fill the freeze. Who um,
who fought in the UFC and before
that he beat Fujita in 2013.
I didn't know Fujita was still
fighting. Oh, I didn't know that either.
He fought in the A in Gnocchi.
A New Year's card. The
boom buy a car. Okay. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. And before
that it'd be Jeff Manson.
He's won a bunch of fights
and already moved here too.
He's trying to get residency. Oh really?
Cause a Japan judo won't take them back.
Oh, I see. Flight doodle. He beat
Tim Silvia. He Beats Sean McCorkle.
He be Kerry shawl. He then he beat
Pedro his though Clayton Jones,
Jeff Monson Fujita and filled the freeze.
Those are all he's opponents,
so he's still working at it. You know,
he looked at his first fight in MMA.
That ever was Yoshida. Yeah.
Yeah, she does. Was just too
much of it. Too much. Yeah.
Too much of a jump seat.
It was already adapted to MMA.
Is that a big part of fighting?
Like that's something that you see in
boxing that I don't necessarily think you
see in MMA as much as we're a
fighter is brought up correctly.
Like they give them tests that
they can win and then you know,
they test them and then they graduate
for those tests in the UFC. No, right.
Not as much. There's a lot of guys
get fed to the dogs, like real early.
I mean like the Q f and stuff.
Then you really gotta be good to
make it into that. Huh? The what?
The two F that's house. Oh,
the Tuf the ultimate fighter.
But I think that you're seeing now,
like I watch the ultimate fighter.
Sometimes you see guys
gas out really quick,
you see kind of low level
striking and Jujitsu.
I think the talent pool is kind of dry
in a lot of ways in every now and then a
new guy comes up like a Uriah hall who,
uh,
who got on the ultimate fighter and
just knocking everybody out and look
sensational.
And you saw like real talent in
that guy and the guy who, uh,
I mean, Dillashaw came from tough,
you know, and now he's a champion. Um,
just,
I mean there's guys that have come from
the ultimate fighter who just won the
tough to this, the silver
sewn in one, that ball,
he had no hair. Um, yeah,
that guy was good, Huh? Yeah.
I'm trying to remember his
name. Yeah, I forget his name.
There's so many of them now.
It's almost impossible to Calvin
gas alum who beat Uriah Hall,
who's another super fucking
talented guy who came from that.
But for every one of those guys,
there's like 10 guys that are just,
they're just not at the same level.
They're not because it's such a new sport.
[inaudible] has been around for
ages and so many boxes that there,
when you really think about it, high
level MMA is only 15 years old, you know,
really ab it.
Like we said,
Vito Belfort 97 so it's a little
bit a little bit older than that,
but it's just so fucking crazy sport man
exploding growing thing right in front
of us. Can Imagine. I wonder what's
going to be like in 10 years though.
I can only,
I think when we look back at history,
they look at the history and the growth
of mixed martial arts of martial arts
period.
They'll,
they'll see that martial arts grew more
in 20 years than it did in 20,000 years.
It exploded out of nowhere and they
really figured out what works and what
doesn't work. But you know
what tripped me out is when a,
when I first went to watch the UFC and
the Vegas and I saw the fighters pictures
on the billboards is I couldn't believe
that. It's weird, right? I mean,
back in the day when
I used to go to Vegas,
we see like Donna Summers and
Kenny Rogers doing a concert,
but man,
the MMA fighters up on the billboards.
It's like a total different level. Yeah,
it's wild, isn't it? Yeah. I love it.
It's great. I mean, the bigger Amy May
gets, the better it is for me, you know,
for sure. What do you plan on
doing in the future now? I mean,
you're making your bracelets and a, if
people want to buy those, by the way,
where can they get dusty for.com?
The book also is available so that again,
destiny forever, destiny
forever.com. Yeah. Um, yeah,
making bracelets.
Uh,
I'm doing the relief work is always going
to continue up north and I'm writing
another book.
Second,
second part. Do you think that you're
going to be involved in martial arts?
Um, I'm not someone that's going to
try and promote or someone that's true,
going to try and get involved.
But if there's anything that I can
do like it when people asked me to do
seminars, so to come and be involved
in something, I'm more than willingly.
You know, there's some kind of big
tournament of the, the Uga, right?
The underground forum.
What is it as a tournament?
He has to have it though to have a
little little, um, like an amateur fight.
Really? Yeah. I'm, I'm, I'm trying
to help with that too. Okay.
Pulls two winners like that, you know?
Oh, that's cool. Nice. I mean they given,
even like when Dana comes to Japan,
I always offered him if
he ever needs my help,
if he needs any help with anything
up there now that's awesome.
While he's willing to help but to
be involved in that way, for sure.
But what about like running a
school, running a gym? Again,
teaching fighters did that for
quite a while. Yeah. I, I'm not,
I haven't been doing that actively
at my gyms. I've been doing seminars.
I just did one in New Zealand. I just
sweat and worked with the guys at a,
in Portland at fisticuffs.
Yes. Cool. Yeah.
So I'm doing that kind of stuff.
And I think I've,
I still have a lot to offer
to the fighters, but sure.
On about doing it every day
and on teaching every day
and being stuck at a gym
at that, you know, 95 or even
like a every day at six to eight,
you're going to teach it.
I got to teach a class on,
I don't know if I will ever be able
to live in myself to that, but yeah,
my life's exciting man. Traveled
all over trouble all over the world.
When you do these
seminars and uh, you, um,
you sit down with young fighters,
how much of the seminar has to do
with mindset and how much the seminar?
Half of it? Yeah, so what
I do is, um, for me, I,
I have the techniques to have on
the ground in real basic techniques,
stuff that worked.
Um,
I think I have more to offer
into the mindset. Yeah.
So mine is always like a
seminar. Slash. Philosophy.
So I will talk and then I'll show a
technique and then I'll ask him a question
and then I'll,
and you know like,
like one thing I asked
them that the New Zealand,
when I went to New Zealand did one in
New Zealand. I asked him, you know,
I asked him, well why do, why do fighters
tap? Like if I asked you that you why,
why do fighters tab? Because
they're afraid of injury. Yeah.
And so they're essentially,
they've made a decision,
I would rather not get my arm broken
and just admit defeat. That's,
that's in the lines of it.
But basically where a fighter taps is
because he's anticipating what he thinks
is going to happen. It's an anticipation
of what you think is going to happen.
And that's why fighters tab,
you're anticipating your arm breaking,
you're anticipating going asleep.
And a lot of,
a lot of times people that the spectators
think it's because of pain because it
hurts. But a lot of
times it is a, you know,
you don't harm partners and really hurt.
I mean, you can feel like I, you know,
y'all fuck my arm, my ligaments are going
to start stretching off. Fuck know. But
it's not to that pain, that pain
level where you like how far I get.
So sorry I got a tap. You know that
you've even talks, it's not like you,
you'd know it's this anticipating
what's going to happen, you know,
and I kind of develop on that kind of
stuff. Like you know that kind of mindset.
Yeah.
That there's a brief window where you can
pull victory out of the jaws of defeat
by not having the mindset that
it's, it's, it's a focus here.
How many of those moments happen where
a fighter like has that that door opens
and either you can tap or you can push
forward and occasionally the guys put
forward and wind up winning doesn't some
of that, that's that gray area, right?
That's that weird moment that do or die
moment that you feel like with the Jason
High type situation that the fighters
aren't allowed to express and push through
it. Then I'll have to show how
tough they really are. Yeah.
When guys talk to you
in seminars you have,
did they talk about specific fights and
ask you about specific moments in your
career? Like what would one comes
up that you are fight come out?
Of course right before it comes up a lot.
What about the Randy fight?
The Rodney fight, I'm not that much, but
it's always the one that's mentioned.
Yeah, it was a big victory. Yeah.
That was a huge victory for me. Yeah,
that's like my claim to fame kind of,
you know, that kind of, that kind of put,
you know, what was good about that was
that that victory made people accept that,
okay,
Anson is good and after I they need to
prove that I was good by getting wins.
So, so it kind of gave me that
window to fight with my heart.
Know that I didn't need to pull out
the winds anymore, but back in the day.
But unless you pull out certain wins
you like, he's just a tough guy. Well,
that's a crazy thing about
you is not just your approach,
but your openness in
discussing that approach.
The fact that you weren't necessarily
pursuing wins as much as you were trying
to find out about yourself.
That sounds like, you know,
that sounds like something that someone
would write about someone in a movie.
And I mean like you wanted a white
about some crazy warrior and a movie.
You know, I'm not about
victory. I'm about, you know,
finding out the answers for myself.
Who am I as a man?
But that is really how you lived. Yeah.
And at the time it was stupid, but not,
no, but it's not. You say
at the time it was stupid.
I don't necessarily think it was,
it's definitely not stupid.
Why didn't you do this?
She could have won the fight,
but as a decision that you made the same
way Diego Sanchez makes those decisions
in a fight.
The difference being is I think
Diego is just hardwired that way.
You know? I mean, maybe
you wore too in a sense,
but those things and those moments
define you in a lot of ways.
There's a lot of fighters from that era.
But when people talk about
guys with a ferocious mindset,
you're one of the ones
that always comes up.
And that's one of the reasons why
people want to see you at a seminar.
I want to talk to you,
want to hear you on this podcast.
You know the funny thing about that
is that I had so many fears too.
But you're open about that.
And like we talked about before,
you embrace those fears.
You, you face them head on.
And that's one of the fascinating things
about you is that you were so willing
to discuss it, but honestly, no
fake tough guy. Bullshit, nothing.
No bullshit man. No bullshit. Yeah.
Even the book is all real names, man.
Real incidents. Exactly as, as men.
And I always live my life thinking that,
you know,
if I get punished for something that
I've done and I did it and they say the
right thing and I get punished for it,
then let it be because that's
what's supposed to happen.
So if I get into trouble with stuff
that I wrote in the book is I'm not
bullshitting. I'm not talking shit
about nobody. I'm not bullshitting,
I'm not exaggerating.
I'm just telling things as it is and if
I'm going to get in trouble for that,
then it was meant to be. Where can
people get stuck? Man? Same thing.
Destiny forever. It's on Amazon.
Okay. Amazon and it's live as a man.
Dies a man.
Become a man and get an
order@yourdestinyfor.com Anson.
Another fucking awesome podcast. Great
time brother. Thanks for doing it again.
Anytime you're in town,
let me know and I'll be
texting you whenever I let
you know whenever I'm in town,
anytime, man. And I enjoyed it. I
always do. All right. Thank you brother.
All right man. All right folks.
That's it. We'll be back next week.
Um, um, I'm off for the rest of the week.
I'm going to be in Canada this weekend.
Um, you could check Joe
rogan.net for the dates.
We're going to be in
Lloydminster tomorrow night.
I'm with Tony Hinchcliffe and Brian Cowen.
And then we're at the Orpheum in Vancouver
on the no Thursday night Lloydminster,
which is tomorrow night. And then
Friday night, the Orpheum in Vancouver.
Uh,
thanks to stamps.com go to stamps.com
entering the code word j r e for your
special offer and thanks to
legal zoom. Uh, use the curve,
the referral code,
rogan@checkoutforsomesavingsatlegalzoomandusethatsamecodeforonat.com
to save
10%
off any and all supplements.
Uh,
lots of crazy podcast guests coming
up next week. Ladies and gentlemen,
I got a lot of shit coming for you.
Um, got Dan savage is coming up.
Uh, he will be here on the 16th. Uh,
Joey Diaz going to be here on the 18th.
Duke Roufus on the 19th.
Lots of Shit happen and folks, so we'll
talk soon. Much love everybody. Take care.
What's up?