Hello Freak bitches.
I want queefs.
I don't break for queefs.
You don't like,
you're fucking going and you hear that
and they sort of want to stop fucking
right for it to be there.
That's like I'm driving on the highway
and someone goes,
hey,
okay.
Let me ask you this.
Do you eat pussy when they're on their
period?
Uh,
I used to,
but as I got older,
no.
Hmm.
I don't give a fuck.
I used to fuck chicks with Shane a lot.
And how dare you?
We would accidentally touch dicks
sometimes.
Like one time I was just like the
operation game.
I thought it was fucking a girl in her
ass and it went into her cunt and
actually went into his condom inside.
I'm looking down at her how looses his
cotton?
What is it?
A fucking trash bag.
I was harder than making sense.
At least resistance.
So I'm looking down at it,
man.
I swear to God I'm got inside his
condom.
Yup.
So using the condom ever believes me.
But this container so that you guys
could rub dicks together.
But that wasn't the plan.
But I was,
I was like,
I'm fucking this bitch his ass.
And I looked down and I see an asshole
and I'm like,
how many assholes does this woman that
I'm in?
At least one of them.
And then I reached down and I feel a
condom.
How drunk were you guys?
Not Drunk at all.
Why did you not know where you're
putting your Dick?
Don't you look?
What are you looking at?
You,
you're fucking,
you're on the ass.
You're pushing and pushing and pushing
and then you sort of feel,
and then it slipped.
Yeah.
So you go,
oh,
that must have gone in the hole.
The one that was pushing again,
girl doing the whole time.
Calling
like Donald Sutherland in invasion of
the body snatchers.
Yeah.
Well she's got to Dixon in Vaginas.
She's fucking,
oh,
huster listen,
she was from Malta.
I hate to wrap this up on a,
on a high note like that,
but we're out of time story.
So anyway,
I've,
I've reached down,
I go,
I didn't have a condom on,
I have a condom on and then I pulled out
and I busted not on her butt.
And uh,
if people go,
but you touched a dick,
but when you're doing that kind of
stuff,
it's like two mobsters digging a hole
for a body and their shovels clink.
Like you don't fucking know
where you're at work.
Right.
I understand.
Yeah.
I still,
I want him to get you wrap that up nice
and tight.
Do you know I had a revelation the other
day when it came to movies?
Uh,
I went to see the Martian.
It was pretty good.
Interesting.
But the problem is,
the problem with that movie is,
you know he's going to live,
you know,
he's gonna make it so it's like someone
gave you a spoiler alert before you even
got to the movie.
It's like,
oh,
is he going to die on Mars?
Am I paying money to watch two hours of
him and he's going to die on Mars?
Get the fuck out of here.
Everybody knows he's not going to die on
Mars.
But the revelation was there's,
there's too many movies and like even
really awesome movies like sicario
supposed to be pretty bad ass.
We couldn't,
that's the new Benicio Del Toro movie.
It's supposed to be pretty bad ass,
but we couldn't get a ticket to that
one.
Um,
in time,
uh,
we,
we were sold out so we went with the
Martian.
Um,
but the point is these movies never
stop.
Every week there's new ones and they
don't go away.
Like the old ones don't stop being
around like you can go watch them too.
It's like there's too many of them.
Like I was thinking about all the
different movies just on itunes and
Netflix and I was scrolling through them
and I started thinking like,
this is a,
this is a neverending equation.
Like it just keeps getting tacked onto
it.
We live in the epicenter of where it's
created.
It's all around here and it's,
it's very strange because the body of
work just never stops.
Like he used to be when I was a kid.
When a good movie came out,
you would go to see that fucking movie.
Like Star Wars.
I saw star wars 13 times and I was in
nothing compared to the real geeks.
Like there's,
there was like,
it was a big deal back then to see how
many times you could see a movie.
Like you couldn't run a movie long
enough to see for someone to see it 13
times now because there's new ones,
there's new ones come in.
We got to get this fucking piece of shit
out of the theater.
You would never have a movie like star
wars.
It played over and over and over and
over and over and over again.
And if star wars came out today,
people would shit right in its mouth.
It's,
it's weird.
That is to me in my childhood,
one of the greatest movies of all time
when I was a kid and that movie came
out,
I remember when Obi wan Kenobi was
talking to Luke Skywalker and,
uh,
they were in the sand.
I was like,
this is the greatest thing I've ever
seen in my life.
This is amazing.
This guy's in space and he's got an Obi
wan Kenobi is going to teach them how to
be a jet.
I,
ah,
this is the greatest movie ever.
I remember it couldn't have been more
perfect.
I remember seeing that movie and
thinking,
this movie is fucking perfect.
Now you go watch and you're like,
oh my God,
it's such a clunky Turd.
It's clunky.
The special effects look like shit.
Why is Darth vader evil?
Does he,
doesn't,
does not even a reason why he's evil.
He's just evil.
What does he get when he takes over the
world is even get pussy is even going to
get any pussy in space.
He know he's just building some giant
star that can blow up planets.
Really?
This is so dumb.
Like it's so dumb.
Oh,
uses the dark side.
not the dark side.
It's so fucking dumb.
And it's puppets.
It's like kermit the frog and the
skywalker.
But it's day like if you judge it in the
context of its day,
it's one of the all time classic films.
It's just,
there's so many more now and they're
better.
They say you are a fighter.
Power example,
you got to opponent,
but this time the opponent is yourself.
Mm.
And,
uh,
and you know it from the inside and you
feel it from the inside and it makes you
happy.
It makes you strong and makes you
healthy.
And this is what we have lost from the
nature and now it's back.
So,
so in a sense,
what you've done is you tapped into
something extremely primal by dealing
with one of the most primal elements of
all,
which is cold.
Yes.
So the cold,
like the,
the,
in the vice documentary,
I thought that was really fascinating.
You said cold is your God.
Yes it is.
Yeah.
If I had a teach,
I've never had a teacher.
That's it.
That's amazing.
I know.
Goudreau or mentor or Sifu or anything
like that.
The cold.
That's my teacher.
That's my God.
I've been dodging the colts and tells a
little kid.
It's amazing.
You just felt compelled to jump into
that.
Yes,
absolutely.
And what was,
when you were saying this to people,
when you're 31 years old and you're
telling people I can control my immune
system,
they,
they must've been like,
you're out of your fucking mind.
Look at this guys jumping in the
freezing water and he says he can
control his immune system.
How did you convince people to the point
that you got actual scientists to
measure your blood?
Do legitimate scientific studies on you?
Like what was it your accomplishments
like you went for people that don't know
you,
you did a bunch of really unbelievable
tasks.
You,
you climbed everest in your shorts.
Um,
did you have shoes on when you climbed
everest?
Yes,
I had to with spikes,
spikes,
climbing.
Slippery,
right?
Add a random Americans.
No showed on that.
I think I go buy clothes.
It's insane because it's like you are
not challenging,
uh,
nature you can go up with,
with their car as well.
And then you go up Everest,
right?
Anything artificial you use in nature
doesn't make you having the right
connection with nature.
And what I wanted to challenge in all
the challenges I did,
like marathons beyond the polar circle
in midwinter and short,
but also in the heat of the desert
without drinking or hanging by one
finger on,
I want to half Columbia,
like a mile and up in the air.
What it in winter time,
you hung up by one finger.
A mile up in the air.
Yes.
Where was this alternate Holland's her
between two hot air balloons and then
climbing between them.
And then there was a,
you know,
a,
a thing,
uh,
a device I could kind of put it on with
one finger.
Yes.
How long has your hanger for a 25
seconds.
Five seconds with one finger.
And in winter time,
winter time,
you know,
you lose control when the blood becomes
cold or in the hands you lose control.
So that was the challenge.
It's mind over matter.
And I wanted to show that in all the
challenges,
the adaptive power of ours is enormous.
But as we are not stimulating or using
that anymore,
you get a neglected body and become sick
or half in its potency.
And so very logic.
So the,
the powers that our body has,
the untapped power is that we probably
had for millennia dealing with the cold,
dealing with the heat,
dealing with adversity,
dealing with struggle.
All those powers are not being tapped
into.
So because of that,
the body just atrophies.
And we don't,
it doesn't know what to do like
yourself.
Exactly.
Yeah.