[inaudible] this episode of the podcast.
See, didn't say it already
took my Alpha brain. I'm Brody,
Steve and I took on the Brody Stevens,
a cadence.
A lot of people already
took my Alpha brain.
Eight one eight I need to hang around
him while I used to be able to do a good
Brody imitation,
but it's gotten very generic.
Now I've lost the tone. You know I
still have Joe D as in my arsenal,
but I've lost the Brody tone. I need
to be around him. I need to see him.
I need to feel him.
This episode is brought
to you by Squarespace and
Squarespace is the all in one
platform that makes it fast and easy to
create your own professional website.
Yes. You the average person,
the Sam Tripoli's of the world,
the Joe Rogan's the world. Brian Redman
is far more computer savvy than us.
He can actually,
he can actually create a real website.
He knows co we are not capable of that.
I'm sure Jamie can do that as well. Me,
not so much. I'll show you how to
throw a sidekick. I can't do nothing.
I came do sidekick, but you can
do Squarespace, Sam, Tripoli.
You can do it. You could set
up a fucking online store son.
I have faith in you and it's
all done through a simple,
easy drop and drag interface.
Just like if you are attaching an email
to your Facebook page or a picture,
you know, cutting and pasting and email,
posting a picture, posting a video,
you know how to do that on Twitter.
If you can do that,
you can make your own fucking
website and it can be awesome.
It can be awesome with a full
online store, sand triplet,
sell copies online of your new CD
that came out motherfucking today,
Sam Tripoli. What's it called? Believe
in yourself. I liked that message.
This message can all be relayed through
squarespace.com and if you go to
squarespace.com they have 20 pour,
24 20 polo seven. They have 24,
seven support, 24, seven
support. Um, and uh,
as I said,
simple drag and drop interface
and websites that work
on everything had to work
on your iPad. It'll work on a
android device, an android tablet,
or work on Unix. If you're a one of those
fucking Weirdos who had cysts on Unix.
By the way, we need you. We need
you on our team. We need Unix.
All the people that are those coder guys,
we're so glad that they're not evil.
You know when you think about it like
the coder guys that bring down shit,
find out fucking creepy shit that
people have been up to 100% I totally,
we need them out there fighting the fight.
The dictators in check.
What is foreign and abroad?
The people suppressing the masses.
We need those motherfuckers don't
understand unix cause those evil military
dudes, they don't know they're up to
no good. We need the rebel forces.
You don't know Unix.
Anyway,
go to squarespace.com and use the code
word Joe for a free trial and 10% off
your first purchase.
Go there and also
check out the logo creator.
Good.
Squarespace has it so you can make a
clean and simple logo design for yourself
in minutes. I think we need a naughty
show logo. Brian, you're naughty.
Show logo. Well, I do the honor
commercial. All right, well John, Brian,
Brian's going to do that just to show
you how to make a punch drunk or a sports
one. Fuck yeah, you could do that too.
Well you guys should probably pay him
now because you now you're fucking $5
quest and tried to get
her to work. Um, anyway.
squarespace.com use the code word Joe.
Save yourself some mother fucking money.
Yeah. We're also brought to you
by [inaudible] dot com that is,
oh and and I t on it is a website where
you can buy shit that can make things
better. What do I mean
by that? What on it is,
is what we call a human
optimization website.
And what we sell is shit like Alpha brain,
which does work.
How to prove it. Show I took one, I took
four, I take four. I'm fucking crazy.
I'm accessive cause she got a brain.
You got a big brain. I feel like, um,
there's nothing in their toxic,
I'm going to let this pitch right.
What are you afraid of?
Not Afraid of much,
but I'm definitely not afraid to take it.
For Alpha brains for a show,
what is Alpha brain?
Alpha brain is a nootropic and
if you don't know what neutral,
because I suggest you Google it.
Google all the people that say the
vitamins dealt worked. Goodall, Google,
all the people that say
nootropics do work vitamins,
new tropics nutrition.
There's so many contradicting
opinions when it comes to um,
uh, health and wellness. I am no expert.
I have talked to a fuck load of experts
though and we've been very fortunate to
have some experts on the podcast exports
like a doctor, Rhonda Patrick, uh,
experts that actually
understand nutrition.
So it's a very complicated
thing and there's a lot of like,
you'll real read on one website.
This is going to kill you.
And then another website,
this is essential.
One website says this prevents
cancer. Um, believe in yourself.
Logos being created right now while
we're doing this at hot males,
like what am I, yeah, it's
the black hotmail. Anyway,
uh,
on it.com we sell 'em all sorts of various
supplements as well as strength and
conditioning equipment.
All sorts of shit that you can use to
benefit your life are our idea behind
doing this show is what's the stuff that
I use that I feel makes my life work
better? Like what's the things
that make my body work better?
What's the things that make my mind work
better? And Aubrey and I have a Servo.
The similar idea about that. The
similar, a similar opinion. You know,
both of us are fascinated
by, um, the latest trends and
strength and conditioning.
Both of us. This is distracting
me. What does the tea,
what are the people see right
now? They see a logo. Yeah. Okay.
That is not a fucking commercial
jackass. You confusing. Fuck.
That's the problem, right? You distract,
distract me. There's just no way for
me to do a logo at the same time. No,
don't do it. Leave on it.com. Just
leave this little thing scrolling it.
Can you do all that shit off
screen? Is that possible? Yeah.
It's not that it has to. Oh Wow. Punched
rock's going to have to wait. That's fine.
I'm good with that.
On [inaudible] dot com go, go there. O, n,
n I t used the Codeword Rogan save
10% off any and all supplements.
Everything is explained. They're far
better than I can explain to you. Um,
but one thing I will say is
that on it has a 100% 30 pill,
90 day money back guarantee on all the
controversial shit like shroom tech sport
or Alpha brain.
Reason being is people are justifiably
skeptical about things that claim to, uh,
enhance cognitive function or things
that claim to give you more endurance.
He should be skeptical. There's
a lot of bunk shit out there. Um,
what we had on and have done is
taken what we believe is the law,
the best body of research
that explains you supplements,
put it up under research.
And we've also done our own tests on
our own tests on Alpha brain and ongoing
other tests on the other various
supplements that we have.
But all of them are backed by science
and that science is all researched with
references all uh, under
the, the research tab, uh,
whether it's for Alpha brain or for
any of the other supplements, there's,
if you don't think they
work and you try him,
just say this is bullshit and you get
your money back. It's that simple.
You don't even have to return the product.
No one's trying to rip you off just
trying to sell you shit that I use.
Your body is made out of food and
vitamins are in food and we've isolated
certain, not we obviously
not me, I'm retarded.
But they have isolated certain things
in vitamins that can enhance various,
various parts of your life,
whether it's your endurance or whether
it's cognitive function. All of it. Again,
explained that on it. O, n,
n I t use the Codeword Rogan and
save 10% off any and all supplements.
Oh, that's, wow. That's a website.
It's an amazingly designed
websites. Pretty Nice. Well,
it's cool when you scroll
down, it moves. Yeah.
But what's really dope is
that it's all made in house.
Ah, the, the honor people that
work in the actual studio itself,
Arby's put together this amazing
crew of talented people. So yeah,
it's all like just very bad ass. Oh, it's
like one of the best company websites.
Our, they're, they're amazing. It's
guys kick kickass. They're creative too.
It's cool. Yeah, it's pretty cool. Yeah,
it's really dope. Anyway, on a.com oh,
went in our tea. That's
it. Saps your bully. Is He?
Hello? Chuck. Chuck. Chuck.
Brian does know how to press play
the Joe Rogan.
He fingered her job.
Joe Rogan podcast by night.
All Day.
We're full Sam Tripoli. Boom,
back in the saddle. Powerful.
Which Sam Tripoli and with a brand
new comedy CD I brought one for.
I know
some people don't even have CD players
anymore, but uh, I bought it for you.
This our work by my buddy and uh,
and it's called, you can do this,
it's called believe in yourself.
It was either that,
it's either that or I was
going to call it shady shit,
but I didn't think iTunes would let
me put that up. So it's good. Yeah.
Well kind of a, if you listen to the
album, you get why I call it that.
So it's like fun. Well I have no your
materials. So I would agree with that.
Like thematically sort of a,
a fun, having fun with it.
It just goes against the grain.
It's the feedback that people have
already listened to it really love it.
And I'm, you know, I haven't
put out a CD for a while.
So I was like really excited to put this
whole group of hour of power together.
And I did at the Edmonton comedy strip,
which is one of my favorite clubs to
play because it's literally the only club
where I got off stage and two
separate times the owners one, uh,
Tammy one, Rick Bronson would pull
me aside and literally go, dude,
can you work dirtier? And I go, what? They
go, we'd really like you to work dirtier.
And I'm like, are you crazy? So
ridiculous. So then I go up and say,
I'm just getting filthy for the
sake of getting filthy. And uh,
but it's one of the grays
clubs. And I said, you know,
this would be great place to do
CD. So I decided to do it. They're,
they're maniacs up there and
now they're at Minton's crazy.
Well they're living in a place,
you know,
it gets 50 fucking below zero in the
winter there and those are hardy folk and
everyone's got cash cause
they're fracking. Oh yeah.
They're all fracking up there.
It's their unemployment is like 0.0001%.
Like they're giving like 12 year olds
shops because there's not enough people.
None of people that go around
for all the jobs. Well it's uh,
it's interesting too because people
that live in that kind of environment,
if you could survive that kind of a
winter and you stay job or no job,
if you don't fucking plot and escape a
year, you're a different kind of breed.
Like yeah, it's blue collar with
money, which is a dangerous situation.
It's blue collar with money,
but it's also people with like
a certain level of character,
like you have to, to get
through the winter, you can't
be too much of a fuck off.
You know what I mean? Yeah.
Like when Shit gets 50 below,
you've got to be on your God Damn Toe.
You gotta be on your game.
Like if you are a real case,
fuck up.
The kind of guy who like winds up falling
asleep and parking lots all the time
and you have security guard
finds you at 9:00 AM you die.
That chick that happened to some,
I dunno where it was,
somewhere in the northeast,
she passed out on her doorstep and then
she woke up and like half her body had
all frostbites and they were going to
have to amputate shit because she had
passed out on her who just walked
and somebody had walked by going,
I think that girl is dead. Nobody
says anything. She was only 19 also.
She was like, oh, it's
awful. It's blues man.
Especially when you're 19 when you're
19 you don't fucking, you know,
you don't know how to drink yet. You could
go way too deep. Like she was probably,
forget the frostbite.
She's probably on death's
door. Yeah. So how,
how fucked up is her body and
she's hot too. How fucked up.
Scroll up. What does it
say? What's the story? Hey,
this isn't as good as may
lose limbs. Oh God. Damn.
It's her hands were three times the size,
but their skin split from palm to finger.
Oh my God.
They spent the night playing drinking
games with friends during which he lost
several rounds to check off,
like down at least 10 Tequila shots
tweeted earlier that day to kill shots
tonight. Yup. All my
God. That's awful. Joe,
do you remember a guy named Fast Eddie
that use hang out at the comedy store?
The Fat Mexican. He was called
fast that he's there all the time.
He was there for his birthday
one time. Was he a comedian? No,
he's just one of the guys that
really nice due to hangs out.
He's saying out the patio.
I know him.
You hear them start to hang
out there forever. Okay.
I probably know him that for ever.
And uh,
it was his birthday and everyone was
buying them shots and we're driving around
and I mean he is gone. I mean, he is God,
he's like dropped me off at the club.
You know, it's the guys who were like,
yeah, we'll drop you off. You know,
we will just throw you out of the car
and you might die in a dumpster. But,
but if it's a chick, nobody lets that
happen. Everyone's like, no, you come on,
you too drunk. That's not true.
Depending on what kind of chicken is,
if it's a giant mouthy
chick collects to fight,
dudes will kick that bitch out of the
car and hit the gas. Get your ass kicked.
Yeah.
I mean only bad people would kick anyone
out of the car in the fucking winter.
Oh, you have to be a really bad person
and you're like, okay, good luck.
Or that guy's a total piece of shit. He
some loud mouth dude wants to fight cops,
you know, driving by in a
rolled on, we fuck you pig.
Like put the fucking window down dude,
what are you doing?
We were driving and I just heard my window
down and go, what's up? And he's like,
whew. And he just hold down the
side of my window, which is nice.
They got outside the car and didn't just
fill up my backseat with Mexican vomit.
You ever hung out with a dude who doesn't
have it? The whole lot of friends,
but he seems like a cool guy and you're
like, man, this guy's pretty cool.
You know when or why did nobody's
hanging around with this guy?
Come hang out with us and
then the dude gets drug.
It just becomes a maniac.
Fuck you to the bouncers and fucking,
I mean there are dudes like that that
gets this. Jekyll and Hyde just get, oh,
I used to be way back in the
day you used to be used to be,
do know you were Jacqueline Hyde because
I knew I would just get drunk and I was
just like, but did you feel big?
You becoming Jacqueline Hyde? Yeah,
but you would do it again.
You don't really know.
That's why I don't really drink that much.
I don't even drink at all.
Actually back then when you would
do it, you would like, okay,
here comes taking my medicine.
I used to warn people.
Sometimes I get a little crazy. I
been around. You are drunk, dude. I'm,
I'm gonna be honest with you.
I don't,
I don't think you're a
Jekyll and Hyde Guy lion now.
Well No, no, no. I've been around you
and you're drunk and you were younger.
However I fucking doing
you at least 10 years.
Probably like 13 I got picked up at the
comedy store and just be around 2000 so
during that time we have all seen
each other in completely in a,
in a state of,
if somebody wanted to have sex with us,
it would technically be raped.
Yeah, that'd be raping us. We've,
we've all been in that state seeing
each other that can't rape the willing.
Right.
But you can according to,
there's like a lot of people that are
actually arguing this and they have to see
you can rape guys.
Yes.
There have to say it about
guys when they're saying
you about women if you want,
there's obviously they recognize that
there's a real issue with that when it
comes to like being contradictory
and being hypocritical.
If you start saying that if a man has
sex with a woman who's had a few drinks,
that's rape where you have
to also conversely say that
if a woman has sex with a
man, has had a few drinks, that's
rape and if you're both drunk,
you're raping the shit out of each
other. That is the weird thing, dude,
is that it's a double illegal act.
So yeah,
technically she did rape pim,
but I mean is it not the same
face on technical at all?
It's not a tactical at all
because she didn't write them.
She had sex with a drunk guy and we all
know what that is and we have to add all
these goddamn extra layers. It doesn't
change the actual act of what it is.
The real problem with defining all these
things is this is rape and that is rape
and this is privilege and that
is, no, no, no, no, no. It's,
those are all just labels.
You're putting labels on things that
we know exactly what they are. Okay.
If a school teacher blows a 14 year old,
it's not rape.
I totally agree with you on that one,
but here's the thing. If she's gross,
it's an issue. It's not at all,
and we all know that to be a fact.
We all know that.
If a chick who looks like Tara,
Patrick winds up blowing
some 17 year old kid,
that's not a goddamn crime. I mean, yeah,
it's going to fuck that kid's head up,
but it's not a god damn. Not in a bad way
though. What Dude's like? Oh my God, Tara,
Patrick's suck my dick. How has it
been raped by high fiving people?
How was it rape? No, I
agree with you on that one,
but not live in the country where it's
like you can't technically have different
laws for different people, right? We
have to apply these laws to everybody.
I agree with everything you're saying.
It's good though.
It's good that people would
that hypocritical because
it exposes it when the end
is subject like this,
which becomes so preposterous when you
start talking about it exposes how crazy
it is. There are people, men and
women like to get drunk and fuck.
If you engage them in that activity,
you don't automatically become a rapist.
Yeah. But there is a level that
you get to that gets rapey. Yeah,
there is. And we all know this.
Yes. Label it all you want.
We all know there's something wrong if
someone's really fucked up and blacked
out and you say fuck it and
you have sex with them anyway.
That's crazy. That's fucked
up. There's also women,
there's also women that you've met that
her so conniving that could probably
rate like,
like, Hey, I want to have
a Joe Rogan baby, you know,
and like gets you drunk to the point
where you fuck them and comment on Condo.
Yeah,
yeah.
It's totally possible. But again,
you, there's had to take a condom,
they have to grab the condom,
take it,
put it in the toilet and flush it because
these women will take that card and
squirt that bait and it's this x and the
thought of just having a baby for the,
for the sake of making money.
The fact that that's acceptable or not
just that it is definitely that.
But I think there's also a part of it is
having a baby with a guy who ordinarily
doesn't want anything more than sex from
you. Yeah. Now you connect with them,
you know, so there's, there's
those options. There's
someone who just wants a baby,
you know, there's some people that just
want a baby and this girls had just like,
God damn it,
I want a baby.
I'm going to give a fuck if this guy wants
a baby or not. I want a baby. You know,
obviously not supposed to do that.
You should probably like tell the guy,
like you could probably find a guy
who's willing to just give you a baby.
But then it comes back and then
there's all that legal stuff.
Well, there was legal stuff
with a guy who, uh, got he got,
he was a sperm donor.
He gave sperm to these people.
They had a kid and then the,
he got sued for a child support and he
lost because his DNA made the child,
I mean, this poor guy, he wasn't involved
in the raising of this kid at all.
That's incredible. This new thing with
the guy from Los Boys Up, lost sellers,
Patrick, the movie, what's his name? Pat.
He was like the lead vampire. He, uh,
his ex wife,
he had,
they had donated sperm or some
shit like that and she took in,
had a kid and then he,
he was trying to get custody or at least
get visitation rights and he finally
got, got the right by the
judge because he is the father.
But it's like that's some crazy shit
that you could donate sperm and then it,
then it comes all this crazy
issues with it. How's that?
Even society's just crazy. Jason. Patrick.
Yeah. Patrick. Right. What I say? Uh,
we all think we remembered his name. Yeah.
The lead to God about that dude. Yeah.
He like, he was really big and
the, I think he did like speed too,
and then it just went off
the rails. He, um, is uh,
John John Machado student.
I've seen him hanging around with
John Job before it takes Jujitsu.
I love that name. John Chalk. You can't
work at Burger King with a name Sean Joke.
You could, yeah. I'm John Jock.
Jason Patch closer to be
reunited with Sun. Okay,
let's let me read this. I'll get sad.
He's a sperm donor and now he's got a kid.
Well he was married to
this woman I believe,
and she took his sperm and had a
child and now he wants the beans.
Kids' life. Oh boy. Bar. Bar Bar.
That's why even when you
get into massage parlors,
they tied the condom in a night
and throw it in the frigerator.
I think it's sell that shit.
They don't throw it away.
And they take the condom out of that room.
Yeah. They don't want your
loads. Do they nuke your lows?
I throw them in the microwave and then
make Godzilla mother load is out there
talking about that's his gold and then
their condoms and like we'd find a mate.
Got It. Boas. How smooth sailing
from here. What do I got here?
Calling their friends up to you to do. Do,
do, do. Oh, what's up Matt? Too little.
I got here. I tell you what I got. I
got a little rubber baggies of goals.
This is our ticket out of here.
I got red band come by
and calm down Twitter.
He got a hundred town
Jean come.
He's gonna want it back. Rubber band, man.
It's a little more talent than I
think people give him credit for.
I got to work with recently and
I feel like a, I never really,
I mean it was just fun hanging out with
them and they think he's a little more
time looking at him because I don't
say while you're looking at him,
that's his weird. I am weird though.
You are weird. I'll give you that.
I'll give it back. I'm a weird
dude. I'm a little crazy,
but I got a new CD out.
Believe in yourself by it. Is
it on iTunes? Awesome. Yes,
and it's on all things. records.com
Brian, we talked about this before, but
why don't you put together like a set
and do like a CD or something digital
release? I need to do. They just need to
do more stage time first though. Yeah. Do,
yeah. Do comedy is that Shit. I can't,
I can't get spots anywhere in La.
Um, you can, you just put
together your own shows.
Do dual those fucking small idea.
I can tell you where you can go.
You can go to the John Lovitz,
you can go to this new club
out on Hollywood boulevard.
There's a bunch of place you can go.
I mean if he can't get the
store and you can't do the,
I don't know why the Improv
doesn't put you up. Yeah.
Probably someone doesn't like your
sexiness. That's right. I do believe
your man, he makes people
very, very intimidated. You
can get spots though, dude.
You can get spots. You just got to
hustle. You got to hustle and do it is,
you know, that's the issue. You've
got to decide what do you like doing,
like doing a million other podcasts or
do you want to do like two or three your
podcasts,
podcasts a lot lately and be smart.
It's focusing on the comedy thing,
which is so tiring. Cause as you know,
like going on the road and
finding a spot yourself doing it.
The Doug Stanhope Way getting like a
rock club and getting the door and doing
all it is the most stressful thing ever.
That's why managers,
I get that 10 or 20% that
they take because that shit
is just annoying as fuck.
It's just hard though.
It's stressful. And Harvey,
I just went to Vegas and it was such a,
it was so fun. That place was amazing.
But there this the headache around
booking it and getting everything.
You could get somebody, dude, you can
get somebody to book you. It's worth it.
And they can put you in places where you
ordinarily might not have a connection
with a guy. And have you tried
to get a booking agent? No,
I don't even know what to do.
Well you should get one like other comics
are doing it and you're friends with a
lot of comics. You know, it's
not hard to do. But once,
once you like start doing it on a weekly
basis and really hammered and then the
act like starts to take shape.
I've doesn't blessed man lately.
I've been touring a lot and it's
totally fun when you just keep going.
When you get to work on a joke and over
and over again and then all of a sudden
you just riff on a new
punchline now just boom, boom,
boom and it just builds and you know,
cause I'm trying to now write a new hour
to do an the finally shoot something
I've never shot in our special.
So you want to ride an hour additional
to that and then shoot it and how much
time?
Well I'm debating whether I do like,
cause I have another CD called crime
fighter and that material's really old but
do the best of this and this best of this
new stuff I'm doing and then shoot an
hour or just do a whole new hour.
They do a whole new hour because that way
people could still find this stuff and
they could still tuned to
the old stuff. Yeah. I'm,
I'm a about 35 minutes into a new hour.
I made a mistake once of not doing a
totally new set because my, my set,
like I had certain jokes
that were just better,
which in my showtime special and then
when I did my CD on comedy central,
there was a couple of bits that
I don't know how many bits,
but there was more than one that crossed
over. That was just a better bit now.
And I've just stuck to the
in any way cause I was like,
not too many people saw the Netflix
one because Netflix in 2005 was in its
infancy. It was a completely different
thing. But uh, I regret that now.
I probably shouldn't have done that.
I probably should have
just done totally new,
but I had better versions of
those bits. I'm like, God damn it.
These are so much better.
I saw your new special,
it was on youtube and yeah,
it's hard. He, yeah, people take it and
they stick it online. You know, you can,
I don't really try to take it down.
I uh,
down a couple of times.
I feel like there's a bunch of bits
on there that I hadn't heard before.
Did you do new stuff in that
special? Yeah, some of the
brave as shit right there.
Putting out new bits on
the, and especially I guess,
well one of the things about
doing a podcast is you're,
even if you're not writing during the
time that you're doing the podcast,
you're thinking about shit it a
way and you're going over like,
especially if we're like doing a podcast
like this, like hanging out with comics,
just talking shit.
It's not like someone who's promoting a
very specific book or you know about a
very specific subject,
which is fascinating as well,
but doing these kind of podcasts like
you're forced to think for long periods of
time and you get ideas and I
think it's easier to write.
I think it's easy to write shit.
I think there's a bunch of
different ways to write,
but I think that just talking as a is a
way to write too well, you know what is,
what does writing, it's just coming up
with an idea, having a creative idea.
You get a lot of those just talking,
you know they're not,
it's not the only thing. You know that
you also get a lot of them doing stand up.
You get a lot of them writing stand up
and you get a lot of them writing other
shit.
You might write an email to somebody and
have a fucking great idea in the middle
of just trying to be silly in an email
and you're like, Holy Shit, that's a bit,
and then take it and copy and paste it.
It's a bitch.
Just a matter of just being
in motion all the time.
View. Right. If let's
say you write 10 beds,
how many do you think actually
make the act if out of worth it?
Yeah. There's a few that are
just like, what was that?
Go back over the notes and you're
like, the fuck was I thinking, man.
I tried to take everything that happens
and tries to turn it in.
I tried to turn into a bit and
then sometimes you're like,
this is going to kill and you go
out there and it just flat lines.
But I also get Bambi legs when I'm doing
new material, when I have material,
I know that kills. I just, you know,
I'm like for throwing like fucking
hammers of the God and then I get up there
and I do this new bit and I,
it just like,
I get the Bambi legs where my legs
start shaking and I thought I started
dropping f bombs. I like every
other word is a fuck. Fuck, fuck.
You can't let that happen. See,
you know what happens, right?
You know that that happens and you talk
about it, but you, you let it happen.
You can never let that happen and
try not to never let it happen.
You just never let it happen.
It's not going to happen.
It's just you could feel the energy
of just go. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
But when guys do that,
like you'll see guys like on the road,
especially if you bring guys in the row
that has been on the road before and you
see like the first time they
go on stage and you know,
fucking Fort Lauderdale or something
like that. That's so funny. Yeah,
that's happened to me. And a joke
doesn't go over well in the, in the,
the fuck's to start flying out. And what
it is is like they're saying, ah Yup.
They're like, it's a, the guy,
a fucking guy with the fucking thing and
the audience does not want to hear that.
A poor use of words.
You see that at the Hollywood improv a
lot because a lot of people think that's
like the office.
That's where you go to work when
the industry is going to be there.
And when you're young comic and it's
the first time he gets set there,
a lot of them put like this humongous
amount of pressure on themselves to do
well there. And I've always felt
like as you move up to comedy chain,
I feel the gigs kind of get easier.
You know, you, you know the DA,
the ticket price goes up and
as a ticket price goes up.
I always feel like people want to laugh.
They're like,
I'm dropping 50 bucks on this
ticket. I'm going to laugh. You know,
I want to laugh. So, so people, at
least I couldn't disagree more real.
Yeah.
Why would I don't understand why anybody
would be more inclined to laugh cause
they paid a lot. They would love,
they want to have a good time.
Like if you're paying $50 compared to
going to show where it's like free comedy.
Okay. That's the difference. Because I
think that people who go free comedy,
they could've done anything else. They're
not really there for comedy. Right.
Someone pays for comedy, even if it's
10 bucks, you know, whatever it is.
If they're paying for comedy, they're
going there to see a show. Right.
But there's a, there's a big difference
between that and like we paid 50 bucks.
We're going to laugh hard. Right? I mean
I think it's the opposite really. Yes.
When the ticket prices get high,
people do a little bit of this like
how much should I have to fucking pay?
There's guys out there that
charge 150 bucks a ticket.
I've seen those $50 a ticket. You know
there's like they have tiered seating,
like the seating in the front,
it's like 200 bucks seating behind
that is 150 and you see people in that
audience like this.
I was just in Pachangas Brian Regan's
playing there and I think it's like a,
he's like $110 but some of it's up there.
Oh Shit.
I pay that to see him.
He's hilarious I think is great.
You know we talked about
that on the podcast before,
but apparently we were incorrect
when was about Jay Leno,
so we should probably correct.
It's a good opportunity. The uh,
when you see the super high tickets,
those are actually scalpers.
That's like ticket hub and shit like that.
But this was an advertisement
on, yeah, tango. I understand.
But we were talking about Jay left and
we were quoting like $250 tickets and
shit like that. Apparently his tickets are
not that expensive. It's just that, uh,
you know, scalpers. They exist.
I've been doing his spots on Sunday
nights at the comedy Magic Club. Oh,
he's not doing it anymore.
Well, he's on the road a lot,
so I do some of those some of the times
and he's not there. I'd do a spots.
That's great.
I think you'll be in there
as great because it allows
it to a kind of shift the
comedy a little bit when they were talking
about the differences in the crowds
between my crowds and Jay Leno's crowds.
It's pretty hilarious.
I think it's great, man. Well,
it's, it's a good spot, man.
I mean it's in the place has
been there for a long time,
but now chow and I'm there. Dude,
you owe the food. I chowed down.
That's a good club, man. I mean,
it's a club that's owned by a guy
who really has a love of comedy.
He's a great place. He, I
think he started that club.
I think he bought it in 1978 I don't
know if he started it or if he was the
first. I think he was the first, but
either way it's like a goddamn museums.
I'm blown that stinky shit in the air.
That's stuff's gross.
Slide love stinky man.
It's like,
it's like spraying perfume in
the air at Abercrombie and Fitch,
which fucking gross. It smells
bad. You don't do those cigarettes.
I don't want to smell it.
It's fucking gross band.
Stop it some.
I saw some guy doing that at a restaurant
the other day and it was like it
filled the room with this stinky
smoke or they're starting to band.
But I mean you could see it all over
the place and people are looking around
like, is that smoke? Like what is
technically what the fuck is going on?
If I have to breathe your shit, we're in
a gray area. Yeah, but it's not illegal.
It's not legal and people are still
doing restaurants and then nobody,
it's like if you lit up a cigar
in a restaurant, people go nuts.
They would fucking beat your ass.
Somebody would kick you out.
But this guy pulled one of these
things out and start puffing it in,
in a restaurant, and nobody did anything.
It was like this weird state of mind,
like,
are we breathing it and smell it?
Smells it had like a strawberry
smell to it or something icky. Yeah.
It isn't smoke though. It's
vapor, but I don't believe that.
And it smells just vape shit to him. If
it's just vapor. Okay. You tell me this.
What's the difference between you and
hailing that vapor and me and hailing that
vapor. It's going into your
body and you're blowing it out.
So inside when you're doing that,
it's transporting the t the nicotine.
So when it goes out into the air,
isn't it also transporting at
least some of the nicotine? Uh,
it has to be. It is. It's
so small and it's nicotine.
It doesn't matter if you're
forced to that, but what?
You can't say that because you're,
you're asking other people to in the,
in gesture nicotine. That's
the whole purpose of making
secondhand smoke illegal.
I think it's so smart that it will,
you won't even feel any,
shouldn't be anything.
It should be zero,
should be zero amount of drugs that you
could put in the air that affect other
people. That's not something we have
to deal with. We don't do that as a,
let me guess. We do. I was going to
say we don't do it with our bodies,
but I guess some checks give off a fuck
the purchase volume or like when you're
in a mall and you go buy a can like a
Yankee that's way worse. Not like perfume.
It's not like perfume. You're actually
breathing in. I see it in the air.
It's like when you blow that thing
out, I can see it. It's a fog machine.
I don't believe that. I
don't believe that. I think
there's some of them that are,
but I think some of them, man,
that shit lingers. Like smoke.
Like there's some that
you see it like the plot.
It blows out and within seconds it's gone.
It just disappears.
But there's other ones that float around
in the air and that's the thing they're
saying about these e-cigarettes.
They're saying, look,
they're absolutely better for you
than regular cigarettes. Cigarettes,
health experts are saying this.
But what they're not saying
is all e-cigarettes are equal.
And what they're not saying is that
all cigarettes that are, you know,
using these little electronic mechanisms
have the same mechanism that they act
in the same way. So when you see
what looks like fucking smoke,
you're seeing a guy who
burned some tobacco oil. Yup.
I mean that's what it is.
It might not be plant matter.
It might be just the oil,
but I feel like it's smoke.
There's no regulated standards that
everybody must have the same thing. Yeah.
I'm not sure enough to
really discuss the wild west,
but what I've understood by
listening to people talk about it,
this is the standards are very different.
Like, like you can get like one,
like a blue e-cigarette.
Like if somebody had a blue in this room,
there's smoking in.
I'm pretty sure that is just vapor.
Like that's all you're getting.
You're inhaling this thing and
you're puffing out just vapor,
but when you buy one of those
fucking fire hydrant looking bitch,
it's like Rosanne has those light
sabers with a two bucks thing.
One of those flute things that,
what are those things called?
Those like a flute w when
you suck on the end of it,
what would the the mouthpiece called?
Fluke. Oh yeah. Fluke. Now that's a fish.
This thing, a fluke. F
L. U. K E is a fish. Oh,
well maybe it's a fluke in it. That's
she had a mouth. I thought it was,
this could be, look it
up. All right. Here.
I thought it was a flute
wasn't a flew f l u e flute.
That that was a fluke. But isn't that a
part of like a musical instrument? Yeah,
I fell you e. Yeah, and I think
that's what it, that's why the call,
same thing because it's like,
well that's why we
googled times.
That little thing you put in like a,
that little thing would be to put
on the end of a wooden instrument.
It's also hot dog joint.
You're read it flew keys,
the many different words of the
English language. Um, well, okay.
The flying, the Flying Fluke, um,
the part of an anchor
that catches the ground,
especially in the triangular
piece at the end of an,
of the end of each arm.
Hmm.
Under anchor a Barb or a
barbed head of a harpoon,
a spear Arrow or the like,
and either half of the triangular
tale of a whale. Okay. There's
another, um, there's an accidental,
like there's a fluke,
like it was a fluke victory.
That's one that was a fluke or an
accident or chance happening. Uh,
an accidental accidentally successful
stroke such as in billiards.
It's a fluke shot and billiards.
They say, uh, obscure origin.
Okay. Fluke. Like a guess. All
right. Any of several flute.
Perry, no. American flounders.
I used to catch those when we lived
in Massachusetts. Just catch a summer.
Flounders they're called flukes
and uh,
any of a variety of other flatfishes no,
it doesn't say that.
Now let's look up flu. Flou he, cause
I think that's what we're thinking of.
Oh,
I might be wrong about that too.
Flu is a passage or duct for smoke
booth chimney. So it's a flu.
It's not a fluke.
You fuck heads ruined the whole thing.
And he ducked our passage for air gas
or the like. So it has to be that,
you know what I've found man,
you know, uh, those uh, you know,
green mountain grills, they make those
pellet grills, they make appellate,
not green mountain grills,
but other companies,
they make pellet smokers really
well. You can do like, you know,
you go to the barbecue, like I've been
looking up the smokers man, you know,
because I did that smokey thing with
the ham. My smokers kind of wack.
It fell over in the wind,
the wind knocked it over and it's
all fucked up now I'm like, hmm.
I mean it worked fine for the mom,
but it was kind of a pain that Dick like
you had to get up every couple hours
and stick a wood chips in it.
I thought it would be more
self contained in that,
but they have these things like green
mountain grills or you know the green
mountain grows a pellet smoker
or its appellate cooker. Um,
but they have pellet smokers to that
work like in a kind of a different way.
It's more smoke than it is just the
heat from burning the pellets I guess.
But you could make ribs and shit on them.
Yeah.
When,
when Joey Diaz says that he got the meat
sweats because I got it the other day
from eating meat for eating meat
ribs. Uh, what is that from?
Because I mean it was serious.
Like I thought it was having a heart
attack after eating cause I was,
I was getting hot and then shaky and then
your body's just trying to
burn off all that extra flesh.
He just stuffed on your law. I mean
that's what it is. Your body's just going,
Holy Shit.
We aid a Fogo de Chao
eddies match with boiler and
we were sweating like crazy.
Just dig in when you eat a lot of meat.
I love it.
I take one of those things where I'm
driving by the hospital in Burbank and I'm
like, should I just like pull over and
just wait and wait this out to make sure I
don't need to be there soon.
We thinking you were dying.
It felt something was not right, man.
I, I felt like I was something was up.
Are you worried about your health?
Is that why you go into
the electronic cigarettes?
You just doing this because
you were in the studio?
No, I I I mostly do electronic cigarette
cause the girl, she'd only do it.
The girl I'm with hates it so much.
So I have good, good for her. Good.
What does she hate more your
cigarettes or your a hand job places.
I know. Shh. Jesus. Sam,
you are spell it out.
No denial.
You fucking cock blocker.
Yeah.
Well let me have Sam said the robot.
Hey listen,
uh, Sam Shabbily knows what you
do. He always does that shit man.
There's been so many times for Sam
has said something where I'm like,
you're fucking,
what are you shooting?
Like trip
out maps.
What are you talking about?
Interesting guy.
You'll get mad at me all the time for
just bringing up something you talk about
onstage.
He's got a big,
like everybody mad at me
on Twitter because it's
something that I just literally
just was like, Hey, did you
see write back and say this?
And then at the firestorm breaks out.
Not think she's on Twitter.
She's like a social media person.
It's so weird.
I know. I'm out of shape. No Way. Because
I was running one day in La Jolla.
People randomly started cheering me
on as I was running down the street.
Guys on bikes were giving me high
fives and thumbs up. I was like,
dude, I'm just running. This isn't
like a fucking marathon. Yes. You
know that they didn't see you
perform at the comedy store there.
That's right next to La Jolla.
Or maybe it was so funny seeing your boobs
that they were like, yeah, how honey,
you know hog called.
Why would you assume?
Why wouldn't you assume
that they knew who you were?
You were performing in that fucking town.
How many people do you think are in
La Jolla? I know, but it was in PB.
I know it's the same basic place, but
nobody knows for. How long ago was this?
This was like a couple of weeks ago. Sam
Tripoli. You're internet famous in a way,
you know that, right? Do you have a
fucking CD? That's number 11 on it.
Believe in yourself. Yeah, but I mean
seriously stop and think about that.
What are you confused that people would
like give you the thumbs up if they
think you're funny? Yeah, I do, but I
just feel it himself down. Sam triply.
Yes. I'm the, I'm the, I'm the house of
self doubt. That's where I come from. Yes,
I do have self doubt,
but I really had to think it more has
to do with me looking like I'm barely
holding on as I run.
Well there's a little of that,
but I'm trying to give you a fucking half,
half glass full option and you're not
even willing to take it at some defeatist
type thinking. Sam, I don't know why.
I just have a feeling as more to do
with the running kind of rocking cause
you're trying to work in your material
about running and people getting true at
all. Working in a bed. Come on. Okay.
There's a bit of a bear. A little bit
of a little, a bit of a something there.
I know I can ramble with Pacific beach.
It's fucking beautiful isn't it?
It's gorgeous. I don't know why. I like,
why would you live in Cleveland
when you could live in PB?
People get stuck.
They don't have enough money to move in
the hairy scary to try to relocate to a
new spot.
I would smoke a ton of crack that way I
wouldn't have to eat for like two weeks
and I just save all my money for
a great crack grows on trees.
A gray,
I
mean give it a crack bullish on the
corner. I mean cracked. He grown trees.
It'll put crack dealers at a
business but everybody be on crack.
Everybody would be imagine if
that was like a real issue.
Like crack was just growing everywhere.
A lot of people in trees.
There'll be a lot of people that are dead.
This is a joke on my CD.
I was walking my dog next door.
I've crackheads everywhere. I was
walking my dog, I looked in the trees,
there were crack heads in the trees.
That's a true story.
They were hanging up out there and there's
like five Prac gets in these trees.
That's, you know, you got good crack.
It's like if you go buy a pasture
and you see big fat, healthy cows,
that's some good grass. Those, those
cows are eating good. But if you, uh,
if you see a crack head up in a tree,
did you see the one nearby
has some really good,
do you see the video of the,
the jazz band playing jazz and the cows
just all walk up and start listening to
the band jam. Really? Yeah.
And it was like the co they have to pull
over and take a piss and guys starts
playing his thing and all the cows,
you start looking and then you see them
walk over and they start listening to
the band.
That's so cool. Cows than people. I'm
such a fascinating relationship, man.
That's a weird thing. Yeah.
We eat them. We'll need,
we don't just eat them like
very, very, very, very, very,
very few people have them as pets,
you know,
and the people that do have them as pets,
they usually get something out
of them like milk. Yeah, welcome.
And then the big male ones, boy, not
really interested in being your friend.
You've got to keep them in
the fuck away from people.
You got to cut their balls off at an
early age and those are the ones you cook.
Yup. You make your, your dairy.
I've won a fucking weird relationship
that these animals have somehow or another
like sort of developed and been groomed
to develop to be these docile giants
that we just pick meat from.
So strange.
I mean we've accepted it because it's
normal. But if, if human beings, the,
if the concept of eating other animals
didn't exist and then, you know,
we started introducing the idea,
we found a better way to get
our protein then beans. In fact,
if you eat animals, animal protein
is high in omega three fatty acids.
And we started extolling the
virtues of murdering cows and Edm
people will be like, what the fuck are
you talking? What are you crazy man?
Eat animals flipped the
fuck you going to eat him.
But because we eat animals all the time,
it's just no big deal.
They acceptables totally murders fine.
Well and we just have this thing.
Well you know animals eat animals
and fucking they would eat us,
which is totally true. Yes
they would. But it's weird.
What I'm getting at is it's weird and it
goes back to what we were talking about
about living in Edmonton, cause it's
weird what people just get used to.
It's weird that people
get used to 50 below zero.
It's weird that people get used to
plowing themselves out of the driveway
everyday because it snowed a foot and a
half over night while they were asleep.
And so they have to get up two hours
early just so they can get out of their
fucking driveway and drive down that
slippery road to a job. That sucks.
But people do it.
They just fucking do it.
They just accept it, they accept it,
and she's like, this is my reality.
Cold as fuck. Even prison. That's
where it gets really weird, man.
People except their prison reality.
That's why they say that men
become institutionalized.
Like I guess women as well.
Probably right. If they're
locked up for a long time,
they become used to the
community and the, uh, the,
the social schedule schedule,
they get used to that world.
And when I say the community,
I don't see it. It's like,
it's fucking great community. Great
NBC show. No, I don't mean that either.
What I meant was that it's like they
get used to that sort of structure.
That's social structure.
They get used to that world and they're
scared and when they get, they get free,
they'll commit like some stupid
little crime to get locked up.
Nobody gets hurt so they get sent back.
Yeah. That definitely does happen.
There's a guy of the option,
I think stay in. Look,
I think if someone's gotten you to
the point where you're so fucked up,
you want to stay in prison
and you don't want to be free,
or if you are so fucked up and you
have the, the ability to recognize it,
you know, like if you're a child
molester or something along those lines,
which you know,
take away from the horrific act of
what molesting a child is fucking
unbelievably evil, disgusting,
disgusting and evil. But imagine,
I don't understand like some people's
motivations for things. I don't, I don't,
I don't, I'm not inside their
head. I could speculate,
but I really couldn't imagine what it's
like to be a child molester. Somewhat.
Obviously can, could you imagine being
a person who does not want that in them?
It does not want that, that
whatever the fuck it is that, that,
that aberration,
that fuck up,
that horrible left turn in their mind
that makes them want to molests kids.
But it's there. And so, you know what? If
one of them was like, you know what, man,
don't let me out just to leave me in here.
I think in here I'm having a good
life or they're good enough life.
There was a story about a guy who
infected women with HIV and he,
he had infected a bunch
of them because he said,
because he didn't believe he had it.
He thought it was bs and he's just him.
Tommy Morrison. Toni Morrison
was saying that. Remember,
but he went to jail and this guy,
they wouldn't let him out.
They kept him in jail for longer till
they figured out what they were going to
do with them.
What can you do?
How can you stop someone from giving
a disease and how can you, you know,
just you have it, dude. You got it. You
can't give it to other people. Yeah.
I mean people have been giving people the
clap from the beginning of time. Right.
You know, I mean, how many
fucking people have chlamydia? No,
they have chlamydia and still go
out and fuck, that's gotta be rough.
It was rough. But then they
would do it with aids to man.
People do with everything.
There's obviously they, you know,
obviously people do give it up
because it gets spread around. Right.
Well how about this fucking magic
Johnson Donald Sterling thing,
this, this whole thing like a part of
his whole thing that a lot of people are
ignoring was her and the guide sterling
and her having this conversation where
he was saying, you can go
fuck these guys. He was like,
I don't care what you do with them.
Fuck 'em go out. You know, fuck them.
Like you're, you're hanging out
magic. Wait a minute, hold on. Well,
he even said that he,
I said that in the Anderson Cooper
interview that this guy was going around
having sex with people
when he knew had HIV. Yeah.
He said that in the Anderson Cooper
thing and I'd heard that before.
We'd probably does.
But what's crazy is that it's
just like everything else.
It's just like having plumbing Ia. It's
just like having herpes. It's just like,
like people don't think of HIV,
which can be potentially fatal.
I mean,
I guess less fatal now that
they have a lot more drugs.
I think eventually it's just
going to be like diabetes almost,
but you can give it to somebody. I think
that's where it got an hourly thing.
Drugs for it forever. They ever
kind of wore it. I think lover,
I think what they should do is
whoever's got billion dollars go,
this is $1 billion. You need a
lot more than that to secure it.
If you like to have scientists
that can have this billion dollars,
if he could cure it. No, it's, it doesn't
matter you the funding in order to, uh,
to make a drug that's capable of doing
something as incredible as curing HIV or
curing aids. I mean right now they've
got them apparently now again,
when I'm discussing this,
I have zero medical background or just
two dudes talk to idiots that happened to
be dirty and smarter than the other,
but we don't have,
I don't know who the fuck is up tomorrow.
Leave it out there. You know, big words.
I'm sure. I know it does
it. I'm saying it again.
It's just the words that they use,
actual mechanism behind the smart.
It's very debatable, but the
look, the bottom line is,
I don't know shit about
medical science at all,
so anything that I say about
a, about what's, what's good
for you and bad for you,
it's just fucking pure speculation.
However,
what I understand is that they've got
it down to a point where you don't even
test positive for HIV anymore.
Like you.
They've had people that are HIV positive,
but the drug goes into such remote places
and squashes out the virus in such a
way that even though you still have
it, it's like, and you could shut it.
I don't know. That's the question. I don't
know. None of it makes any sense to me.
It's chaos, but viruses don't
make any sense to me. Bacteria,
it doesn't make any sense to me.
The fact that you need bacteria
makes no fucking sense to me.
Can like a virus. It lives forever.
That's a good question. Some of them,
they've eradicated and they've come back.
You know, like some of them they got,
well, that's one of the things that people
get so upset about with anti vaccine
people.
It's like,
do you understand that they have taken
shit like polio and made it almost
nonexistent?
They've taken things like smallpox
and made them almost nonexistent.
What about this mers or mar immerse
takers like has that always been around or
is that just like something comes out of
nowhere and they ain't got to be like,
oh, it was the Middle East thing. How
much is this manmade? You know, like,
well, don't get crazy. I will. All that
is the thing that people do do this.
I do have a a little bit of information
about this because I did a whole special
on it on that Scifi show on infectious
diseases and I got a chance to talk to a
lot of these guys.
They're not making any new diseases.
They don't have to make any new diseases.
They have some shit weaponized
smallpox that if they released,
we're Foxville.
Yeah,
they had this stuff in mass quantities
in Russia and that's a fact.
There's no need to make
any new thing like mers.
Mers is not very effective because look,
it's not spreading.
There's a very small amount of people
have gotten and they were talking about it
years ago. It's a very dangerous and
deadly disease once people get it,
but there's not that many people
that have it. It's a very small,
I only think like six people
ever have died from it.
The problem is it's like half the people
that get it. It's, it's just bird flu.
New Bird flu is not new.
All of these fluids.
This is another thing that
I found out during the show.
They're almost all of
them come from livestock,
whether it's a swine flu, whether
it's the avian flu, bird flu,
all these different flu's a shit ton
of them come from the way people raise
animals in factory to make love
to them. No. Okay. That's up.
There was a lot of fucking, and
that was the aids one. The monkey,
Sam Kennison.
Yeah, that Sam kinisons
bit UN aids. It was like,
at the time it was so taboo and so wrong,
but there's so much of it that
was so fucking true and funny.
The thing that we're used
to like, you know, he's like
Sam, they say Sam, Hey,
just a heterosexual disease.
Straight people die from it.
Do they want fucking guy?
Fuck you.
It's not our,
it's not our fucking dance.
That's a horrible joke.
Terrible. And mean.
Who is someone's talking
about? Right. They were,
they went back and they watch Eddie
Murphy's like delirious or raw, I forgot.
And they were watching it with their kids
and then at some point you had to stop
and go,
listen,
we don't talk like this anymore because
it was like very raw and obviously not
just raw,
like the difference between like a gay
joke and an evil like homophobic joke.
There's a difference in, they used to
that what used to be pretty normal,
like an evil, homophobic joke
in the 80s was pretty normal.
Like you could get away with it. Yeah.
You know, and now it's like, whoa.
It's like you can't just shit on someone
just for their sexual orientation. Yeah.
It's gotta be an observation of it.
I mean, what is the line on that?
Because I feel like some people
think that if you just bring it up,
it's homophobic and I just completely
disagree with that. Yes, that's,
I agree with you 100% that the subjects
are always going to be completely open.
You can talk about
anything you want on stage.
People may or may not find it funny.
There's the question is do you find it
funny and can you find a way to relay it
to an audience? If that's your
intent. Just finding humor in life.
There's nothing wrong with
that. And you can, you know,
you could talk about any subject you want,
but that's not what they were doing
back then. They were just destroying,
destroying gay people.
You know,
you remember when US Sebastian Bach
from skid row had a t shirt on.
AIDS kills fags dead. Yeah,
man. You could find it.
Pull up the picture. It was a
huge controversy, but it's like,
why would you say that?
It's so weird that is as
homophobic as you can get.
It's probably the worst it, well, it's
just right up there with God hates fags.
That, uh, Phelps guy that died recently
walking around with a shirt on like that.
Like someone thought that was cool.
It's cooler than not wearing that shirt.
There it is.
Is there irony loss in the way he's
pouting with his gay lips and his fucking
Farrah Fawcett hair and just that whole
loop of that music genre was all dudes
who tried to look like chicks.
Yeah.
You remember when you first saw
the poisoned CD, you're like,
those are some smoking hot chicks and
your friend's like, dude, those are, Gosh.
You're like, ah, I want weird.
What a weird time in music, man. I,
I blame Rob Halford Cause Rob Halford
of Judas priest who was gay as fuck and
coolest shit all around bad motherfucker.
He,
he's such a bad mother fucker that he
was wearing like obvious gay biker garb
and he got people to
think that gay biker garb,
like onstage with
something cool manly shit.
And because he was sort of closeted,
you know,
I guess it was understood in the industry,
but they didn't talk about it,
but he didn't hide it. You know, it's one
of those things. It wasn't like Liberace,
you know,
back in the just flaming constantly ask
him when he was going to get married.
It was, it was a different sort of
a scenario but rob Halford, God,
he changed like metal.
They all started dressing like that.
They all started dressing like gay
bikers and I think that during that time
everybody got so perplexed.
I think bad gay motherfuckers,
just bad ass gay dudes infiltrated the
music business and got everyone to dress
like a homeowner. Yeah, they all,
everyone was wearing spandex tights and
their cock was pin there to pick up.
Everybody looked like that's not,
but that's not for women.
Like that flowing lock
thing with a tight pants.
Chicks like the Marlboro man.
They want a guy who's built
like Don Frye who's got like,
they know he's got a six pack under
that like fucking cowboy shirt,
but they don't see,
they want to see it on the outside.
That's a guy thing like guys want
to see like yoga pants on a chick.
Like a girl could walk down the street
with yoga pants and a camel toe.
Totally acceptable.
Guy Walked down the street with
fucking ballet tights on and no shirt.
Jesus Christ is Hugh Jackman. That's
not real. Yeah. No it's not. Come on.
That's not real. That guy's face is
Photoshop. You're so full of shit.
Look at that guy on the left
last night. The lighting,
the lighting is totally bad.
Not Real there they have their
shadows are in the wrong direction.
Hugh Jackman Shadow's coming towards us.
This guy's shadow is going towards
his left shoulder in unreal.
Kicked the fuck out of here. How dare you
think that Dude's HGH in? Uh, probably.
Yeah, if he's smart. Shred it out,
Bro. We were, for whatever reason,
Brian was obsessed with the
fact that Hugh Jackman was Kay.
He wouldn't stop talking about it.
It's fucking hands were moving.
He kept puffing on the glass. Dick. He
was like, I hear you. Jacqueline's gay.
There's multiple pictures of him
holding hands with guys. Come on,
son is multiple pictures of me
with big black dicks in my mouth.
Hold on a second. Back that up because
one of those look real. Go ahead.
Go piss you weak bladder
at son of a bitch.
Who's the guy with the
beard is a Wolverine Fan.
He's telling them how I'm watching
that movie. Uh, made him cure cancer.
That's what it is. So Hugh Jackman's
guy in the right, let me see,
is he really holding that guy's
hand or is that a perspective,
that perspective thing.
Who cares if he's gay?
But it's a weird thing like a chicken.
Be Gay like a Jodie foster and everyone
knows she's gay. She's out. It's all good.
And she could play elite. Okay.
That is super gay. God sexy.
He looks so,
he's looked so big.
But you know, if a woman like Jodie foster
be decides to come out and you know,
proclaims that she's gay, that's not
real either. Stop it. Just stop. Stop.
Now it's a my pants.
What's this guy doing?
It's talking about cook.
I didn't play on this. Um,
a woman could still play
a heterosexual woman,
but a man has a really hard
time unless it's that, um,
the dude on how I met your mother.
What's his name? Neil. Neil.
Patrick Harris. Neil Patrick Harris.
His case. He's still lovable. Yeah.
Well he's not just level,
but he plays a guy who's like
a ladies' man on the show,
which is quite hilarious.
But you know why I think though,
I think because he had some money from
that Howard Kumar movie where he plays
such a pimp. I think that's, that's
kind of Burton people's thoughts still.
I never saw that movie, so I have no idea
what the white castle, I never saw it.
Never know.
But he's a funny guy and a talented actor.
I think that's more likely than ever.
And I think we're,
we're in a different time.
I think people like supporting the idea
of a guy being out and open. You know?
I think especially in Hollywood,
that's like the place where people,
but when it comes to movies, movies
are a different animal because movies,
you got to sell tickets, you got to
sell hard fucking tickets. And you know,
if the Midwest, no
worries. I'm just talking.
The Midwest comes over and you know,
they see that some big gay guy like Hugh
Jackman is in some fucking movie where
he's playing a girlfriend too.
Who's the chick that's always on sports
illustrated? Kate Upton. Oh, Kate Upton.
He's playing Kate Upton's husband. You're
going to like get the fuck out of it.
Yeah, he's good. He
wins. He wins. He wins.
He's big. He's gay. He's beautiful.
He's got, he's got it both ways.
The New York Times apparently wrote
a thing about him being by, right.
That's what you guys are saying.
Yeah.
But I think that's just someone's wishful
thinking because he does musicals.
Yeah. No. If you like theater, musical
theater, apparently you've got to be gay.
Yeah. But manage. If you were straight,
how much asks you be crushing,
cause it'd be you,
a bunch of gay dudes and chicks everywhere
if you are in musical theater. Yeah.
If you were straight guy,
musical theater,
do you really think women are the
primary viewers of musical theater?
I think there's, I mean, acting
and dancing. How dare you.
Dancers in musical theater pull you,
push your seat back and think this over,
put your hand on your Chin like
this and do this. So Fuck No.
The whole room is not gay. The whole
audiences, gay and menopausal women,
that's who goes to see musicals in the
few confused young girls who eventually
abandon the art form and then just go to,
they want to look cool in college.
They say, Oh my God, I love musicals.
And then they go and they realized
musicals are dog shit. If it was any good,
it would be in a goddamn movie. All
right. You'd be able to see things happen.
Real monsters. Amazing. Blowguns it is,
but like a comedy performance
than it is a musical.
I mean they call it a musical, but it's
really like a sketch comedy performance,
like a Saturday night live piece that
goes on for an hour and a half. I mean,
that's really what it was like really
good. But to call that a musical, no,
musicals are drab.
There's like fucking,
there's songs in there about romance
and love and the two people meet again,
they're nonsense.
We have movies now.
If you want to tell me Chicago chicks
don't like to the musical Chicago,
they'd love to tell you.
I've seen the musical
Chicago and it is dog shit,
dog shit. And I went to watch
a very good friend of mine.
I went to support her and
sit there and watch Chicago.
And when it was the halfway through,
we were all sitting around,
we're all talking and really, so what do
you think? Wow. It's really, really good.
Like everybody was like, you know, like
hedging the words. I go, it's dog shit.
It's watchable dog shit.
And finally the older gentlemen in
the group who we look to for guidance,
it goes, it's, I've never been a fan
of the art form. It's fucking terrible.
And we were like, it's not
good, right? Like what's going
on here? Like you go see,
go see,
they don't do cats anymore.
But if you went to see cats
halfway through cats, he'd be like,
what the fuck am I watching?
What are you doing to me here?
This is a murderous assault
on my attention span.
And somehow I know that
you've convinced to,
I'm sure a lot of people think
that in my act, but that's fine.
You don't have to go see it.
All right. Some people like
it. Some people like cats.
I get that as well. I just don't
understand those people at all.
Have you heard of, Oh, have
you heard of that movie?
That's a like or I mean that play, that's
like we're guys all act like horses.
I there's like three. Yeah, I heard
that's pretty sweet. You should go.
You should go and give a full lines.
Kre King.
I see lions fuck out of here.
Get the fuck out of here.
I would say I saw Cirque
de Solei and that was dope.
Cirque de Solei is because it's uh,
it's like watching the Olympics with
music and it's like you're watching people
do shit that's impossible.
Guys doing handstands and they have like
a woman like attached to their hand and
they were like supporting her.
Like they have one hand on the ground,
one hand up in the air that's
holding a woman you like.
How are you even fucking doing that?
The guys like there's guys who are
doing handstands on each other's arms.
Unbelievable.
It's insane.
You feel so weak and feeble when you
go to see more so than going to see the
UFC,
you feel weak and feeble.
When you go to Cirque de Solei
cause you watch them do things.
Do you like how long would it take me
to even come close to being to fuck,
I can't do that. If I have
those skills, I become a Ninja.
Did someone die recently? It started. So
yeah, they did some, but it wasn't, no,
it was Ringling brothers.
It was both.
It was Cirque de Solei and then
there was like nine people that died.
I went and saw a show
where the guy missed it,
missed the thing and he just felt hope
and the whole room was just quiet.
How was he? Uh, he got
back up. Up Man. Whoa.
I'm sure he took a beating off stage.
Fall only like about six or seven feet.
That's still, man, that
jumped from the ceiling. That
would fuck you up. It's like,
well, how tall is that ceiling is about
eight feet. No. Yeah, that's good.
I got to be more jammy. 10, eight, eight,
nine two the droplets go nine. Okay,
let's go nine. You, you know,
that would suck. That would suck.
I would suck and hurt,
but we're so weak.
My cat is 17 fucking years old.
I got a cat that I've had forever,
man. My sister gave him to me, her
to me, she had a bunch of kittens.
There were all these
wacky kittens and her cat.
She had this one cat and they like you.
They lived in this rural place and they
didn't fix their cat and their cat one
up getting fuck by some other, cause I've
heard the cats fucking outside my door.
It sounds like murders going
on. Well, anybody who does that,
you release a male cat.
Like you're creating a real fucking
problem and an a spade and unspayed female
cat.
You're creating a real fucking problem.
Like feral cats are fucking huge issue.
Not just because of the fact that they
decimate bird populations and things
along those lines,
but also because of diseases they carry.
They're the number one purveyor
of this toxo plasma. Uh,
in toxoplasmosis,
a bacteria or a disease rather parasite
that people have really common in third
world countries,
dirty pussies effects your affects.
Your brain does a lot of fucked
up shit to your oh yeah. Yeah.
And it's super common and it, it also,
the cat shit gets in the meat. It's like,
it's like a real issue
with, uh, with fucking cats.
Is this something about like some
bacteria that gets in or a virus, virus?
It gets into a mouse's head and he
has it to run inside the, it's a rat.
If it's a,
what it does is,
I've talked about this many times
in this podcast, but it hasn't,
it's been a long time,
more than a year.
The way it works is it rewires the rats
sexual reward system and it makes a rat
attracted,
sexually attracted to the smell of cat
piss to the point where it's testy swell
up and he gets like, he's in
estrus, he's like, he's hurting,
he's got blue balls because he smells
this cat piss like red ban on hot rod,
5,000 red ban all day.
So all day.
So he essentially on a double
dose of Cialis with, uh,
an added a acorns. It, it's no,
well it does a weird thing to um,
their,
their fear system.
It hijacks their fear system so
they're not afraid of cats anymore.
If there's videos like pull
up his video, Brian. Um,
it's a toxo plasmosis
infected rat chases cat.
This rat is running after the
cat trying to get some cat piss.
It's like go running up to the cat's ass.
Like has no fear of the cats.
So cats eat these rats
and then the cats get it.
And apparently it doesn't really affect
the behavior of the cats because cats
are evil from the jump, that evil
from the evil, from the jump.
It doesn't make a more evil. They don't
get the worst roommate ever. They're like,
pick up my shit. Yeah, feed me.
I'm out of here. This is the video.
These cats are like, what the
fuck is going on? I look this rat.
You could kill them the language,
but this,
this rat starts going towards these cats
and he's like literally trying to get
at their,
their bag.
Give me that buck that Iran is not afraid
of. He just jumped on. That cat's back.
Look how crazy that is. Give me
that. But Yo dude, how crazy is that?
That rat just jumped on.
That cat's back.
They're not afraid of peep of cats at all.
Like how does that even happen?
How does that sort gangster man,
they really are gangster animals.
But why does that virus come around
or that bacteria, whatever it is,
and how's that form and how did know
to do that to that mouse and make that
happen? And there's only one answer.
Jesus. There is the Jesus man. Jesus.
The Jesus is the answer. It must be
God. Why? Jesus? Yeah, we'll look.
God has a plan. Sam.
That cat's ass. Yes. Yes.
That people right now angry. They're
angry. And you know why you're angry.
You know why you're angry?
Because what I'm saying,
it makes you feel like what you
believe is silly. And do you know why?
Why wait for it?
Because of what you believe is silly.
Silly talk wasn't silly.
I wouldn't be able to make you angry
if like people were joking around about
what men when I was sex with women.
Well cause it feels good. Oh,
you'd be like,
okay,
if that's the reason why
Hetero phobic doesn't work.
Like if homophobic people looking
at us like, Eh, yeah, what do you,
but you fucked girls,
Eh,
what do you a breeder ill he'd be
like, okay, you're just being mean.
You're not hurting my feelings.
I feel your mean energy.
But this shit doesn't work. Doesn't
change how I feel about life. You know?
That's what's going on Sam. I
get it man. It's just weird.
And I was talking about this on
stage the other day about how like,
is this a bit you working on
another bit right now? No,
but I'm just saying that it goes along
the lines of what you're saying is just
like, you know, there's all this,
these people who are conservative
morals and stuff and they don't,
oh you shouldn't do this,
shouldn't do that,
shouldn't do that because you've
been told us over these years,
but yet over the last century or so,
most of those thoughts have been debunked.
Meaning there's places where people
allow what you're saying is evil.
It's going to ruin society and
a society is going to crumble.
People allow this happen and it doesn't.
Yeah. And so what are you saying?
Cause if like all this stuff where
you're like you shouldn't pay for sacs.
He shouldn't do drugs, you shouldn't do
all this shit cause it's gets the, the,
you know the god yet in Amsterdam,
all of that is legal and there's not fires
coming from the skies and monkey find
monkeys, tea bag and everybody and
you know, just like it just is,
it's been proven that that
what suppression is not
good for people that don't
like it. It's a bad way to raise children.
It's a bad way to raise a nation, right?
It's just people don't like suppression.
It's really that simple.
They don't like it.
They got upset.
[inaudible] you're another person and
you're telling the guy what to do,
telling the guy can't shirk off.
What does that guy want to do?
He wants a jerk off as soon as he gets
away from you and wants a book doors and
just jerk off in privacy and then feel
terrible about it and then repent and you
know, Kellogg, no sense. You know,
Kellogg's, the guy from the cereal,
Kellogg's cereal. W The reason why
this is you got to read this book,
sex at dawn by this Guy Chris Ryan,
podcast guest, fascinating guy. Um,
I've read that book. I've done a bunch
of podcasts with him and Duncan Trussell.
He's a really interesting guy,
but one of the things the,
he sent me hip to his like Kellogg's,
you can find us online,
created cornflakes,
created mild tasting food to keep
people from getting sexually aroused.
Said that he lived with his wife for
like 40 years and bragged about having
never having had sex with her,
but kept a male intern who
would give him daily enemas.
That's fucking Kellogg's.
So think about that.
Repressing sexual thoughts,
unbelief, pressing and actively,
actively repressing sexual thoughts.
And yet obviously fighting off
the gay tooth claw and Fang,
right?
Obviously fighting off the gay.
The guy had a male assistant who's
mustache gay, he's gay as fuck
face boy. Put a leather, uh,
paper boy cap on him and uh,
no shirt and cutoff jeans.
Okay, you see it? Please do.
Let me do that right now, Jack. Now,
I mean if you see that guy's face,
just what a great book,
you'll probably get an even better
picture of them where you could go full,
full fucking body and then go with
the color specific thing. Mcdonald,
get an obvious Photoshop, make
it. I think it really looked real.
I wonder if she was getting Dick
on the side. Mrs Kellogg's. Oh,
sh Mrs Kellogg was fucking
a personal trainer.
They didn't even have post
personal trainers back then.
She invented, vented it.
She'd vented just so that she
can have somebody touch me.
Did Jesus touch me?
Unbelievable.
Well, that's people, man.
People that are suppressing other people
are usually doing it to try to suppress
him.
Something in themselves.
That's why a lot of conservatives, I
just, I just, it's like you're lying.
I think a lot. I'm not judging all, but
it's like when you sit there and you say,
Oh, you shouldn't do this, this and
this. Most of the time you're doing this,
this and this.
You just want to put laws on other people.
Like I go to Arizona a lot to do
gigs and it's a fun state to do gigs,
but they have all these crazy laws.
Yeah,
they party more than anybody I know.
So it's like they're just making laws
for other people that doesn't apply to
them. Why do you think that is? What
do you think that is? I don't get,
I don't know why, man. You're
right. It's fear. It's also theirs.
Here's the other,
the
problem with fear and this idea
of everyone should be loving.
There's certain folks
that are already done.
See this is one of the real problems,
okay?
This is one of the real problems
with society as a whole.
Cultural in general and
just human interaction.
This is one of the real problems
is that some people already done,
somebody has made them, they've done
a piss poor job of feeding them,
raising them, and then sending them
out into the world and they're fucked.
These people are fucked.
If you can run into those people,
they can ruin your fucking life.
And that's a fact.
So there's no way of fixing them either,
by the way, they might fix themselves,
but it depends on the severity
of how fucked up they are.
Some people are too far fucked.
You never bring them back.
And those people are out there
wandering through the world too.
So when people see that and they see
that you can't treat that with love.
And some people say, well, you got
to treat him with love. And they go,
oh you fucking liberals ruin everything.
And then you have this division between
people that are conservative and that
care and then people who are liberal than
care and the liberal people think the
conservatives are cruel
and the conservative people
think that the liberals have,
you know, some idealized view
of the world that doesn't work.
It only works because hard man are out
there doing the bad deeds to keep the
world safe and they fucking
support the troops on their bumper.
The real problem is it's a
mass, it's huge. It's a mass.
It's constantly changing and
it's going on all the time,
whether you like it or not.
When we sit in this podcast
room for three hours and talk,
there's murders and rapes and robberies
and car accidents and lies and there's
just so many people that it's going
on in some way, shape or form.
Someone's doing something fucked up.
Yes,
and that's why we need to figure out how,
first and foremost,
how fix people that are fucked up.
That would should be before
we talk about going to Mars,
before we taught what we should be
concentrating as a whole, as a co,
as a culture,
is not just like figuring out how to
fucking frack or figuring out how to pull
out of Afghanistan, how you fix
all these fucking crazy people.
How do we think some,
can you fix them?
Could it be done with mushrooms
and Mtma and electro shock therapy?
Can we change their blood?
Can we add artificial fucking genes
to their system that induces empathy?
Is there a way,
is if there's not a way,
then we're always going to
have this vicious cycle of
dealing with shitty people.
Sheedy people making more shitty people.
Should he be bill
fucking shitty people up?
People dealing with people who fucked
them up their whole life in therapy their
whole life.
You know,
constantly talking about the abuse had
happened and then when they were wrong.
Cause it's defined them as a person.
And I also feel that there's so many
people making money off of Shitty people.
You know, the drug war,
the, uh, the, uh, uh,
privatized prisons and stuff like that,
that you're fighting against this group
who it's not in their best interest that
these people get fixed. Yeah.
Well, it's like anything else,
anything that comes along,
even if it's a legit issue like
global climate change. You know,
the real issue that a lot of people have
when it comes to global climate change
is when you see a guy like Al Gore
who's made a fuck load of money off of
climate change, then people start
saying, oh, it's a business.
These kinds of invested interest. There's
thousands and thousands of people. Like,
yes, but still the world's the
fucking, the climate is changing. No,
but yes, yes, people
are making money off it,
but it doesn't mean that it's
all bullshit. Like there's
a lot going on here, man.
It's not an,
it's like almost everything else in life.
It's not a black and white issue.
There's a whole lot of different
fucking things going on. There's,
there's people that are bad,
then there's a problem and then there's
people that are bad that that profit off
of a real problem too.
Did you watch the last vice I or two
vices ago when they were doing about the
drought in Texas? Oh, I didn't see that.
People were just praying to the
God for this and then they bring,
do you believe in global
warming? Nah, not really.
But then they would have
singing hymns to God too.
It's just so interesting about how like
people have manipulated other people to
believe in their best interest
when you're like, it's like, well,
it's not just that though.
It's also voluntary.
I've seen people that want to believe that
the world is not changing temperature.
I've seen people that want to believe in
global warming simply because it's like
the conservative viewpoint.
They're like, oh, come on.
It ain't cause they've been told that
from the top. You know, I had this guy,
Randall Carlson on the podcast recently.
You've talked about climate
change throughout the history,
the known history of the earth.
And it was incredibly fascinating and he
absolutely believes that a human beings,
and you know our carbon footprint
plays a part in, in global warming.
But he said that the real issue is
there's a lot of other factors that play a
part and they have throughout history,
like we're co concerning
ourselves primarily with people,
with what people have done.
And we have done a fucked up
job on this earth and he said,
I'm more concerned with the particulate
matter that like burning coal and
pollution and stuff,
but what it does to our air quality
than I am the actual warming.
Cause he started going off about global
cooling and about what it used to be
like here on earth.
And it was one of the most terrifying
podcast I've ever listened to.
Jesus this cause he knows a lot
and he's not just making shit up.
He's talking about ice core samples.
You're talking about known history.
Even just the known history.
Totally noncontroversial known history
that all scientists accept is that 10,000
years ago North America
was almost entirely covered
with ice and that there was
a two mile high thick
wall of ice over Canada.
Oh my God. Two miles. It's
insane. It's unbelievably insane.
It's unbelievably insane and
it's a fact. Oh man, that's real.
It's like this fine line between
wanting to know the facts and just like,
it's out of my hands, dude. He was also
talking about some without a doubt,
beyond a shadow of a doubt,
factual evidence about the
amount of species that used
to exist during that time
that died off.
I got a huge percentage of all the
animals that were alive back then.
Our jobs are gone. That's just 10,000
years ago. It was like unbelievably scary.
It's just a cycle in a weird way.
It's not just a cycle.
He believes that it ended abruptly and
it probably ended because of a meteor
impact. That cycle was like
how people dealt with life.
They're just like those people
that live up in Edmonton. You know,
the people that were in a place like
Canada, the guy, there was nobody there.
The reason why there's so few fucking
people in Canada and they're so cool,
it's because they've only been
there for a couple of hundred years.
Everything's fresh and new,
like a new chick fucking nobody there.
There was native Americans, you know,
some of them had ventured up there,
excuse me. But most of them, you know,
most of them fucking came, you know,
around the same time that settlers
came to North America, you know, the,
the Columbus days, that's
most of the, uh, the,
the people that wound up settling up
there in Canada before that man, not much.
And well, you know, why is
that? Because if you fuck,
a thousand years ago was under ice,
two miles giant glaciers do.
And I was there three feet dropped
the day I flew into of snow. I'm like,
this is insane.
Like giant walls of snow in between
each lane as you're driving where there
should have been like traffic,
little, little things, ma'am. Boom.
Just giant walls of snow.
And occasionally polar
bears and occasionally Paul,
I haven't seen one in Edmonton. Edmonton,
a woman was working on a rig recently.
She got killed, eaten alive by
a black bear. What? Yeah. Ah,
which is rare. Blackberries rezone
people, but if they catch you slipping
bears, you know, they'll
look at you though I might
be able to make this happen.
I mean the child down on
that tasty hot pocket,
you know what they're really
worried about. They're
really worried about hybrids.
Grizzlies and polar bears are
apparently getting their freak on little
interracial.
So hybrids
are very different than the regular grid
disaster. Stronger Blake Griffin's well,
they're more like polar bears
who are strictly carnivores.
So different seen a grizzly bear and a
polar bears. If you see a grizzly bear,
that bear might not give a fuck about you.
Have you see a grizzly bear out in
the fields and they're eating berries,
that bear might just look at go, I mean,
I don't give a fuck. It's plenty of food.
He's not hungry at all.
So the build a bear has a belly full
of berries and it's just sitting there
chewing along.
It doesn't give a fuck at all.
But if a grizzly bear sees
you and you're hungry,
is that the guy hanging out?
Yeah, it looks pretty good.
Kellogg mean Kellogg.
I think your chest tattoo.
Very Brock Lesnar is a new
thing I'm working on. Um,
a polar bear sees you.
You better run if not worth running.
Cause all polar bears do is eat meat.
That's all they do.
So anything that's moving a polar bear
is going to eat. There's no berries.
So I don't go where polar bears are.
That's a good move.
That's why I go with the La Jolla
California. That's a good move.
Where they laugh at me when I run there.
There's a polar bear den. The zoo though.
Careful that motherfucker gets out.
You're doomed. You will find me.
Cause he sees how slow I run.
He'll give you a thumbs up and let you go.
It's like when you see a retarded fish,
see a fisherwoman sideways.
You don't try to snag it. Let that
one go. That one going down river.
Did you see all the sardines that
are washing up in Venice right now?
I guess because the water got so hot
that it's oxygen and tons and tons and so
like now sharks are just dying and all
these fish keeper dying because there's
no oxygen. Cause there's so many
sardines. Yeah. They call it dead zones.
Apparently it happens all the time. And
the ocean smells like ass hole. Yeah,
it's bad. You know what
a good ass. I'll leave it
found out a way that they think they're
going to be able to bring back a plant
vegetation and shit in the ocean and a
sort of recede areas and a [inaudible]
the oxen and Jane the Ocean kitchenaid
and it involves dumping iron in the
water. Like iron scraps and iron
is a really interesting thing.
I read about it. I'll pull it up. Um, the,
the idea was that dumping iron into
the ocean would increase the amount of
plankton and that all these plants
would grow off of the a rusting iron.
Oh, the metal and the iron would
actually facilitate plant lysis. Yeah.
And that plant life would uh,
develop more oxygen in the ocean.
It was really kind of interesting
shit, man. Dumping Iron in the,
there are some people are way
smarter than I am. Yes. Yeah.
In this room, dude, I'm a human
being. I know. I hear you.
I have feelings. I know you do.
Thank you dude. Jesus Christ.
What do you need? Oh, cookie. There
I put it. Okay. Stop. That's enough.
Yeah.
Adding iron to the oceans.
They're slowing down global warming.
This is the idea
and they're throwing, this is a weird
fucking idea, but it kind of makes sense.
The premise is simple.
It says iron acts as a fertilizer
for many plants and some like the
phytoplankton that forms the base
line of marine food web need to grow.
They needed to grow and adding iron to
the water stimulates phytoplankton growth,
which in turn gobble up carbon
dioxide through photosynthesis.
This results in a decrease in carbon
dioxide and reduces temperature.
Since carbon dioxide is one of the main
gases responsible for trapping heat on
the earth's surface through the greenhouse
effect. Interesting. Unbelievable.
There's interesting shit.
Yeah.
That's the other thing that this guy
Randall Carlson was talking about is how,
um, this, uh, increase in carbon
dioxide that we have there.
They're also directly correlating
it with an increase in plant growth,
which is kind of fucked because we
always think of like people adding carbon
dioxide to the air being a poison
and they were poisoning the air.
But the reality is that plants
need carbon dioxide to grow.
So it's not saying that you should go
out and burn carbon dioxide to fucking
help the plants, but it's one of
those things again where it's,
it's not black and white for station.
They're cutting down the plants mean
there's last plants to take in the CO2.
And that's where the problem is
right now. No, that's, no, but okay.
But what he's saying is there's more
forest than before that forests are
actually increasing in size and
there's more plants into the plant.
Growth is actually increasing because
of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere.
But there's definitely concern that
people have, like in the Amazon,
a lot of different places
that people are chopping down.
Well what the real problem with what
they're doing in the Amazon is that those,
they're changing the whole weather
system in those places because these,
these plants, they're responsible
for, like they're there,
the whole ecosystem is wrapped around
these plants and he chopped them down.
Then you have these dry areas is exposed
to the sun where they weren't exposed
to the sun before because this is
deep canopy of leaves and the rain,
the [inaudible], yeah, this is
just flat. And so then it becomes,
they don't have the root system. So then
you get mud slides and then though the,
the, uh, the ground, it becomes
very difficult to grow crops on it.
It's really kind of fucking crazy.
Like what they're doing.
They're just chopping down trees and
thousands and thousands of acres just damn
deforestation. Yeah, that's not
good. What about cows farting?
Do you ever buy into that?
That that's a big problem?
I always feel like they just picked
something that they could blame it on and
like there's way more people. No. But the,
the amount of impact that a cow has is
way more powerful than the amount of
impact that a person has. But
there's way more people. Yes.
Cow farts. Every cow,
there's probably what?
100200300 400 I don't know.
But here it says,
my dad can crushed scientists say cow
farts are more dangerous than they feared.
This is trip man.
There's a real study.
How'd he has revealed that the amount
of methane greenhouse gas 20 times more
potent, but far less prevalent
than CO2? Well, so it's,
it would be 20 cows to every person
to balance that out or 20
people to every cows rather.
It's about balance that out because it's
20 times more potent if a cow was the
size of a person,
but it cows way bigger than a person.
So it's even more so if is product
five times bigger than a person,
so instead of 20 times,
probably a hundred times more impact.
That's my unscientific calculation.
Cow Fart is 20 times in the environment.
That's crazy.
20 times more potent,
far less prevalent than CO2
released into the u s atmosphere.
It's significantly higher
than previously thought.
We find greenhouse gas emissions from
agricultural and fossil fuel extraction
and processing. Uh, I,
he oil or natural gas are likely a
factor of two or greater than cited in
existing studies.
So agriculture just by
itself is a big impact.
Unbelievable man.
Blessing methane is a fucking
issue though, man. When I
used to visit my parents,
my parents used to live in Pennsylvania.
I was driving from New York to a rural
Pennsylvania and there's this stretch of
highway where it's all farms,
dairy farms and slaughterhouses and shit,
I guess saw cows.
It's unbelievably bad smelling like you
can't imagine these poor fucking people
that have to live in these areas.
And it was hot. It was in the summer.
We'll just that it goes back to,
I've been to some people just accept
that I'm from kind of that area.
I'm from Cortland, New York, which
is, is a Pennsylvanian Cortland, ours.
Same kind of country. You know
what I'm saying? I got tough.
I have tons of cows in my hometown,
man. Really? Yeah. I mean,
I didn't realize how redneck my
hometown was until I left it.
What does it smell like when you go back?
Because they say that all factory senses
like the sense of smell is a newer
everywhere you can pack your senses. The
sense of smell is something that alters,
um, or it, it only picks
up a alterations and smell.
It doesn't pick up constant smells.
So if you live in a town town
stinks like some of those, uh,
industrial you ever been in New Jersey,
when you drive it through New Jersey
and you smell industrial pollution,
those towns,
they don't smell it.
You only smell it because you're driving
for fresh air or reasonably fresh air
into that area. That's how you used
to be. When I went to Niagara Falls,
had this giant factory called Hooker
Chemicals and that's what the name of it
was.
Hooker Chemicals.
And you would drive in and you're
like this day like saber plants,
paper stink like up in Portland. Now
here's the thing about hooker chemicals.
It's pretty much been closed down,
but they won't completely close it down
because if they completely close it down
then they're going to have to
go through and clean it up.
All the environmental cleanup.
So they just keep like 30
employees in this giant factory.
That's just huge.
And they just keep it open.
Hooker gets cheaper for them to do that
than it is for them to hire someone to
come in and clean it up. That makes
sense. There was something, a love canal.
Do you remember the old love canal?
A thing that's hooker chemicals.
They dumped all these these name company.
Yep. And they're still open. Yeah.
And they won't close it down because
then they have to clean up the
environmental mistakes.
That's awful. That's weird.
Did they let them get away
with that? Well I, yeah,
that's good because it's like a one of
those legacy companies cause it's been
around for a long time.
I think that's just probably the rule.
If you demolish or shut some down,
you've got to clean it up so
it's environmentally safe.
And so these guys just keep it
going cause it's cheaper to do that.
Dan is so fucked up.
That's so weird.
Well it's the same thing with like
GM right now with their cars. Right.
They'd like,
they knew forever.
Don't they do something where they like
they guesstimate how much it would cost
to do a recall versus how much it would
cost to go to court and if really yeah,
if something's cheaper they go with the
cheaper option. Oh Man, I'm not sure dude.
I'm not sure. I'm not sure.
I'm not sure about that.
I think they do that. I think that
was the big thing on uh, what was the,
what was it? You got to pull that shit up.
You can't just say that. That is, if, if,
if it's cheaper to go to court,
they'll go to court. But if it's Oh, you
shut. Shut the fuck up dude. Seriously.
Okay, I'll shut up. You got to
Google that. We can't say that.
You can't say that when it comes to cars,
man,
everything comes to any major corporation.
They'll do the re what's going to cause
us more a recall or going to the court
if it, if it recalls cheaper, they'll do
that if course cheaper than go to cheat.
I, I've heard it. I don't,
I'll put I think can't,
you can't just say that when
you say something like that.
Like you gotta really know what you're
saying. I do. I you're saying GM,
you're saying like a specific company.
Yes.
Somebody might have gotten in
trouble for some sort of recall,
but it could've been a safety
issue. Google that. Okay.
I'll Google it right now.
So let me Google it. Gm. Am I saying okay.
Avoids recall. Look Google, Google,
whether corporations decide
whether recall or court is cheaper,
they go with the cheaper option. Can
you do that? I'm doing that right now.
It's from a movie cause
I remember something like
that like like right now and
there's not enough people that are
having the problem so we're not going to
worry about it. They, they guesstimate
if it's cheaper for them too.
You can't just say that.
Here's the problem with just
saying something like that.
You have to really know
what the fuck you're saying.
You've got to really know what you're
saying because if you just say it,
then you don't have to do that anymore.
It's 2014 it did actually find out.
So if you want to talk about something
and you want to talk about something as
serious as someone not doing a recall
because they'd rather just like get sued
because they can save money that way you
gotta know what the fuck you're saying.
But I'm saying now I know that.
But you don't know that because
you're not pulling up any facts.
You're not stating any guys in here. The
super computer, which was great hair.
Dawn is some legacy shit.
You don't have to do that anymore.
You have a fucking iPhone. You know
how to get online. Battery's dead. Oh,
we'll plug it in. So it's an old one.
Oh, well you fucking cheap bastard.
Go get a
new one.
When they get done with this.
I'm sure there's been some
problems with, uh, oversight.
problems with recalls,
but saying that they like actively got
together and said, hey, let's just, uh,
not fucking, let's just not recall
these things and just take our role,
our chances with the lawsuit because the
study has shown that we can save money
if we go that route. I believe
that's what happened. I have no,
can't just say that. Okay. I
will. That's how you get sued.
I understand that you could get
sued, Sam. What if they come, what?
GM comes down with the hammer of the law?
Well, they can take what I don't have.
Why would you say that you have a
number 11 on the fuck it's called.
You can do it for the move. You believe in
yourself. Believe in yourself. Go Rocky.
When rocky, believe in
yourself. Believe in yourself.
Do you ever thought about doing a
song like a wacky songs go along with,
I do like red bands, great
songs though. He has a,
he should do some live music songs.
Gm says safety is our top priority.
And today's announcement
puts all manufacturers on
notice that they will be held
accountable if they fail to quickly
report and address safety related defects.
Oh, this is us transportation
secretary secretary, uh,
Anthony Fox with two exes.
He said he would continue to aggressively
monitor GM efforts in this case and
called on Congress to support a
move to increase the penalties.
The regulator can levy in cases like this
from a maximum of 35,000 or 35 million
to 300 million,
sending an even stronger message
that delays will not be tolerated.
So this is what they're saying.
The GM was fine.
35 million bucks and agreed to take
part in an unprecedented oversight
requirements,
um,
on Friday over its massive recall of
cars with faulty ignition switches that
have been linked to 13 deaths.
The U s department of Transportation
imposed the records civil penalty for the
automobile makers, a failure to
report a safety defect in the,
in the vehicle to the federal
government in a timely manner.
So it didn't report it in time.
What does that mean?
Did they find out that it was bad
and didn't report it into the scene?
John Oliver's new show,
but hold on. I'm sorry.
We should figure this out because we've
been talking about this for a while.
It has something to do with that.
We'll go ahead and talk.
All right, well here I found it an
article to help you out. Sam, on Ge, uh,
justice.org, there's a, uh, they
all knew and failed to pdf. Uh,
it's called, uh, they knew and failed to.
And these are true stories of
corporations that knew their products were
dangerous, sometimes deadly, but
they failed to do anything about it.
And one of the things it says is that car
company that discovers that if it does
not spend $11 per car to fix a defect,
a hundreds of people be horribly burned
and decides it would be cheaper to let
them burn. What company did
that? I don't know, but it's a,
it's on justice.org though. If
there's a whole pdf, wait a minute,
we got to read that. It says, it actually
says that right here. What company?
A car company just has a car company
and it goes through all of it.
Like here's medical devices like
heart defibrillators that, that,
that the title of it
again, uh, it's called,
they all they knew and failed to a true,
true stories of course,
operations that knew their products
were dangerous, sometimes deadly.
So as far as a, this GM thing, it looks
like they definitely fucked up. Well,
you know, the reason I brought
John Oliver because he got,
he was talking about these memos in which
they would tell their employees words
they could not use.
And it's crazy.
Like they knew that these were death
traps and that they were telling their
employees, you, you know,
you can't say certain words about
the cars to describe to cars.
And they were like insane
words like Kevorkian,
NASC and stuff like that.
Here's one from Firestone tires.
Uh, I guess that they, uh,
they knew their tires are bad. Yeah,
I remember that too. I think. Oh,
they finally announced they knew about
it in 1997 and then finally announced in
two thousands.
Uh,
you know, I think that that
was a different era. You
know, that sounds crazy.
But 1996, 1997, like comparing
that to 2014, I mean,
I know there was only 20
years ago or 18 years ago,
but didn't it fascinating that that might
as well been a hundred fucking years
ago
that cause that was all pre
and in terms of the internet,
Morton Pinto, remember the Pinto when
it, we used to blow up all the time.
They found out they actually had a
chart where it says the 180 burned desks
would be 200,000 per death.
And then they just added up
how much it would cost to that.
And to recall a $11 perch car with uh,
looks like 11 million cars and
affiliated it.
Also the calculated severe burns,
serious burns 2,100 burn vehicles
and it all came to 49.5 million.
Whether, but if to recall 11
million cars came to 137 million.
God,
God, that's unbelievable. You know,
the whole thing was at GM
was trading their, their,
their, their people, their employees,
how to answer these questions,
how to deflect,
how to do all this stuff because
they knew they had a faulty thing.
And when was this,
uh,
this was when they discovered
the faulty part in their car?
Well, the, the, the, uh, actual, uh,
thing was an ignition switch that disabled
the airbags and the Chevy cobalt and
a Saturn ion. Did you have a
Saturday night on what do you have?
Did you have one of those a
long time ago? Saturday. Sunday.
Oh,
it's Saturday an l 200.
Oh, in the, uh, ion in the cobalt.
They knew about it for 10 years.
Chevy Malibu,
a general motors and new
for several decades that the
placement of the fuel tank
and a Chevy Malibu created
a big risk exploding in the
event of a rear collision.
So for a couple of decades
they knew that that was,
I never even heard about that with the
Malibu. I was hurting with the Pinto.
That was like a joke. Yeah. The Pinto
would blow up. That was the, yeah,
I remember that.
Still use the pinto as a punchline
the other day and I'm like, dude,
nobody gets that. And
that reference, hipster,
ironic at this point. It's kind of
hipster, ironic old Milwaukee beer. Yeah.
Yeah.
So I mean that's his craziest when
people start picking cash over lives.
That makes it sad. Hmm.
Well, it's just fucking evil.
Does it now that paper that you saw,
that was an internal paper,
is that what that was?
Yeah.
This is actually from a court records
where GM actually decided that they could
have up to 500 fatalities per year.
Each fatalities valued at $200,000
there are approximately 41 million GM
automobiles currently operating on
the US highways, and so they had,
they were like,
you know,
doing the math on the cable where they
doing the math about a particular issue,
Chevy Mal, but yet the amount when
it blows up. Oh, thank God. Yeah.
It's so awful.
I don't want to ever buy a Chevy again.
I don't want to ever buy a Ford again
either because the Ford fucking horrible.
Let's not the same people anymore.
Obviously,
obviously it's a totally different
group people, but still it's like, okay,
what is it?
What do we do?
We do we recall or is it going to be
cheaper just to go to court and deal with
lawsuits? And that's what
sucks. It's kind of like,
it's,
it's Kinda like one of those things that
I don't think is going to be around the
future. Uh, I think with like wikileaks
and shit along these lines, like you're,
you're not going to be able to get away
with that and not gonna be able to get
away with saying that someone's
life is worth $200,000.
And so we have x amount of dollars
invested here and you know,
we'd say 50 million if we just let these
people burns. Unbelievable. You all, they,
they should hang them by their ankles
in a, in a fucking room fold with Rad.
Do you think there's a level of like
psychopath that you have to get to be like
super high up in a corporation
where people become just numbers?
I think people definitely can justify
a lot of shit. Like you have to,
you have to detach from humanity and look
at people as numbers and resources and
all that, whether it's super high up, a
military, super high up and corporations,
any corporations. I'm not just
saying like, you know, uh,
oil corporations even just like high
up in entertainment, like, you know,
it's like sometimes I'll have to,
no, you don't have to be there.
But definitely a lot of the people
that get there are, yeah. But, but
I think that's all a lot of
that is going to be in the past.
I think it's still going on
right now to a certain extent.
But transparency is making it more and
more difficult to get away with shit like
that. You know? It's just, it's gonna
make it more and more difficult to hide.
What the fuck you did. You know, when
you were talking about things like this,
I don't think you can hide this
anymore, man. That's why, you know,
going back to what we're talking about,
all the hackers and all that stuff,
that's why like when this net
neutrality stuff is coming up, I'm like,
I just don't think the hackers
will let that happen. Well,
they're going to have to for a while, but
they're already fighting back. One Dude,
uh, hacked into the, uh, FC FEC,
SCC. SCC, right. That's what it is.
FCC, no. Federal Communications.
Is that what it is?
They are responsible for the Internet.
Yeah. Well they're the ones making the,
whether they're going to let time Warner
and what was the other one? Verizon,
Verizon, whatever. Ones can be huge. A
T and t is about to buy direct TV. Yeah.
And they're freaking out about that.
But doesn't that go,
who does that go back to?
Was that Clinton,
they've just made it so that every,
you know, they could consolidate more.
I'm trying to do that. But
the, the point about the, what,
what they're doing with the FCC is a,
that these hackers attacked the,
a SCCs website and turn
the FCC website down to 28,
eight like an old school, 28 eight
pit Mod Modem. So they, they,
they throttled them down. I love, this
is what this what it's like stupid.
Like you can't do this. This
is ridiculous. Yeah. Well
basically making it so, uh,
you know,
certain websites you can get to quicker
and then if they won't find mine,
it's going to take forever for them
to find where it is. It's evil,
it's evil and it's just another
opportunity that people have to corrupt
something to make some money off of
it. So people do, if you let them,
if you let them, but I
think transparency, again,
like this is something they would have
pulled off in the 80s like that no one
would have had a say about it.
No one would have even known about it.
Maybe a few protests on schools.
Yeah.
You'd be walking through the
campus and someone would be like,
save net neutrality. He'd be like,
Oh, save the whales, save the CEO's.
I got to go to class. You know, you would,
you would sort of like be into it
for a little bit but not really.
Totally understand it. Whereas now
it's like hitting your email every day.
Twitter every day. And my constant
here and about net neutrality,
I'm constantly hearing about it.
So it's this different thing where I
think today it's way hard to cover shit up
and the people that are involved,
the last thing those motherfuckers want
to do is be up for any public office or
being, you know, applying
for any sort of a job.
And explain your role without
eliminating net neutrality.
And what was your position? Well, he sent
the guy that who's in charge of the FCC,
like used to work at like
time Warner or something,
has something where it's like he was
high up and the customer is the king of,
has a co sort of an idea what's going on.
His head
isn't the guy where's the dresses?
Isn't Wolverine Holding hands with guys?
I've been so far though,
with the exception of the Wolverine,
I've been right on everything else,
right about wolverine.
And you know where he got the car thing
for him by the way, where it costs money.
I think you got that from
fight club that cause that
character.
Actually
I read that. I read, I read it
occasionally. Come on son.
How often do you read,
now I'm reading a book about the
Guy who thought his dad was the,
might've been the Zodiac killer.
Oh you seem that were really reading that,
you know,
he's not the first and several of them
thinking that their dads were the Zodiac
killer by, have you seen that
picture of his dad versus the sketch?
That's identical. Really? Oh yeah.
Imagine if your dad was out killing
other people and you were worried that he
was going to get you, but you want
to keep your mouth shut about.
Unbelievable because he's your dad
bullying. Well, the work, cause I bought
the book. Hmm. Did you
hear about that killer? Uh,
the guy from shield that just killed
his wife in front of the kids today.
The one actor a shield.
Think he was the guy.
He was the black lab cost guy right here.
Watch.
Remember fucking way.
I was on the news last night.
They showed him my tough God. No, he
killed his wife in front of their kids,
the kids,
and it was over a money problems.
I guess he filed for bankruptcy recently.
Oh, he had stopped paying off his house.
Ah,
fuck.
What is it about people I shot my wife.
What?
How do people get to that place?
Where do you get the kill?
Somebody that they loved at least
at one point in time, loved.
How do you get so low bankruptcy
problems? That's really, that's that.
Did you got to the point where you were
on fucking the shield so you don't get
back? Everybody was on one of the best
cop shows ever, so you don't get back.
Do you see it fucking guy who was just
has a normal life freaking out because he,
wow, look at them. They're man, Jesus
Christ. It's over. That is so crazy.
You imagine how crazy that guy has to
be to have just shot his fucking wife.
He goes from being on like one of the
all time greatest cop shows has a crazy
role on it. A really good role.
Like here's the gay guy, remember
man, you think that's
drugs also? Who knows, man.
I've heard stories about that people
owe Dan and their kids are in the house,
got hanging themselves. Kids are in the
house. It's like what are you doing dude
killing the wife man. Some, no. So,
so much more common than the wife killed
the husband. That's a fucking awful,
awful shit man. Real. Yes,
he was a file bankruptcy and his house
was about to go in foreclosure. Oh butter,
kill my wife.
It's not only ready to get a job or kids,
it's like the thing where people hit
that wall where they don't have any other
solution and you know, someone will say,
oh it's depression. You know it's, yeah,
okay, I get it. But how
does it make you kill them
now? There's no solution
and silver. I mean,
cause he called nine one one and said it.
Oh my God,
that's going to be used against them.
I mean like, what are you going to do?
Who knows, man? It's like, what do
you deal with that? I mean, it's like,
I'm not married, ma'am.
I just seen these guys.
He's married guys that are just like,
the only way out is to often,
it's always the always the
husband. So he's just so, you know,
it's like so funny because, well,
it's not always the husband.
I mean it's more often the
husband more often. Yeah,
like people that I know where the
guy in the woman, you know it was,
it was Phil Hartman was killed
by his wife, wasn't she?
Yeah, sure what? Yes he was. Yes, I heard
that. Awesome. Heard it all day. All Day.
She was on Zoloft and cocaine.
And when does she eat an ex escort?
I don't know how it goes.
I'm sure people have alleged that,
but you know, she'd go and fuck a guy
for dinner. Basically. You're an escort.
A lot of escorts out there.
God bless him. You know,
there's a lot of girls that go like,
go on dates with guys and that and that
for a free meal. Why not fucking them.
Just because they feel bad. He got
went out and bought drinks and dinner.
That's real. It does happen. I don't
encourage him, but it does happen.
You don't need to fuck a guy for dinner.
Joey Diaz has a funny joke about that,
about the Liberace movie. I don't
think he does it anymore, but he uh,
he goes, uh, he goes, he goes, if a, if
somebody buys you dinner and he goes,
you don't have to fuck them.
But if you fly a person out somewhere,
he was talking about Liberace flying that
guy out to Vegas. He goes, you fly outs,
someone's getting the Dick
sock. Yeah. This is different.
This gene,
someone visiting you.
That's like what people always have an
issue with like a girl flying out to hang
out with a guy and see the weekend I've
had the comics have heard that happened
to them. Like they meet a
girl on the road. Like, man,
I think she's really cool.
She's going to come out and visit me.
We'll see what's up.
And the girl flies out to visit them.
And then nothing.
I had a buddy who in the hell fluid chick,
he met a chick here in La
Fluor to Toronto. She took
the flight, got to truck,
cause she's from Toronto, got there,
never called him, never hung out.
He kept calling her like, where
are you? She like did, no, I can't.
I can't hook up right now.
She uses them for a plane ticket. Hey,
there's unscrupulous people out there.
Some of them have vaginas. Yeah. Some of
them have penises. Yup. No one's immune.
Yup. Some of them are crazy. Comes
in all sizes. Some of them are gay,
some of them are transgender.
There's some fucking shady people
out there in all walks of life.
What do you think about the word tranny?
Transgender and all that stuff.
I think of it's okay to call a cab driver.
A cabbie.
She'd be able to call a transgender a
training. It's just an abbreviation.
I don't think it's, I believe intent. I
think what we were talking about earlier,
like when you're talking about
what, what is rape? You know,
we all know what's bad.
When you define something by a name,
you know when you say like,
Oh,
you have a couple of drinks and then
you have sex with somebody that's rape,
they have sex with you,
it's rape because you've had three
drinks or we have two drinks.
Now it becomes rape. I think defining
people like this is this, this guy,
oh, he's a fag. Oh, this guy, oh, he's
a homo, this guy. Oh, he's gay man.
Like what do you, what's in your
mind? What's the intent? Yeah.
What's your in your mind when
you know, if Justin Martin, Dale,
we're here and we're like,
well,
if homeowners like you could stop
fucking monkeys, what would we be doing?
What would the word intent be?
Are we love Justin? It would,
our intent would be to make fun and have
a good time and with no hate at all.
But if we were like sitting
here going, well, you know,
it's pretty clear in the Bible that the
gay will suffer and we say it today,
let me say it to him.
And like in an evil way,
there's nothing wrong with
calling someone gay. Right, right.
But there's something wrong
with saying those words.
It's something went wrong with projecting.
Where is it coming from? Of course.
Do you try?
It's like Patrice O'Neal
when um, you know, he got on that
MSNBC show or whatever the fuck it was.
Would that lady lady who was arguing about
a opie and Anthony get in trouble for
a rape jokes, rape joke
or is it a joke about, no,
you know what it was was that homeless
guy got on the show and the homeless guy
w started talking about Condoleezza Rice
and he was doing like saying he would
rape her and then they got suspended and
what Patrice O'Neal was trying to say
was that when someone is
trying to be funny like that,
it's all coming from the same place.
It's all coming from a
place of trying to be funny.
If it's coming from a place where you're
trying to hurt someone's feelings or
you are discriminating or you are
being evil, that's a different thing.
It's not the label.
It's the intent behind it.
And we get all tied up in the words
like they were trying to stop bossy for
awhile. Were you aware of that? Yeah,
they were trying to say that bossy
is like the new cont, you know,
like calling someone bossy is like
they're doing that with,
uh, he's a what's a ghetto?
But what is the word that like these NFL
players we're trying to say gangster or
get oh yeah,
ghetto is the new n word ghetto when
he's acting really ghetto like a,
this one guy, uh, what's
the, what's Richard Sherman?
People really flipped out
on him because he was like,
went off on this football player
in the middle of this, uh,
interview after game and he's like, oh,
he's all ghetto. He's acting all ghetto.
And they were trying to say that's
the new way of saying the n word. Oh,
that's hilarious. Yeah. And it's just
an, he just becomes something new every,
you know, everybody wants to get offended
by other words and it's just like,
listen to the n word and the f word.
There's definitely history behind
that when you're asked for it.
Compared to when you're talking
about gay guys, right? There's,
there's a history of oppression out
there that comes with that work.
Whereas some every group wants get
their own word, but what about faggotry?
I love that word. I can
really say why. Okay, listen,
you don't like the word faggot. I totally
understand that you couldn't eat fat.
It's the same thing. I mean, listen, I say
everybody can say whatever they want to.
Either you like it or you don't and
we move on. If you don't like it,
you don't like it. Don't watch
the comedy. Don't watch the show.
Don't buy the product.
Move the fuck on.
There's two different things that are
problem here. Two very different things.
There's one, there's the, the thing
is people saying actual slurs,
having mean intent and being, you know,
a an evil person with evil intent.
Then there's also another thing going on
where people just going after words and
the use of words and trying to limit
the use of words and try to limit the
language that we use,
not the intent and not the thought
behind the words, not the, the,
the philosophy or the
way of looking at life,
which I think for most of us is constantly
evolving and changing from the time
we're younger to the time we're older.
We learned life lessons along the way.
We have fought cops. We, we make mistakes.
We'd say things we wish
we could take back.
We say things all the time and
then we see things that we,
you know, we realize her. Cool. Well
when you had to know six together,
you got a lot of
different things going on.
It's not just about the words themselves.
What it's about is people having like
good intent and there's a lot of people
also,
I think that they use these words to
inject some serious fucking hate and
vitriol out into the world.
They use other people using those words
to be more hateful than the actual use
of the word itself. You know, the
more angry like fine, you know,
youtube comments where
people think they're being
social justice warriors going
after someone you know who might
have a used an incorrect term. Yeah.
Or going after someone who says said
as disparaging thing about transgender
people or whatever the fuck it is,
and you're just going to find fucking
anger and hate coming from people that are
supposedly progressive on a scale that
you rarely see even coming from people
that are conservative.
What I hate about the political correct
movement is that how much fine print
comes with that word,
meaning like they should,
they totally accept it and almost in their
brains convinced themselves that this
person who they approve of uses the word
is actually use that word to make fun
of those who used the word is negative.
They actually convinced themselves of it.
There's so much fun about the coal Baer
report them. Well, not even though that,
yeah, that girl drives me fucking
nuts. If you don't know that story,
it's a genius story. Cole Bear.
Um, [inaudible] smart. Yeah.
Well this cancel cold bear was
this thing that started, uh,
you know,
trending online because they thought
that Steven Colbert put out a,
a racist joke, like pull, pull the
video. Probably pull us off of Youtube,
but I think it's fair use. Um, we can
just do that. Our article about it. Yeah.
But the two e two is her neighbor
spark suey park and you know, she's,
she uses a lot of big words and she
uses a lot of progressive lingo.
Well she was interviewed by us,
somebody on huffing, but let's explain.
It's explained that the thing,
the punchline was I'm willing to show
the Asian community I care by introducing
the Ching Chong Ding Dong Foundation for
sensitivity to orientals or whatever.
And it was meant to be a satirical analog
to the Washington Redskins original
Americans Foundation, which is
hilarious. Yeah. I mean, it's funny.
It's so funny when you
hear it coming from Kobe.
He's making fun of their callous,
how safe they are that the people who want
to keep the name red skins. So people,
some people only saw one part of it.
And I think it was a tweet
that was a was put out.
So cancel cold bear,
um,
to comedy central actually
put out the tweet,
the hashtag cancel cold bear became one
of Twitter's twinning trending topics
across the United States.
And it was because this one chick,
but it's not just her because
whether she was wrong,
I mean she might have like saw that and
overreacted and didn't understand what
was going on. That tire didn't see
the whole thing, just saw part of it,
started it off and then boom, she was
caught up in this wave of interaction.
Well I would say I would disagree with
that statement that she was caught up in
it because she would keep doing
interviews about, well after, you know,
like a week or so after people are like,
you understand it's satire.
And then the guy interview
on this hub team posting,
which was really funny and she's like,
I know it's sad. And she gives the,
the literal definition of satire,
meaning that she basically read what the
definition was. She didn't get the joke,
well, here's where it gets
even better by lunchtime.
Deadspin published a post by two Korean
American writers with the tongue and
cheek headline Guccis
don't get redskin joke.
So fellow Asian Americans were attacking
her and cancel co bear became a joke
more than anything.
And then not only did it not get canceled,
well he got the goddamn tonight show
or the late show with David Letterman.
He's the new lunch almost makes me wonder
if the whole thing was fake. I mean,
my hope opinion is that I'm
starting to see like these things,
these internet outrageous over statements
being made by comedians and it almost
gets to the point where I sometimes I
wonder if they're just fake outrage.
Just the drum up publicity behind this.
What's being said?
No, it's people realize
that they can get attention.
That's exactly what's going on.
They would realize they can get attention
or they get attention by pretending to
be upset at something.
Or what if the people who said the
statement people behind them drum up fake
outrage. Put out this,
pull up this outrage.
P O u t outright cash rage a
of Suey Park as co bear lands,
the late show. There's this guy who
does, is a online commentary, uh,
picking apart everything from this,
this controversy to feminism
to everything. I mean he's,
he's pretty hilarious.
So we palm council coal there,
his name is that under
phones in Time magazine,
Corose promotion of more white male
celebrities prove is it the entertainment
industry has perfected the
development of white cis,
straight male characters
and the marginalization of
other voices except one of
those others.
A bolt in only to eat in
the punchline of a joke.
This is a,
they're showing people
of color being bad ass
and women.
This is all the voices except one of
those others are boarding only to eat in
the CIC.
Punchline joke is complete.
This is aggression.
We do not have to accept,
we will protect this until
it ends of this one to seven,
just immediately.
Young Asian American women with
little institutional power.
I'm not supposed to be loud.
Our voices are not expected to be
ready on believable. Oh, raised.
They're not meant to travel.
Actually silly.
If you all lucky they weren't following
that. There's the old saying goes,
it's better to remain silent and before
to fall the top open one's mouth and
remove all doubt
and how genocide and slavery in oriental
have them all work together to uphold
white supremacy. Right. Really kind of
the way that I understand as my work,
which is why a lot of my work,
anything essentially with these
mainstream Asian American activist groups,
because the simple truth is the young
people generally don't hold institutional
power because they lack
general experience.
They'd like life experience.
Now I know you left home to go
to university for a year or two.
My mom just came home.
Okay, maybe you went to university for
a year or two and now you think you know
everything about the world
president suing you park.
They all shrunk as you with your 23
year old wisdom set about solving of the
world's problems and
many will have chuckle,
a quiet chuckle of mirth.
And then I sold as you got
whole lot on your own Hubris,
only about a week or so after your
campaign though, cancel Colbert.
It turns out the coal bat was indeed
couldn't cancel and instead he's now going
to take over the reins from David
Letterman on the eminently prestigious
leacher.
Oh this seems to trigger,
these tears are range from you
in your latest article. It's not,
oh you were till we say it's all the
is a taste of unfashionable sorrow.
They are.
So the white man as you frequently refer
to him has now become the beloved white
one.
Yeah.
Because being white must mean that
the white man was always reasonable,
always pure,
always deliberate,
always complex and always innocent.
So he continues the recent which the
game by correcting us dismissing.
Yes.
No, this is kind of unfair. And
this is like a part of the Internet.
You know that a young person.
Cause if I was 23 and you ask my
opinions on virtually anything,
you would get something
half as intelligent as that.
We're all idiots at 23 years old.
Well No,
just a bit unfair about just
the nature of the Internet that
someone can just,
I agree man.
But I just think there's something in
this country we're like, and listen,
racism does exist.
100% save it for that real rate.
This fake out. This girl wants, this
girl wants credit for oppression.
She never went through. Well, she's got
a tension. That's what's going on her.
Her Butler, her like her, her brothers
are like all doctors and lawyers.
I mean like she's, I mean I
do joke about her, you know,
it's like she's born in like 1991 like
talk about the dark years of 98 we'll
Usui like what did you go through in
1988 the oppression that you had to go
through, like they didn't let you wear
your hello kitty backpack to school.
Like that's racist. No, it's not. Ranking
them on Asians were in hello kitty is,
I'll totally okay. Call me racist them
right. Shuts my points at least racial.
That's my point. What are you going
through? I don't think you have a point.
I'm going to be honest with you.
I do have a point.
What was 98 that's the year where you
kind of come into consciousness like point
is there,
was it just the thought of that?
She's trying to equate what she's
gone through with like what,
but I don't think she is.
You know what she is?
She's getting attention and then she's
running with it and I think you know,
as much as she might have thought she's
thought this stuff out, what's going on?
Is she looking at a white belt in life?
She's a white belt.
She's a young person who's sort of, you
know, maybe she's smart, maybe she's not.
I don't know. Maybe she's educated.
Maybe she's not. I don't really know.
It's hard to tell from this because
what you have is a bright spotlight on a
person who probably shouldn't have had
it on them. Yup. Made a big mistake,
hit a chord.
That chord is the racism cord and hit it,
hit it accidentally because
didn't understand the
satire of have a joke and it
didn't understand the context of a tweet
that it was a part of a much larger
piece.
And,
and taking that out of context and
running with it connected to a system.
And once she's a part of that system,
once she starts being
interviewed and you know,
people were calling her a fucking
idiot on Fox News. Like I said,
I think it was Fox News where
someone called her stupid, like he,
the guy actually called her stupid.
Like I said, you're, you're,
what you're saying is so
stupid that I can't even,
whatever the fuck the guy's statement was.
The point was he called her stupid.
Like that's when you gotta
be pretty fucking bad at
relaying a point on the news
for someone to call you stupid.
Well, I, I just, I mean,
I understand that to have 23 it's just,
she's a black belt. She's white belt.
He's cute though. Yeah. That's my
whole thing. Who's been meaning?
Who has been more oppressive
to hot young Asian girls?
Why old white men or like they're
Asian parents. A young kid.
She's young kid, you know, she's 23 years
old. Yeah. She so she was called stupid.
Um,
by uh,
Josh Huffington post lives.
Josh Zaps.
That was a funny interview in a heated
debate. Yeah. It's kind of funny,
by the way. She's doing the interview
on that one in the background.
She has stuffed animals on her bed.
Meanwhile, she wrote after that in case
anyone thought I was censoring Cole Bear,
please know that I was just talked down
to muted and silenced by Josh Zips and
Huffington Post live.
And then Josh Zap tweets to her,
uh,
the righteousness of
professional umbrage takers.
Suey Park wasn't muted or silence.
I invited her to explain herself
and she declined. That's funny.
She pulled that whole thing like you
can't say that because you're a white guy
thing,
which is a classic like,
well that's a new thing. The
new thing. Chicago peeps.
I'm going to be doing a comedy show
on June 26th. Suey park rights away.
Show off the cackle. Oh my God.
That's not real. That's real. Yeah.
Oh, she's now getting into stand up
comedy, which is the store. I like.
Jamie Kelsey is going to coach her.
It's going to work out well.
We'll welcome you with open dicks.
Don't open your Dick Up.
Things will fall out of there
like hey is this is crazy.
She's so the guy said to her, he
said, it's just a stupid opinion.
She argued that satire is
supposed to punch up. Oh okay.
It's that thing you shouldn't,
you shouldn't say anything.
Oh please pull that up.
Pull that video up. Cause
Suey Park and uh, Josh zips
basically said that he's pretty much not
allowed to comment on it because he's
not an Asian man cause he's not Asian
and pays with white privilege.
Do you know like privilege
is a thing that there was a,
a recent article that everybody
critiqued or criticized it.
Some young kid at Yale wrote about being
told to check his privilege. You know,
this, this whole thing that's check
your privilege thing. It's nice. Uh,
let's pause that for a
second there. It's, it's,
it's a nice thing to want people to be
kind and considerate is a nice thing.
But when you give them a tool,
like check your privilege,
whenever it involves anything racial,
you're going to silence the debate because
now someone is being told essentially
to shut up because they're white,
which is wait for it.
Racist.
So you're not even allowed to have a
point of view if you're the wrong race to
talk because your privilege,
that racist privilege.
So there's like a balancing act going on
and the white people are not allowed to
even debate ideas.
You're supposed to check your privilege
and shut up and listen to whatever,
whether it's a woman or an Asian or
whoever it is other than the white man.
I always feel that like
really young boys like, uh,
like young white boys have to pay
for the sins of their fathers and the
grandfathers.
I live near a high school and I drive
by it all the time and I see groups of
kids hanging out and
they're all multiracial.
So the whole experiment that's been done
in this country about making everybody
integrated has worked to a point.
There's a lot of integration
in these young kids.
It's working and it's getting
better and it's got more room to go.
But I feel like young white boys
sometimes have to pay for the sins of thy
fathers and their grandfathers.
There's this whole thing in the Mba
that people get really mad that the last
couple spots on an NBA team tend to be
given to guys and there are really upset
because you know, it's like well why
should they be making that for white kids?
Well it's the same thing that
they're doing in Hollywood where, uh,
you know where the,
the TV shows have to have multiracial,
multiracial characters.
The commercials are multiracial so the
young kids see themselves in there and
realize they could do that too.
It's about reaching everybody.
Well as I grew up as a young kid
who wanted to play pro basketball,
there was a woman, yeah. You know,
I wanted to play pro basketball and
I wanted to be the first white guy,
the plan Georgetown's basketball team.
Cause at the time it was all black guys.
Right. And I always wanted to be on
that cause I want to be the white kids.
So I can understand to a point why you
have a couple of white guys on the team
because a lot of kids who are young,
white kids dream of being plain
dream of playing pro basketball.
So it's the same thing.
The thoughts of,
of action for white
people. Tools point. Yeah.
I think that here's the problem with all
this white guy stuff. Without a doubt,
white people have it
Wazier way better way, way, way,
way, way complaining it. Yep.
All about it makes you look like a
fucking idiot because the idea of white
privilege,
the real idea is that white people have
an advantage and they had an advantage
culturally and how they're treated
by society. I think that's true.
I think it's 100% true.
It doesn't mean that you should have to
check your white privilege when you're
talking about ideas cause he cause
saying something like that to someone.
You're not saying, hey look,
white people have an advantage.
But realistically that's all unfair and
we should all be equal and we should all
be one and just let's just go and talk
about ideas from an even playing field.
I totally agree.
But this whole thing of like anybody
having an issue on something,
but then again,
imagine if you were going to school and
you are a black guys experienced a lot
of oppression, some rich white twat
was giving you some dude who just like,
you know,
grew up with rich parents on the fucking
Hamptons and he's giving you a hard
time and he doesn't understand that he
got a fucking easy run. The sperm. Yeah.
So you would want to say
check your privilege to him.
I checked. I get that too.
I get it when it's appropriate to
let everyone know, like, look dude,
you got lucky. You, you, you fucking,
you found five aces. That's what it is.
You were, you were born on third
base. He didn't hit a triple. Okay,
you're right there.
I got lucky as fuck.
And that's a lot of people
and that's annoying to folks.
But the idea that a white person can't
have an opinion about satire because he's
white and he doesn't understand what
it's like to be an Asian woman who didn't
get the joke. Holy Shit, that's
dumb. I agree. But that's the PR.
The problem is she's 23, she's
23 years old. She's, you know,
a young person with ideas that maybe
aren't completely formed yet thrust into
this weird position to defend
something that was a mistake.
I've always said that, uh, you
know how the Israel, Israel,
you have to serve in the army.
I've always felt that people in America
after they graduate high school,
high school, they should all
have to wait tables at Denny's.
Dude,
I'll tell you this man,
people aren't canceling core bear
up and fucking Edmonton. Okay?
They're beaten seals to keep
their fire warm. They're fucking,
it's cold as shit up there.
It's a different world.
If you have this really fucking easy life,
you start finding shit to bitch about
and you start finding shit when you have
his Internet connection,
you have the ability to get a bunch
of other knuckleheads involved.
You start bitching about shit and you
find that there's a bunch of people that
it resonates with and then
you're caught up in a wave,
you caught up in a wave of attention
and you see it all the time.
A lot of these people that are the
so called social justice warriors,
they're aggressively asshole ish.
Oh.
I also think there's a lot of it
that there's a lot of personal.
They're trying to make a dollar off.
They're like the Susie chew now she's
going to go out there and you should
choose. So what park wood over
him is more racism. I'm first,
it was hello kitty now as soon as you
chew. So she's gonna go out there.
She going to do stand up.
She's probably going to write a book.
She's going to be making an appearance.
It's only eight and four.
Let her make the money.
But my point is how much of it is pure
B B behind actual wanting change and how
much is it just to make a buck
off it? Well, I don't know,
but let's listen to this video because
it's quite fascinating. I liked it.
This a Joshua's apps video weeding.
Suey Park. No, don't do that asshole.
What are you doing man?
Don't do that.
I was going to ask her if she want
to do podcasts. Dude, don't do that.
Oh God. Uh, cancel Cole Bear.
That's what some Twitter users are
demanding after the call. Bear rapport.
Put out an album now deleted
tweet reading. I'm willing
to show Asian community.
I care by introducing the Ching Chong
Dingdong Foundation for sensitivity to
orientals or whatever they're set off
a Twitter firestorm late Thursday night
with people sounding off.
Hashtag cancel call back cause we
really don't need another white liberal
celebrity trying to justify racism
using satire that ironically ridiculous
Asians is not productive for indigenous
or nor any marginalized group.
White humor blows.
Hashtag cancel call bear.
Why and the willows via
suey park white people.
Please keep a hashtag cancel Colby
or trending until there's an apology.
This is not the burden of people
of color. Fix it. Do something.
Joining us now is the author
of that very same tweet.
So we park and also still
with us is huffpost politics
reporter Jason Lincoln's.
Thanks for being with us. Sui
acquire. Thanks for having me.
Why cancel Cole Bear?
What did you hope to achieve with that?
Well, that's a loaded
question. I think it's sad,
but unfortunately a lot of times our
demands aren't really met unless we have
really serious asks, are we generating
these larger conversations? Um,
unfortunately people usually don't listen
to us when we're being reasonable. So,
um,
I think it's really to make a statement
that this sort of thing happens weekly,
that I'm Asian Americans
are always a punchline. Um,
and so I think we're just trying to
make a point that people will be held
accountable the next time
they do these studies.
So just to clarify the context,
the tweet was related to a segment
that was lampooning Dan Snyder,
who is the owner of a certain Washington
DC football team that has a racist name.
It was meant to be, it was
meant to be satire. I mean,
do you understand the point of
satire that you say something that's
intentionally absurd in order to ridicule
or not the people who are the target
of what you're saying, but the pit,
but other people who might say it
of I understand satire.
I'm a writer.
I think that tire caters to the
audience that you're speaking to you.
So it says something about what the
audience finds humorous or acceptable when
you're using this sort of
jokes. And I think that Tyra's
supposed to punch up. Um,
so unfortunately he's not doing that when
he draws a parallel to orientalism to
make a point about a
native American mascot,
but isn't his point that there are lots
of stupid racist people who isn't even
in their attempt to be
conciliatory on race,
end up putting their foot in
it and saying something dumb.
I really don't think that we're going
to end racism by joking about it.
Like I'm glad that the white liberal,
it feel like they are less rates.
That's because they can joke about
people that are more explicitly racist,
but that actually does nothing to help
people of color. Why? Why attack us?
Tickle,
attack on dance,
not as racism instead of just
attacking dance night as racism.
Uh, well if you're familiar
with my activism where my work,
I've been very vocal about
a native American mascot.
So I went to the University of Illinois
for my undergraduate career and when we
had [inaudible] and I was incredibly
vocal about it and I had the same sort of
backlash,
um,
and that kind of backlash happens no
matter what you're really attacking,
whether it be, um, you know, the word
oriental being used as a slur, um,
yellow face jokes against Asian American
people or if I'm really just talking
about native American mascots and Dan
Snyder, um, I know I helped trend,
I'm not your mascot. Um, on
Superbowl night. Um, if I, you know,
the name red skins and not your Tonto.
And I had the same sort
of backlash though.
It really isn't fair to
kind of individualize these
things and ask why I'm not
shifting my behavior.
Because honestly,
if white liberals cared about
really getting rid of the mascot,
there's a lot they can do to help organize
or get involved besides caring about
their joke. So for them, it's not
really about whether or not, um,
the Redskins exists or
whether or not racism is over.
It's really about them feeling
like they can't have fun anymore.
I'm feeling entitled to be able to laugh
at things that aren't really funny.
Jason, a part of the whole, the whole gag
here is the use of the term orientalism,
which is such a weird old loaded, like
it's just, it, it's a stupid, stupid,
a word that the butt to
get upset about that,
about the use of that word when it's
in a satirical context strikes me as
misguided.
I want to take a look though at a
tweet which a cold bear rapport has a,
has tweeted out,
says for the record,
bear rapport is not the white man.
You know,
hang on till we all come to you
in just a sec. Uh, for the record,
cold bear rapport is not controlled
by Stephen Colbert. All his show.
He is at Steven at home.
Sorry for the confusion. I,
Kobe himself has responded to
some of the criticism on Twitter.
Hashtag cancel Kobe. I agree. Just saw
at Colby report tweet. I share your rage.
Who is that though? I'm Steven at home.
Uh, so you were just going to jump in.
Uh, yeah, I was gonna say that.
I feel like it's incredibly patronizing
for you to paint these questions this
way,
especially as a white man.
I don't expect you to be
able to understand what
people of color are actually
same with regards to cancel.
Call there
being a white man doesn't give him,
it doesn't prevent me from being able to
think and doesn't prevent me from being
able to have, uh, have thought reason,
perspectives on things I don't,
I didn't give up.
I didn't give up my right to be able
to have an intellectual conversation.
I know,
but oh well.
White men definitely feel like
they are entitled to talk over me.
They definitely feel like they're entitled
to kind of minimalize experiences and
they definitely feel like they are
somehow exempt and so logical compared to
them women who are painted as a personnel,
right?
Oh No, no one's minimalizing
your your experiences.
No one's minimalizing your right to have
an opinion. It's just a stupid opinion.
I mean it's,
it's a misunderstanding of what,
yes,
you just called my opinion stupid.
That's incredibly unproductive and I
don't think I'm going to enact the labor.
I've had any to explain to you why that's
incredibly offensive and patronizing.
Explain. I just told you that
when the neck, that Labor, okay.
Thanks for being with us.
Sui Looking.
It's unfair. That's a black belt
versus a white belt. That's what it is.
I mean even if she had a point, you
know, in some way, shape or form,
that's sort of wrapped up in
all this fucking craziness.
Even if she had a point, it's just
what if, what if she's complaining?
Like to me it's,
it's so interesting cause some of the
most damaging Asian racial material is
done by Asian comedians. Like what's
your take on that? Well they do.
Why do they do it though? They do it
because it works like why they do it.
They do it to break the
ice like why they got fat,
guys tell fat jokes so that you can't,
right? Because if you go on stage,
you're a fat fuck and your entire act
is just about all. She's called me fat.
Fuck Bro. I said if you know, if you're
a guy and you're, you're a giant guy,
you better talk about that on stage.
I agree.
Because if you don't and the audience
is going to fucking pointed out what is
this. Okay. She talks back
and forth. Oh and best buddies
course Jamie Kilstein.
Oh my God,
it's so bastard. Just a show
cause is all a simulation theory.
I was choking when I say that he would
help her with her comedy. Oh my God.
It probably helped her with her comedy.
He means, well I swear to God
he does. I just can't. I just,
it's like it's great to males. So much
fine print. It's bad to be a guide.
Don't you know men are men
getting all these women pregnant.
Doing all the raping, building, all
the roads. Unbelieving are assholes.
It's a mess. The whole thing
is, gosh, it's, it's especially
in this country where,
I mean like everything I
know is not perfect, Bam,
but when you hear what goes on
in other countries by that it's,
it's just so big that don't buy that.
This is why I don't buy that.
People always say that, but we know
that it could be better. So yeah,
it's better than what it is. Another
kind of agree with Dell, it's,
it's a crazy thing to say with all the
information awareness we have the least
important thing to concentrate on is
how much better it is here. Right? Yeah.
About dwelling on like patting ourselves
on the back for making this country
better than the other.
Not saying that,
but that's what everybody
does and not saying that,
but she is sitting there and taking a
joke and just making it into this giant
global issue or she's trying to do it
when we have a situation in China where
they chuck girls when they were like,
man,
I don't expect you to understand
chucking girls China as a white man.
I think it's incredibly
condescending and patronizing.
Use the network to we pack.
Can I open?
I would love to you a man will
do it for laid down in Edmonton.
By the way, Sam Shipley's new CD
available to believe in yourself.
Believe in yourself.
You thank you in there and you please Bro.
The set that you laid down when we
were working together in Edmonton,
you [inaudible] did,
did it.
It was a lot of fun and that was
right before you filmed it. Right.
And we're recording it rather,
and it was really worked up because
a bunch of people that we came to the
commissary and said they'd saw me
at your show in Edmonton. Yeah,
we totally worked out ways.
Yeah,
we were at the river Cree and then
Sam was there like how long later?
Like literally the next week.
Perfect. It was awesome. Yeah,
and then they came down to support.
That's awesome because that was a fun
set dude. But you were only doing,
he did a half an hour at my show. How
long has the CD, you have a lobbyist?
Almost an hour.
So even if they did come to see it,
they still got a bunch
of shit that they didn't.
The fucking rob Ford stuff was funny.
Is that on this? That's funny shit man.
Get it on there before it's old school.
Fucking caught him again since then.
They caught him again.
He's at the comedy store.
He showed up with a store and
Brian didn't even pictures of him.
Did you get pictures of him that no,
I was out of town, but everyone, yeah.
I'm like, why don't we just open the
bar and see what we can get into?
If we were back there,
if that was like during the days when
I was hanging out at the comic store,
we would have the greatest video of
all time and he talking to rob Ford.
I would have got him shot. Sweat standings
are bringing shots to open, open,
open bar,
have fun.
I wouldn't call Uber in advance knowing
those going to be too drunk to drive.
I would have just fucking threw my
keys in a in a condom, swallowed them,
lock my car and just
start hitting it hard. Oh,
I would love to all the crazy cocaine
running around that place swallowed my
keys like a fucking drug mule.
I was so jealous watching everyone's
Twitter feed because if you're in La Jolla
and I was like, the one time I'm not at
the comedy story. That's hilarious man.
Have you heard about Drug
Carmichael? Rogan? What?
This kid named Gerard Carmichael,
the nicest kid. That kid right there,
he just shut his first standup special
was a one hour HBO special directed by
Spike Lee in the o are at
the comedy store. Yeah.
You know who told me that was the nicest
kid in Edwards told me he was doing
that there. Dude could not,
I mean really dude. Yeah.
Ian Actually came over to the
ice house after we had done it.
He did it like on a Wednesday
night, right? Yeah, I did
on some crazy nightmare.
Yeah. It was a Wednesday night cause Ian
went to see and then he came down to the
comedy store afterwards. Such a
nice kid, but that's legendary dude.
That is legendary. Ever stand
up on television is a one hours.
It's pretty bad in the most, the most
sacred of rooms. I mean the ors crazy.
How many specials have ever been done
in the or? I think that's the first,
well maybe they're smart and
opening that place up to specials.
They're getting internet. Oh that's right.
Oh well I don't want them to show soon.
I going to see what's there. We're
getting nutty. Why are they doing that?
That's the dangerous dolch.
I don't want them showing our live sets.
You've got to work on stuff.
That's why there was a,
with the laugh factory was doing that
for awhile. There's a comedy club,
and I don't want to say the
name, but they were, they were,
if you signed the agreement, the play
there, they record your set. And I'm like,
I don't want your record my set because
I'm coming here to work out material
that's fucked. That's fucked.
Yeah. That's not good. You know,
I think people that run clubs,
you know,
they're just trying to
get asses in the seats,
try to get people excited about the
colony. And if you don't do the,
the process of creating it yourself,
you don't know how vital that is
unless you're really paying attention.
A lot of club owners do know, but some
of them just think, hey, you know,
we're getting people to look, or you
got 100,000 views on youtube channel,
you know, Sham, triple. He just
worked right. New materials that hard.
We're giving you have a
great place to perform.
She should be happy to perform here.
But that was the thing about some clubs,
especially like the Hollywood
clubs where they have this odd,
this attitude that like working
there was supposed to be prestigious,
that the club itself was like the star.
Like um,
you're a box with a
microphone. Yes. Right.
It's the comedians that have
performed here that are legendary.
It's not this box with a microphone
cause they could've gone next door to the
fucking Hyatt. They could have built a box
there. I'll do, we'd have to do is say,
Hey, you know what? I'm not
performing here anymore.
I'm going to build a box next door
at the Hyatt. Let's pack that bitch.
And you know, if Kennis he never
wanted to do that or let them in.
Everyone or any of those guys
that made the comedy store famous,
ever wanted to perform next door,
they could have done that.
I thought after a wild Sam Kennison
started just doing rock clubs, he didn't.
I'm like sunset. Well he did a lot of
that. But you know, he's the best example.
I've talked about it before about a guy
who was really good and became a really
bad in a short period of time from
making it, just making it just the, the,
the,
the fucking overwhelming pressure of being
famous and being huge at one point in
time. Fuck, I just fell apart. I shrugged.
She think had something to do with it.
Fuck yeah. Dude. Boobs and it drugging
it. His brother talked about in his book.
Really fascinating brother Sam. Have
you read it? Yeah, yeah. It's good man.
It's really good. Get it. It's
great. But I'll read it out of print,
but you can get it off and go to your
house and steal it. Don't do, don't steal.
Sam, what kind of a message that I say
send to the, especially the Asians steel.
Do you see that?
A video?
Elisabeth Hasselbeck was talking to
some guy who was a former NFL players.
Now a lawyer, really smart guy. And they
were talking about marijuana and uh,
you know, she was, it was on Fox
News and Elisabeth Hasselbeck,
they're really conservative,
hot, blonde chick. The view,
she found her rightly place in the
universe. She must be so excited.
She's one of the hot blondes on Fox News.
She was like a reality show.
What was it like as survivors?
Yes,
it was on survivor and then she got
on the view and then a pop popup.
How and now she's a,
now she's Fox News where she belonged.
She is happy to be there
just spreading sate and seed.
And she was talking to this guy who's
a former football player and they were
talking about weed and the guy made
an excellent point. You just said,
isn't it going to send the wrong
message to the children? He was like,
if the NFL today decided to ban
alcohol use for all of its players,
it wouldn't affect teen alcohol use
at all. And she was just like earth.
Yeah, that's her. That's her face. That's
the face that she had. He was like,
there's worst things to worry about.
We're gonna have to play it. I don't,
I didn't want to play it. So fucking dumb.
Those conversations are so brutal too.
When you,
uh,
when you have long form conversations
like on a podcast and like say all the
things we were talking about,
whether it's we're talking about the
cancel called bear thing or racism or
privilege.
These are like long discussions.
They're long debates where if you're,
if you're going to really get to the
heart of something and find out a person's
real opinions on something you,
it's a very subtle and nuanced
sort of a thing. There's,
you need to really be able to
talk for long periods of time.
There's nothing wrong with that,
but when you're doing that on
a show like a Fox News show,
you have three minutes.
This conversation with this football
player was three and a half minutes long.
Football player turned lawyer three
and a half minutes and then at the end
they're like, okay, well thank you
for your time. We appreciate it. Bye.
We're done covering this subject.
We're going to discuss a gay
military people and fucking
what about gay marriage?
And they're wearing
cammo now what do we do?
We take camelback believable.
It is unbelievable what it's,
it's that form of entertainment,
that form of communication,
that form of entertainment.
Let's call it entertainment cause
that's really what it is. It's,
it is not just unsuitable.
It's not adequate for complex
topics. It's not, it's not adequate.
When you discuss the subject
of marijuana and teenagers,
if you discussing it like that and
discuss the subject of the NFL,
telling players that they can't or can
use marijuana and whether or not you
support that, what you're supporting,
if you support that, they can.
They can tell players they can't use it.
You're supporting people having control
over their employees. You're not,
it's no one, they're gone
from work. Exactly. Exactly.
You're not even talking about something
that they're like in showing up at work
drunk. You can't play football drunk
and you probably can't play at high.
Maybe you can. I think fastball plus
dealers do. They love it. They love it
of how big the moment is. Do you know
what I'm, they're not really thinking.
They're more like just in the moment of
playing basketball. Then realizing, oh,
this might be game seven of this playoff
game. Do you know what I'm saying?
To a point, you don't like the smoke the
weed that much, but when when you're,
when you smoke the weed and you do things,
whether it's Jujitsu or playing pool,
those are the two things I could speak
of. You play better. It's enhancing drug.
Yeah. You have a more, you
have more sensitivity, you
feel things better. You, you,
you've, you literally, you're tuned
into like whatever the fuck it is.
Better tune into distance better. He
tuned into the rotations, have a ball.
You tuned into the way a person moves.
Like when you do Jujitsu and you're high,
you can feel things better.
You feel that sounds okay.
You can feel movement better.
You feel balanced and shifting better.
I, the only time we ever perform high
is when I go to the underground cafe.
I'm doing it in June.
Like the Toronto. Yeah,
the 12th through the 14th and it's like,
I don't have a say in it.
As soon as I hit the stage,
by the time my foot presses down on that,
I am gone.
And it's just,
it's very interesting because once your,
Wayne,
why you don't have a say in it because
the room is, well basically it's this,
uh,
we'd bar that has a comedy club
in it and it's so much fun to do.
So they have a standup show,
but usually before the standup shows,
sometimes there's like an improv
troupe or there's an open mic,
which it can be like two hours long.
So people are a hot box and in there.
And then everybody smoked weed all
the whole time before the show.
The stamp show even starts and then the
standup show starts and there's usually
like two or three people go on before
the headliner and everybody's just
hotboxing smoking weed, smoking
weed. So when you walk out,
you're just walking into this just this
room of fucking weed smoke and it looks
like gorillas in the mist. Like you
just see black objects moving in the,
in the background under this,
like this cloud of smoke and,
but by the time my foot hits the stage,
I am gone.
I can tell you I'm high just
from breathing in a second,
just breathing in and I've stopped
going. Okay, I'm so high now.
I just accept it and just start riffing.
Hinchcliffe had a green out there where
he actually had to take off his shirt
and it's so unlike him that he had to
go like sit outside on the sidewalk was
after he was trying to rustle
up some boys that nice gay,
super twink tweak,
shining super tank,
put on an extra show.
Sometimes people that want attention,
they want it all the time,
not just onstage, offstage
as well. I took my shirt off.
I'm so hot.
Anger.
Mm.
So hot outside. Yeah. He's a, he's a,
he's a flirt. That's what he's doing.
He's not even gay gay flair. He just knows
what he's got. He knows what he's got.
He's like a hot chick who's married
and she likes to wear short skirts and
walked past the bar and know
that every guy is like, Ooh God.
She not even trying to
cheat. She's trying. She just
likes the attention. Yeah.
Just trying to like likes the head turns.
Get the party started.
Let's get people excited. Let,
let it, let her, you know,
let her know she's still rocking it.
Keep on rocking in the free world.
So we parked suey park. I don't have
anything against that girl. By the way,
if she ever listens to this much
love to you kid, I'll take her out.
Brian will take you out.
I don't think that's a good thing and
will help him cause I don't think that
helps anybody. But maybe Brian, I
don't even think it helps him. Um,
it doesn't help anybody, but he's
just saying that if you were into it,
you know you can hang out
with them. Yeah. I just,
I don't like anybody who puts restrictions
on comedians and what they can say.
There's this whole thing with
Leslie Jones too.
She got Leslie Jones,
she's a comedy store comedian one. It's
just one of those people where it's like,
that's why every time you follow her at
the store to education, you just learn,
man.
You gotta go up there and focus.
And she did some on Saturday night live
where she did an old bit that she's been
doing together about how she would have
been a first round draft pick in slave
days cause she would put out great slaves
and she did it on there and internet
explodes. She'd gets out of her bunch of
people did, including other comedians,
which I really hate,
man.
I need to wait and wait and
wait and wait and wait a minute.
She said she'd be a first
round draft pick. If these
is, she's a slave girl. Yeah.
She's a big tall, thick chick. Why would
constantly love to ask you for Dick,
why would that be controversial?
That's funny because well the whole
thing was at that one chick up, uh,
prettiest person in the world. It was
the girl from 12 years a slave. Right.
She on she it,
that's kind of where it started from.
Like what draft pick she would have been
and how Leslie would have been a first
round draft pick. Right. Cause she
could put out strong stock. You know,
you talk about that on stage wanting
to fuck a gladiator check. Yeah.
I wanted to make some fun like John Jones,
his mom,
I don't want to get in trouble,
but you know,
you know just the whole thing
about know how amazing that one.
Oh Mr all love for my oak.
It's all my luck.
He's just saying theoretically
in the joke universe.
Well she put out three super
top and super athletes.
That's the amazing woman.
That's the point of the joke.
And he had nothing to do with slavery.
Has to do with how amazing
she is and well that's,
that's what Leslie can you pull up?
Leslie Jones is ran on a,
she did it on weekend update. You know
how the whole thing was that you know,
so and I like didn't have enough
diversity, especially when it came to,
she was my mentor. I live,
she's on sending her life.
She did us a little monologue on
weekend update and people flipped out.
Oh okay.
I'm so fucking confused.
Cause you were saying it was a part
of her comedy special, but no, no.
It's a part of her standup act and she
did as a monologue on Saturday night live.
Why don't you do that? Because it was
weekend update and they would put to the,
she probably pitched it as a
little thing for that girl getting,
pulling it up. Well, yeah, I think
we'd like, you know, if we're smart,
we should hear both versions.
We should hear the,
the special version and the
version that she did on,
let's hear the fucking version
she did on comedy central.
Fuck the Saturday night live version.
But I think the Senate I live versions,
the one that got in trouble. Yeah,
but it's the same thing, right?
Is it on her special? I just seen her do
it at the comedy store a thousand times.
I think he only did it at the comedy
store. I don't think that was on,
I couldn't imagine someone would really
get upset about that. Oh yeah. I mean,
you just hear comics laying
into her and I'm just like,
what do what fucking comic who? Ah,
don't say Jamie Kelsey. I actually
tweeted the comic that did it and he,
he wrote me back saying that he took
down all of his posts about it and he
retracted everything about it. Oh,
cool. So what the fuck happened, man?
What was it all about? Uh,
oh, Shang I know Shang. Yeah,
he did it. Yeah. Oh, oh, got a little
crazy. Maybe he was drunk. Yeah,
I mean you took it down. So, yeah. Well,
I don't know who we're attracted it. Well,
I just, I just think you should, I,
I don't understand that the thought of
restricting what people can say you were,
it's reward and punishment.
If you like what he says,
you reward him by going to his shows,
buying a CD. If you don't like it,
you don't go to his shows.
You don't buy cds.
I disagree because I think that if someone
is saying something evil and hurtful,
that there's nothing wrong
with going after that and all,
nothing wrong with pointing out that
something is evil or hurtful. Right.
But when something is just a joke about
themselves and their own body and their
own race in their own origins, I mean,
and the idea that this is good. I play it.
Thank you very much.
Hello everybody.
Uh,
I wanted to come out here tonight and
congratulate the Peter on winning people's
most beautiful person.
And I agreed that she is very beautiful.
But for me personally,
I'm waiting for them to put out the most
useful list. You know what I'm saying?
Cause that's where I'm going. Shot
most useful. That's what I said.
You delectable Caucasian
asking for Dick. By the way,
let me ask you a question.
If you walked into a club and you saw
me and lapita standing at the bar,
who would you pick? Wow. Yeah, I
know you would pick lapita. Wow.
Well let me ask you this.
If he was in the parking lot,
three
crips is about to whoop yo ass.
Who Do you going to pick?
I would pick you.
You're damn right.
Sure.
And that's my point. The way we view
black beauty has changed. Look at me. See,
see, I'm single right now.
But back in the sleigh days,
I would have never been single six
feet tall and I'm strong Kotlin Straub.
I may look at me,
I'm a Mandingo saying you'd
rather be a slave. No,
that is not what I'm saying. I
do not want to be a slave. Hell,
I don't like working for you. White
people right now. Y'All pay me.
I'm just saying that
back in the slave days,
my love life would have been way better.
Master would hook me up with the best
brother owned the plantation and every
nine months I'll be in the
corner having a super baby.
Every night I'd just be in a corner
just popping them out just up.
No Bra.
Both slaps.
That's what I'm saying.
I'm saying
the number one slave draft pick.
Okay.
Plantations move on me.
I'll be on television like
Lebron announcing which planes.
I like to take my talents
to South Carolina.
I do believe that there's going to be a
lot of opportunities there for me. Now.
I can't even get a brother to
take me out for a cheap dinner.
I mean damn 10 a bitch get a beef bar.
It's weird that she had to do that.
It's weird shit to do it like that.
Like using him as I go, like Oh,
got a banter back and forth to make
it look like it wasn't a bit fucking
hilarious. So it was funny. I bet it's
even better on stage though. She's uh,
she's dude, we call like a,
we call their education man.
You got her to education cause you
got to learn to survive. She sweat.
Oh she loves the sweat
and Hog. Yeah. Yeah.
And then she used to corner me in the
back during the Dublin's days and just beg
for Dick. It was so great. How long
ago was this? Back in Dublin's Day.
You remember that girl? Was
this, what year was that?
Dublin's was like 2006
was it 2000 so yeah,
I'd say 2003 or four. Three or
four. Yeah. It was the early days.
Well Dublin's changed.
You know,
Dublin's was like a spot where it's like
a very few people were going and then
it became like a Dane Cook
spot for awhile. Yeah.
While the Fryer I sit the first year or
two it was great because you know Jay
Davis and Ahmed Ahmed,
it brought in this pretty insane
crowd and like you know people,
you would go up there and you find out
how good comedian you were and if he did
really well there were widespread and
then there's a thing where I'm not going
on after him and you've got to put
me on beforehand and people started
controlling the lineup,
sort of become a prima Donna and doing
an hour in the middle of the show and
stealing people's material,
sitting in the back watching and saying
that they were going to get their
lawyers on you if you kept doing
the bit that happened to me.
And that happened to you Dane Cook,
that's crazy. Sam Aaa. What happened?
What was the bit,
I did a bit about the time.
I was a big tool fan at the time.
And I did and I still am,
but I did a bit about when I got pulled
over by the cops and they wrote me a
ticket for like two 50 for speeding.
And he handed to me and I said thank you.
And I remember how stupid that was to
say thank you for this fucking ticket.
And I at the time I'm like, that's like
saying thank you after get prison rape.
And I used the line, I'm breathing so
I guess I'm still alive. Thank you.
Which is a,
a lyric from a tool song.
And they did on stage cause I
was showcasing for Jamie and I,
Jamie made me this thing showcase
regular where I would always just get to
showcase.
And then I just became a regular really
quick and I was going to do a showcase
and Jamie didn't show up. So I'm like, I'm
just gonna do my regular set, you know?
And so I go up and I started doing my
act and I do that joke where I'm like, I,
you know,
I basically did the joke and I got,
I got huge laughs and I'm
leaving there. And, uh,
all these comics who were my friends were
hanging out in the laugh factory lobby
and it was like Butch Bradley and a
couple of other people and Dane was there.
And I didn't really know Dane by
new of Dane. So I'm leaving with my,
with Scott Ross.
Time
is a picture of him shirtless.
So I, uh, I do the, I, you know
what I'm saying goodbye to everyone.
And I'm with Scott Ross,
who was my roommate at the time,
and I say goodbye to everybody and I saw
Dan and go, Hey Dane, thank you Mike.
Hey Dan, I'll see you
later. And he goes, Yep.
Oh, by the way, you're doing my bit
in front of everybody and I go, what?
And all of a sudden, armo rage just starts
coming through me. Armo rage and range.
Yeah, just that arm RMO rage.
And this is his latest Instagram.
He's got his shirt off and bedrooms
sucking the stomach into the point where
he's probably losing circulation.
He mean that is read the caption.
Does it say,
oh, well that's a caption and a half.
Read the caption. Thank you too. Okay.
Ah, all my fans and friends over my
career. I'm starting a new film next week,
writing,
then my next one and prepping a lot for
a press tours and interviews over the
next couple of months for planes to
a huge surprise and a huge and a huge
surprise. I'm in the best place in
my life. I love the people around me.
I have let go over my past and that held
me and I've embraced a future that is
whatever I want it to be.
I've worked with wonderful
charity organizations over
the years and I'm grateful
to have always given back and being
mindful that the future success depends on
how I can create for others now.
Oh
hmm. How and sign hardware. The
more pound signs by the way,
you have after you fucking statements
to more. I think you're an idiot.
I'm just going to let you know more.
The more time you Hashtag yeah fucking
you have more than three hashtags.
I can't really talk to you unless
they're really funny. Yeah.
And the last one of them says one thing,
one of them says not really.
And in the next one says something
even funnier. Other than that,
if you have a fuck fuck five or six
motivational hashtags like what he needs a
hug man. I mean maybe it's trying
to be ironic or funny Plone what's,
what's that Hashtag lets stop shitting
on Dane here. Jay Did you have an aging?
He's a,
you know it's,
it's interesting guys that were all
like in this great place at one point in
time and then everything is kind of like
kicked out from under them, you know?
And with Dane, like the allegations of
plagiarism, the, the Louis CK thing,
it was very similar in a lot of ways to
the Carlos men see it thing. It's just,
well I think men see us worse because he
found out that people found out it was
a Mexican. That's th that's why
it's, he lost that whole group.
That was devastating. You know, it's all
a lot. That's what people, Hey, I mean,
you'll always,
no matter what,
you'll always have a core group of fans
that no matter what people say with you
about you,
they're going to stick with you.
But Dane Cook thing was so crazy
that people were sending it to me.
Like people were like,
like laughing,
let's not go through all
his fucking Instagram,
but peep that people were sending it
to me going, what the fuck is this?
It's interesting. I don't know. Well,
I mean, he's trying to pump himself up.
He's getting excited about things,
trying to be positive. I get all that.
I know he went through a really dark
time, so that's kind of suck. Why? Why,
why he's standing there with your stomach
sucked in like that, looking all sexy
because maybe that's his cry. I
don't know, man. It's just like,
you should do that. You,
you know what you should do.
You should do like the same
thing that, um, that uh,
Steevo did with Angelina Jolie
where all the tattoos that she gets,
he gets this, you should do the same
thing with all Dane. Cook's tweets, Elvis,
and every time he does an Instagram,
you should do an Instagram in the
exact same pose with the exact same
caption. Hope my tits hanging out. I
mean considering what you just told us,
you know that whole thing. Oh that
was long. I know, I know, I know.
But it would be fun for a week
project for one, for one week.
Every time I do the same work thing,
he does just the same words,
same everything.
Poor bastard. He ain't a bad guy. Did
you, did you think he had a hard life?
Do you see that fight that as Seth
Rogan's doing with Macklemore right now,
now it's Macklemore. I thought it was
fine with Macklemore. Did that kind of,
he put on a costume and a lot of people
say it was a antisemetic cause it's like
it is.
Oh yeah,
I saw that.
He said,
hey that it sort of just a random costume
that a wig and a fake nose is just a
random costume.
It looks Hasidic.
Yeah, look at that. I mean that's
ridiculous that if he's even saying,
let me see the, the photo. The
image. Hold on. I gotta get it fixed.
Macklemore's the one who did it.
That's it right there at the grammys.
Who's the guy who's mad at him?
I think that's just Randy from American
idol or something. But yeah, that's,
I mean he says it's just a random witches
nose and a wig and something like that.
I'm like, yeah. What
are you trying to make?
What else are you
supposed to be right now?
Okay,
so what is a Seth Rogen say first you
tricked people into pretending you're a
rapper. Now you tricked them
into thinking you're Jewish.
Yeah. If you go to is Seth
Rogan's a thing? He's,
he's going back and forth with them
all day. Like, cause Macklemore's said,
uh, a fake, which is knows wig
and a beard equals random costume.
Not my idea of a stereotype of any,
anyone and then any, any anybody's.
And then Seth Rogan guys,
Mac more really,
because if I told somebody to put
together an antisemitic geo costume, they,
they have the exact same
shopping list and you know, yeah.
Okay. But here's my question. Why is it
antisemetic cause he's got a big note.
So what?
What if you did one,
it was an Italian guy and he had a wife
beater on one spaghetti stains on and a
lot of gold chains and he went on stage.
Maybe there's some fucking morons and
the Italian American anti-defamation.
They were playing about it. But you're
telling me that people don't exist.
It looked like that. They
do. That's why for me,
who's predominantly Italian wouldn't have
a problem with someone to be on stage
with a wife beater on and gold chains
with pizza stains it. I mean you could,
you could make a stereotypical
Italian outfit and no one care. Why.
If you made an outfit that makes
you look like an acidic chew,
why is that Anti Hasidic Jew?
If you can tell that that
looks like a Jew, why is that?
Antisemetic because Jews are
sensitive, but right. I mean,
you know what I'm saying? I mean, look,
we're not talking about blackface here.
Black face has a history of the Minstrel,
you know?
Well juice would say there was a,
you know,
there was a lot anti Hebrew propaganda.
It was there in Germany that
lead to the expression as well,
a third of their population. There was
but, but is that what that is? Cause the,
did they dress up?
You know what I'm saying?
Like I think it goes back minstrel
shows. It was tent, right?
I don't think Macklemore who had gay
marriage on his grammy song while he did a
grammy song is going to be antisemitic.
I Dunno, maybe I'm wrong, but I don't,
I don't feel that. But people
are like, there's a lot of sense.
They're not all Ari where they
can joke about it all the time.
Like something we're very sensitive
about that. It's too sensitive,
I think in that situation.
I just think, look,
if you dressed up like a Hasidic Jew, all
right. Say if you went on stage. Okay.
What's a, the rapper's name? Bad
ass rapper. Eminem. No, it guy.
Oh, ah, yeah. My motto, Ciu.
What did I say it again?
[inaudible] that guy. Montas Yahoo.
Modest yacht. Fuck you man. Say it right.
How dare you rude.
Um,
I don't even know what it was five
seconds ago, pretending I'm offended.
Um, Matisyahu uh, if you went
on stage dressed up like him,
is that antisemetic? That's, if that's how
he dresses and you dressed up like him.
If you said it was him, like
he was just being a Jew. Right?
But what was you saying?
These not just being Macklemore.
Was He in wearing that costume?
Was he like doing an offensive Jewish
accent or was he doing the same act or was
he just being silly?
If I can find video of it,
I just don't understand why
looking someone has to be
looking like someone or a
parody of someone has to be anti.
And I use my own nationality,
but I guess Italians there.
So let me ask you into being Italian,
that they're not really marginalized by
their, uh, well, there were people like,
I had a cousin, my cousin who's Italian,
he apologized. He fucking caved. Yup.
You never apologize.
Macklemore issues,
apology for antisemetic chew costume
as Seth Rogan heads out on Twitter.
Seth Rogan wins again. That's why
we went again. What does that,
that was,
that's my Seth Rogen from Yoda.
You fuckhead riced just stop
talking. Well, you know,
it's like a lot of Italians.
Hey, the soprano. So I'm
like, dude, it's not that bad.
It's, it's the, it's the mob. It's not
like he, he's not running gay bath house.
You know? It's like, it's actually
like kind of a cool, I don't know.
I didn't find a fence to it.
Well,
it's ridiculous to say that
people like that don't exist.
Like you're allowed to make a fictional
and if a fictional character is really
close to actual people, that's when
people start getting pissed off.
That's when people start
saying it's stereotypes.
But stereotypes exist for a fucking
reason. I don't know if he just went up.
I think you're right.
If he just went up there and
sang dress in that costume as him.
I don't know what the,
what is actually going on,
but
I don't read about it.
About their soprano's thing.
Like the idea of like
not using stereotypes is,
so in painting a story
is so fucking ridiculous.
Well because sometimes stereotypes are
accurate and if you're going to be able
to paint a story,
create pain and creative vision,
whether it's a television show or a movie,
what's wrong with having a black pimp?
Is that okay? I mean, it seems like
there's black pimps. There's been black,
I saw pimps up hoes down.
Is it a stereotype? I mean,
is this stereotype I tell people,
I mean, I've walked Hollywood.
I think stereotypes work,
especially in commercial.
It's like casting directors like, oh, you
fit the stereotype of the character. Why?
You know,
it's just not just that.
It's like if you want to
paint a story about real life,
you would paint a story about things
that people can relate to and one things
that people can relate to as an Italian
guy with fucking pizza stains on his t
shirt and gold chains on, those are
real people. We're in sweat suits.
If you got a guy like we're in sweatsuits
like fucking Tony Soprano, go, hey,
where's the gap? I'll go, where's
the fucking guy with the thing? Yeah,
it was his GED, the fucking GED. Those are
real people. Like you know those people.
If you listen to Floyd Mayweather, it's
dad. Okay, that's a real guy. Yeah.
It's a real old black boxer.
If you're going to make a parody of an
old black boxer and you had a guy who
could speak very well and he looked
like that guy and he started like,
if you've got Ian Edwards to do Floyd
Mayweather, would that be a stereotype?
Is it a terrorist stereotype
when he's a real person?
That's not that I grew out of them.
I understand it's a stereotype,
but shouldn't you be allowed to do
that when you're portraying fiction?
The idea that they,
that Italian American Defamation League
would want every Italian to be like
Leonardo Da Vinci or
Michelangelo or something like
that. Only the most positive.
You're not allowing
people to create fiction.
You're not allowing them to create art.
Is it because it's like actual facial
features are like Macklemore's knows or
Asian person's eyes.
That's actually what they look like
instead of wearing what they're wearing.
Right. Well I can see what
you're saying. So like,
like Jerry Lewis when he would do
like the nutty professor and he would,
they would, uh, the old days when they
would do like a fake Asian characters.
Well, that's obviously a precedent. That
was, yeah, that was very stereotypical,
but also very racist. What
about that famous actor, actress
who won as the,
uh,
orange is the new black character who
was black and she wanted to be that
character and everyone's like,
that's blackface.
But goes back to what is the attention? I
have no idea. Can you look that up? The,
the actress who went for a Halloween
costume as orange is the new black,
she's a hot blonde actress and she went
and black face as a Latino or black
character.
People like that's
blackface. But the intention
is if I'm a, if I'm sewing,
I want to go is Dwayne Wade.
There's someone when it,
that's it. That's her. Okay.
She loves to show what's the,
what's the intention there or do we
have just a set rule? Blackface. Yeah.
You can't, you can't even go a Tan
face. Yeah. 10 faces. Dangerous.
Right. If you're not tan, like
say you want to be a Brazilian,
you want to pretend to be Brazilian, you
can't do that. You can't do that. No, no,
no, no, no, no. You can't do tan
face. You can't do brown face,
but what you can do is wider face. If
you're a white person, white girls,
you can make, no, you could do,
a white person could make the fucking
like make their skin white as shit and
give themselves red hair and no one
picks up like no one picks up the slack.
I can go as Conan O'brien. Is that what
you're saying? That's what I'm saying.
Sounds like a Halloween costume.
Sam Aaa. All right, dude.
What's the name of your CD again?
One more time. I believe in yourself.
Believe in yourself, ladies and
gentlemen. It's fucking hilarious. Good.
It's very good material.
You can get it on iTunes or all things.
records.com if you get it right now,
it'll a pump Sam up.
Let's get them past the top 10 let's
say where he's at right now while this
podcast has been going on. Oh,
so we're looking for music.
Do we look for music and
then we'd go to genres.
Let's go to comedy because it's a
genre of music or some fucking reason.
And let's see where we're at right now.
Comedy albums number one
and June group are good.
It's been never went for a while.
He's a bad motherfucker.
Bullet one with the bullet. Brian
Regan's number 11. He's hilarious.
Louis C K is number 14.
Where are you at? Sun.
I guess I've dropped.
I can't find
a punch. Drunk sports
food. You're number eight.
That's why you're feeding Louis C K
man. You're beating everybody. Yay.
You're kicking ass, man.
You're beating Brian Regan.
That's why I couldn't find you
been beating Lewis Black. Powerful.
Just through the fucking power of the
Internet. I'm so excited to be top 10.
You're not on any TV shows right now.
He's just slamming it home to the
internets. I'm really excited.
Thank you everybody. That's my brother.
Congratulations. Best thing ever.
Ah, we're at Folsom, true
believer topped. Follow him on,
uh, tomorrow night. Ice
House Comedy Club, Bill Burr,
Tony Hinchcliffe. Me. Uh, who else?
Ian Edwards. God. Damn, that's
a show tomorrow night, 10 30.
You want to go up year round, punching
sports. Brian Red Band as well.
Brian Redman as well. Don't do
that. Fucking Nate, that voice.
That's not what he sounds like.
Oh No, no, no.
Just shut the fuck up. You're the
worst impressionists of all time. Uh,
tomorrow night, uh, ice
house. Ah, okay. We'll see you
soon. Thanks to the sponsors.
Thanks to squarespace.com
go to squarespace.com and
use the code word Joe to
save yourself
Manet.
Thanks. Also to onnit.com go to
o n n I t use the Codeword Rogan,
save 10% off any and all supplements.
Um,
the candidates that I got
coming up for next month, uh,
the Orpheum on June 13
selling out fast bitches. And,
uh, I mean, Lloydminster on June 12th
and I think it's sold out already.
If it's not, it's very close
to it. And, uh, that's it. Uh,
much love.
See you guys soon.
And a big kiss to you all
in one, one, one, one mark.
Yeah.