Hello freak bitches. Do you want to
really go down the rabbit hole though?
Let's do it. Alright, so, uh, do you
know Thomas soul? I know that name.
Why don't we do that name? Thomas
soul is a big uh, famous conservative.
He's at Stanford. Um, he's at the
Hoover Institute, I think. Anyway.
So you know, within this, I mean
first just to set all of this up,
we should set up briefly how
does culture work? Right?
And the way culture works is
that it like genetic evolution.
It works based on blind copying.
So what ends up happening is,
is that you are in all of people, right?
You look up to people and so you
blindly copy the things they do.
And specifically you start by blindly
copying from the outside and then you work
in. So the first thing you do is
you see someone in, you're like, Oh,
that person's fucking amazing, that
rock star, that sports star or whatever.
And you start dressing like them.
You start walking like them
and all of that sort of stuff.
Now in a Hunter gatherer
context that would be, you know,
somebody who is a Hunter or is a
gatherer and you're like, man, you know,
she finds all the best
guavas how does she do that?
And then UNG fucking eats
them. Right? Yeah. Um,
and so, you know, you would, you
would like hang out with her.
You'd sort of like shimmy up to her.
You'd be seeing what she'd be
doing or she's like, Oh, okay.
She looks for a very particular
color of guava. She, you know,
squeezes them in a certain way and over
time you learn what she's doing and then
ultimately you even
learn how she's thinking.
But in a large scale society like ours,
I don't meet Michael Jordan, right?
Michael Jordan just becomes this sort
of distant person that I idolize.
And so advertisers have figured out how
to hijack these mechanisms and they know
if you put a burger next to Michael
Jordan's face that I'm like, Oh,
I want to be like Michael Jordan, so
I'm going to eat a big Mac. Right?
And little children are dumb. And
so they blindly copy that or Oh,
I want to be like James Dean.
He has a cigarette in his mouth.
I want to blindly copy that.
And we don't understand that the burger
or the cigarette is not actually the key
to being as successful or as cool as,
or as good at basketball as Michael
Jordan or James Dean. Right.
We don't understand that.
That's where that comes from.
So we have this tendency to
blindly copy anything we can write.
Does that make sense? Yeah.
Yeah. And in, in a mass society,
we never work our way in. We
never learn the mastery, right?
We just sort of remain at this
sort of very superficial level.
So what that means is that
we're, where did this all start?
It's a good question. Yeah. Where
were you going with this? Well,
we are starting a culture. How culture
works, how culture works. Oh, okay.
So now we're going to talk about
black people. Okay. Christ is Christ.
So Thomas, Thomas soul, Thomas
soul is black guy, right?
And Thomas soul has for years and years
and years been trying to fight racism,
but he's been trying to fight racism
by having a conversation about culture.
Right? And the fact that
there are essentially two
different sort of, you know,
we're speaking broadly here, right?
But this is for the purposes
of communication. Um,
we're gonna tell a simple story to start
off with, right? So broadly speaking,
he puts two different cultures of people
with dark skin next to each other and
one culture is these people from the
West Indies and one culture is this group
of people who grew up in the South with
slavery and all that sort of stuff.
Now what one group, the West
Indies group does really well.
So a lot of the successful black people,
people like Colin Powell are
originally from that cultural heritage.
The other group is the group
that you find in ghettos,
in African American communities
and all of that sort of stuff.
They don't do well, right? They don't
get good education. The, you know,
shoot each other. They're
all these sorts of things.
And the reason why Sol has been telling
this story is because he's been trying
to say, you know, when liberals look
at the people in ghettos, they say,
ah, racism. That's why they're not
succeeding. And soul is saying, no,
it's not. Because if you look at
this group from the West Indies,
they also came from the
experience of slavery.
There was slavery in the West
Indies. They are also black.
So they also face racism
and yet they do well.
So it has to be something else.
And that other thing is the fact that
these black people who are in the South,
there's always been a big question,
were black people robbed of their culture
or did they preserve their authentic
African culture?
And what Seoul is saying is that
they were robbed of their culture.
And so they picked up the culture of
the people around them and the people
around them were rednecks.
And if you look at the white redneck
culture and the black redneck culture,
they have a lot of the same values. They
don't particularly respect education.
They love Jesus. They use
violence in their conflicts.
And, um, they, you know,
there's, there's just, you know,
a lot of the same values and a lot of
the same outcomes. And even at Bonox,
which is, you know, black English is
actually all from the West of England.
So it's actually this, it's from
the West of England. So for example,
if you go to places like Cornwall,
um, there used to be this amazing, um,
uh, these amazing ads on
British TV, right? For this, uh,
this Devin custard or whatever. And
they would always say, Devin knows, Oh,
they make it so creamy and they
would talk like this. Right?
And so it doesn't sound like black
English, but they do say things like,
OEB do in that and we be doing this
and you be doing that and they be doing
that. And so there's the use of that
copula B, right? Where instead of saying,
I am you are, he is, she is,
they are they just say
IBU be we be, they be,
which is the classic
feature of black English,
African American vernacular
English. Right? Now the point is,
is that how in blower mindblower
now let's imagine that.
How do you think that Thomas soul
has been received by liberal America?
Not well. Try not well.
And so for example,
Seoul has a book called black
rednecks white liberals. Okay.
And his whole point is that,
you know, if you actually,
and you know again like soul is, you know,
he researches the shit out of this
stuff. He really does his work.
Now if you,
if you look at the experience of African
Americans after slavery after slavery,
they do really, they, they start
to make real progress, right?
And a large part of the reason why they
make progress is because you start to
get a lot of people from new
England, either, you know,
black people from new England or white
people from new England who come down and
sort of reshape the culture.
They create these schools and they're
teaching those new England values, right?
It's those Puritan values of hard work,
tenacity, all of that sort of stuff.
And so there's all this progress
and you have people like Booker T,
Washington and Booker T
Washington was an actual slave.
And then after he got his freedom,
he got to go work in a salt mine,
which is literally the worst job ever.
And in Booker T Washington's
up from slavery,
he tells this great story about seeing a
schoolhouse, right? And that, you know,
he thought that going into a school house
was about as close to heaven on earth
as you could get. Like this is a
dude who wanted an education really,
really badly. And that's a lot of
what you find in the, you know,
early black experience in, you
know, the posts slavery period.
And in fact, you know, blacks, you know,
before sort of world war II actually had
higher rates of marriage than whites.
All of these sorts of things that you
know, are now supposedly a problem.
And then there's this turnaround, right?
The black experience starts to go
South, right? It starts to get worse.
And what year is this around? This
is post world war II, right? So, um,
so post slavery, black people
experience a, a rebounding,
they're starting to make some progress.
There's ambition and I mean, you know,
if in terms of books to read like w you
know, just to cause a large, you know,
a large part of what I'm trying to do
in general is really let's move to the
place of all people are created equal.
Like let's remove all these
stupid distinctions, right?
And really live that
principle. And the problem is,
is that in order to really
live that principle,
you need a new narrative that beats
slavery. So, you know, it's not,
if you go and talk to racist, you
can't just say, uh, racism is bad.
Like that doesn't destroy
racism, right? Right.
What destroys racism is when you make
sense of the things that they know, right?
They see, you know,
people who are violent in the ghettos
or they see crime or they see a lack of
education where they see that Africa is
poor and you're able to tell a better
story that makes sense of
the things that they know,
but also comes out with
the conclusion, Oh,
we actually all have the
same potential. Right?
But if you have this issue with
people imitating their atmosphere and
maintaining their environment and
this Southern style talk with a,
the Southern redneck influence
on the African American slaves,
former slaves, how do you, how do you
stop that and how do you turn that around?
Well, in general for humanity, I mean,
this is sort of a big problem
for humanity in general,
is that there is not a culture alive today
that is well suited to the world that
we're living in. And
that's because, you know,
culture is adapted to environment and
the same way as any evolutionary thing,
right? So for example, you
know, if you look at, uh,
like let's talk about these
Hunter gatherers, right?
The Yana Mamo or something like that.
So there's a great story in the lost
city ofZ , um, where, you know, uh,
Percy faucet, who was an
Explorer, comes across, you know,
all these tribes in the Amazon.
And one of the examples that the
author gives in there is David Grann.
He talks about how, um, you know,
there's this group of tribesmen in the
Amazon and what they'll do is there's
this special leaf and they go and
they squeeze this leaf, right?
They crush it up and this Milky substance
runs into the water and then all of a
sudden the fish float up to
the surface upside down, right?
They've been anesthetized by this,
this whatever substance in the leaf.
And this little boy goes into the river
and he plucks out all the fattest fish.
And then as the Milky cloud dissipates,
the other's fish swim away. Right?
Impressive as fuck. Like how the fuck do
these tribesmen who don't have science,
don't have any of these
things, figure this thing out.
And it's cultural evolution.
That's what happens is that,
that's the nature of evolution.
That's the nature of markets.
Because markets are an
evolutionary process, you know,
intelligent and answers and intelligence
solutions can emerge from just sort of
competing forces.
And so all of these cultures are well
adapted to a particular environment.
So if, you know, if you,
like we talked about American culture
and we talked about Russian culture,
Russian culture selects for pessimism,
American culture because you had to move
all the way across the ocean, right?
If you've got villages in Italy,
you know, Vietnam, whatever it is,
who is the person in
that village who says,
I'm going to go across the ocean to a
country I know nothing about and you know,
make a fortune. Right. It's
the most optimistic individual.
And so it's basically a magnet for all
the most optimistic individuals in the
world. The analogy I always use
is, do you ever see American tale,
the like old animated movie from like
the must be the nineties or whatever?
Probably. I don't think I saw that.
Well, it's about a group of us animated.
It's animated. Yeah. Um,
who made it? I don't know.
I'm trying to remember. Um,
it's not Disney. That's it.
No, I don't think I saw that. Oh,
Steven Spielberg. Well, anyway,
it's sort of about the,
it's about the immigrant experience more
generally and then specifically sort of
about the Russian Jewish experience.
Um, and it's about this family.
The mouse Kovitz is, um,
and right there on that,
on that, uh, trunk,
there's a five Moskovitz and five
Oh five. Oh Moskovitz um, you know,
in the first part they're in Russia and
there they're all being persecuted by
cats, right?
Cause they're mice and five O Moskovitz
sings a song with all of the other
Moskovitz is called. There
are no cats in America. Right.
Which is so much of what the American
immigrant experience is about. Right?
You're like, Oh, it's all gonna
be perfect land of opportunity.
The streets are paved with gold,
except in an American tale.
The streets are paved with cheese.
A American T. a. L. yeah,
exactly. Or T a I. L. T. a.
yeah. TA. All right. Exactly.
Still, um, so, so the,
these different environments, right?
Just as you have different environments
select for different, uh, different,
you know, beaks or wings or
you know, whatever it is,
select for different mindsets,
different ways of thinking,
different cultural traits. Right?
And what ends up happening is a weak,
become well adapted to a
particular environment.
So what happens to the point of the
lost city ofZ is what happened to all of
these European explorers who
went into the Amazon? Well,
a lot of them fucking died.
And that's because they're doing
things that are well suited to England,
like walking around and will suits
and eating cans of chip beef.
But suddenly when you're in the a hundred
degree heat of the Amazon and there's
all these animals you don't understand,
and you don't know how to use the
plants that you squeeze and have the
anesthetic in them and all that sort
of stuff, you can't survive. Right.
And what they called in the lost
city ofZ , all the explorers,
they called it the Amazon counterfeit
paradise. It looked like a paradise.
It was so lush. It was so
tropical, but there were like,
there's nothing to fucking eat except
clearly there was because Amazonian people
had been living there for tens of
thousands of years. They just did.
The Westerners didn't have the cultural
software that was well suited to
surviving in that environment.
So how does this translate
into African-Americans?
So what is the environment that created
that Southern redneck culture and the
environment it turns out is
hurting, right? So raising sheep,
raising goats and all that sort of stuff.
Cause most of the people
who are in the South, um,
originally came from the Scots Irish.
And when you look at hurting
cultures around the world,
they all have certain traits in
common, right? So if you're a herder,
well you have a big, big problem. And
that big, big problem is property rights.
So if you're a farmer, there
are clear boundaries on my land.
Now there are ways you
can try and fuck me.
You can try and move the boundary stones
on my land slowly inch your field over,
over, over, over. But you know,
what we usually have is we
have some sort of government,
there's a local town official that we
go to and he is responsible for policing
the boundaries. And so towns
would do things where, you know,
you would essentially all get together
and we'd go walk the boundary stones and
we make sure that none of those
boundary stones had moved.
So the intuition of people
from the North Puritans,
people like that is if we have a
problem, we go to the government,
we resolve it through the government,
right? In the environment of hurting,
you can come over and you can steal my
sheep and you can mix the sheep in with
your flock. And I have no way to prove
which my sh which sheep are my sheep.
So we evolved things like branding,
right? Where I have a brand,
I put it on my sheep and
all that sort of stuff.
But there's another strategy that is
used that evolved before branding.
And that earlier strategy is
being a crazy mother fucker.
You establish a as the kind of guy that
you don't fuck with you come on my land,
I kill you. You touch my sheep
or my women, I fucking kill you.
And I use such an aggressive level of
violence that you know that you know,
there is no point in fucking with,
I mean this is not plausible
cause I'm saying it,
but let's imagine a much tougher
person. Connor McGregor for example,
is a great example. You don't
fuck with Connor McGregor, right?
He has a reputation as just being a bad
ass mother fucker who will fuck you up.
Right? Right. So that's how you keep
people off your land. That's right.
And if you look at, let's look
at a couple of herder cultures.
So herder cultures include the
Scots, Irish, who are the rednecks.
A herder cultures include the
Mongolians, right? The Mongols,
notoriously a very gentle
peace loving people, right?
And they include the Bedouins
who are the Arabs, right?
Who had camels and all
of that sort of stuff.
And you'll notice that there
is that same use of violence.
And mostly they fight amongst themselves.
There's this inter clan warfare,
but periodically a charismatic figure
emerged is who unites the clans.
So Gangas Kahn manages to
unite the Mongols and then
one of the Mongols proceed
to do, they proceed to go use
that aggressive use of violence.
They have those horses which
allow them to move quickly, right?
And they're really effective. And they
go and they fuck everybody up, right?
Because you know, the gentle farmers
of China aren't prepared for that.
And the gentle farmers are
Persian, aren't prepared for that.
What happens with the Arabs, the arms
are mostly fighting amongst themselves.
But then along comes this charismatic
figure with the new belief system that
unites the Muhammad and he unites them
and suddenly they fuck everybody up and
they create this great
empire, the caliphate, right?
That spreads all across central Asia
and the middle East and all across North
Africa. Right. And in many ways that
is what Donald Trump is. They've been,
you know, the rednecks have been fighting
amongst themselves for a long time.
And then Donald Trump, the
Gangas Kahn of America,
the Mohammad of America has succeeded
in uniting the clans. And you know,
in our time you don't do it by going
out and like raping and pillaging.
You go and you seize the ballot
box and you vote and you know,
you really like take back power.
And so that's what they've done. Um,
but there are, if you look,
there are certain problems that
occur across these herder cultures.
So if you're, you know,
as a friend of mine who you're saying
essentially saying that the South is that
the reason why Donald Trump has
been elected because of the South,
because of the herder
culture. Well, and it's also,
so if you've read hillbilly Elegy, JD
Vance's book, it's, it's excellent,
right? But he's really talking
about this hillbilly culture.
And so it's not just the South,
right? So what happened is,
is that it's redneck rednecks, which
is [inaudible] or you know, whatever,
or hillbillies or whatever you
want to call them folk. Well,
it's not even simple folk.
It's just a particular culture and
they have certain values. And I just,
it's also worth clarifying because of the
way that I sound and where I come from
and the fact that I went to Harvard. Yeah.
And vitamin then that I'm not a
part of that tribe that you, uh,
Americans owe a tremendous
debt to the hillbilly culture.
And that tremendous debt is that
overwhelmingly they're the people who have
served in the military and they are
overwhelmingly the people who have fought
our Wars and bled and died
and all that sort of stuff.
And that's not a stuff that, you
know, I may sound like a liberal,
but I don't really sit in
either of those cultures. Right.
I can could critique the liberal
culture and I can critique the, uh,
hillbilly culture, right?
And, you know, white liberals,
the whole reason why I started this
thing off is because white liberals have
their own weird things
that are dysfunctional and
that aren't helping black
people and all that stuff.
If you just wore a bow tie,
people would think you were
conservative, so you have to do well.
Then there you go. Or maybe you have it
too. The maximal bow tie, a BOLO tie,
100%. Actually, I would
like to do that. Like,
I like the texting culture rancher,
rancher, like a Jade, right?
Their main polo at George W. Bush B from
Connecticut, but dress like a cowboy.
He was from Maine. Even more crazy.
[inaudible].