Went back,
it was a mess.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we uh,
we tried to,
to come back online.
I was trying to put up a,
a,
an image of a me and David Lee Roth and
what the fuck ever.
Firefox crashed on me,
but I was trying to show you the,
the face.
We're all back,
right?
Everything's good.
I'm gonna.
Um,
try to unload it through here.
It's liquor also has a nice side desktop
loader you should download sometime.
Oh,
just dragged into it.
Oh really?
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll get that shit.
She put the picture up right now.
I think today is the last day of
Firefox.
Firefox can suck it
if it's gotten bad lately.
Have noticed.
Chrome's been really good.
I've been crashing a fucking lot with
firefox.
Like why I stop using it.
Yeah.
Okay.
We're back.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I apologize.
Apologize.
Saved though.
So if you are just coming in now,
the first hour and a half is already
saying,
oh,
that's annoying,
right?
It's better
if I have a white thing on my screen
because it acts as a light look.
Oh look,
there's a light on.
But it's not a light,
it's just a little window open.
I'm so clever.
Make it so I can read your shit though.
You know,
if you gotta light behind your monitor,
it actually eases your eyes and puts
less strain on your eyes.
Dr Ross,
Dr Oz real Dr Phil.
Yeah,
Firefox does blow your ride.
We're using safari right now and all you
fucking silicons that.
Especially the.
All these fucking MCA.
A Ph.
d dot Dot garbage.
Oh,
it's the same guy over and over again.
And Nicole van,
2009.
You are dumb.
Okay.
You're dumb.
You're a dumb person.
This whole Mac versus pc thing.
What do you give a fuck?
And you're telling me that pcs are
somehow or another better than Max.
Guess what?
Douchebag.
Pcs Get viruses.
Max,
don't.
It's.
That's why you bring me one dude who's
ever had a virus on his fucking Mac one.
I know everyone I know who's had a pc
except food and chicken.
He claims to have never gotten a virus.
That's a lie.
Everybody gets viruses on pcs.
Just that alone.
It's better to get a Mac.
Second of all,
Max,
don't fucking crash nearly as much.
This wasn't a Mac problem is a firefox
problem.
Everything else on the computer work
fine.
That's why I was able to reboot.
Listen,
stop worrying about Mac versus pc.
It's just a goddamn operating system.
It's like the Republicans versus the
Democrats.
Most of the people on one side or the
other or just on a fucking team and
they're simple little brains are stuck
on that team.
They might not even agree with half the
shit the Republican say,
but they support them and even say,
well,
we got to support our team.
You know,
I don't agree with they're doing right
now,
but what's important is we support them
and we know push forward and we get a
Republican office 12,
blah blah,
blah.
They're just the Washington redskins
versus the fucking Miami Dolphins.
That's all that shit is.
It's teams.
It's just like Boston versus Philly.
Philly soaks posted rules.
That's the same ironic bullshit.
All right there.
There is no fucking philly.
There is no Boston.
It's nonsense.
You're a dummy.
Shut the fuck up.
All right.
How dare you.
Where was I?
Anyway?
Did you have to that photo?
Of course I did it.
It's not on there.
I dare you.
Oh,
I swear to God I pressed that thing.
They all also up quick.
It is though.
Oh,
so beautiful.
They just told me that they're upgrading
my download speed,
like 30 megs next month.
My case.
Thanks.
I don't even have 20.
I have like I think 16 or 18.
18 inside last time it said 18 to
picture David Lee Roth
to do too.
Mother fucker.
That's hilarious.
This is what caused all the fucking
trouble.
Ladies and gentlemen,
a Goddamn picture of me and David Lee
Roth,
but it was just approved that Brian has
been making this crazy ba phase for
years because this picture David Lee
Roth was like,
what is it like from 2005,
three or four years ago before we got
banned from the comedy or the whole
time?
The store thing?
Yeah.
Because it was at the comedy store.
Right.
So that's 2006 maybe.
It was right before he got together with
back together with van Halen before they
announced that they were going to get
back together.
He was telling us about it though.
Yeah.
All right.
I just put it on my little twitter.
Um,
and then you see Brian in the background
making that crazy face.
He did that your bullshit fucking
hundreds of thousands of times.
That was a long odyssey just to get one
picture,
but it really wasn't worth it.
Epic fail indeed deed.
Everybody's always talking about that.
And no key fan got fella tryout,
chat roulette.
You know what I would think about doing
that.
But I don't want to see any dudes car
randomly.
I did it.
I tried it out.
But uh,
uh,
I found this,
this of somebody already did this
before,
but I found this a big black chick and I
put her on loop and then did it just
this an recorded the screen and stuff,
but it was like maybe 90 percent Cox and
I was like,
yeah,
it's not even funny.
I don't,
I mean it's really sad that there's so
many creepy people out there and every,
well,
you know what it's Jews that want to
show their dicks at work and they just
never get the opportunity.
But they get at home and they're wearing
a fucking wrestling mask and they go
crazy.
And this just suppression man.
It's like Catholic school girls.
Remember Catholic school girls.
When you were a kid,
there were always the biggest sluts,
right?
Yeah.
Why?
Because they never seen the dick there.
They're whisked away to some fucking
magical place where only girls exist.
They have all girl teachers and Shit and
they're told the dicks are evil and they
just can't wait to suck one.
They can't wait.
Those bitches can't wait.
They can't wait to get up there.
And I'm like,
oh,
I just want to do that for bidding
thing.
You know,
it can suppress human beings,
man.
I'd like to do it with maybe like a five
year old girl on loop to sitting there
going like this,
you know,
like that.
And see if any of these guys with the A
and like put it away or if they sit
there,
they will fucking love it.
I think what we could record them and
put them on Youtube,
that's about it.
That's if we get a fake loop of a little
kid just sitting there going like is
looking at the monitor and see if the
guy immediately disconnect or if he sits
there an extra couple of seconds.
Well how does it work?
They pull their dicks out immediately as
soon as you log in.
Yeah.
What,
what is right.
It just automatically puts you in with a
room with another person both on Webcam
and do they have their dick out and
instantly when I,
when I was doing it was just guys
stroking or so right when he went in
there you're like okay,
so that's what you should do.
You should,
we should get a video of like a five or
six year old girl.
Just freaking the fuck out from the
beginning.
So it only works in the guys that
already beat,
not frank,
because otherwise we'd have to time it.
Like Tyler,
like normal,
you know?
And then going,
oh my God.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And have our screen call the police,
call the police.
We didn't have any debt.
We just had the on,
you know that kind of adult better.
Better.
Just call it freaked this motherfucker
out.
Yeah,
because they can catch you.
The freaky weird dudes are mostly
straight gay.
Get Sex all the time.
We are less repressed.
Right?
Shut the fuck up.
Let me tell you something.
Everyone's fucked up.
Don't you tell me the days or less
repressed course you more repressed
society.
Represses gay sex gays are just as
fucked up as religion.
Reply repressing straight sex and a lot
of gays grew up in religious households
too and that makes them extra fucked up
there.
It's not like a coincidence that gay
people do so much crystal meth and
there's so many gay people that loved to
party and their lives become a reckoning
fucking towards their immune system.
Gay People.
There's a lot of crazy fucking gay
people and not repressed.
Doesn't always mean that you're not
fucked up.
I mean,
how about bug chasers?
How about gay dudes that are
purposefully trying to get aids?
You know that gay dudes who purposely
try to get HIV,
they want to get it and they think
there's something hot about it,
and so they go and have unprotected sex
on purpose,
hoping to get HIV.
That's fucked up.
You know,
you can't say that gay people are fucked
up sexually than straight people.
Everyone's fucked humans across the
board universally are fucked up.
It's just way too difficult to come out
and have you shared together.
I mean,
how many people really have their shit
together?
If you had a gas,
the numbers one channel and really has
no,
but I mean have your shit together to a
point where you know,
like,
oh,
he's not doing anything.
Self destructive is being productive and
positive.
It's like maybe one out of 100 men maybe
out of the people that you meet.
One out of 100.
The other 99 are nuts.
You know,
half nuts.
Partially nods.
You're nuts.
I'm nuts with both nuts.
You know what I mean?
How many.
I mean even the Dalai Lama is fucking
nuts.
You know what the Dalai Lama said?
He called?
He said that oral and anal sex,
we're,
we're um,
I forget,
I forget the exact word turns.
He used sexual deviations or something
like that,
but he was saying,
well I forget the term that the Dalai
Lama used,
but basically he was saying that oral
sex is really bad.
It's terrible for you.
Didn't do it like you shouldn't be
putting.
The girls love it.
It feels good and I like doing it.
Right.
You like doing.
Yeah,
we've talked about is that there's
actually,
there's actually science now saying that
it can cause cancer and in the person
that's eating out the grown out or
something like that.
Are you fucking member?
We talked about this once.
We've talked to science?
No,
we never talked about eating pussy.
Yeah,
we made a video.
We made a video about it where I talked
about eating pussy and we were talking
about it in that video,
but we didn't say eating pussy gives
you.
Yeah,
it was something that came out and we
were talking about how you like to lock
out of it,
like a slug.
I know and that's how we started with
that.
I don't remember eating Pussy Jersey
cancer.
Dude.
I think he might've just made that up.
No oral sex please.
Twitter verse.
Tell me.
Sweet Jesus,
please,
please tell me that you don't get.
There was some kind of study that I'm
eating.
Oral sex increases throat cancer risks.
Serious scientists say no,
that's for girls because due to have
fucking Dick Ward shoved their dick and
the girl's mouth and the girl's mouth
gets infected.
Like if you have the human
papillomavirus that goes both ways.
Um,
girls and guys can both get the HPV
virus from eating pussy.
Yeah,
that's chicks because you're mixing up
with fucking blood in there.
You know,
you might get a clot back there in the
corner that gets inside of open sore in
your mouth.
Ever done.
That does sort of make sense.
You know,
oral sex can cause throat cancer.
March ninth,
2000.
So it Kinda sucks because that's my
favorite thing to do.
So I moved on to this.
It's just fuck son,
what's wrong with you?
Boy Tamica here for 43,
but we were down for 10 minutes.
So who's this one dummy?
It keeps saying,
have I ever Shit my pants?
You know,
there's something wrong with you as a
human
being if you keep asking the same stupid
fucking question over and over and over
again,
like the same day.
That's what's interesting to you.
All right,
let's go to war.
We're going to go to forums dot Joe
Rogan.net
and see what the questions are.
We put up a thread like we do it every
week where
Peter
ask questions and shit.
And then Dallas this weekend,
Addison Improv.
Well that's almost sold out.
That's right.
Bitches.
So Friday is almost sold out late show.
Saturday night is sold out.
There's only a 40 or 50 tickets left for
a bowl shows Friday inside or both shows
on Friday and the first show on
Saturday.
So it.
So now quit.
So if you want to come to Dallas by the
time we get on the radio,
when we get on the radio,
it's going to sell quick.
We're going to do lex and Terry and a
couple other radio stations.
So that's,
you know,
if you want to jump on it,
you gotta jump on it now.
When are you going to get your tattoo?
A new one.
It's going to start in April.
I'm getting into the skinny bitch
thought started.
What?
I want to get covered up online.
We're giving you a cap on top of that
because that you're crazy.
Explosion.
Cat.
What?
The Japanese.
You know that Carol?
I'm going to go.
I'm going to go and get this lasered
off.
Lasered.
Yeah.
This one,
the old one I have up here because I'm
doing the whole sleeve.
But he'd be laser.
There are no,
you have to go to a clinic that doesn't.
It hurts like a motherfucker but I
tattoo.
See,
let's say you don't be a pussy.
Yeah.
David did I ever tell them uh,
what,
how I found out what my tattoo about
that whole thing.
Tell us or show the tattoo first.
Tell the whole time.
Okay.
So when I was younger,
I was a manager of a movie theater.
One of my employees wanted to be a
tattoo artist.
While he tells the story,
I'm going to pay,
one of my employees wanted to be a
tattoo artist and she,
her boyfriend owned a tattoo studio,
so the whole time,
uh,
she's like,
you know,
he's teaching me every day how to do
tattoos and I do it on like watermelons
or something like that to practice and
she's been doing it forever.
And finally one day she's like,
you know what,
I'm ready.
Start doing tattoos now.
So if you know anyone that needs a
tattoo,
and she's like,
I'll hook them up.
And I go,
wow,
how much are you charging?
And she's like,
for you,
I'll,
you know,
I'll do it for free or something like
that because you will be my first person
to ever do it.
So I'm like,
thinking free tattoo.
That's awesome.
So I went there,
it took her eight hours or something
ridiculous to do this tattoo.
And it originally was supposed to be an
Egyptian turtle with a my name in
Chinese or the letter R in Chinese,
in the middle of the turtle in Chinese.
It was some stupid.
I was really stoned or whatever.
And it hurts so bad she did nothing but
scar me.
So I have tons of scar tissue and it's
like the gay is looking.
Tattoo looks like Spiderman,
you know,
within a gang gang fight or something
like that.
Anyways,
so anyways,
uh,
so one time I met this bar in the,
this Chinese girl both let me see that
tattoo.
And she goes,
why do you have that on your arms?
She really talk like that.
It was worse than that.
She had a cock in her mouth,
but she,
uh,
she looked at it and she goes,
let me see that.
And she goes,
why do you have that on your arm?
I'm like,
what are you talking about?
That's an orange Chinese,
my last name,
blah,
blah.
She goes,
that's not an rn.
She's,
that's like flowing water.
That's like a waterfall.
Do you like waterfalls?
So I guess my tattoo means water from
again.
So gay.
Anyways,
I was thinking about getting the,
getting the,
the.
You know how there's a cats in Chinese
restaurants?
Yeah.
They have a clock.
That could be like the clock.
Yes.
I'll have Aaron dove the Dover from grew
tattoo.
We'll do it together.
That'd be awesome.
Or we'll have someone else.
Girl,
they have seven fucking killer artists.
He can recommend.
Somebody will have them drawn.
Honky.
I got my tattoo done at Guru Tattoo in
San Diego and they're awesome.
Killer artists.
My God.
You got it.
Did me as Aaron Dellavedova and he only
does big giant pieces.
He did my whole sleeve.
Fifty hours.
We went down there I think seven times.
Right?
But that's going to be the same.
We still do this.
They're going to do.
We're going to do this.
They're too.
We're going to do that again.
And
Yeah,
we've got.
So we're gonna do a Brian's uh,
will,
will find you a good artist there,
man.
He's got a killer staff of killer
artists.
Donkey Kong still there because I wear a
shirt every day that he is.
I bet he is.
We could find out.
No gear attack.
When does red band start stripping
Edward Cat flap all high flaco hello?
Kitty is worse than waterfalls.
It's not the hello kitty man.
How dare you,
Bro?
Hello Kitty.
I didn't think good luck had it.
Didn't take a bump.
I peed.
I've never done a bumper of my life.
It's one of the few drugs that have
never done.
There's a bunch of them that I've never
done.
I've never done anything addictive.
There's hockey hung in there in front of
artists.
They had a budget killer artists.
Man,
that place is awesome.
It's in Pacific beach,
down in San Diego.
Again.
Still works there.
And I worked on.
I don't think so.
I think that guy lost his marbles.
Um.
Anyway.
Well,
what the fuck we're talking about
tattoos?
No shopping.
Doing cocaine in the bathroom.
I've never done a coke.
I've never done coke any ever because
when I was in high school,
my friend Jimmy has cousin of selling
coke shouldn't even send my friend who
let you fucking gas.
But uh,
he was selling it and um,
when he was doing that he lost all this
weight and he fucking who would like
hide in the basement or in the attic
rather.
And just,
they would do coke and watch TV and him
and his girlfriend,
which is zombies.
And I saw his whole life fall apart,
like I watched it happen and I remember
like saying that fucking stuff's bad for
you.
I just remember nothing but bad things
from high school and,
and you know,
right after high school have people in
coke just like,
it was very obvious to me.
That was like the worst thing you could
do.
Nitrous?
No.
Oh,
like from whippets did it once,
once when I worked at a ice cream place,
I didn't like it.
Just give me a headache.
We used to go,
I'm done Mtma.
So they asked me if I done it.
I did ecstasy once,
only one time and it was awesome,
but the next day was so bad.
The next day I was so stupid.
My brain was like,
it felt like a sponge than had been
wrung out dry and then just left in the
sun,
you know?
And then you try to like clean something
with it.
It was just like,
it was so my brain was so dumb.
It just,
I,
I was feeling so bad the next day I was
like,
this cannot be good for you.
It's got to be fucking terrible for you.
Who knows what it was in it though.
It might not have just been mdm,
a pure Mtma.
It might've been like they say that
people cut it with speed and shit like
that,
you know?
But anyway,
I couldn't read the next day.
That guy read Rehm show gallery.
Rem Shoe Gallery.
Yeah.
I couldn't read the next day,
man.
Literally I was sitting in a starbucks
and I was trying to read a magazine and
I was like,
I can't even fucking concentrate on us.
I couldn't literally couldn't focus.
It was.
It was bad.
Know.
It was a fucking great time though.
That night.
I can understand why people do it and I
guess if you're not a big reader,
you don't mind feeling stupid.
The next day wouldn't be a problem,
but for me,
man,
I've talked to people say there's no the
next day they feel.
Yeah,
fine.
It just depends on how it's like
strychnine in it and stuff like that.
If you ever candy flipped where it's a
piece of candy and has ecstasy on one
side and acid on the other side of her.
That's crazy though.
It's a great combo.
Yeah.
But I've heard it's like whenever you
combine things like that,
the recovery times just accelerated even
more time.
I want to do it nowadays.
So what else?
What's the best weed?
The best weed is the weed that you got.
Bitch,
you know,
if you don't have the options.
See,
the beautiful thing about California is
this,
um,
there,
that guy's fucking deal with that guy,
man.
That's the perfect style.
Her style.
I could totally see that guy doing it.
Adam Hawthorne.
Um,
I think,
um,
the thing that's cool about California
is the fact that you get to go these
places and experiment with all these
different strains with Joel Diaz mixes
it up every day.
He thinks that that's that shit.
Was that right there?
Joey Diaz thinks that tiger looks like,
Ooh.
Joey Diaz thinks they should make sure
we meet up every day.
We're on guru tattooed.com
g you are,
you tattoo.
Joey
says that if you smoked the same weed
every day,
get used to it,
but if you mix up strains everyday,
the everyday it's like boom.
So Joey buys like a little bit of weed
every day.
It's like a ritual.
Smoke weed everyday you get used to it.
I mean I have to take a good three days
off nowadays,
but she always made sure that every day
I try not to smoke weed everyday.
Joe Ain't taking no days off,
you know,
when you go when we're on the road and
we'd pass by Joey's hotel room,
like we're all staying in the same
hotel.
When you go to get joey,
his room stinks of weed.
I mean fucking stinks everyday.
It's thinks a week.
He always knows the right guy in every
town to get him.
We'd,
you know.
And he always gets it.
Joey's in everyday we'd go,
I own,
I don't smoke weed everyday.
I like to take days off.
I think it,
uh,
it's better.
Like I don't like the,
I don't like being completely
obliterated every day now.
I don't think that's just healthy.
All right,
let's go to the questions on the message
board.
Oh,
you're Charlotte North Carolina.
Date changed.
It changed or a venue changed to did it.
Is it now?
It's a south and a most south end.
Okay.
Whatever.
There were a therefore a UFC.
So the way it always works is whenever
I'm in town for UFC,
I always do a Gig the day before.
Let's go to the message board.
I did a Gig in Sydney,
had a great fucking time.
Australian people are the shit that show
was fun man,
but the show was.
Could,
could have been better because I got too
drunk the night before.
Oh,
we got too drunk.
My brain was,
first of all,
I was fucked up because I could not
sleep because you're 19 hours ahead when
you go to Australia,
so your body doesn't know what time it
was.
I'd be exhausted.
I go to sleep three hours later I'd wake
up and I didn't know what I thought I
was taking a nap.
Like my body had no idea.
I could not sleep for like eight hours
of the session.
I couldn't do it.
So it sleep like three hours,
get up.
I try to read at beat off.
I tried to go back to sleep again,
that sleep for another hour and I'd wake
up again.
Like it was so confusing that.
But um,
Friday night and we got there.
It was um,
me and uh,
Eddie and um,
who else?
Thompson,
Thompson Guerra.
Me and Eddie and Thompson.
Boy.
We went to a bar and God fucking
blitzkrieg we just pulled up to the bar.
We,
we,
we set up shop like,
right,
right by the bar at this club and just
start buying people drinks.
She just went nutty.
I must've bought a hundred fucking
drinks.
Just appointing drinks cheaper or all
the same?
It's very close.
It's like 92,
two.
Our dollar.
A consorted.
Ninety two cents or might've been the
other option might be to.
I'm not sure which one,
but uh,
people are so.
See any kangaroos anywhere.
Yeah,
we did at the zoo.
Depressed,
depressed.
Kangaroos.
Just laying around like this
motherfucker.
That's what we were talking about
earlier.
We were talking about the killer whale
to kill people.
Yeah.
Just a disease.
Bummed me the fuck out man.
I would like to see Kangaroos in the
wild,
but they're dangerous.
They'll fuck you up.
Was there anything Australia that was
just completely insane,
like their bathrooms have weird no
lights and it's like,
you know,
you grow up.
We were talking about this being Eddie
and Tom about how,
you know,
when you grow up,
you're taught that everything sucks
except America.
Soccer Australia is the shit.
I mean,
it's beautiful.
It's clean.
Really Nice houses everywhere.
The restaurants were great,
the people were friendly,
you know,
the economy's not completely fucked.
You're driving on the left side of the
road,
which is weird.
But other than that you can use that.
What's the difference?
You know,
it's just what you're used to.
But other than that,
it's fucking phenomenal.
I mean,
other than that,
what a great country man.
I mean,
it's amazing.
And comics like,
um,
my friend Eddie gift,
he's huge over there.
Huge guys sells out all over the place.
Does TV shows people come to see him
that he can.
He's told me they write about them in
the paper when he was at a bar,
but in America you can't,
can't fucking get traction for whatever
reason.
Some UFC that was great use arch
Barker's gigantic in Australia.
Fucking monstrous.
He sold out someplace.
Supposedly it was like a 1500 seat
place.
Sold it out.
Something like 20 something nights in a
row.
I mean,
just craziness.
They love American comedians over there.
So the show was fucking fantastic.
I had a great time.
Few people walked out,
but that's going to happen and if you
don't know what you're getting into,
you know,
I always try to tell people that if
there was a big sign in the front of the
show that said,
warning,
this show will contain language and
material as extreme as you could
possibly imagine.
But apparently some of the shit I said
people couldn't imagine.
So they didn't know what to expect but
I'm sorry you bummed out,
but I'm 99 percent of the people that
have a great fucking time.
But yeah,
it was pretty wild.
Crazy show.
But also it was because we were hammered
that night too.
So two nights in a row we got barbecued,
so I was planning on going to Australia
and doing all this.
Writing the alcohol just sticks a fork
and all those plans.
You know,
you,
you said that when he flew to Australia
it's like 17 hours whereas the flight
really did it really feel like 17 hours
because at the point where you were just
like,
fuck this,
I need to jump off this plane.
This is too much or no,
no,
it wasn't that bad.
You know,
you just a cancer fighting,
you know,
you just,
you've read,
watch a fucking movie.
Get on your laptop.
I was going over some material on the
way over there.
The real problem was once I got there I
thought I was going to write,
but it was just so it was all get drunk,
recover from the drunk.
A lot of water.
Construct again,
recover.
You have like small little bedrooms.
All Nos on the plane,
right?
Claim was doped.
We flew first class on Quantis and then
some think it's called the 80 3:10
or something like that.
Giant ass fucking plane.
And they're huge man.
They're the,
the,
the like,
it's like a little apartment man,
wisdom like coach,
like,
uh,
don't know,
two times,
three times.
Coaches are spoken coach you business
classes,
pretty dope business classes just as
good as first class.
Wow.
Pretty close to it.
But coach walk you,
they say tax.
I'd been like,
Hey,
let me hang out in your bedroom up here.
I can't imagine flying 16 hours from one
of these.
Ask chairs.
Just jam next.
Ralphie may on one side and Kevin Smith
and the other after they ran a marathon,
I can't believe that somebody actually.
Kevin Smith
dumber.
You do not know who he.
I guess a lot of people don't know who
he is.
Like the way he looks like they don't
know that that's all.
That's that famous director.
You might want to shut the fuck up that
guys on twitter all day every day.
He probably ruined southwest.
That cost them money for sure.
Don't you think?
Well,
part of me thinks so.
But then the other part of me is like,
they just got so much attention,
you know?
And especially if you hate fat people,
you'd be like,
fuck you,
I'm going to southwest.
So they lost the fat dollar.
I bet there's a lot of fat people have
got bummed out.
How's Ralphie may fly southwest because
he it.
You know how much money that probably
saved them.
All these pissed off fat people aren't
flying southwest now.
Just save them.
There's already studies that they were
thinking this is ridiculous.
They were thinking about making you take
a shit before you flew because they've
found out that if they made everyone go
to the bathroom before they got on the
airplane,
that they would say so many dollars per
year.
Like this was a real study that they
were going into southwest.
This wasn't southwest system is American
Airlines or something like that.
So can you imagine now that they have
all these fat people pissed off that
we're not going to fly southwest.
It's probably,
they're probably earning $5,
million dollars a year.
Cost them more to fly,
like fuel wise to Australia for a fat
guy then for electricity.
Oh,
I'm sure it's big enough times 100 then
that than you would imagine.
Oh my God.
Huh?
Yeah.
Kind of makes sense.
Maybe.
Maybe southwest paid Kevin Smith and
theirs is all just to save them a
million.
A couple million a year.
I would never do.
It's like the integrity.
I met him.
He was
cool.
It wouldn't do that.
He is really cool.
He's a nice guy.
I met him when I came into k rock once.
Care Cue in La.
Very fun radio.
The last of the terrestrial radio
stations in our La fucking radio in La
has vanished.
I'm wanting to do radio for a long time.
I was thinking about doing it,
you know,
I was thinking,
wow,
what a cool thing that would be.
Like we have some interesting
conversations.
You take callers,
talk to people online and shit,
you know,
but it just died when they had that 97
point one FM talk.
I was like,
how cool would that be?
Let's get out.
Let's get on the fucking radio gig and
now let's do.
Well.
You were going to do it in Denver.
He repeated it back.
Yeah,
I was thinking about doing it in Denver
and I was thinking when you go back to
Denver,
keep it will keep on asking me that.
Well this UFC in March,
but um,
I haven't gotten a venue to do standup
app so I might just go back and I'm.
No,
no,
stand up.
Just have fun.
Just do the UFC.
I want to go back and check out my house
and see if I can find a fucking mountain
lion that ate my dog.
When you came here and your dog was
sitting on the front porch,
he's been living off the land and he's
this big butch lassie looking dog now
and got Jack,
believe me,
he was gone for weeks.
There's no way your dog does not
appreciate black peoples peoples.
Well,
if dogs are around black people and then
also they see a black person,
they're like,
what the fuck?
Why did you that color?
What's going on?
Can Dog see color?
They just see darkness.
Don't dogs see in black and white?
Maybe you think it's a dude with a mask
on.
Okay.
Oh,
okay.
Gentlemen,
let's go to a the message Conan,
Conan O'brien as a new look with the
beard.
Well,
you know what,
he's got $35 million in the bank now.
It's just kicking it.
You know,
today I interviewed a squirrel in my
backyard and then through to commercial,
somebody helped me.
That's
pretty Tony and Brian now as a twitter.
By the way,
it's Conan O'brien.
The I love the whole Conan store.
It just shows you how retarded networks
are,
you know,
and first of all they should have never
changed shit,
you know what they should've done.
I appreciate the Jimmy Fallon people
enjoy Jimmy Fallon's show,
but you know what?
Put that on after Conan O'brien,
you know,
go back to the way you had it.
Don't be stupid.
You want to go Jay Leno tonight show
while you want to go middle America,
throw softballs and not offend anybody,
and then keep the Conan O'brien show
where it was because we'd Conan's on.
He can do,
you know all that craziness,
the fucking insult dog masturbating.
But you can do it late at night because
you're allowed to do more crazy shit
late at night.
You know what's his face went?
Remember when we were talking to norm
Macdonald's outside the ice house.
He had the best point norm.
Mcdonald goes.
He goes,
well,
I can never make one time.
He's on anyway.
Nobody watches it and watch it on your
dvr.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
See It on Youtube.
Who Cares?
Rianna 1130 or 1230.
It's 12 years better is you can get away
with more shit.
He was totally right.
I like how you're saying all this,
but yeah,
his phone was from 1982,
so as I have it on the phone at all.
When I,
when I ran out,
Jim,
I ran into dawn Mcdonald once when I was
doing some Canadian gigs like uh,
a couple of years ago.
And when I ran into him,
he didn't have a cell phone.
I had to call his home phone.
That's right.
It never fucking cell phone.
He didn't have one because I don't want
people to just be able to get in touch
with me.
Fuck off.
Disappear.
Know that dude.
Yeah,
he's hilarious man.
He's a norm.
Macdonald hosted a talk show would be
the shit.
Yeah,
that would be.
I would,
I would tune into that talk show because
he wouldn't let get people get away with
anything.
You know?
He's,
he's nuts.
You know,
he's,
he's a loose dude.
He's wild.
You'd be a good couch guy for like Conan
because have you ever seen him on the
couch?
Like,
I forget
who it was in the whole time.
He was like cracking jokes.
That was awesome.
Wasn't it would be a good like good side
guy.
Yeah.
And you know like have like a straight
guy and then he gets the side guy.
What is my take on the weed stores in
La?
Getting raided.
It fucking sucks.
You know,
the whole thing makes me,
it makes me sick.
You know,
the whole thing is so,
so strange,
man.
It's so strange that they're still
fucking with people.
Apparently the way the law is presented
though,
and California and I,
I'm not sure this,
um,
is that they believe that the way the
law is presented is that you can give
weed away and you can sell it as long as
you're not making a profit and that
these collectives are supposed to be to
provide medical patients with marijuana.
But apparently there's people out there
that are flaunting the wealth and
they're making a fuck load of money off
of it.
Millions and millions of dollars off
selling wheat.
Now,
if that's the case,
there's two parts of me,
one part of me that says,
well,
you know what?
Fuck you,
they should be able to sell it.
You know,
you're,
you guys are Douche bags.
But another part of me says,
hmm,
maybe it'd be better.
Maybe it would be really in the spirit
of weed.
If it was free,
maybe you really would be in the spirit
of weed that it isn't,
that there isn't a for profit.
You know,
people will don't,
man,
these stores couldn't exist and they
couldn't sell it.
Yeah.
But we,
it's not that hard to grow them and
people would still grow and sell weed
and you know,
people will sell it illegally.
I mean,
there would be plenty of people that
would,
you know,
if you want good weed,
you got to talk to this guy and it's
expensive.
But I kinda liked the idea of it not
being for profit.
There's something about it,
uh,
that,
that bugs me,
that people are overcharging for this
plant just because it's illegal and it's
fucking,
some places it's super expensive,
you know,
five,
$600 an ounce for like really powerful,
potent weed,
you know,
which I understand that God should get
paid for is growing and this and that
and I totally respect that.
You should be able to make a certain
amount of money for it.
But if it was legal,
it would be way fucking cheaper than it
is right now.
The reality is the reason why it's
expensive at all,
the reason why these guys can make
millions of dollars in profit off of
selling weed is only because it's
illegal and difficult to get and you
have to get it from these places.
If marijuana was legal and you could
grow your own,
which is how it should be,
you would have no need to buy it.
You could have a little fucking plant
your backyard or in my closet is like
that,
but it's not.
This guy got fucking arrested.
It's not.
This guy just got arrested.
This guy just got arrested with 24
different counts and he's going to
charge him and the way it works
apparently is what Obama has said is
that they're not going to charge people
who were,
who were only violating federal law
federally.
It's illegal.
They're going to go after people who are
going to violate both the federal and
state laws.
So you have to follow the state law to
the letter and they're making an example
out of this one dude.
Apparently.
Well,
I mean if you go and get a license,
you're allowed to grow white seven or
something like
that.
Yeah,
you're allowed to grow a lot.
You're allowed to have like a half a
pound of weed and get the other license
that you can do up to like 21 plants.
So I got that.
Yeah,
you have that.
For some reason they asked me if I need
an exemption,
but I said what's an exemption for?
He goes,
well,
you know,
the regular amount of weed is not
enough.
Although yes,
the regular amount is not enough.
I need more.
You could pretty much anyone,
anyone can get back.
Even even kids could probably get this
shit,
but if they can get that license.
So if you just grow within your amount,
you could pretty much do that now.
And even if the cops came over your
house,
right.
But it could be people that don't have
the room to grow and they don't want to
be hassled and they want to be able to
go out and purchase it at a reasonable
rate.
And I agree that there is a reasonable
But right now the rate is so high that
marijuana is worth more than gold.
Marijuana is worth more,
worth more per pound than gold is.
That seems a little crazy.
You know,
I mean,
it's definitely inflated because of the
fact that there's no competition because
of the fact that it's illegal and it's
so fucking plant.
It should be legal.
Everybody should be able to grow it.
And if it was legal,
there would be nobody making millions
and millions of dollars off of.
The real problem is it would fuck the
economy up because pharmaceutical
companies,
which is fucking nosedive,
there'd be so many different
pharmaceutical products.
That would be that there would be
useless.
I,
you know,
I believe that to a point,
but right now I have,
we whenever I want have wheat,
but I still have Tom's for my stomach.
I still have aspirin for headaches,
you know,
they didn't replace any.
You don't have fucking glow coma dude.
You know,
there's a lot of different medications
for add.
There's a lot.
Those are the billion dollar medicines.
It's not tom's Bro.
But you know what description and most
of these people that are saying that
it's the best drug for a glaucoma and
stuff are just hippies wanting.
We'd to be illegal because if you.
If you look at them,
the medication for Glaucoma in
comparison,
I bet you it's better than not.
It is the best for interocular pressure.
I believe that it's what's called when,
when Glaucoma.
Apparently it's very painful for people
and marijuana apparently is the best at
relieving that.
It's the best ever restoring people's
appetite when they have chemotherapy.
That's why cancer patients like it.
It's the best at it.
Suppressed that a lot of different
things do.
There's people that have had kids that
have autism.
There's a video that we showed them that
clip that autism and that was the only
thing that calm the kid down,
made him normal was we'd,
you know,
it's great for a lot of different things
and all those different things are
prescription drugs that are worth
fucking billions of dollars every year
to pharmaceutical companies,
which is why they lobby against
recreational drugs,
so called recreational drugs.
It's just why to this day partnership
for drug free America to this day gets
money from pharmaceutical companies.
They got money from alcohol companies
and tobacco companies,
millions and millions of dollars in the
past and because of that there was a lot
of criticism so they no longer get money
from alcohol and tobacco companies,
but they still get money from
pharmaceutical companies and
pharmaceutical
companies are responsible for oxycodone,
Vicodin,
percocet,
all that shit.
I still don't think it's going to be
like if they made it legal,
like all these companies are going go
out of business.
I know my mom's not going to be smoking
weed.
She's gonna.
Be like,
no,
I'll take.
The other thing would be dumb enough for
a few generations.
Yeah,
there would be dominoes we just doesn't
work with and that's like that's percent
60 percent is that in exchange for the
things that we do
talked about,
it's not 50 or 60 percent will weed is a
real effective medicine for a bunch of
different things,
but more importantly it be great for
textiles.
It would be great for.
You can eat it.
You can.
I mean,
it has all the essential fatty acids and
the seeds,
you know,
amino acids.
There's a lot of different fucking
things that marijuana is good for
besides just just getting you high.
Right.
It's incredible that it's illegal.
It's really mind blowing that it's
illegal,
but in 2010 with the access to
information than we have today,
the fact that it's still illegal.
That's fucking insane,
man.
Because you streamed laggy.
Yeah.
You streams always laggy,
man.
Anything on the Internet slab you'd.
Nothing works perfect.
This is fucking.
The Internet is in a stage right now.
It's not done yet.
The irs plane crash or guy having a
hanger coal leased by Member of Homeland
Security and having ties to intelligence
agencies.
Is that true?
Well,
I know that he stole that plane,
so I don't know.
It wasn't his plane.
If that's what you're talking about.
Oh,
you know what?
I'm all for that guy because what's your
offer that granite crashes building is
planning.
Anyone die in that?
Yes.
All right.
Fuck the irs.
Wow.
I'm still dealing with them.
Bullshit.
They're like fucking bullet.
Okay.
This bad,
bad,
bad.
Bobby's telling me that gold is $1,100
an ounce in a British Columbia and the
best weed is $3,200
a pound and eight more than gold.
It's going for less than $17,000
a pound here in the US.
Oh,
I stand corrected.
Thank you very much,
sir.
That sounds better.
That sounds better now the way I said.
Yeah,
I know what's worth more than gold.
Cash Hash is worth more than gold,
isn't it?
Damn Hash is expensive as fuck.
How much is a pound of Hash?
Go for more than an hour and a half by
half ass.
Fucking punch a hole through to another
dimension to measure.
We smoked a pound of Hash Hash.
They make out a weed somehow or another.
I'm known as the president to do it.
So resin the resin.
How do they do it though?
Do you know how they make it?
A bit of a complicated process,
but I've had it before and it's very
deep.
It's a strange high.
It's very,
very good.
Mr.
Strong.
I might do opium again.
Opens you did opium?
Fuck yeah.
It's not much different than ash.
Really?
Yeah.
It looks a little like no heroin.
No,
no.
It's like a.
It looks like a piece of soap.
It smokes like a smokes.
Smokes like hash in it.
It smells like a Hippie,
like petroleum.
It smells like Petroli when it burns
real.
Yeah.
It's,
it's kind of like,
I dunno,
like a hash kind of feeling.
Hm.
I'm scared man.
Yeah.
The gold thing.
I didn't really research that way.
Well,
it was something else.
Sorry,
I said that incorrectly.
There's something else that,
that marijuana was more expensive than
per ounce.
It was oil.
Does that make sense?
Worth more than oil.
I'm worth more than something that's
worth a lot.
Uh,
let's go with some other questions here.
Dan,
with the USTREAM powerful ustream.
Opium smells like flowers and it's super
addictive from the poppy faggot.
While you're doing something super
addictive.
Brian's already addicted.
Addicted.
Brian had had a hangnail and that got
them to start smoking again.
No,
it was.
And I got audited by the irs for that.
As you cat got a hangnail no,
now that was my cat.
Had a fucked up foot Canada,
his cabinet,
Canada fucked up.
Fuck,
fucking can't take it anymore.
Cigarettes because cigarettes out of
nowhere,
you'll be like,
dude,
I need a cigarette.
And it's one of those things.
Once you do it,
it opens up a door that's always gonna.
Be Open and it's weird.
Cigarettes or this guy did you know you
can add to that
late your pineal by saying the word love
at a certain frequency.
Shut up,
shut the fuck up.
Just like that.
Shot up like the new Mariah Carey Song
is,
has a high enough pitch to open up your
garage doors.
No,
it doesn't,
but loves to say stupid people love
fucking magic.
They love magic and nonsense.
You know,
they love to think that there is like
something like that.
There's real magic.
The real magic.
Eat a pound of mushrooms.
The magic,
instead of having a 16 ounce steak have
16 ounces of mushrooms.
Motherfucker.
Shit,
that's magic.
You know?
Yeah.
You will magically be retarded for the
rest of your life.
You'll probably be communicating with
aliens permanently.
You'll probably be locked into another
dimension.
You know,
tell Jerry Garcia smoking opium wasn't
addicted addicted.
He moved to smoking black tar heroin
after that.
Well,
it's for sure.
Did they used to have an opium dens back
in the wild west?
Don't you remember?
But I never wanted it open the next day
thought about,
oh my God,
I need it.
You know,
it was never like that.
Cocaine was kind of like that.
But for me by that opiod never was like
that.
That was more of like a treat like a
dessert.
Well,
you know,
there's a good argument because this
argument was on the message board as
well.
People were talking about things being
addictive and hit.
The problem with even alcohol being
addictive is that it's not addictive.
Everybody,
you know,
I'm not addicted to.
I could,
I could not have a drink every day for
the rest of my life and I'd have no
problem with that.
But I like to have a drink sometimes and
go on stage.
I like to have a drink sometimes my
buddies just to make things fun.
Just makes you get crazy.
You pay for it the next day though.
Especially rh.
Yeah,
man,
you get older,
do you pay for it more?
But the bottom line is it's not
addictive.
Like I don't,
I don't hurt when I don't have it,
but for some people it is.
Some people have to have a drink.
When I was doing construction,
when I was a kid,
there was a dude who had a mountain dew
bottle and he would fill it up with
fucking beer,
just like cheap beer,
like colt 45 and he would drink beer all
day while we worked all day.
This guy was,
he was shaky.
Jones and Duke.
He would show up for work though.
He was there every fucking day.
Seven in the morning swinging that
hammer,
you know,
he was there pissing every five minutes.
That was always hammered though.
He was drinking beer all day for that
dude though.
I think it's like everybody's got their
own biochemical makeup.
It's like you're addicted to cigarettes.
But like Thompson Thompson,
guerra smoked cigarettes when he drinks
but doesn't smoke other times and he can
go years without cigarettes with no
problem.
But when he drinks he likes to have a
cigarette.
When was the last meeting went a year
with no problem.
Now.
Well he's sending has taken a long time
off.
He's taking time off a bunch of times
and he won't smoke for months and then
he'll have a cigarette,
they'll have a cigarette when he drinks.
I definitely think cigarettes is like
that one thing that even if you quit
smoking,
it can be three years later in avondale
where they'll start smoking again.
No reason why.
I know you said that as soon as red.
So I,
I think,
you know,
I think they're doing something.
Remember that movie the insider with
Russell Crowe or see that movie?
Yeah.
It was all about like all the shit that
they do to cigarettes to make it even
more addictive,
like hundreds of different additives,
hundreds of different additives just to
make it more addictive.
And I've,
I totally believe that's true.
Totally.
One hundred percent believe that's true.
And if that's the case,
man,
I mean who the fuck knows?
I mean they say that cigarettes are
more,
it's not as dangerous as heroin because
heroin will kill you quicker and you can
overdose from it.
But cigarettes will get you hooked
quicker than anything,
like apparently if you,
if you have that thing inside you that
gets you hooked to shit like that,
but I don't,
but I that cigarettes do totally.
He with cocaine too,
you said?
Well I almost,
because I was selling it and getting a
large amounts of it for free.
You were allegedly allegedly selling
really selling me.
It's just like this is like a character
that would buy a large amount so he
could give it away and have some extra
for free.
It was Peter Pan of have.
No,
not Peter Pan.
Robin Hood of cocaine was like one month
of my life back in [inaudible] 94 in
this fictional story.
And it's takes an old story.
But anyways,
if you were rich,
okay,
what if you will,
what if you like Jay z baller,
you know,
private jet rich and you could just get
pure cocaine shipped right over here
from the CIA.
The CIA would drop it off on your
doorstep.
Well,
I think I go back into the program.
I think the only reason it was kind of
addictive to me because I am one of
those people that never go to the
doctors and I probably need to be one of
those people that are on speed or
something because I like having a
thyroid.
I like having a thyroid condition.
Most of my day is spent like moping
around energy and stuff like that.
But uh,
uh,
when cocaine,
I felt like I was alive for the first
time and I think that's what was
addictive more of just like I felt like
I was out of some kind of coma.
Well,
sometimes,
well sometimes I'm having like a normal
day,
like I'm not really into anything and
I'll have a cup of coffee and God damn
it,
I just get fucking fired up.
I.
Right.
Great.
Yeah.
I feel good about life.
Fucking feels like the warm sun feels
better to clean my office.
We get a little fired up from
stimulants,
you know?
Right.
That's what they're there for.
Yeah.
You know,
Cook it.
I don't know what cocaine's like,
but I know that I've had never stopped
talking.
You talked about this,
you would be talking so fast,
your jaw would fly off and hit somebody
in the face.
I have this
think called Martin the coca and it's a,
it's a tea that's made out of a,
I guess I'm talking to myself and our
company,
you,
Monte to coco is a tea that's made out
of a coca leaf.
So it's like cocaine,
the plant that they make cocaine from,
but it's the unprocessed forum,
which is,
um,
it's actually like indigenous people,
a shoe that I think it's improved.
They said it's like really common isn't
approved.
He doesn't know he's outside smoking
cigarettes,
talking to myself.
Um,
they,
uh,
they chew this leaf and it's um,
for especially the people that,
uh,
are at high altitude,
like a high altitude,
a hurting communities,
they,
they eat this a true.
This tea is tea leaf.
But I had it in a tea form and when I
had it,
it was not good for me.
I couldn't shut the fuck up.
Me and Doug,
Stan hope are doing shrooms.
It was the day the Iraq war started and
we were in the middle of the desert at
my friend house and it's pretty crazy
because we're truman and right when the
shrooms we're kicking in,
we noticed on the television set that
they were saying that the war coverage
begins at five and Stan hope looked at
me and he goes,
there's a fucking kickoff for the war.
I mean,
that's really what it was like they were
telling us when the war coverage is
going to start tuning in at five or war
coverage.
It was like a kickoff.
It was like,
that's when the program,
the war program was going to start and
that's when this guy,
John,
my friend John,
who's like,
he's done more psychedelics than anyone
I've ever met ever.
He's definitely probably fried.
His brains.
Got a cool podcast though.
Uh,
but he was talking about,
hey,
take this motto to Coco.
It'll help the mushrooms kick in
quicker.
Maybe it did,
but I,
I could not shut the fuck up.
And I was telling Doug while I was doing
it,
I was like,
I can't shut the fuck up.
This is driving me crazy and he was
laughing uncontrollably because he
thought it was hilarious that I was
talking about how I couldn't shut the
fuck up yet aware of it,
and
it's the worst,
but you know what you would you would.
That's one of those drugs that,
thank God he never tried because you
would freak out and love it because it
makes your mind open up and just think
so clear because you're just nonstop
thinking of new stuff.
Talk about.
Well,
that's for me.
That's how my friend Jimmy said that
when we're kids,
W W with the cousin,
that was a problem with it.
He told me not to do it.
He taught you smell so bad.
Dude.
That is so nasty.
Cigarettes are so funny.
Aren't they?
Kept on talking about it and daddy
needed to taste.
Daddy needed to tell you can't go two
hours.
He had a cigarette right when we started
to buy.
Oh,
shut your fucking hole.
You had your fix.
How'd your goddamn fix 'em anyway,
cigarettes.
Bad Code and go.
You know what though?
What's interesting in California,
I don't know if this is in all states
that have changed cigarettes to go out
by himself now,
so if you don't,
if you don't hit it long enough,
it will just go out because of the fires
out here reading the cigarette companies
had to make something in a cigarette,
so if you don't hit it after a while it
will go out by itself and just makes me
what is.
That can't be good.
Probably doing something like that,
man,
they've probably made it extra addictive
along the way and oh well we can do
that,
but unfortunately caused with psychotic
episodes and make you fucking mortgage
your house for extra cigarettes might
start hoarding cigarettes.
Right.
You know,
if they could figure out a way to put
something in cigarettes that would make
you completely insane and have this
insane desire to collect cigarettes.
Could you imagine if that started
happening?
Yeah,
like a lot of black dudes collect
sneakers.
They have like you go into their house,
I got yo MTV raps or MTV cribs rather,
you know,
you go in,
they have like a whole room filled with
sneaker hiding or jumped from somebody.
They're junk was touched or it's,
it's too big and they have a horse Cox
and they want you to look at the fuck is
he talking about?
He's like,
no,
they're just,
for whatever reason they're into
collecting shoes.
What if people just started collecting
cigarettes like according cigarettes,
like roomfuls of cigarettes and
cigarette companies are like,
well,
you know,
we make a fantastic product.
We can't help other people get excited
about it.
They're just excited about our product
and we found out that they had added
something to cigarettes that make people
want to hoard cigarettes.
They would totally do it if some fucking
scientists came up with a,
a formula where he could have a certain
amount of chemicals and if you put those
in cigarettes,
people smoke cigarettes,
they would have this insatiable desire
to collect cigarettes and buy way more
than they need.
You don't think they would put that in
the cigarettes?
Of course they would.
Fuck,
yeah,
they would do it.
They didn't give a fuck about you.
They sell shit that kills you.
They shit.
They don't.
It's not like they didn't know we didn't
know.
Cigarettes kill you.
Holy Shit.
We're going to stop.
We're sorry.
No cigarettes.
Kill 400 fucking million people every
year and no cigarette companies have
even thought about slowing down and no
politicians have ever thought about
banning them.
You never hear a peep out of
politicians.
All those faggots want to talk about
fucking banning pot and you know we've
got to stop marijuana and illegal drugs.
Meanwhile,
cigarettes are killing way more people
than everything else combined.
Cancer,
AIDS,
fucking heroin,
meth,
coke,
all that shit.
Pull it all together with alcohol.
It can't put a fucking dent.
Not a scratch into what cigarettes kill
every year.
If they could figure out a way to make
you want to hoard cigarettes for sure
they would do it and the people hoarding
it,
they would give testimonials.
I don't have a problem with it.
I enjoy my cigarette collection when I'm
walking to the garage and I look at
much.
I like the smell,
I get out there and we're not.
I don't mean to sound like I'm smoking
more.
People kind of do that,
but you're right,
they do do that with scratch,
but cigars are totally different.
They liked like savor the taste and shit
and it's like it makes no sense.
No different cigars or different flavors
to it.
They taste.
It tastes like shit to me.
They all taste like you're sucking on a
fucking.
I Dunno a tree or something that I like
them.
I'll ask the guys.
I think they taste good.
Really?
Yeah.
When you have a fat steak and a glass of
wine,
you get a nice Cuban cigar with a
fucking good taste to it.
You know?
It's just like you,
you,
you take it in and get a good taste in
your mouth.
It's fun.
Get you a little,
gives you a buzz.
Crazy thing.
I don't like spliffs because you don't
inhale cigars.
You don't have to inhale through your
mouth can you do if you're going to get
high.
Now I've been.
The science between getting high is that
once it hits your mouth,
it's immediately and your stream.
You don't even know.
Is that true?
Yeah.
They,
they.
They did a study where it showed people
that used to think were you supposed to
inhale it and hold it in as long as you
can.
I guess supposedly you get 99 percent of
the thc immediately when you.
When you suck it twitter verse.
Is this true?
Because if this is true,
I will stop smoking weed from now on and
I'll just put it in my mouth.
I'll just put on my off,
take a deep breath and then blow it out.
I always thought the people were doing
that were like,
Bill,
I always thought that Bill Clinton did
not inhale,
but it's because he was crafty.
He didn't know that.
He knows how science.
Is that real science?
It is.
Science is that real science twitter
verse.
What the fuck is that true?
You don't.
Let's keep our googling run.
Love Google.
Google right now.
You do not have to inhale marijuana to
get high
marijuana to get high.
Yeah.
I always thought you had to
hold in for the long thing to Wiki
answers.
What if you do not inhale marijuana?
Answer?
No.
It has to go into your lungs to get you
a high meaning.
You have to inhale to get hot.
Well,
I'm not going to listen to this stupid
fuck because this stupid fuck spelled
high two different times and then wrote,
have in capital letters.
Not very scientific faggot.
Next truck.
Here's a trend.
Do you have to inhale when smoking weed?
Yahoo answers.
Don't do it.
Best Answer.
Chosen by asking her.
You fucking dummy.
The girl says don't do it,
but if you must know you have to keep
this smoke in your loans longer than you
normally would a cigarette,
so you inhale it and then keep it in
there for as long as you then exhale.
That's not true.
It's just dumped to a don't do it.
Why Alyssa?
Because you don't want to have fun.
Why should he not smoke the pot?
Because he doesn't want to be friendly
because he doesn't want to be more
sensitive because you want it doesn't
want to tune into the universe more.
Shut the fuck up.
Don't do it.
You can't tell me not smoke pot because
I'm a goddamn comedian.
And that's like telling a basketball
player to not play with basketballs.
Um,
I can't find the answer.
Shit.
I forget where I read it.
I read it somewhere.
It was like you read it the same way I
place.
I've read that gold is the same amount
as we know now because I,
I was on your side where that's bullshit
in my girlfriend who is going to school
for nursing.
She's like,
that's totally untrue.
And then she showed me all these
studies.
I'm like,
oh,
okay.
It was a,
you have to.
If she's watching get high.
Let's say this guys,
you need to fully inhale and to get
high.
Take a big breath in.
See,
these are people like fucking just like
you have to inhale,
weeding your lungs get higher,
won't do anything.
We'd does not cause cancer.
Okay.
This guy's got a cancer article when our
trunk is about you.
Fuck.
All right.
We have no correct answer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we tried.
We cannot find the answer to this.
Yahoo answers are all written by 16 year
olds or 40 year old retards.
One or the other.
This guy says he knows everything about
cannabis more than seven seconds or
these yahoo answers.
Yeah.
We looked at those yahoo answers,
man.
That doesn't mean shit.
It's something about your.
Your mouth is filled with a whatever the
makes sense because you don't inhale.
I'm a tobacco smoke.
When you smoke a cigar and you get high
as fuck,
you get really high from cigars.
Cigars give you like a serious nicotine
rush,
like,
whew,
that's a good one.
And if that's,
if that happens,
why wouldn't that happen with marijuana
to you know,
you don't inhale the cigar smoke.
You take into your mouth and then you
blow it out.
You don't take a deep head of it like
you do with cigarettes.
Yeah.
That's a,
that's a tough google search and I'll
have to just actually find that.
We don't know.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it was a recent article that was about
six months ago.
I write it some people weed is not
for them.
That really is true,
you know,
like standing hope doesn't like we'd
stand will pay tweet,
which doesn't make any sense because he
likes everything else,
but I think he probably got too high to
get paranoid.
If you get too high we will fucking rock
your world,
man.
Shit makes you really.
The last year see I was and I was
tripping my ass off.
I almost had to run out.
I was thinking like,
okay,
I am just going to leave and go to my
room and take a nap.
Because I was trying to hard from we'd.
Wow,
this is this rivalry says opium trivia.
The term are you hip comes from opium
dens.
You would lay on your side,
on your hip and smoke.
Hence the term.
Are you hip?
That kind of makes sense because if you
ever watched like those old western
movies are dudes are doing heroin or
opium.
The online on their side.
Like what was that movie where Wyatt
earp?
Was it wider?
One of those was buffalo bill or wider
thing.
It was.
I don't remember who the fuck played
them.
Well remember,
um,
what was the moving where a doc holliday
one was fucking Dennis Quaid played.
Um,
Dennis Quaid played Wyatt earp and Val
kilmer played.
Doc Holiday was the dopest doc holiday
before Val kilmer just ate everything
that,
that existed.
Val kilmer dissolve fat.
Fucked up now.
He was like,
go back to top gun days.
Tombstone,
tombstone.
That's it.
We go back to like val kilmer,
like the old days val kilmer is a
handsome motherfucker,
you know?
Yeah.
You started hanging out with Tom
Sizemore and you know,
this whole weed thing.
We could just fucking next time we're
sober.
Well,
just try it.
Ooh,
okay.
Leave.
This guy says,
red band is right.
Arrowhead.
Here we go.
Robberies comes,
comes clean our.
Here we go.
Read it to us.
Okay,
here it is.
Mouse smoking cannabis.
One of the primary health issues with
cannabis is the effect of smuggled the
lungs.
While the risks from longterm cannabis
smoking or not fully understood is
assumed by.
Before I do this,
I will tell.
I will take this copy,
mount smoking is not as efficient as
long smoking and requires approximately
three times the material for the same
level of effect,
but for some people efficiency is not an
issue.
I would say it's not an issue,
you know,
because we.
It's not that expensive as we were
talking about how it's worth a lot of
money because.
But it's not worth it.
It's not that much.
I mean it's one marijuana joint is like
what is it,
like $10 or something like that and
probably wasn't.
How much is a joint it joint?
$10.
California joint will fast for sure.
Fuck you out of your mind joining.
Even if you're.
Even if you smoke a lot,
if you actually inhaled a full joint,
you would be blitzkrieg,
California weed,
California Wade.
So if you take California weed and you
mouth mouth,
fuck it.
You could probably get by on like two
hits of California weed from a joint and
you're gone.
And when.
One of the things that you could do also
is if you inhale it and you breathe it
out your nose,
so you,
you put it in your mouth and then you
blow it out your notes,
but you're not going hailing it if it
even increases it.
Alright,
well let's post this up online just so
everybody knows what the fuck we're
reading.
Yeah.
But I used to.
I remember there was somebody I used to
know that like smoke,
she would only smoke with me,
but she would say,
I'm not going to inhale it,
but I'll smoke it with you and make you
feel better.
I'm like,
okay,
so see if she would always get fucked
up.
And I'm like,
wow,
she's not stoned,
but why is he acting so fucked up?
So I look back at it now when she was
locked up,
I just put that shit up online
so you can twitter that.
They have a.
So now we learned something ladies,
gentlemen,
rivalries,
you know,
a lot of drugs,
motherfucker.
This is the dude.
He runs the whole thing.
It's says he,
uh,
he owns a pool hall in um,
somewhere in Georgia.
Forget where it's from,
make them make them Georgia,
I believe,
but it's a pretty famous pool hall.
This guy owns it.
Lights everything.
Douche squad.
There was a bunch of dudes with the
Dishwasher,
you know,
some,
some members of my board break off into
little separate sex,
like little gangs.
I don't know what they're doing if
you've never been to my message board.
I got the craziest message board.
I don't know how the fuck it happened.
I don't know what caused it.
But,
uh,
I've had this nutty message board since
1998 and right now there is more than
two and a half million posts on it.
I'll put it up online.
I started smoking when I was 15 ray and
uh,
anyway,
um,
this message board,
there's so much fucking nutty shit on
that board.
That's how I met Brian.
I met Brian from the message board.
It's really got a life of its own.
I mean,
it's got my name attached to it and I
pay for it and to keep it running and
you know,
but there's like a bunch of different
dudes who are cool people that I've met
in real life,
most of them that are the moderators on
the board and you know,
it's anything fucked up in the world.
Anything weird,
crazy,
any nutty news.
If you're looking for a video,
like I heard this is a crazy video out,
my board is going to happen for sure.
Right?
When you say that's,
you know,
it's a crazy place.
It's pretty nutty ladies gentlemen.
And on that note,
it's fucking 5:36.
That's two hours,
two and a half hours.
We can't do more than two hours.
Folks Boring.
But we're at the Addison Texas Improv
this weekend,
Friday,
Saturday and Sunday.
And I want to take a link right here,
motherfucker.
And I'm going to open this bitch and I'm
going to put that on twitter so
everybody knows what's up.
Almost sold out.
Yeah.
It is very close to sold out.
Like all the shows went about Houston,
like Houston.
People wondering if you're coming back
to him coming back.
We're right now trying to figure out
whether we're doing the Improv or
whether we're doing the house of Blues.
There was a problem with the House of
blues initially where they said the
house of blues could not a seat.
Everybody and I did not want to do a
show where people have to stand and we
talked about this before that we went to
the Doug Stanhope show when he was in la
and I love Doug,
but I fucking can't stand and just watch
a show for an hour and a half.
It's hurts your feet.
Your back starts hurting,
your neck,
gets cramped up,
and then I realized like this is
uncomfortable.
Sitting and watching a show is awesome,
but standing and watching a show sucks.
It gets annoying.
Not a big fan of the house of Blues.
I wanted to see a concert last week and
I had a horrible experience with those
fuckers with House of Blues.
Which one though?
They went on sunset.
What happened?
Uh,
when you go through,
they stamp your hands.
They quit wristbands on.
They check your ids.
They scan the tickets,
right,
so we went up there and it was general
admission.
We found a place that we wanted to like
sit and stay lean up against the wall.
It was perfect for the concert.
Halfway through the opening,
a act or whatever,
opening band,
security grabbed my girlfriend coming
out of the bathroom goes,
where's your hand stamp?
And she goes,
oh,
I don't know,
maybe it washed off.
I have a wristband.
Here's my ticket.
She goes,
no,
your hands not stamped.
You're Outta here.
And she's like,
well,
I have my ticket right here.
He goes,
I don't care.
He's going to have a hand stamp.
She goes,
my boyfriend's right there.
He goes,
go get him.
And he's kicked out too.
Like it was like,
it was like,
what are you?
Okay,
but that's just la douchebag.
A manager got involved.
Right?
But that has nothing to do with Houston,
Texas or a company dickheads.
He's like,
sorry,
corporate policy,
you're supposed to get hand stamped.
I'm like,
it doesn't matter.
I'm in here.
I have tickets with a fucking manager.
He goes,
I'm sorry,
but let's go downstairs,
which get your hand stamp and let's
figure this out together.
I'm like the concerts on right now.
It's just like the biggest fucking
corporate bullshit.
You know?
That shit wouldn't happen at fucking
Improv.
You don't think so?
No.
You don't have your hand stamped.
You have a ticket.
Come on.
So you think that death.
So what happened then you think would
not happen.
So you think that if we have a show at
the house of Blues,
people might get fucked.
My problem with the House of Blues,
it's a corporate thing,
the whole not being able to make great
fucking time at all.
The House of Blues.
Well you have anytime when you're out in
front of a,
a good crowd of people,
right?
Yeah,
but that's one of the few venues where
you guarantee that everything's going to
run smoothly.
You know,
they get rid of douchebags in the
audience to record your own.
Say That is true.
Now that fans aren't allowed to bring
cameras into the place or they have to
leave them at the box on.
Well,
the problem with that,
as these motherfuckers want to stick
cameras in your face while you're on
stage,
constantly record things and put them on
youtube,
they're going to do that with various
very district going to do that
regardless of what it is annoying for
them and for the bands and for different
people.
I feel like you don't want their stuff
pirated.
They're just protecting the artists.
That make sense to me.
I agree,
but it's not a bad experience.
But I think he had isolated Douche bags.
I mean people that run the House of
Blues and I'm in Vegas are fucking
awesome.
The those people are super cool and
that's the one we go to the most.
Yeah.
House of Blues and San Diego.
Then we also knew it wasn't performance
side night a customers.
That's true.
I've never heard any complaints.
So if you guys have had complaints about
the house of Blues,
let a Nigga know.
You know I need to.
I need to hear that shit.
Maybe Dan Ackroyd's house of Blues in
Connecticut at the Mohegan Sun deal fell
through gigantic fail.
Why don't I read that?
You fucking
motherfucker house of Blues charges a
buttload that is true.
They have a lot of built in costs.
It costs.
I get paid the same amount to do a 300
seat room in Vegas as I do to do the
house of Blues,
which is like 900 seats,
which is pretty crazy.
Yeah.
That's kind of fucked up because they
have all these built in.
Um,
they have built in costs
in pockets.
Oh Shit.
Built in pockets in their prices.
That's another thing.
The prices were ridiculous.
Like a bud light with six bucks or
something like that.
Is it really?
Where is it?
What is it?
Most bars,
but like,
usually,
I mean outside of Los Angeles,
usually it's like three bucks,
two bucks for a bud light outside of Los
Angeles.
Los Angeles.
Under five hours at least.
Easily.
Okay.
Well someone just fucking bitch slap
rivalries.
BBJ Joan says that Shit,
we said about hip.
The opium dens.
He says the actual
or is
two and the answer of A.
Are you hip being opium dens lying on?
He says it's not true.
It's not true.
It says,
to ingenious,
too convoluted and too silly,
is wiki 44,
but that's Wiki.
This is his opinion is often a great
deal of uncertainty and tracking word
origins since we have written worked
record going phrase may have been in
common use long before anybody wrote it
down after all,
one doesn't use slang phrases in most
writing,
such as newspaper,
a certain competence accepted.
They should use slang and everything.
So talk while we pretend to not talk the
way we talk,
I always thought that like writing
professionally,
like when I write my blogs,
I read exactly the way I talk.
I'm just like,
I wrote an open letter to Kellogg's,
which more or less I did as a writing
exercise.
I was writing every day.
I'm from month to month.
My Spike TV special was being recorded.
So I wrote down,
I wrote my material out every day.
Uh,
I wrote not wrote down material.
I wrote new blogs every day and you
know,
I just needed to shit to write about.
And one of them was this Kellogg's
banning Michael Phelps because he smoked
weed because I wrote this open letter
and I wrote it.
The way I talk with swears and just the
way I normally talk people look,
they're going to read that open letter.
Like I didn't want him to read a stupid.
I'm just writing.
It doesn't.
You could read it or you don't read it,
but I'm not gonna write something you to
have more impact.
Just like they're going to listen.
They're going to listen to a fucking
pothead,
comedian slash cage fighting commentator
like Kellogg's is gonna make their
decisions based on that.
No,
it's for you guys.
It's for humor.
It's for entertainment.
Does the word hip really hit heal from a
west African language?
It could be either or though this,
this.
I mean it could be that,
that the,
the original hip that rivalries talks
about is right.
I mean there's,
I mean if,
if there's no real.
If the origins of it are or are murky,
it could.
It could be both.
They're just not saying anything to
discredit that
anyone who gives a fuck
red band is totally right about the Oh,
is he really,
truly right?
I am telling her I.
No,
no,
it's a fucking taste thing.
I think cigarettes are disgusting and
you're sucking on them everyday because
you wouldn't think they're discussing if
you smoke them for when.
You're totally right about that.
You're right.
If I was a junkie,
I wouldn't think they're just kind of
stuff.
This guy had a shitty experience at the
Anaheim House of Blues.
Same deal as red band,
except they had to make me restate my
hand and I lost my stool.
Exactly.
That's what happened to me.
I lost my store and almost got in a
fight with a bunch of Persians and the
guy felt bad.
I felt bad and Kevin buying me a bad
tequila on night and next thing I know,
I was like,
Bro,
alright.
Oh wait,
isn't that are called the compressions?
Iranians.
Yeah,
but they're.
They don't want to be caught.
Not.
They don't want to be confused with
Irene Irania here.
Iranian talk about the fights at 1:10.
It was
fucking awesome.
Cain Velasquez,
the guy's a legend.
He's.
He's going to go down in history as one
of the greatest ever.
I think that that was just some stellar
shit.
Cain Velasquez going to be him against
Brock Lesnar was going to be insane.
I want to see him against fate or really
I would love to see Cain Velasquez
against fader.
I think every time cane fights it gets
better.
You know,
the heavyweight division is a
motherfucker right now,
Shane car wound versus Frank Meir and
Brock Lesnar is going to fight the
winter and you know,
who knows what the fuck is ever going to
happen to fate or fate or ever gets to
the UFC.
The fucking universe might collapse.
It might be insane.
All Right Ladies and gentlemen,
we've had a long ass show at 5:44.
So that means even with our downtime,
we did like an hour and 20 minutes at
least maybe an hour and a half.
Love Ya.
Thanks for tuning in Addison,
Texas this weekend,
next week or early next week.
Uh Oh,
Canada.
I'm in Canada next week.
Shazamm bitches.
I'm in Toronto.
I'm in a couple other places.
I don't know what the fuck I am,
but we'll talk about that shit next
week.
Thank you very much for tuning in.
I love you bitches.
And um,
that's it.
All right.
I got to find out how to end this.
It would've been cooler if I figured out
a way to say thank you.
I love you.
Shut up.
Bye.