Oops.
And people can say all they
want about like the soccer.
Rob was old and he's definitely, he's
definitely, definitely, but dude,
you dismantled him.
That was like the most,
the cleanest, most like precise
performance of your career yet.
I was just like, all right, do this,
this myth to perfect. It was perfect.
It was just perfection.
Yeah. Poor guy. Yeah. That's
business. You know his business. Yeah.
I get old and hopefully,
hopefully it'll slide out before that guy,
after Melvin Manhoef he should have
been like, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What's up man? Exactly. Yeah Dude,
that's business. It's like, you know,
it's kind of like a guy I
looked up to for so long and,
and one of those things like I feel
it's a big respect to the guy and I feel
like I owe a lot of my career
is due to him. So yeah,
definitely those who don't
follow mixed martial arts.
Sakharov was a famous Japanese guy who
was one of the first guys to beat the
Gracies and he fought a bunch
of them. You know, he fought,
fought hoist a couple of
times. They fought for 90
years and the legacy that guy,
yeah. I mean, he's just that that is as
legacy his legacy gets. Yeah. He's a,
you know,
you list like all time favorites,
got damn soccer robbers on everybody's
list. Some of those fight to the end.
Fucking always fuck out. That's what I
mean by what I mean by that is that, yeah,
I like exactly the mentality that he
would always take into a fight is what I
did when I was younger.
I mean,
you know what I always like was
like thinking that's what, you know,
they built my,
what you have to be to be a fighter.
That's what it built my value system.
I was like, yeah, you have to do that.
Which kept me working hard and mixed
martial arts all the way to this point.
You know, like the, so I have
to, they say, you want to
fight him? I'm like, yeah,
I have to fight them. Like I respect,
you know, I can't, oh no, I'm not gonna.
I'm not gonna fight soccer. I was like,
you know, like on, I'm going to fight.
Fuck Robin.
When someone's going to find them,
you get when and what other place in life
do you get to walk up to your hero and
punch his fucking face? What? Where
did that happen? You're my hero.
I get to punch your fucking face. Damn.
What a trip that must've been. Yeah.
You know what I mean? Like I
was like, ma'am, you my hero,
but I'm going to try to smash you.
Read is what are the w is
there a moment in your mind,
in the fight while you're realizing
you're doing this or you? So yeah,
for sure you were relaxed because I
remember the exact moment that I was like,
ah, I got him in this one
move and then I like put,
put my hand on his face and I put my
hand on his face and punched him and I'm
like, man, I'm punting. Fuck
or Robert Right now. Wow.
What did I brief? Like little blink
of a moment when you went back.
Then I was like, oh, you gotta be, you
gotta beat him up. I was like, oh no.
To me it was like, okay,
I'm a robot. Like I wrote,
I wrote for fight magazine before it,
like I'm a robe or Nah,
I think it was on my blog and I wrote,
I'm a robot in there.
I just like go in there and like,
I feel like I'm driving a robot so
I'm just doing this, you know, like,
you know, I'm just doing it like I'm
behind my eyes playing video games. Right.
You know what I mean? Like Oh,
I'm playing Xbox right now.
Is that the best way to keep emotions out?
Fuck yeah.
Cause I'd fought like
messed up my fights before.
I'm like God killed him and then
I'm like, ah, I'm tired right now.
Like what the hell? You know, you
gotta be like looked out. Yeah,
it's more for me at least.
I know some guys have to get
more psyched up, you know?
But for me, I just know that I have
to like chill myself out so I don't go
to bananas. So you just fight,
just say, just do it on a robot.
But every once while you've got to go
into your crazy gene and get retard
strength and that's when
you're in a bad spot. No. Yeah.
That's where he's just got to get like,
I gotta like hulk out of it.
It's like Hulkamania is that was what,
remember when you were fighting GSP and
that's what, yeah, I know it's famous.
Yeah. What's his face? Why am I blanking
on his name? I know mark laymen.
Mark laymen. Jesus Christ. I'm blanking
on Mark Layman's name, but what?
Mark Lehman and he's
yelling retard strength.
And I was saying his corner
is yelling out retards.
Famous. Oh, I did it came famous.
Yeah, recharge. I remember. No,
I remember the people are like, because
those, like I wanted everybody to know.
I'm like, his corner is calling out
for real. Like you need to know this
is the shit man.
Layman is not easy to just not only just
a really good Jujitsu instructor based
soccer. Cool dude to talk to.
He's a smart guy. Super Smart.
Like smart. I know. Yeah. It's
a smart dude. Jujitsu, you know,
he breaks things down. You know, it's
uh, he's a, he's a fascinating dude.
He's a character. I love that
guy. He's a fascinating dude.
Jujitsu filled with fascinating people.
That's what a lot of
people don't understand.
They think of Jujitsu is being like
some sort of a meathead thing. Art,
it's just for people that don't
know that they think that though.
But I mean a lot of the guys that we
train with her like computer guys are like
guys who that athletic back in the day.
Like I felt like Jiu Jitsu is this
like exclusive and expensive thing.
You know what I mean? Like, oh,
like not many people did it,
but the people who did it were like
well educated and they know the latest
thing. Right. And it was Brazilian
Jiu Jitsu, you know, so when I,
I remember I would be in there broke as
hell, you know, training and then, no,
it'd be like four years and you know,
doctors and chiropractors then whatever,
you know, like, and I've just like some
poor kid. Like I would go to the gyms,
you know, it is expensive. That does
keep a log. Keep out the riff Raff.
Yeah. That's a funny way of thinking it.
Right. Did you Jitsu super expensive?
Well,
not anymore really anymore.
A lot of guys have it look a
buck 75 a month to 50 a month.
Like I read that all over the place to
50 bucks, dude, that's Truong money.
That's strong money. If you're
making like you know, $700 a week,
which like a lot of people are, that's
what you bring home. If you're doing well,
you're doing pretty well there.
And then
Jim, are you driving by right
now? Joe Rogan was not driving by,
I'm like reading shit online.
I'm like people how much people charge
for Jujitsu classes and I think Hansel's
or s somewhere around there.
I think John John jocks over like one 75
one especially when a lot of people use
it as an exercise and I paid like
$39 a month from it and you go down
there, you could talk him down. Yo, you
could talk Machado down. Let's talk about,
just come on. He's a cool guy.
I wouldn't, I wouldn't. I would.
It's worth everything and more. He's,
he's great. It was a great year,
but I understand where people are.
If people are broke,
I understand broke motherfucker. I would
roll up in there and be like, dude,
come on man. Just give me some
Jujitsu just a little bit.
Just give me a fucking bro and I'll
take six weeks out. Don't worry.
Come on man. I'll pay you. Oh, that's
cute. I don't like this new setup. Look,
this is me and red band sitting here,
man.
But now,
but now we look like we're in Goddamn
aliens like were in the bunker right now
we're in a bunker over here and Joe
Rogan is missile command right now.
Man told Joe Rogan is
like or touching you.
I can't even tell her room right now.
Should we be paying attention
to these electronics?
You just looking at this
screen, this screen it. I know,
but this is what everyone else sees.
No,
most of them were like in a bunker.
Me Or red banner in a bunker
right out like Joe Rogan.
It's somewhere in this house.
Joe Rogan is here.
I guess people don't, sometimes they
just lift and most people are listening.
Oh my. It's a tiny fraction
of the cost. See watching man,
but what about my screen?
What about my screenshot?
Like this guy is loud as fuck.
Is he talking about?
They don't even know if I idea
what you're talking about. Oh,
well here's the punchline. Everybody is
the computer screen I was talking about.
He's looking at the computer screen with
the live viewers are saying chasing me.
It looks like taking some big shots since
the last time I seen him taking some
shots. But Hey, what?
What's the deal with the,
what is the most you've ever felt like
after a sparring session or after a fight?
I'm like, what's the most
he ever felt like, Whoa,
I just got to settle the fuck down.
What's the most,
do you remember a fight or
if or sparring session or,
cause you've had some crazy sparring.
Actually had some dumb ones.
Like we're only human bronies to Ronnie.
You slam it out or use the
damn box it out. Like, man.
I'm like, yeah, this is fun.
But afterwards you're like, ah
man, I'm stupid right now. Yeah,
there's a lot of guys.
I mean,
how many guys do you know that that did
that too much and they're just not there
anymore? I don't know. It's a
few guys. Right? I know one guy,
I'm 42 I know a few guys
starting to know guys,
guys that used to be okay
and the other not. Why me?
I don't really know Nick Diaz, but,
but you know what I'm saying. Right.
If you go, if you don't know, this has
been addressed on a previous podcast,
but Jason May have know her,
but there was a big incident at CBS where
Jason got into the cage and asked Jake
shields a question. He got jumped
by everybody and it was nuts.
It was Nick Diaz was one of
the guys that was involved in,
did he throw the first punch?
Is that was allegedly,
is that what happened simultaneously with
three other people and it was the bay.
It's probably the best picture ever meet
with my hands, but like what's up guys?
So reject the whole thing is so
ridiculous. It was so unnecessary.
It was so unnecessary on
so many fronts and then,
and we talked about this last time,
we should bring it up again,
but I think it was bullshit that you
got in trouble for it. I think I go,
he got jumped. He got assaulted. Yes
he shouldn't have been in the cage,
but it doesn't mean you should be
assaulting him and I don't even think it's
their fault because it's so
many fucking people in the cage.
It shouldn't have been in there. You
can't have that many people in the cages.
You shouldn't blame,
blame and strike force for letting those,
you guys get close to each other.
They should have been regulating it.
They should've watched a cage. I think
they were fucked up to jump you for sure.
But I think the reason
why they jumped users,
you were allowed to get in that cage.
You shouldn't have been allowed to.
They should have had it all set up.
It should have been like how they would
do it to the UFC or if you were going to
come in and you were going to challenge,
you know,
after a fight you would wait and then
when you know Jake was done talking,
then we'd say,
all right,
now I have a guy who would really love
to sit down and talk to you right now.
Jason May Have Miller and you would
come in. So it's like respectful.
They fucked up by just
leaving the door open.
We're going to leave the door open and
do is get hyped up and like, I want to,
I want to fuck when you've
got to do some of us. Well,
you're doing something on TV, so
I'm sure you're thinking like, fuck,
what am I doing? I'm going to
get in. All right, here we go.
I'm just going to do this.
It makes perfect sense. Yeah,
let's do this. Like there's very
little filter on my brain. We got,
were you sober at the time? Yeah,
totally. So bad. I was like, hmm,
this is a good idea. I just fought
earlier that night. Right? That's right.
That's right. And I thought authority,
Corals Psych, right? Yeah. Okay,
so you're flying high. Yeah, exactly. So I
was real pumped. I mean, you know, right.
I Dunno. And then all of a
sudden we're getting there.
I'm in a bra and I tweet woop. So you
start up this website. Don't be scared.
homey.com because uh,
Nick Diaz is a,
it's difficult to get a fight with them.
Is that what's going on?
What's the actual real cause I know
this is all I know is what I read on the
Internet. Tell me what's
going on man. He says,
don't be scared homie all the time. Right.
That's his, he says, don't be scared.
Right. That's his little
tagline. I stoled it if my mouth,
that's awesome. And look, the
guy that you own don't be scared.
homey.com and that site is all dedicated
to you getting a fight when Nikki is,
well, you know, to me I
like, yeah, definitely.
You are a nightmare.
Imagine pissed may hem off and mayhem
was coming after you let it Nate.
Man, he's relentless. He's
relentless like you are.
You're in this, it's
not like it's, you know,
you're just calling some random personnel.
You're calling a guy out who's an MMA
fighter who you have in all he fights.
He's fought so many times.
One 83 he always fights there.
But then when it's me, somebody, he's
talked shit about like for years,
the guys talk shit about me and
without fail my name, all these guys,
these f bombs with wood painted hair,
these Joe Rogan words with painted hair,
you know, like he's, you know,
he said all these terrible things about
you Paul with hill. So where's the end?
But yeah, and when it comes down to
signing a contract, what is this? Oh,
here she is. His manager
comes on answers. Oh yeah.
Well if he fights it a one
78 I'm like, okay, cool.
I'll fight Alistair Overeem.
He just has to make one 90 that's it.
I'll fight them. I'm fucking
fight that fucker this weekend.
One night he's going to make one night,
right? Yeah. I mean he got loose.
Can you push that? Yeah, we'll, we'll do
what you do. Do, do, do, do dude. Wow.
It hurts my ears. Oh, sorry
bro. Here we go. Here. I got it.
I got it. Let's touch me.
Red Band. So he wants,
he's saying that he wants you to get
down to one 78 which is highly unlikely.
So John, you want to do it in January?
I like, yeah, I, there's no way.
And Jason used to fight.
He fought in the UFC at one seven
goddamn skeleton. God, dude,
that was a skeleton. It was the
dumbest thing I ever did. I was like,
why did I do that?
He may seem to you and I
had a conversation about it
where I was yelling at you.
I was like, you can't do this man, don't
this diet. That shit is too. I'm like,
I'm like, this is too much,
man. This ain't good. This,
there's a lot of guys, man,
that I think fight better when
they don't have to cut weight.
They just feel better. Like look how
much better BJ looked in his last fight.
I don't know.
I don't know if that's just the way
they match up with him and Matt Hughes,
but he just looked like
going into the cage.
You lived did not look healthy when he
made one 55 the last time. He always does.
He always looks a little drawn out. He
always looks great during the fight time,
but he always looks a little
down the magic that you
don't, man, it's hard to do.
Like
even cutting a little bit of weight
is scheduling yourself really well.
You know what I mean? And like
the right way. Yeah, exactly.
Suck the water out the right way. And
Rick rehydrate the right way to use ivs.
Yeah. Yeah. You should always
use ivy. Yeah, of course.
Because I hear some guys don't like to
use them. I'm like, God damn. You know,
they looked at,
I feel like they're doing something gross
so they're sticking a needle in them.
You know what I mean? Yeah. Whatever.
That's science put more in there.
That's the way to do it if
you're going to do it at all.
But because I mean you have to
drop weight. That's the thing,
like that's what you think about guys
like Frankie Edgar guys that just don't
cut any weight at all. They just fight
it. What they find out. I mean, you know,
that's awesome.
I do think there's a benefit to that.
There's gotta be a benefit
physically. Right? For sure.
You don't have to cut the weight,
so you don't have to like
damage yourself that bad.
How much do you damage yourself
if you had a gun or, no man,
I think sitting in a hot box for a long
time will take years off your life for
fuck yeah,
thanks.
Adjusted the microphone. Like he
was changing the collar on a tiger,
preplanned it for like 10 in 10 or
15 seconds. I was looking at it like,
all right, I'm just gonna go in there
real quick. I even thought about, hey, go,
hey Jason, look at that over there and
do them of those things. So if you,
let me get back to the subject, because
this is a fascinating subject for me.
Yeah. If you, if you lose weight, so like
say if I'm say, what do you walk around?
I like to 10 so I'm like,
well actually I'm not less than that.
Two Two oh seven now when you get,
when you get to the point where
you're about to cut weight,
like when you're in training camp,
when do you start
to dehydrate yourself? Do you take
like three days? Two days, three days,
two well to really, and so when you
started to, how heavy are you? Uh,
I don't know. Two. Oh, probably
two oh three two two a two.
So you got to lose somewhere between
1517 pounds. Yeah. Yeah. Wow. Yeah.
And it's in three but I mean,
but I'm already reduced my calories and
meeting of the week so that I'm losing.
Some are like,
you [inaudible] like I'm just really light
and most of my calories are from like
water calories. So I'm like hydrated
then bolt and then dropped my,
drop my weight, all that he'd
done there. Yeah. I mean,
I know it will take some time off your
life because I'm sitting here in the
thought of box with the damn plastic suit
on doing hoppies, right? One, two, three,
four, five, six. So you think that
the benefit that gives you, yeah,
age is well worth it. Most of us are
doing it, so you know what I mean?
Like both guys are like bigger
anyway. Isn't that crazy though? Yeah.
Well what the hell you every little,
every competitive edge and I know,
but I mean you guys both try to find,
you're both doing it.
Is it a competitive edge? Yeah, we
it it'd be better if you have just,
she shakes if I said can yeah, just say,
listen man, don't be
crazy. Everybody's nervous.
Whatever. I know it's a funny thing
though, isn't it? To be like that.
I wish we could just shake hands like, Yo,
let's just do it like this weekend bro.
Like you know, oh like
little away. Come on,
step off our barstools right now,
the cutting weight things.
I think it's a very unfortunate
situation where guys, hey man,
you're not fucking doing it bro.
It's a fucking headache.
It's the only part of my job
that I'm like, this is bullshit.
This only part of my job.
Like, man, I wish I could
just go, hey dude, let's just,
let's keep it real right now.
The fights would be better to write.
Maybe we have more energy, but that
was the question. Like how much,
what percentage do you think
it takes away from you?
Say if you're at 100% at two 10 like this
right now, I don't know man. I want him,
I want to say 100% I'm back.
I want to say that. Yeah,
I want to rehydrate.
You get back to 100% I think so.
I think 24 I've had it
where like, I'm like, yeah,
24 you got it down to a science
now I'm 24 hours. Most of the,
I fucked up before for sure. Like I've
had bad equipment and that kind of thing.
It's fucking in Chicago we didn't have
a damn dry sauna. Oh really? Yeah.
No Dry Sauna. It's, you know. So what do
you do that you turn the heat on or saw?
My God,
we're in there anyway.
Trying to slit the weight out and it took
forever and I was fucking dying and I
had forgot to go fight five. She's 25
but you know, five by 25, you know,
but the damn, um, well
what do you call it? Uh,
it's just like part of the game, you
know? So what, don't cry about it.
You chose this life so you can
just figure out another way to cut.
What do you do if you don't have a sauna?
So you have to cut how many pounds of
water he trying to cut by the last day?
Uh, tenish and 10. Yeah. So when it loud,
maybe like I've tried to
be making like ish, but
I, I've cut weight perfect
before, but, but you know,
sometimes there'll be a 10 or 11 and I've
done that. If you don't have a sauna,
does new and try to trick you. But we
did it, bro. I did it before that fight.
You but would, you said you
didn't have a sauna, right? Yeah,
we didn't have a sign up, but I did
it. What'd you do? The steam room.
It was steam room. Oh, so he did
it in a steamer? Yeah. Wow. Yeah.
So we didn't have the same thing.
Right. You sweat it out, right.
I is it the same moisture
on, yeah. Close you off.
So it takes long die, but I, you
know, whatever. I just worked,
that's just me and I had a bike
harder and stuff like that.
I had to like swept myself out worse,
you know?
So you think that after
the Ivs and everything like
that or your performance is
at 100% of your capacity or close enough
to it, right. You Do, you do it right.
If you from fuck up. I mean that's just
how it is. Here's a fucking science this.
Yeah, of course. I mean,
but you know, and my mat,
like my coach knows how much
I sweat. Like he's like, oh,
we got it timed out about right.
Like Ah, he's got to do this.
You know what I mean? Like in time it
is, everybody is different, right? Yeah.
For sure.
A good coach has to recognize that and
be working with a bunch of different guys
and see a bunch of different,
very different, yeah.
There's some dudes you can't
really cut that much weight.
They get to a certain point they brought
it just don't work anymore and some
dudes can do it.
Some dudes can do huge superhuman amounts.
Thiago Alves like what? Gleason
t bow. What the fuck dude.
Glace and t bow fights at
one 55 and the dude is huge.
He's gigantic.
When he gets in the cage,
he's got these bodybuilder arms and back
and shit and you're like this mother
fucker ways.
One 55 he looks like he easily won 85 he
looks like he's 30 pounds heavier and I
don't know what he actually
ways when he gets in the cage,
they do that with boxing.
They make the guys way in the day of,
I don't think they want to
see those numbers in the UFC.
I know they're so different.
I don't want to,
I don't think they want to see no thirties
you might see a 30 day I go Alvarez
might see at 30 you might see
at 200 200 pound welterweight.
Holy Shit Dude,
that's a robotic goddamn weight to lose.
I don't know how these guys do it.
They all have different methods and every
camp has like their own dude who's a
master at that shit. Who's at what
camp is the best? It cutting weight.
There's some camps are just known for
cutting tremendous amounts of weight.
Like Att, they're known, they're known
for doing it. They cut a lot of weight.
I don't know. Did they have
a guy? How does that work?
Do they have like one guy who's like
the the master trainer and master weight
cut strategist. I Dunno. How do you
guys get there? Yeah, Ryan. Yeah,
Ryan Barson more.
You're more manager who can cause
you can kind of know yourself.
So moreover you need somebody to
like know exactly when to do it.
Like be your coach. You know what I mean?
Through it. So, and Ryan, he knows how to,
you know, that's what you guys have
such an interesting relationship now.
If people don't know
Ryan is Ryan Parsons is,
he's been around for many, many years.
Coach some of the, the, you know,
great guys in the business, spent a
lot of time with Dan Henderson and,
and Randy coture and he's a, he's a
brilliant guy. Very, very brilliant guy.
And he's a manager and trainer to you
and just a couple of their fighters and
King Mo and uh, this new guy,
what's his name? Pat. Pat.
Pat Company Durkin and it just a few.
He works with just a few guys.
You guys have like this incredibly
tight relationship, man. That's a trip,
you know, good guy, great
guy, great guy. And,
but the whole set up the way
you guys have it, you know,
like this one guy running around training
and managing this fucking select group
of killers and guiding them. It's a
fickle, interesting situation. It is.
It's great. It's like,
you know, we, uh, tight,
tight knit group and we all train hard
and whatever, you know, it's like a,
we don't need to open the
floodgates and Brian, right. Yeah.
Individualized attention. It's definitely
better, right? Yeah, definitely,
definitely. And on a core tight
group that you can totally,
completely count on the team. You
know, we're a team but we're not like,
hey everybody come hang out with us. And
we're like, we're a tight knit team. Yeah.
For people who don't know, like
you're, you're such a wild dude.
You're always crazy and yelling and shit,
but you're very disciplined, you know?
And that's what people probably either
wouldn't expect or don't understand.
You're very disciplined. Like
even though you're wild, hard man,
don't show up for flights out of shape.
You know what I mean?
Maybe there's one or two times in your
whole career where you haven't taken
someone as seriously as it should have.
It's true.
You're pretty goddamn discipline.
Yeah. I am. I, I'm a Dork.
I like, I want to play video games. Right.
But look how much time you spend
training very fucking diesel.
But what I'm saying is you go train
and then you play video games. I mean,
you're draining bay tech. That's
the bit that's like, yeah,
but I played video games that for this
or you don't, yeah, that's my reward.
Or you know, whatever. Like I dunno,
I like to read and write and stuff.
It's easier to live that way. So
going back to this Nick Diaz, thanks.
So you've been trying so hard to
get this fight and what do they do?
It is if you'll fight it. No,
they're saying no because the, yeah,
one seven that's saying no.
That thing,
no one 78 is saying no,
but he's no one 83 plenty of times.
And then it's just the fun.
Scott Smith shamrock.
Who else did he find out a way?
I don't know guys that he could beat up,
but he can't beat me up.
This is a fucking very important fight
for ya. Yeah, I mean, I don't know.
I'm angry about the whole
thing like I need, I need this.
Like I'm going to beat you up. You
shouldn't have jumped me. I'm a nice guy.
He bullied me. Right. He bullied and
beat him down? Yes. Really deep down.
Oh yeah,
about Thursdays at 10 30
10 30 and MTV.
MTV was a clip from season three which is
fantastic. That you should watch. What?
What were you when you got in
there and got in the ring? Oh wait,
one tweeted at me, bro. Why don't you
tweet me, Bro. I did. I tweeted it today.
Did you tweet it today? Yeah,
I'm looking back through red pen.
All bombed right now.
Tweeted it today. I actually, somebody
tweeted to me and I retweeted it. Yeah.
Oh, so you just gave me a
retweet. Alyssa. Man, let's just,
I dunno bro. If it doesn't have
your name on it, fucking hurt.
It doesn't have your name.
All right. See, look, I'll
show it to you right here.
It doesn't have your name on Joe Rogan,
red Bam.
And have you seen Ma'am
Miller beat down this bully?
Huge slams and grappling ground shortly.
Some nissions.
Y'All actually, y'all abroad. I
put, I put the guy on a fill a team.
Phil Baroni. You used to have this.
I don't know if he still does it.
I hope he still does it.
If he still does it,
he's going to break some of the neck.
He does a front headlock choke,
but you keep your,
keep your belly on top of his head so
you can lift them off the ground with his
neck. Scott Jorgensen did
that. Yeah. In the WBC,
the front sugar Lindland does it too,
right? Yeah, kind of. Yeah. Yeah. Kind of.
Yeah man.
And you did your Jitsu Dork to everybody.
I realize as you git through
nerded everybody right now, my bad.
Me and you were like,
sorry everybody that wasn't very,
you guys don't get that
joke. It's a technique. Yeah,
we were totally in
descriptive. Yeah, we were.
We get a guy and you get your hands
locked under his Chin and then you place
your body,
your belly over the top of the back of
his head and as you lift him up, his,
his neck is basically trapped against
your chest cavity. You glide. Yeah.
Your hoist him up in the air by
his fucking neck exam. Gnarly.
And it's very hard to stop. If a guy,
a strong guy, big strong wrestler,
it gets that shit locked up backwards row.
Just go like this.
It's nasty. It's nasty. Oh
Man. I'm sorry. Vicious choke.
Last time he was Chris
called him Chris and then he was Chris
on the message board for like weeks
afterwards. People just kept fucking
torture going. I'm calling him Chris,
Chris American. I'm Kristy. Let's
play. Nice. Nice. Mr. Miller.
So when when you do that show,
I mean without giving away too
much of how the show is done mean,
that episode was amazing
again,
and I'll tweet it back at right there.
We'll fucking do a double
tweet background. I mean,
I had never been so happy.
That was like one of the most happiest
was that it was the question like how
much is that coached? Is that
kid just being a Douchey, his,
that's his douchey self. Is that
real dude? It's totally real. We can,
nobody tells him, listen to this, ham
it up for the camera. We could go,
let's we're,
we're beating up mentally disabled people.
Oh Man, God. Are these guys that are
just, you know, they're just super calm,
knucklehead, knucklehead.
No Grad on the block. Right.
What's show this kid?
This kid who got in there with you?
This kid has no martial arts experience.
The best part about the whole thing is
that the guy called me out too and I was
like, man, what a coincidence.
I was like, hey buddy,
what a coincidence that you and your next
bro. And I'm like I'm next. I'm like,
yeah I have next.
Because there's nobody in front of
me cause you know he doesn't know.
He doesn't know that it's me and I like
busted out man. It's a great episode.
It's like I watched it.
They oh you did? Yeah. Yeah.
I watched it at tiger in a mouse.
Beat the fuck out of that kid.
But people don't know is
you are being very nice,
very nice surgical surgical, surgical
like I was like, all right, here it comes.
I'm going to just get,
even when you punched and kicked him,
I could see you were in kicking him
that hard one. Good one. One good one.
And that was it.
I knew I go knock,
you're not going to hurt him real
bad if he just kicked his leg.
Oh my leg by the enemy. He
was like, okay, I'm over this.
I hit him with a body kick cause I would
stop them. The first thing I did. Yeah.
Yeah.
I paid him with a body kick.
I just let them come in and kick and
you didn't even hit him that hard.
You'll sweat the Shin pads
on too. I'm like, man, come
on beard. I was like, really?
It's kind of crazy though that you could
ever get in a situation where a kid
who's just some punk bullied kid could
ever get into a situation where he's on
television and he's fighting.
Well, well you to America.
What a fucking quit who
sanctions this shit.
Who says this is okay? It's cause
it's, it's a sparring session.
Is that what it is?
We're in sparring gear.
You easily could have been the strike
force champion you if you had 10 more
seconds in that round
three. I say three. Really?
You think you haven't had a dark,
it was his, he was turning purple,
the whole deal. I mean, so, okay,
you could have potentially been a world
champion and you're allowed to just get
in there and beat the fuck out of
some kid who's never really sparred,
never really fought before,
never competed. It was beautiful.
Poor fuck that kid,
that kid, he might just,
I feel like there's some
professional turning to a gay
hooker now. He might just,
you know what I'm saying? I mean, when
somebody just a trainee hutches you,
I think you'd be the hottest trend
he might have. So little self esteem,
you want to just start,
just give up on lack.
Come on where America should
would devastate you. Dude,
I saw you on your young man.
You think you're the shit.
Sorry. You're a young man.
You think you're,
you're the shit and you know you're
an asshole and you're an asshole.
Then on television and these guys here,
he's really an asshole to those guys.
That wasn't bullshit. If he, if he, if,
if this guy grows from, from it, right.
Well there you go. I'm doing the service.
If he grows from it, it seems like, yeah,
it's like gross or it's going to kill you.
You get to option. Yeah. I mean, yeah,
he's turned to say that one of my
contestants going to go jump off a bridge
because we got beat up on MTV,
the bully beat downs.
Douche bags are in utter pain and that's
why their dues Deuce, of course, any big,
huge devastating thing like
this could go one or two ways.
They can either learn from it and grow
from it and realize they were being a
shithead or they just become devastated.
Oh my God,
I hit the rock so I can
be depressed about my job.
Joe Rogan at the rocks like this.
Boom. That's just life, right?
You think you're going to jump off and
do a harbor of some sort and the boat,
a speedboat, you're headed towards
the cliff bar slowing down.
I think it's gonna happen.
I think it's that kick guys going to go
and beat the fuck out of those two guys
that put on this show now.
I think he's going to be a super bowling
now and he's going to hate them even
more.
And fucking steel man.
Fight him in age to the death with a tire
iron and a trash can lid as a shield.
Wow. You thought this out. So tell her,
would you have like one of those
leather straps? Are you kidding me?
Why the hell not like I don't
want to hold the trashcan.
Customize that to cover it around here.
Actually. Maybe we could do like pipes,
like pipes. Like they look cool. You know,
like isn't it crazy that just a thousand
years ago that's how they were rocking
bro. They had a shield and a sword and
that's how you took over a town. Yeah.
Fucking a man.
Could you imagine?
I'm just trying to think what some towels
in years. I'm just trying to, yeah,
just trying to mind your own business.
Just chilling,
hanging out with your wife and kids and
you see over the horizon a group of men
with swords and shields.
You like these mother fuckers and
they're just going to come and everybody,
they don't know they're going to fuck
or kill. What is it going to be fucker.
Kill fucker. Kill Fucker, kill
fucker. Kill, fuck. Then kill,
killed and fuck. That's the whole
deal. I think it's fucked up.
No matter who's coming over the hill.
Trying to fuck her is amazing that
people didn't just catch suicide.
What back then?
It's put the live down here.
Medieval days when people are hacking
each other with swords. It's amazing.
People didn't say, she said, I'm just
going to jump off a fucking cliff.
Life sucks. This is
ridiculous. Everywhere we go.
He's talking about a barbarians coming
over the hills with axes and Troy like
that happen all the time. What happened
from one side of every, you know,
16 weeks like you wouldn't like,
you know, you just fucking leave.
You just leave. Yeah. You just
leave. You're like whatever.
All those fucking lies Gingiss con
killed. They're just lazy. Yeah.
They just laying around. I should have
got out of there. That's business, Bro.
Everybody is going to die.
I'd rather get hacked up by barbarians
then fucking go out the way.
I'm probably going to go out.
Shit, whoa. Wait a minute.
How are you planning on going out?
How are you planning on going out at
it's worst than getting hacked up by
barbarians. Did you talk
to Dr Phil About? Yeah,
if you like whatever bro,
though we're not worse ways to die.
That's right up there. No way, Bro. You
just be like, oh shit. And then dead.
Maybe not. Maybe they gut you.
Maybe they hang you by your ankles,
but I would fight the guy for sure. They
would have to fucking kill me. Okay.
I'm fighting them back or I
hear you right? You wouldn't
find a backup. Love them.
You might get a company like sword.
It doesn't mean you can do, fuck it.
I'll double leg the dude and then fucking
steal the sword right off his fucking
back of his horse. Man. I
already thought about this.
Tackle the dude off of his horse,
then fucking grabbed his sword
and just take out as many I can.
Hopefully it will be a Jackie Chan
seat, but if not, fuck it. Whatever.
I'll just go out. Fuck. Ahmed's.
Aw, you hack my arm off. Fuck.
What'd you have a different strategy
of a dude had a double edge sword or a
single edged sword? Yeah,
you would look at him.
You say the single edged sword
as he's kind of fucked. I would,
I would try to make an
assessment as much as possible,
but if they're just coming,
they're coming. Ah Man. I
hit your microphone. Men.
This fucking bunker. It's fallen
apart. Harold. Let me fix that.
Let's play fuck wrong with it.
I think you just keep hitting
it. Nah Man. Oh, hello. Hi.
Anyway,
what to hell with the top barbarian.
Fucking what a strange conversation
that is. A Dude's always have.
If a guy was Coleman to Judah saw Jerry.
I know we're totally tuning
out right now. Yeah, Yo Bro.
You know what a bear could fuck of.
Definitely kill a walrus.
So quick dose.
The best though when there's
instructionals online were
due to defending against
swords. It attacks you sometimes.
You've got to worry about that.
When I was a kid, I was like always
the reading of karate magazines. Like,
why would you have to find a dude with
a knife? I'm like, damn, that sucks.
And if he, I figured the guy
already knows if you're getting Fab,
the DJ is going to stab you anyway. Right,
right. He has no, you know what I mean?
Like if you ha, if you have the
it, he's not going to show you.
That would be the best way
to get fat and let you know.
No one's going to come at you like,
well, maybe if the Rottie Trenton,
you then want,
I'll show it to you,
but you know that now you have
to jump and do the dishonor.
Most people will stab you.
They didn't even want you to know
they're going to stab you. Right.
They tried to sneak in on you.
Like what does racism,
a little racist Britain band.
Why isn't that amazing that just saying
noises like that could be racist if you
said that. What'd you
say? Ping. Ping Chong. No,
I just said Ding Dong Chin and Char Val
Asian person from the 1950 [inaudible]
movie. I know. I would never
offend Asians around man.
You know what's the craziest
thing in the back of the day, man,
those black and white movies, they used
to have a, what was that fucking, um,
there was one television show that
they used to do or a movie series.
He's stew about, uh, um, a Chinese, um,
detective and they had a white guy,
Chinese detective jeopardy. I
know, man. You're like, I am,
it's an old ass show. I'm sure someone
on Twitter. We'll know what it is.
It's an old ass show. What was
it again? It was a white dude,
but he played this Chinese detective
realize old Asian detective,
but it was a white dude who played it
and they had him in all this goofy,
it was goofy ass makeup cause it's like
1930 and shit, you know that. Yeah.
And so this, they had
this dude, nobody knew.
Asian people can't get a good factor
in that. And then you don't want to,
you know, they didn't want to give the
job to that. Charlie Chan. Thank you.
How did I not remember that?
Remember that I almost had that without
even knowing what the fuck you're
talking about. I think I blocked Charlie
out of my mind because of Jackie.
I don't want this because it was
vehicle mob. Jackie Chan, no Vietnam.
He didn't even know the word Charlie.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Joe Rogan, I get back army movies, Bro.
He never played call of duty black ops.
He hasn't tried to get him to play that,
but Bruce Buffer,
when I was at the airport,
Bruce buffer was playing call of duty
while I was waiting for his plane.
We were in England.
He Jacks dudes with his laptop
and just fucking, he's getting
like diamonds on shit and his,
you know his silver distinguished hair
and he's sitting there and his Mac book
playing call of Duty Jack.
How did he do it with the mouse pad?
Now I don't know if he's moving
pretty hard. Yeah, that ain't right.
That belt, whatever bombing he felt. He
seemed to be doing it, you know? Yeah.
I got it in three d Jay, have you
play in three d yet? What? You can
look down the sniper thing and it looks
like it's just as huge sniper tunnel.
No Way. Because you have
the three d TV Too, right?
I know.
I have to bump it to both of
you had three d TV motherfucker.
You are a nerd. That's what a lot
of people don't know, man. You're,
you're a big time computer nerd.
I like computers. It doesn't,
they're fucking amazing.
I this information in a box.
It's something more than that,
man. It's everything. It's people.
The whole fucking universe is connecting
through these things. This is,
we're going to eventually share
one giant consciousness. Well,
it's all going to be connected
through electronics. It's what? It is.
Just happening. Nice and slowly
nice and slowly. It's inevitable.
It's going in that direction for sure.
All this Wiki leak shit.
What this wiki leaks shit
represents is a new ethic.
What's going on is that there's
going to be no more secrets anymore.
You can't have them anymore.
The exchange of information between
people is going to be at one point,
it's going to be instantaneous and
it's going to be all encompassing.
We're going to have everything
I know about you and
everything you know about me.
We going to know everything about
each other. It's just inevitable.
You're telling me you're going to plug
a chip into my brain and we're going to
blend into one thing. I'm,
I'm telling you this is,
this is without a doubt
where we're headed.
There's no question and talking
to everyday, well obviously, look,
if something happens like an asteroid
or a tsunami and each other up for sure.
I was talking to my manager the other day,
my business manager Matt,
who's a great guy and he's
just not a conspiracy theorist.
He's a real level headed
dude. And uh, he lives in a,
I don't want to say where he lives,
but I said,
do you ever think about
living near the ocean?
You ever think about getting like a
place like on the water that may kind of
dope? And he goes, yeah,
but I think about tsunamis
and I'm like, wow. Yeah,
you should think about tsunamis. Fuck, we
all should think about tsunamis, right?
At any point in time,
the earth could just decide
to move a little bit and well,
a mile high wall of water heads towards
Los Angeles like that Shit's real man.
That could happen or we
get hit by an asteroid.
Something falls the ocean and a mile
high wall of water heads towards Los
Angeles and he's not fucking imagine.
Could you imagine?
It's part of the charm of the
city. Yeah. If you're going to die,
it might be the only child. Every time
I'm in a parking garage in Los Angeles,
you live in the fucking top of
a god Damn Mountain. Absolutely.
You live him. I had to drive all the way
up a mountain because you're worried.
You're lucky. I don't
live in Colorado, Bro.
We don't want to be seen
each other when I come to la.
If it wasn't for my wife getting pregnant,
I'd still be in Colorado. All of water,
dude. I worry about everything.
I'm a fucking freak. I
worry about meteor impacts.
I worry about the shifting of the polar
ice caps are worried about pollution or
you should go about war.
You should go downhill mountain biking
because that's going to fix something.
I think it needs to go skiing
now, bro. Well, I would,
except by watching a detailed report
on TV where a lady who was downhill
mountain biking got attacked by a
fucking mountain lion who ate her head,
pulled her, don't do it.
Hold on. I like a cool way.
Her friend was still low mountain land
with a stick as it was dragging her
screaming,
bleeding friend with her face torn off
into the bushes and he's beating with a
stick. So what's the, saw that
lady on TV, man. And I'm like,
I don't think I'll be mountain biking,
but it could have shit.
So that's it happened to you. That's,
yeah. That's hilarious. You should go.
You should do something outside your
comfort zone, bro. Yeah, yeah, for sure.
But I'm not comfortable with anything
that's, I'm, oh, you're not water boat.
What do I need to do that's outside
of my comfort zone? Tell me master.
I just feel like why you don't be scared
of life bro. No, I'm Alyson on my behalf.
Fucking around. I would totally
know you're making me nervous.
I'd have fuck around.
But you know my dog was eaten by a
mountain lion and I saw the mountain line.
Wait, so you think there's some
mountain line with like how to get him
to say it? They have, I have
personal experience with them.
I know that they're dangerous as fuck.
If you're going to go,
if you're going to go around here,
you gotta run into mountain lions.
You can whatever,
whatever percentage wise
or you'll probably be okay.
I would fight them for a minute. Oh you'll
be fine. You know you know what to do.
But a girl on a fucking bike in very rare,
very rare.
They don't fuck with men.
They have killed women.
They killed a 19 year old girl
last year in Canada singer.
He's just a recording contract
of the period. Bullshit.
He wasn't even trying to be funny.
That's cause he's got an animal's mind.
May Have Nice animal
minds thinking about it.
He's just thinking about it. That's
what I would smell it. Smell her,
my period blood be smelling that shit.
I'm, I think I'm going to eat this.
I get all my girlfriends, bro. Yeah, man.
The kid getting killed by
wolves is pretty rare too.
We've talked about that
recently on the podcast yet.
I didn't know that wolves have killed
people as recently as this year. Yeah.
If you'd like,
you're a woman,
you're a food source and you're in
their little sector by yourself. Oh,
you're fucked up. Isn't it weird
that we have this weird thing with,
with wolves where you know it used to be,
everyone was aware that wolves were
really dangerous. You, we went backwards.
We went backwards because wolves are we,
we've dumbed down the wolf.
What do you mean fuck them up so hardcore
that we feel bad that we fucked him up,
but the reason we fucked them up is
cause wolves were eating babies and shit.
Yeah. They're eating people.
Wolves, eating people.
Before there was a kid in 2005 I got
eaten by a wolf and it was this woman that
got killed by a wolf.
This here take fucking kill pain.
So I take it you like don't
go camping or anything, Dude.
I've been camping once and a bear attacked
our cooler. Walked all of our car,
tore our cooler to shreds.
Fascinated to get eaten by animals.
Fucking do it. So should I go with it? Go.
Australia should do to die
by ostrich. Pite bro. You may
just need to turn off the mask.
Every channel at your house.
That would be embarrassing, man.
For all my friends. How'd he die?
Fucking ostrich kicked his
ass. Ate them. Right? Fuck.
He was covered. If they kick you,
you're fucked. Oh, of course.
Your guts will fall out of
that giant powerful legs. Man.
You watched way too much documentary.
I know.
I just got a whole new box set.
Like your leftovers or some shit.
No,
I just know, I don't mean turned me
out like I don't want to buy it myself.
Just keep them. Let me borrow some. I'll
give you some DVDs. I got some shit for,
I got some interesting stuff.
You should switch to cartoons for a year.
I can't do it dude. I can't do it. I, you
know, this is what I do. Okay, I'll go,
I'll go through my DVR.
I'll see like a watch HD net fights.
I watch like I looked at Anthony Bordain,
no reservation show.
I see if there's any boxing matches that
I missed and then I just go straight to
all the space shows.
It's all the universe or it's all like
some crazy shit on the science channel.
That's the only thing that's
interesting to me. This is the,
I can't watch shows like a drama
or a Sitcom. I can't do it. I just,
I can't do it and I'll watch it
for five minutes. I'll just go,
oh you know,
every now and then like breaking bad,
like a watch, like a cool drama.
Those are fun if you like.
When I was getting tattooed,
I was watching breaking bad.
I can watch like a bunch of APP.
I watch like two seasons of it's always
sunny in Philadelphia. Is that good?
What's that? One of the best
shows ever? I think so man.
But network is a well written FX,
FX,
FX, FX, FX. I think it was
the same night as my show.
Really pumping up a competitor. I know.
No, I know, but I watch it. It's like,
it's like my shows on and then you can
take the gentlemen bear show, antique.
We live in Tivo.
Lamb not competing with any of them.
The only time I watch things as they're
happening. His fights. Yeah. Happy to.
If you need to know that it's that,
I mean that's just how life is,
but oh my son is really
good man. They like, they,
they have so many great characters
and stuff and like it's well written.
Did you watch the Manny Pacquiao
fight man? Yeah man. We,
my dad and a hunting trip.
It was awesome.
Like sit out there in the
country with lots of many backup.
My Dad like screaming and yelling like
for the wrong guy. Like what? Man,
let's start it. Even pack out slingbox
I watched it on my laptop in London.
Oh yeah. Yes. Cool. Corey. Damn,
that motherfucker is good. Yeah.
I wonder though what his style though.
You know,
I wonder if he could fuck with
Floyd Mayweather. No, I know.
That's what everybody wants. The
old don't know. I still don't know.
If you look at the way Floyd Mayweather,
the way he just handled men.
My male Marquez. Yeah. You
know one mil. One Mil men.
Well Marcus style style wise though.
I think style wise did that matches
up pretty good. Like I think I'm uh,
Manny matches up pretty good.
I think that mark has couldn't
do shit to Floyd though.
And Mark has a Mayweather went to war
and they went to war twice. Yeah, I know.
Boy. Just shut all that shit down.
But I'm back heals fast patio is,
it's pretty good. He's
fast. He moves well.
It takes a good shot and a and
and you know, uh, Mayweather got,
got rocked real bad by Mosley and
like that kind of showed that. Okay.
You can get touched too, right? I
know what I mean. So he got, yeah,
he got tagged real good.
That one punch.
It really kind of fucked it up for Mosley
cause he stopped boxing and started
bombing, you know, and like he
like lost his, his rhythms angry.
He lost his rhythm. That was a tough
fight for him. Anyway, that dude is,
it's amazing that like me see boxers,
it's so strange that boxers can compete
at that higher level when they're like
40 you know, he's like 39 right, isn't it?
It's business. Yeah. There's some some,
I mean some guys can keep going and
some guys it just all falls apart.
It's interesting like look at
Hopkins because he's so technical.
40 fucking five 46 years old, still
fighting. I mean that's incredible man.
You know, I'm down the big
man at the end of the day,
that's what's the most important in
every combat sport. It's technique,
all that ferocity and everything. It's
so important to me. Have to have it.
You know, you have to have strength, you
have to have endurance, you have to have,
you know, fighter spirit. But
what's most important is technique.
All that other shit you can have to,
that all,
all that other shit has to be
processed through technique though.
And guys had just rely on one thing that
just rely on their aggressiveness or
relying on their athleticism. Like how
many times have you watch guys fight?
Like in,
you know,
MMA on TV and you see like a guy
that's like super hyper aggressive,
but yet he's got all these holes in
his standup and he's dropping his hands
goofy and is not turning his kicks over.
But he's just super aggressive
and that's how he's winning.
And he's getting guys by just being,
and you're like, this guy's just like,
eventually he's going to run
into a guy that as tough as him,
but it's technical and it's fucked.
Yeah, of course that always happens.
It's just the style. I was like, got
this guy's got smarter technique.
You know what I mean? That's
like the big battle, isn't
it? You know, isn't it? Yeah,
man. The, the, the life of martial artist,
a professional mixed martial artist that
has got to be a trippy way to fucking
pay your bill.
So I know I,
there's been moments where I've stood
across the ring for one and I'm like,
I'm about to fight another grown man
on national television. Then I like,
I like,
this is my life right now.
Do you try to squash those thoughts or
you just go, well that's it is what it is.
No, whenever I just go, Ha,
I'm about to fight somebody on TV. So you
laugh. So you think it's my head? Yeah.
It's so weird. Like I
said, whatever, you know,
you just take a different path
in your life. You're like, oh,
this is what I'm doing. You know?
It's, I don't know. It's very strange.
It's very different. But, but I mean, you
know, it's just my job. Like I just like,
this is what I'm good at to do crazy
ass way to make a living son. Yep.
That's a crazy ass way
business so fast.
Don't cry for me, Bro. What are
you talking about? I'm not crying.
We're just talking. I know. That's what
I mean. My life is to other people.
It would be horrific, you know,
getting on stage and doing comedy or,
or talking to friends. I never even
realized that, that that is like people,
a lot of people's number one
fear. And I'm like, what? Why?
Just don't want to be judged.
And he'd done it lately. Me? No,
I mean Ellis show and,
right. You know, there's,
there's a new place they want.
They want me to do a show on a 16 on what?
Huh? A show in the 16th yeah.
Of what? December. What can
I do it? Tow Rope? What?
A comedy show? Yeah. Hell yeah.
You can totally do it. I know.
What do I talk about though? Anything,
right? A bunch of shit down 16th.
What's Today's date?
Today's the 29th Oh,
so you've got like how
many days are in November?
November 30 yeah. 30 so I've got
that long to do it. I'll say,
I'll say some funny shit.
Yeah. You know what?
How much time do you have to go up
for? I don't know. I'll figure it out.
Key words I want you to use period.
Blood. Those two words. Yeah. Use those.
And coyotes.
No,
I'm having to use it from the, I mean, you
guys are seeing if I go, if I go up on,
on uh, the 16th, if they improv,
there's Hollywood punchline
period, blood period. Blood.
That that'll just be the punchline.
I guess girls would think about that shit.
If they got in the water to that sharks
will bite their pussy. Right. You know,
I mean,
my God,
could you fucking imagine the thought
and that's how you dye your hair color.
But the shark is going for your pussy
because he smells your period. Whoa.
What a horror. Someone must've died
like that. Somewhere along the line.
Some girl must've done not by a
shark. She must have. You're right.
It must've happened.
It was all the people that have been
killed by sharks for all the hundreds of
thousands of years. People have been on
this planet. My Dad had like, fuck, yeah,
yeah, dude, you can't get me in that
fucking water and then water can suck.
My Dick Kid just got
half in San Bernardino,
Santa Barbara. He wrote,
why is it so scared?
I'm fascinated. Nope, you're
scared though. But I'm not,
I just don't think that
getting eaten by a shark,
it's worth the thrill of surfing
bullshit, Bro. You feel me?
I don't need to sign. You don't want to
go mountain biking because it's sucking.
No,
you don't want to go surfing because the
fucking sharks or EU breaking it down.
Exactly. Okay. Yes, you
don't what the fuck?
Those are monsters and I try to
avoid monsters in my everyday life.
You don't want to go roller skating,
specially monsters in the water, man.
At least a mountain line. You might be
able to fucking get them in a guillotine.
You know what I'm saying?
Outline might fuck up.
You can't dude a mountain lion my fuck up.
You might get on top. You might sprawl.
You know what I'm saying?
You might take us back.
You might take that mountain lions back.
Your head shucking not out in Lyons.
You're dark thing about loud.
Fuck out of him and his stupid fucking
dirty stinky shit covered pause. Fuck,
I'm out in line,
but a shark will eat your ass hole and
there's not much you can do about it.
You wait, you're bleeding out of
your ass hole. He's going to eat.
You come up from behind so you don't even
see them common and he's just going to
start eating you. So what
bro? That's the risk.
We all take them living here on
mother earth. The great guy. Yeah,
that's beautiful man. I know, right?
I try to avoid being a part of the food
chain except the top part. Yeah, but no,
the chances that you're going to get
eaten by an animal while doing an outdoor
activity are very low.
They're way,
way higher than if you don't go to
those places where the monsters are.
I find that the the best way to cut down
on the possibility of getting eaten by
monsters is to not go near the monsters.
So you're,
would you go hang gliding?
Why am I a fucking bird?
Listen man,
that's a dumb ass way to go.
But you go to the rocks from an
errant breeze. Oh woops. Now I'm dead.
You don't want to go.
He doesn't want to go hang gliding cause
he might get eaten by a pterodactyl.
Brian, why don't you tell him the story
about your dad and parachuting? No,
paragliding. Why don't you tell
the story before you even tell it.
But that's, you know, I bet
you know shooting paragliding
in Paris shooting. So he
jumped out the fucking thing
and die. No, no, no. His Dad,
his dad, Brian, my, My, my dad worked with
somebody that every week she was like,
Hey, you need to come, you
know a skydiving with me.
Cause she did it every weekend and he
was like thinking about it even though he
didn't want to.
And then one day she died,
she jumped out and I guess like her
emergency parachute went with the regular
parachute. What? The devil to me that
was like out of one out of 1 million now.
But I would never parachute. But I think
Joseph go roller skating and if not,
I'm not scared.
Don't be scared to Homey,
homey.com that website
for her to put like be,
don't be scared of me like a sure after
the fight that it's a good idea man.
Look, you know, think about
like what would Tyler Durden do.
Dot Com they have a dark
side. Yeah, it's cool.
Brian's friend Brian. Ah, I want him
to help me. He's a fun dude, man. That
what would Tyler Durden guys WWT Dee Dee,
he says some funny shit,
man.
He's got some really good like one liners
on unreal things that are going on in
the news. He's a funny guy. He's
funny and he hates Paris Hilton a lot.
Uh, Paris Hilton Perez told Harriet. Yeah.
Nope, you're not Paris. Bronx parents,
the guy, oh no, no,
no. He hates Paris. Oh,
he ate his tweets on Paris are hilarious.
Really?
Why would he hate her? She just some
lost child. Why would he give a fuck?
Because it's funny. Yeah, he does.
He's more of a funding gap right
now to make fun of Paris Hilton.
So I'm going to again, fun. Yeah.
Just died off. Yeah, it did. Yeah.
It has to die off like,
because at a certain point in time you
become the joke for caring about her.
Like why are you still
talking about this one?
It was just one person out of a
river of humans. It's the next one.
The next one. The next one. Excellent.
Amazing though that people are
irrelevant to me. It's like why?
Like why do people famous? I was like,
this is kind of a fad. It's amazing.
Our culture. Like I feel bad for us.
Well it's bad and I started getting care.
I start Karen. Cause we other people
can like man damn it. Why do I care?
I will want to pretend that I know
what's going to happen in the future.
Cause I obviously don't,
you know,
I don't know whether or not we're going
to pour ourselves out of this downward
spiral,
this humanity downward spiral with some
sort of a technological innovation or
something, you know? But I if,
if, but if it doesn't happen,
so I forgot what I was talking.
Man,
you are fucking deep in the depths
of content you're talking about.
Before he said that Paris Hilton, Paris
Hilton, this is a quote that he did,
Paris Hilton, everyone hates you. No
one is going to watch your dumb show.
No one cares anymore.
Go Kill Yourself.
That's not enough tweet ever.
It's so being that it was funny.
It was,
sorry Ari Shaffir wrote that.
Oh, this was, so, this is
what I was going to say.
I don't know whether or not we were
ever going to pour ourselves out of this
downward spiral.
But if you look at,
like if you look at a civilization,
if you looked at a civilization like,
like right before it was going to fall
like Rome or like the Greek empire,
like any, anywhere. All you hear
about is stem going crazy. Oh,
you hear about his feathers and they're
eating and then the throwing up and
they're fucking everything
and their fucking little
boys and shit and just lions
versus Christians. It's always the
craziest, craziest shit goes down.
And that's what everybody talks
about after it falls apart. Well,
isn't that what's happening right here?
I mean it has to be.
It's happening slowly. That's what
it is. I mean, we were talking,
Brian and I were looking at the
pictures of the Colosseum in Rome.
We were having lunch at this Italian
place today and they had this photo of the
Colosseum in Rome.
And the photo was from 2010 right.
So the Colosseum was this fucking
incredible old piece of architecture where
people fought fucking lions right
there in the center of that pitch.
And there's cars just driving
around it and the cars,
the distance between the curb and the
fucking walls of this insane building is
what, 15 feet, 10 feet. It's like
there's no space. It's like car,
this insane old building
paper pry.
That shit just fell apart. It fell
apart and nobody fixed it. Yeah,
it just fell right apart. That can
easily happen with us and if it does,
they're going to be talking about us
the same way we talk about the Roman.
So mountain biking, it would
be allowing by, he's crazy.
Assholes had TV shows where
regular people became famous.
Girls became famous because
they were showing their
pussies. They get other cars,
like how many,
how many girls ever came famous,
like we're big or got massive publicity
for showing their pussy on TV or showing
their pussy rather a
publicity for these magazines.
How many times that happened and
so 14,000 that would be something.
I think that's more incorrect.
I think 14 maybe 40 14
girls are shown there.
Person Pretend said they've
accidentally show them pushing.
You think it's for a lot of them are
probably researched having not that many.
Probably like fifth.
No.
Probably the point is that's going to be
something they would talk about in the
future when they study ancient history.
I talk about the fall
of the American empire.
What are they going to talk about it?
They're gonna talk about how nutty we,
where the girls would
just show their pussies.
Girls became famous for leaking sex tapes.
Just fucking sucking cock.
I Kim Kardashians. She got famous hanging
out with a girl who should have been,
should have been, you know, there's,
it should have been no reason for Paris
Hilton become famous. Why was she famous?
While she just figured out how to
do it. Don't hate. There she is,
and so Kim Kardashians was hanging
out with her and goes, you know what?
I got to kick this up a notch.
I'm going to do a porno with a black guy,
so she does a poor, know what this dude,
she sucks his deck. Fuck some everything.
It's all real legit porno and then it's
like, oh, how did that get out there?
Dinette and then that becomes a huge hit
show and then she becomes a mainstream
celebrity on the cover
of almost every magazine.
Every God damn time I go
to the magazine stand.
Her face is on the cover of some magazine,
whether it's a fitness magazine
or anything. It's amazing. It's,
that would be something that
people would look at and say,
look how crazy they got.
They just made regular people like,
you don't have to sing, you don't have
to dance, you don't have to write,
you don't have to. Or she has
curriculum. She's got an ass,
she's got an ass and she
has some charisma. I've met
some charisma. I meant me.
It meant to ass. So
yeah. No, I don't know.
Don't you think that if you were looking
at a culture, if people like, I know.
Yeah. If you looked at it
for, for the future, that's
what you would say. You'd say,
look at these crazy assholes.
Maybe some people are just going to have
the charisma and then all of a sudden
they're going to be awesome. Like I
don't think we're on the same track.
Everybody will you guys met?
Maybe Christine,
how about everybody will just be famous
and we'll all like always we just
connected the two things.
I doubt that's what I was just thinking
that everybody has a computer chip in
their brain and then
you walk up this guy go,
oh he's awesome and then everyone
will just shine in a magical land.
Well I think eventually you're,
everyone's should have your phone
number will be like a channel. You know?
You will have like right to
the brain like ah Bro, let me
get your channel number cause I really
want to dance around in your head. Right.
That's real. That'll be right before
the final, the final immersion.
That's what we'd be the last final
immersion. I'm like, God, I don't even,
immersion is no,
no consciousness other than
the one everybody together
to get all linked up like
a matrix right now. That's what's going
to happen. No emotion, no bullshit,
no negativity,
just all we're going to be and then we're
going to find ourselves back all the
way through the universe back in time
to, Oh man, you're freaking me out.
That's ultimate stoner talk.
There's no more ultimate stoner talk.
Then what happens when you die or future
aliens and the future and what's going
to happen, man, when's it kit man,
I'm a fucking fool. All I do all day
is not even think about the moment.
Just worry constantly about what is
going to happen in the future. Man.
I'm getting,
I feel like you guys are
huddle therapeutic just to me.
It's all just fascinating.
It's all hyping Dr Phil,
how is that you got any secrets at the
doctor Phil? I don't know doctor Phil was.
I was like, Damn. That was just, it was
weird as like me getting ready to fight,
like I'm like man, but a fight a man, man,
I'm about to go on a doctor Phil show
like got paid where? Ah, I was just like,
this is so weird. But I was nervous. I
was just like, what the hell am I doing?
This is give you a massage or anything.
Is there any things that he did when
the cameras are off to touch his head,
but you know that's disrespectful,
right? And I mean just to say I did it.
You know what guy, what was he like
as a nice dude? Doctor feels cool
and no yet no, he had a weight
lifter hand grip. Really? Yeah,
I'm a little bit, I was like, hey
man, doctor Phil's kind of buff.
Wow. I swear. I was like, really? Yeah,
he played football in high
school and for sure the college,
maybe you hang it if Dr Phil
called you up. Hey Jason,
I'm down here at the bar
thinking about getting a beer.
Would you like to join me?
I will walk you [inaudible].
I'd like to talk to the doctor.
Phil, what would you do it?
We'll just start talking pussy man.
Let's cut the bullshit.
I should feel just start
talking crazy pussy stories.
But before I was married,
I remember when I was supposed to be on
that doctor Phil show or the doctors and
you talked me out of it. What
was it about for Salvia? Oh yeah,
and they're going to show my video and
everything. I told him don't be going off.
You're going to do,
first of all,
that's going to contribute to the
end of that salvage. Right. I know.
That's what I was, shit, that shit is
so fragile. He legal. It's not legal.
It's still legal in California. I'm
pretty sure. I thought it wasn't.
Some states it's legal
in some states still.
Some states made it illegal and I think
they just made it illegal in Florida.
That's it hurt anybody,
man.
This is why it's weird that they're
making it illegal. Look the all the,
the problem is it's sort of
a guilt by association thing
because if you consider it,
and even though you look at those
statistics and there's no deaths in,
is no immediate danger, you know, health
wise. Like why should it be illegal? Well,
because it's like all this
other shit that's illegal.
Salvia is one of the most potent
psychedelic drugs in the world and it's
available at headshops whereas,
you know, it's really hard target.
What are you talking about?
They sell sadly at target
too. They really plants. Oh,
Salvia plants. Yeah. That's
pretty tripping. Yeah, you're
right. It's sage, right?
I mean that's what Salvia
is. Oh yeah, yeah. Well this,
I don't know if it's the same strain.
I want to know what it is,
is they extract it, you know, and then
condense it down and they extract it.
So you get like Salvia time 60 you know,
so it's like there's little condensed
former con cannot condensed or whatever.
And then you wait. Can you put that in
your coffee? I know it's like an herb.
It's like weed and you have to get
put that in your pipe and smoke it.
You get this light or that you have to
have one of the crack lighters with the
blue torches and it gets it
up to a certain temperature
and it releases a pretty
much, it was like a whippet of mushrooms,
you know, you're just doing, Oh God,
I'm sure Megan. Oh my God, my face is on
fire and melting. Uh, I'm dead. Oh Hey,
I'm back. But the problem is this,
kids were doing this, you know,
and 50 times a day,
many times a day. Right.
Making the most hilarious
youtube videos in the rural.
If you ever want to see some of the
funniest shit, just go on youtube.
Type in Salvia, the kid and the kid.
Yeah. Kids doing all that shit. Yeah,
exactly. Or all right. Or,
or it's a question of it.
I'd never kind of seizures like a seizure.
Seizures.
Decent. That's good. Caesar.
I told the story about, uh,
or told them before what I used to have.
My friend Johnny,
his girlfriend used to fake seizures.
Why did the grocery wanted to it so bad?
She was to fig seizures.
She would fall down and like
fake a seizure and he would,
he would use it as an excuse to slap in
the face. He was like, honey, wake up,
wake up, wake up. And I'd see
like you like bite his lip.
I was hitting it like fucking bitch like
you like really like give her slaps in
the face. That's the most healthy
relationship. I don't remember.
No chaos.
That's the most amazing thing about
knowing a lot of fucked up people.
You know what is everyone's like,
you have a story like that.
It puts it all in perspective too. You
realize there's, there's a man, my girl,
fuck me.
She's not faking features in a fucking
grocery store or you have to slap the
shit out of her in front of everybody.
That's the saddest thing ever. Pretty,
pretty Goddamn damn ridicule. You got
this chick's number or what? She's done.
Damn. She's dead. She deserves
to be. Wow. She's dead.
I don't know if she's dead. He's
dead though. Aw, poor bastard. Yeah.
It was my best friend.
Fascinating dude. Yeah.
Hung out with a lot of crazy bitches.
Yeah. You know, that could get easy to do,
man,
because you know a chicken is beautiful.
She's banana sandwich and you don't care
either because once you start having
sex with them, you're like,
ah, what am I doing right now?
Problem with dues is once
you start having sex with it,
if it's good and they're hot, where
you have sex and do what you just said.
No, no, no, no. Listen, listen to me.
The problem with us,
when you have sex with a girl and
she's hot, you get addicted to it.
You got one and she's super hot and
she's sexy and she's got a killer body.
You're like, you could get that again.
You could always get that again.
So even if she's crazy, you start
going, oh fuck you want all right. Well,
I dunno. Okay, what are you doing?
You want to go out tomorrow?
And then next thing you know,
you're, you're fucking her again.
And next thing you know,
this is your girlfriend is crazy bitches,
your girlfriend. And just because she's
hot and she's got a good, you know,
I know she's afraid and the crazy ones,
a lot of times they're more fun
in bed because they want them.
They want to please you.
They want to,
you know they really want you to be
rocked so they'll freak you out more and
then you're even extra stuck.
Right.
Cause if you get used to that
you get used to with my friend.
Tony always says that erotic and
psychotic or like they're like next door
neighbors.
What are you doing over there Brian?
He was looking for something to
drink so I gave him some check.
Do you want another coconut
drink? Yeah. Thanks dude.
You're like the best intern ever joke.
I like he's wearing a paper
boy cap too man. I know
man. You need like one index.
It like us Joe Rogan call.
That's one of the best ones.
Regular water.
Regular water on their debit bro. That's
all right. You know what? I've just been,
I was drinking out of the
think I like to do it.
Old School like that's
his jerk off sync though.
He got to jerk off.
Yeah.
He puts his dick underneath the
sink and it drops the water on it.
Like a girl doesn't have bathtub. What?
Have you ever heard of girls that do that?
That,
that,
that masturbate by like putting their
pussy right underneath the faucet and they
just slowly taught. That's gotta
be a benefit of being a chick.
Must be way easier to masturbate. Open
wound. Yeah, totally. Do you think so?
I don't know man. I got her this letter
like our Modi stick stuff in there. Yeah,
they're allowed to. Ah, ah.
If a girl gets used to that,
that's the real problem.
She gets used to a vibrator or some
girls get broken, they're pussies.
Just get broken to regular fiber
stimulation over sensitized.
That happens a lot more than than,
than I thought I did actually.
They got to cycle off like, yeah. Yeah.
You stopped like stop doing coffee for
a while and then all of a sudden you're
like, drink a coffee. You're
like, Oh yeah, I'm fricking
pumps. True. Right. Yeah.
Big Difference. You just stop.
You stop. The weirdest thing.
I know what I'm drinking coffee too much
when I can drink it and then get sleepy.
Yeah. That's where you know like you've
got to stop drinking coffee dude.
You know if you drink it so much you can
drink it and all sudden you get sleepy
or I don't know. It's probably not
good for your liver. Like going Ah,
too much coffee or kidneys trying
to shut you down and go dude.
They say a little bit of coffee is
not bad for you, but you can get the,
the problem with like
Starbucks coffee is if,
which is the best only hate
nonstop. I'm not, when I say,
listen Bro, I'm a gold
card name. Okay man. No,
there's a coffee bean thermos in
front of me, but that's not a,
not because I'm disloyal
that product placement,
but the problem is that Starbucks coffee
has a fuck load of caffeine in it. Wait,
not enough.
That's why I drink it.
My new thing is getting iced coffee
unsweetened with three shots and then ivy
three, three, three, three man.
But they say espresso is not
as much caffeine as coffee. No,
but that's on top of a three cups of
coffee though. Yeah, that's three.
Three cups of Espresso. One was
like 300 coffee, right? Yeah.
A shot of espresso. I was like three
cups of coffee. No, no, no, no, no.
It's like a week, a cup of coffee,
like this, three week cups of coffee,
but they're like, oh, I'm sorry. I thought
you were saying that each shot. Oh No,
it's not quite a cup of coffee.
It's a shot is espresso.
It's like slightly below
an average cup of coffee,
but that's how they may call her. No, no.
It's fucking fascinating subject
because you can get, I mean, look,
when you go and get a Venti,
you go and get a Venti Starbucks.
You take somebody who has
never drink coffee before,
someone who doesn't take any stimulants.
It doesn't do it,
and you just give them that venti.
They might have to sit down
like they might be so jacked.
They might be like, wow,
my heartbeat speeding too fast.
But that's the pitch room coffee.
Your hands can be shaken, but
meanwhile you get used to it. Yeah.
You know you'd get drugged up. That's the
legal drug. What are you talking about?
It is don't caffeine.
That's legal and it's the drug.
How many coffees a day do you have,
Jason? I Dunno, like two 14 not.
I know I'm real high tension.
I don't allow myself more than one go
and tell him it's too is if I'm really
busy work.
And that's what I mean.
I'll go like in the morning and then
in the afternoon sometimes Bam height,
I going to Starbucks. I would like
to see you on a muscle relaxer,
but you'd just be like, hello
guys, how are you doing today?
Oh Shit would have no effect.
Shit broke.
Yeah,
that's,
you'd do they to add a juice me up with
a lot of that stuff to put me to sleep
though. Yeah. Yeah. When I got operated,
put a plate in my thumb and they're like,
all right,
we're going to pump you full of stuff.
And he goes in there to, you know, put,
put it in there and I'm like, role. I'd
feel like a giant rush over my whole body.
I'm like, oh my God. And they're
like, okay, just relax. I'm like,
Nah. Ah Man, I'm high right now.
You beat your best to be
operated on and this is the cut.
Yeah. I like man, I'm high
right now. I was like that.
And the guy looks at me like,
and I realized that the stuff is too weak
and I'm like, you can't knock me out.
You can't have a guy. Like the
guy was laughing at it. I kinda,
I remember as I'm all blurry like with
all the drugs like and I'm like man I
look and I remember him like smirking
at me and then going back. Oh Man,
I shouldn't talk shit to him like that.
Wow.
Cause Cause I came out of it like
thinking I was in a fight like ah,
like, like kicking out the nurses and
everything like that. And I was like Oh.
And I was like, oh my bad.
Like I was like, oh sorry.
Then I felt so sick cause he pumped me
so full of that stuff that like I can,
I was like, man, what did I do?
And it's a fucking nurse or
they do you know what they had?
They were gonna use to it. I'm used to
do like in them. Yeah. They were like,
yeah cause they do like all like
extreme athlete. Crazy dudes. Yeah.
And they're like, yeah, we've, we've,
we've seen people like jump up out of
their seats and they were like, hey,
it was a fellow. And I was like, oh
I burst. Sorry. Like I was apologetic
going out like that
operated on already.
He's stitched up together.
Yeah. Weird. Very strange.
How many operations have yet?
I don't know for,
we've yet done so nice.
Like cleaning out stuff and ACL
replacement and like putting out,
putting up addie. Just one ACL replacement
in the gym. Yeah. Both of them.
Both of them done. Yeah.
Like I had and I had uh,
the middle of my knee cutout cause uh,
cause like it was knowing that a lot
of me, it cut it out. What is it,
what do you mean in the middle of their
meniscus? It was sticking out. Oh.
Oh, a bucket handle. Tam Bucket.
Wow. You know, I left. Oh yeah.
We told him that shit up. Right.
It would click stuck. They'll
get stuck. I'm like, Oh God.
And I'm just like yanked that thing
now. That shit is a ferocious pain
to the meniscus. Pain is tough.
That's tough to feign. Yeah.
Very difficult to ignore.
It's not something you just walk off.
No. And I'll get a bone piercing pain.
We Niesr so fucking painful.
Did you know a couple of testicles added
like 17 testicles?
Brian?
Why you look in?
He just checked your package to 17
testicles and taking might have a few more
than the other guys.
He's got extra balls.
Yeah.
It's amazing that they can stitch you
up and put you back together again now
though, isn't it fucking cool? Like how
many guys do you know that if I know,
I know guys, Yvette
discs replaced, you know,
artificial discs stuck in between
and had their disks fused. Yeah.
Tito had that done. Who else have they
done? Nate Marquardt had no nightmare.
Knee quarry had that done. A lot
of guys over. They're done. They,
they blow up their discs and they get
their shit replaced and they can go right
back and fight against fucking crazy.
That used to be a deal breaker. Like your,
your discs were jacked,
like forget about competitive athletics
on the highest level, you know,
there's no way man. And if you're
used to be ACL got jack, like my,
and you were done for everyone.
Like I was like shocked that I
thought a field that like Nah,
you just go and they, we put you back
together. I'm like, oh awesome. And it's,
it's powerful than the original.
My ACL, this man is stronger
than it was like, I was like,
what the hell did the workouts on whatever
and then it's like you use a cadaver.
Yeah. Well you know they use an
achilles tendon. That's what they use.
It's a big fat fucking cable. It's
bigger than what's naturally in there.
What's naturally in their
sucks. Wow. You're shooting
that. I have like illegal me.
I got both. Both of mine are done. Yeah.
This one was done with a
Patella tendon graft out,
which kind of sucks where they did take
a chunk out of your bone in a strip of
meat where you're tending is and it's
attached to your Shin and then they open
you up and then they screw it in place.
It takes a long ass time to heal from it.
It's much,
much longer recuperation time cause he
got a hole in your Shin or a hole in your
knee cap and a hole in your sharing.
Like if they'd cut it out and I saw your,
your tendon's been all fucked up. So
it's, it's a way more invasive thing.
This one I had done,
it was a,
they did a cadaver than my right one and
there's just like two little tiny holes
and they stitched him up and that's it.
It was all fixed. I mean, it's crazy.
They just get in there and screw this
new joint in place. They used to be,
if you lived, you know, a thousand years
ago, man, you are a cripple. You know,
you were fucked.
You were that guy that would fall down
if the wind blew [inaudible] black
president. We have, we're
in the future right now.
It's just think it's so cool that they
get patched you up and put you back
together again, you know? Yeah. We live
in the future. I don't have a jet pack,
but whatever.
Have you ever had your elbows done?
Shoulders is supposed to be
the worst. No. Terry shoulders.
That's supposed to be out of the
biggest pain in the ass to recoup. Yeah.
Dancing with the devil.
That's what I do every day.
And do you ever think that like, man,
like I'm, I'm, I'm fucking staking my,
my living on my physical flesh.
Dancing is fun. Here's the
funnest thing for you, right? I,
I can't, I can't help it. It's so fun.
And I like doing crazy stuff all the time.
Do you think you're going to have a long
career to get to Redo this for a long
time? Yeah. I think I could do
it. I'd do it for a long time,
but you know, that's my job.
You know, I, I feel good.
He definitely better now than you've ever
been before. And what are you, 29 now?
Yeah, it. Oh yeah, change it up.
You bout to hit 29 about
eight 30 30 got damn.
That's like when you're an adult dude and
no. So I've been feeling it. I'm like,
I feel kind of happy about it. Like
I'm like, I'm going to be an adult.
We gotta get you over in the UFC, man.
All the strike force nonsense. If this,
if this Nick Diaz thing doesn't work,
man, I hope that you have, see picture up.
I'm gonna have to go get
Joe Silva massage somewhere.
Maybe you have to get them a fucking
gift certificate for somewhere cool.
Some wonderful restaurant and
have a nice meal. I take her nuts.
She take them to the olive garden.
Say,
what are we doing with the Strikeforce
nonsense, you know, mayhem. Miller.
I got a good thing going straight for.
So yeah, you probably over, let's see.
Let's see if the has, will, you know,
not be scared to hold me in. Right.
Well, you know, go from there. When watch
the Anderson Silva Chell son and fight.
Now I know you've, you train with chill,
right? I fought chill like you find them?
Yeah,
but I trained with them too in a
thought of me like 19 like man,
I was like 18 years old, man. Yeah.
We going to buy like me. No, 19 yeah.
He just kept taking me down. We
crashed through the cage. Wow.
There's video of it somewhere where a
man, I was so young, man. I was like,
we were like kids man. Wow.
How old is he? I don't know.
Is it as thirties right? Yeah, he's a
little, he's a little older than me.
When you watch this fight with Anderson
Silva, Anderson Silva pound for pound,
best fighter in the world, you know, UFC
long running middle weight champion. What,
what did you think when you saw that
fight? The Chelsea on the fight?
Were you thinking, I
mean, you know, you're,
you're a guy competing for the Strikeforce
title at one 85 you see Anderson,
you know, and you see that, you know,
the shale is, is, is handling them well.
What did you think that
like does that like, yeah,
definitely. I mean, but you know,
like of course my weight,
I'm done.
That was the most intense I've ever
watched the fight. Really like yeah,
that's what I was thinking. It
must be, right? Yeah, of course.
Cause I'm like in the little
soap opera, I kinda, you know,
watching this like the,
we're all, you know,
the same way you can be fighting that
guy either soon. Yeah. Easy. Yeah.
Both guys. Really. Exactly. So
anything can happen. Of course.
How long is your contract at Strikeforce?
I believe I don't have a fight left.
One fight left? Yeah, I think
so. And I'm so that if you, uh,
if you beat Nick Diaz then do
you get to fight for the title?
I have, yeah. I a couple of
bites of things and I have um,
two fights. Yeah, I think
so. Yeah. So what are they
talking about now? If is nick,
if Nicnas doesn't want to fight,
do you get to fight Jack Ryan?
Do you have to fight Tim Kennedy?
Like what do you do? What's next? Uh,
I don't know. They don't know, they're
just trying to get the Nick Diaz fight.
Well, I mean that's the fight
that everyone wants to see
him. That's cool. And I,
you know, I'm down, you know,
it's like, that's my job.
I'm down to do whatever it does it
get in the way. When you're filming,
bully beat down, you know, does
it get any way with your training?
Like do you have to like train, um, like
when you, when you were filming that show,
do you have to like make sure that you
don't have any fight scheduled for a
while? It's going down. Yeah, of course.
I didn't want to run it concurrent
with the right training camp.
It would fuck it up hard.
Right? Yeah. What kind of
hours? I took fight, I took, uh,
uh, you know, for, for training that
bullied be now only takes two weeks.
So what does that monkey on?
What'd you do? Right. Oh Wow.
Did you just cut and paste that but a
pretty cool, yeah, it is pretty cool. Um,
I dunno, you know, I only takes
two weeks to do the bully be down.
So for the whole season.
Whoa.
That's like more than two weeks cause
I have to go to do voiceover or do you
guys do 10 at a time?
Usually. Wow. So it's,
it's a fun like a, it's like a
fun little summer camp. Like Yay,
let's go fill, bully be down.
It's going to be hilarious.
Well it must have been way more fun coming
into this season now that it's a big
success.
Yeah.
Like now everything like everybody like
wants you there and happy to see a and
all excited and so pumped up.
What do you mean people that network?
People in the studio like you're on a
successful show. That's when it starts.
That's what it's fucking bad ass, right
when it's successful. Exactly. Yeah.
You know things are rolling when things
are that third season of it. You know,
I never seen an audience
so pumped up fans.
They're fans or fans first they was
like just people who were like, what?
What is this?
When we used to film news radio,
there's a big difference between
the first season and news radio,
like the audience and the
third season when it gets,
when it gets into where the
fans come to watch the show,
that's when it becomes fun. Yeah, it's,
it is crazy experience filming shows is
so hard in the beginning because no one
knows what the fuck is going on.
You're trying to establish a rhythm and
it's like, you know, you're awesome,
but nobody else,
I wasn't gonna say that.
What I was saying is it
just takes a long time.
Everybody who works on that show
was like awesome people and,
and you know what I mean?
It's like they're all Colby.
I got more into doing the bully beatdown
job by the fact that the people who
work on it are just so awesome people.
You're just such awesome, awesome people.
So I'm like,
oh,
like I really want to do a good job
because these people right here are cool.
So let me try to do a really good job
because you don't see that working,
but they're working really hard now.
Did when all the shit went down with the
CBS thing where you got in trouble and
the,
the big fight and the brawl on television,
did they give you a hard time over that?
What do you mean?
What are they going to give me
a hard time about it for him?
Nobody gives you a hard time bully beat
down people. No one says like, you know,
hey, you know, we can't get involved and
I don't even think they were worried.
What do you mean they weren't,
you know, you know what I'm
saying? Like, no, no, no,
no. What I'm saying is like when, when
when a controversy happens like this,
like they don't want you
involved in anything that's
negative or anything that's
like, you know, like they don't have,
they don't sit down with you and say, hey,
you can't be getting into brawls cause you
know, you, you represented the show. No,
no. I think that they, I think
they understood my thigh. Like,
you know what I mean?
Like they understood the whole
how the whole thing went down.
But I mean in the news it wasn't, it
wasn't pretty, it wasn't clear cut.
There's a lot of people that are blaming
you. Yeah, well they're just jerks.
They didn't get that mad about it,
about it. That bully beat downs.
That's like my fighting career. They don't
worry about my fighting career. I have,
I don't feel like they the what do you
think that MTV is going to Spank me for
that? No, no, no, no, no ma'am.
I was wondering whether or
not anyone was concerned.
Was there anyone said anything to,
you know what? Nobody talks to me.
I'm just ma'am.
So funny you say it like,
like it's ridiculous to ask.
Got You got an a bench clearing
brawl on national television.
But he's a fighter though. I know that
shit happens. That's, it happened again.
But [inaudible]
I know they have the Jersey shore on.
I know they don't fuck around now.
People are just roofie
bad, you know? I mean,
when I saw that girl get punched in the
face, did you see that online? Oh yeah.
I thought like, I don't think they showed
it on the show. They blacked it out.
Yeah, I think they, yeah, they, they
blurted are similar. They blur it.
They didn't want people to see it grow.
Get punched in the face and then say,
because they could show, look, we
have a giant reading spike. Right?
Does this girl gets punched in the face?
This is what we need.
We need more girls getting
punched in the face.
Did you see the girl that's on dancing
with the stars that Sarah Palin's
daughter, whatever Esther Perel
is talking to the situation. Yeah.
It was pretty fun.
That was the most,
one of the most ridiculous on dancing
with show because I get the fee,
the normal like everyday funny
stuff and I would never see,
I never watched a show like that man.
The soup had it on there and it was
man, bring it up. Just bring it up.
How strong,
how strange is it that dancing with
the star has potential campaign vice
presidential camp campaigners
daughter who's like seven wishy,
like 18 or something like you know,
something like that now 19 now.
Something really young.
Like, how has that,
how she's a celebrity and she's talking
because she was pregnant cause he was,
cause it was a story that she was in
the news. I mean that's ridiculous.
Like how is that a celebrity?
That's so weird.
You know that that like
debts dancing with the stars.
Like that's what they're calling a star.
They're calling this young girl whose
mom was running for vice president,
which is happening at pregnant. Everybody
knew about it. They're calling our star.
But that's so odd. You'd
have that a dancing with the
stars. You know, here's high.
She's a star and it's situation.
Check this out very.
You look at me like he was some Zen Koan.
Like what is the sound of
one hand clapping? Exactly.
No she is, but it's like the
line is getting blurry now.
It's like anybody who is in the news,
it's not,
you know when you dancing with the
stars is no longer entertainers.
It's no longer,
yeah,
that's anybody that anything happened
to where they got famous there stars.
It's like idols in Japan. They already
have that and then you become like a show.
They'll check in on,
they'll check in on you to see
what the fuck's going on with you.
And what are you doing today? Crazy.
Like the Carrie Prejean chick.
Remember the chicken ran for a,
was it Miss USA that a gay people?
She's always get something,
man. It's always something
in the mix where you're
talking about the girl want to
check up on her. The uh, Miss
South Carolina pageant, right?
The such as like, uh, no, no,
not, that girl was hilarious,
but that was just a brain fart.
That poor chick,
she just got caught in the headlights.
Whatever was adorable. It was adorable.
Yeah. You liked it. I liked my
girls to be all scatterbrains
girls like gingerly,
like Bambi, like that.
Does that get you excited to like look
at this girl just dragged her into the
mayhem void?
No Man.
Where you think I clubbed chicks over the
head and drag on your personality, Bro.
Just with your personality. You could
just overtake them, do you think so? Hey,
let's run over here and I'm just, see
a girl was saying like as, and um,
you could just dominate your mind.
She's not retarded.
She's just easily led.
So mentally handicapped.
Maude supermodels is what I'm looking for.
Maybe sometimes it's not the worst thing.
That's all I'm saying. Totally mentally.
Like cap it, like really happy
just hanging out with their dog.
Think about it that way.
There's a lot of people that are super
smart and super healthy and they're just
hanging out with her dog and
there's nothing wrong with that.
But a lot of people get plenty of
companionship just from their dog.
So if that's the case and they're
super happy for the rest of the life,
you could date someone who's really dumb.
She's really allows, are nice to you.
Who Cares? It cute. Somebody
just like having a dog.
Somebody like this.
What are you doing, Brian? That's a video
that we were talking about. Excuse me.
Have you ever had a situation
with the, uh, official situation,
excuse me. Oh, snap. Be Pailin.
You mean to tell me that girls actually
fall for that line? Come on. I mean,
if those words don't work,
I got the situation right there.
I hope you're as committed to
same sex as you are those abs.
I know you're all about that abstinence
thing, you know, but come on,
be Pailin.
Are you serious?
Like you're not going to hook up with
like before you mag for real. For Real.
For Real. For Real. For Real.
For Real, for real. All right.
Well you know what I mean?
Just in case you do get into a situation,
I want to make sure that you are situated
because if you do get into a situation
with your situation,
you may end up with a situation and
you may not like that situation.
Trust me though, I'm not getting
myself into another situation.
I know how hard it is to be a teen parent.
You know what?
I totally respect that and I
totally respect abstinence.
I mean it actually has the word
[inaudible] on the situation. I love that.
Very funny. But I'm worried about
you and you practicing safe sex.
I actually practice a whole lot. I mean
a whole lot about the safe part of that.
Ah, the safe part. We got the
safe part down pat. What pile?
Magnums? You know what, I might
be able to spare one. I mean,
you know, I'll give you one. It's fine. I
avoid situations. All right, good. Good.
If you're good in voiding situations
and you're situated and I'm situated,
situation's under control. Well,
I'm glad that we agree on one thing.
Pause before you play.
Pause before you play it right
by them. You know what? This, what
is it? So fucking high school video.
Who made this? What was this
on? Hold on. What was this on
the, uh, the candies foundation. Huh?
What was it on? Television
was a commercial bill. Was it?
I Dunno. Was a PSA bro from, yeah.
It's a PSA of some sort.
Dude.
That shit was designed by the terrorists
that's designed to lower our standards
and weaken our wills and they're going
gonna fucking cross our borders and just
start raping and I totally
mother fucker. That was dumb. Yeah.
Holy Shit. That was scary. Dumb.
It was the situation.
Need situation, situation,
situation. Whoa. Whoever wrote that.
But let's try not to get your tie
a bicycle chain around your neck.
They're trying to get up in the ocean.
You're trying to give the kids a bicycle
chain so that means they could like
pedal out of it baby slowly drown.
What?
I want him to slowly drop just farm.
So I'm dropping in the middle of
the ocean. I just want, you know,
you got to get that chain off for.
Yeah.
What I'm saying is fuck you bitch.
Goddammit.
Jesus stopped knocking the microphone,
man. He's sort of a bitch. Fuck,
aren't you hearing that? No, I don't even
hear it. Does it hurt your ears? Yeah,
dude, it hurts everybody who's listening
to that shit allowed us far. Okay.
Here's the situation.
The situation,
his parents out towns don't want people
to like, you know, Bang each other.
But what is that about? She's pretending
she doesn't take Dick Anymore.
How dare you? How dare you?
You know he's taking my keys.
Doesn't have like sex without a condom.
Yeah,
he's pulling out condoms.
It's had sex in a tanning bed.
He's probably not wearing a
condom. You don't think so? No.
Did you have sex on a tanning bed
on the show? We probably. Well,
that's gotta be bad for your eyes.
Have you ever masturbated tanning bed?
I sometimes masturbate about the chick
that checks me in at the tanning bed
because she's so fucking hot and she has
huge tits and she's, Oh wait, nevermind.
Problem. They have a problem with
women doing that and tanning beds.
I've heard that the women liked
to masturbate. Tanning beds.
One of masturbate in a
hot room, right? Well
maybe an Eskimo.
They're worse as if you spray though and
then it's like early on in the tanning
it starts to like sizzle.
Curse your cooking. Geez,
off what's on your stomach?
It sounds like it's a little
seven up kiss by your ear.
Low point of this
podcast. TJ's all. What's
omelets get your toaster.
I go too far.
Your how many times do you walked out
of the House with dry loads on your
stomach? Man, never. Never.
Whatever's throwing a shirt.
Balance at fucking affairs.
My belly, like I missed the
spot or something like that.
It does feel a little crunchiness.
Jim Norton had a load in his belly button
from the night before and we were on
Opie and Anthony and he was telling
everybody, he's like, oh, I'm smelling it.
Hold on a second. And he dips his
finger in it and he gave it to, uh,
one of the interns.
I forget who it was,
and he made smell it and he almost threw
up. And then he goes, you want to try it?
I go, all right. What? So he
sticks. He sticks the smell. I mean,
basically I smelled it so that,
that dead. Why would horrible smell?
Because I was there. It was on
the radio. Fucking I'll smell it.
I smell some of the load.
Some of his belly load came into
my nose and the form of fumes,
basically. I would say no
to that, wouldn't you say?
Yeah. I should've said no.
Wow. Other radio. I'm just trying
to think of Joe. Sure, I'll do it.
But it's the listening to the
radio when you're on the radio,
just like on this podcast. Everybody's at
Penn. You just trying to have fun, right?
Try to do,
what's the funniest thing?
The funniest thing is that guy says you
want to smell my stinky low? Do you go,
okay, fuck it. Come on. We're on the
radio. You know, awesome. All your load.
If you really want me to get the hell.
And he was kind of shocked as
I was that I was smelling it.
Can I go to the bathroom?
Yeah, go ahead man.
That's right on a jerk offs and put one
load in my belly button. Don't do it.
Don't do it.
There's something about the shape of the
belly button that makes the loads from
Matt and fester and again,
are you really moving?
Know he doesn't really
have to go to the bathroom.
You don't have to go to the bathroom.
Thanks dude. Brian didn't see it.
He didn't see them.
The joke man. Good job.
You didn't even get my jokes
was an awesome job Brian,
and you just totally messed. I was
doing something. I can remember what
we've got it down to a science,
how much pot you should smoke
before one of these things.
But sometimes I was finding another video
for you and when you guys were talking,
the stars don't align. Align.
What was another video?
Another PSA with a situation next.
I don't know if I can fucking take it.
I felt like you wasted moments in my life.
At the same time.
I think it's a step in the right direction
that abstinence people have gone.
Well people aren't gonna stop
fucking so try to wear a condom out.
What they're doing. Yeah, because
before people would like to,
abstinence people are over religious.
It's all religious people. No one of us.
My brain. It's talking about abstinence.
That's just against human nature.
You can't stop.
If that's true.
Why would they even think for
a second to this situation?
Would rep best represent that place?
I think because they think of him.
He's the guy who bangs a lot, you know?
I mean whatever they're trying to paint.
I think they just think he's famous.
I think it's that simple.
I think it's as simple as he's famous.
He's in the news.
They can get him to do it. People
pay attention. Yeah, that's true.
But that shit is so bad. That
whole, the situation, you know,
if you get in this situation and
her talking to me was so dumb Joey.
Okay.
This Joey Diaz.
How dare he,
I'm not answering shit.
So joy anyway,
it's just picking up the phone bro.
I need to remember to unplug this phone.
Most people don't call me
when we're doing a podcast,
but occasionally someone gets confused.
Robot, I know anyone of those, right?
Yes. Just need to unplug it. Problem
is the base is not in this room.
I'm a disorganized motherfucker.
Brian, I wish I had an e walk. I've um,
I've made great strides
though and creating this room.
We actually have like a place
where we do the podcast every week.
It feels like this is where it all
comes from. It feels like it's right.
It's a desk.
It's like we got a soundboard.
It's all professional equipment and shit.
You know,
a friend of mine just started watching
the podcast and he started with episode
one and he's like, Holy Shit Dude.
Like this is the craziest thing ever.
Like you guys are just sitting in front
of a laptop and yet snowflakes coming.
They did all kinds of stupid, it's like
Christmas Eve or something like that.
Or was it something like
that? Yeah, the snowflakes.
We don't even, we lost that
technology. It's hard enough to keep
the image on the air, you
know, with um, these, uh,
these Ustream feeds like a lot of times
it cuts out and a lot of times, you know,
our, our Internet will shut off and it
cuts out. It's a pain in the ass man.
You know,
you just want to make sure that you're
just like most important thing is the
audio.
Where do you get a tube that
goes right to the Internet?
I'm not even sure what the Internet
is neither. Do you know what it is?
Like if someone said, hey, you got to
go fix the Internet is broke. I know.
Like where would you walk
to with your tool belt?
Like you're like the end of this hallway.
I mean,
it would be broke forever if it
was just left. Yeah, we're stupid.
No, you'd be like, where the fuck
is it? And how do you fix it?
You would have to relearn the whole
thing. I figured, Ooh, what's that?
What about your on what's going to be
very strange when everything's wireless
switches and then it's going to be
inevitable, but it's not as, you know,
not when there's no difference between
being plugged in and not being plugged in,
which is probably inevitable. What are you
talking about? It's like that now. Yeah,
but it's not totally like
that now. There's a lot of
places that don't have wifi.
There's a lot of people that have
their computers, computers plugged in,
but there'd be eventually with, that's
not even an option. Like you don't even,
why would you get a plug? But he's stupid.
You just turn it on, its picks it up.
It's everywhere, you know?
That's, that's the next step.
So it's fucking fascinating shit now
fascinating shit where all these computers
and
it sucks when Shit starts
going wrong though.
Like my shit's just all together going
wrong at the same time and I feel like
I'm just in a disaster right now.
My technology,
my computer,
you've got to everything a bunch of,
and one of them that you shouldn't talk
about too much because of the nature of
the problem. Oh you know that
one with the software issue?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. No, no.
Like, you know what I'm saying? Right.
You need a flashlight. Not like
all my, I thought wait, whoa.
Re talking about an eyeball,
but I'll know all my shit's like breaking
at the same time. Like all my, like my,
my dog decided to eat my laptop cable
and my battery decided to dye my hard
drives dying. And then I'm like my
TV, my uh, htmi cable shorted out my,
my washing machine broke the other day.
It's like everything is
Bracey became the apocalypse
technology 2012 I just thought you have
like super powers or something and like
to magnetize the broken cables.
I thought, what are you doing?
I'm putting it inside out. That
looks fucking discussed. Your,
this is the flashlight that our guests
have to touch using it. And man,
it's really dirty when you
take it out clean to clean.
Like it looks really discussed.
Those at the butthole ones. Oh,
this is I the one that you actually used,
remember? Yeah. Oh No, it's not man.
That looks like a real life
butthole. I have to say, man,
the mount hole or two or three times a
week and actual mold. That's a real life.
Someone says, well, you know,
if you weren't in to doing gay porn,
but they offered you 1 million bucks
for a foam mold of your butthole.
They said, listen, we're going to give
you a stone cold, solid $1 million.
All we need,
we're just going to throw some plaster
of Paris over your Bot hold and make a
little impression of me. Yeah, and
sell something rough about hall.
Would you do it?
I'll do it for like
$16
$18 that's random,
Brian,
for publicly for a mold of your bottle.
This would be like an argument that
I'd have to have with my, yeah.
Oh, you mean like don't do it.
I don't think you should do.
It's $1 million. You wouldn't do it.
Yeah. Yeah. You gotta sell your butthole.
Are you going to do it while I'm
putting it out there? Right now,
I'm putting it out there to
all the would be for by, no,
I don't think your athlete over Brian.
I think you're right,
but that's my price. 1 million.
I won't do the training.
You're pricing yourself out.
If some crazy old gay freak with a
lot of cats steps up, talk you down.
Let's talk. You know what do you mean
mass produced? How much for mass produce?
It has to be $1 million. It's
okay. It's very simple. You can't,
you wouldn't go to get a rubber mold
of my butt hole and it will cost you $1
million. I think I'm quite clear. I would
do it for 10,000 Chris to negotiate.
Either way, I'm happy. I'm happy.
If it's yes, I'm happy if it's no,
I don't care if you have
your price and Joe Rogan. No,
I keep some self esteem points. I feel
good about myself. If it's yes, holy shit.
I just made 1 million bucks to lie down
with some plaster Paris over my butthole.
All right, let's take it the other way.
Then, okay, let's do this. All right.
At what point do you throw yourself
so bad? You know what I mean?
That you can't recover.
All right.
How much money would it take
you to like suck a horse?
You know you could go back.
Yeah, you can go too far.
You could certainly go too far, but
could you? Okay. How long has it taken?
A second source is Dick. What if you
only had a struggle? Horses, Dick,
until he came.
What if? What if horses come really
quick? You know? I don't know,
but they're super sensitive when you're
talking to, I'm taking a full load.
A load of the yard swallow
it because you can't. Okay.
Pre comes probably at 12 gallon. Someone
might be able to get fucked by a horse,
but I don't see anybody swollen.
A horse lover. All right.
You will fucking drown and that's not,
that's the worst way to call
the paramedics when you're
drowning by horse load
and that shit would happen,
man.
Maybe that old man show guy that
would chug the beers. Magic.
I'm just trying to keep, keep up with
those says, well it's like, oh, of course.
Of course you wouldn't want to do that.
Of course there'll be a terrible
thing to do. But what if it was,
and this is the ultimate hack premise,
but what if it was for $100 million or
something crazy like that? Or a billion.
I know, Dude, this is a horse horses Dick
for an hour, for a billion hours. My bad.
I should have never said that man.
We don't have to actually suck it for
a whole hour because it probably won't
take that long.
But you're committed.
You're committed to us it for one
hour a horse or can be a pony.
I was thinking,
I was thinking like that's how
juvenile I am Ghana. Um, so juvenile,
that was the funniest thing
I've ever heard in my life.
You just pause for a second picture.
You blowing a pony.
That's all I can think of.
The polling was Brown and white too.
It was really cute. Wow, great. Sort
of like I had red ribbons in hair.
I was like,
why does it have red ribbon?
But isn't about little kids that love
ponies and horses and shit like that.
What is it, man? No idea.
Habits. Having little kids,
man. My daughter loves horses.
She loves horses and ponies.
Like all little girls,
some nice animal that you can
ride. It's like, that's like,
but she doesn't know you can ride
it. What? She doesn't know she's too,
she doesn't know you could ride a
fucking horse. That's ridiculous.
There seen somebody at a fair,
she's seen Barbie. Barbie, right?
Maybe she seen it on movies and movies.
Animated movies for no reason.
But what it is it about girls and horses?
What do you think? It's something
sexual. Absolutely. They,
I've talked to a few people before and
they all say it feels fucking great.
Yeah, it's, it's constantly
rubbing their pussy.
I look at where their sexual organs are.
It's like they're constantly titty.
Fucking that horse.
Why do you think like I live in
equestrian district and why did,
and then like every
time I go to Starbucks,
there's at least four of them in there.
They are always plain Jane girls
because they can't get any dick.
So they fucking ride horses.
They're never hot.
Supermodels are never fucking fat chicks.
Plain Jane Girls.
I will make you stop riding horses.
I agree.
And I don't believe he believed that all
of the women that rubbing horses around
me,
all the women in my neighborhood who ride
horses look like they're getting away
with something. They're like, there's
a dog looking at fairs like smirking
while they're nothing in their gene
brown muscle underneath, I'm just, and
it's moving clip clop clop clop clip
watching iPhone porn as a riding the,
the,
the standard excuse for why
a woman lost her hymen. Her,
her number one, the number one excuse was,
oh, she lost it. Horseback riding. Right.
Did you know that? Because you
know, it was always, hey, you know,
they checked to make sure our
virgin, what's going on? Hooker.
You've been getting Dick stuffed in
there? No, I ride horses like, Oh, okay.
That's cool. Wow. So it
was legit to buster. Yeah.
Legit to bust your hymen and bust a nut.
I bet they do.
I'd been used to carve out their
saddles and make a little hole.
So when they write really
did they? Yeah, just stick
your Dick in there. He just
made that up. He fucked this.
What I would do.
Is that what you mean?
Damn fuck yeah. I wouldn't
think of something like
that. Make a fleshlight some.
How do I attach to my sad,
sad thing that you're supposed
to hold on a long road trip?
You jerk off the whole time.
I've jerked off once in a car that I
can remember. I think I did it again.
I definitely did it once though and then
while I was working and I remember very
clearly after I came thinking I'm
definitely going to do this again.
I'm such an idiot.
Like being disappointed with myself,
like go and I know I'll be doing it
like it's not like I just jerked off all
over myself while I'm driving once like
this is going to be a regular occurrence.
So I'm thinking this is eventually
going to become embarrassing for me.
But then what happened? Man, I just never
did it again. I don't know what happened.
I never will. I guess maybe I just
rationalized, I look, looked it like,
am I really that horny or
am I just looking to be
distracted while I'm driving?
Like what am I doing? You know,
this is stupid. This is life.
Fourth time management.
Let this hard to look at your
gps and imagine it to girl. No,
didn't you have a chick that got jealous?
Because my gps voice, listen to this.
He had a fucking gps than where it was
an English woman's voice and his girl got
jealous and she kept on
making me change it to guys.
And then like I would download
like the British chick,
it was a Tom Tom and a download like
the British chick and she'd be like,
what the fuck is this chick? Just turn
it to the regular guy. This is what,
what do you think that she's hot.
What is it
dad?
Really?
Yeah.
And so what kind of a
hell where you live in?
Was it a fiery lava?
GPS came out hot sticker up the
ass. Hell, tell me about that thing.
It was just when gps came out and for some
reason it had annoyed her. She's like,
didn't like that it was a girl talking,
but she was just like,
you think she sounds hot?
She asked why.
I just didn't have like
a normal guy voice.
She thought it was odd that
I always made it like a sexy,
you know like Asian girls speaking
English voice or whatever.
Whoever they have that I have, they
have like British woman, you Kay,
you know Asian American, Asian,
Asian. Did you ever do it? Yeah.
Did you ever get to the point where
you were hearing that we were going,
I have to get out of this relationship?
No. It came out to the point where they
had it where you could make your own
recordings of it and
thank you man. No, I did I,
why would I want to hear myself talk
to me? No, but I want to hear the shit.
I'm like, thanks lady. Or I want to be
like, yeah, thanks baby. Like you know
I did it. So it's like turn
the fuck up here. You know,
I just cussed and stuff and
she was happy with that. Yeah.
What was she do broke up after? I think
around it. I would have broke over that.
Oh my God, would it, I would have kicked
her out of the car. It was still moving.
Have you ever kicked the girl in the car?
Yeah.
No. He told me what he said. Yeah.
Yeah. But what you're really
saying was of course stupid. Yeah.
And I was saying of course too, but that
was my next thing. Of course. Of course.
How many, how many? I've only
kicked out one girl on my car ever.
I think it was like high school
time though. Like I was like, dude,
get out of my car.
Like it was like little kids that have
one crazy bitch I did when I was 21 just
off the top. Just love to fight.
Just loved to, for whatever reason,
just start picking fights.
When you date people,
you figure out like some people are out
of their minds. Oh, this one was nuts.
She used to like to fight and then
she used to like me to go, hey,
what the fuck is wrong with you? Like
stop picking on me. Stop yelling at me.
Just fucking chill out. You're
acting like an asshole, right?
I'm not doing anything to you.
And then she would go super submissive,
was really crazy and then want
to fuck that was like hers.
There's constant strategy.
So after a while it was like
she wanted to be handled.
So she wanted a rise up.
She wanted to say shitty things
and intuitive would build.
She would start with like a little insult
and then it would go on and I would
ignore it. I would try to just
like, please, let's not fight.
And then we get to the point where she
would say something really stupid and I
have to go, hey, what the fuck are you
doing? Are We, do we like each other?
Why are you talking to me like this?
Like, what's going on here? This is dumb,
dumb shit like you, you're, you're
not, you're not honoring my feelings.
And then she would go, I'm
sorry. You're right. I'm sorry.
Fuck coming out all I'm a loser or you
don't know what's wrong and then it would
just, you would want to crash
and she'd want me to fuck her.
I take the same route. Girls,
it's a sort of like a, you know,
it's like a distraction. Sexual reward
or you want to fight? Well it's just,
they also have that pattern.
It's usually they, the,
every relationship they've had is that,
that pattern.
They have drama with their friends.
They usually have drama at home.
It's like some people become addicted
to drama and the big thrill you get from
sort of overcoming drama.
You know how many dudes you know that
just like you have to fucking get in a
yelling match with this asshole before
you can be friends with them. You have,
I mean, how many guys have you ever
met? I mean our circles and circles of,
of the guys who train in MMA guys
and high testosterone individuals.
There was always this one guy, we
have to go, Bro, what the fuck?
And then he's okay. He turned to
say that about me right now. No,
I'm just kidding.
I'm just kidding though.
What the fuck that sounds
like something else
did I do. It's the shit, isn't it?
I got to fucking complaint
from a young man on Twitter.
What saying that the coconut juice,
I was steering him wrong.
That coconut juice tastes like shit. Yeah,
well he's got to get the right stuff.
You got to get the right
stuff and you know,
I bet there's some people that they're
like, man, I like mountain dew. Gold.
Joe Rogan made me smoke, you know, drink
coconut juice, mountain dew, Goldman.
I don't have a problem out and Duke.
No.
You know what I'm saying there that
they're just like whatever they do,
they drink mountain dew every day and
that's it. You know think guys like that,
like the people that same people that
make fun of me for enjoying grape vodka.
What do you like flavored vodka?
You need to drink Budweiser.
I'm sorry for dropping theF bomb again.
You can say whatever
you want. Oh, I'm allowed to do
that. Yeah. I don't care. I retired.
Not because I saw that.
I know I stopped doing it too.
Yeah,
you be.
Only because Glenn and I want to say it
sometimes cause I'm used to it cause to
me it means something way different.
Yeah. I saw that show Louie's uh,
Louie and I saw the guy and I was
like, ah. I was like, oh I get it now.
I see why the gay people,
I hate that word because not correct,
but it's Ph now based stuff to them. It's
like real hateful heart. And I'm like,
oh to me it's like what we say
when we were little kids like,
like you're just like whatever. Fuck. Like
you don't mean it at anything. Get like,
I've been saying it for so long, I
say, well that was a great scene.
But what,
what I was saying is not correct as a new
saint at the origin of the word faggot
meant that it was, you would throw them
on the fire just like faggots of wood.
Oh that's not,
no,
that's not the correct with the call
entomology entomology now the correct one
is that a faggot,
like a bundle of wood was a burden
and it was difficult to carry.
So a woman became a faggot.
So women were faggots of wood
that was difficult to carry.
They became burdensome. And then when
they would talk about guys who were gay,
they would call them faggots too,
because they were women.
They were just looking at him. He's
a faggot. He's a burden. Some woman.
Yeah, that's what the correct
calling Jason's Mama Fag.
It was actually proper
terminology. Yeah. I don't know.
His mom was a burdensome woman.
She might've been a joy to be
around and a wonderful companion,
like a bundle of wood. I don't know.
So that's, but either way. Yeah,
it's a problem is that it has a
different definition for gay people.
That's fine.
That's the only reason that I'm,
I don't want to say because all my bags,
when did you,
how long ago did you retire? I Dunno,
a while ago. That's really, uh,
I saw that.
And then not because they did,
it took a while I thought and I
thought about it and I'm like, yeah,
that is like hate, like hateful
word, like such a to them.
And to me it's not that way.
And I understand why people say it.
Because when you want to like just
inspect the dude as much as you can.
Didn't you just say that?
But you're not thinking you're gay.
Like it just has a nice ring to it.
It just sounds like mean.
That's why people, you know,
it sounds very dismissive.
Ever said it to a gay dude ever.
I don't think. I never ever,
let me see can that great joke about it.
Unless he was being a faggot
and he said something about did you all
the people from Phoenix or Phoenicians
shut up you faggot. Hey,
how about the sand anymore?
I'm just quoting Louie CK. Oh,
you're just gonna start quoting.
People just want to do, and it keeps
saying Faggot by bringing up that,
I'm not saying it
until the end of time,
so it's another what?
You're not gonna I'm not
going to ignore topics.
We're not going to protect our
real ladies and gentlemen. Okay.
All I'm saying is I'm not going
to use it as a slander, as a slur.
It's not a slanders. You're going to
be mad at somebody. You can be like,
if I didn't retire,
were faggot right
now with the proper time to use
one.
If I can still save faggotry cause
that's not even the same word.
That's like saying niggardly. You know
that's the judge is a tricky word.
That's a step mean.
Stingy. There's no origins.
It's not at all. Not at
all. I know. It's so weird.
It's closing occur. I said
it. I don't give a fuck.
I'm not calling anybody in it. That
means we're just missing. It's real.
So you're more, you're
more scared of gay? No,
I'm not saying I'm not calling anyone it.
I'm just saying that it's a word.
Sometimes when you're
talking about the n word,
it's more offensive to me to
say the n word. Oh Gee. Oh here.
What should we go sit your,
we're going again with you
fucking terrible person.
Did you call someone that's
mom faggot. Oh, I did not.
You called my mom a faggot, bro.
And I know Jason Forgot about it.
Or your mom he bought,
he called his mom.
His mom's gay and he calls his Mama
Faggot. Oh really? Oh Brian did.
He just didn't give a fuck. Look at
him. He's reckless or whatever. Brian,
Brian's doing standard. Does she have
like a short haircut or something?
Now she's going to say less
real live lesbian.
He's running around calling her a
faggot. Why? Cause that's Brian.
That's how he rolls. He doesn't give any
other reason. I called your Mama Faggot.
Yeah. Why you call it felt
is tight like an asshole.
Why she was tight like
an asshole. Brian. Ma'Am.
This is the worst show stopper.
And you've ever thrown out.
Why would you say that to May Hams? Mom.
Dude, my mom downloaded the podcast.
Does your mom downloaded
podcasts? Oh Bro. Brian,
what did you just do? You're going
to have to go back and edit this.
This is going to be the lot.
A lot. Somebody tweeted me.
The time here wakes up and
like four hours bro. Oh,
how dare you man does
not cool. Not, oh. Oh.
What error and she's very sensitive
about. I'm sure that's a good thing. I've,
she was sitting around and at least you
didn't say, he didn't say I was sloppy.
You know,
they're seen probably is happy,
but you're insinuating he fucked his
mom. I did not. You didn't fuck my mom.
She said you guys talked on Twitter.
Huh?
My Mom said you guys talked about too
was how crazy is that Lebron James Story
for one of his, one of his teammates
was fucking his mom. Yeah. That's crazy.
Do you know that story?
Wow.
One of Lebron's teammates
was flopping his mom.
That's gotta be rough weight and what
team? The Miami Heat. Yeah, whatever.
No, the other one. Oh yeah. Yeah.
A lot to do up there in Cleveland.
So they just fuck people's moms.
This to be a lot of things ahead of,
fuck this guy's mom, I'm
from Columbus. That's true.
We just fuck each other's moms.
How would that be you when it gets
to be like my member December, like
that's where I met her
fucking married.
Where? That's where I met her
in this call. This is horrible.
So crammed. My Mom's going to be pissed
off. This black gay man misses mayhem.
I'm sorry. Yeah. For my friend Brian,
most of what he says is
just for comedic value.
He doesn't really mean
that this whole thing is,
you can't take anything
serious on that stone.
I would like to kiss her on the Buckeye.
It's ridiculous.
Please don't take anything I say
ever anywhere. Seriously. I know.
That's the problem I have is not worth it.
It's not worth it.
It's too much of an investment.
Right. It's, you know,
I wouldn't take anything I said seriously.
You don't need to as well. It's fun.
Yeah. I mean that's what the
beauty of a podcast are folks.
Getting a little window into a retarded
conversation that Ma'am and I would have
probably had with or without
you, right? Fuck yeah.
That's one of the coolest
things about doing this podcast.
This is basically hanging out with
your friends except other people all
throughout the world and I'll tell you,
man,
I've gotten all these fucking emails and
I met all these people that tell me how
they don't have anybody like these people.
I don't know anyone like you are.
Like a lot of the guests that I have,
they don't know these fucking people.
They don't have anyone like this in the
light. I don't have by listening to this,
they don't have people to talk but
listen to this thing three, you know,
four hours every, you
know, every week or so.
You get all these weird different people,
you know,
become a part of your daily conversations.
This is like super hyper accelerating
shit for some people, you know,
from people that are living in and
shitty places where they have, you know,
poor conversations with people and they,
they, they long for someone who can,
you know,
bring challenging ideas.
There had radio has always
been like a format of like um,
like mark people I think or people
who were like, you want to like,
well yeah, communication, you
know, communication. Yeah, exactly.
I mean there's obviously
a lot of bad shit,
like a lot of the right wing Rah
Rah talk radio for those people.
You know what I mean?
Like they want to Ra.
The people want something
to rally against.
People want something to be a part
of. So you know, we all do. I do.
I always wanted to win a radio call
in contest. I always want to be here.
My name on the radio when I was driving
somewhere. Dude, you should totally post.
You should totally host some sort
of a regular radio show. What?
You could totally do.
Something like that.
What Jay host some sort of a
regular radio show. MMA hour. Yeah.
You could also crank up a podcast.
You could totally do something like
for serious or something like that.
It's got bellowing. You're
doing it just, yeah.
I didn't even know that one time a week.
Just throw it in one time a week.
Do it for an hour. Are you offering me
a job at Sirius? Right. I'm telling you,
Bryan. Bryan can set up a podcast for
you. He has a little podcast studio,
red band studios in his house.
He's rocking right now and we did one
with Tom [inaudible] and his lovely wife
the other day.
He's done it with Ari and Jason.
We have a new one coming up with Sam Aaa.
It's all about zombies. Really? Yeah.
Zombies. Yeah. Sam Tripoli's
doing a Zombie podcast,
starting 24 can you say about zombies? I
don't know. It's going to be interesting.
Pilots. They're all pride. I
predicted by episode three,
he'll just start calling people a Zombie
so I could talk shit about George Bush.
He's a Zombie seem on TV.
Good fucking,
it's kind of like that one I used to
do with the podcasts with Joey Diaz.
It was all about cats, but like, hey, so
let's talk about cat litter. Oh, anyways,
he used to rape guys, you know, they
do with cats, you know, it's just,
I've never listened to Joe. He's podcasts,
but it's called beauty and the beast.
Right? Yeah. How is it? Uh, yeah, it's
pretty good. I like it. I like it. Uh,
that girls has such a cute voice. I
could listen to her all day, you know,
just does he get as worked
up when he's with her?
Does he get crazy and start yelling and
shit? And sometimes, yeah, it's, it's,
you know, it's exactly what you'd
expect to ATS to be. I mean, you know,
who was a big fan of that? It's
Ms. Miller. Ms. Miller used to
drive home, you know, you
called her miss. Ms. Miller. Mrs
Ms. Remember that shift for a while?
You're trying to rock ms Ms,
you don't know what I am still to this.
That's one of those things I just haven't
cared enough about to like learn the,
yeah, the metric system. This is
the missus and the Moose slurs.
I still don't know one for men.
Mister [inaudible].
You don't even think about voting right
when voting comes around you like what?
Don't give a phone now.
I don't want any court dates.
I don't want to get audited or any,
I don't want to be in the
system as much as possible.
Like did you just hear that the government
just closed down like 80 websites the
other day? Just pull them
off the Internet. They sell
on a bunch of pirated shit.
So,
I mean,
can you just overtake somebody that has,
you know, you know at Torrance are right.
They're not. Was that what it does?
It was towards torrent websites.
More also like a piracy web sites,
like where people were selling like
counterfeit jewelry and shoes maybe.
But it's still kind of weird that they're
allowed to just go Bam. I, you know,
I know what you're saying.
Weird. Well it, you know,
obviously it is and it's once they
can start shutting down websites,
but if they're doing, see
that's the tricky thing, like
a lot of people, you know,
you got to recognize that the courts have
decided that torrents and downloading
copyrighted material is uh, is
stealing, you know, I mean that's,
that's how they're looking at it.
So if the courts or if they've
made decisions like that
and then you're going to
run a website or some sort of a torrent
site, where are you going to, you know,
get people access to a
bunch of illegal shit?
You got to assume that
eventually someone's going to
shut you down. Right? Right.
Well look,
the Pirate Bay,
I don't know if got you saw that
they just went back last year.
I lost and then they lost the rebuttal
or whatever it's called and now they're
going to jail. And it's, the
website's still up though.
And I mean it's like, wait,
so some people are going to jail. Yeah.
And then they just tore down all those,
those guys make money. How does
something like that advertising, man,
there's so much advertising on
that website. It's ridiculous.
People pay just to have an ad
there cause nobody pays attention.
I was fucking ads. Right,
right. You don't do,
when you go to the website was
the last time you clicked an ad.
Some has to be absolutely
fucking outstanding. Interesting.
They're the kind that you just go
there and it says congratulations.
You won a gift card to the olive garden.
Click here. So it's crappy. Like websites.
Yeah. Nobody like legitimate,
but they're paying them.
They must be paying a
mad loop. Right. I Dunno.
Order for them to be fighting
this like this. They're not.
So you think they're just finding
it just because they want freedom.
They want to be able to just
trade numbers. I don't know.
And that's all it is really. I think
that's the whole point of, you know it,
you can't bust somebody for having,
you know,
you can't bust somebody for stealing
of whatever, a milli Vanilli CD.
If you don't have the Milli Vanilli
city on something you're serving,
you're just pointing it to all these
different directions. You know?
I see what you're saying.
It's like Torrance. Yeah.
If you're going right to
the beautiful, yeah. Yeah.
Like torrents are just using like you
have a piece of a file on your computer.
Somebody else has a piece of complete
file on their computer and all of this
website like pirate base pointing like,
Hey,
this is where to go to join this other
way to walk down the hallway down there.
They're walking down his group,
but it's coming from someone who already
bought it and they should be able to
give it away. Is that what
you're saying? No, no.
I'm just saying what am I
someone somewhere or another
somewhere had to attain a
copy. Yeah, absolutely. Man. Know what
I'm saying? I'm saying that they stole it.
I'm saying what's scary
about the pirate band?
What's scary about a lot of these places?
If they don't actually have files on their
computer and they're getting arrested
for things and what makes it stop,
then you know like you getting arrested
because somebody put a torrent file on
your form. Even though, even though
it's not hosting anything, computers,
their whole entire purpose for existing
on the Internet is to connect people
with other people that are selling
things available for download that are
illegal. Yeah. But uh, you,
so Google has maps and then it tells
you where to go to murder people if you
want anything at all. But that's
okay though. The whole PR,
I mean it's not like Google's
called murder Google, but you can,
you can lose advertising or
hey check and they got murder.
google.com I want to start
that serial killer Google.
I see what you're saying.
I totally see what you're saying.
But I I also see like
that, you know, they,
if these companies look for sure a
music companies have suffered big time
because of the Internet going
to shake it up eventually.
If cit is like for me clicking on
Itunes, it's so easy. Then I go,
okay I'll just click on iTunes. Me
Too. You know what I'm saying? Like,
I'll just buy it because,
and not cause you know,
cause I have a boatload of money cause
I would buy about the same amount of
music as I do now.
But like if I was like super poor
but like it's like so easy to do.
I don't even want to feel that.
The only time I ever downloaded something
is when it's not available for sale.
You know, if I can buy it, I buy it or
when it's not out yet, it's just there.
They're finding that equalized
like pressure and I think
that that tows torrent
files. That's an awesome
technology. Like they
need to, you know, use that and
legal ways. You know what I mean?
Like that's just how it is.
It's, it's a, it's a whole,
the whole issue is a very tricky issue
because on one side you have to say,
well this,
you're stifling innovation by stopping
these people from doing all this stuff
and by putting the brakes on all these
sites. But the other side he'd go,
well wait a minute, how the fuck are
these people supposed to make money?
You can't just have something for free
that I want to sell for $20 on amazon.com
you can download it and Tim, what I'm
thinking is it's the same as, oh my God,
like cds are gonna gonna make
everybody, you know, writeable cds.
It's going to ruin it
for the music industry.
Now they got to find an
equal pressure where,
where the cds did a little bit of a dent,
but of course the big dent was done by
the Internet. Yeah, of course. I mean,
look man, do you remember when there
were selling like v record stores,
but they want to rent her now. It's
so easy just to click, you know,
life is getting better, but you know,
some people are going to suffer for sure.
Yeah,
I'm lucky.
I live right across the street from a
record store that does used records and
rigor, rigor, and so
every time I want a CD,
I just go there and spend three 99 for
a UCD. Oh, what's the name of the store?
Don't say it because then people will
know exactly what you live. Right now.
I'm going live right across the street
from it, Brian. I was testing it. Yeah.
I've been doing me Ba Amoeba
records is pretty dope. Maybe sweet.
You know it's like some weird whatever
link to the past where you're holding a
vinyl album. Yeah, no. You're like, whoa,
this is a disk and you spin this
and something scratches often.
Do you buy a record and
I'll buy a CD though.
I'll buy CDs still if I'm someplace,
you know,
if I'm at best buy and I want to
listen to something, you know,
like we have a rental car
or something like that,
but now that I have my phone or
my iPod hooked up to my car. Yeah,
exactly. That's what I'm saying.
All your media in your hand.
What I miss though is a real Dj.
I Miss Dj's are dual personalities,
right?
Oh
Hey.
It's may have in the am
blonde dude.
96.7 we're getting wacky this morning.
Drive on the highways.
You can see that mayhem in the am.
I could see that radio show now. You
would have to get a black chick sidekick.
Yeah, she would have to get to the
first one. You're going to fire.
She's just really, you know, and then
the second one will know, listen bitch,
you get crazy. We're going to fire
you. Or this is the mayhem show, right?
Is it then the Tonya show.
Oh Man,
I read my five Kilkee dear Wendy
Williams talking shit about MMA. Yo,
do you feel fight this weekend? Like
Wendy Williams would be like, no,
so fun. Oh, whatever. And you're
going to do traffic for me, right?
And then we got the traffic,
we got the CD and the one on one I
would have traffic. You would be like,
kittens would be falling from the
sky and there's videos right away.
When you were tuned into the clouds,
it'd be some fucking flaming skull
face and scares the shit out of you.
Had a little bit of blood on my toilet
bowls seat when I got off and today.
Have you seen that video
of that rat attacking?
Yeah. Wow. Wait.
Brazilian jungle rat or something
or it's some crazy route.
I don't know where it was,
but this is rat running after these cats.
And one one time bites this one cat and
it stuck to them and the cats run and
trying to shake the rat off. This
rat doesn't give a fuck. Yeah.
These cats are so confused.
Well,
I mean they're domesticated house cats
and not fighting giant mega monster wrath
that have been mutated by ooze.
And you realize when you see
that how high rats can jump,
they jump up to bite those
mother fuckers jump high.
They're like an athletic animal. They're,
they're pretty loked man. We're lucky.
Rats are little or big.
We'd be really be fuck man.
I killed the rat once in my garage and
I left it there because I was lazy.
So I lived in Encino and uh,
it was a big fucking rat because I used
to leave the garbage back there and I
would hear like these clean my garage
like clang, clang, clang. Oh here,
these loud ass noises.
And I opened up my garage,
I open up the door and I hit the light
switch and this fucking rat moved across
my garbage and it was like, like attack
size. Like he could attack me. Like,
this is a big dangerous
threatening animal. I was
looking at this like, holy fuck,
that's a big rat. That's called a
possum. It was big. It was a rat. It was,
but it was big man. It was like half
the size of how do you know as a rat?
Because I killed it. So I set up a
trap. Got Them. I've got a rat trap.
Set it up there and I came back
and he was fucking big man,
like big and fat. Fucking, I'm like,
this was eating my all my garbage.
I out to put that on net.
If I were you, I fucked up.
This is before he even had Joe
Rogan. Dot. Trap was in his ass.
If I had acted back then I would have
owned Joe rogan.com but I was sleeping
that motherfucker. That to me is one of
the greatest losses as a real estate guy.
Very nice guy from Boise, Idaho. You
want an a shitload of money for it?
You want to like 80 grand, some
crazy. I was like, what? I'm like,
I can't give you that much money, man.
I have not. Dot Net they can find it.
You know now with Google, if you want
to find my website, you can find it.
It's not that hard.
You know?
I can't give you that much for
fucking.com crazy asshole. I know. Yeah,
you're Joe Rogan.
Gimme some money.
There's another guy that has
an issue with that. Tom Green.
Why turn off the tongue? Because
there's another dude named Tom Green.
You're on there tomorrow, by the way,
right? Oh yeah. Yeah. I'm doing Tom Green.
I don't know. Good question. Tom Green's
a podcast tomorrow. That's mod castle.
I Guess Kevin Smith has some sort
of a whole podcast on like a,
like a studio set up. Oh yeah. Just to do
podcasts. Podcasts are fucking taken off.
They are and they are. How about
me? Him and the am a podcast.
If you want to do it, man,
we can. We could set it up.
We can do it at Brian's place. You can
come to my house. Can't rape him. No Man.
No rape promise. Who? Eric,
you might have to rate me. Chris over
here. He can't tell his character.
His name is fucking Eric Bro.
That's today. He used to be Chris,
which just for the record, he
changed his name. Brian First,
but then Chris after he met you
and then Eric after today. Yeah.
I always, I always care of every
name. Yup. Cause so in your red band,
I can't call
you. I get a nickname or my
head for somebody like Eric.
I know you don't do red band,
whatever.
You're just trying to
play with my emotions.
You're like that fucking laugh. This
whole attitude you have towards live this,
uh, I'm not scared to be around
mountain lions and Charlotte.
Why would you be man? Whatever,
man. I'm not saying, look,
I'm not saying you're wrong.
Everybody's scared to be around. I think
you only think about it more though.
Yeah. You're constantly
thinking I'm too, too aware.
I just feel like I'll deal with that when,
when it comes up like, ah, I'm like, Oh,
right now I'm gonna live my life and
then I see a fucking mountain lion.
All right. Why Mountain
biking? Which makes sense.
Cause they both have mountain in them.
I would fucking deal with it then.
It's a very good,
weird thing when you lock eyes with a
big Predator like a mountain lion in the
wild. You know I only locked
eyes with the one that I saw.
I only locked eyes with it for
a couple seconds. But that's a,
that's a very weird moment when you saw
it with your dog from a giant dog boy.
Yeah. My giant dog was inside my little
dog there was outside. They got jacked.
My giant dog is stolen from
you. Yeah, my no, no, no.
My task was injured so
he had injured his Paul.
So I left him in the house.
Yeah.
They want them running around up in the
mountains because they would run all
over the place up there. Just
kidding. You know, they'd get a pack,
there's three of them together
and they would have a good time.
Just go run and play.
And that kept animals away.
But I have a bulldog and he's lazy.
And then this little dog,
which was a Chihuahua Palm, excuse
me, Pomeranian a American Eskimo mix.
And that one's the one that got jacked
cause he was out there wandering around
basically by himself.
He's only 20 pounds and he doesn't have
his hundred and 40 pound buddy to look
over his shoulders and he doesn't have
the bull dog cause the bulldogs is,
you know, would go with them if the two
of them were going, even though he's lazy,
he would go with them.
So it was a lot of action there.
There was a pack that
keep the animals away,
but something that had been stalking my
house for a while because the dogs would
just go crazy.
It'd be on the porch,
just start barking at the top
of their lungs and he, you know,
you'd hear things like snapping in the,
in the distance and the dark trip.
Do I have to worry about,
I probably don't, but I'm
pretty, I pretty much have it.
I'm pretty sure I don't have to.
But as you crows,
crows don't like kill dogs.
Right? Did you not see the movie?
Well I'm not talking about for Hitchcock,
Brandon crozer ruthless cause a root.
That's right.
There's kill your dog like coughing. They
can. There's this guy in this girl crow,
they just sit out and like make these
clicking noise like like the whole time
and then,
and then my dog would come up there and
just be like looking up at it and then
once in a while the crow just swoops down.
Doesn't like attack it or anything.
It's kind of like he's just like,
like about to, do you need it?
I left a stake outside.
It was partially thawed and not totally
thought out and I was going to barbecue
so I left to stay outside for 10 minutes.
I came back, there was two crows on it,
just jacking the steak,
just pulling out chunks of
the meat squawking and I
chased him all Christ. Yeah.
Oh
Dude,
fuck yeah.
You have to worry if you can't like
leave your dog outside if that's what you
mean. Dude, in Japan they have your dogs
for three pounds and she's a whore pouch.
The three pounds will come out.
My Dogs fucking the crows.
The crows are gang bang and your dog, you
get over it. You missed the story. Nixon,
he brought his dog to a party where a
bunch of people at dogs and they all took
turns. Just Gang Bang and his dog
salmon at the same time. All the dog.
10 dogs in the what? A
slut. Yeah man. I love her
c sweet,
sweet.
My hot dog dogs gay for sure because he,
oh yeah,
he got it like a little tiny like dog
have to pound dog like that was talking
about and he was like, not interested
but like he had this little like,
like tight athletic,
muscular little dude dog and he was
just like all over it for banging them
front. Headlock banging. I'm
like, yeah. I was like, what
are you all right? I'm like,
wow, you're into dude's, Huh? Stop.
I guess I figured if I was just run
around with just like a collar on,
I would be, you know, whatever
the line is blurred at that point.
The line is blurry. Like you're,
you're running around the collar,
you're a wild animal, you know, whatever.
If the females in heat then it becomes
very clear. That's what I mean.
He was sniffing at the Coochie
to like quite a bit. He was like,
my pit bull was um, he was in
agony one night, like in serious,
serious agony where I thought you
said something wrong with him,
like he's got cancer or something.
This is crazy.
He was like whining and Yiping and I'd
come near him. I'm like, what's up buddy?
Okay. And I'm like, Whoa, this
is crazy. My dog's fucked up.
Like you'd go down the stairs and you'd
be like limping as he was going down the
stairs come off. I've felt real
sad. I'm like, my dog's kind die.
Something's wrong with my dog. I got to
get them to the vet. This is horrible.
He's like whimpering. So I'd take
him to the vet. The vet looks at me,
he starts checking out my dog's balls.
You're checking out his dick and he's
like, you see this? He's, yes, right here.
See how inflamed the says?
Okay,
there's a dog in your neighborhood that's
in heat and that's what's going on.
I'm like, Whoa, really?
He's in agony from his heart
on his dick was so swollen.
It was so like,
like the glands,
like here's the balls and then there's
these weird glance by the side of the
Dick that are just lie dog has that
sometime. What is your dog fixed? No, no.
My dog isn't either. And they get big.
That's what I said. He shall do anything.
They can't do anything. You can,
if you want a drink, dogs help.
But then red rock is how many times
you going to do that in a row?
If I had to do it every, I dunno, a
couple of weeks. I guess I could. Yeah.
I mean he's a good friend. My friend,
my friend Dimitris to jerk off his dog.
I'm going to answer the phone.
It's right there. Same Person.
Disrespectful fucks. They don't know
we're on the podcast, right? Shit man.
This tells, you know what it tells
me. It tells me they're not watching.
Then I have friends.
They're not friends hurt my feeling.
Same person keeps calling, man. They
don't find you on Twitter. What the fuck?
So for
with that ring comes the end.
That is the end of the show.
There's no reason to keep going. No,
it's eight 30 8:30 PM it is late. Oh Man.
Fuck whatever sign
may and Mila you are,
you're always one of the most fascinating
people to talk to the bag throw.
He's a fun guy to be
around the lamb by the way.
I'm writes a really great article,
fight magazine.
He's one of my favorite writers
and now I'm not bullshitting,
not just as a fighter. And I told
him very early on, I'm like, dude,
you've got like real talent and I really
hope you write a book someday because I
think you could write some
crazy hunter s Thompson shit.
His writing is really good. I mean
it's, it's, it's the latest one of you.
Appreciate Cause I'm in Rio de Janeiro.
Oh yeah.
And you're writing about your experiences
cause you were there for a couple of
weeks, right? Yeah. Yeah. So I was out
there for a while so I did everything.
Well tell me about that real quick before
we take off because what is Rio like
man, man, it's scary. Scary. The article.
It's all kind of read the article and
really give us a little bit into it.
I see the article I'm here right now.
That's like,
give me a little bit
like a whole new Doug.
He was like the next
level. I don't know, it's,
I always had my preconceived notions
about Brazil due to movies and do to,
you know, whatever the hell is going
on. Right. And you know like my friends,
my Brazilian friends to fighters,
what they tell me about it.
I have a new found respect for,
for that city and I understand my
Brazilian friends a little bit more now.
The article really,
I can just see why they
think that everything it like
they have such passion for
their, for their country because
everybody there has a lot of passion.
It was like, it's like that
like it's a passionate place.
Like people love to do stuff.
Like people are good at things and like
they really love it and it's the stuff
that's dirty. It's supposed to be dirty,
like it's kind of dirty of course,
but it's supposed to be dirty.
What do you mean like dirty, dirty,
but in a bad way.
Not that sounds bad,
but it's like the streets are dirty.
Everybody drives with like a vengeance,
like they drive crazy crazy,
but it's like seems skillful.
I saw less car wrecks there
than I ever saw here in la.
It's all what you get used to, you know,
get used to that sort of hyper driving.
Like everybody's used to it. It's like,
exactly. Everybody's just drive through.
I don't know man. There's so much
stuff. Fight magazine, we'll,
we'll have it man for December. And you
gotta check it out, check out the article.
Did you see anything crazy while you
were there? Any violence? Anything nutty?
I mean, I saw him, we went to the favelas.
We went to a couple of times too. Like,
yeah, the ghetto, like, yeah, we
went to the favelas and I, you know,
I write about that in this article too,
man,
about going there and people are like
collecting rainwater and these drums,
you know, to to, yeah, it's
a drink. They're poor and,
and they have like their,
uh, tapping into the, uh,
telephone poles get electricity.
Yeah.
And like the streets are all jagged
and people own that area. You know,
like the drug dealers own
the favelas and stuff,
but they have the boppy coming in like,
which are the Brazilian like kick
ass police force to like the,
the police station that,
you know,
I was right there in the middle of the
thing and everyone's running out like a,
the, the, you can, it feels like a
military presence instead of like a army.
The ones that they have,
they taken over and been nice
again. Wow. Yeah. It's crazy.
Yeah. There's a big article, I think
it was on CNN this morning about that,
but there's tanks moving back into
that right now. It's like, yeah,
a little bit of like, uh,
some Aye. Aye. Marcel Alonzo,
this journalist that I was out
there with a, he kind of a t told,
you know, he kinda told me
that it's dying down right now,
but there's like a lot of guys,
the drug dealers doing crazy terrorist
stuff right now in Rio. It's sucks that,
that, uh, that that's happening right now.
I was in Sao Paulo in 2003,
and a friend of mine went back in 2008,
I believe it was,
and he was arrested. They were,
uh, there, there was so many,
there was so much violence between the
police and the drug dealers that they
were closing down streets and highways
and they were driving to a chew Hoss
Korea with some business clients and
everybody was pulled out of the car at
gunpoint. They had fucking, you know, they
wanted to make sure that they weren't,
they were in a nice car and they didn't
know who these people were and they
wanted to make sure they
weren't drug dealers.
They were just pulling people out and
sticking guns in their faces. Yeah,
of course.
He said it was pretty fucking scary
because they were killing police officers'
families. They would go to their family
and just kill everyone. Really? Yeah.
They were doing it for a while,
man.
They were declaring war on the
police officers. It was pretty,
it was pretty lucked out. No Way.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Brazil, you know,
and the crazy thing about Brazil is,
you know, Brazil's up beautiful, insane,
like tropical jungle country and
the favelas where all like the,
the chaos has taken place is above
the regular city. I know. Yeah. Rio,
which is like the main cities
in the bottom. And then we're,
the beautiful view is that's all the
projects that we have, the richest,
most beautiful view, like
in the world, you know,
and they live living in like
cardboard houses and Shit.
Yeah, no, they put that stuff together on
their own, like crazy. Yeah. But you know,
I mean, I can, I can understand why people
love the country. You know what I mean?
Like I can understand why
it has definitely a passion
filled country, man. Yeah,
that's what I mean. Yeah.
It's great man. I, I dunno,
I had a great experience out there. Like
I, it was just, it was their economies.
I mean, right now. Yeah, exactly.
You have so much going on right now.
And they found, they also found the
oil off the coast of Brazil. So like,
there's a lot of money
in Brazil right now.
Their economy's not fucked
up like ours is. It's,
it's moving in a better direction.
They're talking about doing a UFC there
eventually. I would be a fascinating,
but you know, you talked to like, um, uh,
w Vinnie a Magallanes you have any yeah,
sure.
He was talking about, uh,
the on the underground,
he was talking about doing
a UFC in Rio and he posed,
I think it was him who
posted some link of some, no,
Sonya was post the link of the Formula
One drivers Formula One drivers where a
in some Sao Paulo and they got
fucking shot at and their armored car.
I take try it someone who is trying to
carjack them and they're an armored cars.
What? Yeah. And you're trying
to kidnap him. Damn. Yeah.
Kidnapped from or just robbed him rather
than at gunpoint hoping they get some
watches or something crazy. A buddy
of mine was there. Um, and, uh,
he, I was with a friend
of his that was, uh,
doing something and he had like a
pocket full of money and he had in his,
in his lap and he was like looking
through it and trying to fish through it.
And as he was doing this,
a guy came up in a motorcycle,
looked at his gun or looked at, uh,
his, uh, his money pulled out a gun,
tapped on the windshield,
you know,
told the guy to pull over and they
just robbed him. They robbed everybody,
stuck a gun in their face
and just took everybody,
he said the guy would just drive around
looking in people's cars to see if they
had nice watches or what they have that
look cool and it would just steal it,
man. Yeah, you might be in the
wrong place. The wrong time,
son that's made brown the voice of doom,
doom.
You tell her you're the most
guy on earth right now. Like,
I'm not like Joe Rogan is scared of
the world. It's not, I'm just aware.
I'm not scared of you just pay them away.
Don't get jacked.
But you know as person who's
constantly thinking about shit,
I always have to be a whale
aware of all the variables.
You know he think way too much bro. You
think so? I think you'd think a lot.
You think Soto,
I think you think deep into some things.
You don't need to think that deep.
It can help it though.
It's probably a sickness.
It's a sickness that manifests
itself as a an an excellent career.
You know the sickness of
constantly thinking about
shit and breaking things down
to the finest minutia OCD though or
something. Something probably like that.
That's all.
It's not,
the hard thing with me is just finding
the right things to break down.
Things that are productive to tune my
my energy too cause you could easily get
the awesome thing I and that's what
masturbation or online arguments or video
games or you can get lost in a
bunch of like unhealthy channels.
Hopefully you got some good stuff
though that you OCD about like butthole
tidiness and like trimming
and stuff like that. You.
The show was going to end and it was going
to be fine right there and you had to
come in. Brian. Now man, he wants
to talk about your butthole.
He's all about bottles. I told you bro,
1 million, 1 million, 1 million. Okay.
And no less. And I don't need that million
bucks. I'll tell you that right now.
I would like it. I like it, but if I don't
get it, I'll be okay. God, goddammit.
Jason, that was a good time. Yeah,
it was always a good time with you.
And my friend May Have Miller at
Twitter. Um, so, um, okay, cool.
Um, I've got another coconut
juice for you. Fell off.
Brian's a Twitter is red band.
We want to thank the fleshlight for
sponsoring the podcast. And again,
if you would like to feel what it feels
like to masturbate into one of those
fine sweet bitches I have to do is go to
Joe rogan.net and click that flashlight
link and you get 15% off when you
put in the code name. What does it?
Rogan [inaudible] very simple.
Um,
the tickets for the New Year's eve show
at Mandalay Bay will go up very shortly.
We should have all that done
within a couple of days. And uh,
as soon as I get it done,
I'll let you guys know and uh,
we might be doing one
more podcast this week.
We're gonna try and get Ralphie
may in here on Wednesday.
Oh, I just, Ralphie May.
He's awesome. If Ralph he's got the
time off. We've got to talk to them,
but our right batch, it's hard not fuel.
And um, I'll see you soon somewhere.
Maybe not even see you,
but I'll be there and you'll be there too.
And let's pretend we're all in the
same place. What is this ice tea?
Cause this icy saying suck
my dick is no. Yeah, it is.
Sounds like it. Yeah. This
sounds like a black guy,
but not too black gay. He's
not like Africa, you know,
he's not like check Congo black.
I'm saying it gets light skin it,
he might even rock an afro just to try
to accentuate is more African side.
Yeah, but he has braids and the summer.
Yeah. Because if he had a shaved head,
you might think he was an
Arab or something. Right?
Yeah, baby. Yeah. Light it.
Probably like a yellow, maybe even got
a little bit of like white features,
which is why he's got such an
extra aggressive attitude. Yeah.
I was trying to like accentuate
prop himself up, but you know,
you know your race him.
That's not racist,
Bro. I see. I break it all
down and I hit my look, Bro.
All right, folks, most likely
we will be back on Wednesday.
I'm doing the Tom Green thing tomorrow.
I don't have any details.
That's Tom Green's thing.
You could follow him on Twitter.
I think it's Tom Green
live. That's it. Pitches.
I love you and I'll see you next week
or sometime soon or, or Wednesday.