Yes.
Uh, with me today, this Friday night,
you can catch him live on spike TV.
Glory 19 rights number 19.
Yes sir. Stitch my Joe
Schilling live from Los Angeles.
Welcome aboard brother. Pull that sucker
right up to your face. Don't be shy.
You're drinking distilled water.
Huh? That's uh, to cut weight.
Is that what that is? Yes
sir. How much she cut? Uh mm.
I try to cut like 12 pounds of water.
Maybe a little less, but uh, the process,
it's like five gallons
of water over three days.
Is there like a science
to this or is this like,
does everybody do the same thing or
like it seems like a lot of people have
different methods on how to do this.
Yeah,
a lot of people have different
messages and methods of,
I read about it online probably five
years ago from some wrestler and we tried
it and it worked really well for me,
so I just keep the same way. But uh,
I'll do two gallons of water,
like my Wayne's on Thursday.
So I started on Sunday,
two gallons of distilled water on Sunday,
right?
Yeah.
Two gallons on Sunday,
two gallons on Monday,
one gallon Tuesday to Wednesday,
and then Wednesday for 24 hours.
I won't drink any water, no salt, and just
kind of comes right off. So Wednesday,
no water all the way through Thursday.
No water the way ends a Thursday. Yeah.
And because of the distilled water,
because this distilled water has no
minerals in it, it's just pure water.
It just flushes through your system.
Is that the idea behind it?
And it hasn't had,
it doesn't have any minerals so that
your body doesn't hold on to it.
And because it's flushing through system,
it pulls all the other minerals out with
it. So you know, the first two days, uh,
you just pee and like crazy, you're
sweating like crazy. Put on deodorant,
you're still sweating like crazy.
Your body feels like it's over
flooded with water and uh,
that last 24 hour period, it's still in
that same cycle and you're, you know,
the rest of the water just
comes right out. Yeah. See,
I would think that that
would be not good for you.
That's probably not distilled water.
It just seems like,
cause I know my friend Aubrey,
he went on um,
this weird diet of a distilled water,
like he thought like distilled water be
pure and he started getting dizzy and
shit. I think you, and he
went and got himself checked
out and they're like, dude,
you don't have any fucking minerals in
your system. Like you can't be doing that.
It's definitely not a healthy
thing. It's not a, you know,
I definitely don't advocate it for
anything other than cutting weight.
What do you weigh in at a one 87 weigh
in at one 87 you walk around somewhere
around, if I'm walking around like maybe
six weeks ago, it was probably like two,
10 to 12, you know, if that's
eating whatever I want, you know,
drinking beer and doing whatever I
want to do is everybody's got their own
little ideas about what should be done
as far as like how much weight to cut
before you compete.
Some guys think cut the minimum amount
possible and then there's these extreme
dudes that cut like 30, 40 pounds. Yeah.
Uh, it really comes down to everybody.
And then also like your style of fighting.
Some guys I think need to feel strong,
a lot bigger and stronger because
maybe they're lacking or because they,
you know, whatever reason they need to be
bigger and stronger than the other guy.
But this is a hindrance.
You know,
I've cut too much weight and over hydrated
and learned lessons that way where,
you know, yeah. I think when I fought
Simon mark is the second time. Um,
when I flew to Vegas,
I still had like one gallon of distilled
water I supposed to drink and they
wouldn't let me take it on the plane,
giant gallon of water.
And as soon as I landed they had me do
impress and stuff and I didn't get to
drink that last gallon of water.
Um,
so I started drinking coffee like
crazy thinking. Well that's diuretic.
It helped me lose the water.
And when that 24 hour period came
or it was time to get the weight,
I hadn't really dropped anything.
I was still like 22 pounds over.
So I had to cut 22 pounds
and 24 hours and Whoa.
It was terrible. It was
awful. I've seen, you know,
the first round I came out
strong, I was, I felt really good.
And then after the second round
it was like, it was almost like,
you know when you have a dream and
you've tried to fight somebody but you're
laying on your arm, you can't get the
wrench off. It was just like that. And uh,
yeah, it was a bad performance.
So I learned from that one a lot.
The point of diminishing returns.
That's a big one when it comes
to weight cutting, right? It's,
it's almost like a whole nother event
in itself. There's like the fight,
the training for the fight,
the preparation skills,
training and conditioning,
all that jazz.
And then there's this weight cutting
thing that's a totally different event.
And guys fail at it. Like this past
weekend, two big important fights.
The guys failed that at John Linacre
failed for like the fifth fucking time.
The Guy can't make one 25 but he
wants to be the bigger guy. You know,
he doesn't want to fight one 35 and then
Calvin, Kelvin Gaslamp's same thing.
Couldn't, couldn't make one 70
for like the fourth time. It's,
I don't know how many times Calvin's
Ms, not as many as Linacre, but he's,
you know,
he's cutting it close many times.
He got a guy like Anthony
Johnson. It was like, really?
I had a really bad reputation in the UFC.
He got cut because he couldn't
make weight and then, uh,
finally decided to stick to his natural
weight and he's killing it, you know?
So it's ridiculous. It's a,
it's a weird balancing act.
I think everybody has their own,
you know, you've got to learn,
learn your lessons and work from anywhere.
There's never been a guy like
Johnson who like at one 70, you know,
he's a good fighter,
very good,
but struggles to make weight and then
Fades Leighton fights because he's
depleting the shit out of his body,
goes all the way up to heavyweight
and beats the shit out.
Andre Arlovski and you're like,
what the fuck? A heavyweight.
And then drops down to two oh five to
compete in the UFC. Makes wait no problem.
And is the number one contender now and
just terrifying, terrifying fighter.
Amazing.
It's amazing how this guy like not
torturing his body is now one of the best
fighters on earth. Whereas three
years ago he didn't have a career.
It's career was fucked up all
just because of weight cutting.
Yeah. You know, it's a, it's a
weird, weird thing, you know, uh,
if you don't do the weight cutting and
the, or we did like same day wanes,
then you still have guys that are going
to try to cut the weight and fight the
same.
Yeah. Healthy. You know, it's terrible
boy, especially striking sports.
It's terrible for you with wrestling,
but guys get away with it. Um,
but with combat sports, anytime you're,
you were involving head strikes you,
you really don't have enough time to
replenish all the water that protects your
brain, all the water
in your, in your head.
And that was one of the issues that
people used to have back in the old days
where these to Wayne and
fight on the same day.
They changed that around the
duck. Who Kim fight, I believe.
It's also when they dropped it from 15
rounds to 12 or boxing because they just
felt like 15 is too long and they
changed the bus. The uh, the gloves.
Heavyweights used to wear Aidan's
clothes and then now it's,
I think you have to be under one 45,
two B. Any downs? Clothes. Wow. I mean,
can you imagine heavyweight
fighting with Aiden's clothes?
It's basically just a
different style, you know? Wow.
Well how about the Jack Johnson days
where they used to wear those Everlast bag
gloves? There's a little tea. They were
just Bexley knuckle pads. That's crazy.
Well, there's some guys that
think, and I'm, I'm one of them,
that MMA would probably be more realistic
and better if no one wore gloves.
I feel like if you can need someone in
the face, elbows, someone in the face,
kick someone in the face, why you
punched him in the face with gloves on.
It just protects your hands more
than anything. And also the wrists,
like having your wrist
taped up nice and solid.
Like it makes it so that
you can hit people harder.
You could be much more careless with your
punches. Like if you had bare knuckles,
it would be a much more realistic like
scenario as far as like what you can do
with your body,
you've and everything up and wrap and
everything nice and tight and solid and
padding it, you know, you're turning
your hand to a different thing. Right?
Well it's like some athletic commissions
allow you to tape your ankle.
Some people, some athletic
nutritionists don't, you know,
if you watch like the, uh,
like the okay ones and stuff,
you'll see like butter, hurry in.
And these guys have like a huge amount
of padding placed over their ankle and
their foot that padding is not
protecting the person they're hitting is
protecting you.
So if you're,
if you're ripping kicks and you kick
somebody in the elbow, you know,
and you have a pad on it,
it's going to protect you.
You're gonna be more likely
to keep kicking then if you
smashed your foot in the
first one. So yeah, it's
kind of interesting. Yeah.
I think protected teeth
protect your balls. That's it.
I think maybe that's the best way to go,
but everybody has this thing where it
would look more barbaric if somehow or
another your knuckles
weren't protected bright.
Well then also you've got to look at
it from like a promotion standpoint.
You know, if everybody was breaking
their hands and, and fights, you know,
they wouldn't, as a fan we wouldn't
get to see those fights, you know,
as often as we'd like to do to see
them. You know. So that is true.
But when you talk about like,
uh,
like the impact on the problems
with brain damage and, and you know,
the side effects for
guys after their career,
can you imagine if we had even less
padding on our hands and you know, it's,
well they think that there would be
actually less brain damage cause guys
wouldn't get hit as much.
You'd have to be much more judicious with
where you placed your punches and you
know, because of the fact that you, you
know, if you hit somebody in the forehead,
you're most likely going to
snap your knuckles. Right.
He'd be a little bit more careful. I
don't know. It's a weird argument. Yeah.
It's like the same argument with,
they've said that if
football players didn't have pads,
it didn't have helmets,
it would be a safer game for the players.
But of course it put football,
they're not punching each
other in the face. Yeah.
And there's always going to
be that one guy that like,
just like the one gift
they did same day way.
And there's always gonna be that one guy
that thinks he can still cut 30 pounds
and fight the day of guys are,
yeah.
The one guy who doesn't care and keeps
hitting the person when his hands broken,
you know? That's, uh, yeah,
that's true. That's true.
So you were in camp with Nick Diaz and
preparation for his fight this past
weekend with Anderson Silva, which
was an amazing fight. You know,
and I've been thinking a lot about
that fight after it was over.
And one of the things that really,
um,
really like locked into my
head was there's a lot of
people that are calling for
Anderson to retire now. You know, and
they're saying that, uh, you know,
and even Chris Weidman is one of them.
He said he'd like to see Anderson retire,
but I watched the fight and I was
thinking about myself after the fight,
like with nick in,
in Silva,
that was a better fight then nick and
Carlos condit it was a better fight then
GSP and nick, like, these are,
these are, it was a good fight.
It was a good competitive,
exciting fight. And, um, you know,
Anderson Silva fighting nick the
Nick Diaz is a tough motherfucker.
He's a good fighter. He's very smart
and very crafty. And I think that,
uh, you know, like the guy coming off of
those two fights, it's almost like just,
we expect more of him then have
just a regular fighter. Like,
like if that was GSP in his prime and
he put on the exact same performance and
if you just, you know, CGI GSPs body
and made someone watched the fight,
this good fight while at the
beginning was kind of ridiculous.
Nick was clowning him, which was
hilarious. I was howling laughing.
I couldn't,
I couldn't stop myself.
I was slapping the table when he laid
down and put his head like he's taking a
nap. We were in the corner
laughing. He couldn't believe it.
I was worried about him, you
know, going into the fight.
I felt a lot of responsibility for him,
uh, kickboxing wise, you know. Right.
And I felt like my, my job
helping him out, you know,
he's one of my good friends.
I played with him anyway,
but in this fight at a camp,
I was kind of more of a coaching and
um, I felt a lot of responsibility. No,
not him, not to get caught.
And you know, did I teach him,
did I teach them the right things
that I tell them enough stuff,
felt like a lot of
responsibility. And, uh,
you're gonna be yelling out
instructions or whatever.
And he did that and then I was like,
you know,
and then he stood up and walked right
out and with his hands down, I'm like, I,
I'll get fucking hit. Right, right, right.
But yeah, I was super proud of him. Um,
yeah, that, that's happened to me
in the past too, with the, you know,
when I fought calculi nobody,
nobody thought it was going to win.
That was Joe's going to get destroyed,
you know,
and I was the only one that
believed that I was gonna win.
And then once I had to beat
him decisively, then it
was all he should retire.
He's not good anymore. And I think
that's just not fair. You know,
it's like the guy comes
back from, uh, you know,
two losses and one of them was a horrific,
you know,
Shin break and then Nick Diaz does,
wouldn't, you know, before the fight,
everyone thought nick wasn't going
to go more than one round. You know,
he was going to get murdered
by the, you know, and
then nick puts on a great
performance. Anderson, you know,
Nick's hard to fight and it's
hard to finish, you know,
but then all of a sudden it's all he,
he's not the same guy. He's, he's,
he should retire. I just think that's
not fair for Anderson or for Nick.
Yeah, I agree. I think
Anderson did, like I said,
I think he did better
than Carlos condit did.
He did better than
George Saint Pierre did.
George essentially fought
him a little bit on the feet,
but most of the fight he took them down,
you know,
and tried to take them down
and control on the ground.
And Georgia is a very strong guy. He's
got real good top control. But you know,
Anderson stood up with him and
the entire fight was taking place,
kickboxing and I think
Anderson looked good, you know,
and especially when you come off to big
losses like that and your head's all
fucked up and you know, everybody's
calling on you to retire first of all,
the first fight had to
fuck with his confidence.
So hard to it did that cause he
was clowning and he got caught,
which is everyone's worst nightmare
because like when you're clowning,
you're trying to make fun of
your opponent and then boom,
you get cracked with a big left hook
and the lights go out and you're like no
way that way. Like to lose that
way after all those victories,
after the Vito Belfort fight,
after fucking up jail son and in the
rematch and after all those spectacular
victories against James Irvin
and Forrest Griffin. And so,
you know, to lose like
that, I was like, Holy Shit.
Yeah. I mean that's, that
was w going into the camp,
I was looking at stuff cause you know,
it was a really tough fight
for nick and uh, you know,
a lot of people didn't think he was gonna,
you know,
Forrest Griffin when the fight
first came out so that, you know,
it was just silly fight.
It wasn't, I don't know, I
wouldn't call it a super fight,
you know, he's just too
small for that, you know,
and I think a lot of people count or not.
But when I was looking
at Anderson's fights, um,
things that I noticed where people would
say he was showboating or whatever,
I think that when it didn't
go his way against, uh, uh,
Chris Weidman,
the first time he started,
he kind of broken mentally and
that's why he started showboating.
And I had done that in
the past and paid for it.
But ultimately I think that his style
is to bait people into coming so he can
use his reach and then catching
them a shot. So with Nick, you know,
my thing was you have to find that
middle range somehow, you know,
either get him to come at you or go
just enough that you're inside of that
middle range,
but not go all the way into the clinch
and get and get stuck in his clinch,
you know. And, uh, that was,
I think I had a lot to do with
nick baiting him to come forward.
And then I think I also messed with
a Anderson's head. No one's ever,
no one's ever clown to Anderson.
You know,
a lot of these guys go in there and they,
uh, one I think they get surprised by,
there's not prepared to fight that
level of kickboxing. You know,
they're not used to seeing that, that
level of striking, that speed, that range,
those, those moves. And then the
other thing is that they, uh,
they get out there and they're
like, I'm fighting, you know,
the best striker in the world.
This is the goat is the goal.
And I think that was a big
thing for nick was, you know,
I don't think nick police for a second
that he's the greatest fighter of all
time. You know what I mean?
And same thing with jail son.
And the first time he fought him,
chill,
fun for all this stuff that she'll said
chair really believed he was going to
beat Anderson Silva that night, which
is why he did beat him for, you know,
almost the entire fight until he got
caught. I think the second fight might be,
it was a little different,
but I think mostly the guys that he fought
didn't really think that they could,
they didn't visualize themselves winning
that fight and that gave it to Anderson.
Well, Anderson is a great counter striker
and that's always been what he's most
spectacular at. I mean, he will lead,
but most of the time he only does
it when he has a massive advantage.
Like the first couple of
rounds against Damien Maia,
like he was going after Maya.
But Damien Maia is like applauding guy
who doesn't have good strike where his
speech, especially back then,
it didn't have good striking.
But like if you look at like the tallest
latest fight or if you look at, um, um,
the Patrick [inaudible] fight, he likes
to lay back and let guys come to him.
And when guys just stand there
and wait for him to come,
the fights get really boring.
Like he,
he was involved in a few stinkers
everybody kind of forgot about.
And that was because he's not really,
he's not the attacking style of fighter.
Like,
there's some guys that just fucking
attack. They just go like rumble.
Like Anthony Johnson goes
after you bell rings,
he's charging at you throwing bombs.
Anderson has never been
that kind of a fight.
It's always been like
much more of a tactician.
And then there's always the
air of invincibility. Right.
But that air of invincibility is
gone. It's completely gone. Gone.
I think it's gone. It was so weird seeing
him like weeping after the fight too.
And then nick goes and picks him up.
That was pretty bad as you know.
And Nick was like, come on
man, you can't be crying. Yeah,
you're the greatest of all time.
You can't be crying.
You know, Nick and Nate, they get a
painted to be these like bad guys.
And you know, that's part of
the persona that, you know,
they promote and that that's all
well and good, but like they're very,
very respectful. But you know, when the,
um, uh, when nick beat Frank Shamrock,
he was on the ground after the fight and
nick reached down and picked him up and
said, you know, you're a legend. You can't
be on the floor stand up or whatever.
Yeah. And this is, but all
people see is, you know,
they go for the stare down at the
press conference and Netflix him off.
And frank shamrock grabs his balls.
But they're both very respectful fighters
and uh, you know, uh, I think they get,
they get a bad rap sometimes.
Well, he definitely gets
crazy before the fight and anxious and,
but that's to be expected.
And the shit talking. Look, son
Sue said it and the art of war,
you know, uh, Miyamoto Musashi talked
about it and the book of five rings ditch,
there's all sorts of things that go
on in a fight and, and any contest,
there's advantages to be had and there's
mental advantages that if you do not
take advantage of those mental
advantages and your opponent does,
you're at a disadvantage.
And when nick immediately
starts to fight and he's like,
he's got his hands out to, to
Anderson, like what Bitch, what pitch?
And he's walking towards him, come on,
what the fuck you going to do? Come on,
what are you gonna do?
And you see him talking like constantly
talking and you'd just see Anderson,
like people get flustered
when nick does that big time.
He does it in sparring to, does he
really? Yeah, he does look good.
My Mat Nicho was brought in
for actually the, uh, for, uh,
Nate's fight with violence. Roney
and when it got to the gym, uh,
Nate had hurt his neck or something,
was going to the,
had to go to the chiropractor
or something and they were like,
I'll just wait Nickleby here you can
spar with nick. And I was like, okay.
So like nick shows up and I'm a big
fan of these guys, you know, like just,
I was kind of like, you
know, a little struck and uh,
nick shows up and he's just,
yeah, I'm like totally coached
upon me. And I was like, so
are we going to spar it? We're
going to fire at night. He's like,
unifier right now, you know,
and it, but it was just like,
just like he walks into the
cage, you know, kind of like,
just look at me up and down kind of thing.
And then, you know, we, we sparked it.
It was really hard.
We had like a really good,
a really hard session and after
that he was like kickboxing, Huh.
So yeah, if you want to
hang out after, you know,
and we started hanging out
after that, but it was, uh,
it was very much like a like is, you
know, that's, that's who he is, you know?
It's uh, yeah. What kind of insight can
you give us to, why is he liked that?
Like what is, uh, what's
going on behind behind eyes?
Honestly, I couldn't, you know, I
spent a mix, a good friend of mine,
I couldn't tell you what the hell is going
on in his head. That's just who he is.
Um, I think he gets people thinking like
he doesn't know what he's doing or he's
crazy,
but I guarantee like he,
once you figure out and he knows
exactly what he's doing all the time,
like there was a plan, which they're
totally is, then, uh, you know, you,
you're worried about him sometime.
Like what'd he, what's he doing? Well,
he's an enigma and far it's like you look
at the way he behaves. You Go, oh, okay,
well this is like a thug was just treat
guy. And then you find out, oh no, no, no.
He's, he's on this incredibly
clean, organic diet.
He runs triathlons on a regular basis.
The fucking guy swims back from Alcatraz.
I mean, he's just an incredible
endurance athlete is not,
this is not like a dummy.
This is a very calculated guy.
Legit black belt in Jujitsu. Like
very, very good on the ground.
His boxing's outstanding. There's
too much good. There's too much.
Like too much preparation. Too much
discipline, too much intelligence in,
in the way he carries himself inside
the inside the, the competition.
He's not dumb at all. He's not
though. No, he's very smart.
And he's an enigma. Yeah. Some of the
stuff he talks about it, it's just like,
you know, I want to like take notes,
you know, like the Diet stuff.
He's always on me. My Shit. If I drink
rock stars in energy drinks, you know,
smoked cigarettes from time to time.
He's like, he's just very much not,
did the cigarette thing come from ty
from training Muay Thai because so many
ties, smoke cigarettes. Um, it started
when I was a kid, you know, uh,
my, my dad always smoked my, my
step, I'm over smoke. My brothers,
I'm the youngest of three.
They were smooth from Ohio.
Everybody was smoking back in the day.
And I just started when I was a kid.
And then I think when I started
doing kickboxing it was more like,
okay. Like there was other,
I guess I made excuses.
There was other people that smoke
cigarettes kind of thing. I mean,
I don't have a kid at all, but I'm not,
you know how often you smoke cigarettes?
I smoke cigarettes pretty
often. Really? Like right now.
He'd just woken right now while
you're in training? Yup. No Shit. No,
I like a pack a day. Uh, I tried to go
back, you know, when I'm having
fights, um, just because you know,
from running I'm training really hard.
But yeah, I'm a regular small group.
Cigarettes,
Jesus Christ job.
It's not a terrible,
I'm not going to hide who I am.
You know, some people do, uh,
have vices and whatnot,
but what's incredible is you fought
and I fucking glory tournament,
which was a brutal tournament
which I went to in La.
It was amazing that fight
with Simon markets. When I
went into the fourth round,
he caught him with that right hand.
First of all,
that is a fucking war for one fight.
But the fact that you had a fight three
fucking times in a night against world
class fighters like that,
Wayne Barrett and your next fight,
Jesus Christ and then Levon,
right leaven in the finals,
who's one of the best in the world. That
is a crazy fucking night of combat. Yeah,
it was. It was. It was nuts.
What the fuck is the next day feel like
you have to that man, it was terrible.
How many seconds does he smoke?
The next day I got a mannequin.
We let me say this,
so after this
man, don't smoke case cigarettes,
kids, it's bad for it. Don't smoke.
You don't smoke. It's really
not a joke. And like people,
you constantly hear shit from people
like Joe and Nick and all of the other
people that you don't, you don't get, um,
people don't want to
respect you as much weed.
He smoked cigarettes and make
dumb choices like that. And,
and the fighting community, you
know, it is a, it is what it is,
but will you have great cardio, which
is weird. I trained really hard.
I'm a very hard worker when it's
time to buckle down, like I buckled.
But how much of an edge do you think
you would have more if you didn't have?
I've thought about that for a long
time. I'm like, God damn dude,
probably would have more of an edge,
but like you might be the
baddest motherfucker ever
if you quit cigarettes. Uh,
well I don't think I'm that far off
from it now to be honest. It's true.
Pretty close. Pretty
close. Um, but, uh, yeah,
after I knocked out Simon
and the glory a tournament,
we're in the back dressing room and, you
know, they want me to lay down an ice,
me and all that stuff. And
I'm like, coach, let's go
outside. Let's go, you know,
you smoked a cigarette in my wedding.
I went outside after a Simon and I had
my hands wrapped and walking out in the
security's like, where are you going?
And be like, I'll be right back.
Smoke cigarette, calm down a little bit,
felt a little better. And then, um, yeah,
I felt it w it was such a insane night
that night after the Simon fight.
It was, I was really pumped,
but like I was banged up,
but it felt I was really on like this
high from beating him and he had beat me
twice in the past. And it was really a,
it was a big moment for me. And then, uh,
the Wayne Barrett fight was
just a really frustrating,
it was a really mentally challenging
fight. You know, his style really. Uh,
the first time we fought it
really frustrated me and I,
I did what Anderson did with,
um,
with Weidman the first time I kind of
cracked under like the frustration I put
my hands on my hips and you know, I
kind of gave away fights. What style?
Like describe his style of, it's
just very, it's very different.
It's almost like he makes it a piece.
He's got very strong box.
He's got heavy hands,
he's very, he's very big.
He was the first person
I fought at one 85,
where the guy that I weighed in against
and the guy got in the ring with for two
very different sizes, you know, and um,
that messed with me a little bit, but he,
he was running away. He,
uh, not running away,
but he was trying to use his movement.
And every time I would try to throw,
I just got really frustrated by him
not, not engaging me, you know. And, um,
that was something I had to
really learn from. And uh,
going into the second fight, I was
ready for that, prepared for it.
And I knew it was going to be an ugly
fight and it wasn't going to be, uh,
you know,
the type of fight that I really liked
that Simon is the type of guy I like to
fight. You know, I like to
be in essentially like a
war. Let's fight, let's,
let's get it on,
you know.
And Wayne was like stepping backwards
and put his foot on the rope and jumping
off the ropes and like doing
like a lot of weird stuff.
That was just frustrating for me.
So I had to stay focused in that fight.
And then I got the w I honestly didn't
know who won the fight because it was so
neither one of us were really scoring.
But you know,
after watching the video I see
that I want to fight. Um, and then,
so I had about 30 minutes after the
Simon fight before I got up for Wayne.
But after the Wayne fight, it was like
go in the back, change your gloves.
And it was, there was one
fight between us. It was,
I think it was like nine minutes before
I was back in the ring again and I was
walking to the ring and I
just kept thinking like, how
the fuck am I going to do?
Like what am I, this is like my
calling, like this is fucking crazy.
And it was in the back and
he was just like, don't,
how the fuck are going to do this dude?
Like my legs were just not at all up and
down. My face hurt from headbutts and,
and getting dropped when, when, uh,
Simon dropped me in the second
round and the first fight, um,
he hit me right on the chin and it
didn't really affect me mentally.
I never got rocked by it.
My legs went out right away and I felt
all of the punch, like in my neck.
It was like pop up and my neck and uh,
yeah, walking out to fight our Tim,
I was just really proud
that I had the balls,
I guess to do what I was doing.
Like I was,
I was more like in shock of what
I was capable of, but I didn't,
I really didn't feel like I had anything
left to win the fight. You know what?
I was on my way to the ring
and I was just really proud.
That's some archaic shit.
Those three fights in one night to get
world class fighters to fight three times
in one night. Like, uh, I went there
and I talked to Kevin K who you know,
is one of the big wigs over it. Spike and
I said, this is awesome. Like, you know,
the, the, this event is awesome.
These fighters are awesome.
It's so cool that you guys have worldclass
kickboxing go but fuck all this crazy
fighting three fights in one night. I go,
this is dangerous. This is not smart. I,
if you guys lose somebody because of this,
if someone dies like a worldclass
guy dies because of this,
you guys look like assholes. Like
don't do this anymore. Yeah. I mean,
I don't know if it's that
dramatic. I mean, I couldn't
be, if a guy gets through,
right.
It could be if you have a war,
if a guy has a war with another guy and
gets dropped three or four times in a
fight, like you know some fucking
George Foreman, Ron Lyle type shit,
what they just blasting each
the back and forth and one guy
manages to just get through by the
skin of his teeth and then he gets head
kicked and hour later by somebody else.
That shit is no Bueno. Right. You know,
and that is a possibility. Like
you fight, you should be able,
you should fight once in a night. You
know, you, you're, you're in camp,
you're training for a long time. I mean,
obviously you can do it, you did it,
but if you had a,
if you had your choice to be at your best
to fight a guy like 11 yeah. You know,
you want to,
you want to be at your best,
you want to go through a full training
camp and you don't want to have two
fights that fucking day,
nine minutes before you fight one
of the best kickboxers on earth.
And it's like when you're
going into that tournament,
both times that if I live in your,
your training campus for that first fight,
you know, and then in the back of
your mind somewhere, it's like, oh,
well if I get to the next round,
like if it could be this guy,
it could be that guy.
You kind of try to get some
sort of game plan for everybody.
But then the third fight after
that, you're just, you know,
I hadn't even thought about getting to
11 in that tournament or how I was gonna
fight him. It was beating Simon
who had beat me twice, you know,
and then beating Wayne and
then, you know, it was just a,
it was really tough and yet neither
one. I mean, it wasn't at my best,
obviously it was,
it was all beat up when I fought him.
So I think the fans deserve to
see, you know, same thing with, uh,
with the first time I fought a 11.
It was the second fight in a tournament
that we fought. And, uh, yeah,
it would be really nice to see really who
is, who's the best, who's the, you know,
on when they're on there.
Yeah,
yeah, that's true. Right.
The first time you fought him was
the second fight in a tournament too.
That's so crazy, man. And that turned out
was nuts because I was supposed
to fight Steve Wakeling,
which at the time was the
number two guy in the world.
And then I knew that I'd be fighting 11
in the final just because of his matchup
and a like six days before the fight
Wakeland pulled out of the fight and they
gave me Kingo Shimizu who I'd never
heard of who was like the Japanese,
a champion who used to fight a heavyweight
and was coming down to the middle
weight and uh,
you know,
I had like six days to watch tape on
him and try to figure out a strategy. So
11 such a slippery guy too. You were the
first guy to ever catch him like that,
you know, you had him really fucking
hurt. Like I thought he was done. Like,
Kudos to that guy for getting through it
because you cracked him and then on the
way down you caught him with a knee.
I think that knee actually will come
up to be honest. And why I watch it.
I was like, he was dropping like he was
out on the way down and then my knee,
I think it was like that second impact,
like kind of brought him back. But yeah,
I couldn't believe you got,
how weird is it that that's real.
Like guys had been knocked back, awake,
right, knocked out and then boom,
they get hit again and then all of
a sudden they're back in the fight.
It's very shit a lot in the UFC,
whether these guys are out limp and
then right when the ref breaks and there
they're going for a leg or they know
they're coming back to sort of, um, yeah.
You see guys had their eyes roll back
behind their head and then they get hit
again and it's almost like
they refocus like the,
the new jolt of electricity to
their brain, like clear, you know?
It's very weird. That's another
thing, like with the mean,
we've seen it with like Dan Henderson
and some of those fights were like, oh,
he's out.
And then he comes back,
or like a check Congo when his fight
with a guy, I can't remember his name.
The Guy Pat Barry. Yeah. Like he was gone
and then call it, came back and hit him.
You know. So Pat Barry fight with
Molly. Casa was hard to watch. Yeah,
that was hard to watch.
Padbury is a great guy.
I love that dude. He's
such a fun dude. But man,
he's had some rough Kaos over the last
couple of years where he had never been
KOD. And then he gets killed by Congo
and then it gets Kale by Lavar Johnson.
But the movie costs one was hard to watch.
That was hard to watch.
That was a hell of a shot. I like that
guy, Zach. He's a, he seems like a really,
really good guy. He's cool. I was
happy for him, but yeah, it was a,
he seems like a really good guy. Um,
but he's another one. Like he's not,
he's not built like a fighter. He's pill
like some crazy giant bodybuilder dude,
which is great for like around and a half
and then you get into the third round
or fourth or fifth did you find
a championship fight? And like,
you know what you saw, he fought, uh,
two fights in one night in
that last tournament. Right.
And in the second term he just was a
different guy. He's a different guy.
Like whereas you can be the same guy
for the first round as you can for the
fifth round.
Those big guys,
they w we were saying earlier about
cutting all that weight, right? They just,
when you have that much muscle to feed,
like there's, there's definitely benefits.
You could bum rush a guy and you,
you're just a machine for
as long as you have oxygen.
But there's that weird middle balance
where you're trying to find the
comfortable middle ground between
being ridiculously strong and being an
endurance athlete. Yeah.
Terry, so could you was a, have
had issues with that, right?
I mean, when he first came on
the scene in pride, he's like,
not like just who the
hell is this? Oh, Rona.
And knocks out Nogueira and then UFC
could see like he was really strong and
then he would kind of
fade and then later on.
So I think he has mental issues too.
I think there's a little bit
of a confidence issue too
when it comes to when you
talk to the people that have trained
with them and the people in this camp,
you know, sometimes guys
get through that, you know,
Vituro went for through a long stage
where I had confidence issues and he got
through that some, you know,
it's not insurmountable, but uh,
but yeah, definitely the
muscle have packing all that
muscle is not good for you.
It's just, it doesn't, it doesn't
help you know, it, it helps a little,
makes you really strong. If
you're a grappler, you know,
could certainly give you some
advantage. But those guys, man,
when especially when you're,
if you're built like that and
you're trying to fight five rounds,
now you're taking a crazy gamble.
Not Gamble is I'm going to get this
guy out of there in the first couple of
rounds and then you've got a guy like
we were talking about king the Alaska is
just, yeah, he's huge, but it has like
a ridiculous cardio, you know, it's uh,
he's just a, Freeman's are just so weird,
right? Yeah. They vary so much, man.
They vary so much. You know, you
get guys that like, you know,
you remember cabbage? Yeah. Back in
the old day, man, I love cabbage cat,
which was awesome.
It was awesome.
You could hit Kabbage with a fucking tree
that you could pull a tree out of the
roots and, and climbing off the side
of his head and he would smile at you.
You know, that guy could just take
this unbelievable punch. Yeah.
And that's just biological. He's just born
that way. Yeah. But it's like, you know,
somebody told me that it had a great
chin and they're, the, nick had a great,
somebody sits on by when a
great chin and I said, you know,
don't ever say that about me doing.
Then people start telling you,
you can take a great shot
or you have a great chain,
it means your defense is bad.
You know what I mean?
And they can only last so long. And
then you know, you see it one guy,
you can go take shots forever.
Then one fight later he cannot take a
shot and like chocolate dough chocolate.
Dell is an end. Dan Henderson, this
last fight against Musashi, right,
saucy hit him with a punch that Dan would
have eaten like a tic tac earlier in
his career and his legs go. Just
everybody's got a certain amount of holes.
Jermaine Taylor was like that. Oh yeah,
yeah. Go with public. Knocked him out.
He was fantastic. Boxers still hit all
the skills but just couldn't take a punch.
Anyway. Yeah, this is just a a point
where you reach where you're, you know,
and it's also how you prepare,
right? Like how much you,
how many shots were taken in the
gym, you know, and how are you,
how are we training?
Are you training smart defensively?
Some guys are just fucking full pedal
to the metal on offense. You know?
That's how they train. That's how
they think. That's how they fight.
And then when it comes
to defensive skills,
like they might have like an a plus for
an office but their defense might be
like a c, you know? And then
when it starts going their
way and they climbed up,
they don't know what to do.
They have to think instead of just
being instinctive and rolling with stuff
cause it's a natural part
of your everyday thing.
That's a weird thing about fighting man.
It's like how much emphasis,
especially when it comes to MMA,
how much emphasis to put on striking,
how much emphasis to put on grappling,
how much emphasis to put on your cardio
and strength and conditioning and how
much to put on skills. And I think that
a huge part of that that's missing.
I think in a lot of people or
even just in this conversation,
it's like the mental aspect.
You know, you can train perfect.
You could have a decent weight class,
you could do everything correctly and
that two hours before the fight from the
time you check in to the time
that you walk out in that ring,
if you're not mentally strong
enough and prepared for that,
you just don't perform. You know what
I mean? And uh, you know, was it,
was Anderson Silva that prepared for Nick
to, to lay down and start heckling him?
Most certainly, no, it was, uh, a
lot of the, so I think for me, I, um,
I hired a mind coach, uh, when I first
started with glory and has been a huge,
uh,
it's been a huge change in my career.
And when you see a mind coach
that's interesting that he's like,
it's not a like a sports psychologist.
You call it a mind coach. Yeah.
And what do they, what do
they do with you? Oh, he did.
His name's Vinny shoreman.
He's out of the UK. Um, he's
actually an announcer for, he's like,
probably one of the most active, uh,
kickboxing announced. He was in the world,
used to do k one and it's showtime.
Um, he's been around the kickboxing,
you know, for a long, long
time. Um, he does all kinds
of really cool stuff with me.
You know, I didn't want to give away
too many secrets, but he can. Um,
he does like it hypnosis me sometimes
does he live in the UK
and he lives in the UK
and like he'll hypnotize me
through facetime over the phone.
I swear to God it happened. And like
the first time he did it, like I hit it,
he would have been posting and I had
heard it and heard about them a little bit
and I had had some issues in the past
where like my worst performances were not
because I didn't train hard, it was
a mental thing, you know, and uh,
uh,
well the first time I started talking to
me like one of the hypnotize me and I'm
like, okay, yeah, sure. You didn't have
a thigh as me. And he's like, okay,
I want you to sit down and you know,
you're going to start feeling blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah. And as he's talking,
I'm like just quietly with my clothes
on with suits, so full of shit,
this is not going to work. This is
not gonna work, this guy. So dumb.
And next thing I know, I'm
like, Huh. And uh, you know,
it worked immediately and the things that,
the little things that he told me to do,
I immediately felt a lot better,
like a lot better and I
could see the difference.
My coach could see the difference.
And what's his background?
Is he a psychologist? Um, I think, I'm not
really sure how he got into that. It's a,
he does like a lot of seminars and
goes to a lot of things and studies,
a lot of stuff.
I don't really know his,
if he went to school for that
or what that is, but he's very,
very good at what he does.
He works with Liam Harrison and he works
at Jordan wants and he works with Julie
Kitchen.
He worked with Andy Housing.
Most of like the really high
level kickboxers overseas.
That's, that's, that is a very
important point. You know,
and I don't know how many guys
utilize a sports psychologist.
I know Anderson did a bit for this
fight after the Weidman fights
portant for him going in, stuff like
this. I'm going a lot of guys you like,
you bring it up and they
can immediately see it as a,
as a disadvantage that you even think
that you need help or that, you know.
But for me,
there's so many things,
like fans don't understand the amount of
pressure that a fighter is under going
into a fight and then to go into a fight
where the whole world thinks you're
going to lose. You know what I
mean? You have no chance. Like what?
Like me fighting Calculi I think I had
nine professional fights and you know,
he knocked out mighty Mo and he was a
Roger Dubliner and champion at over two.
Yeah, we don't, if you
don't know who he is,
he's a world famous Thai boxer
who was about 170 580 pounds,
flop mighty moe who was close to 300
pounds at the time and had kicked him and
it was just one of those ridiculous k
one match ups where they used to do in
Japan,
they love freak shows.
They love to put together no gear versus
Bob Sapp or Bob Saps 375 pounds and you
know,
they put a Bob Sapp versus even crazier.
They put Bob Sapp versus
Minoa who's like one 85.
So you've got to [inaudible]
pseudo versus a similar,
the Samoan Guy Kinky pseudo also fought,
um,
fucking the fat guy with the ball. A
butter bean. Yeah, I remember that. Yeah.
That show is ridiculous that we're
talking about more than a 200 pound weight
disadvantage and they go on the ground
and him on top of you and unbelievable.
Unbelievable. Yeah. I mean, but they
don't give a fuck. And Japan, they,
they want to put on Godzilla versus
King Kong. That's what they want to do.
They want to have ridiculous matches
and I want to watch Godzilla versus king
going, you know, I'm into that. You know,
sometimes they see like styles make
fights and like sometimes it's,
I mean obviously you want to see who's
the best of the best of the best,
but sometimes you want to see these other,
you know,
these two might not be
even in the top 10 but man,
they're gonna fucking get down. You know,
this is the fight to want to see. Yeah.
I mean look Bob Sapp versus Nogueira to
me still is one of my favorite all time
find it's cause it was so rich. The fact
you got pile drive in the first round,
which you never see in MMA.
It's kind of illegal.
It's illegal in the u s at least speaking
of illegal. Can we talk about this?
Joe? I think we've talked
about this. Sure. What's up
with all these guys smashing,
trying to stomp kick like Anderson did
to nick. You know, I kinda Nice. Yeah.
I just think it's a little shady
that you got to comes off as such a
catastrophic injury.
And the first thing he does
is start stomping away at
somebody else's kneecap in
a fight. Did you see the, um, the fight
with Miguel Torres, the kickboxing fight,
the recent Jamie pulled this up. Um,
Miguel Torres a need destroyed.
You'll,
you'll find it. It's legacy. Kickbox
it's a probably Gif. You can find it.
The gif file of it. It's
fucking horrendous. It's the
worst one I've ever seen.
He does this a,
the oblique kick and he does it right to
the knee on like the side of his knee.
His knee just, you see it get
destroyed. I mean, I just don't,
I just don't think that's, that's,
I don't think it should be illegal.
I just don't think he should be.
And I'm trying to knock somebody out.
I'm not trying to like actually kill
them. Right. And finish their career.
But I think if you started messing around,
because I've had two knee surgeries and
had to come back from it, it's just,
it bothers me to see
somebody intentionally tried
to check and knee joint.
But what do you think about
it then? Again, the arm bar.
So what about heal hooks?
Like if you see a guy like who's smart?
Paul Harris,
it was like it's heel hooks specialist.
I don't necessarily have a
problem with the heel hook.
I have a problem with a guy that holds
onto the heel hook after you tap multiple
times and then intentionally ripped
your leg off and then which he's done,
which really does, you know, I
don't really care for that. Yeah,
the helix particularly devastating one.
Hang on to it.
Like if you hang onto a choke,
you put the guy out with folks who don't,
who've never trained you, don't like, it's
not that bad to get choked unconscious.
I know it seems like it would be really
bad, but it really is just like a sh.
It shuts your brain off and then
turns your brain back on again.
It's sort of the best way to
describe it is like a garden hose.
You Pinch a garden hose,
it stops the water,
and then you let it go and then
the water keeps flowing through it.
It's not nearly as bad
as getting knocked out.
So holding onto a choke and
putting the Gar unconscious.
It's really not that big a deal,
but holding onto a heal hook,
you tear the ligaments apart and you're
talking about a guy who's going to go
through six months of Rehab Surgery,
the whole deal and then it might not ever
be the same thing I hear when you were
taken away guys livelihood for over
a year most likely just to what be,
you know,
you already got them to tap or whatever.
I just don't particularly go put, highrise
is kind of crazy. There's something,
something does a little bit of a mental,
you
know about his, his childhood, right. His
whole story is really heart wrenching.
I mean he grew up,
he was working full time from the time
he was like a little boy in a, in a farm.
You know that giant scar
that he has on his chest.
He got that when he was working and he
had a crazy glue it together cause like
they had no money for food. They had
no money for the doctor. Like he,
he used to eat pig slop
because he had no food.
Like he would eat like the food that
they would feed pigs. It's a, it's her,
it's horrific. So this guy, like he went
through some really horrendous shit,
like as a child in rural
Brazil, you know, in,
in intense poverty.
So I think it's hard to
get through that unscathed.
Most certainly hasn't. So I think
every fight that he has, man,
he's fucking fighting for his life.
Right. And if he gets a hold of your leg,
he could see this.
What's that?
It's loading up. Yeah.
Look at this. I mean,
he caught it sideways to Miguel was a
heavy on the front leg and he was almost
kinda like stepped in sideways.
Oh,
the dude caught it like just in the
outside. Look at that. Oh my goodness.
Oh,
I throw it like a similar kick to that
where I take the front of my foot and I,
it's almost like a slap kick and I
do it to the, the Shinbone, but it's,
it's not too to injure him,
it's to stop his forward momentum.
A lot of times when I do that,
their head comes forward
and I can throw something.
But to go directly in the knee joint,
I mean that guy through that
intentionally to do that.
I don't think there's any question that
he was trying to buckle his knee like
that.
Yeah, he did attack in the knee and
that's in lookout. Me, he's coming down.
Oh yeah.
Well it's actually Miguel was stepping
forward so his knee was off the mat,
like as it landed. See that?
Oh, it was kind of touching,
but he was coming forward
and the guy caught, yeah,
see his need came up and he's coming
forward and then it just went down on it
and just wrenched it across. Oh,
it's a horrible to watch. Ooh.
And that's, you're out for a year and
it might not have it be the same again.
If you come back. There are
two in this new thing now, man,
where they're three d mapping. Um,
your meniscus, they're taking this, uh,
this thing that they've created. It's
like a scaffolding. They three d map,
this scaffolding,
the insert it where your meniscus is.
And it has proteins in your body,
builds your own meniscus on it.
That's all.
So you're going to be able to rebuild
your municipal awesome cause you're
credible for years. That's been the
thing they can, they can't change.
If you tear your meniscus
like you're screwed.
That's really good that they can do
that. Well, they've Cartlidge too.
They've started to do
that with stem cells.
They've started to inject stem cells
into the area where people are missing
cartilage and cars, cartilage regrown
which is incredible. Yeah. That's awesome.
Yeah. They're doing PRP
stuff to where the, uh,
when we were with my knee
surgeries, they were, uh,
thinking about doing that with mine.
They didn't do a platelet
rich plasma is really cool.
And there's another thing that I've been
doing called Regena keen and Regena.
Amazing.
It's
the, that's the stuff that was invented
by this guy. I'm a doc, I forget his name,
but he's in, um, uh, in Germany
and he created this, uh,
procedure. We take the blood, they
pull it out like a lot of blood,
and then they spin it in a centrifuge
and heat it up. And when they heat it up,
it takes,
um,
the blood and the blood reacts to the
heat is if you have a fever and it creates
this amazing anti-inflammatory response.
This is yellow serum.
They pulled his yellow Sierra mountain
and they inject it directly into any area
where you have an injury and it's like,
like platelet rich plasma times a hundred.
It's so amazing. That makes sense.
It's like a, like the cold laser therapy
where they're like light therapy.
That's what they do. It means a lot. Yeah.
But therapists, you're essentially the,
the light or the heat,
uh,
triggers your body to send more blood
and nutrients and heal itself straight.
Keeping that stuff up and
injecting it back in, you
know? Yeah. It's amazing, man.
It's amazing science. I've had it done in
a bar I've had done on my knee, my neck,
my back, my elbow, my shoulder.
It's incredible. I've,
every time some shit's fucked up on me,
I just go right down
there and get shot up.
That you feel the difference right away?
Oh yeah. Man, my knee was fucking with me.
I,
I've had three knee surgeries and my knee
was fucking with me for like the last
couple of years. I was like, man,
I'm going to have to get this fucking
thing scoped again and I get it shot up
like five months ago. Nothing,
squats, kickboxing, nothing.
Just never fucked with me
anymore. It's weird. It's amazing.
So they can do incredible shit
now with medicine and science.
Thank God there's so many egg heads out
there that are just fucking pounding on
the keyboards and you know,
doing it in the lab and trying to
reengineer human beings. It's amazing.
It's like what Anderson and the and
Tyrone Spong that break like 15 years ago,
they would have like amputated your leg.
Like it would have just been,
that would have been that really me.
Yeah.
Somebody was telling me that
they used to amputate leg
if the leg snapped and like the, yeah,
they were, they said they would amputate.
But yeah, because of the, the something
about the tissue or something.
Just 15 years ago, something like
that. Yeah. That's hard to believe,
but don't quote me on that.
But yeah, that's what I heard.
Somebody might align with some bright
light to me. I'm pretty gullible. Well,
they probably used to have
to like Joe my line to us.
All right now by this gold stuff there,
the re-injecting, I don't know man. I've,
that stuff's a Dana white is the
one who told me about it. He, uh,
he had it done for his ministers disease.
He disease is something you have
in the inner ear and it would,
it was fucking with him his whole life.
He had surgery to try to fix it and he,
uh, he got shot up with this, uh,
the Regena Canon just bang, gone,
just goes away.
I wonder if that would have helped nick.
Nick a herd is a left elbow.
Hyperextended his left elbow and we were
training like maybe three or four weeks
before the fight and uh,
it really started messing with them
like the week before the fight. And, uh,
we were in Vegas and as manager actually
hit called Dana to find out what doctor
or whatever to go to, to get him a
cortisone shot into his elbow. And, uh,
like you wouldn't mean nick won't
even take Ibuprofen. I was like, dude,
take some Ibuprofen. He uh,
I think it was about, um,
when he used to cut really
easily back in the day,
I'll be proven is like a blood thinner
sorta thing or something that he makes
him bleed more or whatnot. But um,
yeah, he was having like he would,
we were walking around the hotel and like
if his arm would lock out and like he
would have to wait a second for it to
like click back. So it was TCIS Christ.
Yeah. Then you're going into a
fight where you're boxing is your,
your strong suit and you don't feel really
comfortable throwing your left hand.
So that's ridiculous. But yeah, I wonder
if that gold stuff for the helped.
Yeah,
but you got through it.
I mean he landed some good shots with
it so he definitely did well once I had
adrenaline starts flowing. Yeah,
that's what I was telling him.
Like you're not going to think about that
when, when you're out there. You know,
the Regena keen thing is all the rage,
like all the basketball players to Coby.
Brian gets it done.
All these different guys get it done.
Guys were flying over to Germany to do it,
but now they have an office in Santa
Monica and I think they have an office in
Dallas I think as well.
They have a couple of them that they're
opening up I think might be opening up
one in Vegas,
but they're opening up all over the
country because the response is amazing.
That's nuts. Yeah. We live in a weird
time. Science is amazing. It really is.
I just got done today. I was doing
cryotherapy if you'd done that yet.
I haven't done it.
I wanted to go to one,
especially after the last man standing
tournament. My entire body was messed up.
I had this, uh, it's still kind of
messes with me a little bit now.
But somehow along the line of
the three nights, three fights,
I got hit in the chest with something.
I want to say it was probably Simon
with one of those knees. But, uh,
my whole body hurt. And
then as the swelling and
everything started going down,
my fucking chest just started
killing your sternum and it was like,
then I noticed I had like this ball,
it was literally like a size
of like a tennis ball on,
on my chest is still square
is up a little bit now.
But it swelled up so much that it pinched
off all the nerves in my chest and my
arm would like, I'd have like a stingers
all the way down my arm and I'd wake up,
I mean for the first like
week or two after the fight,
I was like waking up in the
middle of the night, like shaking.
I would get a fever cause it wasn't so
much pain from the scenario stuff. And uh,
I guess I got like multiple X-rays,
thought my sternum was broken,
couldn't figure it out,
wasn't there was no break and they said it
was basically like, uh, you know, these,
you see these guys when they get hit in
the face or hit in the head and they get
these hematomas on their head and it's
just blood and crap that's stuck between
the skin. And the bone, what mine was,
I guess inside of the cartilage of
my rib or whatever. And you know,
even for the moment by when I would be
training Jiu Jitsu or it'd be working on
my chokes or somebody puts
their weight on my chest,
like it would swell up afterwards.
So I was taking Ibuprofen by like
the handful of there for a minute.
But it's doing a lot better now.
Yeah, the, the crown therapy would
probably helped out a little bit,
but I think that's just one of those
things it's going to yield to the crowd.
Therapy is awesome for recovery. Yeah,
it's amazing. I do ice baths. I mean,
I think the cryotherapy so much
shorter, it like a lot cooler, a
lot shorter,
and apparently a lot more
effective because you're
going 250 degrees below zero
for three minutes. Then you get out,
you get on an elliptical machine,
you warm your body back up and then boom,
right back in for another three
minutes. What's that feeling, dude?
It feels amazing.
You get out of there,
you feel like you could fucking
jump over the moon. It's amazing.
There's such a Wa it's wild. Like if
you could take that in a pill form,
people would just be fucking chewing
on him all day because most people are
scared of the feeling like fucking 253
it's really not that bad. It's really not.
It just kind of stand there. I mean,
I'm not, I don't even freak out.
It just kind of move around a little.
It hurts my nipples.
So I covered my nipples up when I do it.
I don't know why.
I don't want my nipples to fall off.
Not that I use them or anything.
They're pretty numb anyway, but they, uh,
that's the only thing that starts to like,
feel like really bad.
You'd legs get super cold towards the end,
but it's just three minutes, you know,
he's just kinda deal with it for three
minutes and then he'd get out and you,
as soon as you get out, you're like, Woo.
As soon as your body realizes it's back
in room temperature. Well the blood,
apparently the science behind it
is that your body real thanks.
This motherfucker's gonna
die. Okay. You just,
somebody just dropped you off at the
top of the world and it's a zero degrees
below zero and you fucking you,
you're going to die within moments.
So your body's all the blood
to your or to your organs,
try to protect your organs and then
once you get back to room temperature,
it pushes it all out and it creates
this amazing anti-inflammatory effect,
like all the soreness
that you have and just,
it just does a weird thing to your body.
But the energy that you get out of it,
I dunno, I dunno if it's an adrenaline
rush of your body, realizes like, hey,
we're not going to die. Life is beautiful.
Look, the sun is shining. I'm alive.
You know,
it's like when those things where they
say you don't really appreciate piece
unless you've experienced war, you don't
appreciate love unless the experience,
hey,
you don't know how beautiful it is to
be able to walk down the street and not
freeze your Dick off until you're
in tied one of those booze.
But there's a lot of physical effects.
We can try that. That sounds really cool.
You can research it online,
like all the different,
the like what they know about the actual
biochemical effect that it has on your
body. But people swear by it. Like,
again, like basketball players,
MMA fighters like Allen,
Joe Ban, uh, who's a,
one of our guys at 10th Plan
and he's in there every day.
Eddie Bravo does it every day.
It's just,
it's amazing when he was training
for the boiler fight too, especially,
he was in there every day. It's
just, it's amazing. It just,
it just makes you recover quicker.
But the feeling you get out of it.
I love the best. I will walk out of there.
It's like your whole body feels alive.
It's wild. Yeah. He wouldn't,
you come back, let me know. I'll,
I'll take you down there. Yeah, definitely
introduce you to those guys. Cool.
Science actually with, um,
with like cold therapy, uh,
after the last men standing tournament.
I was thinking about doing it.
I just didn't, I didn't, I don't
know why I didn't end up doing it,
but Nike makes a cooling vest that uh,
it's basically like the,
as all of these pockets or are we
out of his pockets in it and uh,
it keeps you like really cool.
So I was thinking after the fight of
putting that on because I found out that
like 70%, again, don't
quote me on these numbers,
but 75% of the your your energy system
misspent on temperature regulation.
So like if you had to have multiple
fights in one night, you know,
how much time are you wasting sitting
in the back sweating and the you're
wasting energy that you
need later on in the fights.
We were thinking about trying
to put, um, to use that,
that cold pack or were
those a cooling vest?
I think Nike came out with
it for the Beijing Olympics.
That's a great idea. You have two fights
this weekend? No, I just have one.
Which honestly it seems like,
you know, my coaches, I was like,
Holly and my cardio is not quite as
good as I thought it was. And he's like,
you only get a fight once. I
was like, oh, all right. Yeah.
It's hard to compare because
when you get and such,
I mean I was in phenomenal shape for that,
for that last men standing tournament.
I think I had like,
we found out about that fight I think
four or five months in advance and it was
going pretty hard for it the whole time.
And uh,
now when you have a camp like that, like
who, who like who structures you can't,
but who structures like
how much running you do,
how much strength and conditioning you do,
how much kickboxing,
how much striking with on the
pads, how many, like how do you,
how do you structure your
workouts? Um, my coach,
we'll do that, but um, have the,
for that camp it was like, okay.
Cause we had just came back from the
Wayne Barrett fight where he just seemed
like a lot bigger than me.
So it was like, you know,
I was fighting at one 75
before I signed with glory.
And then when I went to the Gloria,
it was automatically up to like one 87
and [inaudible] 86. And uh, you know,
the glory tinned tournament arts and 11
wasn't very big guy in English and music
worked out really well for me, so I
thought I was good at that, at that size.
And then with Wayne Barrett, he was just
so massive. Like he's just a big guy,
you know, and uh, so I
wanted to put on some muscle.
So we did a lot of strength conditioning.
Just I was doing like, uh, every day,
sometimes twice a day I was doing,
I'm going to La fitness with my
buddy and doing like a body strictly
bodybuilding stuff, no
cardio, just uh, I was taking,
I think he was shooting for like
3,500 calories a day, which is just,
I would feel lethargic and
just exhausted all the time.
And I did that for a few for a few months.
I think I got up to about two 15,
which was really big for me at the time.
And then the last,
I think it was probably
the last like five weeks,
I stopped with the strength conditioning
was just focused on speed and trying to
get, trying to get used to that size that
I was and I trimmed down quite a bit,
but um,
it was like build the muscle bulk up
and then get fast and loose and then go
into the tournament and then my cardio
and my speed and everything kind of comes
in the last four weeks.
Yeah. Some guy, there's a lot of
guys who like to do that for MMA.
Like they take off from a fight and then
once they're done they get out of camp
before they saved. They know they
have a five, four or five months away.
They'll do nothing but
strength and conditioning, no
fight training, no sparring,
you know, know getting hit, no grappling.
They just lifting weights and just like
jumping boxes and doing all kinds of
pliers and shit like that.
That was the first time
I'd ever done that,
that I really focused on the
strength and conditioning stuff.
And then when I did start,
um,
when I stopped with that and I
started doing the runs and stuff, uh,
nick was actually in town and we
went for a long run at Venice beach.
I think we were at
Ronda as house that day.
And we went for like this long run and
we did like six mile run and I felt
really good. And then
I was like, hey, let's,
let's hit these sprints on the way
back and there's like bathroom,
and then it's like 200 yards, even another
bathroom or whatever. And he's like,
okay, we'll run to that, to that next. Uh,
the next bathroom we'll split. And like,
I couldn't, I was just in shocked
at how many gears I had. I was like,
I'd never ran that fast ever in my
whole life. And it was, we had really,
it was the difference of that time that
I had booked up and really worked on the
strength conditioning and then the
period of, of cutting down and getting,
leaning, getting fast again. And I was
just very, very explosive. And it was,
it was really good sign.
I smoked Nikkia you listen to this,
Nick beat you. That's, that's interesting.
So this is like that's a direct result
of all the weightlifting and all the put
on muscle and strength.
That was the first time I really noticed
a big difference cause I always really
hit hard. I mean I think I've always
hit really hard. Um, but that was,
that was something I really noticed was
my, my explosiveness out of my legs was,
it was definitely a lot better.
It's weird that for fighters it seems
like every training camp is almost like a
science project.
What you're trying to figure out what is
the right mixture and also back to the
mental thing. I think that that's
um, you know, I always say like,
I'm trying to get like the tip of like an
Arrow, you know what I mean? Each fight,
I get it kind of closer to
that and then you know, you,
you make a mistake or whatever.
I'm trying to get to the pinnacle
of like mentally focused,
you know what I'm saying? The perfect,
perfect, perfect, perfect edge.
Do I get too pumped up before I,
if I was at too cold, was I flat?
Was I thinking about the right things?
And you know,
that's what my mind coach really helps
me is there's so many things going on in
my head and he just tells me the
right things to think. And you know,
a lot of it is also like the way you,
the way you talk to yourself or about
yourself, the way you describe yourself.
You know, I used to say
stuff like, uh, you know,
I have really good punches
but my kids aren't that good.
And he told me like, Hey,
you got to stop saying
that stuff. I'm like, well,
my kicks were there aren't that
good and well, you kind of self, uh,
self sabotage yourself. You, you only
allow yourself to get as good as you,
you talk about yourself. That makes sense
at all. Uh, define you. Define Yourself.
That's why I call it like mint, like mind
coaching instead of like psychological,
you know, psychologist or whatever.
It's just like my coach tells me, Hey,
you're dropping your hands or
you're doing this or doing that,
or you need to focus on this,
this and this.
My mind coach is doing the same thing.
And I think that like the, I don't know,
I think everything is really
come, um, the stars, so to speak,
of all kind of aligned for me in the
last, last couple of years. You know,
I feel like I'm, I'm at an
age now, I'm just turning 31,
although I guess I can't
change my Wikipedia page now.
Why was it say it says I'm 31 I
was going to change it to like 26.
I don't do it. It's a slippery
slope. I know guys that are
40 something they'd tried
to stay there 30. Yeah, it's
fucking ridiculous. I think,
you know, I've reached an age
and my career where I just, uh,
I'm a lot more mature. I'm a
lot better athlete, you know,
it seems like everything's
kind of lining up now.
And I have the right coaches behind me.
I built with my coach Mark
Comoros and so I was a,
so it was fighting an amateur fights,
you know,
he's taken me throughout my whole career,
so that's great.
Well that's a guy who knows you really
well done. The Yard in ll where?
Where's the yard? Uh, it's in Lincoln
Heights, right? Announced right outside.
It's on the Avenue 26. It's right where
the five and the one team, one 10 meat.
So it was like downtown area. That's
basically downtown. Is it? Oh,
that's a bitch to get to it.
It the fucking traffic's a,
I kind of live in that general area.
Like I live in Alhambra,
like South Pasadena area,
so it's not too bad for me.
I was living in downtown for
a long time and then my, uh,
my son started going to schools
and I was like, you know,
I'd rather have him in a little
bit of a school system. So yeah,
the best school system we could,
you know,
the best school system I think is like
a orange county, but we couldn't quite,
didn't quite work out for the best
one we could find was Alhambra,
which is like South Pasadena
is really nice quiet area man.
I love it there.
Pasadena was like apparently back in
the day when Hollywood was sorta first
created in the 20s or whatever,
the uh,
the stars would fucking booze it up and
do blow in the Hollywood hills and the
producers are like,
let me get the fuck Outta here.
And then they set up shop in Pasadena.
That's why she didn't go by Pasadena.
There's these giant estate to house man.
Got Some amazing houses in Pasadena. I
fucking love Pasadena. Yeah, it's nice.
There's some, there's a gem. Isn't
there like a sit you'll tongue,
you're talking as a Pasadena?
Yeah.
It's got a kickboxing gym isn't around
for a long time. We tie. Yeah. Yeah.
La is a weird spot where you would think
there'd be a lot more like top level
MMA gyms in this area when there
are, yeah. There really is a,
you know, there wasn't a whole lot
it's written like in Hollywood,
it was like legends. It was like the
only MMA gym for a long, long time. Yeah.
And uh, yeah, who legends
went under and then you know,
you've got some stuff down in Orange
County. Of course you've got rain,
you've got kings, but yeah, Timo Yama.
But there's no like Jackson's MMA,
he got like world champions training
in one facility that's like this center
spot. It's almost seems
like for a lot of places,
like it might actually be better to be
in a small town and bring the guys in and
then of course you're going to have less
distractions and less bullshit if that
happens. Right. But la doesn't have
a lot of great kickboxing either.
There's not a lot of different
spots for as many peoples.
There are 20 million people. Yeah.
When I moved out here from Ohio,
it was to pursue kickboxing.
It was because uh,
Los Angeles and California
was the like, uh, the,
uh, center for kickboxing in
this country, you know. Um,
it was the only show that
only played with him.
But I was moved out here when I was 19.
Um,
they were the only ones putting on a
sanctioned Muay Thai fights was Dennis
Warner and vote vote promotions.
And
uh, but there's a really good
gyms in, um, in Van Nuys there's,
there's a really good gym and um,
north Hollywood,
two or three in north Hollywood, there's
a Santa Clarita has got really good gym.
So, you know, I think that, um,
there's a lot of of Moyie Thai here in
southern California and I think that's,
you know, when I was fighting it and
amateurs and smokers and, and um,
the smaller shows here in California,
it was,
it was the amateur was a very high level,
you know, very high level. And, uh,
I only had, I had, uh,
I was 23 and one is an amateur and
most of those were smokers,
just local amateur fights before Wipro.
So many Jujitsu schools here. That's
what reduction Jesse's, it's crazy here.
Right?
It's amazing.
When you compare Jujitsu to all the
other martial arts is may be like,
it's almost like 10 to one is like how
many Jujitsu gems and then world class,
you know Hickson's here, crones here,
John Joc Machado's got to gyms here.
He gets got a gym here.
It's like on and on and on.
You can keep going over and over and
over this so many fucking worldclass
Jujitsu schools here because Brazilians,
they like the song and they want to
be near the beach. You know, it's like
this is the spot that gravitate to this.
Agree with them.
It's amazing how much that's
changed in this country. You know,
when I first started training
in [inaudible] 96 there
was a small handful of
black belts in the country.
There was just not that many
like worldclass places to train.
Now they're everywhere.
Every city you go to,
there's a legit black belt that's
teaching classes and you know,
there's places that have hens.
I was kind of like 500 plus
students in New York City.
You know that in New York City's
another hotbed. It's like, you know,
there's Hendo and Marcello Garcia
and you know, on and on and on,
you can just keep going.
There's just so many gems there.
But when it comes to a place where you
have like a legit worldclass MMA training
facility, like an Aka, you know, there's
still not that many of them. Right.
You know, and especially when you look
at California, you would think, man,
you know, this is like so much
kickboxing, so much Jujitsu, so much MMA,
like you know, are so much, uh, you
know, so many fighters but not like one,
like it's a big central spot.
And then the ones that it's like,
it must like, you like team Timo,
you has got like Ian and,
and most of their, their team
has, I was a lot smaller,
you know what I mean?
I was going there for a long time and
he's trained with Shane del Rosario, um,
before he passed away.
And, uh, after he was gone,
there wasn't a whole lot
of guys my size down there.
So that's an issue for bigger guys to
write big, especially for heavyweights.
It's really hard for heavyweights to
find good training partners and find a
skillful guy that's above 225 pounds.
It's just, it's not that many.
Right. I think alliance has got a
good, it's a good team. Dumb Go. Right.
They're pretty good guys. They
got some good guys, you know,
of course a Aka has called me
a and a and cane. There's a,
there's some good guys there. I called
him and doing really well. It leads to,
yeah, yeah. Rock holds
a beast. Yeah. This, uh,
this is an interesting time because people
are still trying to figure out how to
train correctly for MMA.
You know,
it's like you've got a lot of guys that
are still holdovers from the early days
where they would get together and
try to figure it out and slug it out.
And there was a lot of like unnecessarily
hard sparring or unless they're a hard
not smart sparring and then,
you know,
people were still trying to figure out
like what's the best way to go about it.
And then you have people
that have figured it out,
like the Aka sort of figured it out or
the American top teams where they have it
down to a science, you know,
but there's just not that many.
Whereas like if you look at any other
major sport, look at baseball or football,
like they have protocols like
strength and conditioning protocols.
We put all their athletes through and
there's been programs cause they'd go
through from high school to
college to the pros. Like they,
they know like state of the art.
This is what we're supposed to do.
This is the best way to recover.
This is the best way to start to
train strength and conditioning.
This is the best way to do this with
MMA also, there's so many skills,
there's so many things to learn.
It's like,
it's one of the most
interesting things about MMA,
but it's also one of the things like,
man, what do you concentrate on?
Uh, that's a really good point. You know,
with me transitioning over to
them and May, it's, it's, uh,
it's one thing I'm really enjoying
is there's so much, you know,
never done kickboxing for so long where,
you know,
I don't know everything there
is to know about kickboxing,
but I feel very at home and if I get
in good shape and my coaches are just
sharpening me of, uh, keeping me fresh,
I think I can get it in a kickboxing fight
and, uh, just react naturally, you know?
And with him it may,
it's still,
I'm still learning and
still thinking about things.
And a lot of times I remember what I was
supposed to do, like 10 seconds after,
you know, I got tapped out, I should've
done this or did that, you know, so,
but it's a lot of fun to,
uh, to be evolving and keep
learning new things for me,
you know,
and there's so much stuff to learn and
so many different styles and different
ways to win.
And that's when really beneficial for
me working with nick and Nate as they
think about it. So, so analytically,
you know, like, Oh, you know,
going on top, going on bottle, I'm
like, if this doesn't work out,
then you're ended up here. And you
know, it's uh, it's really interesting.
D is it difficult cause you're doing both?
He just fought Melvin Manhoef in a big
a MMA fight in Bellator and then you go
on from that and a couple months later
you're finding in a big kickboxing event.
Is it difficult to do both at the
same time? I'm, I'm going to find out,
you know, uh, I right now it's,
it's, uh, I'm living the dream.
I feel like I can be really successful
in both right now depending on the,
the right match ups, you know,
I don't think, um, you know,
I don't think I'm going to a contender
for a title in MMA just yet. Um, but, uh,
yeah, it's uh, you know, there's things
I have to remember not to do, uh,
for both. You know what I mean? If I
knock somebody down in new and May,
I don't walk away and write eight count.
Mark Hunt,
he's the king of the walkaway Kao in MMA.
It was funny when I knocked
out with Melvin, um,
I felt the walkaway like I needed to
do though I knew it was out, but, um,
my coaches and my coach and my manager
were very adamant that that the night of
the fight and then like the week of that,
like this isn't, this isn't kickboxing,
there isn't going to be an eight count.
If you drop him, make sure you go over my,
finish him, you know, like
you need to finish right away.
And so like I hit him with like the hook
cross w I didn't even know I hit him
with the left hand.
I thought he,
I thought it was just the right
hand until I saw the video. And, uh,
I saw him go down and you know,
he's going down with his hands up and I'm
like one of to walk away and then like,
there's like this voice in
my head, like, oh, finish
golfing. And yet, and I went to,
went to go in and uh,
uh,
Mike Belcher had jumped in the
way and then I was just like, ugh,
totally ruined my walk up
and just walked off. Right.
Yeah. Pull that up. Jimmy Joe
Schilling. Kaos Melvin Manhoef.
That was a big fight for you because
there's been that that Guy Melvin Manhoef,
his um,
his style is terrifying.
Like people are terrified of that guy
because first of all, he's black as coal.
He looks like a fucking superhero.
He comes out throwing bombs,
knocked out, Mark Hunt
with one punch. I mean,
he's a terrifying and it's
strikes like 12 minutes long.
Everybody.
Like the week of the fight,
everyone's like Joe Shillings fighting
this guy and they tag me in it.
Like every time I checked
Facebook or Instagram or Twitter,
it was like people reminding me that
I'm fighting, you know, this guy.
And it was just like knockout,
knockout, knockout. You know,
he's got the highlight reel
of death. Yeah, he's a,
it was a really big fight for me.
It was a really tough fight from me to,
you know, I had a, it was a really bad
camp. It was probably the worst camp.
My career, my dad had passed away
like three weeks before the fight.
Then like two or three days after that.
Why does that look so shitty, Jamie?
My cousin passed away so it was
pull it back.
So is it our computer that's doing that?
It's drags cause the computer. Why is
it, but come on man. This is fucking,
it's a youtube video. Is it really that
bad? What do we got to do to fix that?
Tell him whatever we have to do to
fix that. Let's fucking fix that.
Cause this is pissing me off. This
looks like shit. Can't even see it.
Boom.
Damn.
There's that dude's been flatlined a
bunch of times over the last few years.
It's a those Dutch guys.
A lot of fucking tough guys in Holland.
Man. Lot of tough kickboxers
in Holland. It's like,
I think of them almost like a kamikaze
fighter. It's either like can be killed,
but that's why I'm a fan of it. You know?
Who doesn't want to watch a moment, man.
I'll fuck. Yeah, no, I'm a huge fan.
Mike's gym producing some goddamn savages.
Bought her Hari. He's a God damn savage
to what did, what is he doing these days?
Is he going to jail again
or what's happening? Sure.
Out what his, uh, his, uh,
what that situation is. But I think
he's based training for a fight.
I think he's fighting in
a global fighting, um,
championships and Russia or somewhere now
these, and I was fighting glory. He's,
I don't think that'll
hasn't glory get that guy.
I asked myself the same question. Fun
heavyweight. He's a fun heavyweight guys.
One of my all time favorites. So
yeah, that dude's a mad. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm not sure he's going to pass
any piss tests, but he's a,
he's a mad dog and a lot
of fun to watch that.
That's kickboxing scene is
not one for Piss test. So
yeah, that's, that's one
good way of putting it.
I think America's the only country in
the world that really drug tests their
athletes. You know, especially
with fighting, you know,
I don't think that there's any drug
testing and you know, one's are paying.
There was definitely in
the drug that was in Japan.
They drug test you to make sure you're
doing steroids to make sure you're doing
yeah. Make sure I have a
friend who, uh, was, uh,
it was a natural, I mean he should
have been fine. One 55 and uh,
he was going over to Japan and they
wanted him to fight one 85. Yeah.
They were like, you know, you're
a big guy. Let's do some juice.
Let's get you pumped up.
And he was like, what?
He leads used to deal with American
promoters where they never said that.
Then they sat,
they sat them down and flew him out there,
sat them down and they essentially told
him to get on steroids. What did he do?
He did. He did. He wound up finding
an America, but he went over there,
you know, and had the meeting and he had
one fight over there and they, you know,
they liked him but they
wanted him to go up.
Think he fought over there
at one 60 and they, uh,
they wanted them to fight one 85. Like
what the fuck are you guys talking about?
I mean, it's one thing if you're like,
you're a big guy already and they're like,
oh, we want me to go up and wait.
So yeah, you're really good. But uh,
we want you to put on 20 pounds
of muscle on fight. Well,
I think in Japan they feel like the larger
weight classes are the ones that sell
the most. And I think that was
their, their, their thought process.
He's a good looking guy. They
feel like this guy give, put them,
puts a big muscles on him, we're
going to make some money. You know,
they're definitely not thinking like, Hey,
for your career, this is the best move.
Right? Or your safety. Well,
you hear those stories about the
Yakuza back in their pride. Glory days,
giving you bowling ball bags filled with
money. I heard a few stories like that.
They show up at a,
you know your hotel room the night before
the fight with like grocery shop. Yeah.
Bags full of money. What guys?
I'm take them back with them.
They would be taping rolls of money to
their body because you're going to take
$10,000 or something back.
So they'd be literally taping stacks
of money to their body to try to get
through security voice had like every
member of his entourage had to hold like
$10,000 to go on the plane to go back
after. Yeah, but try explaining that.
So you traveled with this dude and
he's got 10 grand to and this guy,
well no coincidence.
She's got 10 grant.
How's this going to have 10
grand to what did you guys do?
Fucking find some money over there.
Like what the hell happened in Japan?
No taxes for that. The glory days. It's a,
that's a beautiful thing
about this sport though,
that the glory days were only like a
decade ago. Right. You know, it's like,
it's so young,
22 years since the UFC was first created,
it's hard to believe and that those guys
in the glory day are still competing
now. You have a lot of them. Yeah.
So is your plan to see glory days
and you're fighting and glory?
I would love it if glory became really
successful because I'm a huge fan
kickboxing,
but I don't know. I mean
how, how successful was their
pay per view venture? Uh,
the piggery venture, I didn't think, I
don't think I did very good at all. Um,
but I think it was more about
us, like a, a strategic thing.
Like if you give away your product
for free all the time, then it's,
it's hard to ever establish, okay, now
you have to pay for it. And you know,
so I think they did that as more of like,
it needed to do a pay per view,
but they're put repeat
buys weren't that great.
Which I think was kind of unfortunate
because that was like the end all be all
for a combat sports in one night. You
know, you gotta put that on Spike TV.
I think that would have done huge
numbers for building their brand,
but they had a great,
you know the other thing they did on that
was they had two cards one at one time,
so you have, you know, cro
cop was the main event on the,
on the card at that was live on spike
TV and I think it's just hard to get
people,
I mean I love kickboxing,
but I'm not going to watch it for an
hour and a half and then pay another 60
bucks to watch it for another hour
and a half hours a night. You know?
I think that was just a, well
they tried the UFC, the strategy,
the way the UFC has the prelims on Fox
sports one and they have the main boughts
on paper view afterwards. They
tried that strategy, but the UFC,
it's just way more established.
I think it's really hard to do that with
kickboxing because for the most part,
most of the people that are watching have
no idea who anybody fighting is. Right.
So you watch now shilling except Joe
Schilling and uh, whoever he fights.
But if you watch the UFC, you're, you're,
they're prepping you for the big stars.
But they haven't really established Gloria
enough to have big stars yet. But man,
I level of kickboxing is so high and it's,
it's,
it's got a frustrating because
you know, for the, for the, uh,
what do you call like the, the new
fan. Even for him, it may, you know,
you still get people like all,
what's this boring stuff on the ground
that don't appreciate the sport.
They just want to see the, you
know, the action or whatnot.
Like those people need to tune
into kickboxing. You know,
those people need to eat paint rep,
they all need to eat, lead, paint,
go fuck themselves. It's just
so many, this whole fans,
that's the one thing that
does disappoints me so bad.
When I go on Twitter and I read like a
fighter will post something, you know,
after the fight and you
read all the people talking
shit about them and just oh,
fucking rice to man,
there are so many douche bag and it's,
it's kind of worse for him
and May, you know, uh, yeah,
obviously like there was a
lot more exposure from my
fight with, um, with Melvin.
You know, I always knew that there was a
bigger fan base for MMA then there was a
kickboxing, but I had no idea
how much bigger it was. You know,
when I won the glory a glory 10,
that was the first American to ever win
a global combat tournament ever. And uh,
it was like a huge deal.
It was the biggest pay day I think
of American kickboxing history.
And I think there was like three
stories down on me about it total.
And then my fight with
Melvin was, uh, you know,
it wasn't for title or for ranking and
you know, it was just the one fight.
And you know, it's, it's been all kinds
of publicity and more following from that.
But like within like two days,
there was people on
my Instagram like just
writing the most degrading,
disrespectful shit about like my family
and my mom and my just ridiculous stuff.
And then, uh, so you know, you get more
fans, you get more in a whack jobs,
but there definitely seems
to be a little bit more um,
ignorant fans that did hang out
trash and people and even may,
there's just so many dummies in this
world to get Terry, right? Yeah.
And they have, they have an outlet to
reach you. Where's before, you know,
they would just be yelling at each
other at the gas station. You know,
they're going to go into a wall.
He ain't going to hold our
kicking [inaudible] ass.
And that's where it would end right now.
These,
these delicate tweet directly at me,
they have an Instagram and they get on
your page and you should leave these
posts. You read them, you just go,
fuck man. Imagine if, you know,
someone came from another planet and they
were trying to understand what people
were like and they read comments on
Instagram, right. They'd be like, well,
we got a nuke, this fucking thing. Nuke
this thing from orbit. It'd be like,
like that movie aliens.
I've got a new kit for more,
but just to be sure like these assholes,
these guys have bombs and missiles and
this is the way they think, you know?
It's not indicative of the,
the best example of humanity,
especially combat sports. There's
something about fighting, well,
it kind of sports in general, man,
I've been, I'm not a sports fan.
I don't pay attention
to football or baseball,
but every now and then I
will read like comments,
sections on blogs just to see
like if they're the same as like,
and it's the same shit. Same
Shit. What's up? Yeah. He got
a seven in the morning and
that's a desperado cocaine move.
I test that motherfucker
immediately fired from ESPN.
Did they fire up immediately fired from
ESPN. That's hilarious. That's hilarious.
Did she give him a raise?
At least she's not raping anybody.
It's trying to get a hook is trying to
pay for it. Give the man a break. Ugh.
That's the worst possible. Like
what? What could be worse than that?
Prostitution was getting
caught picking up prostitutes.
They shouldn't even be a big deal.
That's the guy's trying to get a massage
on his dick. That's all it is. I mean,
look, if, if it's seven o'clock in the
morning, he was trying to get a massage.
Nobody would bat an eye. You're trying
to get somebody to touch you for money.
That's what it is, but oh no, they're
touching the bath. Bought the Nadia.
Ooh, this is crazy. You know if you had,
if you paid a woman to the sock on the
back of your neck, nobody. We'd be like,
ah, okay. Yeah. I paid her 1000
bucks a suck on the back of my neck.
People would be like, okay, all
right, we'll get an that's seems okay.
We checked the rules. That's all right,
but I paid her to suck my Dick. Fuck it.
Why did you say, why would you do
that? You're fire. It feels good.
What did I do wrong? I don't know. She
needed 1000 bucks. I need a blow job.
Who got hurt here? I'm so fucking
confused. Well, the sponsors,
the sponsors won't tolerate it. Joe
Schilling, we need to sell Gatorade.
We're not selling blowjobs. It's
fucking ridiculous. It is fucking,
we live in a goofy,
goofy babyworld.
This is an infant tile
world guy gets arrested.
Fucking soliciting prostitution. Who's
was, did he hit up a cop or something?
I don't know that I had heard the
whole story. I was hoping you knew.
Do you know what happened? Jamie? You
should know you're the gossip monger.
He admitted to, I guess
the girls said that, uh,
he was assaulting them two girls. Oh.
And then when the cops came for that,
he admitted to the solicitation
of prostitution, but not
the, not the assault.
Oh, so he's a douchebag. All right. I
take it back. Yeah. She know what man, if,
if there was like a legit establishment
where he could go to and just give them
money and it just, to me, look,
I have daughters and the last thing I
would ever want is my daughters to be
prostitutes.
However,
I believe that part of our issue that we
have as human beings with prostitution,
it's just this weird puritan view of
sex that sex is somehow or another this
forbidden evil thing.
It's just two people
touching each other's bodies.
No babies are getting eaten,
you know,
and then no fucking slaves
are getting whipped.
No one's getting tossed off cliffs.
This is not a horrible thing.
It's fine if you do it for free,
right?
No one has any problem
if you have sex for free.
The idea that if you give someone money
and you have sex all of a sudden is this
terrible, awful evil thing.
I think that's stupid.
I think it's stupid and it's,
it's archaic in this world that we live
in is changing and people are starting
to realize that adult human being,
look,
you got a fucking hundred years on
this planet if you're lucky. That's it.
It's just this wild ride of good times
and hopefully friends and good food and
lump wonderful life experiences and who
the fuck is anybody to tell you that
paying for sex or someone paying
you for sex is bad? I mean,
who is that?
Who are those people?
But those are the same assholes to
tell you shouldn't pay for weed.
He shouldn't be able to smoke weed.
The same assholes that tell
you you shouldn't be able
to do psychedelics or you
shouldn't be able to whatever the fuck
it is, if it's not hurting anything,
Nancy graces of the world.
That's it. That's it.
Did you see her have a interview
with two Chainz? Oh my God,
I was so like, first of all, someone
stole one of two chains chains,
cause he only had one chain on. I was
getting the whole video. I was like,
where's the other chain?
Motherfuckers got one chain.
You can't call yourself two chains
and have a fucking debate on CNN. Sir.
You need to use your goddamn birth
name. All right, I need to see it.
Fucking birth certificate,
driver's license, two Chainz,
two chains. You know, I'm
not, not, my name's is Joe
Schilling. It's crazy donkey.
You know, if, what would your rap name
be? What would that wrap? Maybe? I Dunno.
Would it just be, this is can't stop
crazy. I guess. So this cancer, what did,
where that slogan can't stop crazy
come from? That actually came from a,
I think it was my second pro Muy Thai
fight. I just kind of went berserk and uh,
with elbows and knees and one of the
guys that train in my gym was like, aw,
you know,
you can't stop crazy.
And I just remember thinking that it
was the dumbest thing I've ever heard at
the time. Dude. Later on. Um, uh,
there was a time when before glory,
before lion fight got a TV deal,
there was a kickboxing and the
shoulder shows that I was fighting on.
The fans didn't really have any connection
to any one of the fighters unless you
went to every show.
So there was,
it was really hard to set
yourself apart as you know,
the high level guy or the better guy,
like who was really doing it, you know,
because there was no media in bottle
and uh, me and like the other, um,
five or six best kick boxers
and the United States got
together and started like
our own website and started
promoting ourselves. And we are got,
are the best photographers in the sport
and kind of just built our own media for
ourselves. And um, you know, eventually
lion fight gone, got a TV deal and um,
you know,
glory came,
but for a long time it was just us
kind of making it for ourselves.
And we're like, what do we call it? And
it was like, oh, can't stop crazy. Okay,
that's cool. There's kind of a movement.
It really kind of took off. It's,
it's weird.
I can't even describe what it is now.
People always ask me to describe it.
It's just a group of people that, uh,
we sell t shirts and we used to,
uh,
do our own interviews and
with no TV backing, you know,
there was nobody promoting us. You know,
these are the shirts right here. Some
you could wear this, this is 100%
douche free. No one would have any idea.
Note the lack of skulls.
Yup.
There's no swords going through a broken
skull with a snake wrapped around it.
There's no pit bulls getting
fucked in the ass by a dragon.
It's still actually a juror.
If you're listening or
designer, I would like a shirt
made with a pimple getting
fucked in the ass by a dragon
in glitter glitter and that's
going to be the Joe Rogan show.
Some Japanese foil writing behind,
you know? Yeah. I don't know man.
The uh, the world of [inaudible]
dropped off pretty quick.
I remember that was like,
I wonder why
Ed Hardy was like, it
was like a, what was it?
It was like von Dutch for people with head
injuries. Yeah. It was like, you know,
people like by von Dutch.
It's just fucking too clever
for me. I mean, you think,
what do you think really
started that downfall for them?
Was it the whole Kogan show where he wore,
they call Kogan was like their poster
boy for it and then they kind of,
I think it's just overexposure
anytime things get, I mean,
people love those old school
Americana Tattoos, which to me,
that's what Ed hardy always used to
represent. Like it was kind of cool.
Those old like sailor tattoos, like
dough. I liked those and then flip it,
dazzled the shit out of it. Yeah. Then
it was like, what is going on here?
And then it became this weird,
it was like a von Dutch thing.
Like von Dutch used to be the
fucking shit. Ashton Kutcher,
we used to wear the stupid trucker
hats and everybody was like, man,
I gotta get one yet. And I
would look at it, I was like,
what the fuck are you wearing man,
that looks like you wearing like
some diner in like Cincinnati.
They have like a hat
that they sell, you know? That's what
it looked like. You know what I mean?
Like it's just some obscure
like truck stop diner,
you know? And then all of a sudden all
these people were wearing it like that,
you know, full tilt it to soil. I'm crazy.
It's just, I don't know what happened,
but it became this thing that Douche
bags would wear. I don't know.
I don't know how it happened. Yeah.
But it went and it came and everybody,
you know what it was like,
it's like the spinning wheels of clothing.
Remember those spinners that
people used to have on the rims?
They lasted a little while where people
are like, what the fuck are we doing?
And it,
those spinners killed the custom
wheel market because you used to be,
everybody would get a car and
then they would get custom wheels.
Like you can take a pretty decent car
but put some sweet wheels on it and
everybody like that's a pretty nice car.
But those fucking spinners came out
and everybody's like, that's it.
We're going the other way.
Don't ever change your wheels.
Just leave the fucking wheels. The car
came with like, this is ridiculous.
We can't be associated with this.
You notice that
now it's like they're,
they're like painted wheels
are like stand like low chain.
Yeah. Low Key. You know,
he might have nice wheels,
but they're like painted black and match.
Your car was giant gold spinning,
you know?
And then they had like 28 or something,
they came out where it was like,
I took the wheel and then they would like
make the lip of the wheel even bigger.
So it looked like, you know, yeah.
They had tires that were like literally
the thickness of an iPhone. You know,
that was what it was like your tire and
they put it on like a old Monte Carlo
now. Now it's like a Monte Carlo Monster
Truck. You know, that's a common thing,
right?
Those impalas,
they would put it on these ridiculous
cars if like wagon wheels. They were like,
dude, the most preposterous wheels ever.
And those things break all the time.
You go over a bump, hit a pothole,
there's no tire. This isn't,
it's like you're running around
on metal rooms. They bend. Yeah,
I put a 20 inch wheels on
my, my accurate, and it's,
they're not like flashy. They're
like paint black wheels or whatever.
But the either had a role,
the offenders,
which I didn't realize when I bought the
car, but what kind of accurate you got?
That's a TL. Nothing, nothing
spectacular. But it's, uh,
when I got the wheels, I, uh, I
didn't know that you couldn't fit 20.
I just want to go. They rubbed out.
They would rubbed unless you rolled the,
so I got, when I ordered
it, they were like, well,
you need to get these 30 fives
are 30 tires or whatever.
I didn't know what it was. Apparently
a 30 tire is like this big, very thin.
It's incredibly thin and you know,
it looks cool, but I'm constantly,
every time I drive up north, I get, I get
a flat tire. I like all the time I've,
I've had to repair the,
uh,
the rims like three or four times
just because the tire gets so low. Oh,
he hit a bump and it puts a hole in the
or bins or cracks the rim. Yeah. Go,
go back to standards. They go put
my stock wheels back up. Yeah.
Put The stock wheels back on. Accurate.
Makes a fucking hell of a car though.
They're underappreciated car.
Yeah, they really are. I love it.
Two of those I had to Nsx is there. My,
I still might go out and buy an old one.
I'm still, I'm looking for one that
was fucking cars are great, man.
I loved that car.
Never had a problem.
Every time you go to start rumbling
starts right up on does just do,
you can't fuck with Toyotas and Hondas
that does. Motherfuckers will run forever.
I had a Honda accord when
I was in high school.
It was like a 92 Honda accord and I
never changed the oil and the thing.
And the guy he does,
I didn't know money.
I drove around with $2 of the gas all
the time. Like you know, you never,
it never changes there. And I think
I ended up having two clutches.
I went through two clutches cause
I was like fast and furious.
The movie had come up like that and it
was like burnouts at every like stop
playing man. I did a lot of dumb shit
with that car. You know those uh,
those whippet Umm, things
where you can, it's like, uh,
I think it's the actual use for it is a
to me like a whipped cream, yay carrier.
But you can,
it's like a canister and you can put a
little whip it cartridge in it and it'll
uh, he hit the button, it'll fill up and
you can fill up your balloon off of that.
So I had,
it was like 16 or 17.
I had wired like put a tube through my,
um,
through my a glove box all the way
into my intake in the front and I put,
I was like doing a little street racer
guy and I would crack off like four or
five whippets in that little container
and thought I had an interest in my car
to my glove box. It's your
story. But that Honda,
I ended up giving it to a friend when
I got another car and he drove it
literally until the wheel fell off till
the front wheel fell off and it had like
over 325,000 miles on it.
And I think he, you know,
never, you know, it just ran until the
wheel fell on Japanese make amazing cars.
I have a friend who was Alexis
that has a million miles on it.
It really a million. Yeah. It's
like, it's a famous car. Like,
I don't know if it's his, he drives
uh, Matt Farah from the smoking tire.
He always has a images of it.
He's, he brings it everywhere.
It just puts it online. It's got a
million fucking miles on anything, a male.
Again,
they just don't break.
This is like something happened
along the way where we,
it became acceptable for
cars to just fuck off.
That's just be a piece of
shit and it's American cars.
Why do we do that to ourselves? You
know? So he's just a, I mean it's like,
it's always the, the Japanese cars
that lasts forever, don't they?
The Lexus or the Toyota or the Honda.
Even German cars, which are amazingly,
I had German car, shit, they fuck up.
I know someone who has a
Porsche Cayenne and uh, she,
she went to start at the other day,
catastrophic fucking failures.
Engine light's on year old car.
Probably like what a fucking hundred
60 grand or something like that.
Cayenne turbo pressing buttons. All
these lights are going on. Like,
what's going on here? Nothing. Got a tow
it and get it towed. They'd be like, oh,
there's a problem wrong with your thing.
And they replaced the thing and like what?
Like what if you were in Alaska
and then shit went wrong.
Like what if you're driving
across country? Yeah.
You know when you're driving your
portion, Alaska, you never know.
I guess there are people in Alaska
of portrait. This is must be,
people don't want to ask
you about some cheese.
I want to fucking be a ball out there
and drive under Mousse with a fucking
Cayenne. Yeah. It's something
about those Japanese cars though.
They for whatever reason,
it's like the Japanese culture itself.
You fought in Japan. I haven't, I
haven't. I would think that that's like a,
for a,
especially for a kickboxer when it
comes down to like the k one glory days,
those are probably the glory days of not
necessarily have more time because you
know, there's a lot of like the great
Moy Thai fighters particularly, uh,
like in the lower weight classes
came out of Thailand. Yeah.
But as far as like heavyweights and
the larger kickboxing bouts, like,
man, it all took place in Japan.
That's where, when I moved out here,
when I was a 19, I was, uh,
going to school and then I couldn't
afford cable ahead of the job.
It's like a room service attendant
at the Bonaventure hotel. But I had,
I would go to this,
uh,
video store and little Tokyo and
they sold all the k one videotapes,
and that was where my girlfriend
coming over and just being like,
can we watch something else? So that was
all the time was just like all the time.
K One max or a k one heavyweights. And
uh, yeah, I think that was the best,
like the hundred foot giant screens,
you know,
the long walkways or as they had in k
one and that was the golden era of the
pageantry and it, which is
what Gloria is now, you know,
so I wish, yeah, I wish the,
uh, the fans that love kid one
would pay attention to Gloria. Well,
I just think he, for this
thing to fail, you know,
so long that we're trying to get
this sport going and, uh, you know,
nobody's gonna Watch a glory show and not,
not fall in love with it.
You know what I mean? It's just ingrained.
Turn on the damn channel. You know,
I told the UFC, you know, maybe
like seven or eight years ago,
I told him to buy a k one cause
I heard the k one was for sale.
I said you guys should buy k one.
Does you know the ultimate fighter was
originally supposed to be the cabling?
Really? What do you mean? Uh, Mike
Kogan, my manager told me this,
he used to work with k one
and k one you will say what?
Scott Cougar that the uh,
the ultimate fighter TV show was
originally supposed to be um,
k one on spike and they the deal
didn't go through or something.
And then Dana and the fatigue has picked
it up and did the UFC one originally it
was supposed to be Kaitlin.
I would double check on that
if it's coming from my Cogan.
That's what he said. You
never know. He might be right.
Joe Schilling is the most
gullible motherfucker,
but I think that the levels
there, you know, like, like here,
like the big fight, Rico
Verhoeven, he's like, you know,
like one of the best kick boxers you could
put him back in the k one glory days.
I mean 85 right around a lot of
those big name guys. Oh yeah.
I mean like think about the guys
that they have. I mean there's,
there's just like, there's a, there's a,
there's a wealth of talent in kickboxing.
Especially like a lot of these European
guys, a lot of these guys from Holland,
I mean there's so many good fighters.
It's not a lack of talent. It's,
it's one of those things where it's like,
at this point it's almost
like it just needs time.
It's almost like it just needs,
it's like if they're willing to do with
the UFC did and put that and put the
show on and you know, I mean, look at
the, wait it out. Daniel Gita. I mean,
[inaudible] Saki mean there's
a fucking great fighters.
Can you guys have Keratan off now to
some really exciting fighters in the
heavyweight division as well
as all the other divisions.
But if they just take the,
like the UFC was $44 million in the
hole before the ultimate fighter,
he got on the air and they were
ready to pull the plug. They even,
there was one point in
time where Dana had, um,
had a conversation with Lorenzo
and they were like, look,
we can't keep hemorrhaging money. Let's
just sell it. Let's just get rid of this.
Let's see what we can get for it. And
they were going to sell it at a big loss.
And, um, the next day I'll look,
Lorenzo slept on it and got up and
fucking changes my, I said, fuck it.
Guns blazing. Let's go, let's keep
going. Let's ride this bitch out.
Which is what you can do when
you're a billionaire. Yeah.
Well, I think that's, uh,
that's probably not real far
from where, uh, you know,
the glory story is right now. Uh, Pierre,
the owner of glory and the had
a chairman or whatever is, uh,
is definitely one funding of 90% of this
stuff and, and pushing that. So, you know,
thank you Pierre. Please
keep it up. You know, unless
they're, you know, almost, look,
it's so cool. The product is
there. See that's the thing.
It's like the product is there, the
fights are there anybody who watches that?
The,
the event that you were in,
the last man standing right at that
fucking shit is on my DVR for life.
Which by the way,
it cut out before the end.
Somehow or another really don't
know what the fuck happened.
Maybe I only recorded for three
hours or something like a retard,
but the,
of any watches that tournament,
it doesn't get hooked on glory and
hooked on kickboxing. You got no pulse.
And that's the other thing about the
Gloria is doing, which I don't know,
I don't know any of the
finance stuff about it,
but they're not going cheap on there.
On any of it. You know what I mean?
Like that is a huge event.
The, the production is insane.
The fighters are insane.
I mean all of it is just really top notch.
You guys got Mike Tyson pimping for it
and now apparently they got Mike Tyson
doing this thing, which is a, it's
cool. Yeah. If you go to the glory page,
go to Glory World series.com Mike
Tyson is doing the intro video,
which is pretty fucking bad ass and uh,
is uh,
Rico Verhoeven versus a Errol Zimmerman.
And then there's a you versus a,
this kid is only 20 years old. Huh?
I think he's 22. Robert Thomas
from Canada. Is He 22? Yeah,
they call him the White Dragon.
Jim, he's good. He's a good fighter.
Is going to be interesting. Yep. Um,
have you seen him fight before? Yeah,
I saw a couple of fights on line.
He fought a arts 11
then he fought a Alex
Perreira who's another guy,
the top 10 in Brazil and we came up
short on both of those. But you know,
that was, I have a lot of respect for
somebody that young in his career as,
as going after the top top fights. I mean
that was me. Um, the, I was the guy that,
that one of those tough shots,
so I know how dangerous those
kind of people can be. Yeah.
Last fight in glory was Gloria 18 in
November. He CalEd Mike Michael Mer. So,
uh, I'm just going to be fun, man. I
just, I just loved the fact, like I said,
that they're doing this and uh, Nicky
Holsten is fighting to, who's a fuck.
He's so high level. He's, he's really
fun to watch. He's so fun to watch.
Really good technical man.
Everything he does just said
that classic, moist, you know,
the classic kickboxing style from Holland.
His boxing is like from the Nolan.
He's been,
he's are going back and forth doing the
professional boxing over there between
fights and uh, yeah, his hands are
really good. He is, he's my pick for,
to win the tournament.
But then they also got a Raymond Daniels
is human highlight real, you know,
he's a really high level martial artists.
I don't know if I'd really
call him a kickboxer. Well,
he's becoming a kickboxer really like
a karate guy who's getting into MMA.
It was getting,
getting into kickbox you'd rather,
but the shit that he does like that,
that touched jumping sidekicks,
spinning back kick in the air that
decode his last opponent with as well.
But you don't do that on the bag.
I got to know the height he does
that and then like the timing of it.
It's really, really, it's really,
it's something else. Yeah.
He's learning the kickboxing game.
We still got like some
gaps in his is striking.
We see that especially the transitions
between kicking and punching. Right.
But the stuff that he can do, you know,
and he's still fairly young. I mean,
you could still learn it. He's an La
guy too, isn't it? Yeah, I think so.
Do you ever train with him? I supported
them once, probably six years ago.
I think when,
um,
they had that world combat league when
Chuck Norris tried his little thing,
it was so geared for,
for his,
his type of style that karate guys like
none of the Moitai guys did very well in
that. Um, well that world combat
league did they allow leg kicks,
they love leg kicks butt
underneath those pants.
We had thick shin pads on
like Oh really shin pads.
And then there was only one, three minute
round they made you wear Shin Pads.
Yeah.
Nope.
There's one three minute round and it's
really hard to do to really make leg
kicks that affective and three
minutes with giant shrimp heads on,
you know what I mean? That
seems ridiculous. It was,
well Chuck Norris was Lee his league
and it was really geared around like the
point karate guys and um,
and that type of style.
You know what I found really
interesting about it though,
it was the lack of ring. I really
kinda liked that. I don't don't,
I'm not sure if the slower, yeah, for if
you don't know what I'm talking about.
They kind of,
it was almost like a very shallow swimming
pool or it's like it was flat in the
bottom. And then for folks
who didn't watch it, the,
the edges were kind of sloped up but not,
not a big slope,
just a slight slip,
just don't enough to let you know that
you're at the edge and then it would
bring everybody back to the center.
It wasn't very big thing.
But I think that for,
for MMA in particular,
one of the things that drives people
crazy is people being pressed up against
the cage. And like a lot of people
don't like that aspect of MMA.
Like the clinching up against the cage,
throwing knees to the leg and you know,
they get, they start booing and
they want everybody separate.
I've always felt that like I have a
football game can be played in a fucking
China, a hundred yard field and a
basketball game to be played in this,
you know,
really long court.
Why can't an MMA fight
take place on a flat,
like just big round,
flat area like that where you don't have
a ring and there's like there's a red
zone where you're out of bounds, you
know, and make that red zone, you know,
whatever fucking five yards or something
like that and then bring everybody back
to the center.
Well you don't have any of that.
If you're going to get a take down,
you've got to get an
honest fucking take down.
Like you're doing a wrestling match,
not pushing a guy up against the cage
and pulling his legs out from under him,
but an actual legit takedown.
Like giving them pride.
It was a little harder to get a takedown.
Oh yeah. Cause he couldn't put, you know,
cause what they do is we'll
shove it up against the fence.
Then they suck your legs out.
They use that a certain thing.
I mean I have a lot more, I'm a lot
more comfortable defending takedowns um,
in the middle.
You know,
stuff like there's a lot easier to stop
and take that once they start smashing
it against the cage than there's a
lot of different variables and yeah.
How many fights like um, Tim, Sylvia,
I think it was Tim Silvia
and Brandon Vera. Really?
He spent like three rounds just smashed
against the side of the cage the whole
time. It happens, it happens a lot and
people get crazy. They boo and they,
you know, and it's also hard to
see through a cage. Like if you,
if you're standing in, in, in the crowd,
even if you're in the, on the floor,
if you know your couple of rows back
and there's a pillar and they're behind
that pillar and they're fighting,
you can't see shit.
You wind up looking up at the big screen.
That's what I was curious.
Maybe you could tell me about this.
When they're the UFC judges,
do they have a screen in front
of what to watch now? Okay.
This is something that we had a complaint
about for a long time because I'm
sitting there and the whole fight is
going on in the upside of the cage and you
can't tell what's being
landed or what you know. Well,
there's only punches and like a lot of
those punches that Anderson was thrown on.
Nick, you did a really good job of
blocking them, but if I'm 30 feet away,
I can't tell if it landed or not.
Well,
it's sometimes it's really hard to
tell for while we're doing commentary,
like sometimes I have to watch a
replay to see if something landed.
Like if a guy's got his back to you and
you see someone threw a punch and the
guy falls down, you're like,
oh, we got hit. But then you
watch and you go, oh no, no,
no. He stepped on his foot and
he slipped and then he went down.
Like sometimes it'll
look like a guy got hit.
Sometimes it's better to watch it at home.
Really? I used to watch it live. Yeah,
we watch it at home. You're going
to get the perfect angle. You know,
the UFC broadcast team, those
guys who were the production
guys, they're the best.
I mean there are so good at
catching all the right angles.
The replays are always on point. They
know exactly what they're doing. Right.
So you could, you could almost see
it better from home then you can.
But there's a lot of people that
complain that like sit in the crowd,
like I can't fucking see.
And they wind up like you see
like look out in the crowd,
they're looking up at the giant screen.
I've went to quite a few a
UFC fights were up. It's just,
I feel like you go there for the energy,
you know what I mean? You're there,
you're there for the energy of the crowd,
but like you're watching a screen. Yeah,
yeah. Well it's an event. I mean
there's, there's nothing like it.
Like when you're watching it,
like nick versus Anderson,
like when they were about
to fight and you know,
and they're there in the center of the
cage and you know the referees reading
them the instructions and then they
back up and you're like, Holy Shit,
it's happening right there and it's
fucking 30 feet away is about to go down.
There's nothing like that.
That's some goosebump inducing shit.
And then he lays it down and you're like,
Holy Shit.
When he laid down and put
his hands on his head,
like he's taking a nap as wedge and like,
Yeah Dude,
I was careening, laughing, CTV.
I was pounded on the table and crying,
laughing. I couldn't help myself.
I just was so funny. It's so
good. Why W I had wondered too,
whether or not nick was going to clown
them because all the stuff leading up to
the fight was totally respectful. All the
stuff leading up to fight was like, hey,
you know, nick was saying, I want
big names, I want a big name fight.
This is a big name fight. So you know,
I respect him and we're ready to go.
And then when it got to the octagon,
immediately he's talking shit.
And you could see Anderson was just so
not comfortable being the guy that gets
shit talked to.
And I was telling him keep talking.
Like I'll say like I said fucking with
and be like, keep fucking with him.
It's weird because
when nick stopped fucking
with him in the later rounds,
Anderson started doing a lot better. You
know, I think no doubt has definitely um,
you know,
the mind game and uh,
I think it was a really good
strategy that he didn't come up
and I,
he kind of,
he said in the back that it was
going to do something like that. I,
I had no idea he was going to lay down
and put his hands like that. Well,
he probably didn't even know before
he did that. I think he just,
he just knew like if he's gonna, if he
doesn't want to engage with, you know,
I think he said I'm going
to flip that switch.
I didn't realize that was the switch he
was talking about what God was awesome
and really like, it's hard.
Like, you know, that there's, uh,
an article just came out and said it
was called the sober replay or like the
sober thought, like when you watch a
fight after like the next day or whatever.
And when we were in the the corner,
you know, we're yelling instructions,
but between Gilbert and Nate Diaz and
Cesar Gracie and that all of us were just
sitting there like,
this guy is such a fucking beast.
Like we are so blown away
by what he was doing.
We were just so impressed and
I was really proud of him.
Well, especially first
time finding it one 85 too.
He steps up and fights the greatest
ever at one 85 after two year layoff,
two year layoff words, not, you know, just
really not pursuing any fights at all.
Just,
you know,
made a shitload of money off the George
Saint Pierre fight and just laid back
and relaxed for a little bit and just
said he wanted a big fight. You know.
I mean he had said before, he goes, I
want a title shot. And they're like, well,
we can't really just give you a title
shot. Like you got to beat somebody,
you know, and this was an opportunity
to fight, you know, a guy who it'd be,
it's just like getting a title shot.
I mean five round fight with Anderson
and then to do so well, I mean the,
the judges' scorecards and they
gave it all five rounds to Anderson,
but every one of those rounds were
very competitive except the fourth.
I think nick took off the fourth round,
but every one of those rounds I thought
it was really competitive and really
close.
He was competitive enough.
And especially if you consider the
other fights in Anderson has been right.
I think that's probably also,
you know,
they say like you have to
beat the champion so to speak.
I felt like you have to really beat
this underdog and it didn't feel like
Anderson did it that much.
You know what I mean?
You really didn't whoop Nick's ass.
He'd won. I felt like he wanted,
I feel like he played it safe as fuck.
Right. I mean he threw some wild shit.
He threw a wheel kick at one
point in time, but there was no,
no moment in time where he was
treating nick the way nick treated him,
you know where he was like, come on
bitch, like let's do this, let's do this.
You know, like stood in front of
him. He just wasn't ready for that.
I mean the psychological aspect also
having a guy like nick taunt you.
If nick knocked him out,
like what if he was taunting him and then
all of a sudden boom, nick catches him,
he's down.
Like that would just be devastating
and he just was not prepared for that.
Or Nick lays on the ground and
he jumps into the next garden.
Niggas trying to name triangles.
Yeah.
Anything can fucking happen in MMA and
a guy like Anderson knows it as much as
anybody now, especially after it
happened to him. Right. I think also too,
the pressure of competing at that high
level and being the champ for as long as
Anderson was like,
I remember when Bj Penn beat
Matt Hughes and I talked to Matt,
he was after it was over and he was really
honest about it in the cage. He said,
honestly, is a relief. Like being a
champion is a lot of fucking stress.
You know, he didn't swear, but he was
like, it's, it's, it's a relief. You know,
I'm glad I got this weight lifted off
my back and I'm gonna go back and relax
and see what's up. And that's kind
of the impression I got from Georgia.
And I was talking to George. He's
the same way though. It's extremely,
there's a ton of pressure to be a champion
for that long. And then everybody,
you know, everybody wants
you, everybody calls you out,
everybody wants to fight you.
Everybody attacks your character.
That's got to get pretty old.
And Nick was talking about that the
other day and his post fight interview,
he's like, you know, I wish I would fall.
I kind of wish I fell off and people
stopped talking about me. Well,
he's such an enigma, you know,
there's no one liked Nick Diaz,
such an unusual character.
He really is. I mean,
I'm good friends with them and I really
have no fucking idea what's going on in
his head 90% of the time, which actually
makes it really fun sometimes. You know.
How often do you train with him?
Uh,
I was training with them a lot for the
mill and fight until my dad died. I left,
uh, his, his pad to go to
the funeral and stuff. Um,
but yeah, I'm go up there
pretty, pretty regularly.
And when nick is in between camps is,
I mean like does he,
is he training on a regular basis?
Does he still do everything or is
he just a relaxing, like what does,
what does he been doing and like over the
two years? Yeah, when I was, had the, uh,
last man standing tournament, that was
back in northern June, June or July,
he hadn't, I don't think he had booked
through the intercept fight yet.
He still was running with me and I mean
I'm training for the hardest part of my
life were running six and a half miles
and he's pushing me like I'm trying to
keep up with him.
Wow. He runs at a ridiculous pace.
He's just your runs or an insane pace.
Does that fuck with your explosion at all?
Like there's some people that believe
that all that slow running and slow twitch
endurance type work that again
actually fuck with your explosion.
A Knicks guys disagree with me, but I
think it does. I think that him, uh,
nick and Nate both are,
uh,
not the most like a explosive people
when it comes to like their movement
patterns or whatever.
I feel like with me doing more,
I do a lot more sprint work than I
do long distance kind of stuff. Um,
but also like that's more of
their, of their style. They're,
they're very technical with their stuff.
They don't use a lot of strength and they,
uh,
both of them will wear you out and
then whoop your ass after it. Right.
Both of them have beat the piss out
of me from just being durable as shit.
And I'm throwing and throwing and
throwing and throwing and throwing and I'm
like, Oh fuck, I'm tired. And
then there's a bump motherfucker.
Yet they still talking shit. Once you're
tired they start talking to Ya. Well,
just the whole time, you know, the whole
time he, you're sparring let me talk shit.
Like what's he saying? Uh, you know, uh, I
don't know. Come on, Shit like that. Nay.
When, um, let's see, when the, uh,
for this last fight we
were sparring and nicotine,
I think it was when the UFC was filming
it. Um, nick had done like nine,
five minute rounds with fresh guys.
I was like me cheaty and Connie had
brought in to spar with him and then, um,
another guy and like the last round I
could tell he was tired and it was kind of
like clenching me up against the fence
and was like holding or whatever.
And I'm like, come on Nicole school, like
kind of like motivated and he's like,
fuck you motherfucker. And like
started whoop my ass. Like you know,
the thing about without
cause has mentioned is like
sometimes it's a lot better,
which I agree with.
It's a lot better.
Sometimes disbar people you don't
know instead of like your buddy,
you know you get,
you go a little harder or you're a
little more competitive with somebody you
don't know.
And like when nick and I first started,
I mean he used to be a lot more
competitive with me and then now we're,
we're pretty good friends so I have to,
I find myself like talking shit to him
or trying to piss him off or hit him hard
to get him to, to push a little
harder. That's interesting.
So replicates and actual competition
more in that way then it does like light
sparring with your friends. Right?
I mean I think there's different,
there's different times, different
stuff, you know, like something,
I'm at the point now where I don't feel
like I don't have to win in sparring. I,
you know, I can work on other
things. I can work on my
defense, I'll work on stuff.
Whereas I used to be like
I have to win in sparring.
If I lost around in sparring, I was
really upset about it. Um, but like nick,
uh, I always say this like with nick, uh,
yes ma'am. She, he'll, uh,
he'll coast or he'll, uh,
with this camp he was coasting
and some of the rounds,
or if I put him in there with
somebody that wasn't that hard,
he would like not do so well.
And then we just kind of go at the
level of the person he was going with.
So I found that, that, uh, you know, I
would tell the people to hit him a lot,
fucking harder, almost try to piss
him off, talk shit to him. I tried,
I tried my best, like Anderson Silva come
on, come on, like a impressions with, uh,
when we were sparring, his kicking
was a lot better in this fight.
And we never seen it before. Was, is that
all, you know, there's a lot of people,
interviews people, some guy, some
interview guy, I forget which, who was,
but he was like, you know, how do you
feel about this fight with nick? You know,
looking at Nathan, Nate,
Nate's last performance, you
know, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Was trying to compare like Nate versus
[inaudible] major inducer good against
[inaudible] then you know,
and I'm like how the Fed Samara,
my math two fucking completely different
people. Two different opponents,
two different people, two different
weight classes. But uh, yeah,
a lot of times when people have
complained to the, both of them don't,
don't block kicks very well.
And their understanding of of
kickboxing is a little different.
So like for me as a, as like a
coach, so to speak, in this camp,
I was trying to put and bring in the best
possible sparring partners I could for
them.
So I brought it art some love and I
brought in Shitty and Connie was sparring
with me. I believe in a lot.
I got a lot of flack for this.
I believe all three of those people are
better kickboxers that Anderson Silva
being that they're kickboxers and
Anderson Silva as Ann Mei fighters.
It's not a knock on Anderson Silva. I
just think that those are very high level.
Um, well, it's just a reality. It's
reality. You know what I'm saying? I mean,
Anderson has had spectacular
striking moments in MMA,
right when it comes to his actual real
world kickboxing experience. It's,
it's fairly limited.
There's not nearly as many fights,
especially in like worldclass competition.
But it was like,
you know, uh, our team has
a very like, confident,
like a head movement. He's like a
cold, very elusive, very sneaky,
similar traits that Anderson
has, but at a higher level, um,
I think I hit a lot harder than,
than Anderson and am a little
more aggressive and you know,
whatever things that I do
well translated well and,
and nick for as far as the
looks and the feelings.
And then what Judy and [inaudible],
he's got phenomenal movement.
He looks similar to, um, Anderson. He, uh,
he's got like four inch longer reach than,
or somebody has a very,
very similar movement patterns and the
things that he does. So my thing was,
you know, and nick didn't necessarily
beat any of us in any of that,
you know what I mean?
But he got used to seeing those
situations so that when it happened,
when Anderson through that spinning
heel kick, nick was prepared for it,
moved out of the way. Um, most of
the kicks he blocked, you know,
nick through a lot more kicks then
and he usually does his way more.
His awareness of kickboxing, it showed,
you know, and that was, you know,
I didn't know how to
fight was going to go,
but I knew that I felt a
lot of responsibility as far
as if nick got caught with
something, some kick or
some, some kickboxing move.
I felt like I was going to be my fault.
But I didn't show him holding pads
with him. Totally fads for him.
Just so you were working
on this combinations like
that left leg kick was big.
That was more,
he landed more leg kicks on Anderson
than anybody had ever done before.
If you go back and watch Anderson's
fights, nobody, nobody landed like that.
That left leg kick over and over again.
He landed that,
I don't think Anderson expected that.
Right. You know, Anderson stands southpaw,
so that right leg is exposed.
And,
and nick landed that left leg kick
over and over again. Yeah. Uh,
there was something that we
had worked on was just him,
him throwing kicks and being
more comfortable with kicks.
I've always tried to get him to kick
more, but it was something where, um,
he's a lot more confident with his hands.
He's had more experience with his hands.
And then sometimes if
you don't kick enough,
someone's making you forcing you
kick all the time and the gym,
you get tired when you throw a kick.
You know,
if I'm used to boxing all the time
and the throw one or two kicks, I've,
it's like going for a
take down on their tires.
So I wanted to make sure that
he felt, felt good. You know,
we worked on some elbows from the clinch.
I thought he did really well.
I'm against Anderson in the clinch,
especially if you look at like how
rich Franklin did. So, you know,
my goal wasn't to make
nick a high level kickbox.
It was just to make him his awareness
of kickboxing and his defense, you know?
And I think, I think it showed the, he
showed a lot, you know, I didn't know it.
It definitely did.
Now does nick do any weight lifting?
Does he do any strength and conditioning
stuff for this fight? He did. Um,
but again, it's not, was it
wasn't that heavy, but he,
he worked his way up and he did,
he did start weightlifting for that
and I think he put on, you know,
he still was like right around 201
it was walking around for the fight,
you know, he was, he was by no
means like two oh five or to 10.
That's still heavy for him. Made
a hit tool five. That's for him.
That's pretty heavy though,
isn't it? But yeah, it is.
And I thought that like when the, when
fight week came and he cut the weight,
he had a pretty easy weight cut. I think
he dropped like 10 pounds of water, uh,
want to say he got in the
ring probably around one 95.
But like you could see he was
definitely bigger than he was,
but it was like solid weight. It wasn't
like somebody blew up and you know,
j pen fought Machita or something
like that, which all sloppy. Right.
So is Nick gonna Compete
again or would it,
what does this thoughts after this fight?
Uh,
probably said it four times on
this show, Jill. I'll say it again.
I really have no fucking idea what's
going on in his head. Uh, I hope he does.
I think we, uh, you know,
there was some stuff that, uh,
one of the problems that we had in the
fight was it was the first time I'd ever
cornered nick. And when I
was yelling stuff at him, he
didn't recognize my voice.
So a lot of the stuff I was saying,
they told me after, he was like, oh,
that was you. And I was like, what
was it screaming fucking Portuguese?
And was like, fuck, I didn't know if
that was, you know, and um, that's funny.
Yeah. I think we could do even better.
And I think, um, I think you did great.
I think he has some really
exciting matchups for him. Um,
I'd like to see him rematch,
Carlos condit.
I think that'd be a huge fight
will be great fun to watch.
I'd like to see him rematch. Uh, you know,
Robbie Lawler would be huge, you know,
maybe to Carlos and then that gives them
a title shot and maybe didn't give him
title shot. I don't really know. I'm
just guessing. I love those two fights.
I think jazzy, fantastic. After a
two year layoff or whatever it is,
if he does decide to come back, I think
that's another awesome fight. You know,
Nick says he wants the big fights.
He's obviously a marquee fighter.
I think that there's a lot of uh,
really exciting. Matchups well,
I think this fight only
raised his profile so too,
I think he did a fantastic
job against the greatest
of all time.
It means him and fade or those are the
two arguments or who's the greatest of
all time? It's Anderson and Fado
and uh, you know, it's one of those,
no, there's no right answer, you know,
fade or had some amazing fights in pride.
And then, but the problem is
those guys that he fought,
they came over from pride
and they fought in the UFC.
They didn't look nearly as good.
So what does that,
is that because fade or beat them up is
because they're not on steroids anymore?
Is it because they weren't that good in
the first place? Is it their shopworn?
Is it the cage? Right. There's
all these different questions,
but those are the two guys that,
in my opinion,
I go with Anderson because
it mostly because I've seen
him live and I think that
the level of competition that he faced
is probably a little higher, but it's,
it's an argument that I could see,
like,
see when people say a fader was the
greatest of all time, I'm like, yeah,
I could see your argument. You know? I
mean I'm not, I'm not 100% against it,
but to go five rounds like nick did,
being a guy who fought his original
career at one 55. Unbelievable, amazing.
I mean you fuck fucking Diego Sanchez
at one 55 and he fought a lot.
Sean sherk one 55 and fights Anderson
30 pounds heavier and it's very
competitive.
They're seventh fight where somebody,
he is his opponent was either at one time
a UFC champion or went on to become a
UFC champion. He fought six or seven of
those guys in his career. That's amazing.
That's amazing. Right. Was the thing up
to your face soap? So I hear you better.
Sorry. And then when, uh, when
I was going through his, uh,
I was looking at the opponents
and the strikers that, uh,
Anderson had fought in his career.
Then I was looking at the strikers and
the opponents that naked fought and his
career.
And it was just for my own curiosity,
but like nick fought straight straight
would his words hitters and at their
best, you know, Paul Daley,
Paul Daley, when, uh,
Robbie Lawler was a monster,
you know, at his best when I'm,
or now he's got a new best, I'm not
sure, but I think he's at his best.
But then Chris Lytle, you
know, uh, a lot of like really,
really good strikers when they were,
you know, uh, the Japanese guy, uh,
when he fought him in pride,
gummy gummy. Yeah. Jeez,
go me was knocking the shit out everybody.
And so nick has always taken those really
tough fights and whether people love
him or hate him,
no one can ever say that.
Nick doesn't fought his way
to get where he is, you know?
No doubt. It's really impressive. No,
he's a very good, very good fighter.
It's just one of those
things where I just,
I just feel like the right
now is a great time for him.
If he wants to like
follow through right now,
if you really want to remain active
and jump right back in there,
there's so many marquee battles for him.
I would love to see nick versus Hector
Lombard. You want to talk about PR?
I mean what the fuck would happen with
the tax or Lumbar of nick starts talking
shit to him like that, you
know, and it's good fight too.
Great Fight Hector's a monster
and Matt Brown would be an awesome,
there's a lot of really exciting fights
from at one 70 and I'm sure there are
some in one 85 as well.
Yeah.
And if he's wants to do some good fights
and you know now that watching them
against Anderson Silva,
there's not really a way class.
I want to see him fight that.
You know what I mean? Which
was heavy, heavy weight,
but no higher than one of the
five. But all those guys. Yeah,
I think he could go back and forth
between 70 and one five he wanted to,
and it's funny that you know, people are
watching that fight and they're like, oh,
Anderson's, you know, that would,
let's see, Anderson retire,
he's not the same person anymore.
Nobody's saying that about Nikka and
that's after a two year layoff. It's true.
She's really impressive.
Well,
people are concerned about Anderson
first of all that, you know,
after the fight was over
to watch him like weeping.
Like that is also one of the reasons
why people concern. Right. You know,
they're like Jesus Christ.
Like this is like the,
the pressure on this guy must have
been tremendous. Right? 39 years old.
I've come back from, uh, from teen,
from knee surgeries before and like,
that must have been such a relief,
a really challenging thing to come
back from all that. And you know,
you know, maybe he wasn't crying
because he was, he said it was theirs.
I don't know why he was crying,
but I'm sure that was a lot
emotional to go through, you know,
and to come back after being
knocked out and you know,
basically humiliated and then
we're going to next fight again.
Your leg shattered and you're out for
another year, you know? Yeah. It's a lot,
a lot of pressure on, on somebody and
maybe those are just tears of joy.
He was happy to, or pride or whatever
it was, you know? Right. Well,
the second fight that what disturbed
me wasn't even the leg snap.
I mean the leg snap was disturbing,
but I'd seen that before.
What disturbed me was how easy
it went down in the clinch.
He got clenched up and Weidman hit him
on the right hand and it's like his body
just gave out. And I was
like, I don't like that.
Because if you go back and you
watch Anderson's younger days,
he took a fucking tremendous punch.
You go back, watch him versus uh,
uh, what's it Jorge Alovera. Yeah.
And he gets cracked with Jorge Rivera.
It was Jorge Rivera, not Oliver. Uh,
George Rivera. Yeah, Jorge. Right.
He caught whatever he calls it. It
was a big puncher. He's a big puncher.
And Anderson like stood in front of him
and let him tee off on him. It was weird.
And then he was like smiling at him and
then, and then fucked him up afterwards.
And I'll tell the Lee Marie fight,
he got tagged by Lee Marie and when he
marries a fucking murderous puncher, fine,
no, you know, no problems at
all. It's just one of those
things where when it goes,
it goes, yeah, that's true.
And that was something else that we
were looking at like in the and the uh,
and the camp, you know,
are looking at, you know,
we're obviously concerned that of a
hell nick was getting reacting to clench
with, um, with innocent after
seeing Anderson's fight with
rich Franklin, you know,
and then watching the fight over
again with Weidman and I was like,
I want you to punch from there.
Just start throwing punches and cross
space to get out of that. Clinton,
you see how,
how easily nick was able to get out of
it and how well it worked for Weidman.
It was like with Rick,
with a rich Franklin,
he had really no idea what to do there,
you know? So yeah. It's interesting. Yeah.
Rich was at a loss when it came to that.
He,
he know he's a very tough guy and
a very well, well conditioned guy,
but I don't think it was
the most technical when it
came to certain aspects of
fighting. But he was at a different, he
came up in a different era, you know?
And that was,
that was my goal when it came to like
bringing in the sparring partners and
putting them in those situations.
Rich Franklin obviously is capable of
doing a lot of different things in that
clinch.
He just had never been in that situation.
His training partners didn't expect it or,
or what hadn't been prepared him for that.
So once Anderson hits you with a few
of those knees, you're kind of fucked.
Oh yeah. Yeah. And then, uh, you know
what you're going to do makes it,
if no one's ever taught you anything
other, it was like, oh shit, I'll need me.
They're getting them back.
It's place. So, yeah,
he didn't know how to control the hips.
He didn't know what to do and it just,
you know, that was, that
was, he was new school.
He was like the new era in like 2003.
That's what Franklin was.
He was like the new era of
athletes supreme. We conditioned,
I remember they used to show on those
countdown shows, these show his training.
Right. You know, his workout
routine. It was brutal.
I mean nobody worked out back
then as hard as rich Franklin.
He was huge for one 85.
What was that Hawaiian League he used
to fight in before UFC was like a super
bro. He was like two 25 champion.
He's a heavyweight. He was a big guy,
big guy. It's really fic. And uh, when he
went down to one 85, you mean he was a,
it was a struggle there.
The first few fights at one 85 before he
figured out how to dial it in perfectly.
It was a struggle.
It's a,
that's the weird thing about what
we were talking about before,
the weight cutting. Like what, what's
too much? What's not enough? Yeah.
You know, and then he, you know,
he was the guy to retire chocolate
Dell at two oh five so it's, you know,
nobody saw that coming.
Right.
You ever thought that rich Franklin
was gonna knock chocolate, Dell dead?
You know who, who thought that was going
to happen? What a weird fluke shot.
Not a fluke.
I mean obviously probably meant to do it,
but the way that chuck went down,
it wasn't like you seen chuck get hit
with way harder shots for that. Yeah.
That was just a sign. You know, like
once you, once it's gone, it's gone.
He got tagged earlier in the round two
that I think contributed to that and he
got,
he got hit with some big shots earlier
in the round where you could see like he
got dinged.
You know,
Dana and I actually talked about it
before and he said he felt like chuck was
hurt early in the round and you know,
that was just the one that just put
them away was the one that that landed.
It was crazy that rich was, he hit
him with a broken arm, you know,
he hit him with a right hand and then
after the right hand he hit him with his
left and his left had been snapped
earlier in the fight. He didn't even,
you know, just threw punches,
didn't even realize it.
And after the fight he realizes,
Oh shit fucks going on with this thing.
That's a common thing.
And kickboxing though isn't it like
blocking those kicks on the forum taken
kicks on. The arm is uh, there's a,
there's a way he can do it though,
like a lot of people. Um, and that was,
I think it was explained
to nick and this campus.
Somebody along the line told Nick to
block like you're holding pads this way.
So that's like exposes your skin.
This is like exposes your,
your for like the bone on bone.
If you keep this inside,
you're going to take it on like the
meat of the arm, the meat of your,
your other arm.
And then you put one hand here.
So this doesn't hurt nearly
as bad as going here.
It's bone on bone. And the Shin
is going to win against the owner,
whatever button every time.
It's so weird when you watch a guys
shit get broken like the Tyrone Spong
[inaudible] Saki fight. Especially when
a guy likes bong. It's just such a,
such a high level.
Kickboxer you watched him throw a kick
and then you see his leg just go noodle,
just snap. And then,
uh, I think, uh, Jerome,
the banner had broke [inaudible] arm
back in k one once in the past two,
so,
well remember when [inaudible] fought
against Alistair Overeem and the finals?
His arm was shot. Yeah.
That's what it was.
He got hit and his arm was fucked up
before, you know, that fight even started.
He threw like one more kick everything
off. Yeah. He was done at arms done. Yeah.
The bones to just nothing, nothing
that makes them any tougher than that.
You know,
you're born with a certain amount of bone
density and you could lift weights and
they'll get thicker and a
little bit stronger. But,
so someone was telling me
that they, cause usually, uh,
all of the guys that I can remember that
I've seen with it breaking their legs
were always black guys.
You know, this, this wow,
somebody was telling me that I think
you can Google it, that there is a, uh,
there was actually studied them by it,
that um,
if vitamin D I think it's d three, like
something that we get from the sun, um,
the darker skin people have like a, almost
like a filter of it and they don't, um,
they don't, uh, don't absorb as
much, absorb as much as it and,
but it was like Corey Hill tireless and
long and he said Sova Danny Beal back in
the day, like almost every
person I can think of the head,
their lakes snapped and
kickboxing was this black guy.
I've definitely seen white guys online
get their leg snapped and kickboxing.
I'm sure white white dudes are
just as vulnerable. Had the guy,
I thought somebody told me that and I
googled it and then sure enough there was
like a study done on it
that it works like a,
you're darker skin tone works as like
a filter and you don't absorb as much.
I think it was d three that's weird
because I guess you know the more melanin
acts as like sunscreen. It was melanin.
Something like that's interesting.
I don't know about all that
and I couldn't believe it.
Joe Rogan's like Joe Schilling gold
throws out facts and that's what everybody
does in ratio though. I do it all
the time, but I think that like,
but I did Google that one I want.
It's true,
but African Americans tend to
have thicker bone density. See,
I think it was the exact opposite
is what that says. That's not true.
They definitely have more bone density
because in fact African American women
tend to have the same,
a similar bone density as European males.
Brilliant. Yeah. Yeah. Africans have a
thicker bone density Africans in general,
but you got to realize that that varies
with strength training. Like when,
when they do that with people,
a lot of times they're,
you're not testing people that are
lifting weights. When you lift weights,
your bone density increases dramatically,
especially with people who do like power
lifting and you're like, their fucking
jaws get wider. You know, their head
gets thicker and it's because your body,
your whole body is dealing with,
there's a little bit of that going on too.
But even if your natural
just carrying that, you know,
just lifting very heavy things forces
your body to go, oh, this motherfucker,
what are we doing with our body here? You
know, your body's pretty adaptable man.
I mean,
you look at people that are Yogis,
it can get in all these crazy positions
and they're not born that way.
They're just slowly stretching
themselves into that position, you know?
And that's,
that's the flexibility of your muscles.
It's the density of your bones
that the body will adapt to stress.
The more you give it,
the more it sort of tried to conform to
this new work that you're asking it to
do by then like kicking pads and like,
oh yeah sure our phones get
thicker. Oh yeah, like the micro,
micro whatever. Well they also say, um,
when you're kicking like
Shin on Shin all the time,
what you're also doing is you get these,
the posits of blood and it fills up and
calcifies and you know all the bruises.
When it heals those
microfractures and tiny,
you're getting all this calcification,
it almost leads to like a Shin instep
protector, you know, all over your Shin.
Like do you ever see that fight in lion
fight or mallow pet just starts, uh, he,
he kicks his guy and you see the guy
react and so he just starts going Shin to
sham with them just winging his shins.
And I'm laughing at the
guy cause Malpass shins.
It's been known since he was like six and
he's got over like 400 fights I think.
Yeah. Ridiculous nuts. But it's almost
like he's got armor on his shins.
He just smashing them into the other
guy shins and laughing at him while he's
doing that because his shins all
just fucking covered this, this,
this layer of protection that's
been built up like knuckles,
like those dudes, those co Karate
Maki Wara guys I had to go constantly.
There's lots of,
does that fuck your hands up though?
Cause I would think that like,
I would think so.
I mean I used to tell him all the time
like bro you were, we work gloves,
wrap your hands.
The fuck is the point of that shit.
Like kick that thing cause you've got to
do it. Like what the fuck are you doing?
You know? But he was like on
some like Samurai type shit.
Well his knuckles were just be like
just crazy calcified me my up pretty big
knuckles now too. But I don't, I don't,
I would think that like your
hand would not work properly.
Got Arthritis and shit. That's what
I'm looking to be worried about.
The arthritis. My friend
John, he used to do that shit.
He used to break bricks and those
karate demonstrations and Shit,
but he would always practice like
hitting the Maki Warrah and his, uh,
which is a mock, your war is just like
this for folks who don't understand.
It's like a two by four that's wrapped
with rope and they, they, you know,
lock it into the ground so it's real stiff
and they would pound this two by four
with a rope until you develop all
this calcification and all this, um,
this,
uh,
calluses all over the top of your
knuckle where it's like one big knuckle.
The first knuckles become
one big giant knuckle.
But does that help your hands?
I protect you from getting
injured. I don't, I don't know.
It seems like it would,
I think most of the time that Andrea
is a happen in boxing or fighting is
usually these bones, the
small ones towards the pinky
and the next finger, right?
Yeah. They're not protected as
much. Well, like this is actually,
if you break this and
you go to the doctor,
they're going to call
it a boxer's fractures.
I broke mine when I was kid.
But these are usually the bones of break,
but usually they say like you want to
hit with these two bones that cause these
two buttons line up
directly with your wrist.
These two are like kind of on an angle.
So it's a lot easier to break these. Yeah.
Yeah. Especially considering
like how your hands built.
Like some people they
have a more narrow hand.
Maybe it would be more
protected by the outside edge,
but mine's sticks out on the side.
Yeah. It's like a weird thing man.
The hands just not
designed to punch people.
Speaking of which like
Nick's is not really,
nick has like this crazy
not right here on his,
I just saw it the other day and it was
on both of those and like what the fuck
is it
probably broken and never did anything
about it. That is nut probably broke it.
Just let it get me a lot.
It sounds like this crazy lifted up thing
like right here in the center of his
hands on his hands.
That's probably not good.
That guy's got some scar tissue.
He's got some cars that she's
been through some fucking wars.
But look at you man, looking
beautiful. 31 years of age. Look, I me,
if people didn't know you,
they would never think you're
a professional. Kickboxer
that's true. I've had a few
cuts and scratches. I've got uh,
both of my own, both sides of my
eyes that have cut under both eyes,
never broke my nose.
All those Simon Marcus and I think
our first flight he had slammed me,
like trip me and like landed
on top of me and knocked me.
I was out of it and stand
up and I'm walking the wrong
direction and the ref was
a plantation and said fight and I
just got blasted like two more times.
But after that fight, like one of,
one of the things he finished him,
it was like a push kick to the face.
And after that fight,
like all of the cartilage inside my nose,
like this ball or whatever is not,
doesn't sit right anymore. It's like
a little crooked because of this.
I can't fix it.
Does it breathe? Can you
breathe in? You know,
I read that the both though.
That's good,
but it's like if I stick my finger in
this part of this space and like this one,
there's like a ball in there where he
just kind of rearranged my cartilage,
gave me a nose job and
knocked him out. Or even,
well, the last fight is the
fight. That's the most important.
Right, right. You know,
if you had knocked him out the first time,
then he'd beat me a few times.
He wouldn't feel so even, yeah, we
were talking about taking punches.
I need to put him on blast or no,
he uh,
after I was the first person to knock
about and he was 39 and o or it's super
impressive record, you
know, it was awesome. Um,
but he just fought in China I think a
week or two ago and he got dropped like
three or four times and finish
like he can take a punch anymore.
Like we haven't really affected it as a
fan, as some Chinese guy. I don't
remember. Just say, Oh shit.
If say look up Simon Marcus,
that's, that's important.
That's really incredible.
When you think about the fact that he
did have that amazing record coming into
that fight with you,
that fucking righthand that you
landed on him was so perfect.
It was so perfect to watch him fucking
just drop like you guys shot by a sniper,
you know, to the front of all the
people in la. You know it's gotta.
I to tell you that before
that that can't stop.
Crazy is fun until you have
someone fucking yelling it
over and over behind you
here.
Why are you trying to watch the fights?
I was watching the fights and
some chick was yelling crazy.
Like fucking relax honey.
Okay.
We heard it the first 30 times she did
allude to the cap cap yelling at while
you were fighting. Really
can't stop crazy. I Dunno.
Just trying to get on camera.
I don't know what it was. That's
awesome. There's quite obnoxious,
I mean it was obnoxious but awesome that
you have that kind of supports. Awesome.
Out of that kind of support put dude when
he went down that place with deafening
cause he's in your hometown in La. That
was wild shit. It was such an incredible,
I mean I, I'm used to get him before
glory came along. I was fighting it man.
I had some pretty bit lion fight. That's
a big shows when um, uh, the hard rock,
but for the most part it was like
Hollywood Park Casino, you know,
1200 people to be at the
forum and like walking out.
Usually I walk out and I'm like
tunnel vision. I don't see the fans.
I'm just focusing on one of them too.
I like when I walked out for that,
like the ovation from all of
the fans was like, it was,
it kind of chokes me up a little bit.
I had to like take a breath and
like blow kisses to the fans.
I had to do something just to
show my appreciation. It was,
it was really overwhelming. It was
an awesome environment. Managed.
The forum was so packed and
it was so intense and it was,
everybody was also recognizing that
this was a big moment for kickboxing,
kickboxing. You know, I've been to a
bunch of smokers and I've been to some,
some probe matches in La and around
the area was always, they were small.
It wasn't that, you know, well
received. It wasn't that big of a deal.
But man this was a giant deal. All of this
spike TV cameras, you know, everybody,
people being interviewed and the
whole deal it was like it was,
there was so much energy behind it that
like everybody was realizing wow this
might and the fact that there's
a big pay per view card,
like this might be a big
moment where kickboxing becomes
just like MMA, you know,
becomes like this next level sport.
Cause I'd always had like when you
look at the level of competition,
like when MMA became huge,
the level of competition was not nearly
as high as where the level of kickboxing
competition is right now.
The level is very high.
Like the Nikki Holt Skins and
the, you know, the, the, the,
the guys that are at the very
top of the list. There's this,
this level that's like a real solid
world championship world class level.
We're, the MMA wasn't really there in
2005 when it went in merged. It's like,
it's like all the pieces are in
place. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well that's like tough guys. They
weren't the skillset. Yeah. But we'll,
we'll go back to rich Franklin.
I mean rich friend goes a
very good fighter but like
the difference between like
rich of,
you know the, the rich Franklin, the
fought Anderson Silva and say like, um,
you know like one of the like mighty
mouse Johnson who was in my opinion,
the most technically sound fighter like
that mother fucker is worldclass at
everything he does. Everything he does
is perfect. You've got that, you know,
like we'd mark to bond
to you got that with you.
You got that with the
elite kickboxers of today.
Whereas I don't think MMA had that when
it started to take off. So like if like,
if the promotion was behind
it and if they just, if,
if it caught on with the American
people and the names started getting
established, you know, Joe Schilling and
all these guys and you know, these, these,
these names became more established
and it became something that became,
you know, mainstream. I just think
like the, the quality's there,
the product is there,
it's all just a matter of
promoting it and getting people to,
that's the other thing that Dana said
when I was trying to get them to buy it.
Like way back in the day,
they're like, you know what?
Americans were so poisoned
by like PKA karate, you know,
that they just have this idea in their
head is like, it's just dog shit. Right.
You know,
like the,
like when guys would throw like a bunch
of flippy kicks just to get the kicks in
and you know, you have to throw like five,
six around or whatever after that. Yeah.
It was like, it was a weird time. It
just wasn't the same. It's like the,
the level just wasn't the same. It's
not like what you see today. You know,
like what,
what you see today when you see they're
throwing kicks cause the kicks are
effective. Like, like Raymond Daniels.
I mean that guy is throwing some wild,
crazy shit.
You know Daniel Gita,
he's throwing some fucking
powerful fucking kicks.
That's what's really exciting about the
kickbox if we were talking to the day,
but there's, there's the heavyweight
division and MMA right now is uh,
it's lacking compared to
the other divisions, right?
When you look at kickboxing heavyweights,
you got guys like digital Kita
who's like six [inaudible] five,
like 245 pounds through an heg kicks
him punch speed of like a middle weight.
You know, Rico Verhoeven like
the heavyweights and kickboxing.
You got guys that are like six, five
and they're still throwing head kicks.
They don't move like Tim Silvia,
they don't like these MMA guys are
used to seeing. And it's just really,
really exciting stuff. Like Rico
Verhoeven is incredibly athletic. He, uh,
he's a sparring partner with uh,
with, uh, shit, I forget his name. Um,
really high level boxers and a Europe.
And then a aerial Zimmerman is just a
knockout artist from, from the k one days.
He fought all the top guys in k one
it's just really, really exciting stuff.
And Rico Verhoeven is conditioning.
Yeah. I mean for heavyweight,
he's a lot like Cain and that sense to
where that guy just does not get tired.
I mean, he will go
five, 5 million or five,
three minute rounds and
be 100% through the,
and that's where he beat Daniel Gita.
I think he started wearing them down and
then the conditioning sorta took in me.
He can fight at a very high level for
a long time. And he's a young guy too.
He's got a, he's got a
bright future. I don't know.
I think he's 20 I'm sorry,
at most. Yeah. Yeah. It's
um, what's it say here?
And he's a huge guy. You know, when, when
you're next to him, like he's huge hands.
Like he's just a big giant,
giant man.
Yeah. I just hope it takes off, man.
I really do because I think I like,
I do enjoy boxing. I'm a big boxing
fan, but I like kickboxing a lot more.
Like I will watch kickboxing fights over
and over again. I will rewatch them.
Where I think the more elements
you add two to fighting,
the more interesting it becomes I law.
I actually kind of wish it was more tie,
you know? I think that the clinching
is an important aspect of it.
The tying up the knees to the body and
in the dumps. I think those that's,
that's an important part of the art that
I and also the elbows and knees in the
clinch. I mean I think they're very
important. That's why I love malign fight.
Well and Kevin Ross is your guy, right?
Train with him on my best friends. Yeah.
I love that guy.
I love watching him fight too.
He's a pure Moitai like
you watch him fight every,
I mean the way he controls distance,
the distance between the throwing the
kicks and the punches in that like he's
doing everything the right way.
Where like the right technique for
the right distance. It's all like,
it's a beautiful thing to watch.
You get to see the true art of Moitai
represented when he's fighting. You know?
Absolutely. Absolutely. They think
that's, I think that's missing in,
in a little bit in Gloria.
I'm like,
I think I wish they would go with the
elbows and the knees and letting guys tie
up in the clinch and
throw knees to the body.
I think their,
their thought process with the
clinches that it turns to some guys,
it turns into like a way of stalling or
with like, you can't punch with them.
You can't, you're not as
good at punching and kicking.
So you just clinch him up and then,
you know,
it ends up being like a wrestling match.
What they're saying.
I think they're silly. I think my two
fights with seven Marcus. Absolutely.
Well Simon Mark is, that is
his style, right? That was,
that was one of the reasons
why he beat so many guys.
He's clinch was phenomenal and he was
so physically strong. Right. You know,
how much of a difference did you feel
fighting him in a Moitai fight and
fighting him in glory?
Um, I didn't really notice
that much of a difference,
to be honest with you because I was in
a lot better shape and for the A and lot
more prepared for the,
for the last man standing thing.
But I think it also forced him.
He had to,
he wasn't able to hold on the way he
wanted to and to do what he wanted to do.
So I think it's unfair for me to
say it if it was, I don't know.
That was a really good fun. I
enjoy it. It's great fight for you.
I really liked and I always thought
that a glory rules with elbows would be
really interesting.
Like even if he didn't allow the clench,
but you're loud elbows because elbows
are actually my favorite weapon.
That's how I got my,
my ring name.
Most of my first 10 knockouts were by
elbow or from like knee to the head.
From the clinch. Yeah. I
think it's a great tactic.
It's a very great technique I think. I
don't know why they don't do it honestly.
And then k one they didn't do it because
Japan isn't like big on the blood thing.
So maybe that was why know they
stop fights and wiped the blood off,
all that stuff.
But uh,
I really love elbows and like people
get guys like Nathan carnage more. Sure.
Yeah. He was like the elbow
God was like, Oh yeah,
beautiful boxing ability and the
sneaking in the elbows, you know, I,
I'm a big fan of the elbow. Yeah.
And I think that those guys,
when they're fighting and
kickboxing as opposed to Moy Tai,
there's like an element of their
game that they've worked so hard to,
to adapt and to, to get proficient at.
And then that element's been removed.
You're forcing them to fight it like 70%.
Exactly. Yeah. And this happened in with,
with Simon, you know, in that fight
with me. And that was his first fight.
His first loss was his
first kick boxing fight.
First knockout loss was
the first key proxy fight.
And then this one that just happened was
also in kickboxing or San shall rules
or whatnot. Yeah. Oh, it was
tan shall rule secret. Wink.
When lung fung or so San showered, you're
allowed to throw takedowns and stuff.
I don't know really know about that. I
mean they call, it seems like San show,
but they call it something
that weanling fung. Um,
I did it once and it was horrible for me
is actually when I tore my knee apart.
Um, but it was like you're allowed
to judo throw or like, uh, but,
but somehow they were yelling at Simon
when he was trying to clinch and I don't
really understand it.
What do you think about what John Wayne
Pars doing that cage combat thing?
He's got like,
he's,
he's like got Moitai but they're
fighting in a cage with like MMA gloves.
I particularly don't care for it. I mean,
I don't like, um, I think it's, it's,
I just see it as a gimmick over trying
to tap into the MMA scene. I mean,
like we just talked about the cage.
It makes it really hard to see.
I don't think that you can clinches
well against the cage as you can in the
ropes because you couldn't
move them backwards.
And I think it's more about like a,
just attaching the gimmick or making it
more brutal than, you know, thing that,
and I think a lot of guys or a breaking
their hands with the little gloves,
those little gloves doing it. I wouldn't,
I wouldn't want to do it defensively.
It's a big issue,
right,
with the little gloves so we don't
slip punches through where you can't,
you know,
I thought it was going to be,
and then when I started training
for the Melvin fight it,
I didn't find that much difference.
Um,
although I think if I had,
if Bella had a boxing glove on,
it hit me on top of the head there.
It might another put my legs out and I
might not have dropped as as easily as I
did.
Um,
I don't know if Melvin would have went
down from that right hook with a boxing
glove as,
as dramatically as he did.
Did Glory adopt k one rules just because
k one was like the big organization to
k one started to fall off and then it's,
showtime came along and it,
showtime put up some really big fights.
And then Gloria kind of came along and
took that over. I think that's, that's uh,
exactly what happened. I think that, uh,
the, from what I understand that guys
k one was k one and then most of the
fighters from Holland were under one
management team. And uh,
when k one started to fail,
that management team
had all the contracts for the k one guys
and they started it showtime because
they already had all the fighters in a
contract. And then when it's showtime, um,
eventually sold to a
glory that the company glory
and then they, so they, it
was just like same people,
same scenario. It just grew from
that. And then now it's um, you know,
so lion fight is the only really big moy
promotion like national on television,
national more type promotion.
Yes.
Country. I think legacy fighting
just got, just made a deal. Um,
it was on TV and on their
own and be access as well.
Oh, their access to interesting. Yeah.
Yeah. Access is fucking great man.
Which used to be HD net.
It's like one of the best accesses or
best ways to access like up and coming
fighters and like the
smaller organizations.
Right. Uh, I think uh, yeah,
I don't get that channel.
I remember with HD net was on there,
then they had the MMA MMA shows with her
on h was it WEC was on each thing then?
No, it was um, up in
Canada. The fuck's his name.
Oh God damn it.
I can't remember in Edmonton.
You know what I'm talking about
the dude. But uh, now, um,
and you remember what your spike TV
when the UFC was still on it and had the
ultimate fighter that was like the
kind of the home for combat sports.
And I know that a spike TV is now a ending
I think in March and they just signed
a spike. TV's rebranding like or re
self and like the change in the name.
No, a rebranding. They're changing,
they're revitalizing their look
or something. I don't know.
They're trying to get back to
being the home for combat sports.
I know they just signed a deal with
the Floyd Mayweather is a manager.
They may have boxing, they're gonna
have boxing on, uh, on Spike TV now too.
Oh yeah. They're having
like golden glory, right.
I mean, not golden glory. A golden boy,
golden boy productions is going to be
on a spike TV if it's and golden. Yeah.
Boy, it's a I'm Floyd Mayweather's coach.
I forget what they're going to call it.
What's Al Haymon um,
is promoting it.
And then so now they're going to
have boxing kickboxing and you know,
Bella Torben may on spike,
which is really, that's
beautiful. The good for a cause.
That's their Devindra, the
demographic, you know, it was,
it was all kind of geared around the
ultimate fighter and all their shows were
like the same. Um, I think
from my perspective, so
I think it's great. I think that,
you know, the more, the better.
I just think they just changed. Name
belter yeah. Fucking like goofy name.
What do you think better?
What does it mean fuck is a Bella tour?
How to even spell it? Is
it one l I spell it wrong.
And every time. I love the
fights. I love the organization.
But the Chicago just spike TV, MMA,
it's fun. It's mixed martial arts.
Everybody knows what it is. It's just
why, you know, like when you watch boxing,
it's not, you know, the funder Phis
boxing right now. Like why have,
the name is the UFC? Like when
it comes to MMA, UFC is like NFL,
right? It's got that. It's like cute tips
and Kleenex. You know, you don't want,
you don't ask for a tissue. You, hey, give
me a kleenex. You know, give me a cue tip.
You don't ask me. I have a cotton
swab. You know what I mean?
It's like they become names. Like I'll
have a coke. Like, you know? Yeah.
It becomes like, I think velcro was
actually a patent, isn't it? I don't know,
but no,
exactly.
Why a father-in-law's in the army
and they don't call it velcro.
It's called something else.
Can loop,
hook and loop or something because
of old crow is a brand. Right.
So it was the same thing,
right? Yeah. But that said,
MMA is what it is. Everybody knows
it's mixed martial arts, you know.
And I think that if they just went with
MMA, you know, just have MMA on Spike TV,
have the name of the fighters be
the the what's important, you know,
I think Bella tore this, the name itself
is kind of goofy in the fucking helmet.
Like why is it a Roman guy with a helmet?
Was that or did that come
about around the 300 thing?
Cause it seems very thorough. We
have to ask. It is kind of kind of,
I think it's a Roman thing,
the the name, but whatever.
Maximum fighting championship was what
I was trying to go. Remember. MFC,
mark paviches organization
would shop in Edmonton,
which is another good thing to watch where
like you see a lot of like Ryan, Jim,
Oh came out of there a lot of young up
and coming guys that are really good
fighters came out with these hg net fights
and they step put on back in the day.
So if, if, if spike can do that and
just make it like the home for fighting,
like every Friday night boxing and MMA
kickboxing people will get programmed if
they just stick with Gloria. I
feel like a can't miss. Yeah.
It's just a matter of
promoting it correctly.
Getting people to understand like these,
these are the best kick boxers on
earth and it's super high level shit.
It's not like,
you know,
they're just learning how to
kickbox we're putting them on TV.
Like these are the best of the best.
Do you think in there needs to be more
Americans fighting for American audience
to a cause? I hear that a lot and
I don't know. I mean I read that.
Are we that some people, I don't know if
we were that way or not. Some people are,
yeah,
there's a lot of us go,
I don't want to watch this Turkish
guy cause it's Turkish liar.
Fucking American flag on a short,
send them out that don't want them talk.
They'll talk, they'll do
that. They'll fucking,
you'll get caught. Well listen
man, I know you must have to pee.
You've been holding onto that water? I
do. I know you do. And uh, this weekend,
this Friday night, um,
folks who couldn't watch it,
it's going to be live on spike TV. It's
glory 19. And where's it is from Virginia,
Hampton, Virginia, Hampton,
Virginia Colosseum I think, um,
is is a huge event. If you've
never watched kickboxing before it,
let this be your first one and definitely
cheer from my man Joe Schilling who
will be fighting in the Co main
event of the evening. It's a, it's a,
it's going to be a big card for spike
and a big card for Gloria and Goddamn,
I hope it's successful. So
let's try to pump it up. Set
your dvrs, watch that shit.
Joe Schilling, much love my French. Thank
you very much. Really appreciate it.
I'm a huge fan fan boy geeking out
right here. So this is great. Um,
you could follow Joe on Twitter. It's Joe
Schilling three is his Twitter handle?
How come three, who the fuck is or do
you find Joe Schilling? One or two?
Let me know cause I'm going to sit back.
I don't know how I got stuck with three.
They should be able to take that over.
Is there a guy that's Joe Schilling
one who's Joe showing? What's luck?
I don't know. Oh, he's a basketball
player for Duke. You dork.
How dare you? I still got two
followers come. What the fuck?
He's not even really a,
God dammit, Joe Shit.
He's got two fucking followers too.
It's terrible. This is bullshit.
Bullshit. Take it over. Okay. All
right, my friend. Good luck to you.
We'll talk to you soon.
Appreciate it.
Great.