I got stories,
I got that magnetic shit I did in my
brain.
Now is it happening?
It's happening right now.
Crazy how it works out like that,
right?
Yeah.
Well we just spelled the same way.
I did some magnetic stick to my brain.
Yeah.
I can go.
I feel like,
um,
your,
your depression correspondent.
Like I go out and do crazy shit.
I did that.
I'll.
All right.
So it's called tr.
I talked about it last time I was here.
I was going to do it.
I did.
Um,
I did ketamine,
which I got to say I cannot recommend.
Really?
Yeah,
I did three.
No,
actually I did six sessions.
Uh,
which was crazy.
Did it?
But the side effects long term where my
eyes burned for straight up two to three
months every day.
Yeah.
Houses like burn,
like I needed drops constantly.
Like I'm like,
you stare at the Sun burnt when
irritated.
I'm like,
I got something in them.
Yeah.
More like that.
And I just felt like kind of groggy and
out of it for a couple months.
Really?
Yeah.
Then I did.
Um,
let's explain.
So Ketamine last.
Yeah,
yeah,
well I talked about the last time I was
here,
but yeah,
uh,
because I got a lot of talk about you
were going to do it or you don't,
it maybe I was gonna do I think you had
done it?
Yeah,
I had done it and it was still too early
to tell,
but I remember running into in the hall
at the comedy store and you were super
happy.
It was amazing the first time I did it,
the first two sessions were great and
then after that I kind of hit a plateau
and,
and the,
the,
I just kind of felt like,
just kinda like groggy for a not
kidding,
like a couple months.
So the first session you,
did you get this positive benefit from
it?
Yeah,
they point in continuing,
uh,
because the,
the,
the treatment is six sessions,
the protocol,
that's the protocol.
So,
um,
hold on.
I think I have video of it too.
I know I have video switching and not
even that if you're just in a basically
in like a hospital room.
Right.
But the experience itself,
you said was full blown psychedelic.
Straight up fucking 100 percent
tripping.
Tripping balls.
And this is all FDA approved.
Uh,
it's FDA approved as an anesthetic.
It's not FDA approved at that actually
know what and getting the.
I think it is.
They're actually because otherwise I
wouldn't be able to talk about it.
Yeah,
it is approved as an off label a
depression treatment off labels.
Tricky Shit,
isn't it?
Yes.
Because there's no.
They don't know.
Yeah,
maybe.
I mean that's all of them in some ways.
Especially with antidepressants.
It's all like,
yeah,
this might,
could do something.
Maybe not.
I liked that.
There's stuff that they can do to you
that is definitely beneficial,
but it's just,
you know,
your insurance isn't gonna cover it.
If you have the cash you can pay for it.
Yeah.
That's kind of the situation I was in
where it's like nobody
was going to pay for it,
but if you want to roll the dice and I
rolled the dice and I got to say,
but you,
do you think that if the initial
treatments that you had the first couple
that you really had good responses from?
If you just stop there,
you'd have a different opinion of it.
I don't know.
That's the thing.
If I had just done it once,
it kind of felt like you ever do acid.
Yes.
You're not paying that.
Like super clear feeling you get.
That's how I felt the day I saw you.
I did ask him for the first time,
like I was,
I want to say four months ago.
Oh Wow.
A months ago.
That's great.
What'd you think?
Loved it.
Yeah.
You didn't find it too intense?
No.
Okay.
Because it can be speedy as fuck.
I'm so used to edibles and float tanks.
Yeah.
That I think it's,
uh,
it's very introspective.
It was very clean,
like the,
I,
the idea behind it,
like the,
uh,
the,
the feeling behind it,
the thought process behind it.
I was like,
Ooh,
this is like some mind clarifier.
It's like,
you know,
Bill Hicks,
he used to call it a squeegee and your
third.
I like mushrooms.
That's,
it felt,
it felt very,
uh,
clarifying if that makes any sense.
But it makes total sense.
I felt great.
I felt really good.
Felt really friendly during.
Yeah,
man,
like you must have had good stuff
because a lot of times it can be speedy
and it ends up feeling like mushrooms
and I think my math.
Oh,
combined?
Yeah.
And you end up with this just like
intense fucking is not the God damn
problem is that it's illegal.
Getting weird versions of it.
Here's your thing,
here's the doctor put in the Ibmi arm.
Okay.
Oh Jesus.
Just can I say it?
Yeah.
Oh Christ.
Did you take this with the 19 eighties
phone?
No,
that's just the way it's saved or
whatever.
Why does it seem so little?
I don't know.
This is blue bar.
He's blown.
Okay.
No,
can't.
So this doctor is,
it looked like in Ob Shapiro.
Ojs Council.
Oh,
just lead counsel.
You can corner.
I don't know.
Um,
so we just,
you just go into a regular doctor's
office and sticks this thing.
It's thing in your arm and off you go.
Now the doctor has,
he tried it himself?
Uh,
he would not say,
but it was said.
Well,
he said it with a wink that he had.
He was like,
I won't comment either way on whether
I've done it myself.
So all those guys didn't want to keep it
on the sneak tip.
Yeah.
But clearly he had.
And so yeah.
So I would say for,
for the first session was amazing.
That's when I saw you.
And then after that it got a little
dicey.
Now what does it feel like when you're
in it?
I was in a,
it felt like I was in a pod,
a pod in like a small.
It's a small world after all,
like pod.
I'm going into the on now crossing arms
and I would like a little boat just
going along through rooms and the rooms
I would say were designed like kind of a
bit like a,
what's the,
a clockwork orange,
but like the milk bar thing,
a bit like white walls,
white breathing walls and yeah,
breathing,
breathing.
Yeah.
They were inhaling and exhaling and,
but I was never freaked out and then
there was like kind of digits on it,
like the Matrix.
It had like a green hue to it.
Um,
my biggest worry when I was in it was
like,
I'm so out of it,
if there's an earthquake I'm fucked like
I,
and then I would get like wide shots of
California,
get wide shots of California and think
about like the hospital crumbling and
then me trying to get out and going
like,
I can't go,
man,
you're not going to have to go without
me.
Give me 40 minutes and I'll catch up to
you guys.
Uh,
so that was my biggest worry,
but for the most part it was just like a
fairly pleasant.
I just couldn't get over the fact that
this was happening in a doctor's office,
just like a regular ass fucking
doctorate,
like literally waiting room with other
physicians and their patients,
old Weirdos met shitty magazines and
then you go in and you trip your fucking
head off and so you're sitting in like a
regular chair.
You're sitting,
it's a,
it's a recliner,
double bed type thing.
Oh yeah,
it's real nice.
They spared no expense.
So you're sitting in this craftmatic
adjustable bed,
um,
you,
you get the needle in the arm and they
leave it in there for how long?
Forty,
40 minutes.
Forty minutes.
Now if an earthquake happened,
could you just pull the needle out of
your arm?
And I was so out of it.
I don't think I could have.
I think once the drip happened,
like it's in you for awhile.
So what's the drift happens?
You probably have however long.
I mean it's a 40 minute trip apparently,
but I don't know if it's based on one,
if it's,
I don't know how much is going in at
once.
Now that stuff,
ketamine is weird because it's,
um,
it was a tranquilizer,
right?
For animals events also.
Exactly.
That's a,
it's a,
it's a horse tranquilizer and they use
it as an anesthesia for humans.
Yeah,
I've heard of that.
The guy was an anesthesiologist.
He was,
yeah.
Don't they use that in war time?
Because it's easy to carry around.
I believe they have in war time because
you can use very small amounts and it
puts people under,
you know what that sounds like.
That sounds like a Joe Rogan fact,
you know,
I don't know for sure,
but it sounds like.
Yes.
I think,
uh,
I'm pretty sure that's the case.
I'm pretty sure I was listening to a
podcast,
whether you're talking about various
forms of anesthesia and it sort of the
evolution of using anesthesia and that
ketamine worked really good in the field
because you could have a very small
amount and you would put someone under
pretty deeply.
I don't know what if it's local,
do you know what I mean?
Like,
I don't know if you could done surgery.
It wasn't like I couldn't feel myself.
Right,
right.
It was more like I had no interest in
it.
When you on here following FDA approval
in 1970,
what did that?
And Stesha was first given to American
soldiers during the Vietnam War.
Oh,
there you go.
Uh,
yeah,
there's a lot of shit on reddit about,
about it as an,
as an antidepressant treatment.
Frantic for depression.
So for you,
um,
you heard about this,
how,
I don't know,
I want to say if you just google
depression treatments page two or
alternative depression treatment,
that's probably what I,
what I googled.
Now we've had these conversations before
you and I about it,
about depression and different
treatments.
How much exercise do you do?
Did we talk about this before amount?
I've run probably three,
four days a week.
That's pretty nice.
Yeah.
That's supposed to be one of the best
things.
Yeah,
depressions,
cardio.
But like,
I've never gotten a runner's high.
That makes sense.
Really.
I think I have a shortage of dopamine in
my brain.
Just naturally.
Like I just think I don't have a ton of
dough for me.
Like I don't.
Joy is not a thing I think I've ever
experienced.
What I repeat,
joy is the thing that I don't think I've
ever experienced.
I'll experience adrenaline rushes and
like ego,
but I'll never be truly like Julius.
Yeah,
it stinks.
It fucking stinks because it's something
I'm,
I,
I believe in.
I just don't.
I've accomplished things I've done,
you know what I mean?
But I never get this sense of like this
real,
you know,
in very small doses,
vic streaming like micro doses.
So like let me put into perspective like
career wise.
So yeah,
you had a nice comedy central special to
put a lot of hype behind it.
You did.
I watched,
he did really well.
Got a great response.
How'd you feel when all that was over?
I felt cool.
Cool.
Do you know what I mean?
Like,
yeah,
exactly.
Like all.
Alright,
good shit man.
Keep going.
See what else?
But it was never like during Chappelle
show,
I never got like A.
I'm the king of the world,
you know what I mean?
Never that sort of like huge,
uh,
you know,
something that would make you want to
scream.
You feel so good.
Do you get that much all day?
Twenty four slash seven.
I just hold it and try not to scream if
you want to take a break.
If you want to go up on the roof.
I'm the worst guy to talk to this about
because I don't really,
I don't really get depressed.
I've been depressed before.
But answer my question,
the join question.
I'm joyful all the time.
You.
That wasn't a joke.
You've really.
I'm pretty happy.
That's great.
You.
Here's a good enough.
You seem happy.
Yeah.
Like I don't.
I buy it.
I'm not letting his fucking Joe.
Joe Rogan thinks he's happy.
You seem happy.
I have a lot of friends.
Yeah.
Like that's a big part of it.
You know,
a lot of cool friends.
Love.
Uh,
I love having a family.
Love what I do.
Like my jobs.
My day is filled with stuff I enjoy
doing.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
It's just fucking.
I'm just lucky.
Yes,
we provide,
but I have many of the same things.
I just don't feel that.
That sense of satisfaction you have now.
Has it varied?
Have you had higher and lower feelings
of satisfaction?
Yeah,
I think when I'm working a lot I feel
pretty satisfied.
Oh,
okay.
Um,
So accomplishments or task?
Task and goal oriented.
Like I like it's satisfying to do a
special or direct to commercial or,
or,
or write a TV show or you know.
Well,
I'll tell you one thing,
I say I'm filled with joy and I'm happy
all the time when I'm not working or I'm
not accomplishing anything or I'm not
doing it.
Like if I get real lazy,
I can get depressed.
Somebody else told me that they said
that a very,
very joyous guy told me when he gets
injured,
he just takes it out of him.
Ken,
I've been injured a gang of times.
I've had a bunch of surgeries from,
um,
you know,
athletic injuries.
But um,
for me,
uh,
if I go into lowe's,
like if I'm not accomplishing things or
in the past I don't allow myself to get
into those anymore because it's just not
a good feeling.
And even,
it doesn't even necessarily have to be
like a career,
like oriented thing.
But I have to have things that I'm
enjoying.
Yeah.
It could just be like I'm really into
doing yoga,
doing yoga every day,
and now it's,
I do it,
I get it done and now I feel great and
yeah,
but if I'm not doing something I,
my brain for whatever reason,
needs tasks,
it needs stuff to do.
And need stuff to figure out.
It needs like puzzles.
Yeah.
If I don't get that,
I have real issue.
Yeah,
agreed.
Do you like big longterm goals?
It's just like.
Yeah,
you do.
I'd like to it or micro thing.
I like.
I like those too.
I like things that are due in like a
week as opposed to something that's
like,
yeah,
whenever you're like,
I'm outlining a movie right now.
And I'm like,
yeah,
but I don't.
I wish it were more like bang,
Bang.
Yeah.
Like I'm meeting about it tomorrow,
like specifically to,
to kind of focus myself.
Like you write a joke and then you go up
and do it tonight and it kills like.
Yeah.
Oh that's okay.
That's something that,
that's joy.
That's pretty telling their joy.
Yeah.
Or just writing a joke.
Writing a joke that it.
And it kills.
It's like that feeling,
man.
Don't you wish you could give that to
people who don't do standup?
I it,
I've,
I've had this conversation with people
before that don't do stand up and like,
man,
I wish I could tell you what it's like
to crush in front of people finding
100,000
dollars.
Do you know what I mean?
That's how it feels.
It feels like,
oh,
I just found 100,000
dollars and you know,
what led me there,
my personality and my experience and
your work ethic and your work at.
That's exactly right.
So it's like you feel like,
oh,
this is so.
It's so personal.
Yeah,
it feels like this could only,
if it's a good joke,
only you could have written it,
you know.
Well,
uh,
even if other people could have written
it,
you wrote it like this,
this thing came out of which sky and out
of your shows you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It shows you,
yeah,
whatever it is.
Uh,
so that I,
that I will say is like,
that's,
that's a sense of euphoria.
But I think in some ways I try to kind
of contain it a little bit in that where
I'm like,
Whoa,
you know what I mean?
Like with this thing,
I don't know what to do with this
feeling because it's the kind of thing
where you just want to like go up and
kiss women and smack you on the ass and
would just fucking wrote a kid,
wrote a fucking closer.
What do you mean?
Like you just feel like,
like a,
like a musical.
Tony Hinchcliffe had this new joke and
uh,
he did it.
He and he came off stage like right
after he didn't.
And he was literally like,
like fist pumping.
Like he was just so fired up because it
killed so fired up.
It's like he was charged with
electricity.
Yeah.
That's nice when you can allow yourself
to just like,
yeah.
And nobody gets.
You can do it in a way that no one gets
jealous or feels like your,
your prenatal to hang out with better
people were hanging out with basically
the same.
But I'm saying like,
if that's the problem.
Yeah.
You know,
and I've,
we've all been there before too,
like the way things are going well and
you're hanging around with someone and
they get super weird and creepy with
you.
And they withdraw and you're like,
oh yeah,
yeah.
What do you get?
What?
You just kind of like,
what do you want me to do?
You want me to fail?
Well,
there's people that do definitely want
you to fail,
but what they definitely don't want you
to do is highlight the fact that they're
not succeeding.
Well.
Yeah.
But that's what most people consider.
A lot of people consider your success.
They'll their failure.
That's such a bizarre way of looking at
it.
I know.
It's so common though.
Like what evolutionary benefit does that
have?
Well,
finite resources.
Yeah.
I think that's what it comes from.
I think it just comes from there.
You know,
when people go,
oh,
there's enough jobs for everyone.
You and I both know.
No,
there's not.
No.
There's enough jobs for talented people,
but if you don't feel like you're
talented,
then you are fucking.
Yeah.
Panicked all the time.
And then it's a,
it's a self fulfilling prophecy because
that sort of famine thinking is really
bad for progress.
If you are a person who's really worried
about other people getting things and
you start thinking in a jealous man or
about other people's success,
that fucks up your own ability to
express yourself.
Yeah,
and that fucks up your ability to
succeed.
It depends on how it hits you.
It can.
It can be a motivator,
I believe.
Sure.
Definitely.
Where you're like,
fucking,
he got it.
You know,
I can't get whatever that is,
but it's hard to.
You got to kind of wrestle it into a
positive way because if you get upset at
somebody else got something,
then usually it's a bitter motivator and
it doesn't lend itself to success,
but I've never,
I've,
I don't think I've ever had something
where I was like,
this should have been mine.
Do you know what I mean?
Like one.
Have you ever had that where it was like
a job,
a,
you were like,
definitely when I was younger for sure.
What sorts of things were they?
I'm sure looking back to their absurd,
absurd things that I didn't deserve.
You know,
like someone else getting a television
show or someone else headlining a
certain place and it's for comics.
There really is not,
it's not a finite situation.
It's not like there's a limited amount
of resources.
There's so many different clubs and
there's so many different topics and
there's so many different jobs.
I mean,
I think that's one of the reasons why
comics are so ruthless when it comes to
plagiarism because like say if you have
a really unique idea and this idea is
come to you from the universe when
you're sketching it out and putting it
together and some fucker comes in and
sees this and says,
ah,
I can,
I can
bad jokes as interventions and it's
like,
you stole my fucking invention.
That's my invention dude.
Like I don't my inventions or word
inventions or premise inventions or
whatever.
Like,
so it's intellectual property,
you know,
like you know that that's mine.
So to steal it is,
is worse than plagiarism.
It's like copyright infringement.
It's like it's.
Yeah.
It's like,
it's,
it's unforgivable.
It also cuts in and creates that weird
competitive finite resources mentality.
It creates,
it creates like a mind fuck because then
all of a sudden you start thinking like,
oh,
well this is,
this is not like a community of
likeminded people.
They're supporting each other.
There's like some parasites in here and
there's some,
some vampires
with different standards because we all
more or less have,
I don't know if it's learned in the
comedy community or,
or we all come into it with certain
standards,
but there is that thing of like there's
an acceptable,
you know what I mean?
Like it's almost like not closing with a
super dirty joke if the person after you
isn't a dirty comic,
you know what I mean?
Like there's just certain you care about
them.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
There's certain unwritten rules that you
want to do.
Lottery.
Yes.
That you don't want to fuck people over
and then when somebody else does some
shit like that and you're like,
wait a minute.
Um,
but the way I've thought of it,
it's like one was right.
Another one.
I mean obviously it's the worst and it's
unforgivable.
But like I've had people steal shit from
me.
Yeah.
It's going to happen,
but it fucks up the best part about
standup,
like last night at the store was hanging
around with a stand hope and Michael
costs and all these guys and we're just
laughing and hanging around.
There's a cool concept.
Great.
Lately,
Michael Cost has been like hit his
stride that the kind of jokes he's
writing are fucking great.
Very Funny Guy and really nice guy too.
Like such a sweet guy.
Yeah.
But that place is filled with that kind
of cool comradery.
That's the point to me.
Yeah.
Do you know what I mean?
Like that's really like the fun of it.
Yeah.
Like,
like what you've done with your people
and other comics and like your,
like your group of the dense whenever
you want to call it,
but like,
but,
but that's the point of like that's my
favorite part of it and it's,
there's no close second,
not money.
It's not.
It's literally like a vibe and it's
connecting with somebody.
Yeah,
I agree.
It's all hugs.
You know,
you go to the store on an any given
night.
It's all hugs.
It's a whole bunch of guys that
appreciate each other and girls,
you know,
will really funny get together and that
place right now is,
it's hotter than it's ever been last
night.
Tuesday nights sold out and pack main
original room and belly room.
Yeah.
It's crazy.
By the way.
It should be.
Yeah.
That shows are fucking bananas.
The shows at the comedy store,
our fundraisers anywhere else in the
world.
Yeah.
But here it's just like White Joey Diaz,
Duncan Trussell,
Ari.
I mean,
it's fucking crazy.
The lineups.
Bang,
Bang.
You just see killer after killer Ian
Edwards.
Shit.
Yeah.
Jeselnik.
Oh my God.
All the time.
It's,
the lineups are amazing,
but it's also like the feel like you
feel like,
man,
I think we're in a golden era.
Yeah.
Like it feels like,
wow,
we're really lucky to be here.
Right?
Yeah.
I mean,
yeah,
there are guys like you that almost
created it in a way like by going back
to the store and by validating it and
then you,
your fans go and then it's like a self
fulfilling thing.
But.
But yeah,
it definitely feels like,
I don't know what I feel like.
Although did you watch the roast?
The roast battle?
Yeah,
I thought it was fucking great.
I didn't watch on comedy central.
Oh No,
it was in part of it I think was in
Montreal.
No,
I was in the part that was in the belly
room or they feel they did a special
that I didn't watch.
There's five.
There's five parts that they did for
Montreal and it hurt.
It was really great.
It was great.
Like the relative may get Ralphie.
I heard he took a beating.
He got.
Yeah,
he saw us.
But again,
it's an entire career flashed in front
of his eyes.
But what do you expect when you're doing
a row?
It's like,
I know if I do a roast,
people are going to fucking kill me on
Chappelle repeatedly,
of course.
So on now I'm just like,
all right,
let's judge this level of how hard
you're going to hit a.
So Ravi got hit on a weight joke,
which is weight in his divorce,
his family.
Oh right,
that's hardcore.
Yeah.
Family like left him.
So he's alone.
He's fat.
Yeah.
Depressed.
And then someone just kept teeing off on
him.
Who is he?
Roasted A.
wasn't Mike Lawrence.
Mike Lawrence.
Who one is really funny.
Yeah.
He's a really funny dude.
But apparently Ralph,
he just didn't take it so well.
Yeah.
Well I'm happy to take a swing at him.
Wasn't that close?
It was like,
you know,
it had that even on tv it was that
feeling of like,
oh,
I would,
I could see this going to go in a
certain way.
It's,
I don't want to do that.
I don't want to say that to people.
I don't want to say anything that's
going to make money.
I definitely don't want anybody saying
that to me.
That's going to make me feel like
there's a zoom in on Ralphie's face and
you as you're watching it,
you're like,
did they zoom in or designs zoom in in
zoom in or did they do that?
There is a god damn brutal show.
Yeah.
But good for comedy man.
Really good format.
It's a cool format.
They figured out a new format and they
joke writer format.
It's like it's fair and he's like
literally just like head to head and it
rewards good joke.
They laugh at the.
It's like it's like a Madison Square
Garden.
They say people know basketball.
They're like NBA players say people know
basketball.
Like they.
That's how it feels at the roast battle.
Like people know comedy and they reward
high,
high level of difficulty jokes.
Yes.
I,
I agree.
And also I think one of the things that
rose pedals really good for comedy is
it's pushing the boundaries of
acceptable jokes.
Yeah.
And this is a weird time where people
are fucking,
you know,
this whole idea about punching up and
there's so much horseshit involved in
like what is and is not acceptable and
stand up today.
Yeah.
And it's,
it's a bunch of people that are trying
to control behavior and thinking and
that just doesn't fly in that world.
It's the pushback like what Bros battle
is the pushback to this pc era that
we're in right now.
If they could prove to me that joking
leads to action,
I would pay more attention.
Do you know what I mean?
Like isn't right now,
but if they could say,
yeah,
Hitler made a lot of jokes about
invading Australia before you used to do
tons of bits about Austria and then
eventually he brought the hammer down.
Like if you could prove some sort of,
some sort of,
you know,
the A and B,
a plus b equals c,
then yeah.
Then it's like,
okay,
I agree,
but you also know that that racism and
all that shit is like.
It ain't about joking.
It's about like a,
it's about,
a lot of times it's about poverty.
It's class,
it's so many other things that aren't,
that aren't necessarily comedy.
Yeah.
And,
and even poverty of ideas.
I mean it's a,
it's a thought process.
Poverty.
It's poor thing.
Yes.
Yeah.
I mean that's what racism really is and
what jokes are,
is like,
you know,
that there's a certain amount of racism
and you play on it and there's a,
there's a wink as you're doing it,
like in a joke form and there's some
racist shit that people can say to each
other and that joke battle of the roast
battle.
That is fucking hilarious.
Yes.
Yeah.
There were black people can't swim to
nine slash 11 off the fucking tons of
nine slash 11 jokes.
George Perez and Sarah Tiana.
We're roasting and Sarah Tiana was
roasting him about Sarah.
Tiana is insanely good at that shit.
She's like one of those things where
it's like someone can talk real fast
summary.
You're like,
I didn't even know you could do this
shit.
She's like double jointed or something
like,
wait,
what you can do there.
You can do the splits.
All right.
It comes off even crazier because she's
so sweet and she's got this smiling face
and I believe yes.
You know what I mean?
Like there is no hatred in her.
In her roast.
No.
No,
but she knows.
She knows where the soft spots are and
that's where she sticks.
The blade.
Did she came in second?
She almost,
she just kind of ran out of steam.
Like she just,
it was later.
Right.
A lot of jokes.
Oh yeah man.
It's brutal.
So yeah.
But she,
she.
Sarah,
congrats to Sarah.
So Hinchcliffe did it with a suit of
armor on.
Yes.
And would have won but fucked up his
last joke.
Maybe it was really close and his last
job was a clunker.
I think his first joke in his last joke,
but hence is good at that shit too.
Oh,
he's really good at it.
He just.
Cliff is mean.
He knows.
He knows that a certain guy that he
means what he says.
He's up there.
He's doing a documentary.
He's not.
He's doing a documentary about his
thoughts.
It's not a lot of like there's art to
it,
but it's like,
oh,
this is all based on a true story.
Yeah.
Well I'm just happy that comedy central
is taken.
That's a big chance.
And they've taken quite a few big
chances recently.
Like I think with Ari Shadow Arusha fear
show this is not happening.
Yeah.
That was a big chance.
That show is really racy really out
there.
Some of the stories are fucking
completely outrageous.
So they've got that and then they're
taking chances with this as well.
And it's,
you know,
it's off the beaten path.
This is a new thing.
This is not like another guy's doing a
talk show.
Oh Great.
I think they're following the sort of
what's working alive.
Yes.
And smartly going,
how do we televise it,
because the truth about comedy central
is the ratings are so bad at this point
that they,
relative to what they were,
that I think they're like,
it's Kent Alterman just going like,
I like that.
Let's do that.
Right.
And leaving shows on that are not
particularly highly rated because he
likes it.
If they do that though,
I think that's the right way to go.
If they just find what people actually
enjoy that like,
like la right now has a comedy scene,
a big comedy scenes and roast battle is
one of the highlights of the comedy
scene.
Everybody goes to see it,
man last night.
There's a fucking line like Rosebelle
start at midnight.
Yeah.
I got there at 10 and the line was
already around the fucking outside of
the uh,
patio,
the store all waiting to get in because
I think people didn't know about it
until this week.
Literally the TV,
the show.
Yeah.
That definitely had an impact,
but it's,
it's cool to see.
It's cool.
It's great.
It's fair.
Yeah,
it's what it is.
It's like,
okay,
this is fucking,
there's a little goddamn justice right
here.
Like a funny thing that people were
doing live and I think like famous
people,
judges helps,
but for the most part it's just,
it's funny to watch.
It's fun to watch these people go head
to head.
I heard the Whoopi Goldberg was awful.
Uh,
she was just like,
why are you making that face?
Yeah,
I would agree.
A wifi was never like a comic.
Do you know what I mean?
Well,
will people was a comic.
It wasn't really real.
They're not like a club comics.
Yeah.
But I,
to me she did that one woman show which
was in a theater was not stand up.
And then she did comic relief where she
was doing a monologue with two other
dudes.
I'm pretty sure she did comedy clubs to.
Okay.
Maybe.
Well pretty sure I saw her.
Sometimes Joe things pass you by and a
certain certain shit.
It's like you kinda.
When she was going back and forth with
Jessalyn neck and she just said,
I have Oscars.
Yeah.
She's like,
all the shit I got and jasmine was like
a bunch of shit from the eighties was
just like,
well that doesn't make you funny either.
Oh,
exactly.
Exactly.
It's like,
yeah,
you brought up,
you brought up.
You brought up an Oscar to a comedy show
because it not only that,
it's the opposite of being funny.
Like talking about your accomplishments
is the opposite of like a good comeback.
Yeah.
Like somebody,
somebody said that they were an argument
with somebody and the person goes,
I have a million dollars.
Like,
okay,
buy your way out of this fucking
conversation.
Well,
if someone calls you a loser fucking
loser,
and you're like,
well,
I'm actually one.
Yeah,
there are no,
I'm not saying you should never bring
up.
Bring up having a million dollars.
Like if someone says you broke,
you broke motherfucker.
Yeah.
You can't be like actually have a lot of
money.
I can't say that.
There are certain things in which I've
succeeded.
Um,
so yeah,
so,
you know,
but the swordsman it's fucking,
it's cool.
It's magical again.
Yeah.
Well not even that.
Again,
like I've been there on and off for 20
plus years.
It's never been as good as it is now.
No,
and it's because it's the right way.
It's Adam's book and good people.
He's not booking.
He's not booking like viruses.
You know what I mean?
He's not booking people that when you're
on the show with them,
you're like,
what the fuck?
Am I only getting two spots or how am I
only getting four spots and this guy's
getting whatever.
Like where you see a guy that just kind
of is a bummer,
comedically.
Like that has no merit,
right?
That has no merit whatsoever.
Comedically.
And they used to have that because I
think there was just a lot of people
left over from like the eighties.
There was,
there was some weird.
A lot of legacy acts.
Yeah,
that's a good way to put it.
Yeah.
But now there's like,
there's young people coming up that are
really funny.
There's guys like Ron White who really
established who love hanging out there
now is there all the time now and it's
cool.
He's like a part of the community now.
You're there,
a lot of birds there,
a lot jeselnik lot dave,
when he's in town,
Chappelle,
we and that backbar too.
God Damn.
We were at the back bar less and I'm
like,
how fun is this place?
Just makes you feel like tingling when
you're there.
Yeah,
yeah.
It feels like you're in a movie about
this time.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's fucking awesome.
That's awesome.
Um,
yeah,
so,
so I did the uh,
I did that so that the ketamine,
I will say I will,
I will say I cannot recommend,
but you recommended for one
session.
I,
I look,
ketamine is a drug as interesting as
fuck the thing that I felt the day I
saw,
you may have just been that,
that lsd hangover feeling that hangover
of like the where you're not hung over,
but you're not yourself.
You feel like that,
that like high pitched clarity that like
squeak.
So I can't.
But beyond that it just became.
Now I complained to the guy and he said,
you're the only person who's ever felt
like this.
Um,
the.
Yeah,
the,
the Ad,
a little nausea as well.
I'm 100 of those balls,
but they're awesome.
Yeah.
Amazing.
This is a wad workout of the day.
I think the it Wad supernova.
This is the tiny one.
There's a little one.
The big one is actually better.
Yeah.
But you stick it on your back.
Oh yeah.
You can use it on your head ever.
Now.
Did you got shit in your head?
You got muscles in your head.
You don't even know,
bro.
You got muscles.
You don't even know my bro Bro.
My head is yoked a row.
You gotta everybody knows that about
you.
My fucking head is really.
I bet you have like weird shit up there.
Um,
so.
So yeah,
so I did the academy,
didn't,
can't recommend it.
Then I tried something called tms,
which is short for transcranial magnetic
stimulation.
Joe,
I've got a video and it's going to be
full frame.
Oh,
Jamie,
you'll put it up on the big screen.
Oh yeah.
How do I send it?
Uh,
yeah,
that's probably the best way.
Okay.
Hold on.
Um,
so,
uh,
I've been really interested in this idea
of a stimulation the outside of your
brain after listening to a radio lab
podcast called nine volt Nirvana.
Is that the memory one?
No,
it's one that we're,
they talking about skill acquisition.
Okay.
Yeah,
that's what I meant with the sharp
shooter.
Yes,
yes,
yes.
This is too big to send to you.
Oh,
can we?
This?
If you send it through google will go to
google drive and I wrote to him with the
password.
Thank you guys.
Got muscly head
Yo.
My fucking head.
He things my head is power lifting.
I remember when I was a kid,
they did this cat scan on marvelous
Marvin Hagler,
who was one of the greatest boxers of
all time,
had very large muscles around his
temples,
like extraordinarily large,
like not just a little bit bigger than
everybody else's,
but like two or three times larger than
the average person.
Like essentially you get to see it
feigns.
Yeah.
He had like thick veins that I remember.
Yeah,
he had headgear.
He essentially had muscle head gear
around his temples,
like in the side of his head and they
were like,
what in the fuck?
And they didn't know if this was
something that was developed from years
of biting down on a mouthpiece and there
was a lot of guys that did a bunch of
different exercises.
Further jaw itself.
Like I remember Gerry Cooney had a thing
that he put in his mouth.
It was like a,
like a thick rubber cable that had like
electrical tape wrapped around it and he
would bite down on it.
You know what's funny about 15 weeks,
his jaw is that shit doesn't make you
fear the guy a little bit more.
Like he'll use fucking tape bro.
He don't give a fuck bro.
Listen Bro.
All right,
let me show you guys.
They were actually lifting weights with
their jaw,
which makes sense.
You could power lift with your jaw.
Some guys chewed gum too.
There was nothing they would do.
They'd get like a stack of Bazooka
bubble gum and it turns into cement
after.
Chew it for a couple minutes and they
just take that shit.
And,
and um,
which totally makes sense because if
your jaw is loose and weak and if you
look at guys with big jaws like a guy
like
that's another thing,
the ball on your jaw.
Yeah,
you're gonna fucking,
you're not going to believe how strong,
how like rough.
And like I have a knot in my journal
right now.
It's just not a ton but enough to get
by.
Do what you've got.
I mean,
you know what I mean?
Spots whenever I get a massage and then
they work your head.
I get so excited.
I'm like,
my head feels so good.
Daughter was rubbing my head the other
day.
She's like,
does this feel good?
I said,
actually that feels really good.
And you immediately become an eight year
old boy.
What do you do?
Feels?
Yeah,
it feels good.
It's an area like your feet,
like it feels good to get your feet
rubbed.
It feels good to get your hands rub.
You ever get your hands massage?
Yeah.
You would think that enhanced nothing.
I'll feel good.
Like you shake someone's hand and
doesn't feel anything,
but if someone like rubs your hand,
they start pulling your fingers and make
them pop and stuff and they massage your
palms and the tips of your fingers and
all the little connective muscles and
all the tissue in between the fingers.
It feels great.
Yeah.
I need to get a massage.
I haven't gotten a massage forever.
Really?
You strike me as a guy that would get a
massage three days.
We used to get them all the time.
It had been too busy.
It's been a month at least.
Yeah.
Maybe more.
Maybe two months.
I just got them all the time,
but I get them to one.
I get.
I get a guy who does a lot of rolfing.
He just uses a metal bar and reading
my muscle.
My nose.
Yeah.
Well that's what Ralph.
They go up apparently they go up your
sinuses.
No,
I've never seen it,
bro.
They fuck with your brain,
Bro.
They massage your fucking brain brow
from saying uh.
Yeah.
You can roughing.
They're supposed to go all that shit.
Whoa.
Your sinuses?
Yeah.
Alright.
Coming incoming,
nervous.
Um,
yeah.
So this,
this tms thing,
transcranial magnetic stimulation
covered by blue cross.
Yeah.
Uh,
so yeah,
that's what,
like it's,
it's,
it was really,
really good.
Like I,
for a lot of my life I felt like I had
a,
I had like a,
a thing like a,
it almost felt like a metal weight,
like a bit of like five pound weight on
my upper left forehead.
My left.
And then so I went to this.
Whoa dude,
that sound is like an Mri.
Sounds.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
It is,
yes.
It's basically the same exact magnet as
an MRI,
but it's just made your day.
Yeah,
they put it on your head.
It's pretty simple.
The first time they measure it,
they have to get to like the exact spot.
Here's,
there's another video where my finger is
pulsing that you'll enjoy.
And what is it doing to you?
Like,
what's the benefit?
Uh,
it's basically magnetizing and
electrifying a.
it's waking up basically did a synopsis
according to them.
Really?
Yeah.
So it's,
it's waking up dead synapses and waking
up dead.
Waking them up so they're dormant.
Uh,
that's what they say.
You don't even look into it.
Good.
Shoot me on.
Yeah.
What is it can I do?
And this where I don't have kid man.
So I'm like,
yeah,
I don't give a shit.
Whatever,
whatever it's going to cost me.
I'm happy to do it.
If you had kids you think you wouldn't
do it?
I think
kids,
I'd be like,
you know,
sort of more,
more cautious about it.
Yeah,
probably because I'm not like reckless,
but I'm not.
I'm not like A.
I do recently.
It's also vague anyway,
the research.
It's also like,
I think it does this.
Most antidepressants they know.
They think they know what's happening.
They don't actually know.
Yeah.
That's a weird one.
When you think about how many people are
prescribed these things and then there's
not really a direct understanding of how
it impacts each.
Each person.
Like they'll tell you,
hey,
we'll try this medication and if it
doesn't work we'll try another one.
Yeah.
Does this one work will just cycle
through it and now how do you know if
it's working for you?
Or if you're having a good time in your
life and so you're feeling better
because maybe you started a new
relationship and a new job and it's
going well and hey,
it's just a.
everything seems pretty good.
I was on medications that made me
nauseous for a year and a half before I
was like,
you know what?
I literally thought I was nauseous
because I was eating too many lifesavers
and not even fucking kidding.
Literally.
I was like,
I gotta take it easy on these life
savers because every night I throw up
all the way to the laugh factory and
then I realized like,
you know,
Neil,
you're taking a pretty high dosage of
Zoloft.
You might want to just take it down a
notch.
That zoloft stuff is supposed to be
really weird for your discerning of what
matters and what doesn't matter.
Like,
like it's hard to.
I've never done it so it's hard for me
to describe it.
But yeah,
the people that I've talked to that have
done it and said one of the issues that
they had with it is nothing had the bad
things didn't feel bad anymore.
But the good things didn't feel good
either.
Well that's the,
with a lot
of antidepressants is they,
they raised the,
the floor,
uh,
and they also lowered the ceiling so
that it,
it narrows your band of experience,
basically a witch.
But if you're severely depressed it can
be very,
like,
like ketamine apparently is a lifesaver
truly for.
They may start administering it in a,
in emergency rooms for suicide cases.
Really?
Yeah.
Because it does,
it's dry.
I mean it's a,
it's a hallucinogen.
So you know,
hallucinogens will make you like see
things differently.
So they're starting to,
uh,
there at least they're talking about
administering it as a,
as a,
a sort of almost like a whatever that
drug is that you can do almost like an
Epi pen for,
for,
uh,
for suicide or suicide thought thinkers,
thinkers.
Yeah.
I'm about to do it.
Um,
so yeah,
so the,
so the tms,
transcranial magnetic stimulation,
half an hour of that,
of that debt,
that debt,
the debt doesn't feel like much.
Feels like a,
like a Shitty Woodpecker,
like a fucking sleepy woodpecker is sort
of going at your head.
But you're not like,
Hey,
get out of here where you're just kind
of like,
okay,
how much longer?
And you just sit there and watch TV.
Um,
and how many times are you supposed to
do it?
I,
you do it 40 times four.
Zero.
Four zero times half an hour.
And how deep are you in right now?
I'm done.
I finished it at 40.
Yeah,
I did all 40 in the fall.
Wow.
And uh,
and I'm telling you it lasted and um,
and you could go back for,
for um,
like sort of pick me ups every whenever
you feel like you need it.
Um,
so I'm telling you this is the thing
that has worked best for me better than
ketamine if way but better than them.
Zoloft.
Better than I was on a.
what's an Ssri?
Sarah?
This strategic Sarah Selective Serotonin
reuptake inhibitor.
Um,
and uh,
and went off at once.
I did this magnet shit.
So you know,
you're off everything.
Yeah.
Wow.
And you feel great.
Yeah.
Just no joy.
Well,
no joy,
but that's not what never had it.
You didn't lose nothing.
I just look at you kids have fun.
I'll be over here.
Yeah.
But it's not.
I'm not miserable and I'm not also,
there's no physical manifestation.
That's the biggest thing.
The,
the,
the head thing,
the feeling like there was a plate on my
head.
Getting rid of that was really,
really,
really great.
So when you say like a plate on your
head,
like there was a pressure or.
Yeah,
I have a little weight,
a little weight and a little pressure.
Did you ever when I want that in there?
No,
because there were times where I'd go
off of antidepressants and I have my jaw
muscles and muscles in my temple would
be so tight that I need to use like a
massager well on them.
So I knew that there was all,
it was all sort of connected.
Um,
you know,
Ding on his.
That was pretty sure that my thing,
unless it's me,
it might've been brown have been me bro.
It was your thing fuck up there yet.
Um,
so.
So that was a big one.
That was really helpful.
Then I did a,
it was in New York for a couple months,
did that show three mix,
which I think I talked to the premise
the you told me,
but tell say it on.
So the premise is onstage,
I put three Mikes equidistant apart from
each other.
One is for stand up,
one is for one liners that I just
couldn't fit anywhere.
And then one is for true sort of
emotional confession,
any type shit,
talking about depression,
talking about shit with my dad.
I'm like the sort of the,
I won't spoil the surprise but pretty
heavy shit between me and my dad when he
died or right before he died.
And then the,
and then the second monologue is about
um,
kind of about like celebrity and,
and,
and dealing with,
with the having a partner and then
breaking up and become my own guy and
all that shit.
Um,
so it's basically like it ends up being
probably 40 minutes of stand up 45,
stand up in a half hour of true stories
and then five minutes of one liners.
And did you do it after you had
completed your treatment?
I did,
yes.
I did it after.
Yeah.
And in the middle of it I actually
stopped taking everything and it in the
middle of recording or inactive in the
middle of nowhere,
in the middle of the run.
I had had an eight week run I think in
New York and uh,
and I stopped everything in the middle
of it.
It's not like suddenly just like,
I don't think I need it.
Wow.
Yeah.
Now,
what were the,
what's the difference when you get off
medication?
What was the difference in the way your
brain was functioning?
I can almost tell how well my brain's
functioning if I'm not depressed or not
slowed down by depression.
My associations are much quicker.
Like if you're just like the simplest
thing of like,
that guy looks like so and so like a
sort of a little rose,
like a little,
like what is that shirt fucking looks
like the kind of shirt.
Like if I'm not depressed I can think of
those quickly.
Uh,
if I'm depressed,
there were times where I'd get
depression would affect my memory.
Right.
I couldn't remember the,
the,
the test.
I would always do my head is there's a
guy who directed,
gone with the wind and the wizard of Oz
back to back.
He's.
Yeah,
and I would try to remember his name.
His name is Victor Fleming,
but if I was depressed I couldn't
remember it.
Like it affects your fucking a resource
thing,
like your brain is so concentrating on
the depression and feeling like shit
that just doesn't have the resources.
I think it.
I,
I tend to think it's more a dead synapse
thing and I think it's A.
I think it's an energy.
I think depression is a lack of energy
in the brain,
so in maybe you're right,
maybe it is.
It's all going to one place,
but that's my own personal
interpretation of it.
Well that makes sense in that,
in that way,
in that definition that a aerobic
exercise would benefit people that have
depression because they say that this
particularly running and a long form or
will be exercise.
It does something to stimulate brain
growth and brain function.
We also say like x,
if you want to remember something,
there was a thing last week or two we
feel about memory where if you want to
you should study then exercise and
you'll,
you'll have a better memory.
You'll,
you'll remember this shit.
You had your,
you studied for me,
there's nothing like physically writing
something down with a pen.
Yeah,
I think there's something to that too,
for sure.
Like where you see it because it is like
two senses.
You're hearing it in your head.
It's three.
You're hearing them in your head,
you're seeing with your eyes and you're
actually physically forming the thoughts
and I actually do say the words out to
when I write something down like a
slave,
say it like write it down.
You've got like and then like an
illiterate person you'll be like.
And then we were allowed to ride a bike
and then I went to the va that no
writing.
You're trying to keep them from getting
smart.
Well I had the thought yesterday.
Black people probably didn't wear
eyeglasses until they didn't.
They weren't,
they couldn't.
There was no.
Do you know what I mean?
Like nobody intends to them.
Certainly not bifocals.
Yeah.
They weren't being tested for vision.
It's.
You think about it for a second and you
can only.
All you can do is do it loud.
Exhale.
Yeah.
We've been talking about perspective
recently a lot.
It's come up a few times about how
insane.
Like yesterday we were talking about
slavery.
We're talking about the confederate war,
the civil war rather than the
confederate flag.
And we were just talking about how
insane it is that slavery was 18,
65.
It was abolished.
Like that is,
that's,
uh,
a week ago.
Yeah.
And you also think it ended immediately.
It didn't fucking end immediately.
No.
It ended like,
Hey,
see you eight guys.
We're going to try it.
It's like at the club where they turned
the lights on.
There's still people that are
stragglers.
There's people that don't want to leave.
There was also then it just shifted over
to sharecropping,
which was like,
yeah,
it's subsistence farming.
You can,
you're still going to live here.
A lot of people were sharecroppers.
I read a book called,
uh,
some of my best friends are black.
What seems ironic that I would read that
book,
but,
but uh,
it's about integration arrived because
some of your best friends with black.
Yeah,
ironic.
Uh,
but it's about integration I should say,
and it's written by a guy named tanner
colby who's going to.
It's insanely my name.
I'm literally off the charts.
Like if you were going to build a white
name,
it would be tanner colby and always
wearing a golf shirt.
Might as well be,
uh,
but he really went deep into
integration.
What was interesting was,
uh,
I highly recommend the book,
but he said You,
when you think about integration,
your resistance,
you go,
yeah,
white people didn't want it.
Black people didn't want it either,
but they were like,
we don't want to hang out with those
motherfuckers.
Like these black people didn't trust
white people any more than white people.
Trusted them.
Like it was a mutual suspicion.
At least black people had a case.
White people had no case.
Other than that,
I think white people,
a lot of racism is basically a white
people fearing karmic retribution.
I think when I think fear of black
people is like,
there is a Karma coming at me,
like it's almost like too black and you
think like if they,
if they did something to me,
I kind of have it coming historically.
So let me just kinda like these.
Even if you don't have it coming,
they can make the argument and uh,
and it's not a long argument and it's a
good argument.
Um,
so,
so that was interesting.
And again,
I think I've talked about and maybe I
haven't talked about in here that one of
the biggest proponents of integration
and ending red line and you know about
redlining,
redlining was a thing where a banks
would only give loans to people who
lived a,
they would circle lines on maps,
they'd circle neighborhoods and go,
if you live in that neighborhood,
you can't get a loan.
And guess who's neighborhoods?
They circled back people.
Uh,
so,
so black people couldn't move.
And the biggest,
the guy who ended it was Mitt Romney's
dad.
Well,
how about.
Yeah,
well,
how about Baltimore or Baltimore?
They had littoral areas of the town
where they would not sell it.
Black people.
Yeah,
they can't.
You can't unlearn what do you have?
Cash.
You can't move.
They literally can't
fucking move.
You could buy within that neighborhood,
but you just moved for the most part.
Couldn't get loans no matter what you
did
and isn't it ironic that in a lot of
those neighborhoods the saving grace
financially is white people gentrifying
the neighborhoods and making them like
super rich again?
Yeah.
My saving grace,
that saving grace for people that were
lucky enough to buy Roche has happened
more.
That's happening at a fairly good amount
of,
but in my neighborhood for the renters,
it's pushed out so it's like,
look,
you wanted the neighborhood to be worth
something again.
Yeah,
yeah,
but we can't afford it.
People are buying up these houses and
redoing them and then selling them for
shitloads of money will Benson Hurst,
which was always like this horrible
neighborhood.
Bensonhurst is over.
That's going through this wave of
gentrification mountains going through
like the entire burrows going through it
except for the poor.
The poor Italian neighborhoods are
pretty much the same,
but,
but yeah,
like the whole bed Stuy,
bedstuy,
Fort Greene,
Bensonhurst,
and those,
those,
those are the ones that we always
associated with like dead deep.
The racism,
the baseball bat racism spike the wife
Beater Baseball Bat,
real good.
Italian racism.
Real Italian sausage thick.
Yeah.
The fucking Ragu.
The real stuff.
Yeah.
Uh,
with men and goat.
Do you ever do a stand up in those
areas?
I did stand up in,
um,
in Bensonhurst once,
now.
Yeah.
There was a gig out there.
God,
I'm trying to remember where it was,
but it was.
I mean I might as well been a spike Lee
movie.
Yeah,
I'm sure it.
Did.
They like you.
I think at the time they did.
Did you start to remember,
use not like you play it up,
but you did it feel like,
well you could pass for Italian.
Are you a metallic.
Oh,
there you go.
That's why you passed.
I'm,
I've one quarter Irish,
but most,
most of it is Italian.
Yeah.
You seem Italian.
Like you.
Look,
you look Italian.
I mean that in the nicest possible way,
Joe.
Well,
when I went to Italy recently and I was
like,
oh,
now I see what's going on.
Those are some talking motherfuckers.
Oh yeah,
they talk up a storm.
But what's interesting is my driver,
uh,
we,
we got a cab and the driver was fucking
hilarious and not intentionally
hilarious and that this guy could not
stop staring at women.
He would like hit the brakes to look at
them better.
Oh,
look at.
Jesus calling was invented by Italian
dude.
Basically their pigs.
I mean this,
I mean in the most beautiful way.
Like it's kind of hilarious that this
got me.
He's,
he knew he wasn't gonna get the fuck
these women,
but in his mind,
like you had to slow down and head out
the window.
Hey,
fucking era with the fucking thing.
hey mama,
hey.
But they so stair there staring at these
women.
There's this a framed poster that I have
on my wall at home.
It's an American girl in Italy and all
the dudes are whistling in the
background and they're grabbing their
dicks and it's 1954 and I remember
looking at that when I was a kid
thinking,
wow,
this lady in this photo is probably like
100 years old now.
Right?
Or dead.
More likely dead.
But like these guys like this isn't.
This isn't like something they learned
from Washington Soprano's like,
here it is.
This is the photo.
Oh No,
I know.
Absolutely.
Grabbing his Dick and look at the old
man who's got his arms inside the
jacket.
The jacket just thrown over.
Shoulders guys.
Sharing a,
a nice guy.
The guy in the school?
No,
not the finest broad we've ever seen
either.
Well,
it's hard to tell because she's got this
look on their face.
Like,
oh my God.
Yeah,
I guess I guess it's all relative.
but,
but it's just that it's a girl by
herself walking past this cafe and all
these pigs.
There is this weird thing in their
harassment,
uh,
which is like a maternal respect to it.
It's like you're beautiful.
Like a my mama
that's like built into it,
whereas American harassment doesn't
really have that.
Whereas the Italian harassment,
there's a certain little fucking little
maternal like,
Hey Mama,
Mama,
Mama.
Because those guys,
there was a big thing a few years ago on
60 minutes were Italian guys don't move
out so it will be in their mid thirties
and their moms don't want her to move
out.
They don't want to move out.
They're like,
I don't,
I may not get married.
No one can compare it to Mama.
Just Italian guys in Italian.
Guys in Italy.
Yeah.
That's always been an issue with tying
guys in the east coast too.
That live in America.
Yeah.
Well they got it from,
from,
uh,
from.
Would you ever live in la?
I think.
No.
Go on.
Fuck that.
Blake.
Go on.
No,
no.
Well,
first of all,
I can't speak Italian and I don't have
enough time.
I mean,
I just don't learn.
You're not really interested.
Second,
if you liked the lifestyle though,
I guess my question,
I loved being there.
I love it.
I don't need to like live somewhere to
experience it for a week or so.
I think we're there for eight days is
beautiful man.
Like we went to the Mafia coast.
Holy Shit.
Is that pretty?
Yeah,
pretty.
And I think the Vatican,
the Vatican is a life changing
experience.
Go on Hook.
Why do you say that?
It's immense.
Oh,
it's hilarious.
First of all,
they have a 4,000
year old obelisk in the center of the
town.
Yeah.
I mean you look at some of the artifacts
and some of the stuff that they've
collected there.
There's so much shit there that it's
just laying around stuff that would be
under two,
two inch thick glass and America.
You could walk up and touch it.
They're,
they're like new shit would be our
oldest shit.
It's amazing.
And it's amazing.
Church in Rome.
I was,
I used to go there pretty often because
I was dating a girl that lived there
and,
and a long distance relationship.
It wasn't that serious joe.
Um,
but no,
I remember she worked
dating in air quotes.
Thrust your girl.
I knew I knew a girl in the Oval Office
and uh,
no,
she just telling me that he had,
I have a piece of Jesus's cross and it
was like believable.
Do you know what I mean?
Like I don't even think they made a big
deal out of it.
Like there weren't a ton of signs about
it.
Like that would be like a,
a huge attraction that would be like the
number one attraction in,
in,
in certain states,
in America.
Well there's a church in Ethiopia that
is purported to contain the lost Ark of
the covenant and they know,
they know where the tree and they have
the architect.
This is what,
it's weird.
The people that guard this church,
they all have like cataracts and shit.
And it's,
it's,
it's a very strange thing.
This is all from Graham Hancock's book
where a,
it's one of the first things that got
him into this idea of like lost
civilizations and that the idea that
people had come up with like some pretty
high level of sophistication in their
societies.
But then the societies would crumble
either due to natural disasters or war
whatever.
And then they would have to sort of
rebuild civilization,
but he was investigating this one church
in Ethiopia where the people that guard
this church in Ethiopia,
it's like a very specific sect and they
won't allow anyone to get into the
sacred secret areas of it.
And the speculation was that somewhere
inside that church is the lost Ark of
the covenant and that the reason why
these people have cataracts and the
reason why these people have all these
issues like health issues,
it could possibly be that what's in that
last arc of the covenant is some sort of
a,
a toxic element,
whether it's nuclear or whether it's
chemical or whether it would stand to
reason if you watch the raiders of the
lost Ark that makes those guys' faces
melt.
Right?
It sure does.
I don't know what could be substantiated
if anything,
your face melt unless you close your
eyes,
you know,
like one of those things or.
Well,
look,
if someone came up with some sort of a
nuclear reactor,
you know,
there was a kid that got arrested.
I'm going to close my eyes if there's a
nuclear blast.
And just hope for the best.
That's a move.
Like when bugs bunny would jump out of
an airplane right before it hit the
ground.
Exactly right.
But there was a kid that they found,
um,
I forget where he was,
but he was building a nuclear reactor in
his fucking backyard,
I want to say he was 17 and someone
found it somehow or another they found
it.
They're like,
what the fuck are you doing?
But if this kid can do that in 2016,
the idea is if there was some sort of
super highly advanced law civilization
that had reached an incredible level of
sophistication when it came to,
you know,
the ability to manipulate matter and
possibly even come up with some sort of
a reactor and that,
that was what the Ark of the covenant
was.
That's why it was so sacred and
fascinating because they realized they
had an immense power,
but that,
that power was probably like some sort
of a small reactor.
That would be cool.
I hope when.
That'd be cool.
Be Crazy.
It all ended up being true.
Well then they know for sure that
they've found batteries,
they found batteries in Baghdad and uh,
I believe in some of the ancient
Egyptians sites that what it is is a
very ancient sort of a method of
creating a battery like that.
That's 100 percent confirmed that I
believe.
Yeah.
And that's confirmed.
They know that they did come up with
something and they,
you know,
they figured out a way to use that
battery.
There it is right there.
That's the Baghdad battery.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Yeah.
How old?
That's old as fuck.
I don't want to say,
I want to say it's at least three or
4,000
years old.
Find out how old that fucker is.
How,
let's guess I say it's 4,000
years old.
Three.
I'm going to go to to 2000.
No,
let's see.
What does it say?
No.
Well they must be able to carbon date
it.
Nineteen 38.
They found it in the 19 thirties.
So to say how old it is.
That's all I want to know.
Speculation,
speculation.
Some believe that it was [inaudible]
doesn't say age.
40 elements.
Battery hypothesis,
nothing.
Civic it,
um,
so,
but see if you can find actually before
he can find out,
see if he could find the thing about the
guys who guard the Ark of the Covenant
in Ethiopia because apparently these,
these monks,
that guard,
they all fucked up eyes.
That was one of the things that Graham
Hancock thought was like super
disturbing when he started investigating
it and was like,
why is he got why these guys have all
cataracts and shit.
Like what?
What's happening?
And if somebody can come up with a
battery,
obviously there's a big step between a
battery and some sort of a reactor,
but if this kid in his fucking backyard
is building a reactor,
who knows,
they had enough,
a high level of sophisticated should
whole.
They had a high enough level of
sophistication with the able to
construct the pyramid.
Right?
Look at the Great Pyramid.
It's an incredible piece of engineering.
Two million,
300,000
stones all cut.
So precisely.
You can get a razor blade in between the
rocks.
I mean especially if you look in
tie up at the pyramid.
Do you think you needed to be to get.
Do you know what I mean?
[inaudible] like in like is there.
No,
but I'm saying in terms of,
you know,
in terms of like what you do,
what your position was.
That's another pitch.
I got an office on the eighth floor of
the pyramid.
The point I want to hear this,
my office is up at the point.
If you worked on the builders,
probably didn't that probably.
Although I don't know how,
how what the.
If if jobs were considered a big deal
back,
they used to think they were slaves.
They don't think their slaves anymore.
They stopped thinking they were slaves
about a decade ago.
I think when they.
They uncovered some of the little camps
that the people used to live in and buy
the food that they were eating and by
the quality of the clothes and the
plates,
they think they were skilled workers.
They don't think they were slaves in.
Which makes sense because you're.
You're talking about something that if
you $2 million,
300,000
stones.
I think the way they described it as if
you cut and placed 10 stones a day,
it would take you 664 years.
So how long did they think it took?
They weigh between two and 80 tons.
They don't know.
They don't know how long it took,
but they know that it was constructed
somewhere in the neighborhood of 2,500
BC based on carbon dating.
So they don't even know who exactly
which pharaoh built it like this.
They get real weird with like what,
what they go on in
terms of like,
what's the evidence that someone made
this or like one of them is this finks
the way they,
uh,
decided to attribute the Sphinx to one
guy where there's a passage that it says
that he,
it came to him in a dream that if he
uncovered this,
thinks that he would be the pharaoh.
He would become the Pharaoh of Egypt if
he uncovered it.
And so the speculation by the people
that are sort of back dating history is
that the Sphinx could have entirely been
covered in sand.
It could be incredibly ancient because
when Napoleon found it,
it was covered in sand when,
uh,
when people found in the 18 hundreds is
actually photographs of it before they
had dug it out and excavate it.
Actually
shooting the nose off.
Is that a fake thing?
Supposedly is true.
Somebody fuck the nose up.
Whether it was Napoleon or one of his
crew.
That's.
I don't know if they know that for sure.
I know.
They do know that the nose and the face
are different from the original nose and
face.
The original face they think was an
alliance.
Well,
that's amazing.
Like just people's love of faces.
Like there's a human you've ever heard.
I feel like I've talked about it weird
that there was a,
they,
they put a monkey's.
It's like,
it's a,
it's a defensive like star power and
charisma.
They put a monkeys in a lab.
They gave them the option of unlimited
cherry flavored juicy juice.
Or they could watch video of the leader
of their pack and they chose watching
video of the leader of the pack.
Wow.
This thing in human beings like needing,
needing kind of God's needing a,
some sort of pillar or needing something
to like it also,
it speaks to this charisma,
isn't it
possible?
Also though that what they really needed
is to get the fuck out of that cage and
that the leader of their pack on a video
maybe like,
let them know your message.
Maybe someone's going to let me out of
here.
I mean there's just pay attention.
Maybe.
Yeah.
But that's also something to like.
There's something about certain people
you just like watching,
like there's a certain element of
charisma,
charm,
whatever you want to say.
Like certain people that you see them
and you're like,
okay,
it's the definition of charisma is you
want to say yes before,
you know what the question is
[inaudible] uh,
and,
and monkeys,
monkeys got it.
Joe,
they got this,
they got the effect on the Italian thing
and got that thing.
They got this thing.
Well that,
that sort of makes sense if you think
about kings and pharaohs and the fact
that,
that there's always been this Alpha
character.
There's always been this one ruler for
pretty much every
realization,
every single city,
every single state,
every single country always has that one
charismatic leader that stands in front
of the people and lifts his hands up and
everything.
That's the thing that people
underestimate.
I don't think we should talk about trump
for a long time,
but.
But that's.
He's got a lot of charisma.
Say what you want to love the guy.
He's got a ton of charisma and that's
weird.
Kind of charisma.
Yeah.
He's got like this mean guy charisma.
You want him to like you.
So you say things like you don't even
believe.
Yeah,
because you want him to think that
you're on his side so he won't come
after you.
Yeah.
That's a bully charisma.
That's absolutely right.
But it's charisma nonetheless.
That's the.
And that's the thing about stars and
movie stars and stuff like that.
It's like you're watching this guy.
You Watch Denzel Washington waiting for
him to snap.
He never does.
But your weight,
you can tell he's gonna.
He just doesn't.
It's like Robert Downey Jr.
I feel like with robert downey jr,
you're watching a guy not do cocaine.
Yeah.
He wants to do everythIng in him,
wants to do cocaine.
So you're watching a guy not actively,
not do cocaine from second to second.
That's such a good analysis.
Yeah.
You just watching this guy,
this thing,
this car accident.
That never happens.
Yeah.
You're watching a guy struggle slightly
with.
Yes.
You're struck.
You're wondering.
I almost want you to see it on him.
It's kinetic.
He's just got a little bit and that
little bit allows him to be like snaRky
and weird and get away with that.
He didn't get his medicine,
but you could almost do that with,
with a lot of dramatics.
There's comedy stores less so,
but there's something about tom cruise,
that's that.
Oh yeah,
for sure.
Right.
Like you're just watching.
I Don't know if he's.
He's not going to snap.
He's almost going to like fly away or
something.
Well,
he'll snap.
If you talk about like psych psychiatric
drugs like matt lauer,
you're glip.
Matt was amazing.
Yeah,
that was.
That was a perfect example of why really
big time movie stars should not have
podcasts 100 percent.
Right.
You're absolutely right.
But it's also a testament to his
charisma that he said that and we're
still like,
eh,
fuck it.
I need to be a movie star more than I
need him to agree with me about
religion.
Yeah.
He bounced back.
But what's really interesting is what he
bounces back on,
like is most successful is these
wackadoo fucking science fiction movies.
That's where he's done the best since
that,
the,
uh,
the day after tomorrow thing or
whatever,
that edge of tomorrow beginning.
What is it?
There's two of them.
He did two of them.
He did two.
They did like one the mission impossible
for the ones that,
those.
Or is that too?
Yeah,
that's true.
But that's.
Tomorrow movie was a good movie.
Fucking very good.
Yeah.
You don't was a really good movie and I
don't know if deadpool,
deadpool,
I couldn't fucking believe how much I
love deadpool.
Sought on a,
on an and he
kept cutting out and it was still
excellent.
Yes.
Like,
I'm not going to say it was perfect,
but there were some there moment to
moment.
It was as good a movie as I can
remember.
Yeah.
For a superhero movie is probably as
good as it gets.
Yeah,
I totally agree.
Yeah.
That was a really good movie.
It was very,
very pleased with that movie because I
had no expectations.
Yeah.
And at the end he still gets to bang the
girl,
so there you go.
The way they bang that banging montage
was great.
And then him putting up a picture of
what's his name and his face Just like,
oh,
that's really fun.
It's like where they let writers write
well,
like,
yeah,
just,
that's a funny idea.
So we'll just do that.
Well,
I saw ghostbusters,
I didn't see it and I liked,
which I feel awful about.
There's some funny shit in ghostbusters.
Like overall it's not a good movie.
This is not a good movie.
But they did some funny shit.
They,
they came up with some fun and I almost
want to know like,
man,
what could this have been if you let
whoever came up with all that.
Funny shit just make,
make a movie out of it where they scenes
where they died.
It was a dialogue,
scenes and dialogue.
There were scenes in.
It was such a combination of things.
That movie and it's so had the feeling
of the hands of the producers and the
executives.
It's so handled that what
you you.
In some ways.
the thing I liked about deadpool was I
was watching it going.
The producers of this movie did a good
job where they were like,
this moment doesn't work.
Make it work everYday.
Like micromanage.
Like I worked on chris rock's going to
be top five a little bit for a couple of
consulting for a couple of weeks and the
producers is guy named scott rudin who's
like a famous producer and what I
couldn't believe was the level of detail
that guy was worried about.
It was He busted christmas balls for a
year,
but the script literally made them
rewrite and rewrite and rewrite and
rewrite and rewrite and then onset.
The guy was worried about shirts and
buttons and that's what I realized like
okay,
these deadpool producers.
Whereas it feels like maybe on
ghostbusters that got,
you got to get,
you have to get lucky too with studio
where they they,
you all haven't agreed to set of of
what's good and then you build them over
from.
There was also this a problem that the
movie had a very clear agenda to be a
pro woman move,
which gets means nothing wrong with
being pro woman,
but if that's.
It's like a.
It's a goofy.
It's not a theme for a movie.
A comedy movie.
Yeah.
All the men are buffoons.
They're not just buffoons there.
There cartoonishly retarded.
Yeah.
Like chris,
whatever the fuck stands for.
thor is so retarded.
It doesn't even make sense.
Yeah.
He's,
he's so fucking stupid.
It doesn't make sense.
But they keep them around because he's
beautiful and it's like the joke.
Well that's a funny,
but I,
I liked these revenge jokes where it's
like,
so you're just going to do what men did.
How long is this gonna last?
Like what's the next?
It's easy a man to say like,
hey,
do something else honey.
But like,
but it just feels like there's got to be
like a next,
uh,
next.
Uh,
there's a lot of like rep retribution
right now.
Twitter is it blood just wasn't
believable.
A lot of what twitter is.
Twitter is it,
it's a lot of people.
It's like digital lynch mobs of people
that are rightly so.
They'll go after people for saying
something fucked up about race.
Like they went up to juStin timberlake a
few weeks ago because he said some of
them were all the same and then it's
like,
but you can't say that and it just
becomes this mob of people.
And it's purely about racial revenge
as far as I'm concerned.
well it's definitely about people having
the opportunity to shit on
people that didn't have the opportunity
to before and now they have it via.
They,
they have social cache and they have
social power and they use it for the
same bullshit of white people use it
for.
Well it's not even just black people
doing it.
It's a lot of white people,
women,
any,
any sort of marginalized group,
whether it's poor,
any like literally any group.
this movie like this is,
there's a bunch of problems with the
moving,
but this,
the fact that all the men in the movie
were ridiculous.
All the men this mover buffoons all the
men in the movie,
like they,
like bill murray gets fucking killed in
it.
Spoiler alert.
I mean it,
it's weird.
It's weird.
It's like it's an agenda driven movie
more than they'd wrote something.
They figured,
well,
it'll work if you do this or if it'll
work if you do that.
Like they didn't even have romantic
interests in the movie because men were
just so retarded.
Like the women didn't have boyfriends.
They didn't have husbands.
It didn't have like they had chris
hemsworth.
Yeah.
But that's it.
And he was just eye candy.
Well,
the thing we
tell people is when you're writing about
a specific gen,
like for a long time,
women in comedy,
women in comedy movies were a props or
they were like,
andie macdowell always used to be like
the love interest in,
uh,
and she was always just like this warm,
sort of like vaguely disapproving.
It's either like you're disapproving of
the guy or you're approving to a fault
because that's,
if you're,
if there's a movie about a certain,
uh,
gender,
which was usually men,
the women in their lives for the plot to
advance.
They didn't have to be for the plot or
against the plot.
Right?
So then women started complaining like,
will you see us as these binary goofy
things?
And obviously women in life are more
complex than that.
So,
so now that women are starting to get
their own movies and it's about groups
of women,
you see it's,
it's a writing problem.
It's,
you're in a trap where the men and
bridesmaids were goofy as fuck.
It was an irish cop in milwaukee.
Tell me more,
because I've never seen that my whole
life.
A guy who's just like in bridesmaids is
a fucking masterpiece for the most part.
Just that part.
I was kind of like,
wait,
so he's a cop and he's got an endless
uh,
appetite for wig even though she's not
interested in was it?
It was dicky to him,
but he still,
he'll take her back,
whatever,
and it becomes about.
He's basicallY the only man in the movie
and it's kind of a goofy part and it's
once because it's about a group of women
and that's just the purpose that men
have in that plot,
you know what I mean?
But they,
but they always say people take it as
like this a sexism thing and I just take
it as like a screenwriting thing.
Well,
it is that definitelY.
But one of the problems that people have
found when they're talking about this
movie is that you can't criticize it
because if you criticize that your sex.
Yeah.
And no,
it's not.
It's not a good piece of art.
Yeah,
there you go.
It's not really well done.
But who did,
who did bridesmaids that I'm talking
about the same guy who did it.
He's done whatever.
He's done it twice now,
but like I think he knows he's a really
good writer.
Like he knows you can use.
It's hard to write because it's never
been.
I always tell people,
listen,
I go show me a good example of a,
a movie about a group of guys where the
woman isn't just even in deadpool,
she's a prop to the in love with them
unconditionally.
Even though his face turns into a
monster,
she still wants him to eat her pussy and
they make fun of it.
Yeah.
They make fun of it in a funny way.
Like their meetup there,
meet cute and then they think about like
the damage they both are.
That was like perfect to me because it
was brief and it,
it's like the thing they always
complained about when you're developing
movies,
like I don't buy this couple and I can't
fucking mouthing.
Sorry.
I don't buy a lot of real couples.
Well,
not only that,
they have to spell it all out in two
hours.
Yeah.
And they have to meet and fall in love
with him.
Five minutes.
Well,
there's a lot more to a relationship in
that.
Yeah.
We can't show you all that other shit.
Because that takes hours,
days and weeks and months and you fuck.
That is correct.
The sad thing about the movie,
the ghostbusters movie is there's some
stuff in it that was really clever.
There was funny stuff and I,
in the beginning I was enjoying it.
I was like,
you know what?
I bet people are not given this thing a
fair shake.
And then as it got on and I was like,
oh,
they just.
This is just so clunky.
Yeah.
There's parts of it that were just so
clumsy and poorly because every single
one of those women are fucking home run
hitters.
Yeah.
Melissa mccarthY is fucking funny,
man.
The dude.
She's fucking funny wig.
Kristen wiig.
Which one?
She,
uh,
she was in bridesmaids.
I don't,
I don't know what.
She's the auburn haired woman.
Yeah.
Leslie's a fucking monster.
She's,
she's handicapped in and they give her
some clunky lines.
Uh,
and then,
uh,
the girl from snl,
kate mckinnon is really,
really.
She was really funny in it.
Yeah.
She was very funny in it,
but it's not that bad.
I mean,
I didn't it.
I want to see what my kids.
They enjoyed it.
But um,
there was,
there were some moments I laughed pretty
hard.
Great.
But most of it not.
yeah.
Well,
it's hard to make funny movies,
man.
At the end,
they way they wrap it up,
you're like,
oh,
christ,
get the fuck out of here.
It's like,
it's so clumsy.
Oh,
that's just so awkward because nobody
told me there were no stakes in the
movie.
It was just like,
yeah,
there's ghosts and we're going to fight
him.
Uh,
we got them.
Yeah.
It is weird.
It's hot fucking mean.
It's making a funny good movies.
Really hard budget budget movie.
A big budget with a legacy and a star in
a,
in a release date.
Yeah.
And if they just see if there was no
ghostbusters before it,
there'd never been a ghostbuster movie.
And this was the first ever ghost buster
movie.
There wouldn't,
we wouldn't be talking about sponsors.
It would be different.
yeah.
well it may be.
People would enjoy it more and maybe
they wouldn't be so handicapped because
they had to sort of connect with the
legacy and tie all these loose ends in
and they could kind of do it anyway they
want,
but that's really a car.
Whenever You try to redo an old movie,
even if you do a great job like member
jason statham redid the mechanic like,
dude,
I didn't know that was a remake of
fucking charles bronson movie.
You don't even know that.
Oh my god.
Charles bronson and that handsome fella
from those seventies who went crazy a,
god damn it.
What is this?
No,
that was another one.
What is his name?
Charles bronson in the mechanic.
What does the other.
He was this really handsome actor who
became like a crazy alcoholic.
He was really huge.
And Michael Vincent,
he would've been the next.
He was really huge back then.
Like he was beautiful frame right there.
Look at that hair and this just
tombstones in the banks and protestants
all time favorites.
It was korean.
So,
um,
we called graphic right there.
Jess.
Perfect.
And bY the way,
no video.
That's film.
Ladies and gentlemen,
that's,
that's where kennewick,
it's american.
Back then when they,
um,
would do a movie like this too.
I mean,
like,
you didn't get that many movies every
week.
It's not like today.
Jan Michael Vincent played his,
um,
his protege and charles bronson was a
hitman.
You saw this in the theater tv.
I think I saw it on television the first
time.
It was 1972.
I don't think I've ever seen a charles
bronson movie.
So he revenge is right.
Who the fuck are you?
Is not a revenge movie necessarily.
I mean,
in some ways it kind of is,
but really,
which is a revenge movie,
right?
yes.
Death wish was a,
a,
a white man's dream.
The white man,
his daughter,
something,
a bunch of,
a bunch of dark skin.
People don't remember exactly what the,
what the premise behind it was.
I don't know who that guy
is,
but I like him.
He's interesting.
Um,
but charles bronson and jan,
Michael Vincent,
uh,
they had this movie,
you know,
which was a classic movie at the time
and then it was redone with jason
statham and this other guy who is a
really good actor who foster that same
ben foster who was in that movie 30 days
of night.
Jefferson,
that movIe.
No,
I didn't see that.
But he was molested a in.
He was getting another movie with woody
harrelson.
Yeah.
About the,
about Iraq.
Yes.
I know what you're talking about.
I don't remember the name.
He's great in everything.
That fucking guy.
He's,
he such a good actor.
There.
He is all creepy looking.
Um,
so He played the jam.
Michael vincent character,
which is an interesting sort of twist on
things.
It wasn't a bad movie.
It was a pretty good movie.
I enjoyed it like as far as like a
mindless action movie,
but you're redoing a fucking charles
bronson movie man.
As soon as,
as soon as you try to redo a charles
bronson movie,
do you have
any desire for remakes?
I'm never like,
oh,
thank god the remake and it.
Because I just would rather watch the
original because it contains everything
that I want,
which is the actual movie and then the,
the memories I have of it.
I liked when they remade the hulk
because he kept doing it like over and
over and over again.
I'm like funny fucking guy trying to bit
that never gonna work,
but
did it with the eric bana.
That was shit.
That was the.
That was the super emotional one,
right?
that was the only one that was like very
emotional.
Yes.
I got to say I didn't really like the
last avengers,
the I should say the first vendors
because it just seemed like,
like they just spent the whole movie
just like,
hey,
you guys want to,
you got to come fight.
And they'd be like,
nah,
I don't want to know.
You got to come.
All right.
I'll come.
And then they had a big fight at the
end,
but the hulk one was especially shitty.
I saw the avengers right after I saw x
mokena,
which was one of my all time favorite
movies ex back and it was very good.
Yeah.
Incredible.
I saw,
I saw that one week and then I saw the
avengers the next week and I was like,
this is shit.
This clunky.
Yes,
fucking movie.
But,
but homeboy played away better hawk.
What's the fuck's his name?
Mark refollow.
Buffalo.
And then add an orange to was in the
original.
No,
he did the second one deal.
He just doesn't want to fight.
He's very strong,
but he's not interested.
No.
Scientists.
The scientists was doing an experiment
and he was exposed to massive levels of
gamma radiation and when he gets angry
he don't want green.
I want to know.
I understand.
I don't want.
I'm not interested in that.
yes,
he's angry all the time.
That's,
that's mark rufallo secret.
Oh,
is that true?
Sacred.
Oh,
got it.
Yeah.
So it was a rageaholic yeah,
he just keeps it together and he's been
at any moment he could just let it go
and when he decides to let it go and he
can't,
can't
control it because why isn't it just one
of these things like in the vendors it
seemed like they were like,
hey,
come help us with this
specific guy.
And He did tough to get them to pay
attention,
but that's the brothers,
right?
You can't,
he can't guide it because it just seems
like,
hey,
how calm.
And he's like,
but I don't.
You guys are going to make me get angry.
It seems like a small price to pay.
Like yeah,
fucking get a little bit angry guy.
You're going to need you to save the
world.
Save the world.
You fucking selfish fucking animal.
Well,
when they would go to find him the first
time he's in Bangladesh,
like boy,
he was in the.
Yeah,
he was in like at a,
at a like an remember that save the
children type.
Yeah.
I feel like I've given money to support
whatever the hulk is working,
whatever.
Dr.
Bruce.
And they'd come and get him with fucking
rifles drawn and everything like that.
Like to realize like you can't do that.
like that violence is getting mad.
and now read the dossier.
Do you don't have anything but guns.
What are you gonna stop them.
Yeah,
like don't move.
I'm like,
oh jesus,
you got me.
You know,
you don't have.
Don't move.
Oh,
don't move.
Don't move.
what if I fucking move?
What are they going to do?
They're going to shoot him before he
moves.
They can do anything.
You have bad news for the hulk.
Wait until just the right moment to
tell.
So you and also your wife fucking
somebody and then you fucking run up.
Well,
maybe that would be the way that you
would get them to stop in the hall.
Just give them ecstasy.
oh,
that's funny.
Yeah.
Just,
that's the new treatment for the hawk.
Just keep them on.
Very micro doses of ecstasy all day
long.
If he knew,
I know a ketamine guy if you need.
Um,
I also am a little mad that
uh,
lou ferrigno is not involved because he
to me was the ultimate hoke with a rip
george ripped jorts the ripped jeans
shorts.
That is always going to be the problem
with the hawk is how the fuck are those
pants still on?
Yeah,
it should be a dick flapping.
Oh,
for sure.
Mark.
Look,
I can'T even wear pants from someone who
weighs 20 pounds less than me.
Yeah.
Just to add to the brown corduroys,
that's how we used to do it back then.
Joey brown fucking corteroids.
Well,
it was supposed to be purple.
The hulk always had purple pants.
Oh,
that's interesting.
For whatever reason,
weird fucking seeds.
Blue jeans.
But if you go to the hulk,
like the cartoon hawk,
you'll see that he always had purple
pants.
Green and purple or a better man.
The hulks pants.
P a n,
t.
You've watched
pumping iron,
right?
Look at that.
See always purple.
Yeah.
What the fuck is that?
You have seen pumping.
Are you see the new one generation iron?
No.
Good.
It's on.
It's on netflix.
It's a banger.
Really?
It's also got one of my favorite moments
in a documentary ever.
Which if you want to bring it up,
I and you don't laugh at this,
then you then you're not yourself.
This is like an alien test,
like.
No,
this is joe rogan.
I believe it's joe rogan.
If you've laughed at this,
well then now you're setting it up.
It's a wasted moment.
There's an I know.
I it.
It's that good.
What's the funniest moment?
I've ever seen the documentary.
Really?
Yes.
Are you going to spoiler?
I'm not going.
No,
I'm not going to spoil it.
Should we play it a?
Yeah.
If you bring it up on netflix,
I will show you where it is.
MighT not be able to do that.
Fifty four minutes in time.
ReCommend this clip a lot it.
Don't you think the clip is probably on
youtube?
if it's says strong,
maybe.
What is it?
Why don't you say a generation?
Iron horse generation.
Iron horse.
Seen separate words.
Interest.
I stand by it.
So is it a,
just a new film?
A new film.
Alright,
back it up.
Back it up,
Pause it.
Okay.
Oh fuck you.
You ain't gotta.
Hear the guy.
set it up.
Go all the way to the back of the clip.
I dOn't think it's long enough if you
show.
And if you show me another one,
the guy talks about.
You see what it is,
guy riding a horse,
right?
If you go back,
uh,
to.
And the thing is he talked about how he
never gets injured.
Oh,
he's liteRally talking about die.
Never get injured.
People say,
get injured.
I wasn't even a real injury and now a
pass.
Two injuries I've had.
Well,
we're in the gym.
They were outside the gym,
so I haven't been hurt in the gym since
2003.
That's go.
Oh shit.
The horse just decided enough.
Yeah,
he was at the horse has had enough of
him taLking about never being injured.
The horse,
he's talking about not getting injured
and the horse throws him off the fucking
horse.
It's such fucking poetry to me and he
lands hard.
He lands hard and says,
oh jesus.
As he lands,
he's so big.
You would think that guy is like,
well,
I guess he's kind of protected a little
bit.
All that muscle.
You see that car accident sculpture?
Yes.
Yeah,
that's right up your alley.
Yeah.
Well explain what you're talking about.
There's a day.
There was an art installation.
Ate so many sculpture of what the human
body would need to look like to
withstand a car accident,
to evolve in order to be able to
withstand car accidents and know how the
fuck they figured this out though.
That's one of the weird things,
so I was like,
why their arms so skinny,
like damn one inch or one image of it.
There's some cars.
There's nothing important in the arms to
protect your brain and your heart.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
Why does it have nipples?
Like what are all those nipples over the
rib cage?
Um,
I think those are like panning.
Maybe those are nipples,
whatever it is.
Those are like when you first get
nipples,
when you're of those,
what are those things?
Ridges.
Isn't it funny that what we look at
today,
when we see a person,
we think it's normal,
but it's just what we're used to is what
happened.
It's just what we are.
I mean,
people are fucking weird looking by the
way.
They didn't do any favors with the,
with the facial hair and the haircut.
Yeah.
It's a weird goatee.
LIke why I'm like,
you look extra monkey ish.
It looks very odd.
It's really disgusting.
He has a weird choice.
And also the like the line to heaven
down to his pecker hairline.
Yeah.
It's a weird,
weird hair trail.
Like what is going on there?
It looks like a constellation space.
Shit.
Or like a tesla coil.
Yeah.
Radiating air.
It's uh,
I don't,
I guess.
Do you have a tesla?
You don't know?
I do not.
Oh,
you made the observation or maybe it was
you or bird maybe.
Absolutely.
What if there's a power outage?
Yeah.
Well tHat's,
there's that for sure.
But all.
I drove one for a day and I was shocked
at how quick the battery went down.
Oh really?
Yeah,
I drove,
I drove from here to my house,
to the improv,
a to my house to here again.
And it was more than half
dead.
And how many miles was it?
100.
That's not even 60.
That's too bad.
Yeah.
I mean maybe maybe 70,
80,
maximum.
Maximum 80.
And it was more than half dead.
so like when they say you can go 300
miles without a charge or what are they
saying to 5,250
miles.
That's under ideal conditions on the
highway.
Sixty five miles an hour.
Drafting behind a fucking semi.
It's not like stop and go traffic.
It's not,
it's not a,
it's not speeding up,
slowing down.
It's not ligHts.
That's.
It's not ready.
I think it's ready.
I think it's,
I mean depending on how far you need to
go,
that's half full.
It's still pretty good.
Well sure.
You could use the average person only
drives 35 miles a day.
Yeah,
I mean you could for sure you could use
it as a daily driver if you could plug
it in every night,
but it's not ready for me to adopt.
it's just so limited that the fact that
it takes so long to recharge like you
can,
you can charge in for a certain amount
of time and I'll give you like 80
percent or the idea that maybe they
could swap batteries.
you pull into a place and they take your
batteries out and give you new
batteries.
But then you've got to trust that
they're connecting the batteries.
Right.
You've got to trust that the batteries
are good.
You've got to trust who,
who had the batteries before anybody
dropped muckrack.
Um,
are they going to like my fucking car on
fire now?
Because that was one of the issues that
they were having with people in the
chevy volt.
I have not.
There's been.
No,
I get 300 miles a gallon.
That's a hybrid though,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
what the teslas,
when they first came out,
we're developing issues where the
underbody would get hit by rocks and
would start.
And then,
uh,
do you remember the fisker fiscal karma?
Yeah.
Do you know how that would killed that
thing?
No.
What happened?
Remember that big storm that hit the
east coast?
There was a big storm that hit the east
coast.
Sandy one.
Yeah.
I think that was a couple of years back.
Um,
destroyed a lot of houses in long
island.
that was hurricane sandy.
They hit a port,
the,
the storm hit a port where these things
were parked and apparently when they get
up to the door height and water,
they explode.
Look at this.
This is the,
uh,
see that sales,
those fires going on over there.
And the,
since the,
that's the trigger of former.
That's not the cars.
That's the transformer.
That's the transformer on the east
village.
Is this a different video that says con
ed explosion?
No,
you got the wrong.
There's,
but there's one that's like this.
It's pretty similar to find the video of
the hurricane sandy fires.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Maybe they don't have a video of it.
See if he can find it.
Anyway,
point being those things.
When you get them wet,
they blow up.
That's good.
No,
it's not great and people don't like
that.
So that company went under.
Yeah,
I have a volt.
It's been great.
That's a good move.
Like a hybrid is a really good move.
Yeah,
because it's like gas and electricity
and kind of run on both 40 electricity
every charge and I can charge it in four
hours for a full chart and pickups.
Good drives.
Good.
I'm not like,
I never really need.
I'm like,
the only time I'm using pickup is when
I'm driving like a dickhead,
bright,
you know what I mean?
So it's like you're trying not to drive
like that,
but if I'm cutting people off and doing
shit like that,
then you need the I need to pick up
because I'm an asshole.
right.
uh,
but for the most part I don't need
pickup like day to day.
You can only go so fast.
Well one of the cool things about a
tesla is the idea of driverless driving
that is fucking amazing.
Name tesla at all for that.
For the guy dying recently.
The one that autopilot one,
I think they've deterMined that
autopiLot didn't have anything to do
with that.
He was watching Harry Potter.
He was,
yeah,
it was proven.
He was,
it was still playing.
It was like greg giraldo's joke about
about rappers show him watching porn and
they get into an accident and they're on
the side of the road and the porn is
still playing.
Rappers watching,
I think it was rappers want,
it was,
it was people having everyone on cribs
had a monitors.
Right.
And their color suv.
And he was talking about if you got into
an accident and you're dying and it's
still playing fucking dumb shit on your
monitor is still playing porn.
Yeah,
I think it was born.
There was a guy who got killed in
Michigan.
He was jerking off while I was driving.
His car flipped is jerking off to this
man.
Yeah.
He can't wait.
His car flipped and he died and he died
with his pants down.
His phone was still playing the porn
when they pulled his life
body from the wreckage.
That's a long clip,
by the way.
More than a dozen fisker karma.
Hybrids.
Caught fire and exploded.
No video.
Just pictures.
I guess.
So we're wrong.
So we have false memories.
Yeah.
God damn.
That's what happened with trump on nine
slash 11.
Yes,
he was.
there wasn't.
He didn't eat celebrators oh yeah,
in New Jersey.
So I'm all the way across the.
Yeah.
Well,
some people musT have celebrated.
So what?
Uh,
I don't think anybody was so.
I mean,
I don't think to,
in jersey I'm sure people were like,
yes,
but I don't think people were going
outside and fucking who knows,
because then we'll get you popped maybe
back then they didn't know.
Well no.
When.
I mean that's a fucking chaotic moment
to be able to predict what's gonna
happen.
Yeah.
And how did it.
Yeah,
exactly.
Who knows what was going on.
Then they didn't know when that first
happened.
Yeah,
I mean they could have been instead of
celebrate and they could have been just
going,
wow,
that's crazy
funny.
As I think when I.
I think I saw it happen,
but I was in paris and I saw like
someone said like,
I am very sorry what happened to your
country?
And I was like,
what are you talking about?
Like the world trade center and I'm
like,
what?
And then I ran to a monitor and saw
psalm and butting my head.
I saw it live,
but I just didn't.
Do you know what I mean?
Like that's the faulty of faultiness
memories,
which is creepy that you can't.
It's like you say ship with absolutely
no certainty this point
memories are very bad.
Yeah.
I'm and I have some super clear memories
that,
that I can verify,
but I've also got a lot of fuzzy ones
and the problem is when people start
attaching all sorts of emotions and all
sorts of different things to memories
and then they start distorting them and
then repeating the distortion of the
memory until that becomes the memory.
And then in their mind,
like there's people that have been
involved in business deals and they
think that they were so wrong.
Then everything went so terrible and
this piece of shit and then my wife left
me.
And then when you break it down to them,
no,
that didn't happen at all.
This is what happened.
Like they don't want to hear the
results.
People I think that are a little bit
crazy.
I'm talking about you ever be arguing
with your wife and you're like,
I didn't say that.
And then you think,
did I say like,
especially if you're barely paying
attention,
that's the key longterm relationship
case.
Just got to be able to hit the fade
button that they do.
Is that you think that's helpful to
round out and do you think she realizes
it?
What do you think?
She knows that I don't know what you're
talking about.
Would you say?
What were you saying?
Yeah,
you just fade out.
But that's exactly the kind of
conversations you start having.
Like what?
What'd you just say?
What?
I just lost everything.
What did you say?
Some will say so then we're going to
light it on fire.
What?
Yeah.
Okay.
Now I have to pay attention.
What are you going to light on fire?
Who's going to light one on fire?
Yeah,
but that's the thing about
relationships.
It's all kind of important,
but none of it's that important in
retrospect.
Hindsight in the day.
On the second of it
sometimes.
Yeah.
The most nonsensical thing could be so
important.
Neil brennan,
so important.
You have many daughters.
Well,
my situation is pretty comfortable and
easy manage,
but I have some friends that have some
bad relationships with their wives and
the.
It's basically when they get togetheR
it's just who's going to win today's
wrestling match?
How many,
how many people do you know with,
with marriages that you envy?
Let's say you weren't married.
That's a good question.
Not manY because that's the thing.
It's like not many.
It's you know,
most of them are.
It looks especially from the outside,
it looks like way too much work.
Yeah,
and it looks like disastrous happenings
once it breaks off,
which is different than a a boyfriend,
girlfriend.
If a guy and a girl,
uh,
dating and they just decided to call it
off like,
this isn't working.
That's it.
Yeah.
It's,
there's very little cleanup.
Yeah.
That.
Well that's it.
Yeah.
but if you are some man or some woman,
even like a woman who makes a shitload
of money and she has a husband's kind of
a lay about and then that starting to
happen,
fuck yeah,
it is.
Fuck.
That is.
And then all of a sudden this dude wants
a ton of alimony.
Yeah.
Like,
yeah,
like jesus christ and this woman who
doesn't even like this guy anymore has
to pay him 10 percent or 15 percent of
her salary every week.
And she's just like,
I can't even Believe this.
Like that is always been the case with
men and women with a man having to pay
the woman.
It's always been alimony has been around
forever,
right?
Child support,
alimony.
But now that it's in more and more cases
becoming the woman playing the man,
like talk to roseanne barr about how
much he had to pay tom arnold.
And you're like,
what?
This is it's league.
It's legalized stealing mixed in with
prostitution.
It's long,
it's a long con.
Prostitution in in many ways and it's
involving the legal system and the banks
and as soon as there's a system that's
set up where people are profiting off
that system,
good luck buying it from their fucking
hands.
Yeah,
and that's the political system that we
have right now,
but it's also the marriage system,
like if you've talked to someone who's
gone through horrific divorces and had
to deal with the financial implications
are or complications,
it gets insane.
Well,
that's what buddy mine was like my wife.
the sad thing is the deal she's going to
get.
I offered her two years ago,
but she says dragging it out.
They want to drag it out because it
costs you money in legal fees.
That's right.
And it there.
You're still connected to them and
they're punishing you.
If you want to get the divorce,
even if you don't want to divorce,
there's a reason why they want to get
divorced or they're mad at you for some
shit.
You fucking.
My friend has to pay his ex wife for the
rest of her life and he has a new wife
and he has a family.
He's got kids.
She doesn't have a new husband though.
No know if she has a new husband than
the money that cuts off,
so hE has to pay her hundreds of
thousands of dollars every single year
for the rest of her life.
It's almost like he fucked her so hard.
She can't work anymore.
Like that's what the court says.
This guy.
Well that's what it is.
It's like how feeble were I guess.
I guess it's societaly like women had it
so much worse in the seventies when
these laws were made,
but it seems like there needs to be some
kind of correction.
Can't have it so that if a guy is
married to a woman,
he has been not married to her more than
he has been married to her.
He was married to her for like 12 years.
He's been divorced for like 14,
but it doesn't matter.
He stIll owes all that money.
[inaudible] like because he,
they broke up,
he has to pay her because they went past
12 years being married or whatever the
number was his two pair for the rest of
her time on earth.
Like he,
he might not have any relationship to or
he is responsible for her survival
forever and not just survival but living
really well.
Like that's.
I guess the question is how
important were the women who've got
these laws passed?
Meaning what do you think you're doing
that is entitling you to this money,
and this goes for men now too because
it's like,
well how good of a husband are you that
you deserve half of her income for ever
clearly your that good?
Because she dIdn't work so there should
be a penalty right there.
There's not,
I don't think they easily get half
forever or whatever,
but they get a giant chunk chunk and
then a stipend.
Yeah,
they get a monthly payment.
It's just strange that someone could
like people meet each other and then it
doesn't work out anymore.
They like each other.
They spend time.
Then they don't want to spend time and
when they don't want to spend time to
all of the sudden legally obligate them
to send money like this is not.
We're not talking about someone who by
virtue of their relationship could no
longer move her body,
you know,
like with a man and a woman gets
together,
the man has to pay because once a man
starts fucking a woman,
they eventually go paralyzed.
It's just how it works.
I mean,
if that was the nature,
yeah,
that was the case.
Well,
yeah,
you have to take responsibility for
having sex because the man does
something.
Well,
by the way,
guys would still claim like I didn't
even.
That wasn't even me,
man,
I fuck her harder.
You think I'm the only what you think I
could even fuck a woman in the book and
into a vegetable.
It's,
it's stealing,
but it's also like you're cornering a
person and forcing tHem to just get
thrust into this weird legal system.
So this weird legal system,
it's pulling as this thing is spiraling
down.
The legal system is pulling money out of
it.
So there's this,
there's this guy who's earning all this
money,
he works 12 hours every day is
constantly hustling and doing deals and
this and that,
and he's putting it all together and
while he's getting divorced,
this woman,
they're going through the court system
and the court system and this two year
fight is spinning this whole thing back
and forth and you,
you need to get more man because you
have to consider his earning potential.
Is gonna increase over the next few
years and it wouldn't have happened if
he wasn't your in around.
I mean your stability in the
relationship is part of the reason why
he had the confidence to pursue these
business deals and you should be
compensated.
Well,
that's what I wonder who were these
wonderful people that this lawyer.
No,
I know,
but who was the woman that they could
hold up as well?
You did this,
therefore blahbity blah blah.
Is that.
Well,
first of all lawyers,
a lot of them get a percentage.
Yeah.
So I think there's that.
I think there is
so.
And they make the laws.
Yeah.
Well they definitely argue the law.
If there's a strong Benefit to there
being an extreme financial consequence
for getting divorced,
a strong benefit to the people that
profit from taking people to divorce
court.
So and by the way that benefit doesn't
exist like the other way,
like if if your,
if your lawyer saves you a fuck load of
money,
he doesn't get a percentage of what he
saves you.
Yeah,
but if the lawyer on the other side,
if they can figure out a way to get the
court to rob you,
but again you got to give your wife $50,
million dollars or something like that.
Like that lawyer gets a chunk of that.
Like he gets paid if he successfully
incentivized for the.
A lot of roommates to attack the rich
guy through attack the man or the rich
woman.
The sound bar situation.
But that's the way they get the money.
They don't get the money if you don't
get penalized.
If you go into the case scott free and
you know and go,
I'm not paying that bitch shit.
This relationship is over.
And the jury says we agree mr.
Mr.
Brennan,
you could walk and so you like,
that's right bitch.
all you're doing is going to pay your
lawyers hourly rates and they have no.
There's no financial benefit to getting
this done quickly.
The financial benefit is to drag this
fucking thing on for two years and then
let you know,
hey,
we got out of it,
you know,
and then you realize
a lot.
It's like mandatory minimum sentencing.
Exactly.
Nothing they can really do unless you
have a prenup or you can do a,
a good,
a litigator to a or like a whatever.
The,
the,
the where they sort of a mediator I
think you can get paid less than normal
with the mediator.
This also here's another situation,
like someone was talking to me about
like the donald sterling type sugar
daddy situation like and they were
saying that it's awful that these men
get preyed upon by these vicious women.
I'm like,
if you don't know that,
that girl is fucking you because your
rich.
If you have a $100,
billion dollars and you're 90 years old
and this girl tells you she loves you
and she's with you all the time,
she's acting perfect.
You don't know that she wants that money
and by the way,
if she's fucking you,
she deserves a lot of money at least as
much as you're going to at least half.
If you're a donald sterling type
character and you've got some tWenty
five old super hot
stripper that you're laying pipe too,
you got to pay her.
I'll lot because what she's doing is
first of all,
very difficult to do.
She's pretending to be attracted to you
and you're disgusting and it's acting
and basically surgery.
It's the worst parts of acting and and
and surgery.
It's and it's super valuable to you.
Like if you're that old rich guy and you
have a 25 year old can get anything on
earth except young girls,
you gotta pay literally.
You can get anything you want.
Like lamborghinis costs less.
They're more accessible to use it.
That a,
that a young girl that's actually tried
to do a young girl that's actually
trying to do,
doesn't exists there.
Unicorns.
Yes.
To leprechaun.
Mythical creatures.
They do not exist.
Only in your imagination do exist if you
keep her like constantly like covered in
diamonds and furs and whatever the fuck
she needs and crocodile skin purses and
chinese named shoes and whatever the
fuck you need.
Do you believe that is,
if it is possible to be legitimately
attracted to a donald sterling time?
I think that I think there are women
with big enough father issues that like,
yeah,
I'm legitimately attracted to him.
Like I would be a 20 year old.
I would never say that.
Any like anything when it comes to
attraction is impossible.
Yes,
exactly.
Because there's chubby chasers,
people that are into weird shit on
people that are in a weird shit and
there's a lot of women that find like
older men hot.
They liked the idea of like some white
haired old dude laying dick num.
Whoa.
Who knows man?
Yeah.
People like weird shit.
People like furries.
There's a lot of people that are really
into being a furry.
I also have no problem with,
with,
uh,
with prostitution on its face.
Like I don't have like,
why do I care?
Why is it okay to get a massage?
Not okay to get a hand job.
RighT.
Exactly.
Stupid.
Too good.
Yeah.
Well it's weird.
We're regulating sex.
Like were puritans.
Yeah,
it's,
it's preposterous,
but it's also,
you have to think if it was legal,
would it encourage or would it
discourage the sex trade?
Like in terms of like you have to worry
about like sex slaves and some are,
you know,
that's,
those are real issues and it's an issue
that's completely unresolved because
people on both sides of it claim their
right and they both seem to have a good
argument.
And then also the argument is like,
isn't it possible that there's a big
fucking difference between a sex slave
and a woman who like,
maybe she's like a young girl living in
New York city,
the rents are really high.
She decides to fuck some rich guys for
money.
Like why is that worse than working at
denny's?
Yeah,
exactly.
why is it worse?
I would go a step further,
which is,
let's say it is an emotional problem.
She was molested.
She wants to overbid,
she has.
She gets whatever.
That's no different than the reason most
people I know are showbiz
and I don't see anyone picketing that.
That's true.
It's based on an emotional stunt.
Right?
And why is it sex?
Why sex?
The only thing that you can't take money
for because jesus.
that's really why.
Because jesus.
Come on,
man.
That's a weird thing.
That sex is the only thing that you
can't take money for ever.
You can't take money for it.
Yeah,
but you can.
You just got to be slick about it.
If you can't yet they dress it up.
well,
like if a girl.
Is it dinner?
Yeah.
if a girl's your a sugar baby.
It was a sugar based sugar.
no sugar.
It would be.
They would pay sugar.
Sugar baby is your baby.
She was.
That was sugar daddy.
Yeah.
Okay,
so whatever the girl's name,
whatever you would call her.
If she's dating some super billionaire
type richard branson type character,
and he just gives her a salary,
like what if he's,
she's got a salary.
It's like,
look,
baby,
you get $5,000
a week to just go crazy with and give
you a credit card.
It's got $50,000
limit.
Here's your fucking bentley.
There's the keys.
You're all set.
woo.
She's on the payroll.
Is that a prostitute?
Uh,
I don't.
Roger ailes.
The guy had fox news had that he did on
staff.
Yeah.
And it was an open secret.
How many of you have had one?
but then he would just harass everybody
else.
Really?
Uh,
yeah,
she was on staff for years.
She was a researcher.
Researcher.
Yeah.
Surely you must research.
Maybe she must've done something
worthwhile.
Yeah,
definitely.
Um,
at least something.
Some of write up a memo or something
that.
Is that a business partner or is that
thing of like this thing of sex?
If you look at sex as this holy
sacrament,
than it is a.
If you look at every ejaculation as the
holy sacrament,
Which the church would have you believe?
And then they get into government,
they make laws,
whatever,
uh,
then then it's not legal,
but if you look at it like a milking or
even a teeth cleaning or a haircut or
anything that you need,
any service that you need fairly
regularly,
then it's,
then all,
all laws are like nonsense for the most
part
is part of the problem too is the,
uh,
immediately accessible nature of the sex
is troublesome to some people because if
you have a relationship with someone
who's basically fucking you for your
money,
like at least you have this relationship
with them and you hang out with them for
long,
you have the time with them.
There's a lot of time that's not having
sex.
So you actually have to be like friends
with them.
Yeah.
And some sort of a way.
But the sex for money thing,
you just show up and you go,
yeah,
I'd like to pay for sex.
And then you go and you have the sex and
you're like,
here's your money.
Thanks.
Bye.
Like people have a problem with the
brevity of it.
Like bullies don't even entangled.
Yes.
Sue transactional.
It's not,
it's a goes against god to their mind.
It goes against god.
It's like,
that's not what god.
God wants you to sit and be bored.
Yeah.
And go on a drive and help listen to
them.
They listen to your stupid stories.
You listen to their stupid stories.
Yeah.
Boy the fuck out of each other and
comfort each other.
Those are the rules.
Yeah.
That's how we do things.
That's the fucking rules.
You can't just be going in there all
willy nilly getting paid money for sex.
Yeah,
it's too.
It's too.
And,
and I guess because sex can create life,
you know,
the other thing is the pill is pretty
new man.
That's true too.
You know,
abortion in the pillar,
both pretty new and the laws haven't
really caught up well.
It's just
you shouldn't be able to tell people
what they can or can't do with their
body.
That doesn't hurt anybody.
Other than that.
Yeah.
Like you can't tell someone that they
can play rugby.
You can't say no,
you can't play rugby because rugby,
they run into each other and you're
going to get hurt.
What do you think's going to happen in
the nfl?
I don'T know enough about it,
but what I do know is that there's a lot
of people that have some serious fucking
brain damage from playing football.
Yeah,
there's no doubt about it.
I've met people that have played for it,
um,
that,
that are pretty open about it.
And I met like michael irvin.
I don't know what issues he's suffered
from it,
but that guy is sharp as a tack.
He's sharp as a tack.
When you talked to
said it with cocaine,
is that what it is?
Balanced it out now?
Super intelligent or all of them are
very smart.
It's,
but it's,
it's a late onset tHing for a lot of
guys.
Yeah,
no,
for sure.
I was talking to a guy who who plays and
he was saying like I said to them about
he plays whatever,
and I in him,
he goes,
yeah.
He's like,
it's not that hard.
He goes on on,
it's authentic.
You have to remember more shit.
He goes,
but there are times on defense where
I'll black out and not know what's going
on.
And you just keep playing,
which just like jesus.
Yeah.
It's like,
all right,
so is the blackout from memory or from.
It's from penn's impact sHe had.
it's christ.
Yeah.
Cranial impact.
And I,
it sounds like that's all of them.
He didn't say it like he said it.
It completely like conversational
[inaudible].
He didn't say it like
not a problem.
Mr.
Oh man.
well I think they're used to so much
trauma.
Yeah.
Well They used to running at each other
full clip.
We don't think of it as being the most
violent sport because the thing of mma
is being more violent because you're
actually trying to hit the person.
That's the goal is try to hurt them with
your hands or your feet,
but it's not nearly as powerful.
Someone running into you,
like someone running in us.
that's a crazy amount of force into your
head with that.
I think that's where the league may be
headed is no helmet.
sometimes they go flying through the
air,
like you see guys get clipped and spin
and they spin or they disguise
gravitate.
They like take you like somebody just
knocked a 200 plus pound man through the
air.
Like a pillow?
Yeah,
like data.
That's a car accident.
Yet that guy just hit by a truck.
He got hit
by a 300 pound truck every play.
I think someone died.
Not even beginning.
When I watch,
when you watch it,
you go,
oh,
that guy's dead.
He's definitely dead.
I know I'd be dead if that happened to
me,
but it goes to that weird thing where
they have powerful,
more powerful fucking mandibles and
weird muscles and like I think they
build up a tolerance.
I don't know about all that.
I think after awhile they all just go
down.
What is this?
Oh my god.
Yeah.
Jesus.
Currently they're running at each other
run.
Here comes another guy.
Lookout,
boom,
boom.
Oh,
that was just.
That's nothing.
That's what I was going.
excellent.
Play.
Oh,
that was good.
But look,
there's something dope about it,
right?
Like with this guy.
Oh my god.
He took a hard hit there and he kept
going.
It's completely elemental.
It's the most basic instincts in the
world is like running from a scary
thing.
Yeah,
there's fruit.
There's that,
there's that element of it that works.
It's so primal that you're like,
god,
it's so exciting.
It's,
oh yeah,
that guy got lambasted.
Yeah.
There's something about your running
from someone who's trying to harm you as
well.
Like it's the most basic primal,
the monster,
the lion that whatever's coming to get
you.
And then there's the warfare element,
like the ground warfare of like
capturing the,
the taking the,
the hill or whatever.
I get why it works.
I think they just got to get rid of the
helmets.
It's amazingly difficult to move your
body the way these guys are doing.
Yeah.
Did you watch the oj documentary?
No.
One of the,
the big,
big takeawaYs is how good oj was a
football,
because you forget I'm,
I'm not old enough to remember playing
football,
so I heard he ran for 2000 yards,
but they,
one of the episodes,
five,
five parts.
One of the parts.
It's basically just about that,
about how nice he was.
Football.
Wow.
And he did it in 14 games and,
and like,
he was like,
it's crazy.
Well,
you know,
one of his doctor said that if he had to
rerun the trial today,
he would bring up ct.
Yeah.
Which is,
it's,
that's weird thing to do Because then
they would have to admit that he
actually did it because the trial.
Yeah.
But can you let.
Then it would have to make a law about
that.
What's weird too,
because we all know he's in jail for
those murders.
Yeah.
Thanks.
No,
no.
They found a loophole and they're like,
yeah.
Um,
I don't see any reason souvenirs.
He's in jail for really the fifth part.
If you gotta watch it by the way,
like I demand it.
They demand it because it's,
it recontextualized something that you
think you know,
everything about.
Right.
Uh,
and it talks to mark,
mark furman's justification for not
being racist
is a,
I'm not racist.
when I was out on the street,
if somebody wanted to go with me,
I'd fight them straight up.
And that's his reasoning.
Like,
so therefore is therefore I'm not
racist.
Were you just like,
whew.
But at the same time,
you actually,
I kinda like mark from it after watching
the movie really kind of like,
I like meaning it,
I understood his,
he makes sense to himself,
you know what I mean?
Like you see his lodging guard.
I know why he thinks the way he thinks.
Um,
but uh,
not like I'm a Fan of the guy,
but you know what I mean?
I hear you.
I know what you're saying.
Um,
but uh,
but yeah,
like it's an amazing movie and say could
you could,
if,
if they did say with cta then we've kind
of lost the book.
It's like temporary insanity,
right?
Well,
not really.
You'd have to,
you'd have to really quantify what kind
of effects he t hat on him.
Like you'd have to be able to figure it
out.
Like,
is it responsible for you?
Go on,
man.
I don't know.
Should I take that from math thing?
I'm thinking about doing this too.
Or is it,
is it completelY responsible?
Like how much of the cte is responsible
for your decision making?
Well,
there are guys that save a blackout
behaviorally
blackout and you have to believe him,
you know,
you have to think that there's,
there's for sure are going to be some,
some severe neurological implications of
getting smashed in the head over and
over again by the big gigantic dudes
like that.
You've got an cte for a bunch of
concussions.
Right?
For sure.
What were the vomiting and grogginess
and shit?
Man,
man,
I don't know.
I,
I do remember a sparring sessions,
just sparring sessions where I got mY
bell rang and I'd go home and lay in bed
and then my fucking head would be
throbbing and aching.
Just ball ball.
Yeah.
I'm just sitting with every heartbeat
and you think I'm.
What am I doing with my parrain if
that's what I was thinking.
Yeah.
I come to sun even any money in this?
I'm like,
I'm getting punched in the head all the
time.
Yeah.
As I was doing a lot of sparring and
wearing headgear?
No.
Oh god,
no.
Why gear?
I couldn't see kicks coming.
I didn't like headgear.
Headgears weird.
When you throw in kicks with other guys
guys wearing them,
a lot of ufc fighters were.
A lot of people don't.
I?
I had a problem with them.
I tried to were the ones that were the.
There's a bar that goes across your face
to protect your nose.
That's the worst.
You can't see shit.
I had to,
for me,
I had to go like the Mike Tyson style,
which is one that Mike Tyson used to
where where he,
a lot of his face was exposed.
A lot of people kind of criticized it
because they said that he was more open
to cuts and there's a reason why they
had those big cheek,
but you can't see left and right.
Like peripherals,
like if you're,
if you're sparring a guy and he throws
like real wide stuff on you especially
kicks guys who sneak kicks around your
shoulder.
Like you literally don't see them until
they're on your neck and it's not good.
I didn't like it.
I was like,
I'd rather get hit with no head gear on.
Well then you have a chance.
Yeah.
I feel
like I can move with it better.
You can still,
you're still in a bad spot,
but the real Issue is cuts because a lot
of guys get cut and sparring.
You might collide heads,
you might an elbow or something like
that and when that does happen,
the problem is then it could delay a
fight and if you're an mma fighter and
you're training for it,
it's probably pretty smart to wear
headgear,
but it doesn't really protect your head
that much.
In fact,
there's an argument that it acts as more
of a fulcrum point because the headgear
makes your head larger so you can like.
Yeah,
that's interesting.
Wait and everything.
It actually can make your head move
more.
well,
it's funny what happens to your brain,
which is,
it just goes flying against your skull.
There's nothing technical about it.
It just goes like bullies.
Yeah.
And it can't maintain signal while
that's going on.
He can't maintain order and especially
if you get hit in the base of your head,
like one of the scariest kicks,
the can get hit with it.
A lot of guys get hit with his neck
kicks,
you get necked and uh,
when you get neck kicked,
guys go down like they got shot.
Like a,
there's a because it,
because of what,
what,
what gets hurt?
It just shut your brain off.
Uh oh.
It's like this thing.
That's the shit.
No,
it's the shin slams basically against
the base of your skull.
It's like really?
The back of the sheet is basically a
switchblade.
Yeah,
it's under here.
Google this ernesto hoost kaos.
Maury smith.
Maurice with smith is a good friend of
mine and he's a former ufc heavyweight
champion.
Former world,
more thaI fighter,
more more time champion.
He's a bad motherfucker,
but he fought this guy who's just one of
the greatest of all time.
Ernesto hoost.
And he got caught with a kick to his
neck and I knew how tough more.
He says,
I knew how good of a fighter he is.
So when you see a guy who's at the level
that maurice's watch this boat,
see how he threw that over the top of
his head and it just shut maurice off.
Look at this.
He slides on the outside and he lifts
his head up,
ellipses a foot up brother and goes over
the shoulder or maurice doesn't even see
it coming until it's already too late.
It hits the back of his head.
It's crazy and that's his foot,
which hasn't even been hard.
Well,
it's still hard.
It's ernesto hoost foot,
but it could be way worse.
You're right.
If it was a little bit further back then
it would have been over,
but a lot of guys knock guys out dead
coal that's in a punch to the back of
the head and boxing.
Right.
But you can kick guys and when you've
landed,
oftentimes lands in the back of the
head.
No one ever thinks is anything wrong
with it.
It's real weird.
It's a super gray so you can't punch In
mma.
You cannot punch the back of the neck
and head,
but you can't.
Exactly.
That's very odd.
It's so odd.
Well,
it's a.
It's an issue with kickboxing as well
because some of the best techniques land
on the back of the head,
like here's another one that does all
the time too.
We'll kicks like someone will throw,
we'll kick like a spinning
heel kick and they'll catch a guy boom
right on the back of the hat.
It happens all the time and that's
technically it's an illegal place to hit
someone,
but because head kicks are like,
that's sort of like the ultimate
striking weapon I give you knock someone
out,
like knocking someone out with a head
kick because like the ultimate striking
mountain because it's everything we
always wanted to see in karate movies,
you know,
so because of that is so encouraged to
like push the guy just because it's so
encouraged.
We don't think about the implications of
kicking someone in the back of the head,
which is probably way worse than
punching someone in the back of the
head.
But it happenS all the time and
kickboxing and all the time in mma.
It's one of those weird things where
nobody wants to talk about it and,
but everybody knows that's the case.
You're kicking,
you're kicking a guy on a totally
illegal spot,
but you're not trying how double the
standard.
They all know it.
They all know it for sure.
Everybody knows that,
especially everybody's been hit by one
of those are hinton's hit somebody with
one of those.
You know where you're hitting them.
a lot of times you're hitting the back
of the head.
If you're aware of can you punch?
If someone you can punch the all the
back all over the body.
You can punch the legs,
you can punch the groin,
but you can punch somebody in the ass.
You can punch in the back,
you can punch him in the back.
You can't punch,
punch above the elbow.
Strike the spine.
There's some weird rules there.
Actually,
we were talking about this yesterday.
Jamie and I looked up there.
Jamie said they came up with some new
rules and one of them involves knees to
the head to a downed opponent.
Now a downed opponent means you have to
have both hands down on the mat and
they're.
Your palm has to be flat.
You can't have just one.
if you have one hand up,
they can see you in the face,
so that's not a downed opponent because
there's a lot of people that were
criticizing this down to potent thing
because people were sort of what they
would call gaming the system where you
would lean down,
you just touch your hand on the ground,
like as if it's safe and then the guy
can't hit you,
so that's how you're.
You're getting out of exchanging.
Got it.
Instead of you're totally capable of
standing up or totally capable of
covering up a.
You can make your choice like you got to
this position or he got you to this
position.
It's advantageous to feeLs like a fairly
standard position.
Yeah,
It happens all the time,
but the issue becomes if you are
incapable of getting out of the way,
should you be able to nea guy in the
head because some guys like when they're
down like that,
it's like,
well that's a devastating maneuver to
nea guy and ahead when they're in that
position.
So they for for good reason,
they wanted to decide when it should be
legal because there's other
organizations.
We could do crazy stuff like stomping
people.
You can stomp people like stomped their
head in certain organization.
So that was a big one in pride.
You could soccer kick guys and stomp
them,
but oddly enough,
they didn't allow elbows on the ground.
That doesn't.
They felt elbows on the ground were
barbaric or something.
They had a line.
That's everybody's.
People are so crazy with their lines.
They draw.
Can I pee
real quick?
Fuck yeah.
That's the part where I have to go to
the bathroom.
You drinking that delicious pellgrino I
got into bubbly water lately.
Jamie.
I hate to admit it.
I like,
I like sparkling water now.
I used to think there's no nutritional
benefits.
I had it in my head that like regular
water was better for you.
Was that your thing?
Yeah.
Uh,
the uh,
keepers of the ark of the covenant.
I found it.
I looked up,
I found something where it said that
there was a report of one of them having
milky cataracts and a description,
but it's not all of them from what I'm
reading.
Goddammit graham hancock christians in
Ethiopia have long claim to have the ark
of the covenant.
A reporter investigated.
Go down to the very last chapter or the
very last paragraph rather.
See what the fuck they said.
Yeah.
See,
that's the thing about these things.
The final moments of any search,
I could not judge whether the ark of the
covenant truly rested inside the
nondescript chapel.
Perhaps ma menelIk manilex traveling
companions did take it and spirited home
to Ethiopia.
Perhaps its origins here.
Stem from the tail spun by.
So nothing.
He's got no evidence.
Yeah,
there's apparently also a storm and
leaky roof that was going to make a move
it in 2012.
But I didn't find anything that said
that,
whether it was seen or not.
And that,
uh,
the battery,
the baghdad battery was supposedly also
not a battery that think it was used for
electroplating statues with gold and
silver.
Oh,
that makes sense.
There was a little bit of a charge in
there,
but not enough to be considered a
battery thing.
Yeah.
Oh.
So it was just a way they kind of made
paint.
Yeah,
sorta started cover stuff,
so I think they had a hypothesIs that it
would spin it in there and it would
create a bond
to the stone or whatever they were.
That makes sense too.
So that's the way they would use it on
statues and stuff.
That's fucking amazing.
God damn it was so cool.
When you think of how these people had
to use a little monkey brains to invent
the first wheel or did vent pottery,
like the people that.
I mean,
when did theY figure out pottery?
So if you had a guess,
let's guess,
what do you think?
5,000
bc.
Four after a fire,
not fire after fire.
They just figured out what he get.
Hardened stuff stuff.
probably just accidentally.
Let's google it.
I say a 5,000
bc.
No,
because that doesn't make any sense
because it's like qumran or not qumran.
Samira samira was before that.
$6,000.
4,000
potter's wheel though.
Oh,
oh,
okay.
This potter's wheel was invented in
mesopotamia sometime in between 6,000
and 4,000.
Does that say 4,000,
4,000
bc period.
You guys going over ancient inventions?
What's going on?
We're trying to figure out when they
invented pottery.
oh,
that has to
baghdad battery that we were looking at
earlier.
Apparently jamie found out that it
might've been used to electroplate gold
like that.
It created a small charge,
but really wasn't a battery.
It was just used to make like almost
like electric paint and then we're
trying to figure out.
Well,
I was like,
how fucking cool is that?
Like how,
how crazy were the first people,
the first monkey people from like a
million years ago at wherever I was,
I figured out how to make a flint knife.
You know the first people that figured
out pottery if figured out how to roll
dirt and light it on fire.
There's a duncan brought up as last
appearance.
Not as most recent one.
There's a whole Youtube channel.
have a guy that does this.
He makes tons of different experiments
and trying out primitive technologies
and processes.
He doesn't talk at all.
I'm going to look it up so I can find
out what it's called,
but It just made a really cool one where
he pulled little pieces of metal out of
iron ore and he had to.
He invented this way to get his flame
hotter using some sort of thing.
He and he shows you make he makes.
The whole thing was really,
really cool.
Shit.
Just amazing.
When You think of how long ago was it
felt?
Well,
we don't even know what it was.
It's someone first invented pottery.
That potter's wheel was at least 6,000
or at least 4,000
bc.
There's also the idea that people
invented it and it just never got out
before that.
You know what I mean?
Two thousand years earlier.
Maybe somebody invents it and then he
just never.
No one ever leaves that village.
Hm.
yeah.
That,
that definitely could be it.
So what does this gentleman doing?
Primitive technologies that youtube
channels.
So it shows them make.
He's making a forge blower.
What's funny is he has cave hands.
Looks like the original.
This dude is one of,
uh,
there's a bunch of people now that are
experts in ancient ways of living like
ancient archery in ancient,
like house building and shit.
It's really weird.
Will there's something cool that I was
going to say.
Uh,
you meditate at all.
Yeah.
Well,
sort of in the tank.
I do.
Um,
so I went on a,
a seven day silent meditation retreat.
Whoa.
Yeah,
no talking,
no talking.
Well,
It ended up being like,
we talked a for three minutes,
starting day three,
we'd talk for three minutes a day.
Wow.
But I got to say it was at,
on the first day.
I'm not kidding.
I fucking cried.
Oh my god.
Dude.
No talking.
No television,
no computer,
no phone.
Here's the worst part.
No reading,
no writing,
just meditating and eating and whatever
and being like,
being in this village thing.
Whoa.
Um,
but,
uh,
this video is fucking really cool.
This video is dope as fuck.
This guy made these,
uh,
like made like a little furnace blower
out of this pottery thing with a wheel
inside of it that he would spin and it
would blow air with fire.
And so yeah,
it's like you got like a handmade fan
and he does it by moving it around with
his fingers and now he's making a rope
and twine so he could pull it probably
like,
whoa.
Yeah.
And what he's been able to do with it as
stoked as fire up in this incredible
way.
I mean it's just blazing and it's all
from the wind that is blowing into it
with this crazy invention.
And this is some shit that people did
thousands of years ago or something.
Yeah,
they were quoted,
watson,
we problem solve all these things.
He just keeps happening is first early
videos.
He makes us hut that's behind them and
it's just out of nowhere.
He was just in the middle of the forest
and he goes and he makes his little
bricks and he hates him up in a killing.
He made and he started wIth no fire and
yeah,
he's built all this stuff.
It's pretty
cool.
Watch his wild though.
He's doing all this clay and shit.
There's a bunch.
Is that.
Don't eat that.
What the fuck is he making,
man?
Getting the carbon and putting it in
with the iron ore and he puts it in the,
in the,
uh.
Oh,
that's right.
He's going to make metal.
Yeah.
This is insane.
If you make a call with you,
megan.
Yeah,
he's gonna.
Make metal.
This is how people did it,
man.
It's what's,
what's really crazy is someone had to
figure out how to take all the elements
that are involved with the cameras about
fire.
I know,
right?
This is,
this is why it looks like fake fire.
It does.
It looks like some cgi fire.
This is all cia bullshit.
This is preparing us for the zombie
apocalypse.
They're teaching us when the grid goes
down.
How to make our own fire.
Uh,
yeah.
So silent meditation retreat.
So wake up at a.
So day one I cried,
cried.
Chris straight up.
Cried.
Wow.
From like,
it's,
it feels like you're dead.
You can't talk to anyone,
you know.
Whoa.
And you can't get online,
you can't read,
you can't,
you literally are like an apparition
years walking around like a ghost.
And,
but day three and four were two of the
best days of my life.
Really?
Yeah.
Because all you're doing is meditating
and meditation,
uh,
brings on,
like to stimulate your brain,
makes you happy.
Like,
proven like monks take mris and they
just look like they,
they don't stress,
they have high,
uh,
incredibly low levels of cortisol and
low,
very high levels of,
of,
uh,
of positive chemicals.
Um,
so you just,
I would meditate nine hours a day
and.
Yeah,
and you just end up like.
And the other thing I would do because I
couldn't,
uh,
no one could talk and I didn't really
need to talk to anybody.
I would smile all day.
So if you smile all day,
it tricks your brain into thinking
you're happy because your brain doesn't
know.
Like if your muscles are just,
they go,
I guess we're happy.
So everybody act happy.
Uh,
it can work backward.
The gun and paul ekman rid of book.
Uh,
but it was,
yeah,
it was an amazing experience.
Amazing.
I didn't know.
What I realized is I came away with
like,
I'm so overstimulated at home with
podcasts,
television shows,
computers,
fucking phones,
texting constantly that it's made me a
really cut back on everything in a way
that's very,
very positive I think.
Wow.
Yeah.
CAuse the dude I wake up,
I don't,
most people wake up and you immediately
like mainline information or technology
like,
like I used to do when I smoke
cigarettes,
I'd wake up and have for cigarettes and
drink coffee and just like shocked my
body and I feel like it was awful and I
feel like that's what I do now.
All right.
What I used to do with technology,
just like constantly turn my phone on to
a tax,
going New York times going this thing
going,
eh,
I go on reddit going all these places.
And it wasn't make,
it was just stressing me out.
Yeah.
It doesn't make you feel good.
but that's hard in that weird thing that
we all do.
Constantly were acknowledged.
Like it doesn't make me feel good.
Yeah.
We need discipline.
That's a big,
big factor in managing the electronic
world is discipline the discipline and
I'll watch too much television.
Yep.
Discipline and not fuck around you.
Phone two months.
It did discipline.
Did not play games too much [inaudible]
you can,
you can get lurched in the word lurched
sure minutes.
Yeah.
It's not really the right word.
It's probably not ultimately beneficial,
right?
I mean like certain amount of balance to
it is really good,
but it's so addicting.
We should have like one person,
like a responsible guy.
Like will you look up like The world
should have that where it's like,
hey,
look up when,
when so and so was invented.
But for the most part we can just
communicate because that's the thing.
That's another one of those things where
you talk about what,
because I look up what actually makes
people happy.
Communication,
a real connection.
A community volunteering makes people
happier.
Uh,
which I like in the big brothers program
and it's like,
man,
it's not bad.
Um,
it hasn't given me a spike or anything.
A spike of,
of,
of uh,
adrenaline or a good feelings of like,
not even adrenaline of like a serotonin,
um,
and,
but really connecting with people.
Is that maybe what you like about doing
the show?
Because I always find that I enjoy doing
this show and people are like,
it's so long.
I'm like,
yeah,
I know it's long,
but I don't know.
There's something About just like
sitting here and just like staring at
each other and like,
what else do you think?
Do you think that?
Here's what I think.
Yeah,
will.
And there's something
about it for listeners.
probably too.
Yeah.
Well it's so long form that you get.
Everybody gets real relaxed and you get
to.
it becomes more of a,
the way I listened to it like,
a lot of guys do it this way,
now I'm ari does it this way.
A lot of guys do it.
They'll just let just let it go.
As long as it goes in.
When you do that,
like conversations,
they evolve,
they,
they move around,
they get deeper,
they get lighter,
they get silly.
There's no,
it's not organized.
And I liked listening to people talk.
Yeah.
Oh,
you like ideas?
Yeah.
So you like to hear like,
what's your idea that's not a good idea
or that is a good idea.
Yeah.
Uh,
you got to be super flexible with your
ideas.
I've gotten way better at that since I
started doing a podcast way better at
trying to figure out like what is it
about an idea that I disagree with and
how much of it is that I had a different
idea then that idea in my head,
that preconceived notion,
how much of that is how I'm affected by
the disagreement or the called motivated
reasoning.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a perfect way of describing it.
That's exactly what it is,
right?
That's super common man for all of us.
And I think that having conversations on
a podcast with a variety of different
people that have a variety of different
opinions,
it's been really interesting because I
get to challenge my own opinions like,
well,
where are my opinions coming from?
They've been really vetted out yet.
Or are they just some like convenience
stuff that I've held held onto because.
Yeah.
Well yeah,
you have the shelving built,
you have all this shit.
You will have like,
hey,
I got the t shirt,
I got the old thing,
I've got the right adapter.
Yeah,
yeah.
Uh,
but yet,
so it is this,
this,
that was what I learned.
Like the,
the walking around not having to talk to
people.
Yeah.
Was cool in it.
There was no pressure and it was also
like the least sexual environment I've
ever been on because everyone just looks
like they have the flu.
Basically.
People are struggling.
Did they have rules?
Could people hook up?
Uh,
it was discouraged.
It,
I also would say like everyone,
I didn't have a roommate,
but like you're in like olympic style
dorms,
like were you have a roommate and it's
like eight rooms and each floor it was
like a summer camp basically where you
did nothing.
It's seriously would be kind of hot
though.
It was having been there gal.
Both sIngle.
Both can't talk.
Yeah.
Having been there though,
it really runs counter to what you're
going for.
You're like,
really?
It's fucking interesting where you go,
like you really see what's inside.
Because I was trying to think of what it
was like,
like I was like,
basketball camp was like,
no basketball camp.
We had tv,
vcrs and talk the entire time.
Uh,
this was like nothing.
It's like nothing you've ever done a
you.
And then we would talk and then they
would do it talk every night,
some theme,
some buddhist theme,
and then the next day you would,
you would talk in a group about that.
And what I found was I didn't even
really want to talk.
It's like,
fuck it,
I've come this far.
Let me see how long I can.
Not like,
let me just see what a.
But you see what's in there and you see
like what your brain does.
You see what you're interested in.
You see what you remember.
Any recall?
My recall was really good because your
brain's.
What I realized with the,
with the all the technology is you.
I would create chaos in my head,
uh,
with somebody voices and sounds and
noises and did a that I couldn't even,
I couldn't remember because it was like,
I can't even get back there.
I can get through all this garbage too,
like the file that I'm looking for.
So if I couldn't remember something I'd
be like,
just hang out.
It'll come and it would always come.
Um,
but that was the,
the thing of like,
I don't listen to the radio when I'm in
my car now,
which is on,
so just drive like a fucking old man.
Whoa.
Just literally just me and fucking me
and silence.
Just to limit the amount of signals.
Yeah.
And it's not easy,
but yeah,
I got a buddy of mine lives in our law,
um,
Australia rather want to say Alaska
summer.
He lives in Australia and he takes these
trips out into the bush where he goes
out camping and he'll be gone for like
eight,
nine days or he won't see people for
like nine days.
And he said that when he comes back
oftentimes it feels really weird to talk
to people.
I can almost like forgot how to talk to
people where that has been nothing but
him alone with his thoughts,
with no cell phone service for like
eight or nine days.
Yeah.
it's really worthwhile because what I
also realized is that I was like,
with all the signal and all the,
all the noise and everything is,
is I was upsetting myself.
Do you know what I mean?
Like it'S like,
nah,
I don't need this much,
and I would just overload myself.
Like,
no,
this is,
we're in the golden age of information
and I can access any fucking video and
look around the godfather and fucking
scarface and all this shit.
And it's like,
no,
you need to slow down man.
Like that's not,
that's kind of my temperament.
But at the same time my,
my nervous system was like screaming
like you gotta chill out.
Wow.
Yeah.
But I don't smoke weed or anything like
that,
so I don't have any way to,
to separate.
Yeah.
Or to like to quiet my nervous system.
I mean I've answered a stuff like that
or.
But,
but meditation really helps and since
I've been back I've meditated pretty
much every day since,
which is really for like three months,
which is really.
I've missed a few days,
but it's definitely like an entrenched
part of my life now that I miss if I
don't do it.
Time for reflection is very important
and to avoid getting stuck with
momentum.
Right when when you have the momentum of
your life like and you just cannot let
things keep playing out and just
adjusting long.
the fly that separation to step back and
look at it so it's so critical,
so important.
It's so hard to do because I think once
once things start going in your life,
Whether its obligations or financial
responsibilities or whatever things that
you're working on that are occupying all
of your time,
they.
They become so much a part of your
thought process and you consIder them to
be like a primary importance because
this is like,
I have to pay these bills.
Hey this,
I have to deal with this shit.
I have to.
This is what's going on that they.
They sort of overwhelm cognitive
reasoning.
they overwhelm perspective.
We don't have the opportunity to sit
back and go,
hey,
you're not here for that long amount of
time here.
Yeah,
that's what it was like.
Oh.
So I died like,
what was this like?
It was a bit like the mark twain thing,
like of like seeing your own funeral of
like,
oh wow.
I was away for a week.
I got,
I had the automatic email thing and I
knew so people knew I wasn't around,
but I only got like 50 emails.
It wasn't like an ungodly amount of
emails.
I got maybe 10 texts which all
manageable,
you know,
like it's not like,
oh I was,
I was so missed,
the world needs me.
It's like,
no,
we can all duck out.
Obama could duck out.
Was in martha's vineyard right now.
He's reachable,
but he's not like working,
working when he does that,
like how much do you thInk he works
while he's doing one of those?
Those trips?
like I'm going to bet three hours.
Three hours.
Yeah,
I bet in the morning and then again in
the afternoon.
So it's just a random gift that's a
completely uneducated.
It's based on fucking nothing.
I think people are gonna miss that guy
so much.
They're going to make it even so much.
You can't even quantify how much they're
going to miss him.
He kept it together in the face of
overwhelming criticism,
which is really interesting.
Like the way he handled it without a
hint of bitterness or anger.
He's a fascinating guy in that way.
He's a very,
very measured guy.
Yeah.
He's nothing if not measured like that's
the.
He's half everything.
Yeah,
and I think the.
One of the good things about having a
guy like that,
one of the most important thing is like
you can criticize him,
you could with them,
you're not with them,
but having a guy like that sets the tone
for the way we think about ourselves and
he was a nice guy.
He's an arTiculate guy.
he was warm and friendly.
I believed him.
Yeah.
That's the tone.
Whether or not he was really like that
24 slash seven,
I don't fucking know,
man.
It seems like he was,
but he's setting the tone with his
behavior like,
yeah,
that's what what people are most
terrified of by something like trump
becoming president.
They're worried that there's a lot of
people that are like super aggressive
and that like having like an insulting
president
who.
Yeah,
I'm,
I'm thinking about whether I agree with
you about whether obama raised the
discourse because it got courser and he
got yelled at and you lie and all that
stuff.
He made peopLe worse in some ways toward
him.
Uh,
how much can you talk radio and internet
and talk radio got worse in the last
eight years,
which could just be natural.
It have been worse without them.
Yeah.
It's not a simple because it is like,
it did get worse,
but I think the thing that you said it's
really worthwhile.
It's like the level headedness event
dude,
and like a really measured kind hearted
guy.
See,
it's hard for me to discern how much of
the hate he gets his from his policy
from where the just the current state of
the United States is in the eyes of
ourselves,
the world financially,
resources,
jobs,
all that stuff.
And then how much of that,
how much of it is racism?
Yeah.
How much of it is,
um,
how much of it is legitimate criticism
that makes sense?
How much of it is,
you know,
this a criticism that he's always had
that by trying to be accommodating to
everybody,
he really gets nothing done,
you know?
I don't know.
I don'T understand it.
Um,
it's,
it's way too complicated for me to dive
in.
The hatred thing that I point out always
is,
I think it's probably half 50 percent
racism and february percent republicans
fucking hate democrats.
They fucking hate them.
It's so.
That's two presidents in a row that
they've said we're not legitimate.
It's so because they did the same thing
with clinton where they tried to indict
them pretty much from day one and
investigate the fuck out of him and his
wife.
Well,
do you rememBer that republicans versus
I should say republican,
uh,
politicians because they can't say,
you know,
I can't speak for all people.
Sorry.
Donald Trump was a birther.
Oh,
right now I know he was the big.
He was the big proponent of it.
Yeah.
He was saying he's kenyan.
He's,
he's only down by three.
I mean,
he kept saying it too.
He kept going all in member.
They released the birth certificate and
everything.
Like this is a forgery.
Yeah,
too.
God damn forgery.
Yeah.
It all these reasons to believe it's a
forgery.
Yeah.
He has people in Hawaii investigating.
How hilarious is it though,
that people would be worried if he
wasn't born in the right spot?
Uh,
well that speaks to people's,
a suspicion.
They want to believe that there's a
manchurian candidate and it's really.
There's a pod and there's a sale here.
Neil brandon,
as jesus is my witness,
he hates America.
And in the second amendment to peak a
ball and it feels good to play the
victim.
Yeah.
That's the thing people also forget is
like,
no,
it feels fucking really good to go.
Like he's out to get us.
And he doesn't believe what I believe.
It was like,
no,
he's fucking boring ass.
He,
I believe he may be an atheist,
but I believe,
but he's a boy.
I think that's the worst thing you say
about him religiously.
Otherwise he's a piece christian at
least.
So the idea that if he's a muslim,
he's an awful muslim and he knows
another vacancy,
what happens?
Yeah.
I'm sure.
Yeah,
exactly.
So I bring garlic to the vampire house.
That's right.
I don't know man.
I just,
I don't think anybody's ever going to be
able to do that job.
I think that job is a ridiculous job and
I think that at the very least he moved
some social issues in a way.
Like during his time I feel like people
were more tolerant in a lot of ways.
Like it,
it,
it opened up a lot of social issues that
I don't think would have been addressed
wIth a,
a less measured,
more easily accessible
truly is like progressive where it's
like,
yeah,
like I'm a progressive politician so I
want things to evolve.
But then there's like the fucking ed
snowden shit.
Well that's the thing is he's super
authoritarian and some with drones and
snowed and shit like that leaks.
They were worried about leaks than bush
was.
Yeah.
But here's the thing about drones,
right?
Was that happening anyway?
Was that just going to happen anyway?
And is,
is it because he's an office,
I mean,
how much of effect does he have on what
the heads of military decided to do and
not do with things like drones?
How much of an effect do you think,
like personally he has on that?
I feel like a lot.
did you watch the,
the,
the cia thing on a showtime?
What?
That was like the last seven heads of
the cia.
They documentary about the.
No,
it's fucking good.
But it talks about.
Yeah,
it's like seven or eight.
Michael hayden,
bunch of them.
These guys.
Uh,
and,
and they talk about having leon panetta,
they talk about having,
having a guy insight on video live and
having to decide whether it's go time.
Jesus christ.
Oh,
master's years.
Wow.
Yeah.
Good.
Huh?
Yeah.
Really good.
Crazy john.
Super like,
you know,
right wing.
It's like it's,
it's,
it is very pro death and pro pro fire,
fire,
fire our weapons.
We got the weapons,
let's use him type thing.
But
it's interesting that everybody,
pretty much that's involved at the
highest level in,
in military is.
I mean,
there's a giant percentage of them that
are probably conservative.
Right?
Right,
right.
No,
I
think so.
I feel like it's 80 percent even though
I'm making that up.
Yeah.
I would say I agree with your made up
quote.
Thank you.
That's a good number.
I would agree with that.
I don't even think.
Here's an interesting one.
What percentage of merchandise do women
buy in America?
Percentage
of mert all merchandise in America.
Forty percent.
Eighty percent.
Oh my god.
Isn't that fucking insane?
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Wow.
Eighty percent oF merchandise is
purchased by women.
Oh wow.
I don't even know what.
I've known that for months now and I
still don't know what to make.
That's incredible.
yeah.
I juSt googled it said 85 percent can be
as high as 85.
They're window.
Yeah.
And they market,
but the market,
I guess they market to men to get the
women to say,
hey,
buy this for me.
I don't know what I'm [inaudible] men
wouldn't have been by like video games.
Deodorant.
Yes.
Shoes.
Yeah.
jamie's really into shoes.
um,
wow.
That's a big number.
that's a big fucking number.
It was like,
almost like it's trying to in some way
replicate something that exists in the
wild.
This is the great joe rogan to go on.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean classic rogan numbers so strongly
in the camp of women buying shit.
Who,
why?
What is god saying?
Yeah.
It's got to come from the gas thing.
They want to collect stuff.
Yeah.
It's like the same leftover echoing urge
that made them pick wild apricots.
Yeah.
And we want to go and hunt.
I bet percentage of men hunting is at
least 80.
Yeah.
There's a lot of men.
Um,
I don't know what the number of women
would be.
Go ahead and they do it,
but a lot of women do it in and they
turned it into a career or how come?
Because if you can be like,
I'm a personality,
a hunting personality and you're a
woman,
that's like a legitimate career path.
Like there's a bunch of decent looking
and you can shoot for the bow.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And um,
it also allows men and women to watch
their hunt and shows together.
I like when the girl when's.
She's always right.
Yeah.
It says the same thing for motorsports
says everyday agree that women racist
bring fans out to the game.
Seventy four percent of males in 62
percent of females agree that women
racers bring fans out to the games.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Well that's some underdog shit.
I think it's the woman among the.
I mean,
I think it's like the girls who race in
nascar,
they go like,
danica patrick is so hot and you're
like,
eh,
she's all right.
She was like,
you know,
we'll give her a six and a half,
seven out of 10.
That's hilarious.
Um,
yeah,
like I can't say that she is like a,
you know,
uh,
but,
but it is definitely like more.
It's the thing that you notice.
Yeah,
iT's super odd,
right?
It's super odd for a woman to want to do
that.
But,
but normal.
I mean it's nothing.
Nothing wrong with it.
But for a woman to want to race like
formula one or something like that.
Well there's a,
there's,
ooh,
she's created looking.
It's primary fo allow you say that the
right way.
she's misalign tropic.
Oh see,
these are all race car drIvers.
these women.
Jesus.
Wow,
that's gangster courtney.
For us.
It's good name.
Hope that sounds so porn daily,
but you have to be like a wild person to
be a race car driver.
Like a one new thing.
It's a characterological thing.
I wonder.
It's so risky and it's so rewarding,
I would guess in a sense of like a
sensory perception sentence.
Yeah.
Well,
yeah.
You want to talk about upsetting your
nervous system?
Yeah.
And the consequences are terrible.
if you fuck up,
you know,
car accidents at 150 miles an hour and
not cute.
Yeah.
Instant.
Horrific too.
When you see people get spun around,
they could fucking crashed and firing
like that.
Like The,
it explodes like flex and you're like,
was that a foot?
I just saw dude,
but having said that,
high,
high a rate of mortality,
like the or I'm sorry,
low rate of mortality.
Like they actually survive way more than
you think where you go,
oh,
that's another one that was like dead,
dead.
You're dead.
Those people are dead and they're fine.
Yeah.
Have you been seeing these people that
put these balloons around their bodies
and get hit by bowls?
I haven't.
We got to show you this.
I'm looking forward to it very much.
This is a recurring theme on this show.
It's almost like one of those top 40 a
morning radio zoo shows where they have
those weekly gags on.
One of our weekly gags is show one of
the guests,
the people with the balloons on that get
hit by the bowls and this is my take on
it.
I don't think people realize how
vulnerable they are.
This is a.
Oh,
this is a different one.
okay.
Cool.
This is a different one.
And look,
they got a rodeo clown and everything.
They're trying to rope.
Oh,
this got the bull is going after it.
Guy get out of that suit on.
Oh,
he got flipped.
he got jackson.
Oh my god.
This is even more horrific.
So this was.
This is obviously something went wrong
because the bulls,
they still seem pretty happy to be in
there.
They're not leaving.
Oh my god.
The guy was fun.
I liked.
It's interesting about.
It's an interesting metaphor about bowls
and a temper tantrum.
They go after the guy,
even though they're just mad that their
balls are tied up,
but they're like,
well,
fuck it.
I'm in a bad mood anyway.
This is the better one.
This is the one that we were talking
about.
This one looks like
it's first of all,
definitely taking place in Mexico,
right?
Second of all these cushions these guys
have,
they're just not big enough.
They only go from the waist up.
Would you want to cover your dick?
I think.
Yeah,
you're gonna.
You're gonna carnage.
Watch this because the bull gets loose
and when the bowl gets loose,
these fuckers in this thing,
I think they just have this,
this stupid plan that they're going to
be fine.
You've got to back it up a little
because the guy who already got jacked.
Yeah,
but he got jacked before that.
Right there.
Boom.
So they let the bull out the bowl sees
these assholes walking around with these
giant jelly fish.
Fish balloons.
I'll get a boom.
I mean he goes flying,
he gets gored on the ground.
He gets run over.
I mean this guy gets fucking jacked
and looking at the horses though,
huh?
No,
the horses.
Even the bowls know like,
man,
I don't want to fuck with that.
Well they don't.
I think they don't see.
They don't recognize him as the is doing
anything.
People.
Oh,
they just don't like people.
Right?
I think.
I think because of the ball stuff.
Come on cow.
I think cows have always realized that
people want to eat them.
Look at that.
Boom,
boom.
I mean if a cow sees a person,
what are the odds that that's going to
be a bad thing?
The odds are pretty god damn strong.
Yeah.
Nothing good's going to happen like,
oh good.
They might squeeze your tests for a
couple of years and then shoot you in
the head for sure.
One day they're going to shoot you in
the head.
Do you think it's naturally ingrained
though?
I don't think [inaudible] is like an
enemy then you can't pass that on june.
Genetically I don't think.
Do you know what a scrub bull as a.
No.
Tell me
scrubble or animals that until like the
last,
you know,
x amount of years used to be domestic
cattle,
but then they get loose and they live in
the countryside and this,
this is something that happens often in
Australia where they are not necessarily
like the same strain anymore as like a
strain of cattle that you would use for
like beef or you know,
like that you would bring to market.
They have dIfferent,
they have different genetics now because
they've been wild for so long and
they're not like an angus cow.
So if you have angus cows and this thing
shows up and starts fucking your,
uh,
your,
your cattle,
you've got a problem,
you get some weird cross breed of a cow
that might not be like the best for
eating right.
But these things,
they live wild in the bush,
in Australia and in Australia there's no
predators.
They have like,
you know,
small things like dingoes and stuff like
that,
but they've never taken out a bull.
There's the you would need a lIon or
something like that to kill one of these
things and they get cool looking like
they look different.
They don't look like a cow anymore.
They start looking more and more
primitive in some weird
way.
They start looking more like like a
animal that you would see in africa or
something.
It's really fascinating,
man.
Like here's some of the photos,
like look at that.
It looks like a long time ago.
Yeah,
that was a different animal,
but if you just google scrub bull,
is that what it is?
Okay.
Like that one in the upper left hand
corner is a perfect example.
Like that is not really.
Obviously that's a cow,
right?
It's a bull,
but that looks way different than the
average bold that you see either at the
rodeo.
I'm looking at his balls back there.
Right.
I'm looking at john jay.
That's up package son for them.
Huge balls,
giant antlers or horns rather,
and his his face and just the way his
body's buIlt.
It's different.
He's a wild animal and he's living the
way they're supposed to be and that's
why he looks like a wild animal and you
know what else?
He's fine.
He's doing great.
They're super aggressive though.
There's some of the most dangerous
things to run across if you're out in
the bush as it were.
I don't see what you mean.
That's another one of the most dangerous
things.
What is that?
That's a buffalo,
I don't know.
Well,
they rammed earth.
Oh,
yay.
Is there been like a lot of animal
chasing?
You saw the tiger eats the lady last
week in beijing.
That was pretty wild,
but a lot of like giraffes chasing cars
and shit.
Have you seen some of these videos now?
Look,
drab lookup.
Draft chases,
a chases.
Listened.
That only makes sense.
Hauling ass by the way only makes sense.
Yeah.
They're tired of like,
here you go.
Oh,
I've seen this.
Yeah.
That is crazy.
The strides on this motherfucker.
I know this shit in their pants.
Look at it.
Running behind them.
You know if they would hit you with
their head,
we're right behind you.
It's like you were saying about the
equip thing.
Oh my god,
this is terrifying.
I think he comes around a corner again.
I think he does.
I don't know if this is the right one.
Oh my god.
What do you think it would do to those
people?
Just start smacking them with the
tender.
Yeah.
Whip whip his neck at them.
It's really dangerous.
Like you got to think of how big his
head is,
man.
Have you ever seen them fight so cool.
Yeah.
It's really painful.
I mean like in,
in terms of animal shit,
like that's one of those things where
you're like,
I don't know guys.
it is.
What am I fighting?
But that's like really fucking odd.
It's one of the weirdest.
and you want to talk about a concussion?
Oh yeah.
Like they must just be evolved or have
really small brains are very tightly
packed.
Brian's
well,
you know,
sheep can slam into each other like
super hard,
but their brains are literally connected
to their head different than ours are.
They're like,
they've evolved to absorb impact.
Yeah.
Rad would assume rams are too.
Yeah,
yeah,
that's,
that's insane.
Those wild desert bighorn sheep,
like,
oh my god,
this is crazy.
Like what a strange trait to develop to
have neck fighting.
They're fighting like two snakes.
Oh my god.
I beat the fuck out of each other too.
See if you can find a,
a good video of a big horn sheep head
button
each other because these fucking things.
They have these giant like battering
rams that grow out of their heads and
they like raise up and crash into each
other and the sound sounds like a rifle
going off.
Yeah.
And they do it in the mountains.
Oh,
these things,
these fucking things.
Living with jesus and decided to drink.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
We don't have to listen to what that guy
saying.
He just talking about snow on the ground
and the sheep are a going after it.
It's crazy how hard they had head butt.
Each other.
Boom.
Is that.
what was the,
the audio is from or was it from
something else?
it's weird audio,
but they,
uh,
they evolve to do this.
It's just such a strange trait.
Look at this.
Oh my god.
Play that back hoe.
Yeah,
that's a rifle.
They're getting rid of the fuck.
I think troy,
that's so weird.
These things are straight out of star
wars.
They really are.
Yeah.
I mean,
look at this fucking animal.
Any kind of natural defense is always
interesting.
A shell or a horn.
Yeah.
Oh,
there's,
these things are dope as fuck man.
You know,
they uh,
have brought them back to a lot of
environments now.
They,
they,
they've transplanted them all throughout
the west.
It's kind of interesting.
They did it.
They brought them to a bunch of
different states.
They took like a viable males and
females and they installed them in these
areas and monitored their growth.
Are they indigenous to,
are they indigenous states?
They used to be.
Yes they are,
but they used to be in More areas.
They used to have a wider territory.
But what happened was,
I guess after world war or after the
civil war,
rather,
there were a bunch of people that,
uh,
were market hunters and you know,
the same type of people that shot all
the buffalo for the hides and all that
jazz.
They did that with a lot of animals all
throughout the entire west and they,
you know,
potentially wiped out or got close to
having them wiped out like a bunch of
different big game species like elk and
deer and it took while to bring all
those
things back.
So what a lot of these,
uh,
conservation organizations are doing is
taking these things and dropping them
off into the mountain someplaces then
monitoring them and making sure their
population survive.
But it's,
it's,
it's a fucking way to cool it vanana
mall to not figure out how to bring it
back.
She got to bring it back to.
I've seen them in the wild.
They are fucking cool.
They're cool.
And they seem Like they're nature's
okay.
Despite the headbutting.
Oh no,
they're just chilling.
They just don't want that dude to fuck
their girls.
Yeah.
Like tomorrow.
So that we understand it.
Yeah.
As far as violence goes,
it's like probably like the nicest
violence to us.
It would suck if they head butted us,
but it doesn't seem to bother them.
But I also would promise you that nfl
players watch that and they're like,
yeah,
we get enough today.
Yeah.
Like before games and shIt,
maybe have nfl players have to evolve to
develop now a connection to their brain.
Like a ram's.
Yeah.
They need to heart.
I think it's gonna be awhile.
It's going to take a few deCades.
You hear the helicopter,
by the way,
still still going on.
TheRe was some sort of a gas leak a few
miles away.
Some shit went down.
Still going down.
Um,
yeah.
I'm watching those things.
Head butt.
Each other make just makes you weirded
out as to how the different ways that
things evolve.
But they're all kind of life.
Like how strong the differences between
an octopus that can get out of the hole,
the size of a quarter squeezes whole
body through and that thing that slammed
his head into one of the other competing
man's raises up on his back legs and
come crashing for it.
And if they don't even budge,
man.
Yeah,
they collide with each other.
It sounds like a gun went off and they
just stare at each other.
They're like such a cool animal.
They have giant nuts.
Huge that this is based on firsthand.
Okay.
Yeah.
It was pointed out to being by this guy
steve rinella.
It's amazing.
The,
you know,
when you,
you think I don't see a lot of dick's
day to day.
You see so many dicks like on animals
and dogs.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
And we are fine with animal dicks.
It's true.
But human dx,
we are.
We have laws about hm.
But we are living in a,
in a,
in a playground of fucking animal cock.
Well,
you know what I think,
I think people are supposed to live.
Um,
I think like naturally like,
well we're inclined to live.
We're inclined to live in a place where
you don't need to do anything as far as
clothing.
If you go back to like the people that
are the indigenous people in the amazon
that are chilling and drinking iowasca
and going fishing and growing their own
vegetables,
they're basically naked,
right?
Yeah.
Probably been like that forever.
They're walking around barefoot when I
think as soon as you put on clothes,
as soon as you can manipulate your
environment and live in a spot where you
normally wouldn't be able to live,
but you figure
say phoenix.
Oh yeah.
Perfect example.
Perfect.
My friend
mike goldberg lives out there and he
likes it.
He just goes from one air conditioned
room,
another air conditioner room workout in
an air conditioned gym.
Go home to an air conditioner in America
are either way too,
like how did you put up with this cold
or how do you put up with this heat?
I wonder if that could adversely affect
your health if you're only breathing in
air conditioned air.
Okay.
Time.
Oh yeah,
like mortality rates.
Yeah.
I wonder.
Probably not though,
because the old people go to Florida and
they go to it.
Yeah.
They thrive.
It seems to put a couple of years on
them.
Yeah.
I think struggling with your
environment.
Yeah.
Uh,
yeah.
People are less likely to have.
I think I can fuck with heat.
I could take phoenix way over.
Like Minnesota.
Yeah.
A lot of people feel that way.
The like,
um,
the,
the negative aspects of heat is you just
have to turn the air conditioning.
The negative aspects of that cold is
like,
nothing's happening.
You might get shut down the fucking
power michael out.
You might have to light your couch on
fire.
Stay alive.
Yes.
Whereas I feel like I could withstand.
Yeah,
130 degrees if I had water.
Yeah.
Like here,
here's all the.
You would have to have.
You'd have to have two things happen at
the same time.
A pandemic epidemic as far as like a
disease and power going out.
you'd have to have those two things
happen in the winter and you,
the people that are supposed to turn the
power back on,
they're not going to go to work.
There's just some kind of an evil flu.
If you get near people and they Sneeze
on you,
you're going to be dead within 24 hours.
Like that's all possible.
That can happen.
And if that does happen and the power
grid stays down duRing the winter in
someplace and they can't figure out how
to get people to go out there and fix
it.
And
yeah,
whereas what's the,
you look up the stats on heat hot when
the air conditioning doesn't work after
it's $500.
Fine.
Oh no,
you're 100 percent right.
But you can take your shirt off his
shade.
You can lay in the pool,
sweat,
you sweat.
It's a natural thing.
There's negative known natural defenses
against cold selling.
Pussy.
Jamie,
you know,
you sound like jamie.
Sound like a no good.
I went through a week with a no power in
the middle of an ice storm and we
survived it.
You got,
you can put on layers and get warm.
You can,
you can start a fire if you want to get
cold.
You can't get cold when it's 100.
I've seen that argument.
My buddy has an argument.
It's a,
it makes sense,
but I don't,
I don't mind super duper hotness though.
I just don't mind it.
Like I,
my body likes it better.
Yeah.
Well I think everybody's body is
certainly different.
I mean,
you,
you'd have to wonder,
you know,
if they believe that there's certain
people that have diets that um,
would better suit them because their
ancestors came from certain parts of the
world.
Like that's the theory.
I think that that kind of makes sense
that people would have a different
temperature requirements as well.
You know,
what makes them feel like it works?
Yeah.
I think it stands to reason.
It's like I don't have good circulation.
I just think that people in being able
to manipulate the environment the way we
can.
We will.
There's too many of us.
We couldn't stay in all the good spots.
We can't all just live in which I live
in san diego.
Yeah,
exactly.
In fact,
people don't even really want to live in
san diego and it's there now.
Sandra was here.
Yeah.
But san diego is amazing.
No,
I know that's.
But they still are like,
it's perfect climate and people are
like,
no.
I would even say san diego's not warm
enough for me.
Really.
I like la heat.
Wow.
Yeah.
You know what?
There's a lot of cool people in san
diego.
I've always enjoyed hanging out with
people in san diego.
I think it's a.
It's an interesting combination between
like military and like surfers.
Yeah.
They're not a very stressed out group.
No.
San diego.
Paypal.
I think it's a really good city,
man.
I think it's a really good city.
I think san diego is like probably one
of my favorite.
Definitely one of my favorite cities in
California and julia has the most
ticklish audience is ticklish.
That's what I say when the crowds like
so good.
You're like,
oh,
you guys are just ticklish.
That club is awesome.
Yeah.
The lawyer store.
I think I want to do that the next time
I go back there.
You,
what?
Do you do?
Theater?
Say?
Yeah,
I've been doing theaters there,
but uh,
I,
I did a laughing skull in atlanta last
week.
Oh yeah,
that's really good.
It was so fun.
Yeah.
And it,
it made me think like,
you know,
I got to do more little places as well.
How'd you end up doing the laughing
skull?
because I wanted to do a small spot
beCause I did the tabernacle there last
time I was there.
Yeah.
And I want to fuck around and come up
with some new stuff and I've got some
stuff I'm working on and I just knew
it'd be a real intimate,
real,
a real tight little crowd.
something like 80 people.
So.
Cool.
What'd you charge?
20 bucks?
No,
nothing crazy.
Yeah.
But the um,
but it wasn't like a $100 gold circles.
It's comedy club prices.
It's a comedy club.
Comedy clubs are there are so important
and a lot of people that like get to
theaters and they get to that theater
stage.
They never want to give back to the
comedy clubs.
They always have this like weird
adversarial relationship with club
owners.
But I'm always like,
look,
nobody's perfect here.
But if it wasn't for these people that
are willing to open a comedy club,
crazy assholes,
like you and me wouldn't have any place
to work,
we're not going to make our own club.
Right?
Like gods like that are awesome.
like bob fisher was the ice house.
like he's such a sweetheart of a guy
that it it,
like it doesn't just benefit you to do
it because it's a good thing financially
to help him and help that club,
but it's,
he's like,
you need people like that,
like this.
The only way we ever get to work.
Same with comedy and magic club.
Oh my greatest.
Yeah.
He's the sweetest guy.
He's one of the nicest people that's
ever walked the face of this planet.
Yeah.
Great.
Yeah,
man.
Look all the shit jamie masada takes a
lot of heat,
but think about all the charitable stuff
that jane dishonest.
Absolutely.
Jamie masada has done a lot of great
stuff.
He really has and he continues to work
with a lot of underprivileged children
and he does a lot of different kind of
get to do comedy camp on saturday.
He,
yeah,
he's a good dude.
Jamie.
Jamie's good dude.
And we need all these folks,
these folks and they need us and it's
like it's.
But there's something that happens when
people I think definitely happens when
you don't get the respect,
you think that you deserve early on
comics club.
Yeah.
But that was the offers are pretty like,
yeah,
1500,
like really shitty sometimes and then
they go like,
well you haven't done anything.
It's like the negotiation thing.
It's hard to forget that shit.
It is.
And it does become this thing of like it
forces you as a comic to go like,
well,
when I get the chance to fuck you,
you're going to get fucked.
Exactly the same way.
You're fucking me now.
And they do it too.
And they fucked pretty much everyone
and the,
the developed this connection in their
head.
The club owners that all the club owners
are adversarial with each other.
No.
With you?
Yeah.
Like this is,
these are all your advocacy.
Yeah.
This year,
the comic,
those,
the club owners,
they're trying to fuck you.
They're all pieces of shit.
Yeah.
You should give you your fucking money.
It should be happier there.
Yeah.
Opposite sides of the aisle.
Yeah,
absolutely.
It's like the weirdest relationship.
But if,
if there was no comedy clubs,
dude we do,
we will be fucked.
We're so lucky that those goddamn things
exploded in the eighties.
Yeah.
Like when I think about like the lenny
bruce days,
when he first started out,
he used to have to mc.
He,
they're like,
yeah,
you still have to go on,
you do standup inbetween strippers or
fucking or something along those lines.
Like there was no comedy clubs like
they,
that's a really recent thing in terms of
like the last hundred years.
Well I was explaining to a buddy of mine
about the,
how comedy has become so necessary and I
think it's partially because of the news
in that when the news started,
every news division like lost money and,
but you,
in order to get a license you had to
have a good news division.
And then in the eighties they
deregulated it.
And then news became a profit center for
networks and,
and good journalism basically went out
the window.
So guys like John Stewart and guys like
Michael Moore and guys like chris rock
and guys that were like political and
had tv shows became almost like the
function of um,
of news programs before this.
And I was explaining to him,
he was like,
oh,
okay.
Because I was finding someone like how
john came,
how his rise to power and cole bear and
all these people because there's no
alternative.
You can't.
And now the internet you can get at
least lIke reddit or,
or like there's a lot of shitty websites
with quote unquote news on them.
But,
but for a long time you couldn't get,
it was just,
there was a vacuum of like,
there's no big objective opinion or John
Oliver on hbo where he'll do these deep
dives into,
cause no one else is going to do them
because there's no money in them.
Allegedly.
They'd rather do some sensational,
uh,
like the dumbest thing that the most
recent dumping trumps that,
uh,
and there's no,
like there's a premium on,
on objective truth or at least subject
funnily subjective truth.
Joe rogan,
your thoughts.
This is a weird time.
So weird time when it comes to,
uh,
trying to dis disassemble the way we've,
we've got this bizarre system set up the
way we've got it structured.
like we're getting older,
you know?
and as we get older,
we realized,
well,
we're just going to pass on this stupid
system to the people that are coming
next.
Yeah.
We haven't fixed anything.
That's the
one of the things I almost don't even
know how to fix the shit.
Oh yeah,
it's looking real good question.
But there's an entanglement problem like
we were talking about earlier when we
were talking about different ways that
people are making money,
like there's so much money to be made.
Like we were talking about it in divorce
courts,
but think about how much money there is
to be made in keeping this system of
government exactly the same way it is
right now.
Yeah.
There's so many jobs that are dependent
upon it.
Like even if we think that it's a
ridiculous idea,
we need to abolish the whole thing and
start from scratch.
What do we do with all those people that
are working for it?
Well,
the other thing I was thinking is
there's people like the thing that I do
like about the trump movement is people
could just go and like know the system's
broken and it doesn't work for it.
Doesn't Work for people anymore because
everybody is bought and paid for
everybody in congress.
Lobbying is,
pays,
literally lobbyists,
right?
Laws,
so people and people don't like it and
they don't know how to stop it.
Right.
So you've got people.
I've got a system.
People go,
well,
do you know anyone that you think would
run for office?
No.
Do you know what I mean?
And as much as it's like because it's a
weird job into,
I don't know anyone who's just like that
ideologically driven and could navigate
the way it is now.
So as much as I'm like,
well they're going to change.
We're going to shake the system up to
what?
but it's not just that stop and think
about what it is.
It's like to elect a leader for someone
to campaign and tell you that they would
make the best leader.
Like all throughout history,
the people that are proclaiming
themselves to be the ones that you
should follow are almost always the ones
you should never fall.
Exactly right.
so when someone is proclaiming
themselves to be capable of leading this
land and I am going to be your king and
I will take you to the highest heights.
Right.
But I don't even think I needed to do
that.
Right.
Well,
the chance to do that,
you'd have to kill the king.
You have to be the.
Yeah.
But this is essentially the same model,
right?
That they're doing when they're running
for president,
even though we know that that's not the
kind of personality trait that you would
want from a leader,
you would want someone who's who's not
in any way promoting of themselves.
Yeah.
A selfless,
selfless person who does this thing
that's incredibly a self interested
and they would have to figure out how to
have fairly monitor this.
The society that we live in had a fairly
well.
When do you decide when you put people
in jail,
when do you do?
Do we throw all the old rules out and
completely look at them all with new
facts and new ideas?
Did we just.
Is it like there's a lot of weird drug
arguments where there's certain drugs
that are illegal that are way more
dangerous in certain drugs that are
illegal and then you look at this money
trail behind all that and you're like,
okay,
how can you guys still do this?
Like how can you still do this?
Like let's,
we should make things legal that the
scientists agree should be legal and
then everything else is dangerous.
we should figure out how to regulate it,
but you can't decide like why?
Why is everybody deciding based on like
ancient information?
Right.
It doesn't make any sense.
Socratically elected government and.
But the p again,
it attracts the wrong kinds of people.
It's a,
it's like churchill or somebody said
it's the,
it's the best of all the bad systems.
Oh yeah.
For sure.
Obama released a or exonerated a bunch
of drug war victims today,
which I thought it was fascinating thing
is a few hundred.
Yeah,
I think like 300,
something like that.
Yeah.
Which is what I hope he said don't like
if you fuck up,
you're fucking me.
Basically the poets who knows what kind
of damage is done for time.
Guy can't vote,
can't,
can't get most jobs.
right.
Uh,
yeah.
It's like a very,
very fucked up system.
How does that work?
Are you an ex felon?
If the president you have to clean out
of you're exonerated?
I don't know.
Does that make you,
uh,
ever pardoned?
She's been touched by magic.
You've been touched by magic.
The president has magic.
He can tell the court that they have to
let people out of jail.
Yeah.
How old is that wacky idea?
That might be the wackiest of all the
people.
Like I'm going to.
Yeah.
You can decide that the gardendale
killed people should get free.
Yeah.
Because you're the king.
Hinkley went free the other day.
See that?
What?
Yeah,
what?
He's out on the streets,
man.
He might be listening to us last week.
John hinckley,
the one who shot reagan.
Yeah.
Holy shit.
They let him free.
Yeah.
They're trying to get obama killed after
35 years.
Who was he trying to say?
Wow.
He was trying to impress jodie foster's
right message.
He was.
It turns out you were barking up the
wrong tree for and she don't like dudes.
Hey bro,
you don't know about that.
Um,
the,
she's out the right guy with the right
deck to this spot with the right dick.
Brought it back to back to the land of
the heroes.
I gotta get outta here.
Joe.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Dude.
I did want to tell the people that I
will be,
uh,
in chicago and,
and uh,
and madison,
Wisconsin,
the 18th and 19th.
Go to [inaudible] dot com.
Where is it?
What do you do in chicago?
I'm doing three myths.
Three valiant theater.
follow your theater.
Chicago's got a lot of cool old theater.
Yeah,
it's cool.
And I'm the madison.
I'm doing The majestic and then I'm
shooting three mics in los angeles.
September ninth.
Don't have a venue yet,
but majestic theater in madison,
Wisconsin or said that's a dope spot.
Yeah.
So you,
um,
you don't change shirts or anything?
Do you know?
Same shirt,
had wardrobe changes?
Yeah,
it'd be pretty great costume on.
Um,
so,
uh,
so yeah,
so three mikes September 9th and la go
to [inaudible] dot com and,
or follow me on twitter,
I'll update it and 18th in madison of
august and 19th of August in chicago.
I'd hopefully delved enough into that.
A magnetic treatment for depression.
Yeah,
look it up if you're interested because
it's really,
really.
It was very,
it's nothing has been more helpful to me
in my entire career of depression.
Is it available to everybody?
I mean it's tests thing.
Yeah,
you can look it up.
Like I said,
it's covered by blue cross,
so it's a really impressive.
Yeah,
it's a hugely helpful and the numbers
are really good.
Uh,
there's a new one also called like I
want to call like feta burst or alpha
burst cmt,
but they're using the cmt shit for tons
of,
like you were saying about that radio
lab,
they're using it for tons of different
brain areas and it's.
And it's really effective.
So I,
and I'd say that having experienced it
firsthand,
it's kind of crazy.
We're juicing our brains up with
electricity and firing them up.
Who gets her?
Yeah.
Good.
We're gonna have magneto helmets one day
for sure.
Right,
like the x men dude to put that helmet
on and all the magnets and he would
float through the air.
yeah,
we're going to pull those fucking
things.
We just got to make it to the,
to we're going to make it past or are
failing bodies,
but once we get there,
I think one of these cranial helmets,
if they had a cranial helmet that came
up with that,
how these electrodes just constantly was
zapping your brain while you're walking
around with it on.
Yeah.
See your life clear.
Yes.
You know your boy joe.
Everybody knows that.
You're a good man as well.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Nice.
I always enjoy our conversations too.
Yeah.
Fun.
Neil brandon,
ladies.
Gentlemen.
I'll ride.