Her freak bitches.
Sure.
I agree with you.
Can I switch gears?
Yeah,
I've got to ask you about that.
Yeah.
Ask me about anything.
Joey Diaz.
Tell me everything.
How did you meet Joe Diaz?
Cause I want,
cause then I want you to ask me this.
I want you to ask me what my experience
with Joe,
but how did you meet him?
How did he come into the fold?
I met Joey Diaz in the late nineties,
uh,
at the comedy store.
I think I met him in [inaudible] 96 or
97,
something like that.
Uh,
right when Joey moved to La,
we just started hanging around the
comedy store.
We became friends and then,
uh,
I started taking him on the road with
me.
Like,
uh,
the late nineties.
We've been best friends forever,
so I know of Joey.
I don't know Joey.
I've never met him.
Never met Joe.
Never.
I call him up right now.
TV and the whole bit.
And you know,
I know him from,
from immediately when I see your podcast
and all that.
But,
and he's in the circles.
He does some Jujitsu.
He's funnier than hell.
And he's a gangster.
So I like him,
but I don't know anything about him.
So he comes on my podcast now he has a
podcast.
So of course my opening line to them is,
hey,
how'd you get into pocket?
Right?
I'm going to put here,
here's your plug for your podcast,
and we're going to go on and talk about
my agenda.
So I say,
Joe,
I say to him,
Joey,
how'd you get into podcasting?
And his response,
you know,
chill.
Sudden he wouldn't call me jail.
It was always shit.
You know what?
Chill still calls me Joe Rogan.
I'm mugged a hooker down in New Jersey
and senator Lee set her wig on fire.
It's like,
okay,
we got two,
there's two moving parts here.
First off,
that is,
I don't know how that answers my
question of how,
but now I need to know the story here.
So we ties it all together with,
he went on something,
just something,
he got an appearance.
He told the story of mugging her,
a hooker in New Jersey and setting her
wig on fire.
And all of a sudden he blew up overnight
and he goes,
yeah,
I realized people like the stores.
I never knew that I had stories from the
part of the country I'm in and the
neighborhood I grew up in,
I thought everybody had these stories.
He's like,
chill center.
And I thought I'd tell you I Mugu Hooker
and light her wig on fire.
You Go,
yeah,
well I'm up 10 hookers and let 10 wigs
on fire.
It's like I didn't know I had stories.
And then it just goes from there.
And he starts telling me about so,
so he,
so he ends up doing two years or 18
months.
And I said,
well,
what kind of jam did you get in there?
And he said,
well,
I was actually,
I was doing the cop's job for him.
You know,
the cops don't want drugs on the
streets.
I went and took two kilos off the
streets for him.
This is how he presents it to me.
He goes,
yeah,
you know,
the two kilos wasn't as big of a deal.
Oh.
He said,
oh,
so I robbed two kilos.
He goes and you know what else?
Chill.
Sudden I just happened to have a machine
gun.
And I go,
well,
I can see where that happening because
she has some times you just back into a
machine.
I had a machine gun with me and he goes,
but it's funny,
I wasn't in trouble for the gun.
I really wasn't that much trouble for
the drugs.
What they were upset about was the
kidnapping.
I'm going,
okay,
what?
What happened?
And this is my intro to the guy.
I'm like,
what?
What in the hell is this story?
You probably know the story,
but I did it.
So he tells me the whole story.
He says,
yeah,
but you know,
kidnappings kind of a weird charge
because when you and vandelay gotten
that scuffle in the ultimate fighter,
if I come and grab you and I take you
into the next room just to cool you
down,
taking into a room against your will,
that's kidnapping.
So I think like they got him on a
technicality jam,
like what they're doing with Frank Mir.
Some of these guys were talking about
and I said,
okay,
is that what happened?
And he goes,
no.
I duct taped the guy who was in my trunk
and then I held him in the house for a
week before I let them go like,
well,
the why didn't you tell me?
Why did you bring up the initial example
of taking me next door and cooling me
debt?
What that have to do?
I still don't know because he's crazy.
Very kangaroo looking to Kangaroos scare
the fuck out of me.
Now all of a sudden they started getting
jacks.
We saw a lot of that in Australia.
We're in balance.
When I was a kid,
when I was a kid.
Do you think they lift?
Yeah,
they definitely,
they check.
They looked like they were like fucking
school teachers.
Like they were newspaper reporters or
something or like a librarian.
He didn't look like these yoke monsters.
You see the one that's knocking on the
window of the person's house like I want
to come in.
Have you seen that video yet?
This jack came knocking on the door.
Look up,
look at them.
Come on.
Look how big that thing is.
There is big look.
Yeah,
look it up.
What in the fuck is that?
That's fake.
I've seen it live.
So what the hell is going on?
Do you think they have that extra muscle
thing like you said,
taking take pills or steroids and dicto
fucking bizarre animal that is,
that is amazing.
Bouncy mammal that will kick you and try
to hurt you.
Fuck you up.
No,
no,
no.
They're not always nice.
I felt the big guy.
You gotta be really careful around that.
Real.
Is that a real post?
Yes.
They say though,
they say though that if you find them in
the wild you are not supposed to ever
approach to beating off is that can't
move.
Eat.
No,
no son.
We saw two having sex.
Whoa.
The video though that it's kind of went
around last week is a kangaroo sing its
reflection in somebody's window and it's
trying to fight it.
So,
but the guys on the other side with the
camera and it's just as jacked like
kangaroo,
like punching the window.
Like it's scary.
Well.
Yeah,
it's one of the coolest video that came
out last week.
If you just type in a kangaroo,
a window,
this fighting himself in a window,
shadowboxing,
a window.
That's a weird animal.
I love them.
I think they're great,
but it's so weird what it does,
like the way it acts that sits on its
tail.
We spend,
it's bouncing around these legs and then
it's got those jacks,
upper body.
They were,
there was like a,
they get spooked.
Easy to like this one big one was trying
to have sex.
I'm going to say it wasn't sex.
It was definitely rape,
but it was like he was pulling her back
and she was trying to get away,
but there was a reason she was trying to
get away because there was like a weird
wing come.
They want to keen.
They all scattered.
Then they went under the tree and then
they got into it and I was like,
oh,
maybe she just wanted some privacy or,
that was really interesting how they had
to sneak out.
But she was scared.
And then as soon as this weird thing
came,
it was like a wind.
They all went scattered and then they
got back into,
it was exciting.
I liked Kanga.
Yeah.
This is it.
This is so scary.
I mean,
so it's you knock on the door.
That one's not too jacked.
Boy.
Boy,
it's creepy though.
You haven't looked at it.
All.
My God,
watch this and he starts getting pissed.
You scratched my window.
Can you scratch my window?
This is not the right video.
Or maybe,
I guess.
Yes.
Yeah,
he's the mirror.
Oh my God.
He's throwing himself at the window.
Fuck man.
He's trying to chess by himself.
Oh.
He's trying to fight what he sees as a
reflection in the window.
Okay,
whoa.
Yeah.