Hey fuckers,
what's going on?
Party people.
Welcome.
Welcome once again to the Joe Rogan
experience podcast.
This episode is brought to you by
stamps.com
stamps.com.
If you've ever gone to desk dot TV and
ordered one of those cute little kitty
cat tee shirts,
guess how they get to you bitches?
They get to you through stamps.com
because that's what brian red band uses.
You can buy and print official US
postage for any letter or package using
your own computer and printer and unlike
the post office stamps.com
never closes.
You can get posted whenever you need it.
Twenty four slash seven to a great asset
for small businesses
and not only it can eat,
you can buy these stamps so it looks
just like a stamp or you could just buy
it like on a.
It just prints it out.
So like if you have an envelope,
just an envelope in your printer and it
prints the stamp right on the,
on the envelope.
It's so fucking easy.
Like I was scared to use this for awhile
when I first started shipping tee shirts
out.
I would actually go to the post office
and sit there for like an hour with
these boxes where this old lady that
sits there puts a stamp on it and go
ways it and it took forever.
So I finally did this and man,
I will never ever go to that post office
again.
Post offices,
brutal.
There's a reason why they fucking shoot
each other every now and again.
They just fucking inbox outbox and bug.
I think the post office stamps.com,
I think it was like super fast,
like why are they saying.
It seems to me that the post office is
on its way out.
The ups store is way fucking easier to
use and something like stamps.com.
If you have a small business,
why you would be crazy to use anything
else.
Like it's the last thing you ever want
to do is take a bunch of fucking
packages to the post office with
stamps.com.
You don't have to do that shit.
You can do it whenever you want.
Twenty four hours a day.
It's convenient.
It's the way you want it.
You can just anytime you want,
wake up at three in the morning and do
it.
You don't have to go in line and have to
do.
You have to deal with nobody else.
It's a.
it's a beautiful thing.
If you use the Promo Code J R,
e,
m,
if you look up,
if you go to stamps.com,
there's a little microphone in the upper
right hand corner and if you go to that
microphone I said Adam Carolla
microphone.
It's an old school one.
Chris rock from one of his specials and
Lenny Bruce too.
Nobody ever really used those
microphones,
but if you want to look slick,
you'd get one of those microphones.
Meanwhile,
those microphones are pieces of shit.
It would sound like fucking dog shit.
If you ever did a comedy show and you
had one of those microphones,
everybody wants to use those microphones
for like their fucking head shots,
but if you were at a concert and you had
that microphone,
you'd be like,
what is this fucking stupid piece of
Shit you've given me?
This ancient shitbag goofy looking
fucking microphone.
It sounds great though.
Doesn't even sound that good.
Those old pieces of shit.
They sound terrible.
Anyway,
go to stamps.com.
Type in aj r,
e into the.
And there's also,
um,
there's a $110 bonus offer that includes
a digital scale and up to $55 free
postage.
So,
uh,
go there and check it out.
It's an excellent service.
And again,
Brian uses it to send out all those
desks.
Squad,
kitty,
cat tee shirts.
So stamps.com.
Go to the mic,
click it.
Offer the offer.
Excuse me.
The offer code is j Dot r dot e Dot.
So,
uh,
go check it out.
Scale.
Get it looks like a fat ass scam.
Yeah,
it's dope.
Where your drugs on drugs,
but you shouldn't,
shouldn't do drugs.
All right,
top.
See what your stamps.com.
Before you do anything else,
click on the microphone and during jre
and save yourself some catch $110 offer.
See that you get a $55 in postage
coupons.
You get a free digital scale,
which is a $50 value,
$5 supply kits and a four week trial.
So go check it out.
It's an awesome service.
We're also brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com.
I don't know.
That's o n n I t I don't know how many
of the chimp kettlebells are left.
Um,
I know we're almost out of him if we're
not sold out already.
They went flying off the shelves because
they're the coolest fucking pieces of
workout equipment ever.
It's cool just to have it around like
workout equipment.
These just to put on both sides of my
speakers and my living room.
Just wait till we get the other ones
too.
I'm telling you this is this,
this one's my favorite,
but there's other ones that are just as
bad ass.
They're,
they're right up there with it.
It's collecting matt balls.
Is that an adult?
I can't wait to collect all this.
And we had them all done by special
effects artist.
So they're,
they're really like,
it's,
it's not goofy looking.
I mean it looks like a fucking real
angry chimp.
That's the last thing you would ever
want to see if that thing had its face
between your crotch and it was biting
off your Dick and it had that face clap.
That's the.
I just put your duck off face.
I'm angry.
I'm a champ and I bet you degraff the Ed
asner taking a shit.
I think it adds a little more handsome.
I think being cruel and that doesn't
look like his nose at all.
Chimps are fucking terrifying.
Those creepy animals.
Anyway,
on it.com.
If you go there,
we got all kinds of cool shit for
fitness.
It is literally a one stop shop for
functional fitness equipment.
We have kettlebells,
we have.
Excuse me,
we have kettlebells,
we have the primal kettlebells.
We have regular kettlebells and all
sizes.
The primal kettle bells is just the
chimp right now.
We're expanding the line soon.
Of course we have battle ropes.
We have extreme kettlebell cardio
workout DVD,
which is like the best workout DVD you
can ever get when it comes to like
cardio and kettlebells.
It's a brutal,
brutal fucking workout and you can.
You can kill yourself with a 35 pound
Kettlebell if you're interested in doing
any of this stuff.
The one thing that I absolutely always
encouraged people to get a trainer,
go hire some dude over cost 50 bucks or
whatever.
Just make him show you the correct way
to do things,
filming on your iphone,
and then when you do it at home,
take your time,
learn how to do it properly.
Form is very important to keep yourself
from getting injured and don't try to go
too fast either.
It's,
um,
it's really important whenever you,
if you're just starting working out for
the first time to slowly build up,
you can eventually have really hard
workouts.
But if you have hard workouts right
away,
you're just going to break yourself.
You've got to be intelligent.
I know you feel like a pussy if you know
you.
Oh well me,
20 pounds,
trust me,
did better.
It's better to do it slow.
Um,
we have all sorts of supplements that
can aid you in recovery,
including t plus our fantastic new
testosterone supplement that has been
flying off the shelves.
Lots of people with positive response
for that and no,
it's not going to make you failing drug
tests and no,
it's not going to fuck with your balls.
It doesn't,
uh,
the way it works,
it doesn't work in a,
in a way that would introduce artificial
testosterone,
two body system.
It actually encourages your body's
production of testosterone.
See it would bite.
There's certain routes like this stuff
called Long Jack and as we've seen the
PURINA's,
however you say it,
um,
there's,
there's a bunch of different supplements
like magnesium aspartic acid that have
been shown to increase testosterone and
it's not the kind of results you're
going to get with steroids,
but it's also not going to kill your
balls either.
It's a,
it just enhances your body's natural
production of testosterone and decreases
your,
uh,
your estrogen production as well.
So you don't get bitch tits.
I don't want to get no bitch to sun.
Trust me.
What isn't cod liver oil?
What they used to give,
like an old cartoons that it was always
like the grossest are Annie,
but it was good for you.
It was a castor oil to Castro was the
big one.
Yeah.
Well what they didn't,
you know,
people were like,
oh,
that's all bullshit.
No,
it's not that liver cod.
Liver oil.
Fish oil is fucking fantastic for you.
It's really good for you.
It's one of the best things ever.
If you have like sore joint before you
do anything,
and before you know you say,
oh well I got to take Ibuprofen every
day now please try this.
Just go get yourself some fish oil and
take like they're like a thousand
milligrams.
Take five a day.
I know.
That sounds crazy.
I know that sounds like a lot.
I take 10 a day.
How about that?
Yup.
But meanwhile,
my fucking joints don't hurt when you do
like crazy hard workout shit.
Having sore joints,
sore elbow,
so sore knees,
things along those lines is something
that you just sort of accept.
You just deal with it.
I'm telling you one of the greatest
supplements Avar for,
for any sort of inflammation in your
joints,
it's fish oil.
Try it.
You've come,
let's smell so horrible.
My comes delicious.
I here.
I would have no idea.
I would be pissed if I licked my calm
and it didn't taste like anything.
I'd be like,
what's with all the fucking complaints?
Jesus,
could you imagine you're telling me
you've never tasted your.
I'm sure I have one way or another.
I'm sure somehow or another,
you know,
they say that the average human needs
like a pound of bugs over the course of
their own life because you know,
you're,
you know,
whether it's a candy bar or soda,
like there's a minimal amount of bug
tissue and all sorts of manufactured
foods.
So they say you eat like a pound of
bugs.
So I'm sure of all the pussy now have
done.
You know how I do.
I know I probably.
And so in my own calm,
whatever,
whatever.
I'm here to tell a story.
I licked little esther's ipad last night
and it was so like sort of bigger prints
on it and stuff like that.
And so much of her come,
you've probably looked at her shit.
I didn't think of that finger,
but she got a little scratch in there
and it's like,
what do I care?
It's my ipad.
All sorts of food items are also
available on [inaudible] dot com and,
uh,
including supplements like Alpha brain,
shroom tech,
if you want an exercise.
Supplements,
shroom,
Tech Sports,
the one.
All right.
This fucking commercials too long.
Back o n n I t use a codename Brogan.
Save yourself some cash on any and all
supplements you dirty pitches.
The Great William Burr.
The first Sierra.
You the first.
Uh,
I don't know because he dad,
Bill Burr?
No,
you're William Bertha.
First.
William Bertha.
The first.
Ladies and gentlemen,
one of the finest stand up comedians
America has to offer and is here to
visit me.
The Joe Rogan experience podcast all
day.
Powerful bill.
For this one,
it's going to be something where guys
like you,
uh,
especially comics in general,
but comics from Boston,
I will always have a soft spot in my
heart for comics from Boston.
No flying kick today.
Right?
Right.
You're flying kick.
How dare you,
how dare you,
Mr Burke a.
The last time I saw you,
you stopped by to say hi at the Wilbur
show,
man.
That was cool.
You came down and risk your life at the
end of the world was over 24 years.
Well,
yeah.
You understand?
Hope I had to do it.
Then you gave me a shout on it had
already left because my girl came by
with the car.
I had to hustle out there and I felt
like an ass.
No,
no,
no worries man.
It was cool.
It was cool seeing it was fun.
Yeah.
There was uh,
one of the weirdest events that I've
ever done because we don't usually do
like theaters in Hollywood.
If I'm in Hollywood,
I do like the Improv or I usually do.
Pasadena usually worked the ice house,
so to do like the wiltern it was like,
it was one of those big events that all
these agents come down to that you don't
know.
And I remember there was a point during
the show,
like where it had already started and we
were in the green room.
It was you and me and um,
I think stan home was back there too,
like two guys that I knew and then
everybody else I didn't know.
There's all these agents and they're all
eating my
and they sit there,
you know,
picking at the stuff.
Like I actually feel bad because,
you know,
I,
I know my core group of people.
Then there's people that I know that
I've met before,
but it's just like I don't see you.
I see you every couple of years.
So I feel I actually feel bad sometimes.
I don't ever feel bad when they all just
show up in the green room and just have
conversations and like this is so
strange because it was people from all
sorts
of different agencies.
Like the honey honey is bands,
people and all these other.
I just like to go in there and I
couldn't get.
It was ridiculous.
Right.
It was packed.
I wasn't allowed in.
You would,
you didn't have a badge?
No.
Joey isn't it?
You're not allowed to that bro.
Why?
Joey Diaz didn't allow you to come over
here.
Come on.
He's tired of your bullshit.
That's the place I would love to play,
just because I've seen so many,
uh,
I've seen a lot of great bands there and
really good shows.
I only got to see one of the show there
before I saw,
um,
uh,
Robert Schimmel who was doing show back
in the day for Tom Lucas who was doing a
show at the wiltern.
I was like,
wow,
what a cool theater.
But when we decided Stan hope and I
many,
many years ago decided that we were
going to do a show on December 24th
2012.
So if the end of the world really did
end,
like everybody thought it was going to
the Mayan apocalypse,
we would at least be doing a show
together.
Oh,
that's cool.
Yeah.
So when it happened and I was a little
anticlimactic,
just drove home with to sleep.
Meteors,
no aliens,
nothing,
no cooler cookie Lacan or whatever the
fuck his name is.
No Kettle quadel.
Yeah,
I don't,
I don't pay attention in this.
Yeah,
good for you.
I'm not up on the Mayan calendar.
They lost a lot of fucking credibility.
I'll tell you that.
They're like Jimmy,
the Greek [inaudible] 98 or whatever it
was.
When he went down,
Jimmy got fucked.
This guy,
Jimmy got fucked because he told her the
truth.
God dammit.
He told the truth.
He basically was breaking down.
Dude.
It was basically if,
if what happened in Amistad was true,
it was like you boiled it.
Love how strong you had to be physically
and mentally to make it easy.
Just right there.
You got rid of anybody week,
dude.
You don't see any regular African dudes
coming over here playing fullback
running over people that marathon
runners,
skinny guys is kinda like the big ones.
Like the massage.
They're like really thin guys do.
There's certain groups of Armenians,
Russians,
they're just like,
damn.
Like I would never mess with any of
their.
Yeah,
their heart people.
We got a lot of Armenian MMA fighters
part.
They come out of the womb with a shaved
head ready to grapple.
All of them do.
There's a guy down at the car wash where
I go,
he owns the thing and he's Mike 55 slash
60,
but he still solid and he talks about
how it used to grapple and all that and
I laughed.
I go to all you guys know how to grapple
wrestle and he just goes,
yeah,
yeah.
We did Armenians,
Armenians know judo,
a big judo contention as bad as people
talk and proud.
They're real men to men.
I have my friend Armand,
Armand,
the Armenian.
Uh,
he was telling me a story once and he
was dating this girl and she got mouthy
with him and he,
uh,
he grabbed her by the neck and pinned
her up against the wall and he's telling
me this and I go,
I go,
why'd you do that?
He goes,
she's fucking Armenian.
She should know better than to talk to
me like that.
He goes,
it's one thing,
and some white bitch starts talking to
me like that.
And he goes,
this fucking Armenian bitch gets in my
face because he's Armenian.
He's like,
bitch,
you don't know your place.
Like,
you know,
our people.
I was like,
wow,
like that's a fucking hard environment.
You're coming from.
Like he was justifying,
grabbing his girlfriend by the neck and
penny are to the wall because she said
something just didn't
defensive him.
What did she say?
I'm kidding.
Kidding.
What was.
You had a bit about that,
that about fuck.
What was it?
We want to know what a girl said before.
What was he on a bit.
Now you might get some ice cream over
there and just starts throwing punches
or it was there,
so there was some sort of button pushing
I would guess that went on and she
didn't.
She thought it was only going to go
halfway up the building and it went to
the roof.
Yeah,
right away when he was driving to.
Right.
That's like when the dudes go to the
gym,
go to the zoo and they start fucking
with some animal and they think it's a
joke and then all of a sudden I think
reaches through.
You're like,
oh my God,
this is real.
Yeah.
Like when a lady gets too close to the
polar bear thing,
ever see that video?
The polar bear has a hold of her leg
with its teeth,
has trying to pull her through the cage
and she's screaming,
her leg snapped or femur snapped.
You know what's amazing about that is if
people didn't get there in time,
he eventually would have had the power
in his back and his neck to pull that
woman,
right?
Yeah.
It would have chewed her apart.
He woulda Woulda,
woulda got whatever he could get out of
that one piece of leg and then he would
have reached through and pull.
She would have been eating her.
The worst of the best thing that could
happen when a polar bear comes at you is
you're not.
They're not in a cage because at least
it's over quick,
but if they were in a cage and there's
no one around,
you're slowly going to get eaten to
death because it's going to hold you
down.
Which I would stick a fucking artery
right in his mouth.
That one in effect.
Go ahead,
take a champ.
Yeah,
you'd probably be bleed out from the
legs.
The legs are good.
Spot to get bit by a polar bear.
Something you're not gonna last long,
especially inner thigh,
and you don't.
Is this the one of the lady?
Oh Jesus Christ,
this fucking stupid lady,
crazy person decides to get close enough
to a fucking polar bear that I could
reach out and grab a hold of him.
I was thoroughly involved in binkies
enormous choice.
Take off your belt.
Binky.
I nearly $1,000
is 29 year old Cathryn Warburton from
Sydney.
I that looks 50 fucking leg is marble.
There's a video when we played it on the
show anymore.
Pause around her legs and was chewing
on.
Catherine.
Get jumped over to low lying barricades,
hoping to get a closeup photo of banking
in his cage.
Instead,
biggie got the closeout.
He has plunged his canines directly into
Catherine's three d animated fake
version of wider apart than in other
bears.
That extra space allows them to grasp
and tear too.
They can kill a walrus.
Other teams and they only kill.
It's the difference between polar bears
and grizzlies.
They don't eat any vegetables.
There's no plants where they live.
Medical doctor knows there is not much
time left.
Knowing the anatomy of a throw that
camera at the lower extremities.
No,
it's not good enough.
The best thing you could do there
honestly is a either stabbing the eyes
or a grab a belt and wrap it around its
neck and choke and unconscious,
but you'd have to get close enough to
put your arms around its neck and hope
it doesn't let go and snap your arms as
you're doing that.
Two words.
Zoom button.
There's a long time ago.
She probably got a really cheap two
megapixel Jamey.
Yeah.
I would've loved to have seen how quick
that thing close the distance,
like the closing speed of that,
like a cornerback.
I can make up distance with the wide
receiver and the whatever thinks it's
what dudes wide open and all of a sudden
gets picked off.
That's like,
what just happened?
Oh,
what's over there?
It's your leg is in its mouth.
Have you ever seen how fast a bear can
run up a tree?
Oh,
it's sick.
It's insane.
There's this.
There's a video and see if he could find
this.
Well,
you know when a guy or girl,
person,
girl trapped in polar bear cage,
Oh my God,
Jesus Christ just left under the
surface.
Only a rubber ring distracts it from its
on.
Oh my God.
Got So grip strength,
strength to safety.
Oh my God.
Wet Jackass.
Before the woman had been in a bas grip.
Oh my God.
Is that her head?
When the help is try to get out of it by
the trousers and pulled her back.
I was just born with that weapon,
getting little plunger.
But this was far from a game.
Witnesses looked on.
A six keepers distracted the animals
with meat,
with meat.
They got backup,
emergency break glass.
It would if it didn't have any of that.
Got there.
Like Shit.
There's no meat.
Get the frozen meat.
There's a video of a couple guys
hunting.
They're in a hunting blind and they're
sitting there.
They're hunting for bears and this
fucking bear runs up the tree beside
them.
And I mean the guy's like maybe 25 feet
in the air.
The bear is up to him in one second,
and I'm not exaggerating,
it's just they just fucking giant bear
scoots up the tree.
It is what they do.
Fucking terrifying.
The bear didn't do anything.
The guy that guy just wrote.
That's it.
That's fine.
Top One.
What does it say?
SASQUATCH and black bear.
Adrenaline at its best.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
That's exactly it.
We're fucking bear.
Runs up this tree.
Try to find out where it is,
where the bear runs up.
It's fucking ridiculous because the guys
in the stand and it just decides.
It makes us mad.
Sprint up the tree right next to him.
Here it is.
See the guys looking down.
It's like there's the bear right there.
So this fucking bear just goes for this.
Out of nowhere.
Like,
watch this,
watch this.
The bear passed him.
Watch this.
They get a film in the bear.
What is he laughing about?
Well,
he's got a fucking gun.
You know?
I mean,
I think he's probably laughing because
he's terrified to.
Yeah,
I think that's.
I think he's scared shitless and they'll
watch the bears right beside him.
He gets trying to get the camera on it.
It's just chilling there in the tree.
Look how fucking high that thing got in
like a second was like one second,
but you know their claws.
You ever see a guy climate telephone
pole at those sites?
That's what that.
They have those built in like Wolverine.
They just go and write up the trend.
Let's the thing go down.
Then he shoots it with an arrow.
Check this out,
watch Dick.
It's keeping played.
We played was the thing runs down the
things out there.
It's like,
all right,
I'm not going to kill you.
I'll let you go about your way.
It seems like you just sitting in a
tree.
And so the guy was like,
yeah,
look what I got here.
Ooh,
it's a compound bow.
Hm.
So as that bear like,
just got done checking them out from
lunch height.
I mean it was like mouth to face.
It was right there.
He waits for the bear.
Go to go back to the barrel.
By the way,
the bed,
the barrel is filled with food.
They bait these bands.
That's how they.
That's how they hunt.
Bear a lot of bear.
These dogs and other ways they treat
them.
There's a bunch of different looks.
He's going to fucking put one right
record.
They're delicious.
Perfect.
Do you think there's no native American
that would have done that?
First of all,
they wouldn't have been dumb enough to
let it happen.
They would have had some great code
about.
Used to have some ceremony when they
killed a bear because a bear was so much
like a human,
like it's mannerisms and that type of
thing.
Really.
I overheard it in a bar.
There you go.
Could be true.
Could not be true that we were on a
podcast yesterday.
We talked about what you want to get
down from the tree,
so you got to shoot.
I guess that's what it is because what
if it comes back this time and these on
the bottom?
Yeah.
It just runs out of them.
You know what?
Strike that smart move.
Smart move and he's gonna.
He was there for that in the first
place.
I mean,
that's the reason why the bear.
Was there a reason why he was there?
Spare of the bear did bear spirit.
I'm.
I'm really putting literally putting
human traits on disparate stupid.
I think the die in the woods to dumb the
bears is too dumb to figure out shit,
dude.
He's a good guy.
We came up,
he could've shot him.
He didn't get a shuttle down and he goes
over to his caddy and some of the
fucking Arrow.
An Arrow from 20 yards.
Can you imagine somebody shot him with
an Arrow?
Can imagine what it would have been if
he got the right Sheree,
if he did have the right to imagine will
come up and just grab you fucked up.
Close animals come to victory sometimes
and there's just the one little thing.
They just
the dot that chromosome,
they missing that dumb.
That's a.
that's like the fastest I've ever seen a
bear climate tree.
I didn't know they could get up a tree
that fell.
Oh,
you do.
Your best bet is you have to get up so
high that they're nervous that I guess
that the tree is going to break,
but then you're up there.
Well,
it depends on what bear to grizzlies
don't climb trees.
Never been bear hunting.
I don't even know where.
What are you?
What are the words come from?
Sometimes like,
what am I saying?
Shut up.
Got To do is I've watched this on
discovery from an l shaped couch.
Let me tell you what to do now.
A black bear,
black bear.
This is what you got to start breaking
it down.
Bears are more likely to climb trees.
They climb trees all the time.
Grizzlies apparently don't climb trees,
so if you
never.
My plane crashed.
If I've ever used that information,
but you never know the plane crash.
You gotta do what you gotTa do.
Bill due to plaintiff starts going down.
The first thing I'm doing is taking the
seatbelt off.
Really don't want to survive this
covered in jet fuel.
Coming out with my slacks melted to my
legs.
I get start knocking on the fat.
Fuck next to me.
Just kill me ahead.
I had a great one.
I had a great life.
Yeah.
Why not,
right?
Yeah.
Why not sober?
So you were talking about the.
We were talking about the grid,
Jimmy,
the Greek thing about Jimmy,
the Greek for folks who don't know
Jimmy,
the Greek was a famous football.
The commentator would do the odds,
right?
Take the bears laying three.
It was the seventies where you could,
you allowed to talk about betting
gambling?
Yeah.
For the NFL was like,
wait a minute man,
what are we doing it when men were men
and uh,
he had the gall to insinuate that there
might've been some benefit to these
African American people breeding in
slaves and that
he was doing what I just did with bears
and he was having a drink in a
restaurant and somebody filmed it.
It's like one of the original,
like,
you know what it was?
Yeah,
he was,
he's like in a restaurant.
I thought it was an interview.
Now he's,
I believe he's in like,
I don't fucking remember.
He was like in an interview and he's
like eating potato skins and they're
just like,
what happened to all the white running
back?
So he's like,
here's the theory,
you know,
you're in a bar,
somebody asked a question,
you're gonna answer it.
They wanted to get rid of him anyway.
I'm not saying what he said is 100
percent true,
but it's like they wanted to get rid of
him.
They wanted to get rid of that guy
because that was like back then like
you,
you make that video.
Well I guess they could maybe show them
a local newscast,
but there was so many videos.
There was a girl back then called Jane
Kennedy,
gorgeous woman and some sex tape came
out about her and one of the first ones
and it just went around
the industry and she lost her job.
Like if there was no youtube to upload
it to and they were all just like,
this is absolutely.
And then fast forward,
you know,
35,
40 years later,
it's like a career move.
No one ever saw that and liquid Kim
Kardashian move mean like the,
the,
those girls was when they were all in or
it's just not one accident.
Several,
several camera goals.
But she's like that brilliant to be
like,
this is how well wait a minute.
Paris Hilton already done it.
Paris Hilton got famous that way.
So that's how she got them.
She had a famous boyfriend,
she was dating this guy,
Ray j,
but it's usually the famous guy gets all
the press unless you banged somebody
else famous.
Well he got,
he got a lot of press from that.
It's just he couldn't maintain it.
He just,
for whatever reason,
I mean I think he's still like big in
his and b community or whatever kind of
music he plays.
But uh,
you know,
for whatever reason,
I mean,
it's not like he's an unknown.
He's a,
he's still a pretty known guy,
but she became,
whether he's known or unknown,
it's usually like the unknown person
who's getting banged.
It's,
you know,
it's like Joe blow,
fuck Sahar right.
You know,
like you're just,
you know.
But yeah,
or whatever.
But I guess she was so good looking
people wanting to know who she was.
Like the dvr girl.
All of a sudden everyone's like,
who's that girl in the commercial exotic
looking one and then you look it up.
Yeah,
I definitely think that.
But I also think,
no,
I think that she was just fucking rabid
opportunist and it was in the same time
that Paris Hilton really got more famous
because of her sex tape.
And then remember when girls would just
showing their pussies like they would
climb out of cars and not know that the
Paparazzi,
he had a fucking camera and interim or
snatch.
I mean,
how many girls were.
They had those download photos to the
most ridiculous photos ever because it's
so fucking obvious that you've,
you've,
you plan that the camera is below your
pussy.
You're getting out of a car and the
camera's below your pussy looking up at
it.
Fuck yeah,
100 percent guaranteed.
It's all like Paris Hilton.
It was all these real dumb skanks no,
no offense.
But all these,
uh,
these really silly girls,
you know,
it's like those,
those were the girls are fun girls.
They're just,
yeah,
the knucklehead girls.
And that was their move to show their
pussy.
And they were distinct advantage as a
woman.
Like if I got out with a kilt and you
flashed your junk,
like I think that that would hurt you,
you'd probably go to jail.
It's offensive.
No whipping out your cock is way more
offensive than showing of your pussy.
He can climb out of a car and show your
pussy.
No one to tell you they completely
shaved is the creepiest thing I've ever
seen in my life.
It's like I don't want to be.
You look like a woman up here and you
look,
you know,
you don't like that.
Now it's amazing that it's so popular
that porn has made such a massive
success.
Like it's such a massive victory to pay
around.
The pussies kind of made a comeback.
They'll never go back to like full on,
like,
you know,
energy crisis,
pussy hair,
Jimmy Carter Ford.
It's over.
Yeah.
They will go back to that.
But,
you know,
like,
keep it.
Especially because of the asshole hair.
No one's no one's into that.
I heard somebody told me the other day
that crabs is going in,
instinct are extinct because uh,
no one has a pubic hair anymore.
That it's actually.
Oh yeah,
it's like they pour salt in the,
in the,
in the fields.
Yeah,
I mowed them down.
Um,
so the reason why I brought up the Jimmy
[inaudible] thing is,
this is one thing I wanted to talk to
you about that I got in trouble with for
saying that I didn't think that a
transsexual man should be able to fight
women.
There's a,
a man bullshit.
Yeah.
You got a sex change and then didn't
tell anybody.
Did he get it?
Still got the band shell does that looks
just like a man.
Okay,
got it.
Got a sex change sort of fighting women
and beat the fuck out of two chicks
brutally before anybody figured out that
he used to go to jail for that.
That's what I say.
Do you ever see South Park?
They go and they talk about something
called the heat now call it is.
She goes,
it's not a sheet.
It's a mutilated man.
I hate talking about this because
whatever the hell you want to do is what
you want to do.
But like I draw the line where you know,
you got dude's shoulders and manhandled
and you're going to go up there against
Christina.
I mean,
that's,
that's not fair.
There's a long time ago they had that in
tennis and this,
this guy was.
He was killing it.
Renee Richards.
Yeah.
Is that what I just terrible as a man.
Didn't do well at all.
Started playing as a woman,
got a secretary as operation.
It was just dominating.
Just dominate and kicking ass in a way.
Never kicked ass before.
Yeah,
let's not.
It's not,
it's not fair.
Well,
there's a lot of things,
but make it unfair.
It's not just the frame,
it's also spatial awareness.
There's a difference in the genetics is
there's also different in reaction time
of significant difference.
Ten percent difference between men and
women.
Men have a 10 percent faster reaction
time.
It's,
that's pretty much the bumping each
other in the head.
Being the first ones out there with a
spear.
Our bodies are just designed for
different shit.
When we were hunter gatherers,
we were hunters.
You know,
let's just do this wrong with getting a
sex change operation.
Whatever God bless you,
but like to go in the ring with women
and beat the shit out of a woman like
that know,
especially for fighting is one thing,
if you know,
and this is where I'm getting the
stress,
this is where I'm getting a stress from
getting it from,
from feminists and I'm getting it from
people that support a transsexuals
because they want a transgender woman to
be considered a 100 percent woman and
they're like a trans.
This is the argument I've been getting
all online.
You know,
a trans woman is a woman asshole.
A Trans woman is a real woman.
Your bigotry and transphobia.
I'm transphobic apparently because I
don't want men to get their dick chopped
off and beat the shit out of women.
I mean,
you know,
I am 100 percent supportive of anybody
like a hot dog.
And then they make a giant lay.
Sure.
I'm looking at it right now.
They make like a,
they don't,
they,
uh,
I don't know what they do.
They call it a peanut on version,
actually pnl in version.
And then they got to like a,
I don't know how they scoop out your
tank,
just hardcore.
This has got to be some stuff in there
that you're just.
It's like the crawl space under your
house.
You don't know what's on.
Listen,
if someone wants to do that,
God bless you.
If you want to be referred to as a
woman,
I,
I'm,
I'm fine with that.
But like don't get in a ring and start.
You know,
concussion sounded pounding.
Some woman would,
you know,
come on.
Ain't take estrogen pills.
They shot,
they take shots,
but in their muscle mass does decrease
and their,
their,
their bone density does decrease.
It does.
But there's just some massive mechanical
advantage of the male frame.
When it comes to something like combat
sports,
the shape of the hips are different
because no matter all the take them man
can take all the estrogen in the world.
He doesn't really develop a woman's hips
is a completely different structure.
And when it comes to kicking that
structure makes a big difference.
What's that?
Cheesecake sits on the couch.
It's a saddlebag work like Mariah Carey
built.
No,
it doesn't.
It doesn't look like that Bill Clinton
had bitch hips.
Your body looks like he had big,
big mother and hips.
I bet he had a lot of knee problems and
he was jogging.
Oh,
I'm sure he went out the acs fat as
fuck,
right?
Yeah.
What about this?
What about the guy that has down
syndrome that wants to fight?
Yeah.
Well,
blimey.
Well we'll get to that too,
for sure.
But I thought that.
Oh,
the craziest thing about this is that
these women in this desire to be super,
super progressive and super supportive
of gay rights and transgender rights,
that they're willing to allow other
women to get the fuck beat out of them
because it's almost all women that got
upset with me.
There's a few guys like gay guys.
I got upset with me,
but uh,
quite a few women wanted that,
that transgender woman to be recognized
as a woman.
And I said like,
I'm 100 percent supportive of someone
doing that and I'm willing to call them
a girl in a sheet and whatever your name
is,
I'm cool with that.
You know,
I don't mind,
but the fighting men,
the girls,
it's amazing how much resistance I've
gotten from this.
It's fucking.
It's really,
truly amazing.
I mean,
everybody's entitled to an opinion.
Opinion isn't going to stop them from
doing anything like people get,
you know what it is,
it's just that you're kind of known,
you know what I mean in that area.
So it's a good thing for them to hitch
their wagon to where like I've noticed
that a lot of people,
they don't really get offended by
anything that I say.
It's because there's nothing to attach
your wagon to.
I do try to stand up and like strip
malls,
so I jumped on Conan that.
That's usually the punishment end up,
right?
Yeah.
What are you going to.
What I mean and I'm not a doctor either.
Do like if somebody came up like I
actually,
this is what annoys me about groups like
that as I feel that when somebody says
something and you're offended,
it's very easy for them to get in
contact with us.
Fairly easy with twitter,
facebook,
all of that to to hear that makes sure
that they're hearing it right to clarify
what you say and they don't.
They want,
they want to do is create this,
this,
this hysteria,
and then they get you on tv and you're
on the split screen and that split
screen argument is not about finding
some truth.
It's just about winning.
And then they go out there and as you
start to make a good point,
they'll go see that.
See that?
That's just the ignorance.
That night they shout you down and it's
some of the worst tv you'll ever fucking
debate things where you have three
minutes to make your point.
They're the dumbest ways to address a
complex issue than anybody could ever
get her.
That's get came from PTI.
Think on ESPN.
It was a sports show.
These two good friends used to yell at
each other,
not yell,
but they will make great points and it
would get heated sometimes and that do
and they blew up because you know,
it was.
You saw the friendship there and then
they were just like,
oh,
they like
people yell.
They just boil it down and next thing
you know,
everybody's just screaming.
They always do that.
They have like some guy whose kids got
shot a school and then next to another
guy who's like a fucking one of those
militia guys who thinks we should all
have assault rifles and then Pierce
Morgan pretends it's a debate.
They put two pit bulls and it's what
they do and then they just sit back and
think,
oh,
that's going to kill eight minutes.
Well we talked about it on the podcast,
you know,
that's when the discussion happened that
got to the air.
So they had plenty of opportunity to see
what I meant and what I didn't mean,
but they choose to only lock onto like
some of the things that I said like it's
a guy with no dick and you know,
and that's where they got really mad at
you because that's hurtful.
That's transphobic.
But technically it's accurate.
And I understand what you're saying.
Yeah,
it is.
It is a guy who had his penis removed.
Yes it is.
I mean,
chromosome will try to look like he had
female parts,
but here's something weird I found out
when you do chromosome tests,
what are blowing up right now?
A lot of women have the y chromosome
actual,
just women,
real women.
I don't even know.
Not hermaphrodites.
You don't know what it means.
Women are xx mentor x,
y.
The y chromosome is the differentiator
between men and women.
Everyone's born a woman.
Still respect the fact that you told me
that like I'm going to retain that.
I'm not going to come in the next time
when you bring that up.
But while this was going on,
I was thinking of you.
I was thinking man,
is bill burr was in this situation
because you know,
you're just a.
It seems like,
you know,
like with the crips Chris Brown thing,
you're one of the few guys out there
that will go there with a bit like that.
Why?
I want to know what the fuck she said
before he hit her.
You know,
there's a lot of people out there.
No.
My
thing about that was like,
uh,
I might,
I might question it was,
and it was an honest question was do you
have any personal for your
own safety as a woman to not
deliberately sit there and push
somebody's button and get in their
grill,
you know,
and get physical and hit and do all
that.
It gets to a point of like,
my thing was like respect the fact that
a guy's going to hit you,
don't take advantage of it.
And it's like,
um,
you know,
like I,
I don't know if that's right or wrong,
but it was a question that these groups,
you can't talk to them.
You just want to ask them like,
do you feel like,
you know,
like if you just go,
well that's why your mom's Dad,
man,
I hope you get fucking cancer too.
And,
and,
and just say this horrible,
hurtful shit.
Start pushing somebody.
And it's like,
at what point are you guilty of,
of provoking the next level?
If a woman got in your face and you were
like,
seriously worried that she was going to
hit you and you really felt like you had
to defend yourself,
would you hit her?
No.
Well,
I would.
I would have.
She would have to have a fucking machete
really.
And like,
no,
I.
It would have to be like,
I will be doing that stuff just running
around the walls.
I get
cardio.
Right where you usually have better
cardio the man when it comes to the
jargon,
when it comes to the ones who jog a lot
of,
especially the ones that hit you that
more likely to have pent up frustrations
and getting out with the exercise?
No,
I dated a girl one time.
She,
she had some issues about when she would
get mad she would get physical and I had
to talk to her about it.
That saying that you've got to
understand that the natural reaction to
this is this.
You can't just walk around hitting feet.
That's so disrespectful and it's
childish and it need to grow up.
Like I had to have that conversation
because,
you know,
it's,
it's in that split second when somebody
blast you in the face,
either man or a woman,
it's like you go into self defense,
what you eat,
you might even just out of reaction go
like that.
And you know,
a lot of times guys are so much bigger
than women.
That's a forum.
Then their nose is bleeding and then
you're down the fucking police station.
Yeah.
And then you have like a problem.
So,
um,
my thing and all those,
what is,
you never learn anything you never
learned.
Like was this guy just a bad guy and
this was inevitable and what happened in
his childhood?
Can we deconstruct this guy
psychologically?
Can we go back and figure out what led
to this event?
Or was it like he has no track record of
this and then all of a sudden it just
the right set of circumstances and it's
like,
is this guy a bad guy?
Is this guy I'm unlucky guy?
Like,
like,
what happened?
But I got it.
I got to tell you.
It's like,
you know,
the first punch you flipped out.
I mean once you fucking,
you know,
I think we set up the jab throwing
combinations.
It's like at some point you got to be in
your head like I am hitting a woman,
but the conversation fascinates me and
it's such a touchy subject.
What's annoying is that you can't like
the amount of people who are listening
right now,
but that scowl on her face,
like you can't even,
you can't unless you just go,
you are 100 percent right.
There was no reason to ever do it and
you don't have to respect another being
on any level and you can throw stuff at
them and you can say stuff.
You can,
you know,
push their buttons and do everything you
basically can to get it to that point
and,
and then.
But,
but you're not,
you're not guilty.
You don't have any responsibility.
There's nothing that you could do in the
future to be like,
well,
hey,
next time you know,
it's relationships over the over,
but the next time I'm with a guy,
you know,
maybe I only ramp them up a couple of
floors as opposed to just like,
dude,
you know that they know what to say.
They know what to say,
and I do.
You know what I mean?
Fucking walls.
You know how many lamps you just like,
oh,
like they just know they do.
They.
Well,
this is what you're going to do it.
I can give you the best advice ever.
Cut them off,
cut anybody like that off.
I've had people like that in my life to
try to get in fights with me.
I've had people like that.
The one arguing all the time,
you cut them off.
Even if they're hot,
even if they give good head,
even if they got a great ass,
you got,
you got to get rid of them.
Charlie Murphy gave me the best advice
was just yo,
he goes,
woman ever comes at you.
He goes,
you immediately lock yourself in the
bathroom.
He goes and then call the police.
That's good advice.
Yeah.
Just lock yourself in.
He goes,
you don't have any strike marks because
they can,
you know,
he was talking about it,
somebody was gonna,
you know.
I don't know.
That's a good move.
Okay.
On the swim from.
No.
Well,
it's controversy and you know,
hitting women.
I've never hit a woman ever,
but obviously,
but I could never.
I could never do it,
but I would.
If a woman was attacking me,
I would knock on conscious.
There's no doubt about it.
I mean if a woman was coming in with a
knife trying to hit me with a ball one
or window haymaker right to the chops,
going to take them out,
take them out,
stop playing games.
If you're going to hit a check,
you've got to blast him right in the
face.
Most chicks are just not prepared for
that.
I'm not prepared for that either.
Nobody is,
but I would only do it to save my life
or you know,
my safety.
But you know,
you never know man.
I've seen fucking checks that can punch
really hard.
My friend Tommy,
my friend Tommy junior has a girlfriend
that works out all the time and we took
her to one of those fucking things at
the,
you know,
one of those,
a video game.
Things were the bag pops out and you hit
it and praying and you see what she
fucking hits hard.
I was looking at like,
if this girl's soccer punch me,
I'm going to wake up with a flashlight
in my face.
No
you don't.
You know what?
I don't,
I don't like,
uh,
I don't like watching when the women
fight each other and fighting.
Really.
I don't,
I don't like it.
You know what they should do?
They should have them fight like
convicted rapist and the rapist don't
know that the fight is going to happen.
So then I got to shape eating prison
food.
Just come out there and then you have to
be rapist in the right weight class and
they just get in.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
You can work all the details and they
just beat the living shit out of still a
man.
But to sit there,
well just sit there and uh,
I like to sit there and watch to women
like they don't want to hate a.
When they punch each other and they hit
that Teddy's
sacred.
If I run a rosy and Liz Carmouche,
Ronda Rousey got kicked in the tits,
shout out just before she,
uh,
got back to it.
I'll tell you,
you know,
and you know,
they have a name for that within their
circle.
What that feeling is kick to kick to the
tits.
They got to have some sort of slang for
it where um,
you know,
it'd be funny,
but I would never want to take the ass
kicking was,
is how bad those girls could beat me.
Somebody.
Somebody like,
like three weight classes below me.
Well Rhonda Rousey would be a good one
on me because she's a grappler.
She'd just getting you in an arm bar.
Training is for brothers,
headlock,
dual head
throwing.
Keep it from here to here.
So Dad doesn't get mad it from Chin,
Chin to belt.
Yet if somebody starts winning,
always punched in the hair the.
So the lump lump wouldn't show up,
you know,
it's funny,
we were learning basically how to beat a
woman,
so I didn't really look at it,
but we would do it to each other.
But um,
I think that.
But I really think that like it would,
it'd be great if somehow you could teach
women that because of all these dirt
bags and these guys who do hit women,
if you were to teach them that so they
could have that,
uh,
to be able to defend themselves.
Yeah.
Almost always the best option because
you have your legs,
you know,
a woman's legs,
you think about it can carry you and you
know,
you weigh 130 pounds or whatever your
weight.
They're fucking carrying you around all
day.
You can't do that with your arms.
So you could lock them man up in a
triangle or an arm bar and fuck them up.
You know,
he really,
a woman like Rhonda Rousey could break
my arm easily.
She got me in an arm bar for sure.
She could break my arm.
You know,
there's,
I don't know why they send those kinds
of people to jail,
like rapist to study should just shoot
him in the street like a rabid dog.
That's how I feel.
I was.
You do any of that that sent you over?
We had a guy,
we.
There was a video of some guy who's a
shooter,
a school shooter.
He was taunting the family of the
victims and I was like,
the only reason he's doing this because
he's in a court and because he knows
there's laws and things are protecting
them.
They should beat that guy to death
in the family that's got to sit there
and take that.
Yeah.
Who played by the rules.
It's just like you'll never forget him
taunting you and just like the fact that
he's like still alive.
There's certain rather holidays,
he gets a decent meal.
Yeah.
There's aspects of it
law that,
uh,
that there's aspects to all human
behavior where we have like workplace
rules,
like you have to behave here,
you have courtroom rules where you have
to behave like this and that allows
people to get away with some fucking
ridiculous shit like that.
No,
you're supposed to act civilized to
someone who isn't civilized and I get
that to a certain point,
but it's just like you're not going to
cure what somebody is attracted to it.
So if someone is attracted to kids,
it's like they have to be removed.
Yeah.
There's no way you can
cure that.
Ruins a kid's life.
Yeah.
The recidivism rate years like
generations and generations.
Gee,
this is really heavy topics,
but it's weird how like the,
that,
that thing is like,
what,
what's missing is like common sense,
you know,
and the same can be applied to stand up
comedy.
Like when Tracy Morgan got in trouble
for joking around about a son saying
that he was established son who's gay.
Right.
We all knew it was a joke.
We know.
It was just saying he's being Tracy
Morgan.
He's been fucking completely out of
bounds.
Continues in that direction.
That's his.
His whole act is being outrageous like
that,
but you know,
like common sense goes,
oh,
is he a comedian?
Is he telling a joke though?
That's just,
that's all it is.
You know,
it might not be good.
You might say,
well,
I think he sucks.
That's fine.
You're allowed.
I mean there's a broad spectrum of what
people like and don't like joking about
certain subjects as if it bombs.
Yeah.
Then,
but if it kills every this,
that there's always that legendary line
to the one comic said,
you're fucking trying to get out to your
friends at a diner because you're still
laughing because it was so ridiculous.
I always use Brian Holzman's.
Susan Smith,
one.
Susan Smith was a chicken tender.
Kid's this motherfucker got on the
comedy store stage a couple of days
later and he goes,
I heard those kids were bad kids and
heard.
They sat that close to the TV.
They didn't pull it away.
Their blocks.
They always spilt the milk.
Those kids will not be missed.
And we were just going,
oh no.
Too soon,
and he's,
he's just so great.
I don't want to name the comic because I
never
talk to them to confirm it,
but there was a plane crash and I don't
know,
like North Dakota or South Dakota or
something like that someplace and he
goes on stage like within the year and
it's making fun of it and some guy in
the crowd just stands up and he's like,
my wife was on that flight without
missing a beat.
He goes,
great,
let's dig her up and fucker.
I was just like,
wow.
And if you're not a stand up comic,
you don't understand that because that's
like literally he had to go to that
level to win because if he went,
because if you went like,
oh my God,
I'm sorry.
She always over.
Hey,
what's up with popsicles?
You got it.
Gets too late,
man.
Turn your key on your key sir.
We went nuclear.
Yeah,
that's what it is.
They both had a turn to keep the same
time and activate the button.
Yeah.
Ooh,
fuck.
Holy Shit.
Well,
you know what?
Fuck that guy for standing up and saying
that he's at a comedy show,
you know,
I understand that you might think it's
offensive comments within the year if
you're going in,
you know,
I mean,
Jesus Christ,
I wouldn't go in,
but I support your right to go in.
Just like Johnny Cash didn't really
shoot a man in Reno just to watch them
die.
It's fucking entertainment.
He's,
he's,
he's painting a story and a guy like
Brian Holtzman isn't really happy that
kill white for the guy who actually
got shot and Reno was not in the crowd
anyway.
Yeah,
exactly.
Well that's true.
Yeah.
It wasn't a real event that he was
shitting on,
but that's part,
that's a style of comedy that's like,
I love that style.
Like auto and George will do that.
Dice clay was due that date.
They're over the top.
Absolutely ridiculous.
And there's something really funny about
that.
I love it
and I'm not backing down and I'm going
to say the most ridiculous outrageous
and it is.
It's a form of comedy.
You might not like it,
but to sit there and then act like this
guy really wants to go do it,
and it really meant it sounds
ridiculous,
but if you take that quote and then all
of a sudden you put it on a new show.
I mean,
just the,
the context of it.
It's insane.
There's just like,
we're just taking this one line from an
hour load performance at a comedy club
in a different state.
I,
you know,
it's so funny that when there was that
sort of rash of those videos,
the amount of times that people told the
joke and it killed in the club and then
they would be like controversy at the
laugh factory and then they cut to
somebody and they tell the joke and you
hear it like it's like 99 percent of
people laughed and one person gets
offended.
It's like there's no contract.
Exactly.
It's a good joke.
Yeah.
And,
but it's an opportunity for all these
white knights to jump in and pretend
they're offended and pretend that you
know,
to try to get feminine Brownie points
and step in and try to,
you know,
mark some notches on their side.
Just show up if they ever asked you to
go on TV for what?
If they were just like Joe Rogan,
this stuff you said are most likely no
take crawlspace comment,
why don't you go on the Internet and on
TV and defend?
Because they would,
they would have control over it.
But I would have him come on the podcast
if I felt like someone had a rational
point and they were like,
worth debating,
you know,
maybe in especially if I was exploring
whether or not it was wrong.
I mean I thought I might do it
and I would go on there and the whole
time that person was yelling,
I would just be hyping my dates.
Rutherford,
New Jersey.
We're Jacksonville,
haven't had a piece of paper just
pointing.
It would be the greatest thing.
Like I completely don't pick up a
calendar,
a large calendar,
roll it out.
This is the bill burke calender.
Look around,
see if I'm going to be coming to your
town billboard.com.
That is a good way to handle it because
it is a fucking joke.
I mean you're,
you're operating within these five
minute clips.
You're going back and forth.
A good solid point takes a few minutes
to really establish and to give you a
point of view on a controversial topic,
you really have to cover a lot of
different areas and that's not what
they're trying to do.
They just want you to yell at you,
trying to get you to yell at each other.
That would be the move.
The move would be to do that.
Just start yelling at billboard,
going
your dates.
You just completely ignore them.
I'm getting good at that.
I,
I had a,
had an incident,
uh,
on,
on the airplane going to Indianapolis
with this,
this guy like I don't,
I just,
I just started like interrogating me.
He thought I was some sort of flight
risk about what?
I don't know.
He was on something.
I don't know what happened.
Like I was sitting down.
So He's just a passenger?
Yeah,
and I was,
I didn't know if he was a sky marshal,
but he ordered a doers in the beginning
and he just slammed it.
So I'm like,
this guy's not a scar.
My Sky Marshal,
this guy's boozing it up.
So he just goes to me.
He's like a,
which is sitting there and he just says
I.
He goes,
hey,
you are you afraid to fly?
And I'm like,
what?
He goes,
are you afraid of flag?
Oh No,
I'm not afraid to fly.
And he goes,
you sure?
Because you know it's okay,
you can tell me if you are immediately.
I'm looking at this guy,
what do you mean?
It's like,
okay,
what is this like interrogation,
one-on-one,
build a relationship with your subject
thing that you're doing here.
And I was just like,
no.
He goes,
dude.
ah,
because you know,
you just kind of fidgeting and looking
around.
I was like,
Nah man.
I go,
I'm cool.
He's like,
oh,
you'd like to fly.
I'm like,
when I'm up here,
because you don't have bumped myself up
and go on back there.
I don't like it.
And then he goes,
he's all right,
you know,
but you know,
you,
you can tell me if you're afraid to fly.
So now I'm just like,
dude,
I'm not afraid to fly.
So.
And he's staring at me and I put my hand
like this to show that it wasn't shaken.
I go,
I'm not nervous.
All right,
thanks for asking.
And then he goes,
well,
anybody can do that.
And I'm just like,
oh Jesus Christ.
And I just said,
look dude,
I'm drinking water.
You're drinking doors.
Okay.
And he goes,
that wasn't doers right now I'm just
like,
I fucked this guy.
So I'm sitting there.
You saw a mortar it.
Huh?
You saw him order doers.
I was senator.
He said,
let me get a doors.
And she brought it over neat.
And he threw it back like he was
drinking baby.
Okay.
What's impressive is this guy's old
school starting off.
Good.
Right?
So then there's like five minutes of
silence,
more passengers getting on,
and then the guy goes,
hey,
I'm sorry man,
I just,
I just got off on the wrong foot there.
Right?
He goes,
my name's so and so,
what's your name?
Asked me like,
what my name is,
and I was thinking of saying something
like,
Steve,
you know,
and uh,
or some I wish I wish I said some silly
name,
you know,
but I didn't think of one.
I just went,
it's bill and he goes out.
He goes out,
why?
Why are you going to Indianapolis Bill?
He started doing the shit and I just
looked at the guy and I go.
I'm like,
yeah,
I don't have to answer your questions.
Whoa,
I don't.
He has no fucking authority.
You're not a sky marshal.
You're drinking booze,
you're an asshole.
What are you on?
Are you afraid to fly?
Go Fuck Yourself.
Leave me alone.
Right?
So then he goes like,
all right,
now,
now I am concerned.
I am concerned.
Okay,
why are you going to Indianapolis?
Bill Wright says this,
right?
And they closed the doors and that
they're doing all this stuff and I just,
I just start,
like I joked to my podcast,
I just started smoking like Ryan
Gosling.
He does that little Mona Lisa smile.
We just kind of smile and I'm just
sitting there shaking my head at the
guy,
right,
and I'm literally taking out my eye
pillow.
I wear like a mask just to say I'm so
not worried about anything that you're
going to fucking do all this passive
aggressive shit this to Piss this guy
off and he's got why are you going to
Indianapolis Belt?
And I just kept.
I didn't say anything to him.
I just kept laughing,
just kept shaking my head and um,
was taxiing down and he goes through
because he goes,
I fucking do for a fucking living
such fff and all this stuff.
The lady in front turns around,
starts looking at what?
Taxing down the thing because you don't
answer my questions right now.
I'm going to hit that call button.
I will hit that call button.
I will stop this plane and you will be
fucking arrested like saying all this
stuff.
And I'm just looking at him smiling,
shaking my head.
Like go ahead and push it down.
Let's see what the fuck.
This goes.
Hilarious.
What happens.
Does the pilot come out?
There's a police car pull up to the
play,
no fucking clue.
So he goes to push it and you can't find
it.
It was kind of a weird place and he
finally finds it and he hit the button.
I'm like,
Oh fuck.
He hit the button.
This is hilarious,
and I'm just sitting there.
He goes,
now you wait,
you fucking wait,
blah,
blah.
And I'm just sitting there smiling,
shaking my head at him.
I'm like,
dude,
I don't care.
I don't get.
You're not,
you have no fucking authority.
You're not gonna hit me.
You're not going to do anything.
You're on fucking something,
but I'm not getting that dude.
If that guy had a vibe,
like he was gonna Punch me,
I would have been up in the,
in the ass,
but he didn't.
He just had that.
It was like a kid throwing a temper
tantrum.
He wanted like this.
He almost seemed like he wanted to be an
army ranger,
but he didn't quite make it or what did
he look like?
He was like,
uh,
why reducing good shape,
you know?
Why are we doing like that dude who shot
trayvon Martin kid who wasn't really a
cop,
but he wanted to be a cop,
so he took it to the next level when I
could have squashed the whole thing and
just been like,
look,
I'm a comedian.
I'm going to Indianapolis.
If you'd like to come out to the show,
I could've done that,
but I'm a dick and I hate.
I hate fucking.
I hate authority and this guy doesn't
have any,
so fuck him.
So I just laughed.
Now he pushes the button,
so then the stewardess comes over and
she goes,
yeah,
what's the problem?
He goes to sky is a flight risk.
I am not comfortable flying with him,
but Baba Baba Baba and all this shit.
I was surprised how few people were
looking around.
People just kind of sitting there and
sky was wigging out and I'm just sitting
there and then the stewardess was like,
all right,
did anybody else see any behavior?
And The lady was sitting in front of
him,
pointed at him and said,
yeah,
he was breeding any point and she
pointed me.
He was berating him and I'm just like,
perfect.
So I'm literally putting my fucking ims
down as I'm talking to him going,
hey,
I'm just a guy trying to go to
Indianapolis.
This guy's drinking doers and he's
dropping the f bomb and I'm thinking,
fuck.
I said,
bomb,
you know,
it's kind of a problem with it wasn't a
problem and this guy is just doing this
thing where he wants to win.
He wants some sort of recognition of
what?
Whatever the fuck he thinks he is still
moving.
No,
at this point,
if fucking stopped it pulled over.
I forgot that part.
It pulled over and stopped.
Dude,
it's a fucking red eye.
Okay.
It stops.
Another stewardess comes over and he
goes,
what's the problem?
And he goes through the whole fucking
thing and it's like basically the
captain at this point is going,
do I really have to come back there?
It's like really the red eye fucking
flight.
My last flight of the day I used to fly
combat missions,
you know,
fucking boring.
This is to fly this fucking bus.
I don't want to deal with this bullshit.
So I really have to come back there.
And then they finally asked him,
I said,
hey,
are you going to be comfortable flying
with this guy?
And He,
uh,
I think they acknowledged that he had
some sort of something there because,
you know what?
No,
it's okay.
It's gonna be okay for whatever.
Right?
So they had some sort of something like
some sort of that like they checked with
him,
like,
you're going to stand down sir,
like whatever fucking spy he thought he
was.
So now we get back in line and what
taxing.
And as we're going down the runway,
I got my eye on and I'm just sitting
there and he's yapping in my ear,
you could think this is fucking over.
You think this is fucking over at this
point.
I'm laughing,
I'm holding my stomach in a fucking
laughing and it's driving them nuts and
I'm having a fucking ball with this guy.
And he goes,
uh,
you know,
my dad's,
the CEO is some fucking company in
Indianapolis.
And he starts saying that he's going to
have any fucking arrested when I land.
And uh,
and he starts describing the view I was
going to see from the jail,
like some law and order episode.
Did you get a picture of this kind of
take a photo now?
How could you not have been filming
video this whole entire time?
That would be amazing.
You can,
can't you just be in the moment and not
turn into a film crew?
Just because that was the universe gave
me this fucking moment.
I'm telling this story.
I don't,
I don't know.
So he fucking uh,
so then I got my thanks.
And then he finally,
he's,
yeah,
he's gone.
Yeah.
He,
Oh,
you're going to love the view from the
jail.
You can see Lucas oil field and blah
blah,
blah blah.
And all this shit.
And then he finally oil.
That's where the colts play
this view.
It was such,
such hacky interrogation.
Then he finally said a.
He goes,
you know what?
I'm glad I'm glad.
You know what?
I fucking hope you do something.
We're up there and I'm fucking burst.
It was sitting there with a blindfold on
laughing at him.
It was driving him fucking nuts.
It was great.
So then five minutes of silence,
10 minutes of silence goes by and I'm
finally thinking that maybe this shit's
over or is he just sitting there staring
at the side of my head and then all of a
sudden I just hear it right as I'm
starting to nod off.
I just here,
why are you going to Indianapolis,
Bill?
I just laugh.
So do my adrenaline was going.
I was just like,
wow,
they're going to stop the plane.
This is fucking intense,
man.
It's just crazy what's going to happen
and I'm totally innocent so I got to
kind of watch it happen.
So then I couldn't sleep so I was
sitting there with that stupid mask on
for like a half an hour and then finally
just like,
fuck it,
I gotta take it off and I got to deal
with this guy and I take it off and I
look over and he's just teach this
passed out head hanging.
This fucking special ops guy really
passed out.
You should fucking way Liam with a huge
haymaker right in the face.
And then immediately pretend you're
asleep.
No,
no,
because someone would,
someone would have seen that.
So No,
you know,
what I did was I immediately started
pounding waters because I didn't have to
go the bathroom and I wanted to get up
on the plane just to see if he was going
to fucking wig out again.
Make them so.
So you've made yourself go to the
bathroom,
you would have water and you have to go
to full of fucking bathroom,
like you can't believe in.
This fucking guy's passed out.
He's now.
I held it for the last hour.
He didn't wake up,
wake up until we landed and then we
pulled up to the terminal and I got out
and I stood up and he wouldn't look at
me and I'm thinking he probably slept it
off and I was feeling fucking weird
hopefully.
And The lady in front of me got up and
she just goes.
She smiled and she said,
hey.
And I just said,
ah,
that was,
that was an interesting one.
And then he had the pillow like this
Joe.
He edit behind air in some weird
position in,
in some sort of like Alpha male way.
He tried to get some sort of tough
thing.
The last word,
he took the pillow up and he threw it
down behind it between his legs and he
like grunted.
He went like,
like he threw a pillow down.
That was it.
That was my trip to Indianapolis.
Oh.
And then I worked at a theater and Elmo
was,
there was in the big room.
Elmo and friends from sesame street
before mom got busted and.
No,
no,
no.
This is just the other day.
This is my past weekend.
Will,
you know the dude who played elmo did a
bunch of gay shit with kids.
Allegedly.
Yeah.
You can't say that,
right?
Yeah.
Um,
so what,
this is a different elmo.
No,
no,
no.
This was,
this was burt and the count.
We're backstage.
I had to walk by him and that just like
chilling,
like the counts just sitting there.
I put this video up and they made me
take it down because I had unauthorized
video of them.
But like I'm standing there and I'm
filming and I'm like,
Holy Shit,
there's what's going on.
Burton,
I think burt's waving to me and he's
really waving off like no pictures and
just do it in the burke costume.
Comes walking up and is trying to slam
the door in my face.
But the peg thing is there.
It's a lot.
I thought it was a cute video and it
kind of went with this character.
He's a Dick on the show.
It totally made sense.
But they made me.
They made me take this thing down.
Why would they make you take it down?
I don't know if I'm legally allowed to
show you.
I can show you this,
right?
We can.
You can show it in.
Our lawyers were support you.
How about hey go watch when he weighs.
No visitors going to slam the door on
me.
Don't you got to see this big stupid
head.
I can't believe they took that down.
I think it is.
I get it is because what had happened
and then.
And then also like if,
uh,
you know,
I guess if kids are still like three
years old and somebody takes off the
bird head or like the big bird costume,
they just see it hanging in the corner,
like it really fucks with them.
So I get it.
I took it down.
They asked you to take it down.
Yeah.
The lady,
the lady who runs the tour,
she,
she knew I got video and I think uh,
I may find it on the podcast.
Like they,
she,
she did a job,
she's,
she's on point.
I had that thing up like 20 minutes and
they were just like,
yeah,
take it down,
take it down.
And I was like,
all right.
All right.
I don't think you have to take it down.
The way I look at the way I would
legally argue it was legally had the
right to be there.
You left the door open.
I did not walk into the backstage area.
I filmed in.
That was somebody dropped the ball by
having that door open.
So they were at the same theater that
you were they.
They were in the bigger.
Elmo was playing the big room and it's
the smaller room upstairs.
What is an indy?
Indianapolis.
This is there.
This is after that.
Do that.
Psycho.
The cycle on the plane.
This is this whole.
This is this past weekend.
This whole transition.
Past weekend.
Yeah.
What do you do?
You were you doing it?
Gypsum theater.
Beautiful place.
Never done it.
I'm doing the Morat.
You ever heard of that?
No,
I've never done standup in Indianapolis.
Crate crate and a phenomenal time.
I just did Nashville.
You ever do xannies like a zillion
times?
Fucking love that.
Oh,
I saw your tweet.
Whether it's the Museum of pictures that
you can get some comedians like,
oh my God,
that's a ridiculous.
I took a picture of one of my buddy.
I mean this thing had to be for my 84
and he had that.
Oh boy,
I'm gonna.
Make it that.
Look on his face.
He know that that wide.
I.
I've never been fucked before.
And I'm not gonna.
I'm not gonna name names.
I don't name names because then what's
going to happen is people are going to
go there because they got to take the
picture.
They're going to tweet it to the guy and
I'm going to.
But there's nothing wrong with that
either.
Joe.
I'm a true friend of the guy.
I don't do that.
You can't even throw him right under the
bus.
Blowing rocks has really reminded me of
land of the lost for you.
Those are a Himalayan rock salt.
I knew that.
I know you did.
Of course she died.
I just wanted to remind you,
you put it in there and uh,
that salt,
it just like goes into your pores.
The,
uh,
the headshot.
You don't,
you don't crave bacon anymore.
No,
it's done.
It cured me of everything.
No more masturbating in the middle of
the night.
It's awesome.
The,
um,
the headshot wall in Nashville,
one of the guys on the wall was a,
well,
there's a bunch of them that are dead
now.
It's weird.
Like tennis Wolfsburg was a beast.
Richard.
Jenny paintings on the wall.
He is one of my all time greats.
Fire to pick like a 10,
top 10 all time and he was on that
Carlin road to where he was putting up
like putting them out like boom,
boom,
like an hour,
another hour.
But unlike Carlin,
he was upset.
He didn't want to do that.
He wanted to be like Jim Carrey,
you know,
he wanted to be a movie star and he
wanted to be Seinfeld.
He wanted to have his own show or
something,
something along those lines.
And it just didn't click for him.
Yeah,
he would,
uh,
he would always be bummed out when he
was on the road.
I would always hear stories from people
that worked in clubs with them and it
was just unhappy.
Didn't want to be on the road.
Me and one other guy was brilliant.
No,
sorry,
I was gonna say like you can get away
with shit.
It's Kinda good to not have a TV show
once you start selling tickets.
And it's like,
I played hockey yesterday at like three
in the afternoon.
Yeah.
He never gonna get any fresher than
that.
And you're going to get a show,
but it's not your show.
It's this show.
I compare it to like when your parents,
when you were a kid and they gave you a
bicycle,
you know what I mean?
It's like they gave the bicycle bicycle,
but when you screw up,
they take the book,
you get grounded and they take the bike
away.
So it's not really yours.
Even if it's your name on it,
you know,
you're not an adult.
Yeah.
Like you,
you're going into like the matrix.
So I would have like a real sort of a
funny that I've had in this business
that I have that information now and I
don't know what to do with it because
it's not like I'm going to start my own
network.
Like I don't know what,
you don't have to do anything other than
what you're doing.
You're a great standup comedian.
That's the thing.
Being a standup comic allows you to say
whatever the fuck you want.
Like you were saying,
nobody gets on your case if you say
something fucked up because they're not
connecting you to a show.
But I'd say,
Oh,
bill borough of Fox News said this,
you know,
it's just bill burke comedian
advantages.
Yeah.
To right where I am.
So I'm Kinda like,
you know,
I don't know.
It's,
do you get pressure from agents or
something to do other things or is it
something you.
I want a nice run and doing some movies
and I did a couple of TV shows and it's
great.
But I like doing the movies because I
can see the light at the end of the
tunnel.
Right?
Like it's like,
okay,
we have you for three to six weeks or
whatever.
And it's like,
okay,
and you know,
I'm just gonna do this,
I'm going to hammer this out,
I'm going to know all my lines.
I'm going to,
I'm going to be on time and be a
professional.
And once I get through this then I'm
going to uh,
you know,
on the weekends,
I'll go out to like flappers in Burbank
to stay sharp.
And then once that's over a I go back
out on the road and I get going again.
But like the whole,
the idea of being on a TV show and
playing the same guy for potentially
five years is overwhelming to me.
It's scary.
Yeah.
It's overwhelming.
And I like,
especially like those people who do like
one camera shows like how hard they
work.
Like they,
they're doing like,
it's like a 12,
13 hour days if you know.
Hey,
how's it going?
Oh,
it's great.
Cut back to one great cut.
Alright.
You know this time do it with hey,
no.
Hey,
how's it going?
And then cut.
Okay.
With turning it around,
we got to do the master and all that.
Like they,
they work harder than I've ever worked
in my career.
Like standup is in real time.
You go on at eight,
do an hour and it's done in an hour.
You shoot an hour of TV,
one camera and it's like you're going to
be like those people that I have such a
tremendous respect for how hard people
work on those things.
And I don't think I have
ethical single camera shows what you're
talking.
A lot of folks don't know the terms of
the business.
So like law and order or most dramas,
sitcoms with the is they'll fit little
use many cameras in front of a live
audience and that's,
even though that's hard in the
beginning,
once they get rolling then it becomes
pretty easy.
Like when you did news radio,
how soon before you guys were like,
okay,
we don't get to come in Monday.
Did you ever get to that point?
Yeah,
we got to the point where sometimes we
didn't come in Tuesday,
they come in Monday or Tuesday.
We do a whole show in three days because
they would have a problem with like the
script.
So it would be wrong with the script.
Like we would have script changes like
the day of like many crazy script
changes.
Those were the days man.
Like if I,
you know,
I,
I wish that those things would come back
because that will really.
That's the dream to comes acting gig.
Yeah.
Oh it's the greatest acting Gig of all
time.
But quite honestly when I did it,
I really appreciated Standup,
you know?
And when it was over I was happy it was
over.
I mean,
it wasn't happy because I love those
people that I worked with and it was a
great show,
but I wanted to do stand up,
you know,
and the same thing,
fear factor,
much clear.
Like news radio was way more fun and
satisfying to do,
but same thing,
but it's over.
I'm like,
stand up.
It's just the best.
And then now stand up at podcasting
together.
Are you going to be happier than that?
I would use even the UFC,
which is a great
gig.
I love the UFC,
but if anything ever came up with the
UFC,
said,
hey,
you have to choose between one or the
other.
I'd be like,
you guys take care,
you know,
and kind of.
I had a good time.
Yeah.
I had to bet on yourself.
Yeah,
that's the game.
Well,
not only that,
they pull it out like a paranoid guy,
but they fucking pull you in.
Do you know what it's like?
I met when I would,
when I first came to New York City or
are they would be guys who just worked
one club.
It's like,
why would you ever do that?
Now all you need is one falling out and
you have no spots.
It's got a,
you got to be playing the field so they
can't,
they can't get you under their thumb.
Yes.
That's very important.
Well,
that's what I would the comedy store
when I was living in la or when I was
working on all the time.
I did the comedy store every week and I
didn't do anything else.
I very rarely did anything else.
Like sometimes I did.
Thanks buddy.
Sometimes I did the uh,
the Improv,
like for New Year's or something like
that,
but almost every weekend I was at the
store and then when I had that falling
out with the store I was like,
what am I doing?
Like why,
why would I allow them to have any power
over where I work or don't work?
Like fuck.
Yeah,
I think that's a good mentality.
And so sometimes it can hurt you though.
Tim Allen stopped doing stand up when he
was doing home improvement because he
had that like real.
You've got to,
you know,
for the time a fairly blue act.
And he was doing this super family show
who it was,
you know,
ABC.
I think he was that blue.
I thought he was not blue,
but potentially controversial.
Yeah.
No.
Well look,
that guy like that in me talking about a
guy who,
whose career started right after he got
out of jail.
I mean guys just like,
listen,
I've paid my dues.
Like I don't begrudge any of those guys
who,
who gets to the point where they just
say,
I just don't want to go on the road
anymore.
I'm happy with the show.
And you know,
writing on a show like I,
I totally get that.
Like if it's all,
you know what it is,
it's like none of it is selling out if
you're okay with it.
Right.
What's the other thing?
Selling out?
It's,
it's an internal thing.
Not,
it's not other people saying it.
It's literally like,
if you're,
if you're not okay with it and you do it
anyways because of the money,
then you're selling out.
But if you're alright with it and be
like,
listen,
I'm married now.
I got a couple of kids.
This is an easy act acting gig.
I can be here when my kids grow up.
Like that's not selling out.
It really isn't.
I don't think anyway.
Well,
the only thing that's selling out is if
you stop doing what you want to do as
well.
Like if they come up to you and say,
Bill,
you know,
uh,
we,
we really liked the way you play drums
and we want you in the band.
God,
I wish that would happened,
but no talking no more talking for you.
You say you wish that would happen,
but you wouldn't be able to.
I would just love somebody to compliment
my drama.
You always want to come like compliments
on your hobby.
Oh,
so much better.
can you say a dentist?
Damn,
you're a good dentist.
Done a million of these.
But if you actually just sit there and
be like,
why did you build those cabinets?
Well,
matter of fact,
I did so true.
The thing that you know,
you suck at,
it's so true.
Like my pool plane,
that's probably the worst thing that I
do.
But if someone compliments me on my
pipeline,
good pool player,
I am,
but I'm not a good pool player for pro.
If I was a professional,
you know,
so for a regular person and they're
like,
Whoa,
fucking Jesus Christ.
What are you?
A professional.
But a professional said,
oh,
you play good.
See,
that's why you're so successful.
You're trying to get.
You just don't want to like be able to
beat the guys down at the,
uh,
Dave and busters or whatever
round,
round.
Round was always bummed.
They never showed the Regal Beagle.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
They can't have another set.
How about your anniversary?
I want to see upstairs.
We're talking three's company for the
youngsters.
Larry upstairs was crushing it.
That guy was probably the first herpes
case.
What I love about him was he was just so
crushed and ass and didn't,
didn't Karen.
And the character was not considered a
fence.
It's like that guy exists.
That's the guy who's never in a
relationship and he's just,
you know,
chest hair going was the early eighties,
right?
Wasn't it?
Late seventies and early eighties.
Late seventies,
early eighties.
I love that show.
It's a great show.
They were both hot.
Chrissy and Janet.
What about the middle one?
I had no problem with any of them.
Which Chrissy was your favorite?
The first one?
Yeah.
Suzanne.
Suzanne somers?
Yeah.
That's just like a fun person to put
that sound like a perfect.
Like I said,
that nobody threw anything at me.
Seems like she'd be fun to do things to
cook with her.
She,
she's a perfect,
like almost like the quintessential
story of someone getting too big for
their britches and fucking up in the
Hollywood though because she was on this
massive hit show and she demanded so
much like her management and whatever.
They were trying to squeeze every ounce
of blood out of the next pharaoh.
So the show like locked her out.
Like they're like,
oh yeah,
you're on the phone now.
Like you don't even like they did
episodes where she would call in.
Like Chrissy would call in like,
hey guys,
how you been?
Like they funded.
The writers have writing those.
Oh they must have had so much fun.
And they got.
They just got rid of her.
Oh,
that's brutal.
And she was fucking basically done.
I mean,
what was the last thing I did after
that?
How great would it legs when she did the
thighmaster?
She's pretty hot,
but I don't think she had legs like
women's sheriff.
She did that for a minute.
We went today have um,
like muscles,
like there's a women today,
the Doula crossfit and they do like
weight lifting and shit.
They have like a different shaped them.
It's more of a midi shape.
She didn't have that back then.
The seventies bodies.
They look pretty good to me with that.
That I still.
The thing I just
said it and I forgot it,
but thighmaster thighmaster.
Yeah.
Spring stupid fucking thing.
Actually be good.
If you were working on your guard,
especially your half card,
like really clamped down with your half
card,
why don't you tweak it a little neck
like you invented it.
That would be a hilarious Joe Rogan.
You just laying on your back,
opening your legs and closing.
You want to squeeze.
You want to feel it right here.
This is how you're going to tap right
here.
Oh,
oh.
Oh.
Plus it's good for your pussy muscle.
Yeah,
it'll be.
It'll help postop trannies.
Really tighten up the junk.
Especially.
Tighten up your new thing.
There she is.
Actually.
She does look very pornographic.
Delicious.
Oh yeah,
dude,
that's long socks.
How many cokes spoons?
That's not her dude.
It's lady Gaga.
It's a fake one.
Oh,
is that?
If she gets the Suzanne summer thing,
I actually went to her concert.
Leave a dog.
A has a fucking sick body.
Or your mom did a monster.
What is a monster?
That's a fan.
If my girl wanted to see it and I went
there,
I was it.
I kind of ruined it for,
I would say I had eight beers.
I was watching a football game and I
showed up and we took a cab.
I'm such a jerk and I thought I was
behaving myself and the next day I was
like,
she was just had that vibe around me and
I was like,
come on.
I go.
I wasn't bad.
Last night was I,
and she just kind of gives me a look and
I was like,
I go,
I was just sitting that she goes,
Bill,
you screamed Jesus fucking Christ.
I go,
I didn't want you because you did it
like three times because she kept doing
this self help horseshit in between
every song,
every fucking song.
It was just don't worry about.
We got it,
we got it.
It's okay to be a freak to sing your
fucking song.
And then she was sitting at one point
she goes like,
you know,
I hope you guys are having a good time
because if you not,
you know,
I don't give a fuck.
And then people go,
Ooh.
And she goes,
I said,
I don't give a fuck.
Fuck,
fuck.
Right.
And then she goes through the debt,
the,
uh,
the backup dancer like,
trevor,
do you give a fuck?
He's like,
I don't give a fuck.
And it just kept calling fucking price.
Get on with the not giving a fuck dude.
If you truly don't give a fuck you,
you don't sit around talking about it.
That's like that jerk off on the play.
Golf,
we get up there,
I'm going to x,
Y,
and Z.
Even shut up.
I'm trying to go to sleep.
I got a mask on.
How easy is this going to be?
How long ago was this lady Gaga concert
when the Patriots lost in the playoffs,
which is now no means nothing to you.
We lost to the ravens.
So is that the staple center?
I totally respect your pretty fucking
good,
right?
There's a picture over God.
Damn,
I totally missed it back.
She got ass.
No,
as far as like.
Oh,
is that Suzanne somers?
Yeah.
They just don't have hair like that
anymore.
That like back in the day they didn't
have leaves back there.
Look at those legs.
Oh,
just delicious.
That's right.
That's the thighmaster.
She mastered it and she's like fucking
50 something years old now.
It still looks good.
It's pretty amazing.
I mean not real good.
But like if you were on the walking dead
and you were in the woods with her and
there was no other checks and to grab
your deck you would say let's do this.
Oh,
you know,
I mean she has,
she has the resume,
she has the resume plus.
Yeah.
It's one you wouldn't want to put.
Who was your.
Who was your when you were in the
seventies about my age,
right?
Yeah.
So like in the seventies,
like who is the one parent foster.
She just,
it wasn't even close set magazine.
I mean that poster rather was on
everybody's wall.
Was Insane.
One Post or one photo and it was on
literally every fucking wall of every
adolescent boy all throughout America.
It wasn't girls.
By the way,
you had those posters back then.
You remember that back in those days
they had posters of boys.
They didn't have girl idols that they
would put on their wall.
Guys had a fucking posters.
Yeah,
something happened along the way and
girls started having posters of girls on
their walls and guys started having
posters of guys in there.
Well,
yeah,
that's the
dude.
I remember my dad had the playboy that
she was in where she's naked,
but she's sitting with her knees up so
you can't see anything but you almost
can't.
I think I was like maybe eight years old
and I was looking through it and I think
it was the first time.
I mean,
I don't know anything about my body.
I think I had an orgasm,
but nothing came out.
I remember I was looking,
I was looking at the picture and I just
kind of went.
I went like that,
that brief thing,
and I was just like,
that's what I hate the fact Teresa
stories talking about this.
Like don't you love to be able to go
back to that innocent where you could
look at like a Jordan marsh catalog and
you're like,
oh my some secretary skirt below blower
knees and just their calves.
You couldn't believe it.
Like I'm a kid.
Imagine touching a woman's calves.
Like you just like,
you just never have that innocence.
Well again,
that's true.
But guys who don't get laid,
they sort of have that in real life with
girls.
You know,
when they see a real girl in real life
that you know,
at work or at the gym or something like
that where it's almost like,
oh,
can't believe she's right there.
But if you get laid,
it's just like up yet,
that's a girl.
She probably wanted me fuck her,
but okay.
Whatever.
Do.
When I was a virgin,
when a good looking girl talk to me,
my face turned red.
Like it was so overwhelming.
Like you didn't even know what to do.
You're just like,
oh my God.
Like I don't even know how my body's not
even functioning coco cafe.
This tastes like the milk at the end of
cocoa puffs on it.
And we'll talk in the seventies.
Farrah Fawcett,
Coco milk.
It's good stuff.
It's Cookeaqua.
It's coconut water and coffee in
Espresso.
Espresso when it's fucking delicious.
Delicious.
Kate Jackson.
Oh yeah.
On the rookies when she was married to
Mike Danko.
I wanted to be Mike Danco.
Who's the chick that was.
Who's the,
who's the chicken
that was on?
Uh,
Tj Hooker.
Oh,
that was the one who has been on
everything.
Tommy Lee was married to her.
Uh,
uh,
come on,
guys had a lock earlier.
Had the luck.
Was that her on Tj Hooker?
Was He sure had the luck earlier.
So one of the greatest things that,
one of the greatest like moments ever as
a kid to see them
manly,
man she is.
Wow.
She was so young.
Man.
That's so crazy to see what happened to
that Italian guys that the god from
dance fever.
Is that Danny Terrio?
Oh yeah.
That guy was that guy.
Who is that who he is or I had to just
make that up.
I don't know what's his face.
Captain Kirk was like,
I want my to pay to look like Denny Day.
Terry.
Yeah.
He went nutty with his toupee.
You've got a big fuck.
I'm fat thick one that was all curly and
shit.
I never knew.
It was a Tupac.
Adrian's a med.
He was the he.
Yeah,
he was the host of dance fever.
There was Danny Terrio and then Adrian's
a med.
Right?
It is the greatest luck.
When I was like manly moment that I saw
at that I wanted to be.
This guy was when Farrah Fawcett did
like that.
Two,
three guests,
guest spot episode on the $6,000,000
man.
You remember that?
And he,
he had like whatever those fucking those
Jean jackets with the matching slacks,
with the color coming out and this guy
could jump over a house,
beat up like 90 guys beat up big foot,
right?
And Punch that guy in the face to make
his face come off when he fought the
$7,000,000
man.
You remember that?
Yes.
Yeah,
like as I'm making that noise and all
that.
And then he got to bang her.
I was just like,
I want to be this guy.
One of the great.
Can anybody pull up the clip where he
fights those guys in the snow and the
black guy that got them in slow motion
going into the air like it was right
when Bruce Lee hit and everyone was
trying to imitate them.
So the black dude is flying through the
air going,
I was doing,
my mind was blown.
Show us $6,000,000
man,
dude.
He fights the $7,000,000
man.
And we're talking about at the bus stop.
It's like there's no way when six,
this guy's got seven.
They get into a fight and a course.
They just build the drama like wrestling
with a $6,000,000
man is losing and this guy's just so.
It wasn't powers booth.
Who was the actor.
He's done a bunch of stuff.
He was awesome actor and then finally
what ends up happening was he punched
the guy's face off.
It was like a goalie mask.
It was really bad.
His face comes off and then there's all
this robotics under there and then he
takes the steel girder,
do the like in the Hollywood hills
filming this thing and he picks up some
steel girder and just in pails.
The guy goes right through him.
It was like seeing a rated r movie for
me.
I couldn't.
I couldn't believe it.
Yeah.
Who was the $7,000,000
man I'm looking at.
This guy was in love with this girl.
Who was she?
What was her name?
Daisy Duke.
Oh,
Catherine Park.
You know what the worst thing that
happened to her?
She stayed alive.
Come on.
Hey,
come on.
Well,
I'm saying,
oh,
all the things she did for you.
When you have a bunk bed times a
motherfucker.
My brother,
I told you I met her.
Remember?
Yeah.
Didn't she want to.
She want you to pay for a photo?
Yeah,
it was like six years ago.
She's just sitting there like,
Holy Shit,
there's tacy tuk right there.
And no one was talking to her.
Just,
she was just sitting here like,
look,
like she was bored out of her mind.
So I walked up like,
Hey,
can I,
can I get a photo?
She's,
yeah,
$10.
I'm like,
oh no,
I have my own camera.
I just take a photo.
And she goes,
yeah,
it's $10 a month.
Oh No,
I'm sorry.
Thanks.
Just would've felt.
Go,
go.
Uh Oh.
Shorts and everything you did.
I hope you get another gig.
You deserve it sweetheart.
Go get $6,000,000
man versus the $7,000,000
man.
Go check that out online.
It will pull up a video.
$6,000,000
man versus a $7,000,000
man is one of the most ridiculous
fucking things.
I sat down and pajamas.
It's sitting on a beanbag.
Watching that on one of those TV with
legs.
Just riveted.
Yeah,
they were racing the $7,000,000
man.
It's just slightly ahead of him in the
race,
but they're both white,
so during the race everything has to be
in slow motion because otherwise you
wouldn't be able to realize how
ridiculous it wasn't.
You would think that these fucking guys
were special at.
He's got the $7,000,000
man just slightly ahead of them.
Steve Austin with his heart and his
American knowhow just can't quite keep
up.
Oscar Goldman,
Rudy.
I look at that,
look at that because they don't make
Harry chess like that.
He won't get that.
That is classic.
I've banked every broad you've ever
wanted to
down below the the solar
flexes too.
If you ever get lead.
Can you get Lee majors on this podcast?
Is He's still around?
Yeah.
What is the thing about him?
He's.
He is in a very rare space where he was
on three shows that all went to
syndication.
Syndication.
He was on the big valley,
played a cowboy.
He did the $6,000,000
man and then he did the fall guy.
Yeah,
and they all went.
that's true.
Heather locklear.
I think might have had four different
shows that want to syndicate.
That went five years.
Like they literally like good luck
charm.
So it's just like we got to get this
person in this show.
It's gonna.
It's gonna go.
I've done.
Wasn't the guy who don't.
No,
no.
He fought a guy with black hair.
This is a different guy.
Maybe this is the first $7,000,000
man.
Maybe there's more than one.
I've been on two shows that have been
syndication.
I got lucky.
You got,
you need one more,
one more and then you're in that
rarefied air.
Yeah,
you'll,
you'll do it?
No,
I don't think so.
I think I'm done.
I think this,
this is in syndication already already.
Or wondering what kind of show could
they learn you back?
I'm doing a new thing.
I'm not supposed to talk about it
because I did talk about it and they go.
I don't know.
But um,
that's the new thing is it's fun.
It's crafty.
It's going to be fun,
but it's a lot of things based on skin
grafts show.
After that kind of crafty you make
little octagon with based on lighthouse
Ufo and big foot and shit.
That's cool.
What do you think about that Garrett
guy?
The fighter that has down syndrome,
they.
They've been like showing him on espn
like crazy and at first I was like,
that's kind of up,
but he's actually pretty good.
I don't know if you.
I haven't seen too much about it.
I've avoided it with because I'm
terrified that somehow or another it
would make it into my act.
Right.
Then what about him fighting the
transgender?
I think the transgender women like men
to women should fight transgender women
to men and we'll see what's the better
combination
societies should be more acceptable and
then we'll create a whole new class.
Trent 20 fights.
Yeah.
You're not supposed to even say tranny.
Do you know you'll have if
champion fighting out of the blue
corner.
There used to be a dude.
Now he's a chair.
This guy you said he's good.
Yeah.
I mean,
the only thing though,
it's like,
I don't like to just like the
transgender lady thing,
like you don't know if he's 100 percent,
you know,
like should he be able to fight regular
people?
You know,
that's.
Is He fighting a ball?
A regular guy?
Yeah.
I think
was,
I think in this video that's a,
you can find on espn.go.com
is.
I think he actually fights in this
video.
Wow.
And these fighting.
I'm Stephan Bonner's in his corner and
everything.
Yeah.
See,
this is why I can't watch it.
Just immediately start thinking of bits
and she's not in the fight.
She's just commentating scar right here.
Get out of the fight but a duty look at.
He's got a black eye and stuff did that
to him.
This guy right here,
this is what's going on right here.
Oh,
okay.
So he got fucking power doubled quick.
Well I would think that his reaction
time would be not so good.
Yeah.
I would be concerned that you're gonna,
you know,
he'd be do more damage.
Like I don't,
I don't.
Yeah,
no it's true.
Not Dr.
Berg here thinks that,
I mean it is something to consider.
You just got to be another kid out there
with the same thing and then they can go
at it and he got it.
He Kinda,
you can't,
you can't do this.
They're finding so much fucked up about.
He got manhandled man.
You could see like the way that guy
threw him to the ground,
like as a good grappler.
I think um,
there's,
they're showing a lot of studies now
more than ever about brain damage and
fighting.
And if you already have an issue,
I would,
I would say like,
just get involved in Jujitsu.
Go,
go grapple.
You really want to train and compete.
Jujitsu is fine.
You can,
you can have like really intense high
level competition and you don't get hit
in the head getting hit in the head band
unless you want to fight for a living,
unless you want to be a professional
fighter.
I don't advise getting hit in the head
at all,
but it's good to learn.
It's good to train.
And if you can learn from people that
you trust when you don't hit each other
full blast,
like you kick hard to the body and to
the head and you just punched like soft
to the face.
They say that guy is a monster tattoo
monster energy todd to
yeah,
maybe.
Maybe they're pretty much evenly,
evenly matched because it's shitty
choices.
Yeah.
It's um,
well,
it looks like he was all happy that he
fought.
You know,
I mean,
he can't,
can't take that away from him.
Just the problem with fighting is the
real problem is that you're,
you know,
you're,
you're fighting on credit,
you're essentially finding on brand
credits and are you willing to go out
there and throw them in and you know and
see what happens.
But when you're getting tagged,
you owe that later.
You owe that.
It's going to come back.
It's going to come back with interest.
Am I come back six years from now,
five years from now I've met guys
knowing them,
knowing them when they were fine and
then seeing them fucked up.
And it's not just one.
It's weird to see when you know a guy
for 10 years and then you talked to him,
you see him like looking around.
He doesn't know where he is.
He's fucking slurring his words.
It sounds like was hammered.
It's weird because the sound drunk
because it'll sound like a drunk.
Like that's how they sound.
They sound like a guy who's just.
Oh No.
Yeah.
And it's just from taking shots.
They say like nfl football,
you know,
there's people predicting that it's just
going to not exist.
Like at least in the form I have the
solution you got.
You got to go back to leather helmets.
Yes.
You just go back to that and you bring
all the equipment now.
I mean this isn't like,
this is like A.
I'm Don Cherry talked about that in the
NHL.
What used to wear like these spongy pads
when you played hockey,
you know,
just get the pads I used to wear when
you played sports now they like this
hard plastic and I just took up the game
and it's like dude,
I've,
I've fallen on the ice with nothing.
And if you feel like in my age I get hit
by a truck,
you get all the equipment.
All,
dude,
it's hilarious.
It's just you like,
you'll feel like your Robo cop,
you just fall down and nothing hurts.
Now you get these guys.
Were they how fast they can skate like
25 miles an hour or something.
And they come by and they catch you with
that hard piece of plastic.
It's like getting hit with a wrench.
Like I saw a guy,
a mark severity got hit as he was
falling through on a shot,
got hit.
He spun around 180 degrees and came back
and he's never been back.
One hit really?
One hit.
Yeah Dude.
I mean
it hasn't been back Canon
right in the jaw.
And he spun around like obviously got an
A.
I mean,
I don't know,
Shit like a high level concussion.
He was a phenomenal player.
And uh,
so people are saying we got to go back
to that because I like the pad you had
when you were younger,
like you hit stuff,
you still felt it,
you know.
And then the pads would start to wear
out,
but you know,
towards the season,
you know,
and it would hurt.
But now it's just like that,
this stuff,
it's so incredible if like I play
obviously non contact,
so it's great.
So if you fall down,
you don't hurt yourself.
But um,
the stuff in like the Nhl they're
talking about that they're talking about
like in the NFL,
like having guys starting from like sort
of like a stand up position with the
hands out because they,
every place I cannot bone,
they're just slamming heads together.
Um,
repeatedly when you play the whole game,
you got like whatever,
I don't know,
40,
50 plays,
you slammed your head into another guy's
had 50 times,
just that game and then you play 16
games.
Wow.
Now this is beyond my fucking
capabilities.
16 Times
anyway.
You're getting hit in the head a lot.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
People are realizing that,
you know,
when,
when football came around,
when it became popular,
but the amount of data that they had on
brain trauma and to what they have
today,
it's,
it's pretty minimal.
You know,
now we have a sort of accurate view of
the landscape and we know like,
okay,
yeah,
you're taking a fucking serious chances,
right?
The helmet.
What it does is it really,
it protects beyond a certain hit.
All it's doing is protecting the skull.
You won't get a dented skull but like
your brain is just getting sloshed
around so somebody has to come up with
something.
I don't know how big would that be or it
can kinda like,
like your head just sits in there and
you just
the,
the hellman moves around.
Do you know what video I watched
recently?
I'm like,
I have such a poor science background
and just started like,
like science is like,
it's incredible.
Right?
What was that
dumbest thing I've ever heard?
I'm just such a moron.
Can I leave on that day?
That was the dumbest fucking incredible.
I'm going to go out on a limb and say
that is the dumbest thing I'm going to
say this year.
I really hope that that was the low
point.
That's where you're leaving and going to
be fun.
Science is like really incredible cut.
Have that bill on more often.
That was just so.
It's super neat.
No,
I was just watching this thing on
gyroscopes when I was a kid.
They would call tops and he just spun
him and stared at them.
They weren't telling you what was going
on.
This guy gets this gyroscope going and
he puts it on like a cone and it's on
the side and in my world it's defying
gravity and it's just going around this
thing and I don't get how it works.
I don't get what's going on.
Yeah.
Well there's a lot of that out there.
If you just.
Did I explain it bad?
You were just kinda like.
Yeah.
I don't know what a gyroscope.
What does it look?
Look up.
Gyroscope.
Okay.
I know what a gyroscope is.
It,
it's because it's like seventh grade
talking about sex.
You know what that means?
Yeah.
I know what it means.
Um,
what is it?
Just the momentum a gyroscope.
So what's in those?
Um,
those,
uh,
segways.
That's a gyroscope.
Yeah.
I think it's in a helicopter.
Makes Sense.
I mean that it would balance out the
helicopter.
Well,
I finally figured I finally read.
I didn't figure it out.
They told me like I'm discovering
helicopters.
So that back thing,
that back road or is to prevent the
thing from spinning around.
Yeah.
That's why when it gets shot and movies,
the fucking helicopters.
I saw that and I didn't realize it that
that's what that things function was
understanding of helicopter Gyro.
No,
no,
no.
Just,
just look up gyroscopes.
You gotta see this guy?
What?
What,
what am I looking for?
Just a gyroscope.
Okay.
This guy,
I sweated.
God,
he's going to do something that's a
better magic trick that I've ever seen
anybody doing vegas.
It's just chairs.
Scope on youtube of the little tiny
thing.
Let me see this.
Let's go this fresh face.
Alright,
this guy right here.
Now that's not it.
God Damn.
Is that what you're saying?
Son of a bitch.
A.
The reason why you can do it because
it's going so fast.
So it's pushing down.
You know,
because gravity so like you could have
like on the side of a can or something
like that.
This fast and I hang on you guys say
something funny is this is coming up.
The first one just wondering.
Here we go.
Farish scope.
It's online.
It's up there,
Bill.
Oh,
it is?
Yeah.
Look.
All right,
so what you want to be is get to.
Okay.
Oh,
I see what you're saying right here.
Yeah.
Get to about a minute.
Forty in somebody for the love of God
explained that.
Tell me how that works out.
I'll fuck.
Does that happen?
Oh,
that's it's balancing and it's spinning
around in a circle and it's not hitting
the floor until it runs out of momentum.
Spinning,
gyroscope,
bullet balance on a string.
Wow.
Look at that.
That's amazing dude.
That is magic to me.
Well that's why those segways work
somehow or another.
Yeah.
I don't understand.
I just love that.
This,
the technology of that and then some
dumb ass like me can get on one like,
well,
slam into a wall with a looped around.
One is thinking about a phone,
you know that you use every day and
nobody knew.
If I'm ever out of like if there's a
power outage,
I'm getting one of these.
If I have to entertain guests and I'm
just going to start spinning this thing,
this lava rock right there,
people are gonna be blown away.
Like,
look at it.
You could start a car caused the power
outage.
There's got to be done within me that
would actually buy into it.
Oh,
for sure.
Have you ever watched videos?
It is pretty amazing.
What does it have to do with space?
Hmm?
Do I swear to God?
You could actually see how dumb the
average person is.
Like I consider myself an average
person.
You'd go to a bar with one of those
things.
They literally like five bucks and you
could just like blow minds with the
just blah.
You're like,
wait,
fuck you.
Is anybody ever gotten laid because of a
gyroscope?
You do it.
If you're wearing a cape and you show it
in that thing,
it's over with a big point.
You read things like Dracula and then
you know you do when they ask you
questions.
As you delay for a second and staring at
them like your mysterious,
like Ryan gosling and drive,
I can tell you.
Yeah.
Ryan gosling and drive.
He did that.
He did let that delay thing and you're
like,
mind fucked.
You like what's going on?
What's what's happening here?
Yeah.
He did the broken guy thing like
[inaudible].
Sky's broken.
Oh yeah.
That's kind of emphasis and completely
still.
I owe him an apology.
I completely stole all of that.
On that flight to indy.
I was just like,
I'm going to do what Ryan gosling
window.
I'm going to have this look on my face
like I just got done fucking your wife
and there's nothing you can
you
and I handled that much differently.
I would have.
I would have told the flight lady,
I would have been the one son,
please.
You got to get this guy off the fucking
planet.
Like something's going on right now.
I wouldn't be able to fall asleep next
to their fucking lawyer,
schizo or autistic or something like
that.
Maybe these ratios to get to to another.
Like he wasn't good.
I just,
you know,
just like no.
When you never 100 percent.
No,
I just knew he wasn't going to do
anything and I knew if I didn't I was
sort of feeding it.
I was being a dick.
But um,
tell me actually said a great thing
when,
when he came around you should have
invited them to your show.
That would have been great.
They said you should've given them
tickets.
Wish the old school.
We actually had tickets opened up and
talked about it on stage.
I did open with it that night.
Did you really?
Yeah,
but I was still kind of weirded out by
it so it kind of came out as creepy
rather than.
So I just was like,
all right,
this is,
this is more of a podcast story.
So,
and here we are.
What percentage of your,
uh,
your crowds in our podcast crowds,
like people know you from the podcast?
I have no idea when you say
response,
but I think that they're,
it's like they're into the specialist
there into the podcast and thing.
You just,
it's great man.
You just carve out your own little store
on the Internet.
This is me.
This is what I do feel like it come on
out.
And uh,
and then all you do is you just never
fuck them.
You always come out with a new hour and
you never take a show off.
You just don't fuck them because that's
the relationship.
When they say they love you,
it's basically I love you until you
suck.
Don't fuck me.
That's basically it because we don't
know each other.
So I understand the responsibility of
that.
And I always try to have good openers.
I just want the wire to wire.
Good show you came out.
Good time.
Go out there fucking take pictures.
Kissing babies,
shaking hands.
It's great.
I really like afterwards,
uh,
at first I didn't like going out there
but that was more my awkwardness and
then like my issues with that shit.
But now I've actually,
I kind of know as honestly not like
super trump.
Those people,
you know,
like it was like a motor boat and your
face just spitting
and they're like complimenting uses,
like spitting in your face.
Like that becomes.
And then it's like,
you know,
I have the exact same attitude,
the exact same attitude about the
audience,
like the camp fuck 'em and you gotta
keep,
keep giving them a free shit.
That's why I love keeping the podcast
free.
That's why I love,
you know,
the,
the idea that you're always going to
have them there as long as you keep
providing good content,
you keep coming up with new material
and you can't expect anything more on it
because I've done the same thing.
I love bands in the eighties and then
they started to suck and I never bought
any more of their albums.
So am I really a fast?
Like I like you when you do good stuff.
I like it when you do stuff.
I like,
I have a,
I had a big fear of that when I was
first coming up that uh,
that guy's sort of seemed to have it and
then lose it.
And there's a lot of guys that fall into
that category that were really funny at
first and then lost it,
including contemporaries that I won't
mention.
I don't want to hurt anybody's feelings,
but as far as dead guys,
Kennison was my favorite example of
that.
Kennison I think in like 86,
87 was the greatest guy ever.
I think it was one of the funniest
comics ever ever.
And then when I came along
and I came along and Ada,
that's more like,
like three all time behind,
like prior and then,
you know,
his body of work or a bill cosby.
I mean you just have to like,
it's all subjective,
but I don't.
I put Carlin,
I mean a lot of people would be pissed
at me for this,
but I put Carlin like fourth.
What's the fourth?
All time and me,
somebody's going to get mad man,
you know,
you put Hixon for the coral.
And because Hinduism is funny.
Um,
I think Hicks had this sort of
groundbreaking sort of new take on
standup that inspired so many other
people to sort of like branch down that
path that I always put him right up
there.
Yeah.
And it's also like a bad thing.
Some people like rush and neil part,
some people like led Zepplin and John
Bonham and that thing that happened.
But who cares as long as you're in,
you just want to be in the argument.
Yeah.
For me it's prior,
all time,
number one,
buyers,
number one.
Um,
and then it's Kennison and then Hicks
and then um,
then Carla,
but there's a through line to that,
that order.
That makes sense to me.
Like I could see that,
that obviously,
I mean,
I know that you do stand up obviously,
but like there's like that order.
I like if I just saw someone listed like
that,
I'd be like,
okay,
this guy,
he likes this style,
you know what I mean?
Like Kennison is,
is like if he had just come out the
other side where like,
it seemed like he,
uh,
like just fell into every pitfall.
Stepped in every batch alcohol,
the whole thing.
Lazy.
Like in [inaudible] 86.
Like,
I mean that was one of the,
you know,
his first letterman spot,
dude is fucking unbelief.
Just the vibe in the studio.
You can feel it like we have no idea
what this guy is going to do.
Man,
this guy and he came out and did not
disappoint.
But if you look at the difference
between the first one and the second
one,
it's already starting like whatever he
was going through.
But I remember when he got all cleaned
up and he was getting.
He was coming back.
It was really like the Stevie Ray
Vaughan thing.
Like he just got all cleaned up,
turn in and around in his life.
Oh my God,
I can't.
Even when he died,
they found cocaine.
The system,
it was never really cleaned up.
La Wasn't,
could claim to be cleaning up,
but it wasn't clear that though,
because I know I know everything about
them.
I mean it's first of all,
his brother,
I read his book,
read his brother's book and talked to
will always kill my theories with facts.
He was
that a guy the other day about,
dude,
you know,
and you were standing on stage,
you were getting booed.
And I,
and I,
it just was like,
you know,
that really inspired me and you stood
there and the dude was just like,
yeah,
I was so high.
I didn't even hear the boom.
Yes.
Let me have that fantasy.
The fantasy
me,
my fantasy version of who you are that
he didn't give a fuck.
Oh,
that crushed me.
I got to see,
um,
kinison as I was an open mic or like as
I was starting out,
I got to see him live at least twice,
I think only twice,
but at least twice.
Um,
and uh,
a fucking sucked.
Both Times.
The was better than him.
It doesn't even make any sense.
Carla blow,
uh,
who opened his opening act was funnier,
more energetic,
better,
better material.
I actually had material kinison was
cheerleading by then.
It was already over by 89.
It was already over.
He would go up and he would,
uh,
he would do like this cheerleading thing
about like drinking and drive.
We got to do it.
Who got drag?
Who?
God,
we're going to pull it off because we do
it every fucking.
Yeah.
But it was,
there was no jokes,
the jokes were gone,
like all the shit about the African
children,
like why don't you feed them.
You're right.
But it's not like you don't lose that.
He just,
he was adjusting and right as he was
coming out of it evidently still was
coming a bit according to you.
Like I would have loved to have seen
what that guy was going to do because,
uh,
I don't think he was done.
And this is why I think it was done.
I think you can only do coke for so
long.
You're crushing me here.
I'm sorry.
I can,
I handle the hold on my dream that he
would have come back and he would have
been in 45,
gotten on some fucking Kale shakes,
started doing hill sprints and shed.
But do you know Kennison his story?
His life story is a fascinating one
because he was a normal kid until he got
hit by a truck.
He got hit by a truck and you know,
he,
he suffered like some sort of a
traumatic brain injury.
And after that became reckless.
It was just wild as fuck.
It was like a completely different kid.
It was like Kennison wanting Kennison
too,
and Kennison one was like a normal
average seven minutes.
He got cracked and he got hurt real bad
and from then he was reckless.
Just wild,
you know,
and he did a lot of crazy shit man.
And if you look back at his life,
like his impulse control was like
nonexistent.
I mean he fucked Carla Bose wife.
Carla boat was opening right.
There was carl talks about it.
I wouldn't say it any other work.
This carl found,
Carl found out that his daughter's
father,
he thought it was his daughter and it
was just fucking Sam Kennison who's his
best friend the whole time.
Yeah,
the whole craziness,
man.
Crazy.
Yeah.
You hate to see that.
But I learned a lot watching them.
First of all,
I learned in the beginning what was
possible when I saw him,
his first HBO special specials.
Like there's the grants committee I've
ever seen.
I couldn't believe this is even comedy.
Like I couldn't believe,
like someone figured out this new way of
doing comedy.
But then to see him just become really
shitty after that,
I was like,
wow,
that can happen.
Like you need to know that that can
happen.
I think you've been to water and the
guy.
Really?
Yeah,
because he died prematurely.
You're talking about like he's still
alive in the nineties.
He died in the nineties.
Dude,
I'm older than he was when he died.
Yeah.
So yeah,
no,
I mean like,
you know,
I'm just saying like he was pulling
himself out of the mud and then he,
he,
he died.
So it's like,
it just gets cut off.
So you have no idea you'd given them a
break because he's dead.
I see what you're doing.
Yes.
Am.
Because
it's like your making it seem like those
last few years,
that's what,
that's all he was going to be.
You can't say that.
Well your podcast,
you're right.
No,
it's possible that he could come back.
There was no evidence that he was coming
back.
The material that he was doing was shit.
It was,
it was just poorly thought out.
It was like he never sat in front of a
fucking notebook and actually wrote it
out anymore.
You didn't.
Didn't tighten things up and.
Right,
right.
You're killing.
I'm sorry.
He's my favorite.
He's,
I mean he's right up there with John
Bonham was your favorite drama?
Would you talk about those 52 shots of
vodka?
A tuck.
I'm telling you
was so big.
He couldn't get over to the floor.
Tom Say he had.
He had a floor.
Tom as a rack.
Tom,
because he was so fat he couldn't get
around.
I don't know what that means.
I don't know what you just said.
There's allegedly.
He had a 15 inch rack,
Tom,
by the end of it.
What's that mean?
Gigantic.
It's usually see sing,
sing,
sing.
When the guy plays bumped down to dump
down on the floor,
that's a Florida guy allegedly was so
fucking fat.
He couldn't get around to them,
so he just this giant fucking through
an.
He's younger.
When he was younger,
he's doing is,
he's still in his triplets and he would
do this thing where it was just like
kick left,
right?
And then it was boom,
boom,
and then cross over and then back and it
was,
and we did it like a 90 miles an hour.
You see them at Royal Albert Hall at the
height of his powers.
Dude,
unbelievable drummer.
And then as he got older,
like his finance was,
was incredible.
Like he didn't,
he didn't,
uh,
like he didn't have to do all that to
get the same kind of power and a.
But what people would do is they know
that people like trashed,
like getting off the subject here.
People like what you're doing at
Kennison.
They kind of did the bottom of people.
No,
listen,
I'm not,
I'm just telling the truth.
He fucked up and it's good for any young
guy to sit are out of this.
And a young comic,
I think it's important to see that
that's possible.
But it got caught up in his own wave and
he became a caricature.
You know,
it became like a,
I just pictured you becoming a
caricature of yourself.
How can I do?
And you come out and all you're doing is
just throwing kicks the fucking show.
Coming out with a speed bag comic comedy
speed Piscopo for this going.
Yeah,
I do remember that.
He took a steroid test during his
special.
What?
He,
he had a special where he had been.
One was saying he was on Roids
oh,
because he got really big on
bodybuilding magazines
and stuff.
So then,
and it all stemmed from some comment
somebody made when he took his shirt off
at,
at a pool,
like plastic sensitive performance.
And then he just went the other way with
it.
It just became like shred and that guy
was shredded.
That's where it came from.
Somebody like mocked his.
I mean I've been talking about a
magazine article I read like in the
eighties,
um,
so he got all big like that.
So he has a special actor where he does
like axl rose and he does all these
guys.
And in the beginning of it,
somewhere towards the beginning he just
has a guy in a lab coat come out or
something.
He sent a lot of people say I'm taking
roads or whatever.
So the band's playing.
He goes offstage and basically I guess
ps in this Cup,
no way,
and he does his whole special and the
special ends in this guy comes back out
with the classic,
I'm a doctor,
lab coats and it comes out and he's
like,
what's the verdict?
And they go,
it's clean.
He's like,
it's clay.
And that was,
I sweat it.
I get so to say it out loud is so nuts.
I'm starting to wonder if it happened
and I apologize if I,
if he's listening,
I got it wrong.
I really shouldn't have done that.
I've never been able to find it.
Oh,
it's got to be out there.
Well,
Joe Piscopo is recently been brought to
the limelight by Opie and Anthony Opie
and anthony have been goofing on.
Joe Basketball and they had them on the
show and they tortured him.
Oh,
it was beautiful.
But um,
maybe because of that more people like
looking up his stuff because a lot of
people started.
They started tweeting me,
Joe Piscopo at concert links and videos
and posters.
Johnny dangerously.
It shoots through schools.
I loved him.
Yeah,
he was great.
But,
um,
steroid test get the Sinatra thing with
Eddie Murphy.
That was a great.
That was great.
Yeah.
No,
I mean,
but,
but it's also undeniable that he lost
his fucking marbles and disappeared.
Yeah.
He,
he appeared to undergo a drug test
during a show.
Oh really?
That's you.
Everybody's got that moment.
Your career you'd like.
I'd like
to have it back now.
Fucking watch is still on,
in his HBO special.
Uh,
he appeared to undergo a drug test
during the show is appeared in anti
steroid public service announcements.
He became the subject of controversy in
the early nineties after appearing
appearances of his newly buff physique
on the covers of fitness magazines.
It led many to speculate.
He was using steroids do dude too.
I mean,
he wasn't that big.
He just got,
he got in great shape.
Look,
you can,
you can pack on a lot of weight without.
Um,
did you ever know Brian Frazier?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
When we were in Boston,
Brian Frazier was way bigger than Joe
Piscopo and he was 100 percent natural.
He's the biggest guy that I've ever met,
but I absolutely know for a fact was 100
percent natural.
He was so big.
He would go on stage with a tee shirt on
and I told them,
you can't do that anymore.
I'm like,
you can't do that because no one's
paying attention like I know you and I'm
not paying attention with the fuck
you're talking about because he had
giant arms.
He's a bodybuilder because Andrea twice
as big as mine.
I never fucking enormous.
He's got.
He's got to come up.
You've got to have the button down.
Yeah.
You just got gotta do something where
people are not getting distracted by the
fact that you've these fucking legs
growing off your shoulders.
He was so big at big fucking.
I've never
understood that.
Didn't that big like just theories.
People where they have a too big.
That's not funny.
People.
People want to see somebody up like
people look their theories don't have a
beard.
Beard is bad.
I mean they need to see.
Your facial expression is just so much
horseshit that you hear those theories
all.
Yeah.
They're just trying to define the beard.
Didn't work for him at all.
Yeah.
Nobody can tell you anything.
What made A.
I mean,
look,
Hedberg used to go on stage 99 percent
of the time with sunglasses on.
Who would ever tell you you should go?
Yeah,
I've closed with sunglasses on.
It was awesome.
Nobody can tell you how the fuck can you
be a cage fighting commentator and a
standup comedian?
They'll tell you,
you can't do both.
What a fucking black hole.
Just like so many,
like heat,
like what would that guy like?
I just,
I still kills me.
I didn't even know him that well.
I met him a couple times,
but like me to same thing.
It's just like,
uh,
that guy.
I mean he was brilliant.
Oh my God.
It's so fucking rich.
I mean,
I just sat there and you just became a
fan for some.
I saw him was in the old logo on Fairfax
and what was awesome was there was this
guy who ran the room who was good at
running the room and he had real
difficulty.
Like all those guys were standing up.
Was it was so difficult,
he wasn't likable and he would just go
on stage and you know,
those guys,
they just,
they come onstage and just for whatever
reason,
whatever they're putting out the crap
just hates him.
Right.
And he went up there and just flailing,
flailing,
flailing.
And so he's running the room and then he
brings up Hedberg.
Hedberg goes up there and just instantly
is killing.
And he was doing shit.
Like what if he got mad at fruit?
He was this crazy jokes.
He was trying.
I used to just like fucking fruit.
That's just the way he did it.
He was so fucking ridiculous and it
just,
you are like,
just locked in.
It was,
he was just one of those guys,
I don't care if you had fucking 12 beers
in you,
you just knew instantly I am watching a
genius and you would just,
it was um,
yeah man,
I,
I just
so original the way he would like,
he would,
he would make jokes about shit that
doesn't make any sense.
I mean,
like you would look at a paper,
you go,
how the fuck is someone going to make a
joke of it?
Had the combos for double tree.
They have a meeting,
what do you want to call it?
Let's call it two trees.
How about devil tree meeting?
Adjourn.
I heard that he actually had the balls.
He went on Letterman and on one of his
sets he called back to a job he did on a
previous set on letterman.
Just to see if anybody noticed.
I mean,
it's just like that.
I mean I tap out right there.
I'm just like,
Jesus Christ.
It was really clean too,
which is really funny because he's like
one of my favorite guys ever.
That's basically squeaky clean and every
once in a while when he cursed it was
great.
Yeah.
I would say a fucking them up.
One of the things about being a comic in
Boston is that,
uh,
there was a lot of craft to me.
You,
you came along so a little bit after me
about after my generation of open
makers.
Uh,
but there was a,
there was a lot of emphasis put on the
craft of like the use of the word fuck.
Like,
you know,
you could use the word fuck,
but don't over fuck,
don't break the fuck meter.
That's the guys would say,
I remember that.
I try to keep it to three,
three to five bucks.
Yeah.
Like Donovan used to say
Donovan was a genius man.
Donovan Donovan is one of those
unheralded genius
favorite lines ever is.
He's talking about being at work and
their boss breaking your balls above
going on break.
And one of my favorite,
like most one of those blue collar
details that I never heard anybody bring
up on stage.
He was imitating,
you know,
giving shit to his boss.
He said I'll take a 20 minutes shit on
the clock if I want.
And I was just like,
oh my God.
I used to work with a guy who did that
everyday.
Just dogging it,
just hated his life.
He would grab the newspaper.
It was just like he go,
we just had to break.
The Roach coach pulled up.
We just had the break and he used it to
get.
He was so fucking miserable to get from
the break to get to lunch.
He had this routine where he would go
and he's like,
I have to go to the bathroom and we
would all break his balls.
It's like jail.
You fucking went in there for like nine
hours,
you know,
and he would just laugh and he would
just walk in,
sit down and just read the newspaper.
I don't even think he was taking a shit.
He would just sit on this bowl just to
have this debt.
I never forget that shit.
Like how lucky my life is to tell jokes.
Let's just say that like your game plan
is you hate your job so bad that you
pretend to take his shit for 20 minutes
every day just to get to lunch.
That's a lot of guys that you can get
fired for that.
Oh,
nowadays with all the cameras and
everything,
they can literally break down.
Exactly.
When you come back in the day that fuck
you was six minutes,
there would be an attorney or how quick
am I supposed to take a shit in,
bring it to a diet counselor,
try to get you.
We have to figure out,
figure out some sort of a way to
optimize your time better here at
Performance Inc,
setting the people in the cubicles that
you're walking by.
As you go to the,
uh,
as you go to the toilet there,
they're pulling your load
while you're shitting.
Oh,
that was one of the dumbest things we
ever did.
We used to,
we used to ship out like this computer
software.
We are the middleman between like
software companies and people ordering
software.
This is like the 80,
so there's no internet.
So people would come to our company.
I mean the company I worked for where
they had all this software,
Lotus one,
two,
three,
Dbas,
all this old school shit.
And uh,
one day we got into this stupid guy,
competitive thing like fucking morons.
We didn't realize it like who was
shipping out the most.
So we started saving them competing with
one another and uh,
this guy shipped out 100 packages,
so the next day I did 1:20
and then he did one 60 move fighting and
then the fucking management got room for
it.
They're like,
oh yeah,
why don't you start keeping a and a,
a number.
And then they figured out who is being
the most efficient and guys started
losing their jobs.
So I even back then I was like,
dude,
guy stopped fucking doing it.
Stopped doing it
because we're,
we're literally cutting our own fucking.
Well you're making yourself.
You put yourself in a race that's
there's no.
Yeah,
but we didn't know any.
we didn't know any better idiots.
We were like 19,
22.
We used to fucking go out and drink like
a 12 pack of beer and eat McDonald's at
one in the morning and by like 8:00
crew unloading trucks find laughing and
then we would work.
We do all this shit and that during
lunch hour we would go out and play
basketball and like just regular
sneakers and like five slash 11 blues
number that the butterfly and you'd be.
You'd come back and pouring sweat and
then just keep on.
It's the greatest shape I was ever in my
life.
And then in the end of work I would then
go lift and go ride a bike.
Do remember one time I went on a bike
ride,
hammered.
I was so into working out fucking bike
ride.
I'm,
I'm like a 12 speed bike that I bought
when I still have it,
by the way,
am I garage.
I refuse to throw shit out.
And uh,
I remember being hammered on the bike
and I'm sweating so I'm becoming more
hammered.
I was going to do this 11 mile loop that
it became,
oh seven.
And then I just kind of came back and I
was like on the bike laughing and I was
like 20,
21 and was only beginning to understand
the fragility of life.
And I knew that what I was doing was
stupid,
but I couldn't get,
like I,
I just kept picturing my friends
laughing at me and I was literally by
myself riding this bike,
laughing drunk,
driving up the street.
I've been here for two and a half hours.
Like I'm just taking snippets from
fucking the ads I got.
I got nothing left.
Used to be able to bounce back so.
Well when you're young,
it's amazing.
When you're 20 years old you can get
hammered in the next day.
You barely feel anything.
Food Donald's and tear down that place.
I would get to quarter pounders with
cheese,
a large fry,
a six piece mcnugget.
And I never liked him.
I never liked him.
I never thought an ace to try the
different sauces.
Mustard never tastes good.
I just wanted something to fill the
void.
And then I would get like a couple of
cheeseburgers and uh,
I think just a giant coke and just throw
that down and wake up the next day with
a flat stomach.
And I had already drank like,
you know,
eight,
nine beers.
We've got to fight.
We got into a fight one time right under
the Golden Arches and the next town
over.
Um,
I don't know what happened.
These guys came in drunk,
classic Boston Shit.
They just come walking in and they give
everybody the finger.
Of course we respond to it and next
thing you know,
we're out underneath the golden arches.
There's like five of us and two of them.
And uh,
my buddy,
we always fought,
he starts swinging on the big one and
then the little one he sort of jumped
and it just became this big and it
looked like wrestling,
you know,
and like they all come running out of
the dressing to help each other on snow.
Everybody's drunk just fallen down.
We so fucking drunk.
The cops were there,
like sort of missing mace for like,
I don't know how long,
like we didn't even see him pull up,
like being in the light.
Then all of a sudden everybody's eyes
are like tearing up and shit.
And then what was hilarious was they
just broke us up and they fuck it.
And then like two seconds say we're back
in our car and the same two guys we were
fighting were coming back up to the car.
So what are the cops go?
I thought it was over.
And the guys like that was a bullshit
punch.
I remember the little one goes.
I said,
memory goes,
we laugh at you.
Shit.
It was fucking nuts.
I got to give it up to him.
And he was fucking four on two or
whatever.
And uh,
they didn't give a shit.
They laughed.
They definitely left in our shit.
They,
they didn't care.
They hate that Mason.
They came right back.
They already are right up to our Ford
escort.
They did not give a fuck
into the fighting.
You just got maced.
Something happened.
I don't know.
Nobody got it full on.
Like it was just like you're.
I,
I thought we thought it was the snow.
Like they had thrown a rock salt because
we were on the ground.
I don't,
I don't know what it was,
but it was just like unbelievably
fucking air.
But we were hammered.
A fucking police car pulled up and
nobody noticed.
That's hilarious.
Whatever was going on.
How fucking
common or fights in Boston though?
I mean that's the other thing we.
I didn't realize growing up there that
that's not normal and that there really
aren't that many fights in the rest of
the country.
I was never a fighter man.
I fucking hated that shit.
Like I saw so many guys just like you
just like,
you know that youtube videos,
you see someone's already knocked out
and they're unconscious and they get
that extra two,
three boots to the head.
You're like,
oh my God.
For the love,
for the love of God.
Just you one.
Yeah.
I've never been into.
They either,
believe it or not.
I was always the guy who got the fuck
out of there.
I never wanted to have anything to do
with that.
I didn't mind competition,
but in my kickboxing or martial arts
tournament or whatever,
but a fight on the street.
I was like,
why don't we do in here?
This is avoidable.
This is chaos.
This is why my thing that I always used
to get psyched out because I was like,
all right,
I'll fight my older brother and lose,
then I'll take the ass kicking,
but he has to deal with the fact that
dad's coming home.
This guy doesn't have to stop,
dad isn't coming home within this
relationship and he can just keep going
and I've always been slow as shit so you
could literally tell me what you're
going to throw and tell me exactly what
to do.
You're still going to hit me
big head already.
Like I really like.
If I would have died in 1980,
if there wasn't for all this medicine
and shit like I shouldn't be.
I'm one of the weak ones.
I really like.
I had my appendix ruptured.
I wouldn't.
If it was the 18 hundreds,
I would have died under like a stack of
blankets and say sponged off my giant
for that would've been.
It would've been buried out by the
outhouse.
I Dunno.
It was weird.
It just kinda was kept hurting and
hurting.
How old were you?
A 12.
That's terrifying.
And it was,
it was ruptured.
And they didn't know what was my one day
I'd be fine.
The next day I was at and my brothers
convinced that he knows when we were
playing baseball and football came up
and he said it hit me in the side.
I don't think it did.
I can't remember,
but I just remembered my parents were
always just like,
you're fine,
dude.
I get hit by a car and they sent the
ambulance away and we took a cab to a
better hospital and my mother was going,
just stay awake.
Just say,
wow.
Wow.
Did you hear about that kid that got hit
with a disgust?
He got hit with disgust and died.
He got hit in the hip.
He got hit in the hip with a discussed
in one of dying.
What?
They don't know.
Some sort of a blood blood clot or
something.
I don't know.
But,
uh,
here,
I'll pull up the story you want to have
you talked to them?
Yeah.
There's obviously major arteries that
connect the top to the bottom right.
I mean,
the blood's got to get down there.
So basically you got the four.
Oh,
five on one side,
the one on one or the other.
Fifteen year old kid in Texas died nine
days after being hit with a flying,
discuss it,
and he got hit in the hip to hip.
It wasn't any vitals.
No.
I know the questions to ask.
Yeah.
Vitals makes you sound like you know
what you're talking about is fucking
crazy.
Yeah.
He,
he was in pain apparently and the pain
kept getting worse.
He was admitted a place under intensive
care and then dod from fucking.
Yeah,
you're in pain.
They elaborate.
Don't tough it out.
You know,
now they don't.
They don't know.
It just happened.
The funeral,
it was just a couple of days ago,
so I think there probably were awaiting
the results of the autopsy still,
but he was most likely a blood clot in
your body.
So fucking fragile.
And you know,
I've seen so many people get beat up.
I've probably seen more people get beat
up than anybody in human history.
Did you know what day I'm going to the
hospital already?
The amount of people that I know that
died and they say for three days they're
going,
yeah,
I just don't feel right.
Yeah.
Like when you feel that go to the go to
the fucking hospital,
it's just like,
let's do a full body cat scan.
That's such a scab.
Find something cat scans.
Why is that?
Well,
it's been an MRI for the full body
magnetic resonance imagery,
cat scans for the dome.
All right,
you got that?
I think right now do cat scans for body
once.
This is.
The guy won't admit he's wrong.
They like make you pull your knees up
into your fucking shoulders down there.
All the guys that I've seen get beat up.
I mean,
how many people have seen a thousand
people get beat up?
I've seen at least a thousand from all
the fights that I've called,
I'm an all the the trauma I've seen in
person,
so normally I don't like that shit.
Where after the dudes knocked out and
then the guy comes up and it's like one,
two,
three,
four,
and then the breath gets there.
It's just a shitty referee.
That's what that is.
Yeah.
To the arm bars,
I still remember,
I forget what fight it was.
I think it was when Matt Hughes had a.
what's his face in the arm bar and you
just wouldn't have the gracie family
like Oh,
hoists.
Yeah.
He would not have said something like,
oh my God,
you like that?
You know when you get hyped snap.
Literally I had to look away because I
was like going,
I'm going to see two bones come through
the skin.
That is one of the.
Like.
He was just like,
fuck this.
Like I am not.
That's one of the toughest things I've
ever seen.
He's so filled with adrenaline and it
was his pride.
I mean he was a Jujitsu master and this
guy got him into Jujitsu hold and it's
basically going to break his fucking
arm.
Straight arm bar.
Gosh,
that was one of the.
It's a lot of pain,
man.
It's terrible.
Terrible pain to experience.
But no,
his whole family was like that.
I mean his,
his dad is famous for fighting.
This guy named Kimora,
this big Japanese guy.
His Dad got a shoulder ripped apart by a
Komora.
It's called a Comoran that's a shoulder
lock,
but you know,
Yankee cap wouldn't tap guy ripped his
shit apart and who knows how they pieced
them together back then because this is
the 19 forties.
I mean,
what the fuck they did to put his arm or
his knees back in the day.
They would just,
they tell you I shit out.
Work at the gym where he worked out to
ever tell you this.
I'm bad.
Anybody's still listening to this at
this point was like,
we're for sure getting married.
This,
we always do.
Um,
bobby or I was at the Boston.
It is,
we do like three hour podcasts almost
every time we've done it with you,
pal,
you forgot already know.
I met one time over your house and I
woke up in my elbow coupler and the
fucking thing was over.
Like I didn't realize how much I was
sweating like my back of my knees to my
ass.
It was like I ran a marathon.
That's my shitty office man sitting in
that vinyl fucking chair.
It was leather.
It was a real legit,
legit,
marbled flipped and vital in my house or
whatever the hell it was.
Corinthian leather was just about to
tell you
at.
You just found the last two and a half
hours of know.
What the fuck was I talking about?
Gracie's?
Yes.
He looked at it.
No,
no.
It was past that we went past the
shoulder.
Well,
how they put it together.
The 1940 [inaudible]
oh fuck.
Right.
After that.
If somebody screaming at their car where
you lost me,
I lost my fucking point.
Come on,
let's walk back.
It's no,
it's never coming back.
It's over.
Gilbert.
I don't know what the fuck I was going
to tell you.
Imagine how they built his own.
God knows what they did.
Well,
that's that bobby.
Your Shit.
Oh,
Bob.
Your.
That's it.
Thank you.
Got It.
I worked at the Boston Athletic Club in
Southie and uh,
I was a trainer there when I was 19 and
bobby or used to play racquetball there
and he had,
who knows how many knee operations.
He was a very nice guy.
Bobby Orr was and a super friendly to
anybody would come in,
but I used to have to help him get on
the versaclimber verse climbers one of
those things.
It looks like you're climbing it.
The,
like the,
uh,
the arms go up and your right arm will
go up,
your left arm will go down and the same
with your feet and you're,
it's a great exercise.
It's great to get it made that noise.
Absolutely.
It's a great.
Oh,
that's it.
Yeah.
I remember that.
It's a great cardio exercise,
like one of the best Jujitsu.
Anyway,
bobby or gets on this thing and he can't
really bend his knees.
His knees,
like this is a normal person's name.
They go from here to like there.
That's how you're,
you're nigos his knee goes like this
clink clink.
He,
he gets like 15 degrees of movement.
I mean,
very little.
He's like bone on bone.
Yeah.
So we used to have to pick him up,
pick him up and uh,
get his feet into the thing.
And then you had to be there when he
wanted to get off of it,
as well as like,
his knees would not bend correctly and
when he was playing racquetball,
he would just fall down,
like he would play racquetball and he
would like go for a ball and just fall.
I mean he just,
he didn't even try to stop it.
He would just allow themselves to fall
first.
Sam Kennison not bother your.
He just killed me.
No,
listen,
Bob Yoga was a great guy.
He ate.
He had the same issue that uh,
a very good friend of mine has where
they,
they did those operations back then.
First of all these to cut you open like
a salmon.
They would just,
they would just open you and then they
would go into the hamstrings.
They pull the hamstrings out,
take a big chunk of it,
and then try to reconstruct your knee.
And it would almost always blow out.
So bobby had so many fucking surgeries,
his knees just an up and down.
Both
those guys out on the golf course when
they were shorts,
where they have that Frankenstein car
right over the Patella.
Oh,
I have that.
You have that?
Yeah,
that's my acl.
I had to,
but that one doesn't hurt at all.
I had a Patella that's actually more
than the new school was on the side.
The acl is in the middle.
The acl is what connects the two
together and keeps them from moving
forward and backward.
And there's obviously the outside and
there's a lot of different things,
but one of the ways that they,
uh,
they fixed the acl joint is they take a
piece of the Patella tendon joint,
which is the front one which goes from
the kneecap down.
They take a slice of that because it's a
big thick one.
Have you ever seen a cadaver?
It's very fit and you don't need it all.
So they take a strip of that,
open you up and they open you up and
then they screw it in place.
So I have a screw in one and then
another screw in another.
It's still in.
The screws are still in there because
it's almost like you go through security
at the airport.
It doesn't beep,
but it shows up in an MRI.
I to tell them,
you stand there and do the Jay z thing.
Yeah,
I do it.
You don't do it.
You don't have to worry about that one
because that one isn't even radiation.
That's actually radio waves.
So they'll look.
This is the sharp metal object.
Anybody 12 years or younger they go,
okay,
go through the old school one.
So it's like,
what is that?
Because that will disrupt him hitting
puberty.
Yeah,
they do.
It's because it's their little kid parts
probably.
Well they like,
they'd probably illegal to see a picture
of your Dick.
Oh,
is that what it is?
Yeah.
Because you know a lot of those,
especially those naked imagery things
like that was the thing you were getting
like
there's been several versions are old.
You can see that deck.
That's okay.
That's still under age.
Maybe they just get,
they get nervous when someones too
young.
Yeah,
I dunno,
I just saw that.
I'm like,
if you hit me with enough shit,
the fucking kill him.
I don't want to go through it.
I always go through the pat down.
You get a
pat down,
always Ari Shaffir doesn't.
He goes to,
gets a pat down and he berates them.
Girls are thieves,
thieves and losers and idiots.
Like I've never seen anything like he
gets angry at.
He doesn't anymore.
He's backed off of it and he's decided
now to just be polite but object and
tell them there's other ways to make a
living.
But uh,
they were.
He goes,
well,
can we just go,
come on,
do your thing.
So stupid.
Nobody asked for this.
You're not helping anything.
This is a stupid,
corrupt organization.
So they go,
we're going to get our supervisor.
Oh,
the head guy of your corrupt
organization.
Bring that fucking idiot over here.
And the like,
say,
bring that fucking idiot elsewhere.
He said,
yeah,
he was.
He was dangerously close to getting
arrested.
He came with me to vegas and he was
dangerously close to it all going down.
You should have recorded that,
joe.
I was scared.
I didn't want to go down to I don't want
to go down with them and I was trying to
think of who could open for me in Vegas,
what am I going to be able to call last
minute?
He's getting fucking arrested.
You want to sit there and I don't
understand that.
When something amazing is happening that
all of a sudden you take out a camera
and start filming it.
Now it's like you watch it on this small
screen.
It's like you have a life license.
Well you don't.
You just hold it up and still watch it
at the same time.
Yeah,
hold it like that.
But you're going to check the thing
that's just,
you know,
I guess.
But I would like to have had that video.
When did you have liked to have seen it?
Right now we going to watch it.
You know,
if you know how to tell a story,
you can paint a picture of it.
Like you guys kind of know what that
dude looked like.
You in them.
And I told her it was like a fucking
eight,
nine minutes story.
Alright calls them all thieves.
Thieves are all thieves.
They,
there's still things they still drink,
which they occasionally do,
but you know what,
that's because most of them are just
regular folks work in Shitty jobs and
how many people listen to this podcast
right now goes,
this motherfucker clears throat one more
time believing ladies and gentlemen,
I don't want to be doing that.
I'm sorry.
But uh,
you know,
right before nine slash 11 I was going
through lax and I was like taking a red
eye and a James Brown was on the radio
that,
that get opened up and the girl was
sitting there dancing and singing the
song and I fucking shot or a look and I
think she thought I was looking at her
in a racist way.
I was more looking like,
do you understand that?
Like my life is in your hands and you're
sitting over here fucking sliding across
the floor,
what the fuck are you doing?
And then a few weeks later that bullshit
happened.
Oh,
Tsa person was doing that.
Yeah,
defiantly singing the song staring at me
because she,
she caught my vibe.
Like what are you doing?
And then a few weeks later,
nine slash 11 happens and then they got
all these guys.
Remember they had the fucking guys with
the.
It looked like we were in Israel for a
second.
Now those guys have gone away and that's
the exact same jerk offs.
You know that all jerk offs.
But there's enough dead weight come on
Tsa.
You know,
there's some people that shouldn't be on
this squad.
There's enough like,
well they don't get paid that much.
I mean if you're going to get people
that work for essentially the same wages
that someone does and they work pretty
fast,
that's exactly.
That's really truly gave a shit about
your safety.
They would get who that guy on my plane
was pretending to be.
They.
They would get that guy in red wood.
Stand down.
What you would feel that Desert Eagle
vibe.
They do.
No.
What did they care?
They care is exactly as much as they
have to and if it costs them more to
make you more safe and not really
interested in it,
what they're interested in doing is
spend the minimum amount of money to get
people to shut the fuck up and the
reality is you're not going to get a lot
of fucking attacks.
You're going to get an occasional one
every decade or so.
We're going to have some shit go down
and you could make
fuck load of profit.
I'm more concerned that they're now
outsourcing.
I saw,
you know,
once again saw this,
didn't research what are they
outsourcing or bringing in an Indian
people
just so many miles.
You have to rebuild the jet engine.
They're outsourcing it outside of this
country and the FDA can't regulate it.
Yeah,
that's all good.
I saw a great video on youtube and on a
jet engine forks to suck,
squeeze,
Bang.
Blow that what it's called works.
That's the principal's suck in the air.
You compress it and then you mix it with
the jet fuel and it fucking explodes and
into how you get your thrust.
We started to learn through learn shit
and that's how it makes clouds to right,
and it goes through the atmosphere,
picks it up to that video.
Yet those cloud trails where they to
conspiracy theories think that they're
spraying us.
They're spraying this man.
Look at the clouds and this guy,
man.
I know,
I know a guy who uh,
said to a girl was talking about that
shit.
Chemtrails.
I don't know what his name.
Yeah.
Chem trails was talking about that shit.
And this girl's got.
You're crazy.
So one day you looked up and there was
these weird fucking tic tac toe shit and
the sky that you hadn't seen before.
And he just texted her the next day he
goes,
yeah,
look up.
Well that was hilarious.
What?
That's fight flight patterns.
Oh Jesus,
come on.
Well that's what it is.
It's like,
it is.
You don't know what it is neither the
wise I looked into it.
Yeah,
because I'm tired of arguing with Eddie
Bravo.
Which wing of the Pentagon did you walk
from the UFC?
Come on in.
I talked to pilots,
Bill Burr.
So what the Pio explained to me exactly
what it is,
what causes do you know how fucking
annoying it is to someone who doesn't
fly a plane to come up as the same
person?
Like somebody in the crowd going.
So like how do you get your material?
Do you trying to get Jujitsu guy friend
of mine.
There's a pilot.
Alright.
I'm too far into this to say you're
right.
Here's my comments as it criss cross.
Why is it always go in the same
direction and they're fucking spray
this.
Aren't they down here too?
That's the problem with spraying.
No,
but I heard it long as you up.
They put the president in time.
Those sprays going on Air Force One.
It's in the air.
There's so many levels under the White
House.
They don't even stay in there.
They have like,
you know,
look alikes.
Microchips.
Did you remember when after September
11th when Dick Cheney was always in the
bunker.
It was in an undisclosed location in the
Remember that?
He rubbed it out in there.
I don't think it's hard work.
Good enough for him to rub one out.
Probably.
Probably that's probably how I blew his
heart out.
Probably overdosed on by Agron fucking
blood ticker.
Scary.
If you're a.
If you're a on nitrates that you're not
allowed to have.
My Agora,
the Viagra fucks with guys that have
heart problems.
They take dictate like nitrogen,
Nitroglycerin,
pills and nitrates.
Apparently that stuff mixed together.
I know a guy where he had like major
health problems and he had to get his
stomach stapled so.
And he was using Viagra and they said
you can't use this stuff because the
medicine he was taking for whatever else
he had,
they said like,
it's,
it's thinning
thins out your blood if you know,
if you have sex,
I don't know,
like the blood's going to rush out of
your head or whatever.
Okay.
And you're gonna fucking die.
This is true.
Like I'm just stupid to remember what he
said.
Right.
So he's like,
I was like,
doc,
you know,
if I,
I can't fuck,
I don't want to live.
This is the guy's like,
all right,
there is one way you get.
You can do it when you take the Viagra.
Okay.
You have to be on the bottom and you
have to be laying down.
It's all about standing up so it doesn't
fucking rush down.
So you've got to lay down and you can
have this girl ride you,
but you have for four hours.
You have to lay in this bed.
And he's like,
done,
I'm doing it.
This is how much this guy like,
he goes,
I can't get a pussy.
I don't want to live.
Right.
So he's fucking lay in and this girl
rides him and he lays there for four
hours,
has no fucking problem.
This,
this,
this thing.
And then he starts getting cocky.
Three and a half hours,
three hours that's going on the
computer.
Sometimes it gets up to early and he's
getting light headed and shit.
And he goes,
I didn't think anything about it.
And uh,
he fucking was walking up a flight of
stairs and it just went black and he was
fucking unconscious.
And the only thing that saved him was he
fell backwards down the stairs and his
legs were pulling it up and the blood
came down.
At that point,
my fucking career banging.
It's over
and this guy,
I'll tell you who you know,
the guy,
I'll tell you who it is like you know
afterwards and have him tell you the
story.
Is it Ralphie?
May,
Huh?
No,
no.
That didn't sound like Ralphie did it.
That was like Ralphie and witness
protection.
No,
I'm just,
I just threw a guy out there and try to
get you to tell me who was it,
Jay more.
I'll tell you.
He had to get his stomach staple.
Jade.
A little beer.
Wait,
that was it.
He got it off.
You know who was it?
I'm not sure I would know him.
No,
you know,
actually I don't.
I'm not sure that you would know a
Boston guy.
Why are you going to Indianapolis,
Joe?
I'm telling jokes with Tony Hinchcliffe.
We're going to be at the theater April
sixth.
I'm alright man.
You don't have to tell me who the fuck
it is.
That stomach stapling thing though.
Air.
I'll wait.
I'll wait when I'm outside thunder dome
here.
I'll tweet the results.
The um.
No,
I wouldn't do that to.
Yeah you would.
I wouldn't,
I wouldn't.
No.
I contacted rise a close.
They were,
you want me to turn off the podcast
member when it used to kiss my camera,
you're,
you'd be like Brian,
turn off the camera and that really
meant Brian Act like you're turning off
the camera.
But it got to the point where I would
just act like I kissed the camera.
I'm like,
okay,
it's off now.
And no one really caught it to any
anybody sketchy that wanted to like hide
some information.
Door cameras on hog checks in the mail
site is secure.
That's the new vista.
New a check's in the mail.
This,
this site is totally secure with those
hacker fuckers isn't.
Nothing's ever secure anymore.
The guy who built it has some sort of
backdoor.
That's how he gets pussy the back door.
The back door
happened with us at a,
on it,
at the audit.com
is we uh,
hired a guy to do some coding for us,
for the,
um,
like a gift certificates and stuff like
that for the website and to set it up so
you can gift people things.
So this guy decided to outsource the
coding.
So we didn't even know we thought that
this guy who was a reliable guy was
going to do the coding,
but what he did was he got his online
friend from Vietnam,
gave him the password to the,
to the servers and allowed him to do the
coding and this guy went in and just
started downloading all the credit card
information and so the FBI we had to
bringing the FBI to find out and it went
through this guy and we found out that
that's apparently like super common
because if you're paying this guy x
amount per hour,
he can go to Vietnam and say,
Hey vic,
my Vietnamese friend,
I'll give you a,
you know,
half that you do all the work so it's
got kicks back,
collects fat checks,
doesn't do a goddamn thing.
That's apparently super common.
This outsourcing.
Yeah.
That's why you never never used your
debit card ever.
Really.
It's your money.
Something happens.
That's you.
That's almost to a credit card.
Credit card.
That's the house's money.
I'm not saying to rack it all the way
up.
I got a buddy,
might've prosecutes identity theft and
this is some real shit.
This is real talk.
Yo.
I'll always use,
always use.
If someone's going to double swipe it,
you want it to be their money,
so then they call up and they're like,
did you get a lap dance in Toronto?
No,
I did not have fun with that Shit.
I'm out.
If you use your debit card now they got
you.
They got your card and then it's like
you have to go down to the fucking bank
and be like,
I didn't spend 65 bucks at an auto zone
and all of that shit and you have to.
You have to go.
Rather than it being a quick phone call,
you have to go through all of this
bullshit.
So it's still protected by the Visa
Card.
That's why the visa card logos on there.
So the same rules apply.
Well protected.
It's if it's not good,
I just.
One of those things I don't want to fuck
with.
I mean if you want to do it that way,
absolutely.
It's definitely better to do it through
American Express or someone,
a phone call.
I know it was.
Somebody had it recently.
They had to go down to the bank bag
and I'm just so fucking lazy.
My identity.
Jesus Christ,
I don't want go down to the bag.
I got mine.
I know what happened with me.
It was at a gas station because I didn't
use it for anything else.
And then all of a sudden I started
getting these messages were they were
saying or were you buying chocolate?
And I was like,
what?
That's like,
yeah,
it was good dive a chocolate,
uh,
like gift certificates for like 100
bucks,
500 bucks.
I'm like,
not that special.
It's like a lot.
It was like $500 with chocolate.
You're trying to get somebody's risk
going to jail or like,
you know what?
I'm going to do godiva chocolate.
Let's hit their first.
Well No.
The reason why they do that is to get
gift certificates.
That's what they were doing.
They were getting gift.
So when they get the money and then they
say,
hey man,
I'm doing the black voice and I don't
know why I go to a white guy,
hey man,
would you like $500 worth of Godiva
chocolates for 50 bucks?
And so they could sell that for 50 bucks
on Ebay.
That's another thing.
Yeah,
that's a good one too
is they use the gift certificate and
they don't use all of it and they try to
get the change back.
Can you do that?
You can in some places,
some places you could do.
Yeah,
you can.
In some places.
I've seen people do that before.
You can do that in some ways,
but a lot of ways they said no,
it's a store credit.
I got a buddy who's a lawyer whenever I
go into the time where he prosecutes
because he's the shit I,
I,
if I have time,
if you just sit there and you watch a
case,
it's,
it's fucking unreal.
Yeah.
It must be weird though,
but what have you seen?
You've seen like a real one,
like a murder case.
One I saw drug line and like it was just
fascinating because like the first guy
he brings up,
the prosecutor stewed I know was a
moron,
a fucking moron.
And he's sitting there big,
this cop idiot.
And the dude literally goes like
handsomeness.
He goes,
do you recognize this?
And he looks at the piece of paper and
he goes out,
no I don't.
And they go,
uh,
that's your police report that that's
how bad this guy was.
And I was like,
oh my God,
my buddy's going to get crushed in this
one.
But like when it was over,
he came up to me,
he goes,
how'd you like that?
And I was like,
that seemed awfully guess now,
don't worry.
He goes,
I always start off with the weakest one.
It gets the other people confident and
then it's almost like a comedy show to
start off with the fucking open
microphone.
And then they.
And then they slowly bring the new
surround and then they actually,
it was an arraignment to see if it was
supposed to go to trial.
And uh,
the dude,
they actually had enough so this guy was
going to trial and when he,
in the end he walked by and he said to
my buddy,
goes,
I'm taking this all the way,
like,
is he like,
I'm fighting this all the way to the
top.
Like it dude,
it was the sickest drama
like ever.
And there was a couple of old people in
there.
I'm like,
do they like not have cable?
And they just come down here and they're
like,
yeah,
they come down and they want.
I felt bad.
Like I'm like,
this guy could go to jail and I'm
sitting here being entertained by this.
I wanted to see like,
okay,
I'm supporting my buddy.
But like it was,
it was really like,
was fucking unreal.
It was way better than like even on the
TV.
And they wrap it up,
didn't.
She said,
you know,
when they do this stupid like,
you just yell at somebody the best to
actually see that the way that they do
do
it,
it's still,
it's what it is,
is you slow.
It's like a Boa constrictor.
Every time you exhale,
the prosecution just gets a little
tighter and tighter and you see the
person sitting at their body language.
They're all confident and 10 is an
evidence is getting introduced.
You see them start kind of sitting up.
They start doing it is fucking.
It's unreal.
Human drama,
right?
It's hard to.
Hard to deny somebody freedom.
I don't think I'll ever do it again
because I felt bad because it was.
It was unbelievably in a fucked up way
was it was riveting,
was fucking riveting.
Did you see that case with that chick
who was accused of killing her roommate
in Italy?
She was acquitted because there was some
sort of a problem with the evidence.
Now they're trying to retire and now
she's in Seattle.
They go,
we're going to.
We're going to try it again.
Come on back to Italy.
Fuck yourself.
While the United States not going to
extradite her either because of the
first case was over,
there is no way I could ever sleep again
if that happened to me and they'll
execute.
Mentioned it.
It's just a country.
Could you imagine if she actually killed
her and got away with it?
Absolutely.
Creeping around Seattle.
Well,
what if I just.
Let me just.
Let's just go with my comedy angle here.
Dude.
You're just sleeping in Seattle.
Just like Tom Hanks and Melanie
Griffith,
bless whoever.
Right?
Throwing kicks in the night.
And you just go to sleep every night
knowing this,
a country that's out to get you.
It's an entire fucking country wants to
get you.
And so they're pulling every.
It's like conversations going on in
Washington dc about you go,
come on man.
Look.
Who Do you want for this girl?
Who Do you want for Joe Rogan?
Like they're trading.
You write like a baseball card.
Alright,
you got a political prisoner.
We want for them,
but I'm not giving you phone.
I'll give you three and you're sitting
there.
Then one day that fucking van pulls up.
Dude,
I,
you know,
I would have a cyanide pill on me at
all.
Even if I was wearing a tank top,
I'd have it in a little scraps.
I just run to the ocean and swim as far
as I could afford.
Drone.
Want to grow up my own shield to
straight out,
see how far I could get.
Tried to swim to fucking Australia.
I'll do it.
You didn't have so much hate.
You fish with him.
You never.
You never leave home base.
Like you have to stay within the herd
over here.
You got to be in.
You can't be that little fucking thing
running on the side of the hurt.
Can't even go up to Canada for fucking
hockey game.
Who knows what happens when you go
through customs?
True.
Okay.
And she's right there.
I would be sitting there going like,
what have I got hammered one night and I
started driving up the five and I wasn't
paying attention and I fucking went
through customs and the recipe for
drinking and driving and then they got
some.
They're in bed with the Italians because
they don't have good pasta up there.
They fucking hook them up.
Next thing you know,
you're getting flied back in Vancouver,
Vancouver.
Okay.
Right there.
And you just,
you're in that fucking jumpsuit like.
And then you,
you know,
when you're sitting there,
all you're thinking about it was at that
schwartzenegger movie,
the raw deal where he knocked the guy
out with the elbow and then climb down
the fucking landing gear and you land in
the marsh.
Right?
Right.
That's why I would be thinking of,
is that doable?
Doable.
I know you just go like this.
You Cross your arms like this and you
just,
you jump in.
Do you ever watch any of those shows
where people have to live in the woods
like those Alaska,
the last frontier type shows we're
picking out like in 1963 snowmobile all
the way over here to get an English
muffin.
Make your own English buffet date.
They are literally burning 3000 calories
to get five,
1500.
How do you stay?
How you stay nourished?
It's very hard when it's really cold.
Now you,
you get so fucking hungry because your
body burns off so much fuel just to try
to stay warm.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
They're fucked.
Do we?
We got it.
We got to do a new exercise video.
Just parachute out of this business.
We'll just do like the Alaskan workout.
You're telling me what to do.
I'll do it now.
So what you do is you just stick people
in these extreme conditions,
like when it's snowing out near a mall.
I mean you're right near Shit.
There's an ambulance there,
but he just make him keep going up and
down the hill like as far as that guy
goes in the middle of Alaska.
You just like,
dude,
you can't come back to civilization.
That's right there.
You can literally see a JC penny,
but we're not fucking letting you back
until you go up and down this mountain a
Zillion fucking times and that you have
though.
They'll burn all that stuff and then you
take them over to the orange.
Julius [inaudible] sounds like prison.
That doesn't sound like a real workout
exercise.
Video is slowly working towards that.
Like this is stupid.
What people are doing is they're just
blowing out their joints.
Like if you just knew how to fucking
eat,
you don't have to go like,
these people are going to need hip
replacement.
You don't go on a fucking elliptical in
for an hour straight.
Do the exact same motion.
You're going to have the running the the
hips of James Brown to machines.
Not Bad for.
It's horrific.
Really.
I have momentum.
Don't fuck with me.
I never read.
I don't read.
I just don't want to give anybody any
shitty advice.
While people text,
you shouldn't have asked me what I'm all
about.
I don't think like it's bad for your
body.
Well,
let's look it up.
Let's find out everything in moderation.
It elliptical,
bad for hips.
Okay,
let's check it out.
I think the whole baby boomer
generation,
they're all getting hip replacements and
knee,
a knee replacement,
osteoarthritis of the hip and the leg.
Elliptical,
exercising.
Oh my God.
You might be onto something.
I've been told by four surgeons.
Check this out.
We'll do it.
Even the work that you're doing,
well,
you have to fucking consume a whale's
worth official oil everyday.
She can brush your teeth.
I mean,
there's got to be like,
Oh yeah,
I'm a nominal fucking shape,
but it's just like,
you know those joints got to last you
for rent.
Well,
you know what the reality is is we're
all going to be on roids soon.
They're already doing it with old people
that synergenic late at night.
When they show those guys,
that's hgh.
They just run up old people.
I'm on that.
I'm on.
I'm on human growth hormone and I'm on a
testosterone,
so are you finding your organs?
They're getting bigger.
Just can you
button your shirts anymore?
No,
no,
no.
Do you could.
If you went crazy and took like
bodybuilding size doses of that Chevy
once in a while you do is you slowly go
down and you have that private pilot
look on your face and then your wife's.
I'm already in a world of shit.
I am with.
The idea is to give your body these a
bioidentical hormones that are the same
level of the hormones when you were
young and it gets so much more energy.
I mean it's.
It's amazing how much better you feel.
It's a very controversial thing.
Some people say,
well,
you should be worried about what happens
to your body or be at the forefront of
anything,
but you're not.
People have been doing this for a long
fucking time.
Would you have to worry about as abuse,
like anything,
as long as the most important thing is
you get your blood work done,
go do it with an ethical doctor and you
can't be one of those people that the
outsource is your blood tests like that.
It's local,
but you have to worry about,
um,
it's clean.
Yeah.
You have to worry about abuse.
If a person's impulsive,
they essentially,
they'll give you this testosterone cream
that you rub on you.
If you're a nut,
he just fucking take four times that
dose and rub it on yourself and all of a
sudden you're like,
Dick's,
like a fucking crowbar.
And you're,
you're red lining your adrenal system
and your,
your,
uh,
your endocrine system.
You don't want to do that.
You want to make sure that you do
exactly what you're supposed to.
Like.
It's very minimum doses.
Like the way Keith Richards does blow.
Yeah.
He probably like legend.
Barely though.
We used to be.
I read his book,
man.
It was great.
He goes,
he goes,
I had that bad period.
And that just followed me forever.
He goes,
all these people who died,
he goes,
you don't do a line of coke and just sit
there and do another one.
He goes,
you walk around and Blah Blah.
A couple more hours.
You take another.
Like he's very,
like,
he knew how to do it.
Slashes book was another one where he,
Like he was,
you know,
some people just use comedy as a
stepping stone to get to acting.
And then there's people who just love
it.
Like I love seeing the mic stand,
you know,
when there's nobody in there and it's
lit and shit.
And I got hurt.
I love it.
Slash it gets a junkie.
Like I was reading it,
it was like he made it sound.
He goes,
I love the whole thing.
I'd love copying the stuff.
I hope I'm not misquoting,
but it was basically the gist.
I love the whole cooking it up and he's
like,
he goes,
I was really into it,
but it seemed like because you know,
it's Kinda like a guy who just sits down
and plays drums and a guy could actually
tune them and build a car,
whatever.
No,
no,
no.
You make a lot of sense.
And it's also,
I think if you're a guy who is well,
like for us stand up comics,
there's not like,
oh,
history of heroin use,
but for musicians,
Jesus Christ,
I mean how many great musicians,
Kurt cobain,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
How many great musicians also had heroin
problems.
And I think there's a connection there.
That was the guy from Alice and chains.
Layne Staley,
huge heroin addict.
I mean there's so many great musicians
that were also
chunk.
Why you would ever fuck at this point.
This just
so much evidence that's fucking terrible
for you.
Um,
I think
it's supposed to be an unbelievably
amazing feeling.
It's really fun.
I,
I can move it where he's just like,
I'm going to do it when I'm 80.
Yeah.
I feel that.
Well,
didn't,
didn't stand up.
Have a bit about something along those
lines.
Stand home.
I'm a bit about the really dangerous
drugs,
like save them for when you're like
really old.
The ones that kill people,
you know,
like when it doesn't matter anymore.
I forgot,
right.
Maybe you stand on,
but I've been told by for this,
we should go back to this elliptical
thing so people know I'm for surgeons
that looked in the x rays and say I have
osteoarthritis and need a total hip
replacement.
I'm scheduled blah,
blah blah,
blah blah.
I used to play racquetball three to four
times a week,
but I had to stop.
The question is should I have,
should I stop using the elliptical
machine?
Parental director,
director,
director.
That sounds like a pretty 16 condition.
And yeah,
this is um,
this is not what I was looking for.
Sorry.
Why you lift the machines are bad.
Okay.
Here's one that says something.
Why elliptical machines are bad for your
body hears it says popular piece of
equipment,
but it really is a elliptical machines
over arrested number of calories.
Calories burned in a workout by 31
percent.
Huh?
So they don't burn nearly as much
calories,
calories.
It's a,
I love a good school.
I just want to know if it's fucking
people up doesn't seem to be due to the
fact that you can dance during a shell
when you need like a hip replacement.
Like over the years I've just kind of
doing the same dance moves like prints
James Brown.
They needed like replacements from
dancing.
So here you are,
you're not a Hoofer prints needed a hip
replacement.
But for real,
I thought I heard that.
I really pay attention to how much shit
I say and I always clarify it with.
I can't remember who said it.
Well I know people would do that.
Has reportedly needed a double hip
replacement.
Okay.
God,
I get that.
Maybe you didn't.
What's that buddy?
Thank God God.
Just get that.
Also Lady Gaga got a hip replacement and
I heard from somebody else cause
sometimes they just say that were they.
Because they can't talk anymore.
The guy may hips fucked up.
I'm out already.
Yeah,
I'm taking off the.
I got to tell you man,
the Shit I've ever.
Yeah.
Uh,
apparently said something.
Yeah.
He's uh,
he's,
he's needed a hip replacement since
2005.
It's saying that he learned,
he avoids it.
Oh,
that's good.
Every year they get better at it and
it's like the whole hair plugs thing.
Like I've been told by doctors that he
needs a hip replacement.
Um,
the fallout from years of dancing
onstage and high heeled boots.
Yep.
Wow.
Lady Gaga cancels entire tour prepares
for hip surgery.
Well,
it might not be a replacement
replacements.
Rough for a young girl like that.
Um,
Mark Coleman,
former UFC heavyweight champion,
just had his hip replaced.
Fucking serious shit,
man.
That's a,
that's a rough one.
Apparently they know how to do it.
Got It,
got it out.
I had a buddy of mine,
we went to a game and he had handicap
plates and I thought it was like his
grandmother's car or something.
He said,
no,
I just had my hip replacement.
I was like,
where?
He was like six weeks ago.
He's just sitting there walking.
I'm like,
dude,
what the fuck?
He goes,
yeah.
I needed it like five years ago.
And the guy told me if I can tough out
the pain,
just wait.
And he did.
And uh,
that's the thing like I'm telling you as
far like the hair stuff goes,
you know,
like they're going to come up with a
pill dude.
But there's going to be a price you have
to pay if you want a full head of hair.
I think like it's,
it's like,
would you take a pill to get your hair
back?
Right?
That like they strap you down and it's
like for 90 seconds it's going to feel
like you're fucking head's on fire is
that Shit said shit grows.
But at the end you're going to have like
games
show homes it 90 seconds.
Yeah.
No,
I've been on fire.
Yeah,
I would definitely do it because first
of all,
90 seconds I would want to know like
what they think hair on fire would feel
like.
It would feel like everything else.
Everything else is so overrated.
Like what people talk about.
Like how much things hurt.
Like tattoos.
I fell asleep getting tattooed to
tattoos and not that painful.
This is about getting a butterfly and
your ass.
I've talked to my arms are sleeves.
I fell asleep.
Not Hard,
but what I'm saying is if you ask some
people,
they go,
oh my God,
it's so painful,
but it's not really that painful.
Laser Tattoo removal supposed to be more
painful than tattooing itself.
That's a,
that's a.
But I think like most people exaggerate
about what things.
As long as it didn't kill you,
I'd go,
okay.
Ninety seconds.
Not that much.
I would try just to feel it.
It feels like.
I Dunno.
Yeah,
you know,
it'd be funny is then like it would
become like if you see a bald guy who'd
be considered a pussy
because he can take 90 seconds.
Yeah.
Oh,
he's a man who accepts his feet.
Um,
when he would argue,
but you know,
all those guys with the guy,
Smiley haircut at that point,
I can talk to them in their hair,
would be given them as shit.
I don't want you to do it.
We'll do it right here at the bar with
their Patrick swayze roadhouse here to
do it.
It'd be,
it'd be like the accused,
some ballgown would finally get held
down.
They give them the college kid,
you're next.
I'm happy to do it to me in the long
run,
but there really shouldn't have done it
to me.
I'd like,
uh,
I like having my head shape now,
but I wouldn't do it now,
but they just see how you get more
active work with it.
I mean,
I've actually,
I'm not doing anything about my hair
falling out,
so eventually it's going that route.
And uh,
I just figured,
look,
I look if I was going to be a sex symbol
wouldn't happen by now.
I'm so clear.
So clearly the friend.
How will you know?
40 four over.
It's over.
There's nothing better than
acknowledging that I'm keeping the rest
of it looking good.
But what,
what the fuck are you going to do?
Well,
I didn't acknowledge it.
I had hair transplants or they take
little plastic things with hair stuck.
If you have those ones,
they take a slice out of the back of my
head.
That one?
Yeah.
You take like a trip and they put it on
the Petri dish where they just vacuum it
out.
They take one at a time,
they drop it in and see the whole.
I had a buddy of mine,
she checks you do it,
you just fucking do it.
And I sat there and watched the dude.
It is a bloody fucking doesn't mess.
Not that big a deal.
It doesn't,
doesn't hurt,
but I would say never do it for,
for two reasons.
One,
because I mean I wanted to shave my head
and I have this big stupid smile on the
back of my head,
but two,
because the just shave your fucking
head.
So it's really not that big a deal.
Once you do it,
he'd go,
why would I ever get a haircut again?
So stupid.
It's like really getting attached to
just some shit that grows out of your
head is so weird.
You know?
It's the worst one is a fucking toupee.
Like this hat you just can't take off.
Like how fucking sweaty.
Especially if you exercise like you ever
see those hair from him.
Those guys are fucking playing tennis
and Shit and run and sweat.
And what is it they just.
So it's like a weave for guys.
Yeah.
Well you're,
you're
sitting here.
Um,
uh,
I,
I was,
when I was a young man when I was
worried that I was going to go bald,
I thought about all the possibilities.
I looked into everything.
I wanted to find out what everything
was,
but the hair club for men,
one,
some of them,
they,
they're like your existing hair goes
through it.
So it's like a thing that they lay on
top of you and your hair goes through
it.
So it's some of your hair and some of
the fake hair and then they kind of like
glue it on its death.
I had a friend who had one for a long
time and then he,
uh,
he abandoned it.
So few.
I actually know quite a few people that
have had them,
but it's a,
it's a girl's fucking sweaty thing and
once you just accept it,
like you get used to the fact that you
don't have your hair anymore.
It's like,
it's so freeing.
Like once I shaved my head,
I got to the point where even though I
had hair transplants is still look like
shit.
I was like,
you know what,
the stuff in the back never comes out.
So we put it up here.
It's like,
well,
the rest of this shit is going to fall
out.
So then what's going to happen?
And also it's like,
I feel like I'm dropping this shit
behind enemy lines in the safety zone
the way I described it as like taking a
bunch of people who are really healthy
and moving them into a neighborhood
where everyone's dying.
You go,
it's like,
where's Mike?
He's dead.
But he said he's right there.
He's gone.
Yeah.
They fly off and they never come back.
The,
uh,
the,
the pills though.
When I was going to get into it was
like,
I tried propecia.
That's the shit they give you.
Um,
for your,
you know,
to,
to kill that makes your hair grow back.
It kills a whatever it is,
the testosterone bio.
But dht,
dihydrotestosterone,
dht is what apparently makes your hair
fall out.
But um,
it also kills your Dick.
Lisa didn't mind.
It's all Kinda like I,
I,
I believe in the whole.
There's no getting your cake and eat it
if you get your hair back that he got to
like,
you got something has to be taken away.
That's what I love about the overall arc
of breaking bad.
It's every thing time they get to a
level,
like this is something that loses in
this.
Another part of their soul gets like
taken away.
And I feel like that like,
dude,
you have no idea.
All these drugs.
What the fuck this is doing to your
liver?
I found out the other day,
uh,
this stuff that rhymes with tylenol pm,
I want to get you in trouble.
I heard like taking a couple of those is
like going on a three day bender.
Very bad for you.
I kind of went into the drugstore in
because I knew I needed some.
I still take it every once in a while
and they fucking,
they don't have it.
It got recalled really random,
right?
Pm.
Recall liver.
Yeah.
I'm,
I'm sure that's just fucking our friend
Tim Ferris says it best.
There's no biological free lunch.
He's like,
anything that has a profound effect on
your body's most likely having some sort
of a negative effect,
whether it's positive or negative or
just some sort of bounced back.
I love it.
I love how you can't win.
Well,
not yet,
but you know,
you think about what you can get away
with now as opposed to what you used to
be,
which is why they have those old guys
that are putting them on hgh because
that's not for us.
That's for the fucking guys up top.
They're using them as Guinea pigs.
Let's see if we can keep these guys
alive.
You'd be amazed at how many old dudes
are doing that shit.
You'd be amazed how many old rich guys
and I know that are there taking
testosterone replacement,
so I suppose it was guy was a fucking
riot.
He was talking about how many agents he
knew in Hollywood who would take,
they would take in this testosterone
shit because they thought I gave him an
edge and I was just thinking of some
roided up guy trying to get you a
fucking audition
for according to Jeff.
Listen,
listen,
motherfucker,
I need my guy to be the fucking wacky
neighbor.
My Gosh,
your guy.
I don't know.
Uh,
yeah.
Most,
most of those things are bad for you.
Even the regular Ibuprofen.
It's not so fantastic for you.
Didn't Rob Wolf Tosa?
Chip is terrible for us anyway.
Bill,
or you're the fucking man.
It was an awesome time.
It was a howl as always synonymous with
Albert.
Was it always is my brother.
Where your next work in them.
Powerful.
Going through the De,
the dirty south.
Oh,
I'm gonna go.
Uh,
let's see.
What the hell am I?
What the fuck?
That's Fridays and fifth.
Sundays is sixth,
seventh,
Athens,
Georgia.
Tenth.
I'm at the home,
Alabama.
I'm doing a theater and a South
Carolina.
But whatever.
You're capitalist Columbia,
I think.
And then I got two shows at the
Tabernacle on that Friday in Atlanta.
And take two days off in Atlanta.
Yeah.
I'm going to the masters and then I go
golf.
Golf.
Yup.
Oh,
you're a big golf fan.
I,
I'm a sports fan.
I love going there.
And I think tigers back.
He just fucking.
He looks.
So I think he's going to do what I can
do.
That's Jordan with a golf club.
Um,
and then uh,
I'm going to go on Monday night.
I got two shows at Tampa,
Tuesday,
two shows at Florida state.
And then the Wednesday I'm at the Jackie
gleason theater in Miami beach.
Billboard Dot Com.
Doing a run.
Go and check it out.
I'm the Tabernacles where I filmed my
last special.
Oh,
it is.
It's fucking great place.
Loved it.
Oh,
amazingly.
I'm Atlanta is
amazing.
It's a great town.
It's so integrated.
You know what I like about Atlanta is
like people are like black people and
white people.
You still like hanging together.
And so it seems like completely normal.
But then when you get outside of it,
it becomes the south again.
Word Bill.
Burr ladies and gentlemen,
go to Bill Bird Dot Com and go seatbelt
bill law live.
He is one of the funniest guys working
today and that is no bullshit.
I feel the same way.
It's an honor my brother and honor as
always,
shows only $5.
Oh,
you have one of our specialists to only
five bucks.
Great way to.
You know who did yours?
I did.
Oh,
you did it yourself and released it.
Uh,
okay.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and go get
that shit.
You fucks Jesus Christ.
When did that come out in a well
debuted.
I went straight to Netflix and then
after people watch it on that,
then I had to deal with like six weeks
later you could download.
Yeah.
I love Netflix.
I did my 2005 special with that man.
It was great.
It's my hbo.
I love powerful Netflix.
Go to [inaudible] dot com and go by its
support.
Support Bill Burr.
Honestly,
one of the funniest guys working today.
Bucks a month.
Yeah.
I love Netflix.
I love the shit out of him.
I love life.
I would fuck them if they were acumen
stamps.
Dot Com is one of our podcast sponsors
the newest,
latest and greatest.
If you go to stamps.com,
click on the microphone and type in J R,
e dot.
That's for the Joe Rogan experience.
I broke my scale.
Can they?
If you guys to listen to,
they'll hook you up.
They'll hook you.
Actually sending things yourself.
Do you call?
What?
Are you sending out dvds to my road
gigs.
Do you send them?
Oh,
okay.
Powerful.
Powerful bill bilber stamps.com.
Who Do you call?
I don't know.
We'll figure it out.
Just go to the store and buy one.
Why would you fuck them?
Deal with it.
We already talked about this before with
fucking the Netflix thing.
Go down to the store.com
and you didn't have to go to the spa.
They do,
I think,
but it doesn't work that way.
You should go.
They should look in your eyes and find
out if you're a fucking mess up.
Dumb.
They have that.
They have a website.
Yeah.
Stamps.com.
Use the code named J dot.
He saved yourself some money.
Your Fox there is a beautiful $110 bonus
offer includes a digital scale and up to
$55 in free postage.
Thank you.
Also to onnit.com.
If you go to o,
n I try to sneak a burp in,
but I think everybody knows if you go to
o,
n,
n I t and use the code name Rogan.
You can say yourself off 10 percent off
any and all the most delicious
supplements that we have available.
Actually some of them tastes like shit.
This t plus testosterone will tell you
right now,
this stuff tastes like shit.
So if you have something that you like
tasting,
I've been thrown into my protein drinks.
I don't do that anymore because my
protein drinks the hemp protein.
Hemp,
hemp force tastes awesome.
But t plus tastes like shit.
So I,
uh,
I drank it outside of that.
I mixed it up.
Shit.
Yeah,
carbohydrates right after working out.
I'm going the other way.
Go the other way.
No protein,
carbohydrate.
I like how you do that.
You're a contrarian.
Just blowing up folks.
We will be back,
uh,
the next podcast we have is a actually
this Saturday with a Stanley Kripner who
is a,
a psychedelic pioneer.
I'm like a really fascinating old dude.
We're going to get to talk to a guy who
was friends with Mckenna and Timothy
leary and just,
uh,
and,
and he has a lot of insight on,
on also going to reach out to Lee
majors.
Right?
We're going to try.
We're going to try on a.com
o n n I t codenamed.
Real good.
Go fuck yourselves.
Oh,
we'll see you guys on Saturday.
Big Kiss
the.