Hello
Bitches,
I want to talk for a little bit about
the cryotherapy because this is
something that I emailed you when there
was a disturbing article that was sorta
poopooing the benefits cryotherapy in
the article was I thought it was really
poorly.
Well,
poorly done,
poorly researched and it was also,
it was studied really subjective things
like how sore you felt after exercise
and whether or not benefited from that,
but yeah,
but there are real positive benefits of
Cryo therapy that are measurable.
Yes.
And that happened as well.
First of all that article that you're
referring to from that,
um,
whatever website it was,
but the article was Steve Novella is a
guy and I think what he did is he rushed
to put this article out because that
woman died in Las Vegas from Cryo
therapy and it was a really tragic
incident.
She was by herself.
There's two different types of cryo
therapy.
One of the things we should point out,
first of all,
I don't have any guys I've been accused
of this.
I should just say right now,
I don't have any vested interest in
cryotherapy.
I don't own any of it.
I don't.
I don't make any money from it.
Nothing.
I enjoy the benefits of it and I use it,
but this woman who did it,
she did the type.
There's two kinds.
One of them goes from the neck down,
so you stand in this booth.
Your head is above breathing and normal
oxygen,
but below you is liquid nitrogen.
You can't read that stuff in.
That's why your head is not under.
If you do breathe that stuff in,
you don't have any oxygen.
You'll black out and that's what
happened to her.
She did it by herself.
It was poorly set up and apparently she
was quite short so her head was kind of
below the the the limit where you're
supposed to be.
So she was breathing in the liquid
nitrogen and she fell asleep and blacked
out.
So you get one of those times I thought
she was in like,
no,
no.
The full on ones are much rarer and what
the full on ones do is they super cool
the air with the nitrogen.
So the air itself is pumped in really
cool.
What I did,
that's what you did and that's what
we're gonna do today too,
if you have the time.
I love that.
Okay,
let's do that one.
You can breathe in.
It's just fucking unbelievably cold.
Okay.
So the one that she did was she set up
by herself,
which you're never supposed to do.
You're always supposed to have
supervision.
So it wasn't whether or not.
I mean she's the only person I've ever
heard of this died from this.
And it's a horrible trash committing
suicide.
No,
no.
She was just worried there.
And sometimes women will,
um,
they'll put their face under it because
they want the effects of a cryo facial
[inaudible].
Cryo facial has been shown to improve
Collagen and
flattens your therapy actually prevents
it.
Stopped.
It inhibits enzymes that break down
collagen called college and is.
And that's actually part of the reason
it helps with arthritis.
Arthro College Nase is break down
Collagen and they break down like,
you know,
the tendons college and around the
tendons and seven,
it can cause arthritis,
arthritic pain.
So doing it would make sense why you'd
want to do something cryo because it.
It would have an effect.
Right?
I understand.
Yeah.
Women love it when they get their face
done.
Apparently get or
vein men to or any man.
Hello,
you don't have to be vain to college.
But the point being that article came
out and all these people were saying,
oh see,
I told you cryotherapy was bullshit.
I'm like,
oh my God,
what a Piss poor article.
And it was all talking about soreness
and one of the things that he said that
really drove me crazy was you.
You'd get just as much benefit from a
cool down and stretch after a workout.
I'm like,
tell that to these fucking people that I
see that go there all the time,
that do it twice a day because they have
severe arthritis and it's the only thing
that's given them any form of,
of,
of freedom,
of movement of their hands.
I know a bunch of people that go there
that have had some really debilitating
arthritis and this has given them relief
where nothing else was given it to them
other than like pretty severe
pharmaceutical drugs or Ibuprofen at
high levels or what you were talking
about,
like there's a lady that goes to my
thing,
but she was raving about how she can
finally stretch your hands out.
Like her hands had been locked in this
position for years.
Yeah,
it has.
I mean the,
the cold itself is a hormetic stressor
that is activating a variety of
antiinflammatory pathways,
antioxidant pathways.
You know,
and it's also last time I think on the
podcast we talked about,
it increases norepinephrine,
norepinephrine itself.
It can.
So cryotherapy and cold water immersion
are two forms of cold exposure.
Cryotherapy just two minutes at like a
minus 180 Fahrenheit can increase
norepinephrine.
Twofold.
That's twofold over what you were before
you went in and nor epinephrin.
In addition to the brain benefits we
were talking about how it makes you feel
good,
how it helps with learning.
It also is a very potent anti
inflammatory,
so it inhibits the production of TNF
Alpha,
which is very.
It's kind of like in arthritis,
tnf Alpha is kind of like going haywire.
You're making too much tnf Alpha,
and what happens is tnf alpha is a
signaling molecule to or your immune
cells that says,
hey,
there's an infection here because that's
normally what happens when you release
Tnf Alpha is because there's some
bacteria or some something that you need
to kill.
And so your immune cells,
all they see is the signal.
They don't know what's causing it.
They don't know that it's because your
gut cells and your immune cells in your
gut are seeing bacteria because of your
poor diet or whatever.
And so that's getting into the
bloodstream and causing chronic
inflammation.
It doesn't know that it.
All it knows is that this means there's
a threat.
And so they start to increase the
production of your immune cells make
hypochlorite,
which is like bleach.
So you're making bleach in your body to
kill things.
And that's happening chronically.
That's gonna cause some tissue damage.
It's going to cause pain.
Um,
it also,
they also make hydrogen peroxide.
You make that your immune cells will
make that so cryotherapy inhibits the
signaling molecule so that your immune
cells quiet down because now they're not
seeing that signal that says,
come on,
hey,
fire up,
fire up.
It's not there.
So that's a good thing to inhibit tnf
alpha.
And like I said,
with the college and a's as well.
Um,
but there are so many.
I did,
you know,
I just spent two weeks just researching
and reading.
I've been doing some cold exposure,
you know,
like cold shower and also jumping in the
ocean ice bath.
And I really liked the cryotherapy,
um,
that I did last time we were here and
uh,
you know,
so I've,
I've been very interested in it,
like understanding why you feel so good.
And so I did some reading on it and
there's so many different positive
hormetic benefits from doing
cryotherapy.
So you have,
you know,
the,
the anti-inflammatory part and this,
and this also,
it's been shown that doing like 10
sessions of cryotherapy in a row,
it increases the expression of
glutathione reductase by twofold.
And another glue of that fly on related
enzyme glutathione peroxidase by like 68
percent.
And these are these enzymes like you
could be taking all the liposomal
glutathione you want,
like it's not going to matter if you
don't have the enzyme's active to use
it.
So you can take lyposomal glutathione
and that's great.
You're increasing your,
you make glutathione inside of
yourselves.
But,
um,
we,
we can't make as much of it as we get
older,
but if you take it and you don't have
the enzymes that use it to actually do
the good stuff active that it doesn't
matter.
So cryotherapy was shown to activate to
different glutathione related enzymes,
which is pretty awesome.
So it would enhance your body's ability
to absorb glutosiome no,
it doesn't enhance your body's ability
to absorb it.
It enhances your body's ability to use
it right off the bat and then you're
using cryotherapy.
It would enhance it.
Um,
so what I'm saying is that the lyposomal
glutathione that you take,
all that does is increase glutathione
inside of yourselves.
Gludethyon inside of your cells does
nothing without enzymes that use it to,
uh,
to basically sequester damaging
inflammatory things.
And the cryo therapy increased,
activates the enzymes that use it.
So it's like,
great,
I have all this food with Iowa and
sitting around on myself that I've been
taking and I also now have the enzymes
that use it to do good stuff now are
being turned on that.
What was very interesting is that it
took like multiple sessions before,
before those got like 10 to 2010 and one
at least 10 and yeah.
And then the other study was 20.
So it was it consecutively at 10 days in
a row.
Yeah,
10 days in a row.
But the first day I didn't do it.
So that,
that was also very interesting.
So it's almost like your body is saying,
okay,
this crazy fuck of them.
And do data response.
Yep.
Yeah.
Your body's preparing for war.
It's like a,
it's stressful.
It's a stressful response.
The other thing that's really cool that
we didn't talk about last minute podcast
is the thermogenic effect when you,
when you release Nora norepinephrine.
So that's,
I keep going back to that because it's
like you can't refute that.
Steven Novella,
no one know debunker,
no skeptic,
no,
I don't care who you are.
You can't.
It's just,
it's consistent in every type of cold
exposure period.
It's,
it's,
it's consensus.
You release norepinephrine will.
There always seems to be some sort of a
rationalization with a lot of the
debunking.
Like whether it's the benefits of
exercise,
whether it's the benefits of
cryotherapy.
That's almost like a rationalization for
not doing it.
It's like you're looking for an excuse
to not do it and not really very
objective that was,
which was disturbing about it.
It's like this is like you're poopooing
something that's often people grape.
Yeah,
I,
it was clear.
I mean after I especially,
especially after I did the two weeks of
research.
I mean I think there's a kind of
mentality when you're.
Sometimes people like to think I'm a
deep thinker and I'm not,
I am.
I am intentionally.
Like.
Because if you get in this mentality of
always debunking something,
you're,
it's like the spiral and you can't see
the good.
Like you can't keep an open mind to like
get past.
You're like,
what's in your box that you know?
And that's very dangerous.
I think that blind spot it is.
And there are a lot of scientists that I
know they're very smart,
extremely smart,
but they are in that loop where it's
like just they have to debunk and
criticized and it's like,
you know,
at some point huge discoveries are made
by like connecting the dots and like
getting past that like,
I mean you have to be critical.
Being critical is very important,
but you also like,
I think there's a certain threshold
where you just start to like,
you know,
you get to this like spiral,
but well it was also was infuriating
about this as the data's out there.
This is not like,
it's not like there's no data.
It's like he made a cursory examination
of the evidence and what he chose to
focus on was it was so subjective.
It was focused on a study that tested
muscle soreness,
posts,
exercise with cryotherapy.
Well,
actually the study that he referred to
as a Meta analysis,
and it was subjective,
but it actually came to the conclusion
that there were benefits,
however it said more studies that needed
to be done because there wasn't large
enough sample sizes and the quality of
data was poor because there were not
double blinded placebo controlled
clinical trials and I have to say to you
so that,
so they're actually what he resided in
that article.
There was a positive effect of the cow,
but the problem is is that because they
followed it up with,
oh well it's poor quality,
basically poor science.
The reality is is that you can't do a
double blinded placebo controlled,
controlled trial with cryotherapy.
Like you're going to be cold and they're
gonna be putting this chamber where
there's like cold or you're not and
you're gonna know,
you know.
So anyways,
I thought that was ridiculous.
I just like whatever.
I'm in Oregon,
I'm gonna.
I'm going to read about this stuff
because I know I've experienced it.
There's definitely something going on
and one of the things that happens is
the norepinephrine and when you
released,
when you released that norepinephrine,
it activates a pathway in,
inside of your cells,
um,
that basically our causes,
your energy metabolism,
metabolism to ramp up because you're
trying to generate heat,
you want basically your body wants to
heal.
Your body is saying,
I don't want to die,
I need to make heat.
And so a couple of ways it can do that.
One,
it can shiver and shivering is when your
muscles start to contract and that it
requires energy for your muscles to like
twitch.
It's very,
it's not very thermodynamically
favorable.
So you,
it's not a good way to generate heat but
you generate heat because you have to
like ramp up to twitch.
But then what happens after you've been
exposed?
And actually this happens to me because
we did the crowd twice.
The first time I did it,
I was shivering.
The entire time I was shivering.
It was really crazy because I've never
shivered like that in my life.
But the second time I went in I did not
shiver.
And after reading about it,
what happens is your body quickly adapt
so you adapt.
And what happens is non shivering
thermogenesis,
so the nor epinephrin causes your
Mitochondria,
which are the energy producing little
organelles inside of yourselves,
what causes them in your,
in your adipose tissue to like get
activated.
And it does this by increasing the
expression of a gene called UCP,
one which basically freaks your
mitochondria out because your
mitochondria are kind of like batteries,
they're charged,
they have a negative charge on the
inside and a positive charge on the
outside.
Will you see p one totally uncouples
that so that there's no more charge.
And that charge is very important
because when that charge is there,
your body knows,
okay,
I've been making energy because the way
you make the charge is by making energy.
So when the charge goes away,
your body's like,
oh my God,
I know energy.
So it just starts to ramp up fat
metabolism.
So it does that and you start to make
more mitochondria.
So you're,
you're making more mitochondria in your
fat cells.
And this is often called Brown fat.
Um,
so you can actually,
the reason it's called Brown fat is
because when you look at a fat cell
under the microscope,
if it has more Mitochondria,
then it looks Brown,
so you actually start to burn fat and
you have this thermogenic because you're
burning fat.
It's creating heat as a byproduct so
you're warming your body,
but it has this nice side effect of
burning fat,
which people like.
And the more you expose yourself to the
cold,
the more you're browning your fat,
the more you're increasing those
mitochondria,
your fats,
which means the next time you're in the
cold,
you can tolerate it longer.
So people that have been exposing
themselves to cold,
like yourself,
when you're doing the Cryo,
you know,
often you actually can tolerate the
colder for longer periods of time
because you have more mitochondria in
your fat cells.
And this allows you to then generate
more heat.
So,
and this has been shown in people,
people that have been exposed to a cold,
that they have been shown to increase
their,
um,
Brown adipose tissue.
But like 38 percent,
if they're exposed to 10 days of 50
degree air,
like outside air,
just regular air,
50 degrees all day,
10 days.
So like six hours a day out and like,
you know,
New York in the winter or fall,
I don't know,
something like that being out there for
six hours for 10 days in a row.
Men were able to increase their brown
adipose tissue by like 38 percent or
something like that.
Why people from the east coast or from
the northeast?
The move to California and then they go
back during the winter,
they go home.
My blood gut too thin was really is
there really is like a physical factor
of your body not being accustomed to
dealing with Colebra.
You adapt,
you adapt.
And that's what Brown adipose tissue.
And that's really one cold.
How cold got really popular.
Popularized because people wanted to use
it as a hack to lose weight,
you know?
So they were like,
Oh,
if I do these cold showers,
I use it for the brain benefits because
I noticed I feel really good and also
more focused.
So I like that.
And a lot of people I've talked to have
felt the same way.
Um,
but then I think the other part of this
article was the,
the effects of it blunting some of the
strength training and you know,
I talked about this in this report that
I wrote or the in the podcasts that I
released and it's so complicated I had
to like sit there and literally just
read for like two weeks to try to figure
it out because you know,
the problem is that exercise is a
hormetic stress.
Cold is a hormetic stress.
So exercise itself,
you need some of the inflammation,
you need the bad stuff to get the good
stuff.
That's how it works.
But you know,
the inflammation that's happening
happens while you're exercising and up
to one hour after,
one hour after.
That's when the whole hormetic response
kicks in.
And this has been shown in multiple
studies.
One hour seems to be when the anti
inflammatory response kicks in.
So you've generated the implementation
and then now you've got the
antiinflammatory effects.
If you do a cold exposure within that
hour after exercising,
it's possible.
You may blunt some of the inflammatory
effects that the exercise is inducing
because the cold is activating anti
inflammatory genes too early.
Now I don't know that for certain,
but I do know that this study that
showed there was one study that showed
strength training.
If you did it,
there were,
if you did see cryotherapy immediately,
like immediately after a Cold War,
it was actually cold water immersion,
which is not the same as the Cryo cryo
chamber that it blended some of the
anabolic I'm signaling.
And so there was like some of the muscle
mass was,
was not gained,
but you know,
there's other studies that have been
done that have shown for some reason.
All the insurance guys,
they always wait an hour.
It's kind of weird.
So what I'm wondering is if people that
are doing this research like sit down,
take a step back,
you know,
people are always in this.
I got to publisher to publish,
you know,
was a real big publisher parish
mentality in science where it's like
your bread and butter depends on your
publishing and so you're just constantly
trying to get that data out there.
But you really,
I think things are so complicated just
to sit down and take a look at
everything that's out there and start to
go wait a minute,
there's lots of little details that need
to be considered to design this trial
correctly.
So I'm hoping that at least for those
people doing strength training,
that they'll do one where they actually
wait until an hour because there's been
other studies where there that um,
strength to strength training in
combination with cryotherapy done much
later.
Even the next day.
There are actually benefits,
performance benefits.
Like they were able to do more of those
leg curl things.
I don't know what they called leg
extensions.
Those,
you know.
So,
you know,
I,
I don't really know what's going on but
at what I do know is that it seems as
though it's very likely that doing the
cryotherapy like immediately after and
now.
Then again,
if you're,
if you're talking about someone that's
doing,
like there's been studies that have been
published showing that people that are
doing two bouts of exercise.
So they're like riding a bike and then
they,
they're waiting,
whatever.
Our 30 minutes and then they go and run
or something.
If they do cold water immersion in
between those,
they actually have performance
enhancements,
but you know,
if they,
if they wait,
I'm sorry,
I have to do it between two bouts of
exercise.
Some of that's due to the fact that
cold,
the cold water,
it seems to improve heart rate
variability.
It's actually been shown to improve it
by like two to three fold.
So heart rate variability is the change
in oscillation between heartbeats and
it's also,
um,
people,
people judge a,
the heart recovery from a workout.
So as soon as you're done with an
intense workout,
the ability of your heart rate to lower
immediately within minutes,
that's like a marker of heart rate
variability.
And it's supposed to be good because
you're able to deal with these stressful
changes,
you know,
because when you're making cortisol or
something,
your heart starts racing more or some of
these other stress hormones.
Uh,
so it's been shown to improve that.
And,
and having,
being able to have your heart rates
slower right after a workout and then
immediately going into a workout again,
you can imagine there would be a
performance enhancement with,
with that.
So there's also,
there's a difference in the,
the physiological response between cold
water immersion and Cryo therapy,
right?
Well,
it depends,
you know,
if you're there,
there are differences in the ability for
those two different modalities to
extract heat from the body,
know if we're talking about submerging
ourselves and cold water up to our
shoulders.
Um,
water or ice is a much better.
It's much better at extracting heat from
the body than error.
Um,
but surface area also plays a role and
the end,
the temperature change.
So if you're sitting in cold water
that's 57 degrees,
um,
that's not as cold as going into a minus
180 or whatever crowd chamber.
But you can also sit in the cold water
for a lot longer.
So I to do it for 15 minutes.
I think that there has been a study that
compared the norepinephrine release,
20 seconds at 40 degree water up to the
shoulders is comparable to two minutes
at a minus standard,
something one 80 minus one 84,
no epinephrin,
but a lot of these effects are mediated
from Nora Norepinephrine,
but listened for 20 seconds at 40 to
reverse those two minutes.
So imagine,
imagine staying in the water for five
minutes in that and this has been shown,
so if you have someone that stays in
water 57 degree water for an hour,
they increased their norepinephrine by
fivefold instead of twofold.
So you have a more robust response so it
could be good,
but it could be bad if you're talking
about doing it right after a strength
training session and jumping into cold
water for five minutes.
That could.
That could have some very potent anti
inflammatory effects.
So the best way to handle it would be to
wait at least an hour,
I think.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
What about anti inflammatory markers in
the blood?
So there happened studies that have
shown that cryotherapy lower c reactive
protein,
which would be an inflammatory marker,
and then the glutathione related enzymes
going up and also superoxide dismutase,
that would be a marker for inflammation
because there's also a decrease
inflammation when you have more of
those.
So,
so cryotherapy does.
And then also,
um,
there's been mark measurements of TNF
Alpha going down.
Like I said,
I'm also another marker that macrophages
release macrophage inhibitory protein or
something,
some inflammatory molecule that's made.
There's less of it when you,
when Cold War,
I can't remember if it was cold water
immersion or cryotherapy,
but it's cold exposure.
So.
And that was mediated through north and
ignore epinephrin mediates a lot of
stuff.
It's,
it's mediating the brain effects.
It's meeting in thermogenesis,
it's antiinflammatory,
it's anti-pain.
People get injected with norepinephrine
and their spine to alleviate a pain.
Yes,
because it's anti-inflammatory.
Wow.
Jesus.
There's probably other things going on
as well.
So science just science,
just the hard science.
There's plenty of evidence that there's
benefits to crow therapy.
Oh yeah.
So why would need write an article like
that?
I'm,
like,
I said,
there's the,
there's the bad article that was the
anabolic blunting effects which was done
immediately after exercise,
which made a huge splash because it's
like,
Whoa,
you're right,
your gains.
And then you have the,
the,
the hardcore,
very skeptical people that are like,
well,
the quality of data,
you know.
Well the thing is,
is that there's a large body of data and
sometimes if you can't have a double
blinded placebo controlled trial,
then you have to look at mechanism.
You have to look at animal studies
combined with human studies.
You have to understand what's going on.
You can't refute the norepinephrine.
And we know that in orbit difference
doing all these things,
you know.
So I think you just have to be very
comprehensive,
especially when the,
when you know,
there's the argument that the,
there's no placebo controlled trials are
too subjective,
but there's lots of ways that it's not
subjective.
And this has been measured in people.
People have measured c reactive protein,
they've measured these enzyme
activities,
they've measured these inflammatory
molecules and people also when animals,
you know.
So I,
I'm confident when I say that there are
absolutely health benefits from doing
cold exposure for your brain,
anti-inflammatory,
for,
um,
for thermogenesis.