Boom,
and we live.
What happened?
He took your hat off you go and getting
crazy.
Trying to feel,
you know,
I want to feel at home.
It's that west coast.
Marijuana due to hits you hard.
Right?
That's hard and fast rule.
It's no joke.
Yeah,
it's chemists or whatever they are
buying estes fucking science dorks.
They've done a good job.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
It's not even the same thing anymore.
No,
it's,
it's a uh,
it's a,
it's,
it's Gmo all the way.
Yeah.
It's like,
Hey,
you guys tested this on people?
Yeah.
It's crazy.
I'm like,
I know you took the seeds out of
watermelon,
but what the fuck did they do that?
I don't know.
How did that even happen?
I just read that a Barbara streisand
cloned her dogs.
Did you read that or heard about that?
Jamie told me like the weirdest thing.
She has two dogs from one.
That's weird.
It made two clones of her favorite dog.
That is like the polar opposite of adopt
don't shop.
Yeah.
It's like you can't get any further.
It costs like $100,000.
Oh my gosh,
it does.
She can't have a different shape.
It's impossible.
It can't be a different dog.
So possible.
Yeah,
it's a.
it's a weird.
It's a weird move to fuck man.
If you really believed that personality
comes from that,
if it's the same thing,
like if it just looks the same or you
don't want it to just look the same,
do you know?
It's supposed to be an identical clone
of your original doctor,
so it really kind of would really
stupid.
What if it's your favorite dog?
Shit all over the place.
Walking into walls where we've got bad
news.
It doesn't have an asshole.
It just didn't work all the way where we
go to the way it looks like 94 percent
of your dog and then you know it's
missing an asshole.
It's 30 percent as smart as your last
dog,
which is pretty good because your last
dog was a genius.
Also,
there's another dog attached to it
that's walking in the different
direction,
so it's eventually going to pull each
other apart.
But for now,
now you got six to eight weeks with
these weird to speak for a hundred
grand.
You could just go to the pound.
The fruit there is.
I have a story that I do my act about a
pound dog that I had.
I had a pound dog.
They killed one of my dogs.
Wow.
Pound dogs are tricky man.
You know,
you get a dog that's been in like a
shelter for a long time sometimes.
They were in there for months.
They come out highly aggressive and I'm
like my,
some of them my dog,
but I got her.
I mean she's 13 now,
but when I got her she was a puppy,
you know,
and they found she was a stray puppy.
She's a little black lab,
like just wandering in the Bronx and I
got her probably like three days after
they found her.
What age do you think a dog would have
to be like,
you got to imagine like a certain amount
of abuse that a dog suffers early and
it's life before it gets to the pound
has got a really fuck with his head.
Right?
I think there's dogs that you get at the
pound,
you're essentially like taking on and
abused organism.
It's not ugly.
It's not just that it doesn't have a
home is that it might've been in dog
fights,
like I'm pretty sure that mine,
either it's family was in dog fights or
it was in a dog fight and there's,
you know,
people around you that are probably
kicking you and beating you or.
Yeah.
Or you're tied up for hours at a time.
Like,
you know,
you have no free.
I mean who knows,
but I do think dogs can be
rehabilitated,
but I do think it takes.
You have to have a look to even have a
dog be a good dog like that.
Like I have,
I have,
when I had my puppy,
like I worked with my dog so much and
she's a great dog.
Like I could walk in New York City
without a leash.
Just follows me.
She's really is.
She's amazing.
That's amazing.
But I worked so hard.
And then if you add to that,
you have to first like,
you know,
like a brainwash them or get them over
the anxieties they have.
Like there are certain dogs that just
hate men because obviously in their
former home and was an abusive man in
the house and you know,
they react differently to men than
women,
you know.
Sure.
Yeah.
You mean you never know.
A dog can't tell you what it's seen?
Nope.
I had one dog that I adopted choose too,
and she had mange all over her body,
like all over her body.
And she looked terrible man.
And they caught her.
I'm eating out of garbage cans in front
of this family's house that rescues
pitbulls.
And uh,
I took her in and like within a month
she had hair on her body.
She looked great.
She was healthy,
sweetest dogs,
sweetest dog with people.
But if another dog got too close,
she would fuck that dog up there.
It was like,
she was like,
protecting what she had.
It was real.
It was real hard to have an aggressive
like,
pound dog yet.
And uh,
depending on the dog.
But it is like the thing I would always
tell people to try to do first because I
am a big like adopt,
don't shop guy.
Like if you go to a dog pound you could
find some amazing where I got my dog if
you go,
which like animal care and control in
New York City,
like they euthanized like 100 dogs a
day.
Like it's literally just like the dogs
are coming in all the time.
Dogs with stab wounds,
dogs they find in the park half day and
then they like,
they have five days in that pound and
then they're out.
So it's like I was when I was there,
this is again,
like 13 years ago,
but when I was getting my dog and I was
waiting to pick her up,
this woman came in with two rottweilers,
beautiful rottweilers and unleashes.
And she goes,
I don't want these anymore.
Oh Man.
That the lady behind the counter.
It's like,
well what do you mean like that?
You know?
And she was like,
I just can't handle them.
And then they took the leash and she
walked out.
And then there were just these two.no,
I don't know if they were trained to
kill or not.
I was going to be like,
ed two rottweilers to my test.
Yeah,
you can't do that.
He knows I have no.
I knew nothing about them,
but I'm like,
well,
in five days those dogs are dead because
they're like four year old rottweilers.
I had a doberman that we adopted as when
I was a kid and it had distemper and it
does.
It's a disease that makes them really
aggressive in this crazy way that dog
turned on us.
That's scary.
Oh Dude.
It was so scary.
I was like,
I couldn't have been more than 12.
maybe 12 somewhere around then.
And this big ass Doberman is showing its
teeth
and barking and snapping us out of
nowhere.
It was the sweetest dog before.
And then all of a sudden it's on the
couch,
like looking down on us.
And we were like,
Whoa,
what is happening here?
And so,
um,
they,
they came and took the dog,
I think.
Or did we take the dog to the pound?
I don't remember what happened or to the
vet rather,
and then they ran an examination that
dog and they're like,
this dog is tamper so we just,
we've got it with this vineyard disease.
Then that's like,
you can't have that in a house with
kids.
I don't know what the fuck they do.
Well,
I was a kid at the time.
My parents weren't having it,
but I don't remember.
Like,
I don't remember too much about it.
They send him to the couch.
I just remembered that dog on the couch
showing its teeth snapping at us.
Scary.
And I was like,
Oh shit.
We brought home a dog.
He'll full grown dog that has a disease.
My,
uh,
my mom's cousin,
second cousin was married to a dude for
a number of years who have this
rottweiler that was like a psychotic
dog.
And like at one point it jumped through
their bake glass windows in their house
to try to get the mailman and got
caught.
Oh my gosh.
Swing the two windows.
And was,
it was fine.
I mean it had stitches and they had to
pull some glass out of it.
But it didn't impact the dog,
that's how.
And it dove through a window.
It just didn't make it look like it
would have killed the mail.
It was just because somebody was walking
up their porch,
you know,
and the doctors and that same like
almost one time,
like my grandparents had a house upstate
and they were there,
like my brother opened the door and came
out and you know,
it was just like.
But some people just like having like a
scary dog.
That's not the kind of dog you just want
to run at a kid that you don't know.
People get killed on it.
It certainly can happen,
especially if it's like really
aggressive with people like that.
Like Jesus,
that's so dangerous.
It's a monster.
Yeah.
And they're cute,
right?
Whether it's like 110 and it is those
big males,
those big fucking frying pan heads.
They're giant flatheads.
It's funny too because we're talking
about like genetic modifications or
cloning,
but really dogs,
if you looked at them historically that
they've been that the whole time like
Ben have,
man has manipulated what they wanted of
certain animals and like they've bred
the,
the meanest,
toughest ones to be guard dogs and they
bred the cutest.
Take a piss on a paper.
Matt wants to be left alone.
Those are all choices that were made by
humans by humans.
It overtime by continued breeding of
ones that were the same and same and
same.
You end up with like breeds and things
like,
man,
I really like played a huge role in the
kind of dog man.
Did the whole thing.
Yeah,
because when they did the genome,
the DNA.
It's a wolf.
Yeah.
Every dog is a wolf.
No matter how big the dog is,
isn't that crazy?
Think about how powerful and terrifying
and Majestical Wolf is,
right?
I mean it's one of the most amazing
creatures in the forest and agree more
and we found just the one that was just
slightly bitch ass,
just slightly bitch ass really come on.
And the campfire,
Bro,
dude,
we got free food and he was like,
oh good.
I can just say,
hey man,
I like your hair is poking up like this
dude,
just relax,
relax for years.
I thank you to alert you look into
camera.
And then they found a male that was
like,
that we should make.
They figured out a way to get the bitch
ass family.
They stayed real close to them to fuck
each other.
She's like,
they were like,
let's take the two smallest ones and
make them do you know?
And then they probably dog houses and I
bet doghouses changed the game.
Like this is amazing.
We're in,
I'll have to be a wolf.
So alleles,
extra hair gets covered and not having
to hunt every day.
It's like,
this is great.
I want white curly hair.
I'm a poodle now.
Motherfucker,
excuse me.
I'd like a perm and fucking with my name
on it.
They make them like puffy with this
amazingly food food dog,
but it's still a dog.
That dog will fuck you up.
Yep.
So poodles are ruthless and those things
will come out.
Yeah.
Puddles probably have an attitude to
like no one takes them seriously.
Like if you had yo,
I got a bunch of guard dogs.
What do you got?
The 90 pound poodles just shut the fuck
up.
Oh my God.
Still a dog thing.
It would be so funny if that thing that
looked like a Barbie toy,
right?
It looks like a Barbie Toy.
Doesn't even look a real dog.
That dog will fuck you up.
It'll bite your dick off.
But I have to say I feel bad when I see
dogs have that haircut,
like they have no part in it.
You know what I mean?
Like they're just jamie showing us a
picture of dogs with braids on.
Okay,
now seriously wearing slippers.
Is that cultural appropriation a little.
How does that work?
A little bit.
I feel like it might be there a white
dog.
They're stealing from Santa Claus,
so get the colors.
They got Sanas gang colors.
Got People just,
you know,
like what in the fuck is that?
Okay,
what in the fuck did they do this dog?
We're looking at a dog body is a,
is a pink snail and I'm not joking.
It looks like a pink snail,
like a swirly with with hot pink
accents.
Is that how you'd say it?
Stripes and it's back leg as a flower.
Yeah,
it's fucking preposterous.
Spray painted.
They spray painted.
Ray painted to dog.
That dog is dying.
That's chemicals.
It has green hair too.
It says the poodles transformed into
pandas.
Horses don't do that.
You fuck even snails.
You've seen the ones that they used.
They take certain dogs.
They make them look like a lion with
doctor Campbell flipped the fuck did
they do to this dog?
They turned it into a camel.
Is so mean.
This is just the same abuse.
Come on,
it says Cindy,
the poodle already bad.
It's like hitting a dog in my opinion.
So city,
the poodle.
Just as a new look.
Every year,
a little madonna and nineties.
Oh Cindy.
Now Cindy.
Oh my God.
Cindy wacky parents.
That's a different dog.
Turn this dog into a pan.
It's hair white and black and you magic
wand over someone's house started like,
fuck it,
I'm not in an exotic wildlife.
Excuse me.
You have a camel and a pant in your
front yard.
Hey Dude,
I can't bear.
I can't pay your bare family.
Dude.
They turned it into a horse.
This is deal turned digital football
player killer.
For folks who are just listening,
what is the name of this,
Jamie?
Because we have to tell people about
this.
It's a poodle transformed in the pandas,
snails,
cetera.
Google that,
and you'll find it.
It's one of them.
They turn it into a bison.
Did they put a mask on it with a glue?
A mass to attend?
These monsters are horrible.
What they do,
the dog,
they gave him a muzzle.
A muzzle.
Yeah.
They put a muzzle on it,
so it looks like a football helmet that
he couldn't be a football player from
the thirties.
You know,
you had to have one with the face where
they put a wig on.
How'd they do the Buffalo?
The buffalo doesn't even make sense.
Scroll back up again.
Then brewster,
scroll back up to the Buffalo.
Where's the knows?
Where's his actual head?
Oh,
so they put something over at Ted.
I don't know.
Look at that.
It looks like they put a outfit on him.
Where's his head?
Seems mean.
This is like extra years.
You think they put a basket on them?
It looks like this is so fucked up.
So now you are aware of Wolf?
No,
I'm just a dog man.
Oh,
can I just cocked off?
the last one.
They turned it into a peacock.
He literally glued feathers to its ass.
Asset is just,
it's just,
it looks like it might be actually just
standing there and they have the
feathers propped up against the wall.
Possibly.
Am I seeing that correctly?
But the other stuff has done to it.
I think that's what the platform night.
Yeah.
It's unfortunate.
Not Nice.
Like it just seems like you got a dog
for the wrong reason,
you know?
You know.
Go get a fucking Mr potatohead dog
doing.
How about decorate your house?
God Damn Dog,
man Christ.
I don't know.
People are terrible.
Terrible.
They're gross.
Make so many bad decisions,
but it's interesting that one of the
things that was coming out of South
Korea during the Olympics was people
were talking about,
um,
in Asian countries,
the consumption of dogs.
That became a big hot point issue with a
lot of people.
Yeah.
It's,
it is weird that we choose certain
animals,
that it's okay to kill and eat.
I could agree more,
man.
I think that our,
our food hangups are so specific to our
country.
I think about it all.
But a bacon,
egg and cheese sandwich is fried pig's
ass.
Unfertilized embryo and mold.
Well that's not true and bold,
but what do you mean video but not going
to die today.
Right.
It's an egg.
Yeah.
And it's.
Sometimes you ever crack an egg and
there's a little chicken in there.
I never had that.
I've had a little extra things in there.
No,
I've had like a little grow.
Most really?
Yeah.
Not like a full chicken,
but like,
oh,
that's going to be a chicken.
You know,
I was in my before I
knew that an egg couldn't become a
chicken because I never thought about
until I had to get the rooster.
I haven't been in the hen house.
I didn't know were they just laugh all
the time.
Yep.
I didn't know that until I was in my
forties.
What you got to,
you got to be in a forum setting to know
that you imagine if you were a farmer,
what a fucking asshole you would think
somebody is that you offer on your
chickens.
They'd get someone that didn't know.
You didn't know if that couldn't just
become a chicken like no.
It's like this one things where it's
people that are vegetarians,
I urge you to eat eggs,
eat eggs.
It's a free ride.
They just coming out anyway.
They're coming out,
coming out anyway.
If you get it,
you can get it from a place like just
like you can get organic grass fed beef,
you can get pasture raised chickens.
They do have that.
Then pasture raised chicken,
eggs.
The yolks come out dark.
You just got to figure out where to get
them to.
Not as they're more expensive,
but they're not as expensive as meat.
Right.
I mean,
they're really good for it to last a
surprisingly long time.
It's a free ride.
That chicken is going to eat all that
stuff on the ground.
The bugs and all the worms.
If you don't want to kill anything,
just eat those eggs.
It's good for you.
Very good for you.
You're fucking amazing for you.
God.
Damn.
I'm anti big propaganda.
Do big.
Yeah.
I can eat eggs every morning.
I do.
I eat them almost every day.
Yeah.
I just think that it's one of the most
Karma free things,
like you've got to exchange with these
animals.
Like I haven't exchange.
I give the animals food.
They eat the food.
They lay the eggs.
I'm nice to them.
I come into their little caged area.
They don't run from me.
They'd come around and give him little
treats and shit.
They're like pets.
Yeah.
They have this really cool life.
They get to wander around occasionally.
They get jacked by coyotes.
Really?
I've had a three,
but how?
How?
How much are they?
They're not in a two.
At least two.
One of them.
I'm suspicious that you don't have them
in a coop.
Man.
It's a fucked up story.
I've told it before.
I'll briefly tell it again.
My massive got honey dicked by female
coyote.
Oh my God.
And he thought the coyote was his buddy
and he got to know this is,
I should say that my gender,
gender identifying with this coyote,
I did not have a chance to really
closely examine it.
I'm just being a,
it's for the good of the story.
This is what I think is my theory.
I think it's a littler coyote and I
really think it was a female.
It was hanging around my house for
awhile and it talked my dog and then
knocking down a fence and he's huge.
And when he got through the fence,
he got to the chicken coop and one of
the chickens,
uh,
was doing a thing called brooding.
And when they brewed,
they,
they're convinced that if they sit on
their egg that that egg is going to turn
into a chicken convinced they just to
get like a little depressed to get
nutty.
And what you have to do when they're
brooding is you have to take them off of
the nest and put them in a cage by
themselves with just a perch.
So they just sit on the perch for like a
day or two and then it leaves their
system.
But if you let them lay on it,
it'll take like 30 days.
It takes a long time.
They plucked.
But how do you pluck the feathers off?
But.
So how,
how often are you monitoring your
chickens that you're like,
oh,
we got a brooder.
Oh,
it's pretty.
It's pretty evident for the obvious.
You look at them everyday if there,
if one of them is in the um,
the,
the sandbox where they lay their eggs
and cheese.
I'm like getting weird when you get near
like a little weird with you and the
little package a little bit.
Like they're not,
they don't try to hurt you,
but they're like,
get the fuck away from protecting what
they think is.
They think there's a baby in there.
It is,
it is.
But what's the alternative?
You got a bunch of Cox in your yard.
Just Jack Trends,
they're all running around.
I'd be watching chicken rape but my
backyard 24 slash seven,
maybe like once in a while,
bring a caulk in to,
you know,
give them a weekend.
And so we need his bird birth control.
I don't want these chickens shitting out
kids.
I could bring in a couple of roosters.
I'm willing to make a few adjustments.
This is what I want.
I want sever the roosters.
Vocal cords.
I don't want to hear that shit at 5:00
in the morning.
Yeah,
we know the sun's coming up.
He's shit.
Yeah.
Siri told me serious and um,
that would be one.
And then uh,
make it so as Dick doesn't work like,
like his sperm you like,
uh,
what do you call that?
Yeah,
give them a fix it job.
Just let them bang it out for pleasure.
Yeah,
I'll occasionally,
you'll get one fertile male inch going
to stick their accounts.
I think a rooster without a voice is not
going to be.
You're going to have a brooding rooster
on your hands,
you know,
that's going to take what the rooster,
it's half of it's identity,
man.
Yeah.
What about what a piece of shit?
I am.
No,
I'm saying like,
you know,
people who have clipped their dogs vocal
cords because their dogs barks team.
I've heard of that before.
It's fucking crazy,
man.
That is,
it is annoying when they bark at you
though.
Sure.
But I wouldn't say try to get chickens
have the weirdest birth control method
ever.
Oh No.
What is it?
It's got to be a chemical.
Chickens have long known to a time a
Jack Sperm after doing the deep wow.
That wasn't well established.
Uh,
what wasn't,
was well established was the underlying
reason for what's technically known as
seminal evacuation.
I like how they give us the technical
term is now I understand it better.
I would prefer it's technically turned,
just call it shooting.
Just just the just shot.
But in a recently published paper,
a team led by Oxford researcher,
Rebecca Dean,
explains that this behavior is in fact,
far from random and that the tendency
for females to jettison Burma's actually
finely tuned mechanism of post Copula
sexual selection.
Wow.
That's weird,
dude.
That'd be a weird thing to say,
right?
Walk into a chicken,
chicken,
check your sperm flirt.
She was
a little like,
what would be the like evolutionary
advantage.
Not that you're a biologist,
norma.
We should probably stop there.
What would be the evolutionary advantage
of being able to shoot sperm out?
You get a vibe from rooster that he's an
asshole.
I wasn't consent.
I didn't say yes to that tire is
bullshit.
Yeah.
Who knows.
We're like,
why did he,
why did he take me last?
You know what I mean?
Why?
Why did I have to wait for,
for other,
you know,
chickens.
I wonder if rooster crows are like,
um,
like those,
that's what it's called,
right?
A crow when they see the guard thing.
So I wonder if he's like national
anthems and that some people nail it and
some people just overdo it.
Some chickens kneel during it like some
hands,
just like Jesus Christ,
we,
you're awake,
you're awake.
We get it the first time.
Oh,
see,
that's the determining factor in when
you know,
like,
uh,
Nah,
not supposed to be that long.
It's a shorter song then you're doing,
you're doing a totally different song
doing that.
You're doing a thing with your voice
that can tell you not to do.
Yeah.
They loved that 100 percent of the time.
I wish I could do that thing when I
lived in the East village in New York
City back like a year or 2000,
1999.
It was,
it was.
It hadn't really been like a,
you know,
a neighborhood that was gentrified or
whatever you want to call it at the
time.
And there was a lot of roosters in the
neighborhood,
like these parking lots.
They have these empty lots where there
were no buildings and people just had
chickens and roosters outside.
So I would,
I was like,
I don't know,
22 years old sleeping in my apartment in
the West village and the East village
rather.
And in every morning I'd wake up to a
rooster crowing like every morning and
then after a while the community started
hanging these signs like,
are you sick of the roosters?
Like,
and then I was like,
God,
they turned it on the dudes who on the
roofs,
which is not cool because it like those
guys lived there a long time and have
roosters treated that petitions to get
rid of the roosters.
Yeah.
All these rooster petitions and then
over like maybe a year and a half,
two years was no more roosters.
One of those like,
like end of an era things in New York
City where people still had like just
wandering chickens in an empty lot.
It had like could help caps in it and
chickens.
People don't understand that.
How cool that is.
I don't know.
I don't know if it's like this,
it's this weird thing that happens in
cities where people come in and take all
the culture out of it and then complain
like,
Oh,
what happened?
All the culture is like,
could you were moved it?
You actively came in and removed it?
Well,
there isn't as much of a suburban
environment so you could have kids in a
minivan and all this stuff you would
have had in the burbs anyway,
and now say that though it a problem
that it's not like one individual that's
doing it.
It's like a whole movement of economics,
right?
It's a movement of economics.
But there is a lot,
in my opinion of sort of community like
activism towards making the community
the way they envisioned it to be around.
So you end up with a lot of science.
There's like,
we're working on it.
Tomato Co op and you're like,
well,
you know,
now it's,
so now you,
oh there's tomato cooperate working
night and got to get in on that and you
know,
and then like,
so there's a lot of like,
I'm not saying that things are doing are
bad,
but they're definitely,
you know,
there's,
there's just been a removal of a lot of
that stuff.
And I look,
there's this argument about New York
City that people go,
oh,
it used to be better.
You know,
it's like now,
like it was really dangerous.
You better.
But they're.
So there's an up and down to.
It's better unless you were the guy that
got shot.
Exactly.
And then there's the other part,
which is you can.
I look at cities like this,
it's like you're always building
something on top of something else that
was already there.
So what to us is like,
I can't believe that hardware store went
out of business.
It's like,
yeah,
well maybe my grandfather was,
I can't believe they put in a hardware
store and we're like,
the horseshoe guy used to be like,
oh,
that's really the telegraph guys going
out with this is bullshit.
You know,
like,
like it's probably something people
felt,
you know,
anytime you're somewhere first you
always feel like someone's ruining it.
Yeah.
I think we're in a very interesting time
and,
and in a lot of amazing ways and I think
we're learning more about people and
behavior I think than ever before.
I think we need to give ourselves a
little bit of a break in this because I
think everybody has this feeling like
why haven't we got our shit together?
Why haven't we fully evolved and my take
on this is that this is a really recent
thing like being aware of what the fuck
is going on just in general in the
general scheme of being in the universe
is a very recent thing.
Yup.
And what we know about life and what we
know about,
you know,
just our own finite life form,
how far it's going to be able to be
pushed,
how long we can stay alive,
you know,
how,
how easy it is to transfer information
from Australia to China to fucking
England and back and forth and back and
forth.
Or we're in the craziest time ever and
it's all really fucking recent.
Really new.
Yeah.
Twenty plus years if that.
Because if you go back 20 years ago the
Internet existed but you couldn't like
watch a video on it.
Like the,
to me the smartphone thing is every day
I'm like,
I can't believe I have this big of my
pocket.
It's like if you don't remember what it
was like to like,
you know,
there's this whole like vibe where
people like millennials don't get it.
They're like,
I don't know,
I have the same attention span is a
millennial because I'm on my phone like
Deloitte that adults are better,
you know,
and I'm like,
I don't know if I did a US tour in
Afghanistan a couple of years ago and I
met all those soldiers,
men and women over there,
and I was like really blown away.
I was like impressed this idea that like
our best days are behind us,
all that stuff and I'm going,
I don't know,
this is a really impressive,
impressive group of young people who are
like fighting for the country,
volunteering to fight for the country
and like coming back here,
sometimes wounded sometimes you know,
all the things that they risk going
there.
But then like you meet them and you're
like,
these are like,
they're not like jarheads,
you know,
they're like sophisticated thinkers and
they're like trying to like be a part of
something.
It's,
it's.
I found it very inspiring to be around
that.
Not like,
oh baby boy,
bunch of bunch of losers if millennials
loser.
So I was like,
she's just awesome.
Yeah,
there's,
we have a soft life now,
so there's gonna be a lot of people that
are ridiculous and you know,
there's always been those people that
are weak willed and they want the world
to be nerved up and of course pad their
feelings.
You're going to have that.
But there's also more people that have
an understanding of like,
that's not a happy,
healthy way to live your life.
Not.
And I also think that like reality at
some point will always supersede nerf
padding.
You know,
there's always going to be a push back
on that where you go look like,
I don't want to offend anybody,
but you know,
and I do agree that there is a movement
by the left that really does push,
you know,
I did a thing,
reason.
I'm doing this charity event for a,
like an urban program for kids.
Um,
mainly inner city black kids.
And I'm hosting with my,
uh,
my buddy Mike Yard is a really funny
comic black dude.
And we went to meet with the guys for
this charity and they were telling us
that,
uh,
you know,
were they have an auction like at any
charity,
then write an auctioneer comes out and
they'll try to auction off and raise a
lot of money from rich people to help
the program.
That's a very basically 99 point nine
percent of every charity event I've ever
been involved with has an auction
segment.
The in the dinner,
they were like,
we're going to have that,
but we can't use the word auction.
I said,
what?
What do you mean you can't use the word
auction?
Don't like it's a sensitive word for,
you know,
the community.
And I was like,
and then the yard goes,
are you talking about slavery?
It's like his head almost exploded.
It was like,
ah,
wait,
we can't wait.
We can't say the word auction.
I'm like,
but aren't you hiring a guy from
southerby's?
Yeah,
his card's gonna.
Say Auctioneer on it.
We're just going to pretend that's not
what he's called.
And they were just like,
we just don't feel comfortable with that
word in the room.
And I was just going,
I can't see.
I said,
guys,
I gotta tell you it like you're making
me want to vote for trump.
That's what I said.
That's how dumb I think this is.
I'm like,
I'll agree to it because I want to help
these kids.
But this is one of the dumbest things
I've ever heard.
Wow.
I couldn't believe I was like,
can I say cotton?
Am I allowed to say like,
what other words can I say?
That's the dumbest thing I ever heard.
You're going to get triggered auctions
going to make a joke.
Like we're not going to joke around
about like auctioning off a black
person.
Although yard and I probably would have.
But first of all,
like when you say oxygen,
you automatically think of that voice is
going to avoid him out of my head when
I.
do you think they did that with when
they were doing that with slaves?
I do not think they talked like that.
I don't know what their technique was,
but I do know when I think of the word
auction,
I'm not like,
Oh,
don't say that.
Don't say the a word,
it's like it's,
it's a,
it's a new league.
It's absolutely accepted.
It's a different thing now.
Yeah.
It's like the word gay.
It used to be flintstones gay.
Have time.
Having a gay time was like,
we're out having a gay old time.
Yeah.
And then it became gay and then you had
to stop saying it that way,
but just go back to gay happy.
Like Flint.
No you can't,
but you can't.
For me growing up was the thing we just
said about everything.
Almost everything is good.
Doesn't matter.
Like the only thing you couldn't,
you know,
it was terrible.
But when did gay go bad?
I don't know.
That's a good question.
Went bad after the f word went bad.
Did it?
Yeah.
Was it connecting the two of them
fucking gay and they're like,
no,
not fucking.
I meant the other word for gay people
that they get to the same fact that.
No,
I'm not afraid to,
but I'm just kind of being sarcastic
with the other f word.
It's like the other white meat.
Yeah,
exactly.
But like that was the and not that long.
It was,
it was this idea of like if something
was stupid,
it was gay,
like it didn't mean homosexual.
It meant like,
Nah,
don't be so gay.
But then you start thinking about,
oh,
I guess it does.
I guess it's offensive because you're
saying like that stupid shirt you're
wearing is gay listening.
Of course it's that way,
but isn't it weird that gay took a turn
for the worst?
Wouldn't you have loved to been at the
intersection when gay went bad?
Like for.
We'll have.
Okay.
Time.
That's gay.
Whoa.
What are you saying?
Like a intersection one overran it.
Yep.
The main one beat the happy gay it did.
Gay took that.
They took the word gay and turns it into
either a negative like,
oh,
that's gay or homosexuality.
How is it not connected to homosexuality
before?
I don't know.
I don't know if the connection came from
the fact that like they're like,
oh those guys are gay.
And they were like being like.
Because they were being like,
really?
You know,
like how happy they were like saying
like,
well that Guy's gay,
Huh?
He's really gay.
Like a gay is with that shiny shirt on,
you know,
hey,
that liberace was gay and then maybe
someone was like,
I'll show you the next thing.
You know,
people like,
hey,
we gotta we gotta stop.
You know what,
we should stop with that word.
Come up with a new word gaze.
A different thing now because I asked
the guy to get gay with me and it got
really,
really uncomfortable.
There had to be like a time in between
where it was real confusing,
right?
Where they didn't,
hadn't fully establish what it meant yet
where people were like,
hey man,
are you gay?
Yes,
I am gay.
I'm having a gale time.
Guys like good.
And then guy tackles him in the bushes
like,
uh,
like the word hookup changed.
Yeah.
Like right around like when I was in
high school,
but like my dad will be like,
Hey,
are you going to hook up with your
friends tonight?
You know what I what?
I mean,
what do you mean it means meet up with
your friends.
I'm like,
that's not what it means.
You know?
All my buddies would be in the room
like,
Hey,
you guys can hook up tonight with that.
I'm like,
don't don't it ever was like,
dude,
your dad's gay.
Don't be so serious.
So funny.
Yeah.
The language shifts occur.
I it feel like right now there's more
policing of it and there's more people
act.
I don't know.
There's just.
There's a lot like the word pushy was,
is one of those where you can say pussy
anymore.
No.
People get offended by it because the
idea is you're getting offended by the
word,
but unless you're overusing it.
No,
no.
I'm saying again,
what I say or don't say is what I say or
don't say it.
I take my licks if I have to,
but people get offended by it.
You know,
that's a word now that like if you're,
if you're in a hardcore leftist
community,
you wouldn't say pushing,
but you'll still say dick guys being a
deck.
It's like,
well that's offensive.
Those communities need a hug.
Yeah.
It's like they don't need a hug
actually.
I feel like they need to have too many
hugs,
you know,
and I think there's just too much.
I think it really,
it goes back to our lives are easy now,
so we have a lot of free time to come up
with bullshit.
We do.
It's like if we had to actually,
we didn't have electricity or we didn't
have like all this ease.
We wouldn't be harping on this stuff,
but just like you have a lot of
downtime,
a lot of downtime.
So you're like,
oh,
I'll start a blog.
I think I'll start blogging about words.
You shouldn't say we have so much
surplus that one of our biggest problems
is that we eat too much food and we get
to big.
Yep.
That's one of the number one health
problems that humans have.
Like this is how much surplus we have.
Even though I know people have it hard
and there's people that are starving all
over the world.
I'm aware,
but just in general,
specially in America.
Well,
what is it like one of our number one
problems is people just eat too much and
when we have the wrong shit about people
starving in America and you think about
how much food is wasted and thrown out
for days doing a documentary on it,
there's no,
uh,
yeah.
It's just such a strange concept that
there's like no in internal desire to,
you know,
it's like why I get annoyed at the
Christian,
right?
The like,
oh,
abortions or you're killing babies.
What we need to do is have those babies
and support young mothers who uh,
who support young single moms.
I'm like,
when's the last time you fucking
volunteered to support a young single
mom who had a baby Christian dude posted
on twitter with the last time you give
up a Saturday of your day to take that
kid to the zoo?
Bullshit.
You say it,
but they don't fucking do anything about
it.
You know,
it's a nice little box to put yourself
in.
For some people they think they're a
good person because they're a Christian,
but like,
how much?
How much do you really act?
But you're taking your day to stand
outside.
Planned parenthood was assigned.
Why not take the day to go help that kid
who didn't get aborted and his mom can't
feed him?
Go.
Why not stop by there instead of holding
a sign about the devil?
A clinic for women.
It's just weird.
It is weird.
It's a.
it's,
it's a weird thing that you can do it
too,
right?
I mean that's one of the weird things
about people is that we know that if we
don't do anything and we take care of
ourselves,
a baby's coming and like if you get the
first countdown,
like countdown,
like it's almost like we agree that
there's like levels to the countdown.
Like in the first couple of days,
no one gives a shit.
Just pull the plug,
pull the plot,
and then every everyone's looking at
everybody like you feel,
okay,
what happened?
What happened?
Yeah.
It's not that big of a deal.
It's like would we.
How many cells was it?
It was only four cells at the time.
Like okay for Salads is not a lot of
cells and you start thinking,
I don't think it really ever can be for
sales,
but you get my point,
a tiny little thing.
And then when does it become,
when do you decide,
decide that's a person I get.
I get by the way it looks like one,
I don't listen,
I get the argument and you know,
I,
I do think that I have my own personal
philosophy on how I would handle a
situation,
but I don't if you were a woman.
No,
no,
no.
I'm saying if I was in a relationship
with a woman and she got pregnant and
didn't want to have the kid or didn't
want to have the at night,
you know,
at the end of the day we'd have a
conversation together and if she was
dead set on doing it then we're going to
do it,
you know,
because that.
But,
but my point being,
I do believe that like it's a weird
thing to just tell other people what
they're supposed to do or not.
I do.
I feel about gay marriage.
I feel that way about everything.
It's like,
it's,
it's a strange thing to be able to
dictate to someone else how they,
they're supposed to live.
Agreed because there's too many people
there with that man.
Like we got the right doing it through
the Christian,
right.
And we've got the left doing it through,
you know,
all their,
all their movements.
And it's like,
I think the reason most people are so
annoyed in the country isn't like even
political.
It's like they're just sick of people
telling them how to live,
you know?
It's like I get it.
I can't say that,
oh,
you want me to not have a gun?
You hate guns.
It's like everyone's fucking stopper.
It's like we need like a,
just like a national time out for five
minutes and we're just learning how to
use this thing,
man,
where we're learning how to integrate
society into this kind of communication
that we share right now.
Just while we're still figuring it out.
I did talk about that with somebody the
other day and I was actually just doing
a set on stage and I was riffing a
little bit about how,
you know,
we talked about the second amendment a
lot and the founding fathers didn't know
we were gonna have assault rifles.
They didn't have the foresight to see
that so that we have to rethink what
that means and it's like,
well,
they didn't know we were going to have
twitter.
Right,
so maybe we have to rethink what the
first amendment means that no every
fucking moron who's going to have the
ability to you say stuff out loud,
just on a national level,
just the Internet.
I mean,
imagine how easy it was to govern people
before the Internet came around.
It must have been so much easier to just
lie to them,
lie to them to have almost no access to
the truth and what you get.
We get with Walter cronkite tells you,
bitch,
that's all you get.
What'd you get?
It's like,
it's like the entertainment industry.
It used to be like,
you want to hear a song?
Merv Griffin and Dick Clark will let you
know what song was.
It can hear,
you know,
we're on the side of the people that are
anti abortion.
There's one side of you that has to
logically interpret that.
If these people really did feel like
babies
were being murdered,
like it was their perspective that
babies were being murdered.
If you completely ignore that
perspective and just try to say it's a
woman's health issue like I get,
I almost get where their mind is at.
I don't think that they should be
interfering in anybody's life,
especially when something is illegal and
fundamentally believe that's what's
happening and you could see how that
thought babies were being killed up to
street.
We can't allow this to happen,
but what I'm saying,
I'll tell you that they are babies and
the problem with that argument is it's.
It holds some water.
Sure.
Like you really have to me as if you're
going to be a rational person and I'm
100 percent pro choice,
but as a rational person,
you have to look at what it actually is.
If you don't,
well then we're playing a game.
The game is you want your side to be
correct,
but the reality is this is a very
complicated,
weird thing.
Yeah,
there's like a life in your body and for
sure a guy shouldn't be able to tell
girl,
which you can do.
Totally agree with that can't.
You can't tell a woman.
She has to keep it.
People have already aborted babies.
There's a precedent for it.
You can't tell them what they could do
or you can do to support their decision
or can weigh in.
I think if you're the dad you can weigh
in and what you want,
but at the end of the day she's going to
decide what she wants to do and you just
got to agree with it.
Yeah,
and that's the move.
I think you know,
it's just,
it's a very complicated thing,
but like a life form that will
eventually become a person is inside
your body.
What do you do?
Like you imagine we had to make that
decision.
We're lucky that chicks do it because we
don't think correctly for that,
for that proposition.
Now ability to weigh those options,
but I do think that the,
uh,
the,
you know,
when I think about that,
I agree with you and I,
and I think most issues in the country
are like that and that's the whole
problem.
There's no rationality on either side,
right?
There's no,
no one will.
Rational Center,
right?
Like for example,
people will,
you know,
look,
there's a lot going on with trump and
Russia and all that stuff.
Wait,
what have you heard?
And then,
and then people will post them thing.
Yeah.
Well,
about Obama scandals and then someone on
the left,
the building,
he had no scandals and then someone will
list like five scanners.
They go,
yeah,
those were scandals.
Like you can't just pretend that like
that fast.
And the furious thing was good.
It was bad.
Like if you really like muscle cars,
like,
no,
but you know,
that Obama thing where he like,
oh,
that's where you gave all the guns.
They lost all those guns and some of
them were used to kill people.
Yeah.
So it's like,
I don't know,
like that.
What was the logic behind that?
They were going to trace them to like
Iran contra account.
Did you see that movie by the way,
scam?
Or was it a thing where they were trying
to give them guns that they could trace,
they could trace and then they instantly
can trace because I think that was.
I think that was the gist of it.
Can you imagine that?
That was just really a gun.
I mean this is.
Some people do think it was like a just
an illegal arms sale that happened right
under our nose.
Will you imagine if that's really what
it is?
I mean,
did you watch that?
I just watched it the other night that
Tom Cruise movie American made.
No,
I did not,
but I know what it's about.
It's the first good Tom cruise movie
he's
had out I think in a couple of years.
Like it's funny because he's that kind
of a dark character is not like a hero.
He says,
I know at Barry Seal story,
so he's,
you know,
he's a,
like a pilot who basically like,
you know,
the CIA was like,
hey,
you're a really good pilot and we need a
guy to like bring some guns to the,
it's all the precursor,
the Iran Contra thing,
which as a kid I remember hearing all
about,
but then understanding of the federal
level,
which was us trying to arm rebels,
which we've been doing for,
we are been loud and against the
Russians.
We've been arming rebels for a long
time.
And that's our move,
right?
Yeah.
Big Time Gang.
And then,
uh,
so he became the dude,
the CIA asked to do that and he was
like,
you got to pay me more money.
And the guy was like,
you'll figure it out.
And then all of a sudden it became,
he would land the,
bring the guns.
And the dude was like,
Hey,
we want you to bring an escobar.
And his crew were like,
Pablo Escobar,
we're like,
hey,
as long as you're bringing us guns,
we also want you on your flight home to
bring a 1500 pounds of cocaine.
And then he was like,
I'm not going to do that.
No thanks.
And they were like a 2000,
2000 bucks a kilo.
And he was like,
how many kilos at 50?
Fifteen hundred pounds.
It became like,
it became like this insane to wait
smugglers smuggling guns in and drugs
and guns and drugs.
It's a really interesting story.
What do you think happens today?
Do you think that stuff like that is
still going on today?
Or do you think that this,
when it happened,
like they figured out that it was a
bunch of cowboys,
like ca operatives that were just trying
to make some money on the side?
Or do you think it's like a systematic?
I think that it's like.
I think that it's human error.
I think that like people,
that's why I'm not like a big conspiracy
theorist because it's like I don't think
the government's organized enough.
It's always weird to me when people who
think that government sucks,
who wants small government,
they want the government,
the government mishandles everything.
They don't know how to do this.
They can't magic imagine manage traffic
lights,
whatever they think the government can't
do.
They can't do healthcare.
They're idiots.
Private sector and then they're like,
but there's a giant government
conspiracy where all the government
knows this thing and I'm like,
if they can't fucking manage traffic
lights,
how are they pulling off like a fake
moon landing or whatever.
It's like,
well,
when you that kind of stuff,
to me it's like you're,
you're,
you're perpetuating two very different
views of it.
Extremely competent,
clandestine and group of people who can
achieve these like dark shadow.
We things without anyone knowing or
bumbling morons,
but they're the same people.
They're government workers.
So I don't know.
I think some CIS or like the story
behind going into Iraq is interesting.
Like a CIA operative had a theory about
what we're been.
Osama fucking other dudes so download.
Saddam Hussein had a,
had weapons of mass destruction.
He had a theory and he was an analyst at
the CIA and he wrote up this whole
document and they read it.
They were like,
yeah,
this is bullshit.
Like we have no proof of any of this.
Thank you.
And he was so mad they did that,
that he published it on the Internet,
just leaked it to the Internet and then
that story got on the Internet and then
the dude in Australia who was a spy.
No,
we're like a guy from Australia and
another guy from Afghanistan or Iraq
read it on the Internet,
came to America and said,
I have all the secrets of what he's
doing,
and he just used that guy's document
that he read online and told the CIA and
then the guy came in and goes,
he has weapons here,
weapons here,
and then that analyst goes,
Holy Shit.
I was right.
Meanwhile he's quoting him his own
report,
so then he goes back to Cheyney and he
goes,
we've got this dude talking to the
Germans saying all the things I
theorized and then that's the guy curve
ball.
We listen to a dude named curveball.
So like that's how the whole fucking
thing went down and basically some do
tricked us.
He actually didn't know anything but it
was too late.
We like went off the information that a
dude read off the Internet from a guy
who was mad.
They wouldn't take his info,
which was wrong,
which is why there were no weapons of
mass destruction.
So crazy.
So it's just a crazy.
So yeah,
I think that shit happens all the time,
but I don't think it's,
I just think they're sloppy.
Government employee are dealing with a
bunch of different things for some of
them are sloppy government employees.
Some of them are not.
Some of them are brilliant.
I mean there's that too.
Like Robert Muller's,
there's A.
Yeah,
there's a ton of them.
There's a ton of them that are
brilliant,
but you're also going to have cowboys.
And this is what I think when you find
out about these CIA drug deals gone bad.
Where did you see that one?
Where the plane crashed in Mexico.
They wouldn't let them refuel.
They wouldn't let them land refuel
because they kind of knew maybe they
were smuggling drugs and they made him
crash and the plane wound up crashing
and it had how many tons of cocaine did
it have in it,
and people like,
this is proof the CIA sells cocaine.
I'm like,
no,
it's proved those guys flying.
That plane had cocaine.
Right.
The real question is did they just get
too Loosey Goosey?
Traveling back and forth to South
America,
a little too tight with some people that
have had a little bit too much money and
they realized we could fucking do this
so we could do this and no one would
suspect it.
Well,
that's the thing though.
Say what the what the five point five
tons of five point five tons.
Wow.
Isn't that 11 pounds 11.
How many?
How many thousand pounds?
11,000?
Yeah.
Two Thousand Times.
Five and a half.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
And 11,000
pounds of fucking cocaine.
Dude.
I tell you,
it's insane,
but show the pictures of the crash
because it's crazy.
There's just six of coke,
man.
I want to say like 2005,
six,
but so the but the barry seal story,
was he just a pilot,
a CIA operative who's trying to make
connections with them,
do his mission,
which is given to him,
which is arm these rebels.
So five guys in the CIA have to try to
figure out how to arm rebels.
So he approaches this pilot that he
hears is a good pilot who flies for Twa
and he goes,
hey man,
you're now in the CIA,
but he's not really in the CIA.
He's not part of this age.
Just a pilot that this guy subcontracts.
And then he doesn't tell the bosses how
he's getting the guns in.
So it's.
He just made up a little thing.
He has his own budget to do his own
little thing and he finds this dude.
So it's not like barry seal was
a CIA guy flying cocaine.
He was just a pilot that the CIA told
and only one guy from the CIA told it to
him and then it's crazy story,
you know?
And then he's doing it and then he
starts making his little side business.
And this guy looks the other way because
he just wants buried delivering the guns
and then after a while,
like as it starts to fall apart,
the,
so it's like burn everything with Barry
Seal's name on it.
We've never had.
We've never had connection to barry seal
and entire life.
And that's,
that's all the coke that they got off.
That plane looks like.
What size was that for an army.
Like if you had like a army troop and
like boys,
this is your career and it's all rolled
up in these giant bags.
Is it if so funny though that like that
is crazy.
People still think a wall is going to
work.
It's like drugs were coming in on an
airplane.
Well,
just the fact that the airplane was a
cia or playing,
did they have in the movie,
did they have the reason why they,
uh,
the whole scheme got busted in the first
place?
Do you know the story?
Yeah,
I mean,
I don't know if it like a spoiler for
listeners,
but I'll tell you the real story about
the kids that were murdered.
Uh,
the kids that were murdered were,
that wasn't in the movie?
I don't think so.
The,
one of the ways this whole thing came
apart was two kids were apparently in
the woods when they made a drop and
these kids saw a drop and they were
murdered.
They were stabbed and then they lead
left their bodies on the train tracks
and their bodies were run over by train
tracks and then the parents got an
autopsy and the autopsy showed that at
least one of the kids had been stabbed.
Wow.
And so something I realized something
had happened in New Orleans where the
kids got killed.
No,
it was MENA,
Arkansas.
Okay.
That's the main part of it.
Yeah.
That's where the drop was.
The drop was apparently in Mena,
Arkansas.
So they killed these kids and then this
whole thing happened and then the whole
thing fell apart and then people started
looking into it and then barry seal's
was murdered actually as he was getting
to court to testify.
Well,
he,
yeah,
he says amazing thriller,
like a Tom Clancy novel.
It's a really good and it's done well.
The movie's done well.
And uh,
but they don't mention the murdered kid,
but they skipped the Mena.
Arkansas is the place where they cia
moves in and then um,
I hope I'm not remembering this wrong,
but I think that was the reason why they
got busted.
I could be,
I'm saying in the movie that's not
mentioned,
creative license,
that making a movie,
they're like,
oh man,
I hate when they do that.
Yeah.
I hate when they do that,
when it's a real life situation.
Like there's a.
Did you ever see that wrestling movie
with Steve Carell fuck out called the
wrestler?
No,
no,
no.
I'm with Steve Carell and Steve.
He's the dupont guy.
John Depaul.
Ah,
fuck.
What's the name of that movie?
Foxcatcher.
Foxcatcher never would have gone there.
Yeah,
that they did that in that movie where
they cut out key details.
Yeah,
well they changed a big part of the
ending where Mark Schultz it like this.
It's a UFC fight.
A famous UFC fight were mark Schultz
who is just top of the food chain
wrestler,
fought this guy,
big daddy goodrich who's a really well
known MMA guy.
Just totally dominated them and in the
movie he's fighting some white guy to
just some made up guy.
They just changed it.
It's just changed that they maybe not
get the rights to the name or it doesn't
matter then don't have that to take it
out.
I know what the fuck the history of this
was.
Now if you lie to me about something so
insignificant as who the guy was that he
fought in the UFC,
he takes it out of it.
What else are you lying about?
A great,
but it's just so stupid to do.
It's a real story.
Did you ever see that movie with Marky
Mark and the rock?
I'm serious.
I should.
That column.
Marky mark.
Um,
I think it's marketing.
Mark Wahlberg and the rock and it's like
it's a true based on a true story.
It came out like two,
three years ago.
It's really good and in the middle of
the movie it's one of the coolest things
I've ever seen done in a true story
movie.
They're like doing this absurd thing or
like jumping off a rooftop together and
it just pauses and then a text comes up
and says,
this all happened.
This is still a true story.
Like it reminds you in the middle of the
movie,
pain and gain was oh,
pain and gain.
Yeah.
Fun.
Moving in.
Dump or something.
I knew it was something like that.
Is this the part?
Just the trailer.
The trailer.
Did this a fun movie?
It's a great movie.
Yeah.
Honestly,
my favorite movies that he did.
It's fun ass movie.
Yep.
The rocks.
Good man.
I liked the rock.
I love the Rock in the middle of the,
in the middle of the movie,
they.
They pause it and they go.
This is still a true story like this
happen,
which is cool because it like.
Because it gets almost inconceivable
after awhile.
I think the rock is going to be our
president.
I think the rock should be our
I think he can pull it off and I'm not
joking.
I'm not joking either,
man.
I would never in a serious political
discussion in good hands with my
patients for real politics has waned it.
Look,
we're,
we're on our way there.
You've seen idiocracy,
right?
We're on our way,
dude.
I still haven't seen that.
Oh Wow.
You will love that movie.
I know.
I would.
I,
I got salty because when I had a bit
that was the same premise of that is
about dumb people out.
Fucking all the smart people.
One day we wake up and uh,
all the power's off and uh,
you know,
no one knows how to turn it back on.
That would,
that would annoy me too if it was your
bed because it's not my bit.
They stole the parallel thinking.
So it's an obvious concept if you think
that people are out,
if they think that people are getting
dumber and dumber,
people are having more kids.
It's just,
it's inevitable.
Yeah,
they are.
Yeah.
That's very true.
And I traced it back to the pyramid,
like the whole,
the whole thing was like that.
The smart people just died.
And then the one that had done,
people showed up at the pyramid and then
they just moved in.
Nobody lives here.
Like the alien culture created exactly
that.
A bunch of like fat dudes look good.
Yeah.
The idiot workers,
if you just stumbled into it.
We built this whole generation to go
with the best that's.
So that's still,
to me,
if I had one time in like if you could
go back in a time machine and go to one
place in history and see something,
I think it would have to be Egypt while
they were building the pyramids.
I would just love to see what that
culture was like.
It's so hard to tell.
I mean you look at all the stone and
everything,
right?
Even if you were standing there automat
I've never been to Egypt,
but I've been to cheat.
She needs on.
It's kind of the same feeling you get.
Were you like,
what was it like,
like when,
when this place was popping,
like,
what did this feel like?
What was this?
These people have built these crazy
structures like what was a normal day
for them?
You know,
it's funny,
I had the,
I didn't realize that.
I've watched the documentary about the
Pyramids and not the,
uh,
not the one with the aliens and which
one Nazis and what,
what,
what's that one on?
Like with the guy with the crazy hair.
Oh,
and it George Hill.
Shout out to Giorgio sucralose and he's
like ancient astronauts theorists
surmise.
Tell people that's not a sentence.
Know he's fairly reasonable.
When you talk to Georgiou is just a
lover of all possibilities.
Ufo.
That's an hour's worth of a show.
They're on like season 11,
89.
There was camping out.
You know,
it's not the first one with like the
Nazca lines.
It's pretty interesting.
But now they're like eight inch an
astronaut feared semis,
that palm trees,
what brought here.
But in you're like,
just stop.
Like,
listen man,
you finished it.
If ghost shows are still on the air,
let them be on the air because at least
they're showing cool old buildings and
shit and stone structures ever be
possible.
They have a family wanting to go to
this.
That one ghost man,
at least we have some cool rocks to look
at where you look at like,
you know,
what are those giant stones in?
Is it Peru?
Stonehenge?
No,
no,
no.
I'm still interested in England and in
England.
Yeah,
there's some.
There's some crazy structures somewhere
in south America that Giorgio was
talking to us about and it was one of
the reasons why some people speculate
that it's possible that some of the
things that are constructed that we
really don't have any idea how ancient
primitive man did were actually
constructed by someone from another.
Another plan,
which I don't think it's any less
reasonable than people thinking.
God sent like pointed his finger
giraffe.
You're right about that.
Like half the world believes that you're
right about that,
but it's more reasonable to think that
it was done by people because we know
people are a real thing and we know
people have built a lot of shit.
So the.
Yeah,
this is it.
This is the exact structure.
These fucking stones there,
they're not just cut and placed
perfectly,
but they're in fit together like a
jigsaw puzzle and somehow or another
they carved and move these enormous
stones and if you stand right next to
them,
like a,
there's some photos of people standing
next to him stand right next to him.
Apparently they just tower over people.
So these were all done,
you know,
who knows how many thousands of years
ago.
But it isn't there like a reasonable
thing to think that maybe they had
technology that is lost to time.
Yeah,
that's a reasonable thing to think for
sure.
Like in other words,
like if our civilization crumbles and in
2000 years people dig it up.
Yeah.
And they find the empire state building.
But like how'd they do it?
They're not gonna find like a backhoe
looking at this picture.
Look at these fucking steroids and
amazing.
Go back to the other one with the person
in front of it so you can see the
perspective.
Look how big it is.
Shit.
So I did not think it was that big.
They're so big dude.
It looked like a staircase and this was
one of the things he was saying like we
don't have the technology to do this
right now.
[inaudible].
Like if you wanted to get someone to go
out there and move those giant stones,
cut them,
place them.
I mean we kind of have the technology,
but holy Shit,
we did take a lot of money.
Would it take giant fucking cranes?
It would take forever.
Look at what they did.
They did this whole structure and all
these things.
You got to get the guys to show up.
Think about how it is to like get your
kitchen done because I need.
I need two more weeks.
You know Mike Stone,
guys out of town.
How long would it take to build
something that fucking crazy?
I don't know.
And so the idea was that aliens came
here,
built some thing's fucked with our DNA
and got ghost.
Say Fuck the fuck some early man.
Keeps early man.
A couple of pokes and pokes.
Exactly.
And then decide coyote your backyard.
I didn't finish that story.
So the brooding chicken that was in that
cage,
she honey Dick my mast if into smashing
open the cage because the massive just
smashed the cage like she was trying to
get at the cage.
Like she was like where the chicken was,
the coyote,
the coyote was and my masters like I got
this and just smash the fucking thing
and tore it open.
And then she was running out the back
yard with the chicken in her mouth and
hop the fence.
And I saw her hop the fence with the
chicken in her mouth.
I'm like,
I'm living in the Goddamn Disney movie.
You are.
Look at this.
I just watched a coyote snatched chicken
from the.
From your yard.
Yeah,
that's bad ass.
Who was wild?
But the crazy thing is my fucking dog
standard over there.
I was like,
asshole,
what the fuck did you do?
Is it guy?
Oh,
it's,
she's,
she's serious.
Have fun to pull the kill chickens and
animals are handled today.
I know you can't really expect much more
from a dog.
He's like,
I don't know.
That dude wanted a chicken.
So he's trying to help these bill,
these stones.
What part of the world is it,
Jamie?
So people go look at it.
It's in Peru,
Peru.
And what's the name of the structures?
It's like something tie you.
God,
I wish I could remember the code
district.
Costco.
And it's.
Can't want to try to say that bruce got
some cool stuff.
Is that.
That's not what we were.
Just looking at it earlier though,
isn't it?
That's the whole overstructured that's
what it looks like from the top.
Yeah,
that's what I googled it.
And then it's a fortress to holy shit
that does look like aliens built it well
or super sophisticated man that was
wiped out in a disaster.
That's more likely.
Yeah,
but the crazy thing is how quickly then,
if that's the case,
how quickly then we came from some sort
of ape man to what we are now.
You know,
it hasn't been that long.
The,
the,
the amount.
How long ago was that?
I think this was built,
this shit was built like at least a
thousand years ago I think.
I don't think they know though.
See the problem is if you don't have to
get stuff from like something that
someone ate or it has to be like a
carbon based thing.
You can't test the stone.
You can test some of the material in the
stone or a,
you know,
like scratches on the stone,
like in crevices and shit like that.
You can get stuff.
But when they're around things that
would have been several thousand years
of man's advancing at that point a
hundred years ago.
Right.
Wonder because,
I mean,
I don't know.
It's hard to say because I don't know
when it was actually built,
when do they think it was built?
So there's all these theories and then
there's these uh,
really,
um,
fringe theories that push everything
way,
way back.
And that stuff gets resisted a lot
because the carbon dating though,
right?
So in some,
in some cases occupied since 900,
900 occupied since $900.
900,
somebody moved in.
Yeah.
And then just said to until about the
13th century.
That's a long run.
So who,
who built it though?
Do they know?
When do they guess?
I think it does it say like what year it
was built or as you said,
occupied from 900.
Does that mean that's when they first
moved in indicate the earliest
occupation on the hilltop dates to about
900 seat.
Oh,
okay.
So wow.
I built it over 400 years or so.
It sounds like so more than a thousand
years and,
but like you know the jewels in years,
it's hard to wrap your head around.
The Jewish calendar goes back to like
5,700
years ago and I know.
So there's no nuts,
right.
So band has man had a lot of time to get
some sweet tech,
but 900.
Yeah.
It's so arbitrary that we started at
zero then start up again.
If you go backwards and you go into
negative numbers,
like what's so stupid?
So dumb Christians.
It's weird how we do that.
Yeah.
I mean even with like temperature,
no snapping on the metric system is so
stupid.
So stupid.
Like you go to places Neela Celsius.
What's it's those 20 slash Celsius
outside.
What the fuck is 23 cells if you learned
anything by though.
I agree.
I'm like,
so we should.
We're all going to die.
So we're all gonna die someday.
So winter had her shorts.
No idea.
But they,
a lot of them know our stupid shit,
which is interesting.
There's more sort of a we're,
we're like,
that's like a real American movie.
Like they tried to switch over in the
seventies to the metrics and people
like,
fuck you ain't learned French man.
Dude.
I remember it.
I remember it being taught in school.
So I was in school.
They tried,
they tried soccer too.
Yup.
Just pick it up now.
Just maybe a little heat now.
Little bit,
little bit,
little bit.
But uh,
yeah.
It's funny to me that stuff that like
that's Kinda what I love about America
is that just like that we're not going
to do with that.
I'm interested in the rest of the world.
We don't give a shit.
Fuck.
The metric system.
It sounds fresh.
It sounds good.
Sounds like a gay sister is made three
gay math.
Okay.
We're Americans.
It's
better though.
I mean it's intense.
Why are we doing 12?
So it's better and,
and,
but it is confusing when somebody tells
you a metric,
you know,
they say like,
oh,
it's a leader like leaders of gas.
I'm always aura.
If you drive in Europe and you're
looking at the,
you know,
spin on winner and that it has the
conversion on there for you.
But whenever we,
you'd say like 12 inches is a foot.
Like why 12?
Fuck is that?
What is that?
Why did you,
why'd you arbitrarily.
And it's only us and a few other
countries that still accept that.
Right?
What that 12 inches.
How many people do that?
Do they accept it in Canada?
Canada's metric,
right.
And then three feet a yard.
Like thanks.
Canada is metric.
Yeah,
it is.
I think most places are metric.
Yeah.
I have a friend from Australia,
my friend Adam Green tree,
and he talks in meters.
It was about hunting 20 meters on what
that means.
Nothing like how many football fields.
How far is that?
There's only two distances.
I understand school bus,
length of football field.
It's the way things have been taught to
me.
Yeah.
How many meters are in a real unit of
measurement?
Like a real one,
like an American one.
How many meters?
How many feet run that fucking meter?
You have a fucking goofy ass.
Me that.
Yeah,
it's a yacht.
I want to know what a yacht.
Eighty yards.
Thirty yards away and that's it.
Even when you're in school,
the only way they teach you about the
distance of things.
His stack,
school buses or football field,
like the moon is 147 billion football
fields,
you know like that.
Now I understand whatever the distance
is,
but it's always.
It's always converted.
Two football fields at school.
Buses are always right.
Yeah.
As a student,
that's all I remember ever in science.
He likes taking school buses and going
from here to Australia,
you know,
and you're like,
it's like 97 million school buses.
That's true.
School buses,
that's constant unit of measurement and
football fields.
It's all.
Yeah,
it's true.
The trick of how far does she live?
Like two football fields with three
school buses.
We could walk.
We could.
It's pretty cold.
It's cold.
So how cold is it?
Twenty four Celsius.
Oh,
so a 23 Celsius is probably like,
is that like 70 degrees?
I have no idea.
I literally have no idea.
I know a little bit about kilos,
but very little.
I know the limit is 75 slash 2175 slash
24 slash 75.
All right,
I'll remember that.
And remember that.
And that way if it gets to like 30,
I'll go,
hey,
it must be hot as zero Celsius is 32
right?
Because they're zero is freezing.
Zero is our.
That's freezing.
Yes.
But our 40 below is the same as their 40
below.
Do another math trick.
It's tough.
Nine fifth Celsius plus 32 to nine.
Fifth Celsius plus 32.
Fuck this.
Fuck you.
Why do you do nine?
Almost.
It's almost a half.
A little bit under somebody.
One of you.
Fuck one of you.
Somebody.
We need to figure out who's
are.
Who's got a simpler thing that.
Who's got a simpler thing?
Get the fuck out of here with your.
With your fair to mentally switch over
to Celsius,
but zero Celsius is freezing in 32
Fahrenheit is freezing.
Yeah,
but it's not just offset by 32
something.
Something happens around 40.
Below zero.
They become the same.
I don't know if it maintains for very
long or degrees.
Get Colder and I dunno.
Yeah,
I dunno.
It just zero makes more sense as the
company.
It's weird like how the fuck is if our
32 is the Celsius zero,
how the fuck is it?
The same thing at 40.
Below.
It doesn't even make sense.
It makes sense.
Here's another.
Excellent.
How are you not just adding 30 Canadian,
he said gave you the gay.
My friend gave me this tip.
Double the centigrade temperature.
Subtract the first digit of the result
and the result and then add 32 to that.
Oh okay.
Aren't you really?
Yeah.
So 23.
Oh,
okay.
So 46.
And then what do we do with the first
digit of the result?
There it is right there.
So 23 Celsius equals 74 Fahrenheit.
Twenty three c plus c times two is 46
minus the first digit.
So minus the 4:46
minus four is 42,
42 plus 32 is 74 works.
Hey fuck you.
By the way,
by the way,
that's the easy one.
But what's amazing to me is like when
you meet someone that lets you know like
what you just talked to them about math
and they can do like math problems in
their head and you realize,
oh I am a baby math baby.
Oh yeah,
I'm a math baby.
Alright,
totally.
There's people that were like looking at
that going,
yeah,
that's what you do.
That's the obvious thing in my head.
20 slash 74 degrees.
I'll have moments where like I had this
recently,
I was just laying in bed in an insomniac
state.
Like I offered them in and I was going,
how the hell do you do?
Long Division,
I know it's like I haven't done long
division and I and I tried doing a
problem and I got it wrong and then I
have to read.
I was like,
Oh yeah.
They'll be like,
you know,
like it was like,
it,
it was,
it was confusing and I haven't done it
in was the last time you put out a pen
and paper to do a long division dude.
I barely do the ad.
The tip part thing,
right?
Yeah,
just met down.
You just double it and it moved.
The decimal adding sucks.
I put that on my instagram recently.
It was a depression to get on into mit
in 18,
69.
Wow.
So it's really just the order of
operations.
If you can figure this out,
let e equals eight and the following
equation and there's a bunch of tough.
What is it,
a numerical value of the equation.
Hint,
as a mentioned,
as mentioned earlier,
knowledge of the order of operations
will be pretty important here.
Scroll down to read the answer.
A lot of people did not get it right,
but most people kind of got it right.
Well,
what is it?
The answer's 15 to this.
Yeah.
Are you a well versed in these kinds of
equations?
I remembered how to do it pretty
quickly.
That's like a friend showed it to me and
I was like,
ah,
I don't remember how to do any of that.
Interesting checkmark.
I'm square root,
fairly positive.
I never learned any of that.
Fairly positive,
but that's a good example.
Like I'm a completely illiterate when it
comes to that and that's a cube root.
No one knew what that was either a cube
root.
Oh,
second exponent.
Jesus Christ.
Dude,
I could.
I literally was just nothing I could do
with that.
Well,
that's what's so fascinating about
society and that's why you know,
if anybody tells you,
and it's not all good,
but that's one of the things that's
fascinating by society is that there's
so many different people with so many
different abilities and there are people
that gravitate towards that and are
wizards at mathematics and there's other
people like you and I.
they're good at talking shit.
Yeah.
That guy was guy.
We live in a world where that can
happen.
Oh God,
no.
I often think about how useless I'll be
like if the apocalypse goes down,
you're going to be like the dude you
want to hang out with,
but the apocalypse goes down.
I'm done,
dude.
If the apocalypse goes down,
whatever happens.
You want it to happen in your
neighborhood,
so it's over.
Okay,
Gotcha.
Look,
if a meteor hits,
you want it to hit your house.
If you're.
If it's an earthquake post apocalyptic.
Gosh,
society say we both survived it and we
living in a shanty town,
we kind of.
You have skills,
you can hunt,
you can do shit to do something.
I can teach you the things that I know
how pretty quick.
Bring no value.
Let's eat first.
You would figure it out after a couple
of weeks and fix things.
I know how to fix things.
I don't know how to hunt with a bow and
arrow.
You had figured out,
do you use a gun ever?
You've ever used it?
Not Anymore rifle,
but I would.
It's a.
it's a better way to get meat.
It's more accurate.
You can do it from further away,
you know,
if it doesn't require nearly as much
discipline still requires a lot of
discipline,
but not nearly as much as a bone marrow
donor.
It's just cooler.
It's harder,
it's way more difficult.
But then there's other people that use a
traditional bow and they think that guys
like me are pussies because I use a
compound bow.
You mean like Lego last bow,
like just one Robin Hood.
Just like a lot of them use recurves,
but some don't even use recursive old
school stick bow.
Really?
Yeah.
There's people that like want to make
things tougher on themselves.
They want a bigger and bigger challenge
and you know,
it gets into this weird territory.
So w like some people said like you
should only hunt with a rifle because
it's probably the most deadly thing that
you could use in that situation.
Like so you shouldn't use a bow and
Arrow because you're not.
You're not using a bow and Arrow because
it's more effective.
You're just using it.
So it's more of a challenge to use.
It's like,
well,
let's have a bastardization of the
original idea of what hunting is right
now.
Some people feel like that,
but then other people are like,
no,
it's just a different kind of hunting.
If you do it correctly,
you have pretty much,
you have less likelihood of success,
but if you do it correctly,
you have just as much of a likelihood of
killing the animal.
So it's not like it's an unethical thing
if it's done correctly,
just requires way more work.
And,
and,
and like you said,
more skill.
Yeah.
But if you were in an apocalyptic
scenario where we had to go out and get
food and you and I went out,
I could teach you what you need to know
pretty quick.
That stupid.
No,
you know,
did the hard part would be learning how
to be accurate with a bow.
That will be the hardest I want to learn
that.
I was actually going texted me one day
and go,
what's a good starter?
Bo Got,
want to learn how to shoot a bunny.
Real good means a bunch of good
companies.
I use a white.
Um,
but there's a bunch of great ones.
Like Matthew's makes great bows,
is a bunch of companies that make
recurve bows,
those which are fun to practice.
Like Dunkin has a recurve.
He does,
yeah.
He shoots him in his backyard.
He loves it.
That's cool.
It's just a fun thing to do,
man.
Even if you never want to ever shoot an
animal and you don't even want to eat
eggs and just straight up Vegan like
archery's a fun thing to do.
It's like a weird kind of a meditation,
you know,
like something happens when you're at
full draw and you're like holding on
Arrow and then you release that Arrow
and it just sales right into the target.
It gives you this weird charge.
It's like your,
you're doing like almost like a form of
yoga with your mind and your body
together because like everything has to
be perfectly still.
And then on the release,
if it goes in the right spot,
you get this big burst of satisfaction.
It's really interesting.
Yeah.
There's something and you can't think
about anything else other than the shop
that you're attempting to make.
Yeah.
You have to keep your eyes on what
you're trying to hit.
It's really a mind thing going on with
archery.
That's fascinating.
I do think though,
a shooting a gun is like that.
Not probably not as intense or
meditative,
but there's something like it when
people are like,
I don't know why anyone wants a gun.
I'm like,
have you ever shot one?
Really?
I mean,
I don't own a gun.
I live in New York City.
It's not really been an option for me.
But uh,
you know,
like I said,
I've been on it.
I've,
it was when I was in Afghanistan when
some of those dudes and they were like,
take us to the shooting range and we
were shooting all their different ways
and again,
it was a war zone.
So I'm not getting into my,
my ethical,
you know,
not a huge fan of aa or fifteens for 18
year old.
But I get why people want guns.
I get why people want to own guns.
You know,
I,
I think that's like the argument that
it's like,
I wish people would just like take a
beat and go.
I like you just said about the abortion
thing.
I understand.
You feel like it's like that's okay.
Okay,
so you feel that way and then it's that
way it becomes less of a conversation.
But we gotta get rid of guns,
more of a conversation about like,
all right,
we just have to tidy,
maybe just tidy up a couple of
components of it,
you know,
that kind of definitely have to figure
out how to stop people from buying them
legally when they're crazy.
Well there's something wrong with them.
Right.
You know,
I mean here's a question,
how many of these mass shootings were
actually done by someone who was in the
NRA?
Well,
according to the people on the right,
none.
Is that true?
That's what I don't know that that's out
there right now on twitter.
That's why I wanted to ask you if,
you know,
that could be a Russian Bot for probably
just spreading that fake news.
Hashtag fake news.
But yeah,
a
see if that's real.
Does that make sense to you?
Yeah,
I mean it's an interesting question.
Well,
if that is and then it gets weird,
like why is everybody attacking the NRA?
Well,
I know they were the ones who are making
it easier to access these guys.
They're the ones a cock blocking any
legislation getting done because they
have paying so much money to these
congressmen and senators.
You know,
if you saw that Lieutenant Governor
Delta said they don't,
they don't want to.
First of all,
I got to be honest with you man.
Like I had no idea you got like your
flights are cheaper because you want a
gun.
I was like,
what the fuck dude?
Like I'm just getting ripped off on
Delta because I don't own a gun.
Like what a fucking bullshit thing where
you could actually own a gun.
But it was just like,
what the fuck?
I didn't know the discounts,
you know?
It was just such a weird thing to find
out and now the delta pulled that.
It did.
I was like,
wait,
but my passive mentality cost more money
is so the thought is that the NRA has
made it more easy for crazy people to
access these guns and so we did it.
It's like,
yeah,
the idea that like we can't raise the
age to 21.
Well,
if you can go to war at 18,
why can't you,
I don't know.
Maybe raising,
I mean,
uh,
it's,
it seems like when you go to war,
you're getting trained by the military
versus when you have just 18 and you
walk into a concern and walk out with an
ar 15.
Nobody taught you how to use it.
Literally just bought a gun.
It's a strange,
like I just,
my,
my thought on it has always been like
why not?
Like if you have a driver's license for
a car,
but then if you have enough to drive a
bus or like a truck,
you have to get a different class of
driver's license.
You have to get like a class D or Class
C,
whatever the next level is.
There's different classes of driver's
license.
Like you can't just go buy a big rig and
start driving it around the country.
You've got to get a license for driving
a big rig,
which means you have to go to school,
learn how to drive one,
learn how to park one,
all the things that have fuck it takes
and you have to prove it to an expert
and you have to talk to her about this
yesterday.
So why not just have it be that simple,
which is you want own handgun,
just get you get the class,
a handgun license and you take your road
test which is low,
how to load it,
know how to clean it,
whatever the rules become.
And then it takes four hours to pass the
test.
It's like 10 written questions and then
that's it.
And then you get the license and get the
gun and it's yours.
And then next,
next class you.
I'd like to own a shotgun.
All right,
good.
A Class B shotgun license.
Take the class.
They think fine and then you get to like
the Ar 15 level and they're like,
oh,
now you have an instructor looking at
the guy.
And like,
this guy doesn't seem a little,
you know,
he's got a little bit like of a dead.
I here,
you know,
like maybe we'd all be like,
yeah,
maybe we'd double check this guy or
whatever,
you know,
like you can,
you can get a sense of people in,
in that environment or if it's a five
question question thing you have to
answer,
you know.
And it's like,
what,
like what are your hobbies?
And it's like eating rabbits alive,
you know,
you're like,
damn man,
that guy.
They hide those answers though.
I don't know.
I real crazy person.
A real psychologists can spot a fucking
crazy person based on how they hide
their answers.
Psychologist,
do you think from the written word?
I think that you could divide tasks.
I think you could
devise a written test where someone will
be like,
this is an alarming answer to this
question because it references his
mother and it has nothing to do with
this bathrooms or whatever.
Whatever.
Fucking weird,
you know?
So I looked at that sounds really
unappealing to people and I get that
they were met,
but that wouldn't be banning any guns.
That would be.
You can have any gun you want,
you just have to like do a very basic
rudimentary seven question test and go
to a firing range with a pro for two
hours and he has to make sure you know
what you're doing.
The NRAS perspective is they don't want
to give an inch.
Yeah.
Because if they give an inch,
they feel like the ultimate is they're
just going to lose ground,
are going to lose more grounded,
more ground.
What's the slippery slope for?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's interesting.
Whenever anything happens.
Like now more than ever,
I think people are demanding some sort
of a change.
Like there has to be some sort of a
chain says 75 percent of the country
wants some kind of change.
Even trump to raise the age.
But it won't happen because the
legislation won't pass.
It's one of those things where I,
I seriously doubt,
I'm not saying this is a good or a bad
thing,
but I seriously doubt if we didn't have
guns and all of a sudden guns became a
thing and we all had to vote as to
whether or not everyone should be able
to have guns.
I don't think it would have passed.
I don't think it would pass away.
But it's interesting though because it
exists now and now you know,
most politicians are in favor of it
because some are in favor of limiting it
slightly.
Well,
they got a lot of money.
Yeah,
a lot of money from the NRA,
but it's also like who,
and I'm not saying you shouldn't be able
to have guns,
but who wants us to have guns?
Like if you just going to be completely
democratic,
like what percentage of the people
actually want everybody to have guns and
what don't.
Just out of pure curiosity with no
judgment percentage went everyone to
have guns.
I want people to be able to have guns
and what percentage thinks that no one
should have guns?
Like if you add the site Australia or
something like that,
all the guns.
I think it's a much smaller group of
people that don't want anyone to have a
gun.
Like I don't think so.
I think there's probably like 14 percent
of the country that thinks we'd no one
should have a gun.
Yeah.
I think the vast majority think we need
some new sort of regulations and
restrictions.
Absolutely.
Just reasonable,
reasonable restrict.
I really don't think anyone is saying.
I mean I think that people,
it's a right that's embedded in the DNA,
the country,
whether you like it or not,
it's part of the DNA,
the country.
And like that's very important to day.
It just stays that way forever.
Well,
I think that to me their arguments can
be made about this,
which is,
you know,
I don't,
I don't think people really understand
how everyone,
how everyone lives.
I think there's so many different
lifestyles in this country that like,
you know,
I think you have a perception of like
say like a suburban just outside of
metropolis,
kind of a mom that doesn't realize that
for some people in the country when they
dial nine,
one,
it's like a 50 minute response time,
you know,
like it's not like there's like a local
firehouse and they could,
you know,
like people feel like I have to be able
to protect my family because I can't
necessarily rely on the police to come.
I mean,
I,
I think that's true.
It does happen.
Yeah.
And I also think that like there's a
component to people's fears of like,
you know,
society on folding and whatever that's
perpetuated.
But I actually believe that people from
the dawn of time have always believed
they're going to be the last ones on
earth.
You know,
I believe that,
that they're going to live through the
apocalypse because I really think it's
all about Fomo,
fear of missing out.
And it's this feeling of like,
once I die everyone else should die.
So like,
cool shit doesn't keep happening once
I'm dead,
you know,
but I really do.
I think that people have this instinct
of like,
I'm going to die with everyone else.
It's like,
no,
you're going to die and then we're going
to forget about you and then cool shit's
going to keep happening.
And it's like,
I remember when I left the daily show,
I felt that way.
I'm like,
yeah,
good luck at the show.
Kept going.
I was like,
oh,
they're fun.
I,
my life has no purpose.
You know?
And it's,
it's that.
And it's that feeling of like you want,
you want the sea.
It's like when a football player,
whatever,
any athlete leaves a team,
they're like,
yeah,
like good luck winning without me.
And then they win the super bowl the
next year.
I'm like,
yeah,
you were the problem.
Jeremy Shockey,
you know,
don't think that applies to the
apocalypse though.
I think the apocalypse is people
understanding and knowing in their head
that they're fragile and that they're
very environment is fragile and they
were lucky that it stays the way it is
right now.
But the more we learned about
supervolcanoes,
asteroidal impacts,
earthquakes,
tsunamis,
all the crazy shit that can happen to
people,
the more we realize how fucking
incredibly fragile we are.
So we're always worried about the big
thing that happens because there could
be a big thing that can happen if some
super volcano blows and there's ash that
covers the sun or blocks out the sun and
we lose all our crops.
It's like a new shortages.
It's 100 percent possible.
Totally earthquakes.
Fucking asteroidal impacts all that
Shit's 100 million asteroid hitting the
earth or not hideous.
It's just up to fucking what's floating
around in.
Yeah.
And if people have been alive,
if human beings have been what we are
now for how many thousands of years,
what is it like?
Um,
10,000
maybe.
No more.
I think more than that.
Yeah.
I think you're sick about modern humans,
modern humans,
modern.
You want to say like 200,000
years.
Does that make sense for modern humans?
Yeah,
I think that's probably wrong though.
I think it's mainly because it depends
on what we're calling modern.
Like is there a.
that's a good question.
Yeah.
What do we call modern like a,
a society that has like an African
economy and trade system,
you know,
systems,
trade roads,
schools,
shelter,
right.
When it was,
what do we got?
Stone tools was two and a half million
stone tool,
but that's like.
Yeah,
but that's a.
I saw an orangutan at the zoo using a
stick to try to get bugs.
Then the next thing says a modern man is
200,000
years ago.
Well,
yeah.
Okay.
But I guess 200,000
years ago they look just like us,
but like a homo sapiens pretty close to
us.
Yeah,
I'd be.
I bet if you thought a woman for 200,000
years ago,
you'd be like,
yeah,
she's hot.
You know?
You'd be like,
what the fuck do I do?
Yeah.
That's a long time ago.
Are you swiping right?
What are you doing?
I was just looking up.
I was just googling piece of
information.
Yeah,
that's a crazy notion when you really
think of 200,000
years,
200,000
years ago we weren't even people.
We were some,
some other thing that became people
like,
what are we going to become?
Yeah.
I just feel like,
like I like when you go back to 100,000
years,
it feels like you're,
you know,
that's like pretty close to like caveman
era.
This caveman I,
which really crits,
not like ape man,
but it's like,
you know,
like super primitive,
primitive,
but that's modern human I guess.
I think that was,
that was revised something recently that
modern human was like when you have
trade,
which,
you know,
like civilization,
like the more you know versus the versus
the actual body being.
You know,
I think they used to think it was where
Iraq is.
I think they thought that was the oldest
Tamia that area.
Um,
Sumir.
They think that that was the one of the
first real civilizations.
They think that was the first day.
Well,
at least the first evidence of written
language.
And there's a lot of it there.
Sumeria Mesopotamia as in fact the first
known complex civilization developing
the first city states in the fourth
millennium,
BC.
He,
it was around these cities at the
earliest known form of writing.
Cuneiform script appeared around 3000
bce.
Yeah.
I like everything OBC now for the Non
Christians before current era,
like what is weight?
Why is it current?
What's the,
what is that bce?
Sneaky Bitch.
So that's what it was even earlier than
that.
I didn't think it was 3000 likes.
Five Jewish calendar,
right?
Yeah.
Fifty 700 years ago where they like
started keeping track of shit and they
had like,
you know,
so that's what they watch and that's
about all those structures like the
pyramids and all those different things
that you think that there was advanced
civilizations that died off and that
that's why all those things were there.
Well you know about like the library in
Alexandria?
Yeah.
That's one of those things that probably
loss of thousands of years,
they burned all the shit the Egyptians
knew like thousands of years.
Like we might not ever figure it out,
but I'm saying like just God knows what
they had discovered and how we could
have stacked our science on top of that.
And right now be,
who knows,
we could be living to like 250 years old
for all we know,
like we don't know what they knew or how
they built that shit.
Like it's just like what?
That's like total religious move.
Too much knowledge in here.
Get rid of it.
The enemy.
We're never,
we're never going to be able to convince
these people have an invisible cloud
band.
If they could read these books were
burned.
This fucking picked out.
People had been apparently going back
and forth to Egypt forever knowledge.
They would go there to learn shit.
Yeah.
And it was,
it was a lush place.
Yeah,
it was a,
a Patra.
It was closer.
Cleo.
Cleopatra is closer to the birth of the
iphone than she is to the construction
of the pyramids.
Whoa.
So if you go from Cleopatra to today is
a shorter time period than Cleopatra to
the construction.
That's crazy.
Wrap your fucking head around that jazz.
And if you listen to Graham Hancock,
um,
and uh,
John Anthony West,
this guy was an egyptologist who just
passed.
They think that it goes back way further
than that.
They think that the pyramids of Giza
might be from 2,500
years ago,
but they think there's a lot of shit in
Egypt.
Giant things,
including the spanx that are thousands
and thousands of years older than that.
Well,
did you see that they just invented this
new air sonar?
Yes.
That Guatemalan society in the fucking
jungle.
That's crazy.
My mind exploded all that crazy.
Did you see that lost city ofZ ,
that movie he didn't touch on my.
It's a movie I want to watch,
but then I watched the trailer and I was
like,
Moshe Kasher sent me the book and I
almost read it,
but then I found out there was a movie.
I'm like,
fuck you go.
Let's knock this out in an hour and a
half.
Huh?
For sure.
It's not as good though because portia
was raving about the book.
Oh,
by the way,
congratulations to Moshe and Latasha
from making,
making people.
Oh,
they made a burson testing,
but that city of z movie was really
interesting because this,
these,
these people were just the raw cost of
raw adventurous.
I mean you can get horrible mosquito
bites and then go into the jungle,
these crazy Englishman and like that to
me was what was interesting about that
book to try to see.
I don't know,
I was really well done.
So I assume that their version of like
what these English scholarly gentleman
were like when they were planning out
these epic mega trips,
but when you were watching it take
place,
like the way they did it in the movie,
you really felt like that could have
been how it went down and this crazy
fucking guy went just deep,
deep,
deep into the jungle looking for a lost
civilization.
Journals and things.
Which most of those students did you
know it,
you have to take,
I guess what they're writing with a
grain of salt because you're like,
I want to make myself sound as bad as as
possible for sure.
But they definitely found some stuff
back to.
They went,
they found pottery and they found a
bunch of different things that the guy
colonel pursue faucet.
Is that his head?
Oh Wow.
They think it might be his head.
Oh Dude,
go to that page.
Police.
We need to know about this shit.
Strange stories,
Dun Dun Dun.
Yeah.
They'd probably killed that dude and cut
his head off.
I mean that's what they were doing to
people down there.
They probably got tired of this white
dude stumbled around through the forest.
Had thing.
Yeah.
How do they shrink head?
They cut your skull out.
This is the thing I used to think they
shrunk the whole skull and everything.
I'm so stupid.
I already told you how dumb I am when it
comes to eggs with shrunken heads.
I thought,
Huh?
They got some fucking solution.
It makes their head shrink up.
No,
no.
They take the skull out and then they
take the skin,
stitch it all up together and then they
do something with it to make it like
shrivel up like a put a.
put a coconut or something in there.
I don't remember.
I don't remember how they make it.
That would have never in a million years
have you asked.
That was shrunken head would make and
they stuff it.
I would have no,
I wouldn't even guess.
I think they stuff it to kind of looked
like the guy that's his head.
That's homeboys head.
Yeah,
they,
they chopped that dude up and did
something to his head.
Wow.
That is so crazy.
But what a.
But a dark way of approaching other
human beings.
They have his eyeballs stitched up.
They have a rope coming out of his mouth
for like a.
just a carrying strap.
Yeah.
So you know,
you can put it on your belt.
Might be right.
They stitched his mouth up though,
right?
It doesn't look like his mouth is
stitched up.
That looks like a little bit.
Yeah.
It's like they made a key chain,
you know,
that's what it looks like.
They got that little loop.
They carried that dude around their dick
just walked through the forest.
It was,
it was all for a novelty store in
Venice.
That was their version of forever 21
little like Hudson News in town with
little knickknacks.
What a fucked up practice.
Cutting people's heads off,
taking the skin off,
stitching it all up and shrinking it,
but yeah,
but again,
it's like we were talking about food.
It's like we got a lot of fucked up shit
we did here too.
Oh yeah.
No.
Smallpox on blankets.
That wasn't.
That's not really fucked up.
It's not right.
No,
no,
no.
They didn't even know what bacteria was
back then that they would just know that
they can figure out how to get.
No,
apparently it's an urban myth.
Apparently,
depending on urban or rural.
It's a wild west.
Apparently would happen was just the
first European settlers just alone by
their presence,
killed somewhere around 90 percent of
the native America bringing outside
disease,
all kinds of crazy shit that people had
no immune systems for and that this idea
that they did it all with blankets would
look the is not to say that people
didn't do horrible things to the native
Americans.
They absolutely did and it's not to.
Not to in any way,
diminish the genocide that took place on
the native Americans,
but I don't think that the blanket thing
was true because they didn't know how to
isolate syphilis.
I mean,
unless they just went to pe patients
that had syphilis,
smallpox,
whatever it was.
You're right.
Not just what I thought I guild alcohol.
I thought they just knew.
Yeah,
I got my stories mixed up.
It's a good way to go out.
I guess you go blind,
sarcastic,
but yeah,
I just think,
um,
the,
just exposure to Europeans killed the
great many of them.
And uh,
there's a guy named Dan Flores that I
had on my podcast.
It's a,
an expert in history of animals in North
America.
I think I heard that podcast.
Fucking guys are genius.
He's brilliant.
But he was talking about buffalo and
that when the native Americans died off
and like literally 90 percent of them
were killed by European diseases.
It's just crazy.
And a lot of them that were killed off
by Europeans,
the buffalo were in hunted anymore.
So they grew to these mammoth
proportions.
So it's his contention that those giant
fields of buffalo,
that people experience where there was
like thousands and thousands and
thousands of Buffalo stampeding and
cross the field that would have never
taken place if the same amount of native
Americans had been there previously
because they weren't controlling the
population.
They were the primary Predator because
all they did was follow these.
I mean that's why they had these
teepees.
A lot of them would follow the herds of
buffalo and they'd peck at it from the
outside.
It just nomadic culture.
Yeah.
And they just stayed with the Buffalo.
But they also kept their numbers down
because you know,
if there's several hundred native
Americans or how many in their camp,
right?
They're,
they're killing a couple buffalo a day
every day and everybody's eating it and
then there's no refrigerator.
So go after it again,
keep following it.
So they're basically just eating buffalo
and shooting arrows at them and taking
the populations down all the time.
That's so interesting.
It's crazy.
I'd never heard it before.
He was on my friend,
Steve Rinella,
his podcast,
and he explained it on there.
And then Rinella explained it to me also
independently,
and then I had him on the podcast.
Then I read his book too.
He's got two books to see if he could
find the titles of Dan Flores books.
Yeah,
I mean it makes sense.
One of them actually use a paper.
Populations expand exponentially.
Right.
So it's like the daily America,
right?
Is that it?
Cody America is.
His new book is a coyote.
America said about the history of the
coyote within North America.
Dude,
it's fascinating shit guys.
Genius.
Yeah.
He looks like he knows a lot about.
Like he knows a lot of shit with western
animals.
Any live.
He lives in New Mexico and you get
street cred with naturalists.
If you live in New Mexico,
you know that's a place for.
Whereas a lot of dudes that have a gray
ponytails.
Yeah,
like a lot of great dudes going a little
new agey,
a little,
a little scary.
A little new age.
Santa Fe.
That's where tate's from tape.
Fletcher's from their co owner of
caveman coffee.
Simply delicious and really pumps you
up.
Well played.
Thank you.
No,
I've never had one.
It was caveman,
nitro.
Um,
how susceptible are you to caffeine?
Two hundred 70 milligrams and that
motherfucker.
That's what versus how much in a cup of
coffee?
A large starbucks I think is that much
like a Venti starbucks.
How many times we've gone over this and
I can never remember the numbers.
I want to say that a Venti starbucks is
like 250 or 240 and that's it to 70.
It's a touch mode.
I don't really need it.
Alright Bro.
We'll see what scared I don't drink.
I thought you were kind of giving me the
vibe of like,
look,
I don't have too many.
No,
no,
no.
I just got a new shipment.
No,
that's not what I was giving the vibe.
I just always tell people because I've
given it to people and then like an hour
into the show,
they're like,
dude,
I'm on crack.