Yee ha.
We're live.
So Sierra if you it's my Senate right.
Sierra right.
Ciara Ciara.
Yeah.
Okay.
Listen it's like Shandra Shandra.
Yeah.
Ya ya.
If you had describe
your occupation someone.
Mm hmm.
How would you describe it in one word.
I would say humiliate tricks.
See this is what I learned about
you from my friend Chris Ryan.
He told me you got gotta get this girl.
I'm going to talk to her.
And then I went to Twitter page a Twitter
page is filled with some hilarious
stuff like one of them is about you
sending poop through the mail and then it
was like one of the only times the post
office opened up your box or they tried
to I asked him not to.
And they respected that.
Why did they want to
open up your box anyway.
Well I put it in a box of a very expensive
camera that I had and so when they
asked me like What is this.
I was like oh it's the camera.
And I said well how much was it.
And it's like well I got
nine hundred dollars.
And so they're like Oh we'll have to
repackage this and and then she's like
getting her like knife ready or razor
ready to open it up and I'm like oh no
it's it's fine you can you
can just leave it as is.
And she's like well if it gets broken
it's your responsibility and all this.
And I'm like It's fine.
It's okay.
Well there was more
than just poo in there.
There was like piss
there's toenail clippings.
There was a vial of my spit
like this guy had a hole like.
Value package for me.
How did How the fuck did you
get started in this business.
You seem like a fairly normal person.
Granted I've only met you for a short
amount of time and I seem completely
normal.
It's it's a really good story.
I was 17 years old at the time and I
was travelling abroad I was actually
exchange student in Japan and I was really
lonely like I say to the host family
and I didn't know any Japanese and I only
spoke English and so I was online just
all the time like.
Me and on and on.
I mean this was kind of before MySpace
or Facebook or anything like that but I'd
go to different like social
networking sites and talk to people.
And one day this guy starts talking
to me and he's a total pervert.
He's like into getting peed on and he
really has a thing for like panty hose and
and so he strikes a conversation with
me because he just thinks I'm very
attractive and all this.
And I was kind of like grossed out by
him but it intrigued at the same time you
know.
And so I was like OK.
I'm talking to a guy online
he can't do anything to me.
So I kept the you know lines
of communication open and
we'd talk here and there
and and he always tried to
convince me to meet him.
You really want me to pee
on him and stuff like that.
And I was like No I'm not going to
do that and I'm going to do that.
I kept turning him down.
And then one day he was like All right
look I get it you're not going to meet me
but I just I think you're pissed
should be bottled and sold.
It's like I was like All right buy it.
And like I didn't think you
serious those guys full of shit.
But I was like fine by it.
And he did.
He bought a 12 ounce like bottle just
like this of my urine for ten or fifty
dollars and after that you specify
the ounces that you had to be.
I don't think so.
Now I think just a bottle.
And so it was just a bottle.
Yeah.
Right.
And yeah From there I was like Oh there
has to be more guys like this guy found
me on accident like this was just a
mistake like what it would have been if I
went looking for guys like
this I give you promoted it.
Yeah.
Or like kind of sorted out.
And so it's like OK I've heard of like
women selling their used panties before I
know that's a thing.
And so I started searching to see
if there was like a website that.
Like I could be on or
something that catered to that.
And and I did.
I found this auction site that's just
like eBay but it specializes in like use
panties or socks or pantyhose or anything
like a woman can wear can auction on
the site.
And so I was like oh yeah
this is a I'm doing this.
And I started selling all sorts of stuff
and I've sold anything you can imagine
I've sold like my shirt my purse tampons
like hair from my hairbrush my bathroom
trash.
What is like hair from
your hairbrush go for.
How much can you sell that for.
I've always sell it once I think I sell
off like a hundred bucks versus like a
good log.
Well the thing about my shit is
it's kind of an interesting story.
So when I first started a guy I wanted
to buy my shirt and I was like Yeah I
just won't do this
because I think it's the.
I mean obviously the money but I
think it's an interesting story.
And so this guy bought my shirt for like
one hundred dollars and after that I
knew there.
You know I'm just I'm like I'm just it's
on my panties and it's gonna grow as I
don't want to sell my shirt
anyways.
Fast forward to this year and meanwhile
guys have always asked about my shirt.
I'm like I always gave them just the
most large absurd number like price wise
and they'd always be
like What the fuck now.
And then two weeks I was making money
otherwise but someone took me up on my
offer recently for four thousand dollars
to buy my shirt and he's since bought
it two other times this year.
So I've made a grand total of twelve
thousand dollars off my shirt.
Now you pay taxes on that
should you be telling say taxes.
Okay so what do you what do
you like list under occupation.
I have a really good accountant that
kind of takes care of all that shit
slinger.
Money comes from.
Like
I I make fetish videos
and stuff like that right.
Video producer this is just ice cream
or whipped cream rather for lack of a
better Cherry man cherry
on top whatever so.
So you started from this one
guy essentially this one guy.
Yeah have fueled your imagination.
Yeah yeah.
So I started seeing tangible things and
then from there I figured out how to
open up like my own phone lines where
I get paid per minute like like a phone
sex operator but I wasn't
like talking sexy to guys.
I kept getting fetish guys that were
really submissive and just wanted me to
berate them and talk shit to them.
And so you seek these guys out or did
they it just kind of was the path that I
ended up taking because I just I started
out doing this fetish thing and so such
just kind of was it because I like your
attitude towards people that wanted to
buy your shit your panties like
you fucking losers here it is.
What was that like.
No I think I I think naturally guys that
went by that sort of thing or like want
that kind of treatment.
So I would get guys wanting me to treat
them that way just like you know I'm
such a lowly loser and I want to be weird
pathetic little toilet and stress and
everything.
Wow yeah.
And then it was like when I knew I could
go about the sex industry in this way I
was like oh I want to
do it I want to do that.
I mean I tell people what I do for a
living I'm pretty open honest about it.
And for the most part people
think it's really cool.
So I think I don't think I would get the
same response if I were a stripper or
something like that but I don't think
there's a thing like being a stripper.
But a lot of people do and there's
less stigma associated with it.
So it's like I kind of found this weird
loophole in the sex industry where I was
so odd and because yes I'm a
Metro Oh yeah yeah exactly.
That kind of makes sense.
Yeah but why did it's this is a gig
where do you have an exit strategy.
Do you do you look at the future and go
out fucking shit and buckets forever.
Shit every day I so my shit songs
like Keep friends of these assholes.
You got 12 grand a year easy.
Yeah well for one guy I'll do it.
I always said I'll do it as as
long as it makes sense to do it.
You know open ended right.
But I try to be smart with my money.
You know.
I own a couple of houses back in Portland
and you know I paid for my education
that sort of thing.
So I just try and save as much as possible
because I don't think I'm gonna be
making as much money as I
do now the rest of my life.
Yeah well there's probably going to be
a drop off when you hit like 66 year old
shit's not worth twenty
eight year old shit.
Is that Gulf shit.
Kill.
There's something about Guilford just
MILF is still like hot but Guilford let me
leave her alone.
So do you do you have like a thought
process as far as like you like OK what is
my.
Is that all you do.
Do you have another gig.
No that's my only job for years now.
Oh my God.
Whoa.
It'll be so hard for you to work like
a regular job now especially would make
you think about like how much you can
make by shitting into a Tupperware
container.
Yeah I know.
Think about like how long you would have
to work in an office to make for ground
like you'd have done a
month at least right.
I got a good office job
is 50 grand a year right.
That's a good office.
That's a good living.
Yeah that's that's a
thousand bucks a week.
But you got to pay taxes rent.
So the tax is chopped away.
So to actually get four grand.
Yeah.
I think about that a lot because I'm
I'm very spoiled and I realize that that
that's a stripper issue too right.
So right.
Or like athlete issue like the one thing
we're like Yeah you're making a lot of
money for my time.
Yeah especially like athletes or you know
we're like when it's over it's fucking
over.
Yeah.
There's no you know it's like these Allen
Iverson characters that make hundreds
of millions dollars just eat through
all of it and you never planned on it
ending or having some sort of a
right strategy to continue it.
Yeah so you're just gonna just ride
that bitch right into the rocks.
Yeah.
Finish the plan.
Keep the throttle pegged.
I mean it hasn't.
It hasn't.
Lake gone down like I
continue to make more money.
Well you're still young and pretty.
Yeah exactly.
But how old are you now.
I'm twenty nine.
Yeah.
So there's got a solid ten years
for it starts getting really weird.
Yeah.
No way like 40 and you're
still shit into buckets.
Boy Hey you know maybe
you should not do that.
Or Oh no.
Why not one.
Just keep it if you're doing it now.
You enjoy doing it now.
Yeah it's great it's it's.
Then why stop.
Why am I talking about.
Why don't I just shut the fuck up.
Shut up.
I'm just thinking about your demise.
Why should concentrate most
terrible aspects of your job.
It's hard not to but
it's just so terrible.
What's strange but it's also like this
is not normally like an interview that I
would pursue but Chris kept insisting
that you were like really intelligent and
interesting.
Like he's like She's got
a very unique take on it.
Like it's not just that she's doing
this but she's just like a normal person
that while this is better
than working as a waitress.
Yes it's better.
Oh it's great.
I mean I work for myself and so yeah I
make my own hours and travel a lot and
actually travel and taking off to
Southeast Asia after a few days in L.A..
What do you do in Asia.
Shit on people.
You have a guy there waiting.
No I'm just backpacking just travelling.
Oh my life.
So just doing that for non-work.
Yeah.
Yeah exactly.
Now why you're there.
Do you work.
Do you have.
If you have an internet connection what
I do is because my bread and butter
right now are my videos
I just shot a time like
October and September and all that.
I just shot a bunch so I'm all set up
through February with my videos and they
just automatically.
I'll see you back them.
Yeah exactly.
Okay.
And so how often you release
videos like five days a week.
And when you do them do you do them
specifically for individuals or do you do
them for the public like you do both.
A lot of MA custom videos.
So guys will you know send me their
fantasy and you know I'll charge them and
make the video and then I also
really said to the public as well.
So like what's a typical fantasy
that a guy will call you up.
Hi my name is Doug I'm a fucking loser.
Do me a favor make a video about
how you want to piss in my mouth.
Doesn't worth
bother so many.
All I'll touch on on more recent when
I had this guy is but for me pretty
regularly.
And all of his fantasies involve being
in the dungeon and male chastity see male
chastity devices.
No I'm not shaming I've got it too.
It's basically like a cock cage and
I don't like those words together.
Yeah okay.
So you put your dick in this little cage
and you put like a little padlock on it
to lock him up and then like you know
the woman the dominatrix or whatever will
wear the key and it's all about just
kind of teasing this guy who can't touch
himself or get hard.
Really.
Yeah.
There we go.
Okay.
So what we're looking at for people
who are listening to this if you would
describe it he would describe it as hood.
There's a couple different kinds.
Yeah some metal ones some plastic ones.
Some of them spikes inside them.
Do they hurt the deck.
Yeah.
They start swelling up.
So if they get aroused
it's painful for them.
Yeah.
2 they take it off and
they're bleeding and stuff.
Well it depends.
If the woman has the key to it she
decides to unlock it basically.
So you do do you do.
Only videos or do you do like
one on ones with these guys.
No I don't meet anyone in person it's
online and all my videos I should specify
are like point of view.
So I'm talking to the camera so the guy
feels like I'm I'm talking like to him.
So like this video I'm
describing this guy.
You know he has this fetish for chastity.
So I have a habit with these
little devices and I'll
unlock it and I'll show it
to the camera and I'll I'll kind of move
my hand in pretending I'm putting it on
you know.
And then I lock them up and then I tease
Jimmy scroll up to the upper right hand
corner upper right above that
right above that right about that.
What the fuck is that.
Oh it looks like it goes in your eyes.
Yes this is a giant Christmas tree looking
thing that goes in your ass and it's
connected to one of those cock holsters.
Oh my God.
Yeah looks like it must strap
you in that can't go off.
Yeah you've got this.
Pole in your ass and then your
dick is locked up in a cage.
Wonderful.
Great idea.
This is ridiculous.
Yeah.
So this this one specific.
I like that you like that.
Well it's different.
Does that make sense it's for a girl.
It looks like the female jester.
And so this is like there's a whole
fetish that goes along with this right.
Yeah.
The woman being in control right and
kind of decides like when the man can be
released.
And so how do you do
that in a video though.
The guy's nowhere near you.
So like I said I'll be
looking at the camera.
I'm talking to cameras I'm talking
directly to the slave and I'll take full
chastity vice and I'll all kind of
like go into the camera pretending I'm
putting it on.
And then from there it's mostly just kind
of like a tease show or you know like
rub my boobs together
and talk all seductively.
And so the viewers watching it
as though I'm like seducing them.
Do you think you have in particular it's
pretty morbid so his fantasy is in this
dungeon and I lock him up and I have
this nurse outfit and I'm his nurse and I
talk about how I'm going to train him
to be to to to serve me orally.
But what I do too.
So you can do this.
What was it.
I had to at first remove all his teeth
because I didn't want teeth on my pussy.
So you know I banged his teeth out.
Yeah.
I'm just talking I'm talking about it.
So you wanted me to talk about
you know taking his teeth out.
He wanted this.
This is like his his what is your job to.
I don't know if he.
Probably not in real life.
Anyway a couple of clamps in
his ears to be steered you know.
And then he wanted me to tell him that
his vocal cords would be removed because
I don't wanna hear him complaining.
Whoa yeah this guy fucking hates himself.
Well it's funny because he
he was like Could you do it.
A very sweet sort of way.
Like he didn't want me to be
like a real mean mistress.
Like he wanted me to be like that kind
of juxtaposition of like oh really sweet
but I'm doing all these
terrible things to you.
Whoa yeah.
Now what do you find.
There's a stereotypical occupation or
a type of guy who wants this sort of
treatment.
I think I see where he
might be going with this.
I get all sorts of guys.
I think there's this like kind of cliché
that there are all these high powered
CEO right that want to be dominated.
I don't think that's the case.
I talk to all walks of life
like young old rich poor alike.
And so it's just a fan
it's like a foot thing.
Yeah.
Like just doing his thing a lick of
humiliation thing that some guys just have
that gene.
Yeah whatever it is.
Yeah I know it's a gene
but it's totally not.
Yeah you know I'm just.
Yeah.
The thing.
Have you ever tried to figure
out where it comes from.
Have you ever like been like.
Because I would assume that like from
the first time all these guys like you
know so much body piss you know people
like what the fuck are you talking about.
Yeah but have you ever tried to figure
out like what is wrong with these people.
All right you know what.
Did you get your perspective.
Well you know there's not a lot of
information about it but like the best
explanation I've heard I know like Dan
Savage talks about this and and the
author early Jesse bearing
you wrote that book perv.
He talks about it it's like there's this
kind of sensitive period for guys like
around the age of 9 where their mind is
just kind of almost malleable in this
way.
And they'll usually have an experience
that will you know set them off for the
rest of their life.
That hardwired them to
like whatever they like.
I think for most guys that's
like boobs and blowjobs.
But you know some of the time some some
weirdo gets in there some people it's
just shitting in your hair.
Yeah and and it really seems to be just
like really hardwired for guys like
because I as you can imagine a lot of
my clients don't want to like what they
like.
It's weird.
You know a lot of them are submissive and
you know guys aren't really allowed to
be submissive.
And so you know a lot of
men really struggle with it
and they try and like quit
it like they see it as this
addiction that they need to quit.
Wow.
But you can't.
Like let's let's just how male sexuality
works it seems like you can't just like
something else.
So you say you you think
it's just something that
happens along the way during
the developmental period.
Like a little hijacking of your of what
we would consider normal sexuality to
hear it piques this interests or
gets this fetish fired up
inside of a guy's mind.
Yeah I mean I don't like to
speculate about that sort of thing.
You know I don't want to play armchair
psychologists but like from there that
seems to be I think you've
earned the position.
Yeah maybe so but I mean as far as like
studies I've been on this like that
seems to be just kind of
the best explanation that
you have right now about it.
I've talked to Dan Savage about this.
And Chris as well.
Like we were talking about the guys
that might not even be gay that get they
develop a fetish for a
guy giving them oral sex.
I talked to those guys all the time.
Really.
Yeah it's not forced by the caller.
What's it called forced by forced
by force by force by sexuality.
I thought it was for spy for spies.
Yeah.
No it's guys that want me to force them
to like suck cock get fucked in the ass
and they'll tell me time and time again
I would never do this unless a woman was
forcing me to do it or a woman was
present encouraging me to do it.
It's a it's not about
I want to suck a dick.
It's about I want a woman to humiliate
me in this way because that's the most
humiliating thing I can think of.
See I guess I could kind of understand
like fetishes I could understand like you
know just get really turned down when
you see women's shoes or something wacky.
Yeah but there's something bizarre about
wanting to be humiliated like that's
I'm shocked when I find out how many
people have this thing where they want to
be humiliated.
Yeah.
What are they.
What are they tell you.
Do.
Do you ever have.
You have video conversations these
people or audio conversations.
These people on the phone.
Yeah I talked to them.
Yeah I talked to like on Skype like I do
camera phones one on one and so you see
them sometime if they turn on
their cameras see them right.
And you know.
Depends on if they want to be seen or not.
All right.
I don't really care.
But I mean I'm mostly talking to them
and it when they're aroused and usually
wants the comments like good bye.
So I don't have a lot of like you know
post-coital conversations or anything.
Right.
So I don't know.
It's just it just seems to me like
it's a different form of dirty talk.
Really.
Right.
So it's not necessarily that they really
do want you to force them to suck a
guy's dick.
They want to talk about it and beat off.
Well they don't have a choice with me
because I don't do sessions or anything.
Right.
But a lot of guys do like I'm friends
with women who work as dominatrix is.
And yeah they'll want to set up a session
where this woman like foursome just
like a deck or sell their house on
craigslist or something like that.
And so they do it.
Yeah.
Totally.
That's next level shit.
Right.
None of them do.
I mean some commercials too scared but
certainly guys that do but like the
ultimate for those guys is to find a
dominatrix that will get them a guy that's
kind of fuck them in the ass.
Yeah.
Or forced him to suck his dick.
I had a guy one time is this French guy
and he is really into the whole force by
thing and he was also into being like
blackmailed and exposed for what he was
doing and so he made a video for me.
He put my name on his for head
in big letters like sea air.
And his ass.
And then he just found like this black
guy with just the biggest dick ever.
And just like made a video of him like
blowing on with my name on its head and
then getting fucked in the ass and then
he wanted me to put together a whole
video where I'm like humiliating him
for this video and that I was going to
expose him to the world and expose them
to all his ex-girlfriends and he fucking
loved it like it all together.
So happy.
And it keeps paying me money
so I did more of it in the bag.
Why I this goofy French accent.
He's super flamboyant.
You'll probably watch this and be totally
stoked and talking about him right now
actually.
Wow.
You know what.
So is he gay.
You he's super flamboyant.
Yeah.
Like I would think he was gay but he's
apparently had girlfriends and part of
his kink is that he wants me to expose
him to his ex girlfriends for being the
big fag that he is.
Oh my God.
Cause I need it.
I need to punish him for tricking all
these women when he's really just a closet
fag.
So yeah that's his thing.
I mean he's clearly not totally
straight but bisexual I guess.
I guess yeah because he's
not coming to a man for this.
You know he's coming to me so
he's obviously attracted to women.
But you can go deep with this one.
Yeah I guess maybe he's attracted to
women or maybe he's dated women before but
always secretly wanted a man but knows
that it would be humiliating so that he
gets his kink like pretending
that you're going to expose him.
Yeah I mean maybe like you said Chris
Ryan was saying once an orientation and
one's a fetish.
So it's like yeah it's a fetish for
women but he's really gay the other way
around.
Didn't you have a situation where a guy
like gave you his bank account number
and everything to and wanted you
to pretend to steal money from now.
I get that thing all the time.
That's a normal one.
Yeah.
Well that's that kind of gets into
financial domination where oh that's a
financial domination issue.
Yeah.
I have learned all these terms.
Forced by financial domination financial
domination is basically where guys
literally get off on
giving a woman their money.
Like that's their king status.
Like get off on giving money they get
off on being blackmailed or being stolen
from.
That can be part of the can but a lot
of guys like I get a lot of guys just
sending me money for no reason just like
you got like and that's what they like
to do.
They like pleasing me they like
sacrificing for me and that sort of thing.
And some guys kind of get more into the
control aspect where they want to give
me their bank account number or their
credit card number and watch me like shop.
Credit card.
He put a GoPro on and go to the mall.
No I usually do it online.
I did a a double Cam session with this
girl one time and this guy put all his
credit card information into this Saks
Fifth Avenue website you know and then
gave us the password and was like Go
ahead shop and in an hour we spent ten
thousand dollars of his money just like
buying just stupid shit that ended up
like reselling.
I don't give a shit about Slender handbags
or anything like that but he liked
the idea of these like bitchy kind of
Paris Hilton type girls that would just
laugh at him and just
use them for his money.
Wow.
Yeah.
How strange huh.
Poof.
It's interesting though that these guys
at least have an outlet now like yeah.
I know what they did before the Internet.
Do you think it is somehow the Internet
because of the the access to people who
are willing to do this that it sort
of fosters this or helps it flourish.
Yeah I don't know.
I've thought about that.
I've wondered if these fetishes even
really existed before or if you know yeah.
Now these guys just have an outlet.
I have no idea.
Do you mind saying how much you make
doing something like this or is this
something you ought to keep to yourself.
Like you.
OK I understand.
Totally makes sense.
Especially we talking about twelve
thousand dollars just in logs you start
getting toenails and
bloggers and all that.
Who knows.
Sky's the limit.
Yeah.
Have you ever had someone that you did
this with that like insisted on meeting
you.
I don't know about insisted
I I've certainly had guys
like be really persistent.
But I mean the answer is just now.
I just thought of a guy I wanted to give
you like a million dollars to shit on.
Oh I did that.
Yeah.
No one's offered me quite that zero.
But is there some other effort really.
But it's gonna be a guy out there that
becomes obsessed with you and he's really
wealthy and he's like it's worth it.
It's worth it.
I film it for several camera angles.
Hire a professional crew.
Yeah.
I haven't quite gotten that offer yet
but so most most of time people are
content with the videos.
So yeah.
Yeah.
You seem to do pretty well.
How many of them have the average
asked to meet you in person.
Oh.
Pretty small percentage.
I mean it's hard to say like in terms of
there's some guys I never talk to they
just buy my videos round and there's
some guys who by Cam some guys by custom
videos.
So your videos are for sale to the public.
Like they're never never free.
Yeah.
I mean unless someone pirate some.
But yeah.
Oh OK.
So you have him on your Web site or
something like that and then someone signs
up with a credit card and.
Right.
So I have access.
Yeah.
So I like a a normal subscription Web
site you know like any kind of porn
website where you pay monthly and
get somebody's video streaming.
Think like two or three hundred and then
I have a few like pay per view sites
where guys can buy the
videos individually.
And how much of your day
is spent doing this stuff.
Mm hmm.
That's a good question.
I could have thought a lot and I wish
someone could just like watch me and see
when I'm working and when I'm not.
Cause you know when you work for
yourself at home it's this blend of like
working and then Facebook and then doing
the dishes and then you know working
and so it's it's hard for me to say how
much or how much time I really spend
doing it.
But I mean I put I try and put a lot of
effort into it because like we're saying
before it's not go last forever.
So.
And it seems quite lucrative.
Yeah yeah.
It's it's very strange.
How does your family know about this.
Yeah yeah.
You said that with eyes wide open.
I was raised.
Yeah.
No they know.
What do they think about it.
My mom and I don't really talk about it.
The last time we talked about it was
the first time I told her I had that
conversation go.
Well how did it is that my house and I
knew like it was situations obviously I
wasn't working at Starbucks you know
because I was making good money.
I had a fairly nice apartment you know
about a car and that sort of thing.
So it was like I knew she knew something
was up and so I just figured I might as
well tell her.
And
her response was I think she just
kind of nodded and was like OK.
And then I just assured her I was like
You know I'm really happy and I'm safe
and you know you don't need to worry.
And that was it.
She's got a reserved private person.
So I think you know it just kinda makes
her uncomfortable to talk about it.
So yeah we don't need to.
My dad thinks it's awesome.
Thank you.
Well so.
What.
Yeah.
My dad thinks it's really cool.
Your dad thinks it's cool.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
What was it he's cool about it.
Well I think he was just very surprised.
I mean the same situation like he knew
something was up and unlike my mom he
would make comments alluding to the
fact that he knew something was up but
wasn't like Western Conference because
well like I said like you know how does
one breach the subject.
Well I know you're
shitting in buckets kid.
I know it.
Well I think he thought it was
something like prostitute unquote.
Yeah I think he thought something maybe
worse than it was like Gallegos and he
was alluding to that.
Well no he like.
Like I got like about a car you know.
And I was told him as working at
Starbucks and he just was like wow kiddo
Starbucks is really paying you a lot.
You know like comments like that.
It's like I'm not buying
this but whatever.
And then when I finally told on it he
said like he kind of like stopped me at
one point.
He was just like you know I don't know
what's going on in your life but I just
want you know that I really love you.
And I just need to know that you're
OK and you're safe and and and that.
And I was like all right I should just
tell him because he obviously something
else is going on his head
that's way worse than it is.
Ryan SO I WAS JUST LIKE YOU
KNOW I basically humiliate
guys on the internet for
a living and I don't meet anyone and I
don't touch anyone I don't even really
get naked and and you're just like why.
I mean just know.
Like so many questions and he's just
like wow he's like that's that's amazing
you're a genius.
That's great.
Jimmy he said I said.
Wow.
Now we're dead.
Yeah.
Well he is he's gay so he's you know
wow he's not a you go for whatever
information I'll give you.
You know is that the most
traditional lifestyle himself.
So you know he's open minded he's cool.
I guess you have to be if you're gay.
Dad Yeah.
How did you when did he come
out to me I was 12 years old.
Oh yeah.
What about your mom.
We're 20
now my parents have been
divorced for like five years.
But at that point but we grow up very
religious who grow up Jehovah Witness
actually so they marry young
and have kids pretty young.
And
I was going to be one next question
about how many of these guys that you you
deal with are religious.
That's a good question.
I don't know.
You know I don't necessarily take polls
but there are some guys that like to be
humiliated for their religion one religion
and in particular that I'd rather not
mention publicly.
But I'd rather not mention
it they're too obvious.
Yeah a little fanatical Islam.
Yeah.
And to.
I mean you mentioned it.
So there's a guy who is a Muslim who buys
your videos must be humiliated for his
religion.
Yeah.
No.
And there's guys that will.
I don't do this because I'm not touching
on a 10 foot pole but there are guys
that will pay girls to like piss on
the Koran and they're not Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
So it's it's.
And make videos doing that.
Yeah.
Whoa.
And there's good money in it because
it's like so taboo like a thing that's so
taboo.
Someone's jerking off to it.
You know how hilarious
is what you just said.
There's good money.
It's like.
You're saying that like it's a good
river to catch fish and you know.
Like they got some nice
trout in that river.
You might die.
Eating good.
That is what it sounds like.
Good money in there.
There's good fishing in that river.
Wow wow.
Fuck yeah.
I had one Christian guy that went to meet
it to make a video of me like telling
him to denounce Jesus and worship me
and jerk off in the Bible and I did that
video because whatever Christians are
gonna are gonna come after me for that and
most likely Yeah most likely.
Yeah some pretty fun.
Jesus Christ.
How strange.
Hmm.
What a weird place to find yourself in.
Yeah.
Trapped in this or not trapped
but just in this world.
Yeah a strange world of people strange
fetishes and ideas and yeah kinks.
Does it make you like look I mean you
must look at people so so much different
than most other young girls that like go
walking down the street in Portland you
see people you don't I mean you've seen
the man behind the curtain so many these
freaks.
Yeah well nothing really surprises me
you know and I find that a lot of guys I
guess because I do what I do.
Like what is will tell
me what they're into.
Just like just very openly about it.
Just because they know I'm you're not
jaded as the right word but I was so
accustomed to hearing
like the weirdest shit.
Nothing really surprises me.
I think a lot of people get paranoid that
I assume they're into something weird
like a lot of guys like.
Everyone's always intrigued by what I
do and I tell them there's like wow.
And if it's a guy they're always like
you know they start asking questions but
then they backpedal and just be like
I'm not into this sort of thing.
I just think it's that just dig it.
It's like well I didn't think you were
until you said Is it weird with dating
and dating hasn't been a problem.
I've had it say three
serious relationships.
I see that is right there the
difference between men and women.
Yeah right there in a nutshell that you
say oh sorry it hasn't really been a
problem.
You know why.
Because you're a pretty young girl so
pretty young girls you guys like OK
whatever you do you shit in a bucket
whatever we're gonna fuck yeah I can deal
with that.
But if you know but if a girl met a guy
and the girls like what do you do for a
living is like well I take shits
and bucket said I'm a dude.
Girls I feel like I'm out.
Said look I'm not handling I don't
care how cute you are you fuck.
That's a good point and
somebody threw it before.
What do you do.
I set my toenail clippings shit guys I
saw it in underwear all day and I sent
them to dudes girls to be out
there would never take your text.
Yeah.
And that's I think you probably
guys would assume oh she's a freak.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
She's not going to say no to
anything that's girls off the chain.
She's out there peeing on
dudes we're paying for dudes.
Yeah that's a difference
few men and women.
Men will tolerate so
much more bizarre shit.
Yeah lot girls want to date
like a stripper necessarily.
Like they get jealous and
that's a little different.
That's different because
it's what you know.
Or a porn star certainly.
Would be really hard.
That's that's a hard one.
Yeah.
Yeah that's a real hard one.
I've had friends of dated porn stars and
then it gets to a point where it gets
kind of serious.
Yeah.
And you know these girls
come home from a get like.
I.
Had.
A friend who is a writer who's a writer
on Newsradio and he was dating this girl
who is a very prominent porn star at
the time and they were at dinner and she
you know they were you know trying to
have like small talk like normal people do
at the end of the day at dinner and he
was like Oh so what's going on there.
Hi Ben.
She's like I just had this hard anal
day with this guy pounding my ass.
I'm so tired.
Yeah.
And he was like sitting there like with
his jaw dropped like Oh Christ yeah.
Just he couldn't do it anymore.
No other guy.
I got another guy another guy who
was living with a porn star huh.
Dating living cool with it.
Fine.
No big deal.
Just her job man just her job dude.
And then one day she left a contract out
and you know going over the contract.
Mm hmm.
And he looked at the
contract and he's like.
Was airtight mean.
I know their timing airtight means a dick
in every hole in the mouth one but one
the veg and I like submarine.
And he was like That's it I'm out.
That was it.
The phrase air tight on a contract.
He just realized what he was getting
into it wasn't that his girlfriend was
going off and having sex with another man.
She was getting three men stuffed.
Now she's getting brutalized.
Mm hmm.
That's interesting.
I mean if you're okay with her your
lady you know having sex with other men.
Like what.
How do additional dicks really make a
difference to him it was just the straw
that broke the camel's back.
I know.
I mean I think he's probably close
to not being able to take it anyway.
You know sometimes people get into
things like it's not I it's not what they
want right.
But the girl is so much prettier than
most girls they get so much hotter.
Yeah like I have a friend who's another
one a different dude who has been living
with the porn star for a long time.
Yeah and then she retired recently.
She just does like videos and stuff.
But the whole time where
they were together she was
just getting gorilla fucked.
Yeah like four or five days a week.
And he's like this really nerdy.
Sort of like low key quiet guy.
And she's pretty hot.
Yeah.
And it's like the only way he's
ever gonna get that kind of a girl.
And I guess in him she finds stability.
Sure.
And a nice a meet someone who's kind
and you know and then she goes off and
gorilla fucked.
Mm hmm.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Right.
That's really what it's all about.
Like if it were who at the end of the day.
The real problem is our attitudes
about sex that's at the end of the day.
That's where that's the only place it
becomes a problem because if you're off
getting mass massaged nobody cares if
you go someplace and three people massage
you.
Nobody gives a shit.
Right.
But if three people fuck
you then we're like hey.
You're breaking the rules.
Yeah you know.
Yeah that's really like
in the porn industry.
I mean they're getting tested every week.
So you know it's it's kind of hard to
make the excuse that you know it's more
dangerous for your health because I think
I think their population is actually
like it.
There's less instances of US studios than
the general population are promiscuous
people and the general population.
That makes sense.
Yeah kind of makes sense because we have
to like how many people do you know get
tested every week.
You know Jamie Jamie
is three times a week.
Fuck yeah.
Using my fork he's just paranoid.
No I'm just kidding.
But yeah I would always think that.
Well if she gets tested on Friday then
we bang on the next following Thursday.
Who knows how many dicks have been
around since then infected Charlie Sheen.
You know that's what could happen.
Poor Charlie.
Who saw that coming.
Yeah no kidding.
Crazy Charlie.
Isn't that interesting Charlie.
For a guy is such a victim.
He is a victim.
He's a victim of circumstance.
The crack in the dick were in
the same room at the same time.
He didn't know which one to smoke who
the fuck I'm Tony Hinchcliffe now with
puns.
Do you.
That's a crazy story right.
Apparently he's like blowing guys but
I guess you two enough drugs you know I
guess you get cracked down enough
and you like who gives a shit.
Give me that Dick I'll suck it.
You know you're just off
the fucking rails right.
Yeah just bisexual could be just needed.
Well there was a story a long
time ago about a quarry game.
So it was Corey had Corey
Feldman apparently said that
Corey Haim got fucked by
Charles she sort of alluded to it.
Like when they were when
Corey Haim was really young.
But you know films got crazy.
So who knows.
Allegedly.
Allegedly crazy.
Is crazy but you know I wasn't surprised.
Right.
We were surprised that
Charlie Sheen got it.
Well he's got HIV or HIV curse of our
pee politically correct on the show at
least.
That's super important.
He's got HIV.
Yeah.
No.
That didn't surprise me at all.
It's a total train wreck.
He's a freak.
Yeah right.
I don't know why people like celebrate
him so much like he just seems like an
awful person like.
Well at one point in time what he did
was the unthinkable because he was a
superstar right.
Two and a half men giant sit com on
the biggest it comes in the country.
He had been in Platoon and Wall Street.
He was Michael Douglas's son.
I mean it is Jesus or Martin
Sheen son Michael Douglas playing.
They were different names.
I forget what I'm talking about when
he had that like tiger blood meltdown.
Everyone thought it was so funny.
But it's like it's like he has kids.
Yeah but that's because he was doing
the unthinkable he was owning it.
And in this country what we hate is when
someone gets busted doing something and
tries and they go to rehab.
Yeah you know.
God forbid you know like you get a quitter
no matter what you do.
You could get busted doing anything
you know like Mel Gibson went to rehab
because he was yelling at a Jew when he
got pulled over who's yelling the cop
calling him a Jew and he's like I got to
go to rehab for hate and Jews like you
went to rehab didn't go to
rehab for that he did right.
Yes you're hurting me.
Yeah I think they have
a Jew hating rehab cop.
I don't think the cop was even Jewish I
was just drunk and crazy but it's like
that.
That's what led him like you
gotta you gotta make amends.
You gotta find something
to get pulled together.
Gotta go to rehab to pull together.
That's the move in this country
we demand that you go to rehab.
Yeah.
We can't even do the
kind of rehab at home.
No not good enough.
Yeah I'm gonna go there.
Like if you cheat on your wife.
That's why I'm a sex addict.
Gotta go to rehab.
It a go.
Powerful and I have all this money
and women will fuck me and nope.
No.
Rehab addiction.
Got it.
Got a problem.
Got a sickness got illness.
Gotta go to rehab.
That's what it's like an Amy Winehouse
song would make people go to rehab.
Yeah well rehab is a fact.
When did they invent rehab.
I really want to know.
Mm hmm mm hmm.
And.
It wasn't.
Betty Ford wasn't I don't know.
She didn't she's the Betty Ford Clinic.
Was that the first one.
Good question.
I think you might have nailed it.
That might be it because that was
what it used to be when I was a kid.
It was always oh you went to Betty Ford.
Yeah.
I was like what you would say when
someone had fucked up and just completely
blown it right.
Yeah.
Do you ever get dudes that are former
sex addicts like they have gone to sex
rehab and they've had counselors
tell them that they need to stop and
I don't know but I'm sure I have.
I've never talked about it talked to
any guys about specifically but there is
definitely a certain percentage of guys
that think they are like addicted to me
and it could be kind of confusing because
I think sometimes that's part of the
fantasy is that they're addicted to me.
But there are some guys that legitimately
have a problem with their spending and
their drug off habits and just how much
this fetish world kind of consumes them.
And they may make poor decisions and
like especially if you get into the whole
like blackmail exposure fetish
like oh yeah I had a guy one time
I really felt bad for him actually.
Nice guy weed cam.
And like he would dress up you know
and women's clothing like and not like
classic clothing just like outrageous
kind of bimbo like tutus and just crazy
slutty makeup and then he would get a
bunch of used condoms and put them in his
mouth oh shit and then take pictures and
he would and he would want me to like
you know pretend to blackmail him and
threaten to send him and he would give me
you'd give me like real people's like
email address like ex-girlfriends and
stuff like that already are you.
He was also one of the guys that would
laugh when we make a video and release
it.
And so he didn't pay me a lot of
money to make a video and release it.
And then like a week or so
later I got an email from
a dominatrix that he saw in person and
it was like a really serious e-mail and
she was just like hey you know I know you
made this video for for this guy and I
was you know I just want you to know
that he really struggles with this fetish
and he's he's kind of suicidal and he's
really freaking out about you know that
you put this up even though he asked
you to do it and I just want to kind of
reach out to you and ask if you
would consider taking it down.
And so I did.
And.
Yeah.
I mean give me a match.
I don't know what you're into Joe but
like imagine like whatever you're into
sexually and of it like that feeling
you get were almost not quite
uncontrollable but it just kind of
where you lose it a little bit sexually.
Because you're just so like intoxicated.
Like that feeling for you know being
exposed in this way where there's condoms
in your mouth and you're like dressed
as a woman and stuff like that and then
you come and you're
like Oh fuck what an I.
A lot of guys like really struggle with
that where they get their their desire
comes from this place of just something
they actually really do not one really
like scares them and figure them out
like it's just sex just so that's so
strange to have the the two contrasting
sides sort of right next to each other.
Yeah.
Pre and Post orgasm.
Right.
Why I feel like we all maybe kind of
share that a little bit girls too.
Well I mean.
Well I mean just the idea that I mean
sex just normal sex is kind of weird and
kind of gross.
If you're not turned on you know like
or like if you're like watching normal
porn like it looks really awesome and
feels great when you're aroused and then
you comments like you.
Yeah.
Who was I.
It's like going together you know.
So.
And that's just maybe
two very lower degree.
But yeah you go into these weird
fetishes and that difference is much more
defined.
Well there's definitely a
difference when you're there.
You know there's definitely a difference.
Like if having actual sex with someone
and being aroused and then what it must
appear if you weren't horny at all.
Yeah.
You know.
Especially if you look gross naked.
Right.
You know people look gross naked
then and get fucked they just.
And then when it's over the like Oh yeah.
You look at it all and you like what the
fuck am I what am I doing what is this.
What is this weird urge that your body's
natural reward system sort of been
hijacked.
Yeah.
Just to get you to come in someone's
mouth and then what is this.
Like what is going on here.
And especially if you're a guy it's
like it seems like you're here.
It was like cognitively impaired and
your priorities are just almost yeah.
You're 100 percent driving nice the way
I've described it is like when a guy has
an erection it's like sitting
in the backseat of a really
long bus or some other
dude's driving but it's hard to talk to
him because all the windows are rolled
down and the engine is really loud and
you yell and you know where the fuck
you're going you're watching your life
take place through a dirty windshield.
Like where are we going.
That's it.
Is this so true.
And then once you have an orgasm all
the sudden when the clouds of confusion
part you wake up and you're at the
front of the bus holding out the wheel.
Yeah.
I mean like what the
heck is going on here.
That's literally what it feels like.
Yeah.
To a guy.
But that's how that's how there's 7
billion people on the planet like that.
That switch that goes off where massive
impairment of function of the thought.
Yeah it just gets shot down all those
fused you start blowing off circuits start
shutting off.
That's how people made sure the
7 billion people on the planet.
Yeah it's true.
Especially back when people had never
figured out soap or wiping or anything.
I mean who knows what people smelled like
200 thousand years ago but there were
people two hundred thousand years ago
and they were having sex with each other.
You got those pheromones going now.
I mean barely.
Probably puts you over the
top barely allows you to.
I mean the guys that we on by my underwear
I wear it for a day but they want me
to wear it for a week.
Do you lie and say Don't
don't say no I don't.
Of course you don't know.
Did they ask you to do things
in the underwear like fart.
No.
Yeah I get that shit.
Oh Jesus.
And masturbate.
And anything that can secrete off my body
if someone wants to know wants to eat.
Oh God
is there ever anything that
people have asked you to do.
And he said no.
Meet them.
Yeah sure.
Well because I'm kind of you know I'm
always in control and like the female Dom
I won't do anything that
depicts me as submissive.
I don't get naked.
I get pretty close.
I get pretty scantily clad but
I don't get completely naked.
Yeah.
That's that's about it.
If it's I mean if it's a
video that I can just do.
Just me and the camera and I'm in control.
I'll probably do it.
I have guys ever tried to get you to
not be in control of guys ever tried to
switch it around on you.
Yeah.
Pretty rarely though.
I think most guys kind of get Yeah.
They know what I'm about so they know
it's kind of a lost cause to try otherwise
but once in a while they know what
you're about that's Larry cause you got a
reputation in the humiliation world.
Exactly.
So fucking strange.
It's a strange existence.
It really is fucking weird but it seems
like it's a flourishing existence.
That's what's strange about it is that
there's obviously a certain percentage of
the population that wants
to service yeah yeah.
And it seems like because I know I
haven't been in the porn industry and it
seems like mainstream porn is losing a
lot of money with piracy and whatnot.
I mean I'm sure they're still doing pretty
well but they've lost most of it it's
been the bottom's dropped out of it.
The point where they make money
now ironically is it really.
Yeah that's where they make money.
Yeah.
It's kind of funny.
Thing that's ironic really.
It's like Alanis Morissette Ironic.
It's odd.
Yeah that's where the money coming in
gets that necessary pay per view to pay
per view in hotels.
Yeah but who the fuck doesn't have
a laptop like who's doing them.
It's so like I've seen people even say
like hey don't go to these free sites you
know you should support your local your
performers and you know buy porn but
most people like whatever you know.
Most people don't care.
Yeah it's business but I see a lot of
like former mainstream porn girls like
doing what I do now.
So it kind seems like it's
kind of the new thing.
And there's something to be said about
the more personal interaction and the
fact that there's no middle man.
It's just it's me you know.
When you email me you get me
and write and control too.
Yeah.
Also that you don't
have to worry about it.
Yeah.
You know that's that's got
to be a big aspect of it.
Because if you're doing films and then
you know you don't get to I guess maybe
you decide if you have that kind of power
who you have sex with or what you do.
But if you want to make more money right.
To do other stuff you know.
Yeah it's got to be tricky.
Yeah totally.
Yeah I might.
I don't do anything I don't I do.
So that's pretty sweet.
Yeah I think in that sense the like the
porn business is probably going to go
sort of the way of the
record business in that.
Like the record business was controlled
by these big groups and they're kind of
they're worthless now because no
one's selling records anymore.
And sort of the porn business was like
this big thing where like all these guys
who are the producers and the content
creators like these companies these big
companies they were making millions and
millions of dollars and the girls made
some money.
Yeah but they didn't make
the bulk of the money.
They were the ones that everybody was
paying to see but most the money was being
made by the producers.
Well that's fucking dried up and now the
girls are kind of owning it themselves
now doing stuff like what you're doing.
Yeah and like a lot of the other one I
see like different people on Twitter they
offer like videos and stuff like
private videos they'll do with people.
Yeah.
And I think I mean if a guy is even the
slightest bit fanboy ish they like that
their money is gone directly
to the person and not you know.
Yeah.
Yeah yeah.
Well sure.
I mean there's a lot of
that fanboy shit too.
That's for sure.
There's fat like.
I don't think people who are outside
of the business or aren't in somehow or
another know somebody in the business.
But there's guys that are
like fuckin sports fans.
There's sports fans of porn stars
like they wouldn't want to get like
autographs.
And they they like their fans like Oh
yeah well the avian every year they have
the whole e convention and it's all
just the girls signing autographs.
And what kind of freaks
show up at those things.
It's fun.
I go to your every year.
Because one of the clips for sale on
the sites that I sell my videos off of.
They have a booth and so I'll go over
there and sign and it's so mainstream most
guys don't know who I am but
everyone's smile they will.
But yeah it's kind of like whatever
you imagine a guy like that would go to
that.
You're probably right.
It's exactly what you're picturing.
Yeah but that's also honestly to
the same dudes who go to comic book
conventions.
Yeah you know the same dudes
are really into baseball.
You know we could all be in that group.
Yeah let's throw a few
wrong turns or right turns.
Depending on your perspective.
Yeah.
We have a weird thing in this country
particularly about sex and anything else
where you're really into it.
It's it's OK you can be addicted to
playing golf and everybody has somehow
there's Jamie he's on that
golf course every day.
That's crazy fuck.
But if you're at home beaten
off every day you're a freak.
Yeah you're a loser.
You know you could have gigs and gigs
of porn and you just really love it.
And you talk about the old days and you
know you have like like you know like
Mike Tyson needs to watch like old
Jack Dempsey films and learn technique.
You know like
you can't be like that with porn because
if you like that with porn you're a
fucking loser.
Yeah it's weird.
It is weird.
I mean as long as you're getting
everything else done in life it's not
interfering in any excitable way I guess.
I mean even if it is getting in
the way so is everything else.
People get addicted to those food
people that are nuts about food.
People that love gambling.
Yeah
that gets in the way everything gets in
the way but we look at those things as
somehow or another being
somehow or another being a
better thing to be addicted
to.
Mm hmm.
Yeah preferable Yeah.
Yeah I think you're right.
Yeah.
Yeah we're a little fucked
up about sex for sure.
A lot of fucked up sex but whatever.
Right.
I mean that's how you pay
the bills imagine a perfect
world where everybody was
open minded.
Would you have to do you'd have to be
working at Starbucks just like you told
you.
I know all these guys would be honest
with their wives about what they're into
and then they never come to me for it.
Yeah so it's probably better
that we live in a strange world.
Jamie world.
Yeah I think so.
Echoes of the Puritans who
founded the strange country.
What did you go to college.
Yeah.
What did you go to college for.
I studied psychology.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Minored in business.
Oh perfect.
Jesus Christ you're born for this.
That's hilarious.
Yeah.
So this is a perfect gig for you.
Yeah I think so while I fit right into it.
I don't know how much longer we could
talk about this but I think you kind of
nailed it.
I think I've had a feeling this
is gonna be one of those podcasts.
Yeah.
How long has it been an hour
an hour an hour and 45 minutes.
Okay.
Can I can I do a little selfless Sean
short so please do some self impression so
I haven't mentioned this at all publicly
yet so I wanted to save it for this
podcast because I know you
got a pretty big audience.
I have for the past couple years been
working on a documentary with a filmmaker
Julian Shaw from Australia and he's been
doing a documentary on me filming me
and we just opened up a Facebook about
it and we'll be launching a kickstarter
to help fund the rest of
the movie pretty soon.
So if people want to join and get updates
it's Facebook dot com forward slash
ruin me movie.
So it's essentially a documentary about
what we're talking about here about me.
Yeah about humiliation about how these
guys want you to do these things to the
exact threaten them.
Yeah and we've filmed a lot of it mostly
through private investors but we're
gonna do some crowd sourcing here soon.
So yeah it's gonna be called ruined me.
So it's uh yeah Facebook dot com fraud
slash ruin me movie for updates on that.
All right beautiful.
Thank you.
Thank you sir.
Very nice meeting you too
young Jamie take us out.