Five,
four,
three,
two.
Oh,
we jumped the gun.
Hey Amy.
Hey,
good.
Thanks for doing this man.
Appreciate it.
I'm glad to be here.
How's things?
Well,
outside of Vegas.
Everything's good.
I know,
right?
You have to say that everybody.
I mean this,
these things that happen that sort of
just changed the whole world.
You gotta think that's probably one of
the reasons why these psychos do it in
the first place.
Right?
So that everyone talks about them.
It becomes their,
their big fireworks.
Fourth of July grand finale before they
leave.
Yeah.
There was a very interesting post by a
guy named Robert King on psychology
today and I guess he's doing research in
this and he talked about it as a way for
men to get or chase status and that he
saw two bombs.
I think one was at 23 and one at 41 in
terms of the ages that people do this
and it does tend to be men who have some
kind of their marriage breaks up,
they lose their job in their forties are
the young men are just chasing status,
so it's,
it's,
it's at least some kind of explanation
other than,
oh,
someone just went wild.
They just went crazy.
Which is not helpful because it doesn't
tell us really what we can do to maybe
prevented or look at how do we look for
these people who do this?
Yeah.
Well,
to prevent it,
you have to lock all men up.
Not for that.
That's the only way.
I mean not obviously not the only way,
but it's all men.
That's a giant issue,
right?
I mean it's,
you never see women go on mass
shootings,
but well without men who we'd still be
living in grass huts,
so
listen,
I'm a man.
I'm all pro men,
but it's very weird that it's entirely
men who do mass shootings and drive
trucks into crowds and that kind of
thing.
Well,
I think we may start seeing women do
that,
but actually I don't think it's weird
that it's men because men,
if you look at how men and women evolved
to get partners,
women just have to look hot.
You have to look like you're fertile and
young and have good genes,
which is what we consider beauty.
These what feminists say are arbitrary
standards of beauty or anything like
that.
They're very across cultures.
Men like women with this hourglass
figure and who have long shiny hair and
who are not 72 because if you had sex
with a 72 year old,
your genes died out out.
Yeah.
This feminist thing about arbitrary
standards of beauty as a person who is
deeply entrenched in science,
like that's gotta be frustrating,
right?
Because you're looking at something
that's not accurate.
It's you're pushing a narrative that's
just not accurate.
There's this very takeaway culture
takeaway.
You know all the,
all your personal feelings about human
beings and you look at the mammal,
the human mammal,
and it's.
It's very clear why the certain males
are gravitating towards certain and
contrary or conversely why certain
females or gravitating towards certain
males.
It's biological and this.
It's so unhelpful.
It's really awful.
This idea that people should like you
for Watson down the inside,
we don't see the people.
If you look at porn,
it's not the woman who buys a homeless
man a sandwich.
You know who in the porn.
It's the woman with those features that
are just cross culturally appreciated by
men,
but it's also too,
we're talking only about sexual,
right?
Because people do like you for who you
are on the inside.
Like Melissa McCarthy is a perfect
example.
She's as vibrant,
hilarious woman and no one's.
No one's holding her up as the standard
of beauty or sexual attractiveness.
You know,
you're.
You're looking at her as this fun person
and that's why millions of people go see
her in movies and her tv shows is giant
hit mean.
It's literally what's on the inside and
how she carries herself and she is very
vibrant and if you look at that cross
cultural research,
David Buss who is an evolutionary
psychologist,
did the big,
big cross cultural study and kindness
was what both men and women wanted.
I think that was the top,
the top of each list.
But if you prioritize,
well,
okay,
well what do I.
What are my must haves in a partner?
A guy is not going to want a very old,
unattractive woman as his partner.
If he can do better and a woman is not
going to want to have the guy who is
sleeping in grandma's basement playing
Atari,
Atari or whatever.
I'm a girl so I don't know anything
about football or video games.
My boyfriend tried to educate me on the
way over about some,
I don't know,
some guy who said something insulting to
female sports announcer,
Cam Newton pretty popular quarterback
said,
uh,
he got a question from a beat reporter
that works for the his team and ask them
something about our wide receivers route
running.
And he said it's surprising that a girl
is asking about route running or
something like that,
and he got a lot of shit about it right
now you've got to drop from a sponsor.
So sort of going on further,
is that all he said,
it's surprising that a girl,
I believe so in then they,
I heard that they went further into it,
off off the record a little bit and he
was rude,
is what she said.
Oh,
we really expect the football,
the quarterback to be the height of,
you know,
politeness and social etiquette and
okay,
he shouldn't have said this.
And I think that these,
there are some incredible women who are
sports announcers.
So I'm told by the boyfriend and I think
it's sexy to be a knowledgeable woman in
sports.
Um,
however we now prosecute everybody for
everything.
And the reason we do that is there's too
much media.
Everybody's got a microphone.
Everyone's on twitter.
So now this stuff,
that dumb stuff,
people would have said another era that
would have just gone off into the ether.
Now it is just,
it's a new story.
Do you think is that,
is it,
I mean I'm sure it is that,
but isn't it also that we're examining
behavior on a much more scale
than we've ever done before and we see
things that we don't like and we're
highlighting those things in a much more
aggressive way than we've ever done
before.
It's almost like there's accelerating
social evolution that's going on right
now and along the way you're getting a
lot of bumps and a lot of weird stuff
that's happening.
A lot of social justice warrior stuff
and then you've got a lot of all right
stuff on the other side and they're
battling it out with each other and it's
almost like these intense extremes on
this new landscape and people are
jockeying for positioning on this new
cultural standard playing field.
Well,
I think what's happened is that now
everyone has a microphone and just so
everyone's on twitter,
everyone can make a tweet that put out a
tweet that gets tweeted and retweeted
two,
4 million people and so people are
looking to have standing and they're
doing it by putting out their opinions
and they also.
When you're saying this about these
tribes,
they do it to signal,
look,
I'm part of this tribe.
I'm a social justice warrior.
I'm on the right.
I'm Antifa.
And so I think that that's a big part of
it.
So they're looking for criminal
behavior,
socially criminal behavior and whereas,
you know this guy,
I mean,
do I really expect every quarterback to
have the most pc views?
No.
And okay,
he's gonna lose his sponsorship when he
says something like this,
but you know,
if you open the quarterback can,
you're going to see quarterback stuff in
there and it's not,
you know,
emily post,
well first of all with quarterbacks and
with any football players,
you're dealing with head trauma,
you are 100 percent dealing with head
trauma.
There is an extremely high likelihood
that all those guys on the playing field
or have erratic behavior due to the fact
they're head's been smashed a 150
fucking times a year since they were a
kid.
And that is just a fact.
There's no getting around that.
Yeah,
and I actually,
I really appreciate that.
We're starting to see people look at
that and bring that out so parents know,
you know,
do you want your son to play football or
to play some other sport?
Yeah,
I mean look,
I have kids and I wouldn't want my kids
to fight even though I'm a commentator
and fighting.
Right.
I just think like,
God,
if you really want to do it,
I mean I'm,
I'll support them in anything they
really want to do,
but I would tell them,
but it's just the upside and the
downside.
Like if you can get out,
like some guys get out like floyd
mayweather.
I mean he's just a brilliant tactician
and a incredibly good defensively and he
got out relatively unscathed,
but you really won't know how unscathed
until 10,
15 years from now when you see them
struggling with his words.
Right,
right.
It's just not worth it.
Life is.
Life is short,
but it's long if you're fucked up.
Absolutely.
And you see that from these guys.
I read some story about that the other
day.
I'm trying to think who is the guy so,
so sad and this thing about it showing
up much later where you get terribly
mental,
mentally ill people.
They make those tradeoffs where they
think,
okay,
well I can get money and fame way and
it's quick
and everything like that,
but they don't really realize what the
longterm consequences will be.
Well,
I think a lot of people in the got into
football and even people that got into
fighting,
they didn't.
They didn't know as much back then when
they first entered this sort of journey.
Especially football.
I mean football being we really.
There was no conversation about that.
Think about like the Oj trial,
you know,
I've been kind of on the Oj kick lately
because I started watching that Cuba
gooding jr series where they sort of
reenact and it's really kind of freaking
me out because bringing back the
memories of the nineties and what,
what it was like when that,
when that thing went down,
I was with my girlfriend at the time and
we were sitting in front of the
television holding hands and you know,
like waiting for the verdict and when,
when they said not guilty,
she threw her hands on her face.
Like she had just seen a horrible car
accident.
She was like,
oh my God.
Oh my God.
She kept shooting.
And
now today they're saying the,
the,
the very doctor that was working with Oj
said if they were going to do that case
again today,
they would absolutely bring up.
See?
Yeah.
I think you're right about that.
Absolutely.
And there's so many football players who
got in just not knowing who will come
out like that.
I think within a number of years,
yeah,
that was only 20 years ago,
23 years ago,
whatever it was.
That's not that long ago,
so 23 years ago nobody thought about
brain trauma came to facebook,
which is just nuts.
Well now these guys are debilitated.
There's a whole bunch of different
lawsuits that are going on right now
with the NFL and you're seeing these
older players.
I mean they have on real sports at
Bryant Gumbel and they're sitting there
and they're shaking and they can't
control themselves and you're like,
wow,
well this is,
this is on
unheard of 20 years ago,
30 years ago,
we never thought of this.
This was never in the public discourse.
Yeah,
and I suspect if you go back and look at
those tapes sort of forensically that
you'll see that kind of thing just
shaking and,
and also that if you look at to take a
look at over football players,
how many people have these,
these diseases and mental illness that's
related to this head trauma?
Yeah,
I'm sure quite a bit,
but mean this football player guy that
we're talking about,
Cam Newton.
You know what,
the only thing that's wrong with.
I mean it's not even wrong.
I mean he's trying to get sponsors.
That's the whole deal.
Yeah,
and if you're whatever Coca Cola or
whatever the company is,
you don't want someone representing you
that does something like that.
No.
And so it's sort of normal.
Yeah,
well it's normal that they say,
okay,
we're dumping you and it's normal that
he would say it,
but what's always funny is that these,
these companies,
they profess surprise when it's like,
really?
You thought that this person was going
to be the sort of curtailed reigned in
person.
It's like with Kathy Griffin.
Oh,
you just figured out that she says
events of things that was a surprise to
you?
Well it wasn't.
I mean with,
with her was just so poorly thought out.
It's like,
what do you,
what is
the message there?
You're holding a bloody head like Jesus
Christ.
Like when we.
I mean,
if you want to hold up the bloody head
of some murderous dictator who's killed
a bunch of people,
then I kind of understand.
But even then like what,
what is,
are you isis?
Like,
what's this message?
Right.
Well,
I think she didn't think it out and it
was just okay,
outrage,
trying to be shocking,
trying to be shocking.
And then the sort of fake apology and
then okay,
take it back.
It's the fake apology.
And then it was like a,
he's a bullying and he broke me.
And like,
like playing the victim card.
Yeah,
you're a comedian,
you know,
and I know comedians have like that.
Then you know what someone's going to
heckle you on and so you have stuff
ready for that.
And this thing like where she's all
like,
for me,
my career is over.
I don't have a career now is like,
oh all right,
just take a couple months off.
You'll be fun.
Yeah.
Right.
People forget there's some new outrage.
Well there's always going to be.
It's always has some new crazy fucking
thing and it was also going to be a
bunch of people that are probably
excited that you did that too.
They'll calm down after a while.
It won't be in the news anymore and
yeah,
it's just we live in a time where
everything is hyper examined.
Yeah,
it is,
and so that standard and that's why I
think we have to be more lenient with
people.
This idea that you say something awful
and then you're excommunicated.
You lose your job.
You're going to be living in a dumpster.
This is really wrong.
We need to understand that to be human
is to be an asshole.
We're all assholes.
We all say shitty things to people and I
try to recognize my assholeishness and
apologize when I've been awful and make
good.
If sometimes you have to put some money
into making good.
It's.
It's what the situation calls for
William.
No,
right.
Look,
especially when you run into someone in
traffic and they're screaming at someone
and giving them the finger like you
don't know what that poor person has
been through that day.
Like obviously they're there.
They're at nine,
they didn't start at one when they were
in that traffic incident.
They're probably at nine already and
then this Saben
motherfucker.
That's where they're coming from.
Raw nerve.
Yeah.
And so it really is important.
People see it as a sign of weakness,
but it's actually a sign of strength to
say,
I'm ashamed I did this bad thing.
I did this recently.
I shouted on the phone,
very bad to this.
Some really nice person at the Kaiser
Pharmacy just because you know,
she should magically solve my problem.
It wasn't a problem she could solve,
but after I did that I thought like,
oh,
this is so terrible.
Number one,
I talked to her.
She's kind,
she didn't deserve this.
So I actually,
I went in and I asked for her and I
said,
I'm so ashamed.
I spoke to you terribly.
You didn't deserve this.
You're very kind to date and purpose.
Uh,
excuse me in person,
in person because well,
I was going there anyway to pick up my
medication.
So it was easier.
But I actually asked to speak to her
because I think it means something to
people.
When you do that thing where you say you
put your ego aside and say,
look,
I was bad and I was wrong.
People appreciate that you're doing
that.
It gives them something back and it
steals from people to just do something
and then think,
ha ha,
I got away with it because you didn't.
You know it and actually they know
it and they feel bad and I don't like to
make people feel bad.
Well also you feel less about yourself
and I think that's as important as
anything like one of the things about,
unless you're a sociopath,
when you do something mean to someone,
you feel bad about yourself,
you don't judge yourself the same way.
You look at yourself and your own
behavior and you go,
wow,
I'm,
I'm faulty.
I'm like,
I don't.
I'm not proud of that.
That's awful.
Like what I did was a bad thing.
I feel bad about who I am and if you
just deny that you're just building up
this weird wall of disconnect between
you and reality and you're going to make
more and more shitty choices if you do
that and you are.
I,
I think that you are the sum total of
your behavior so you can feel all sorts
of ways.
You can fail wimpy and afraid and feel
like you don't want to apologize,
but if you behave the good way,
the better way,
the way you want to be,
then you're that person.
It doesn't matter what your feelings
are.
Well,
this is one of the main issues that I
have today with this right versus left
social justice warrior thing that's
going on,
like people are being so fucking
aggressive and so rude and so just the
way they are trying to silence people
from speaking,
the way they're describing people and
attacking people.
It's a.
it's a very aggressive way and it's very
short sided because when you have that
sort of short sided aggressive,
what's you're doing is like you're
yelling,
shut the fuck up.
Well,
when you yelled,
shut the fuck up.
Nobody wants to shut the fuck up.
They don't just go,
oh,
okay.
Like you're,
you're.
This is a childish way of approaching an
issue like the,
the,
the more objective nuanced,
more thought out way of approaching it
is to take into consideration how this
other person is going to view what
you're saying.
Like the only way to get people to
change is to present them and art or
some sort of an argument or some sort of
a,
an idea that is both polite and well
thought out and,
and there's no social issue involved in
it.
Like there's no negative back and forth
between you where you're trying to get
them and they're trying to get you.
The only way to get someone to really
take into consideration your ideas is to
have them in some way respect your,
like you.
And as soon as you tell someone,
shut the fuck up.
Like,
well,
that's out.
Okay,
well that's out,
and now it's just like you're just going
to win by having more people yell or
what are you going to do?
You're gonna put a ski mask on and break
windows like,
is that how you're going to get this
done?
You're not.
You're just going to cause an action
reaction,
you're just going to cause this sort of
rubber band effect.
We pull it back and then it snaps and
then you've got some sort of ridiculous
infighting where people go full tribal
and they get one side goes against the
other side and this is what you're
seeing today and,
and you're seeing people do it to get
attention as well.
You're seeing people do it clearly when
they know the cameras are on,
they ramp it up and starts yelling
obscenities
and being more ridiculous about it and
it's very odd.
It's very odd to watch it play out,
you know,
so short sided.
Yeah,
they practically wait.
Okay.
Are you rolling?
Three,
two,
one.
Okay.
Smash the window.
You know what you said reminded me the
worst thing a man can say to a woman is
calmed down.
It always has the opposite effect.
At cop once said that to me,
I called the local police station about
some problem.
The Guy told me,
calm down.
I'm like,
does that work on your girlfriend?
Because it's not working on me.
It never works in any woman's.
So here's a tip,
dude,
what doesn't work on men either doesn't
work on anybody,
maybe it works on kids,
not just kids and work on anyone.
I tell my kids to calm down.
The opposite effect,
always shut off for any of these things.
He's rude approaches and so the thing
is,
when you get somebody,
what you do is you provoke somebody
defensiveness.
It's a fight or flight reaction.
You know this happens to us on an
emotional plane as well,
and so you're provoking that whole
reaction that's designed to make you get
away from a bear or some type of wild
animal.
But instead of writing and burning off
all those biochemicals,
it's all pooling in you.
You're filling with hate and rage.
So this is not a state in which you can
listen to anyone and so the moment you
take it up to that area of invoking
somebody hate and defense and rage and
all that stuff,
they are,
they're so far away from listening,
you might as well just crawl under the
desk and go read a novel.
It's just so pointless to even engage
with them.
And so the people who do want to engage,
if you engage on a pole light level,
maybe possibly if someone is just not
totally reeled in by confirmation bias,
they might listen and confirmation bias
of course is that thing where we believe
what we already believe and when we
throw away any disconfirming evidence.
And so you know,
if you recognize these propensities,
we have to do that to believe what we
believe,
to be tribal,
to stick to this side,
to not listened to,
not change our views.
The maybe have a hope of changing your
views and maybe if you try to listen to
other people who,
you know,
there are differing views who are polite
and trying to engage on a rational
level.
You can learn something.
I try to be open minded.
I try to take criticism.
I try to not rejected out of hand.
Of course I don't take the criticism
that comes from dear bitch,
you ugly whore.
Like to get those.
Yeah.
But I always think like,
just drop the deer.
If you're going to start with bitch,
you ugly whore.
The humor comes in,
comes in when they're being polite,
whether criticize it.
Yeah.
I love that.
It's so funny.
Well,
people,
when they get in arguments,
it becomes a competition,
you know,
and that's,
that's a big part of the whole insult
thing in the part,
just shouting down thing.
It's like you're trying to win and
you're trying to win an argument that
very few people ever.
When,
I mean it's,
it's,
it's usually like both people walk away
just disgusted with a loss,
you know,
it's very rare that unless someone is
egregious,
Lee incorrect and you literally have to
shout them down because what they're
doing is horrific and you need to point
it out to them,
but usually not the case.
Well,
usually it's disagreement,
you know,
most of the time.
Right.
And these people think they're so
convinced it's religion.
They think that they're right.
We are on the left,
we're right,
we're on the right,
were right and they are just unwilling
to listen.
It's cartoonish.
Now I saw something the other day about
this great girl at Bernard,
Tony Braxton,
and she's this young journalist student.
Tony around accidents a I r e e k.
anyway,
I can see what a strange name.
I know she's from Ohio and from a poor
family and got a scholarship to Bernard
and you see how hard she works.
She's a journalist and she looks to see
different sides of things and I really
respect that in her because you don't
see that in a lot of people that age.
There's just such polarization.
I forget why I was bringing her up.
It's this thing.
Oh,
I know she posted something so she wrote
an article.
They have,
you know,
Columbia Republicans who are,
who knows?
What do they want to bring in?
Like Ben Shapiro.
I love the idea that anyone would be
afraid of Ben Shapiro behind me on the
street.
I'd be like,
oh great.
Fantastic.
Dark Alley.
Ben Shapiro.
No problem.
Sorry Ben.
But who's a nice guy?
I don't know him,
but he seems fine.
You know,
we're a little Yamaka and everything.
I'm post Jewish so I can make Jewish
jokes Jewish.
So I draped it.
Yes.
I'm an escape Jew and so they.
Somebody posted something about being
against white supremacists and it was
really about like they're going to have
a Republican speaker,
you know,
and there was so ugly about Republicans
and I thought,
God,
have you ever talked to one?
My parents are Republicans.
My friend Tom,
who this Christian lawyer I know,
he feeds the homeless because he thinks
that split.
Jesus said you should do.
These are not horrible people who are
burning crosses in lawns.
They're your next door neighbor
depending on where you live,
grows
generalization.
That doesn't do anyone any good,
especially when you're talking about
someone like Ben Shapiro.
Ben is a very well read,
very well thought out,
very reasonable,
and when you talk to him in person,
he's a very kind guy.
There's nothing wrong with him.
He's just conservative,
you know,
and whether I agree or disagree and I'm
sure I disagree with him on a lot of
things.
I had a really pleasant time talking to
him.
I think he's a very nice guy.
His ideas and his,
his.
The way he speaks is very well thought
out.
He speaks very quickly and it's
intimidating to a lot of people,
his ideas and the the,
the idea that he is this extremely
articulate right wing guy immediately.
The best way to silence that is white
supremacy.
Kay Kay Kay.
He's a Nazi.
I've seen people call Ben Shapiro and
Nazi.
He wears a fucking Yama.
I know he's an Orthodox Jew,
right?
It's hilarious.
So amazing.
It's so amazing and that kind of thing.
We see it on both sides and there was
something the other day,
so Dana Loesch,
she's a commentator and she's apparently
very pro nra,
so people send her just the ugliest
tweets and I'm sure I disagree with her
on a number of things.
They don't really look at her views
extensively,
but they were things like,
you know,
I hope you die in a hail of gunfire or
something like that.
Along those lines,
outside the NRA headquarters,
but I love this one.
The Guy said,
dear God,
and he spelled God,
g,
Dash d,
we really are going to pussy foot onto
the oh and in God on the vowels.
Like I love that.
That's like extreme left people that
won't even acknowledged the existence of
God.
So even as they write it,
they put a,
like an Asterick I think he might've
been a religious guy or something,
you know,
maybe.
So,
I mean,
I write books with fucking the title and
I always want them to write the full
fuck,
but it's just,
it was like enough to get the fuck in
there with the asterisk and everything.
Funny that we're afraid of words like
that.
Like,
oh my God,
like,
what do you,
what do you think you're confusing
someone with like,
oh,
they actually meant,
Petunia,
you know,
asterisk makes it all.
Okay.
So there are people,
and my favorite ones,
some people reviewed one of my books.
They would say like,
this book is filled with profanity.
It has fuck on the,
what was your first fucking clue?
Yeah,
it's a really,
really weird with that kind of stuff.
It's just,
you know,
what,
what they get upset about.
Um,
I know Dana,
I've met her.
She's very nice.
You know,
I've been on our show once,
right after that,
Cecil,
the lion thing happened and brighter.
Vaguely remember that she's,
uh,
she's,
she's like a,
a right wing woman.
I'm pretty sure she started at her life.
I think she was very left wing and one
point in time and saw a lot of hypocrisy
in the left and switched over to the
right.
But again,
it's like we were talking about before,
she's very tribal,
you know,
she's nra tribal,
pro gun second amendment and they dig
their heels in and that's it.
You know,
bumps.
I want the bump stocks,
I want the fucking full auto.
I want magazines,
big magazines.
Like no matter what happens and I think
you know,
to be,
I call myself a neither.
I'm neither a Democrat or Republican.
I'm libertarian,
fiscally conservative.
And I think that helps me identifying as
sort of a.
nothing helps me to not succumb to so
much of that.
You know,
I of course being human,
I do have views and I tend to stick to
them,
but I try to be open.
Well,
when you go nra though,
I mean this is the thing is like if
you're like a very outspoken nra person
and she was famously involved in one of
those really aggressive videos about the
NRA.
Just see that video that was,
it was like a sort of like,
it was really recently very
controversial video talking about gun
ownership and there's,
it was like a sort of pro nra video that
was like widely criticized on the left
and I think the,
I know the subject of gun ownership and
just what happens to these mass
tragedies.
I mean it is,
it is a conversation that stirs up
tribalism logic.
It's,
it's a very complex,
very.
And also mental health issues.
I mean I want to know what was going on
with this.
I want to know
this Vegas Guy,
was he on some sort of psych meds
because a giant percentage of these
people are and what's the ramifications
of that and why?
What is causing this fucked up behavior?
Is it simply,
you know,
what people love to call toxic
masculinity manifesting itself in the
most horrific form?
Or is there some other factors?
I mean,
these disassociative psych meds that
they put these people on that allow them
to just deal with life in a way where
they just don't feel,
you know?
I mean,
have you ever been on psych meds?
Yeah,
I took Zoloft ones and.
Oh,
and I forgot.
I take adderall every day.
You're pilled up.
Fuck.
It's great.
I'm not on it now because I would talk
so fast.
I might hurt people with my speech.
So a lot of people in here that are on
adderall because they feel like when
they do a podcast they need to be ramped
up to keep up.
And Jesus,
it's so obvious.
You're like slow.
I want to get them drinks.
And sometimes I offer them drinks.
I'm like,
let's,
let's have a drink.
I know.
I know better even though it slows me
down and I'm on the same dose at seven
point five milligrams and the total
lightweight of lightweights.
But um,
so the Zoloft I took because I went to a
psychiatrist in New York and you know,
date,
they actually tried to give me like
lithium and all these other things like
for manic depressive people.
My friends said you're manic depressive.
And basically it's so crazy because all
I was,
it wasn't some kind of inexplicable,
horrible depression.
I didn't have a boyfriend.
I didn't have any money and I was bombed
and I took us all off.
Then I realized that just shaved off
half of my personality.
So I did the really dumb thing you're
not supposed to do,
which is just I thought like fuck this
shit,
flushed it down the toilet.
And then I fell off a cliff emotionally.
I think that was a bad idea.
Not only that,
what'd you do those poor fish river?
My follow this bodies.
Yeah.
Well they said that there's like Lotus a
bowl,
like trace elements.
Like you could actually measure trace
elements and some water supplies of,
of antidepressants probably.
Sorry everybody water.
But isn't that funny that,
that saying that like I've talked to
people that are extremely defensive
about their use of antidepressants and
when you bring in,
anybody discusses,
especially someone like you who has
tried them and is open about like,
what was the cause here I was bummed
out.
I didn't have a boyfriend.
Like if you say that to people they love
to,
to generalize depression as a disease,
it is a disease,
there is a mental issue and no,
no exercise,
diet,
change of lifestyle,
you know,
love in your life,
none of that's going to fix it.
Having a career that's really
fulfilling,
none of that was going to fix it.
I have a disease and I need medicine for
my disease.
See,
that's such a.
just a sort of wary one note idea.
And I love the research of this guy,
Randy Nessie.
I love him.
He's a psychiatrist and an evolutionary
psychologist and he talks about how,
I suppose it's any sse and you can go on
his website.
He's now at University of Arizona
because he was in Michigan's freezing
there.
Everybody out eventually moved to
Arizona.
All these professors.
Anyway,
um,
so he talks about how depression,
you know,
the sad feelings,
these are adaptive and so when something
bad happens to you,
being sad causes you to slow down,
you have the features of a sad person
which has causes other people to gather
around you and be empathetic.
And if it goes on for too long,
you may chase people away.
But this allows you to think about what
dumb fucking thing you did that made you
get in the state.
And I talk about how emotions are
motivational tools.
We think of them as sort of like
wallpaper for our head to decorate our
life,
but they're not emotions when you're
happy that says do more of that when
you're depressed.
I stopped doing that,
reflect on it.
And so there are different kinds of
depression.
There's a kind that is this medical
depression that's inexplicable and that
maybe drugs are needed for.
But often I think that doctors,
psychiatrists,
um,
my experience was in my experience
listening to other people because I
write this advice column and I get
letters from everybody.
And I've been doing this for a long time
since the early nineties,
is that doctors just say here's a pill,
and a lot of these antidepressants,
they've been shown that they don't
really work and so maybe it's a placebo
effect,
which actually is a thing,
but a lot of times it's people are
medicating away this helpful part of
depression and sadness,
which is reflecting and drawing people
to you and all of this.
And so this idea of it's a disease that,
that it's also used with alcoholism.
It just this idea.
People like to put these things in these
neat boxes and it doesn't really work.
Yeah,
I couldn't say that any better.
And I think that there are people that
do have mental issues that do need
medication.
We're not generalizing.
I mean,
I think just like some people have liver
problems,
some people have thyroid issues,
there are absolutely people that have
issues with their brain's ability to
produce serotonin.
I mean it's just a fact.
And how many of those people is the real
question and to generalize completely,
let's say,
you know,
all depression is a disease that should
be medicated or all depression can be
cured with exercise.
I don't know.
I don't think it's healthy to go either
way.
I think there's.
I know many people that have been in
really bad places in their life.
They got on some sort of an Ssri and
then they started feeling better and
then they wean themselves off and now
their life is in a way better place.
Like a good buddy of mine.
He was suicidal.
He got an a in.
The really interesting thing is when he
got on medication,
like he couldn't find the right one.
And that is really so baffling.
So it's,
it's,
it's science obviously,
right?
When you're talking about medicine,
you're talking about medication.
But there,
there's this little lot of guesswork to
this whole thing.
You know,
I have to say,
because I'm writing a big expo,
say now I didn't intend to do this,
but I tried to shove it off on both Nina
tie shall send a doctor's eads and they
wouldn't,
they wouldn't bite.
So I'm,
I'm doing it reading medical research.
I can't even begin to tell you how non
evidence based maybe even most of our
medical carriers,
it's so terrible and I'm lucky that I
have a psychiatrist now who is really
evidence based and went on for future
training,
further training because I had been
taking Ritalin,
which just made me jumpy.
It didn't really help me with my focus.
Ritalin and Zoloft.
Well the sky,
he changed me.
I told him I actually started taking.
I was self medicating.
This is bad.
This is before I read as much science as
I do.
I was taking Musinex in.
The guy's like,
oh my gosh.
Yeah.
We used to kind of get behind the
counter.
It's like in some kind of like they make
meth out of it,
you know,
they said you have to like sign,
it was buying at different pharmacies
and hoping I wouldn't get arrested,
you know.
Meanwhile,
I'm just taking it to right,
not,
you know,
do anything.
I didn't have meth lab in my basement.
I don't have a basement.
So that helps.
Um,
but um,
so this guy said,
okay,
we're gonna change you because I told
him I couldn't focus.
He said you can't take this,
it's making your heart race or whatever.
And he said that this adderall,
what it does that's different,
it pushes a little dope me up out into
your brain besides being a dopamine
reuptake inhibitor,
which we hear with Serotonin,
with the antidepressants.
So it regulates that.
But it also goes like spurt.
Here's little dopamine.
And the first day I was on that,
the first pill I took,
it was the best writing day I'd had
really in 20 years.
It was amazing.
And so I'm still on the same dosage and
everything.
But this guy,
he gave me my life back because it was
tortured or right before that and,
and,
and that really was a big deal and so
much of a medical care,
if you look at the stuff on Diet and
unit tie shows has been great on this.
Gary Tobbs,
the EADS,
you know,
there are other people on this who have
shown that look,
don't eat this high carb,
low fat diet and the government
recommends it,
will make you sick and fat.
And I'm here this high fat,
low carbohydrate diet for many people,
maybe not all because we have individual
differences.
This seems to be the most healthy diet
and also not eating polyunsaturated
fatty acids and stuff like that that we
know about.
Um,
more and more.
And you see more and more on that.
Yeah.
Right.
And so,
but my doctor,
Kaiser,
I love to say that those healthy whole
grains on the wall,
there is no such thing as healthy whole
grains.
I haven't eaten a,
been on a hamburger since 2009,
you know,
I just wouldn't.
It's just dumb.
I eat bacon and grease all day and I'm
very healthy.
I,
um,
even though my doctor actually thinks
I'm going to have artica heart detect by
next week,
the truth is if you actually think,
well,
because my cholesterol is like 303 and
then.
But what I know,
and this is from Mike eades,
the doctor who wrote the protein power,
he,
um,
he has this great blog where he talks,
he's very evidenced based but explains
it very well.
There are these ratios.
You look at what's the ratio of your
triglycerides to hdl.
And so basically my ratios,
which the doctors don't have,
Kaiser don't understood.
They are so good that I say that I'm as
likely to have a heart attack.
I am to be kicked in the knee by a
Unicorn.
I'm so not in danger of that and it's
just terrible.
They sent me this letter to say,
eat a low fat diet.
Thanks
crazy though.
The doctors are doing this.
I mean,
I understand that they went to school a
long time ago and I understand that a
long time ago.
That is what people thought that if your
cholesterol hit a certain point,
you needed to take some sort of
medication to lower your cholesterol,
but if you eat a healthy diet and your
body is doing well on that healthy diet
like you have to take into consideration
like what are the whole,
what are the,
what are all the factors involved in in
health and vitality and the
understanding of hdl versus ldl and the
balance of triglycerides.
If you're a doctor and you don't
understand that and you're giving advice
and you're telling people to get on
statens,
it's fucking disturb.
It's terrible,
it's terrible,
and those statens are fucking terrible
for you.
Terrible effects.
They can cause diabetes.
They have just the worst side effects
and this is the thing that I look at
when I'm looking at research or looking
at because I do what I call applied
behavioral science,
so it's science help as opposed to self
help.
I look at what are the tradeoffs.
If I tell you this,
what are the tradeoffs in doing this
where you know,
where are you going to have a problem?
How worthwhile is this solution?
And,
and that's what doctors aren't looking
at when they get people statens.
It's sort of like from the drug
companies mouths to you,
your gut.
Well,
it's just so
many doctors are basing their decisions
and the,
the advice they give on really old
evidence or excuse me,
really old knowledge
evidence,
quote unquote keys fraudulent quote
unquote science and it's so terrible and
sees,
yeah,
he did this quote unquote research,
but he excluded countries that didn't
show searches this,
this is,
it was in the,
I think it was in the fifties.
He did this multiple countries study
where he looked at what people ate and
what he did.
It's like this,
there's a story from the Holocaust where
a guy shot all these bullseyes in the
wall and some army person came up to him
and said,
how did you learn to shoot that way?
He said,
it's easy.
I first shot the wall.
Then I drew the bullseye.
And so that's when an sell keys did with
this research and he excluded any
countries that didn't fit what he wanted
to say,
which is eat this diet that we've been
eating.
Our government told us to eat for years,
this high carb,
low fat diet that actually causes you to
be just hungry motherfucker all day.
And then also spikes.
Yeah.
And so,
you know what I learned from Gary Tobbs,
who's actually a friend of mine,
so I got an early on the low carb thing
because I heard while he was writing
this,
that carbs.
So this is potatoes,
starchy vegetables,
fruits,
fruit juice,
they sugar these things cause the
insulin secretion that puts on fat that
makes you diabetic and all these things.
And there's some indication that maybe
Alzheimer's is diabetes.
Three diabetes of the brain.
They need more evidence on that.
But personally I do not eat sugar.
I eat one tiny little ice cream thing a
week just so I won't feel totally
deprived.
But um,
when I,
when I Bacon and stuff all day,
steak and green beans,
drowning and butter,
I don't feel deprived and it's better
for me.
And um,
you know,
if you can do that,
that's not much of a sacrifice.
Okay.
I won't eat the bond.
Big Deal.
I read
Garrett's book and I had him on the
podcast as well.
It's a fascinating thing,
very controversial to a lot of people
email me.
I need to get on and refute what he said
is.
All right,
relax.
I literally got dozens of people that
did that to me,
but the thing that's most shocking,
I started following mark sisson's primal
blueprint diet and when I,
when I started doing it,
cut out all the sugar pretty much.
I mean I fuck around every now and then,
but one of the things that was so
shocking was my appetite,
my appetite was so unmanageable like it
used to.
I was ravenous.
I would eat and then I would be
exhausted and then I would be fucking
ravenous like four hours later.
Like if I went three hours or four hours
without eating,
I was starving and I've,
I regularly do intermittent fasting now
or I'll do 14 hours between,
between.
It's really good for your body and I
lost a lot of body fat for doing that
and then the big.
But the big thing was that when it came
time to eat,
it wasn't like I was holding my breath
the entire time,
but finally it wasn't that at all.
It was just so normal and I was like,
oh.
So there's some other process that I
thought I,
I attributed to hunger.
I was thinking,
oh,
okay,
I get really hungry,
but it's not just hunger,
it's insulin,
it's
insulin.
It makes you hungry in that way.
Before I stopped eating bread,
I went to starbucks in culver city and I
would always get the thing that was the
regular fatty thing,
Chris,
on whatever.
And I know I love all that kind of food.
So good.
But I got by accident,
somebody gave me the sugar,
the fat free,
whatever.
And after about 20 minutes I wanted to
bite off somebody's arm in line.
I wanted to kill people.
The counter get some things.
It makes you feel so terrible.
And I looked at all those years I had
dieted and I,
at one point I just thought like,
ah,
you know what?
If anybody's like me,
a little rounder than other people,
fuck them.
And I started going to bobby's diner in
New York City having this chicken potato
Burrito,
which now he wouldn't eat the bread and
the potato,
but um,
and I started losing weight just by
eating like a normal human being and not
excluding fat.
And that's what,
that was sort of instructive for this.
And now I just basically tried to eat
fat all day,
Greece,
more grease and if you don't have that
hunger.
And also I know it's so much healthier
for me to not eat bread and to not eat
these,
we don't eat bad oils anymore.
And,
and just to tell you another weight loss
story,
um,
my boyfriend,
he was elmore Leonard's researcher,
the crime writer for 33 years and he had
to do this book Djibouti.
And I begged him not to go to effort
because my boyfriend has his look as I'm
American kidnap me and jared is going to
get kidnapped that I knew would get
kidnapped.
I mean he just.
Yeah.
So I just,
you know,
I begged him not to kidnap a lot of
people in effort.
Nobody would kidnap my boyfriend.
He's nervous.
Was that the pills talking?
Is it?
No,
it's gonna be mad at me for saying this,
but he wants,
got his pocket picked in Paris.
He just looks like the American guy
that,
you know,
do something too.
So.
And he's a big guy from Detroit so it's
not like he's wimpy or anything.
Um,
but I um,
he needed to lose some weight and some
doctor gave him these like candy bars
that are $230,
you know,
and,
and the thing of like,
being from Detroit,
not wanting to be ripped off,
I said okay,
if you do exactly what I say because
he's a guy guy so he's not like,
you know,
I'll do exactly what you say,
but I said you will lose weight and you
will not be hungry.
So I put them on a diet of a bacon,
eggs.
He could eat meat,
no vegetables and just copy and spring
water vegetables.
Yeah.
This is like,
this is like,
remember Dr Atkins,
the Atkins Induction Diet,
you have to take magnesium or it can be
blocked up like the Berlin Wall inside
itself.
But um,
he lost 30 pounds in five weeks while
sitting in his chair researching
Djibouti.
The book delmore ended up doing and he
did not leave his chair.
He turns librarians on the phone and
embassy people and stuff like that.
But is no vegetables a good idea?
It seems like you need vitamins now
eventually.
But actually tops has said,
we talked about this once and he said
basically that meat has all the vitamins
except vitamin C and I'm sort of
paraphrasing from long time ago,
so forgive me if I get this wrong,
but.
And that if you.
But if you are eating meat rather than
carbs,
maybe you don't get vitamin C deficient,
you look at them Osi and also the,
the Eskimos.
I think it's the nun.
I think Stefansson was a guy who was up
there and before they started eating a
western diet,
they just stayed blubber and whale meat
and I guess they maybe a penguin here
and there.
The penguins.
Penguins.
I think around our cake with a different
part of the world and nuggets you,
I'm really good on geography.
Lincoln say south.
I failed geography obviously.
Right?
I know that they,
and they also had extremely low rates of
cancer and there were just healthier
humans.
Right.
It's changed as soon as they started
eating the western Diet and Tom's brings
up the pima Indians.
Same thing.
Do they have horrible problems with
diabetes?
Do also though the
to,
to throw some other stuff in there.
That was also an issue with alcoholism
and cigarettes.
There's a,
the,
the cancer and the heart attacks and a
lot of the things that happened with the
nun.
A lot of people,
there's a correlation between extreme
consumption of cigarettes and alcohol.
So it's,
it's not just a,
the American diet,
it's all the vices that go along with
that.
We're good at producing this.
Yeah,
we suck.
We import horrible things.
I mean,
liquid we did not.
We obviously you and I weren't alive,
but whoever looked like us that did that
to the native Americans introducing
alcohol to them and they,
you know,
they didn't know what to do with it.
Bodies weren't used to it.
Yeah.
It's,
um,
there's a doctor,
that I'm going to have on the soon who
is on twitter.
I mean,
I have no idea if this guy's not a.
yeah,
everybody is,
um,
I'll tell you right now,
but this gentleman is a,
he's a full carnivore.
All he does is eat meat and he holds a
bunch of records,
uh,
in a,
like athletic pursuits.
It's really kind of interesting.
You know,
this,
this Guy Stephen Phinney is it,
I'll tell you in a minute,
I'll pull them up real quick,
but he and I had been going back and
forth trying to figure out a time to get
him on the podcast,
but he's 50 years old and it's pretty
impressive what he's been able to do and
all he does is eat meat,
doesn't eat anything but meat,
you know,
and he's an md,
so of course the fucking Internet's not
working here.
Going on with the Internet here.
Young Jamie month working.
Yeah,
piece of shit.
Laptop.
This laptop has been the worst one I've
ever had as far as like connecting,
like it takes forever to reconnect.
Yeah.
I hate that anywhere.
I never leave the house.
I'm always on my big computer.
You never leave the house?
Not Lately.
I wrote a book for three years that
spent three years trying to kill me.
So Jesus Christ,
my boyfriend brought me food.
Otherwise I would've eaten frozen hot
dogs for three years.
Select the meat guy.
But that's not good,
right?
I wasn't.
But the book,
you know,
what happened.
So you plan on writing this book and I
thought,
Oh,
this'll be easier.
So this is this book on how to transform
to be confident.
And um,
I thought,
okay,
this will be easy because I've been
writing this in my column for so many
years.
And then I look into the science and I
look a little deeper and I think,
oh my God,
this is so horrible.
And what happens is.
So this professor will do these people,
these researchers,
they do some research but they don't
totally support it.
And then they don't work in a
transdisciplinary way.
So you have to support.
This one's researched with that one's
research and this became this big thing.
And I just kept having nightmares about
my editor who's a nice man,
chasing me down the street asking for my
advanced back with an x and x.
and x or acts like an x.
right?
Um,
well this guy's A.
I don't even know his full name.
His uh,
his twitter name is s Baker.
He is a heroin.
When kidding to hear trades.
S Baker md is his twitter name,
the sport world record holding masters
50 plus athlete nutrition for
performance and health,
healthcare and not sick care.
No medical advice here.
And all he does is eat meat.
Well,
nothing but meat.
The Guy I mentioned.
So Stephen Finney,
he is a dietary researcher.
He and Jeff Volek wrote a very good book
on low carb.
Jeff,
Alex,
also dietary researcher and Finney I
think bicycles competitively or very
intensely and he says that I'm eating
low carb.
There's apparently some hump you get
over,
but then that is better.
It gives you more energy than this
whole,
like drink some gatorade that people
have held as the conventional wisdom.
Yeah,
but it's not the case with like extreme
endurance sports and oh there's one guy
that we talked about.
What do you got here?
Sean Baker.
Dr Sean Baker,
Carnivore Diet Zero carb Diet plan guy
looks healthy as fuck.
He's on the right hand side.
Yeah,
he does mean he's jacked and he's dunks
basketballs and lift weights and shit.
But he might just be some athletic
freak.
I,
I just don't know if it's jeans too.
It could be.
I'm lucky I have good genes,
you know,
the boyfriend looks at a saltine and he
gained three pounds and I'm lucky.
So my family were eastern European
should hold Jews and you know,
probably wasn't a lot of food and I
don't know,
somehow my body learn to manage that
having lot and having not a lot and it
manages it better.
Sure.
Um,
I'm just,
I'm wondering whether or not that's a
really a viable diet to just eat only
meat.
It just seems like,
well the Messiah do it and,
and,
and they,
and they did it.
And so the question is,
are you missing nutrients?
And I'm not the person to answer this.
Are you missing nutrients?
And that's the problem with being
vegetarian.
There's a guy named Chris Kresser who's
posted on this.
Oh Great.
I love this.
Yeah.
He.
And so he has some really good posts
about what you're missing.
If you provide your tarion and people
say,
well,
I take vitamins,
but can you get the vitamins in the way
you need in the way your body uses them
from taking vitamin pills or even from
eating,
you have to eat a ton of this,
you know,
I don't know,
being curt or something.
Um,
and I don't want to have soy.
That's the problem.
That's the dishonesty.
But vegetarianism and some people
knowingly make that tradeoff,
but I sure wouldn't.
I'm sorry.
As much as the bunnies are cute and
Chris Kresser was a Vegan for a long
time and you know,
he's had,
he had some pretty serious health
consequences because of that.
But you know,
that's just him.
Some people were fine with the Vegan
diet and that's one of the most
important things to talk about is that
the,
the biodiversity in human beings is
very,
it is a broad,
broad spectrum of what people need and
what people don't need.
Which is why some people like my friend
Brian,
his mom can't even touch Brazil nuts.
Have she ate a Brazil nut.
She'd go into shock and she'd be dead.
I mean,
I can eat them all day long.
They taste like shit.
I don't totally like them,
but you know,
there's,
there's a giant curve was
right.
Yeah.
This is the individual differences thing
that I was talking about before.
And there's,
there's this big push to say,
oh,
men and women are alike and groups are
no different from each other,
but you know,
you don't see Jews as NBA basketball
stars and Jews and people from
northeastern Europe tend to have lactose
tolerance in a way other people do not.
So where we are from where we mainly our
evolution took place that,
you know,
and I mean that goes back way,
way,
way back,
um,
that,
that affects our skills,
our abilities as well as our digestive
abilities.
You know,
can you eat this kind of thing,
can you drink liquor and not be really
effected by it.
All those things.
And so that's the stuff that people
don't like to look at everyone the way
you were talking about before that
people like to say it's just like this.
It's this thing,
this is a disease and it's horrible.
You know that,
that lack of nuance that's just so
stupid and it's so sort of anti solution
what people like to do when people do
that,
that thing of,
you know,
saying things are one way.
It's often in a way too.
I think that people try to feel superior
who try to simplify things too much.
They do that so that too,
because we'd like to understand things,
so I think it's that.
And then also there's a tendency to want
to prosecute people to say you are a
slovenly fat person and the reason you
are a heavy is that you did not go to
the gym and I went to the gym and I am a
Holy Gym Goer and you are a scummy
terribles couch sitter and that's not
the case.
In fact,
tobbs wrote a great piece for New York
magazine about how we think exercise
makes us thinner,
but it doesn't and the reasons you were
saying before for doing it for mental
health.
I try to do that when I'm feeling just
my worst.
I make myself get on the bike and do
these high intensity intervals because I
know that that'll help me mentally.
No,
I feel like I'll be there.
Sure.
Interesting exercise doesn't make people
thinner.
That's what.
That's what tops in this piece says and
that's what I see over and over again
and believe me,
we don't want to believe that and I
think people can lose weight through
exercise,
but they get hungrier.
That's the problem.
It's not you don't you exercise,
you get hungrier and you replace that.
I don't have all the nuances on this so
everyone should look up that top piece
in New York magazine because he's just
fantastic and it
with all that is,
it's very anecdotal.
You know when,
when you start saying that diet is the
way to go and that exercise does not
make you thin.
It's anecdotal because some people
exercise absolutely make some thing.
I mean there's.
I know a lot of people that have started
doing Jujitsu and lost 30,
40 pounds.
I know a lot of people that have done
that and it works,
you know,
because it's extremely strenuous,
extremely rigorous.
She burned off a ton of a ton of
calories.
You accelerate your metabolism,
your metabolism starts burning off fat
at an unprecedented rate for your body,
and it does work,
but it's like,
what kind of exercise do you engage?
Again,
you know,
that's,
that's another factor,
like are you just doing like a long slow
jog with very low intensity or are you
doing like power lifting?
Like there's a lot of evidence that
actual weightlifting is way better for
burning fat than anything else because
when you weight lift,
your body makes more muscle,
more muscle consumes more calories,
and if you have the same amount of
calorie intake,
but now your body has more requirements,
it'll start burning off some of that
fat.
I think that's a really great point.
And I am not one to,
that's I'm not,
I'm not an expert in this area and I
haven't read very much in it,
but I have read this.
Um,
what's the guy's name?
shoot,
I'm not gonna remember it,
Mikey.
It's wrote a book with him.
It's um,
it's slow burn fitness.
And actually I do that.
I lift weights.
You lift them until your muscles are
just screaming and I can live like eight
pounds because I'm totally wimpy.
Um,
but um,
and you do it really slowly,
so slowly,
like times barely moving and that does
increase your metabolism.
It improves your heart,
um,
improves your cardiovascular system and
what's the other thing?
And it does help weight loss.
So the new one,
there are nuances on that.
And I just,
I say that because when I look at the
tops thing,
all this stuff,
he support stuff very well.
It makes sense,
but I'm a little light on what the
details are.
So admittedly,
you know,
I,
I think you bring up a good point on
that and also the individual
differences,
things that we are the thing that we are
different and so some people are able to
lose weight in ways that other people
may be or not.
But I think this
you see with kids,
do you have kids?
No,
I have kids.
And one of the things you see is like,
you see kids that can just fucking eat
anything.
They eat anything and they're skinny and
then you see other kids that they're
just really struggling on a really early
age and their body packs on a ton of fat
and they have those extreme endomorph
bodies and there's,
you know,
it's clear differences and,
and they,
they are both on the playground together
at the same time.
They're both the same age.
You're not dealing with a lifetime of
abuse.
You're talking about 10 year olds right
now.
So it comes down to me to how does your
body process nutrients,
how does it process the food you take in
and how well does it do it and where
does it store it?
And so you know,
those kids who are,
you know the,
if you had them do the same kind of
play,
you will see that one kid ends up being
fatter and one isn't and,
and it's not,
you know,
if you fed them the exact same things,
you can see that the factories just
working differently in one kid had
genetics.
The other thing to take into
consideration,
you were talking about lactose
intolerance,
intolerance.
One of the things that I read recently
is that a big part of lactose
intolerance can be attributed to the
homogenization and pasteurization of
milk and that you know,
we're very concerned about diseases,
rightly so,
and that's why I'm in freshness and but
milk's not supposed to be able to sit on
a shelf for three weeks.
It's just not supposed to.
You're supposed to get milk if you drink
it at all,
it should be fresh and that way it has
the enzymes in it and that what we're
doing by boiling this milk and
pasteurizing and homogenizing it is
where you're creating this dead protein,
liquid shit that your body doesn't know
what the fuck to do with and then the
weirder ones is when you take it and you
suck the fat out of it.
Like when you have low fat milk and a
lot of people don't even realize it.
Low fat milk has sugar in it.
They literally add sugar to low fat milk
to make it palatable.
So disgusting.
I didn't know that.
Not you're not getting anything.
It's not.
It might be low fat is in fat content,
but as in the effects it's going to have
on your body,
it's not low fat at all.
Yeah.
Actually Jeff Volek,
that dietary researcher basically agreed
with me when I said to him,
so is it basically child abuse to feed
your child skim milk?
I mean,
here we are,
America.
We're a very wealthy country.
People are feeding their children
nutrient free food.
It's so crazy.
Well,
there I
have not had enough time to study the
research.
They have to.
Most people,
they.
What they hear is if you eat
cholesterol,
you'll get fat.
If you eat saturated fats,
you'll have a heart attack,
and there you're talking about like 19
sixties knowledge.
You talk to top of the food chain
researchers today,
no pun intended,
in 2017,
and they'll tell you quite the opposite.
They'll tell you that saturated fats and
cholesterol are actually good for you,
that they are the precursors for
hormones.
Your body uses them to produce
testosterone,
like your body uses them to produce
hormones and that this idea that eating
cholesterol raises your blood
cholesterol.
That's not true.
Right,
and actually we've been so credulous as
as people,
I think probably it's not just us,
it's probably around the globe for many,
many decades and now part of the good
part of having all this media is that
more of the sort of the counterpoint
gets out there and so it's been sort of
a religion.
People have believed this because the
government put it out.
The American Heart Association,
the Ama put it out saying fat is,
excuse me,
fat is bad.
And recently they did it again with
capstone.
Yet it's so terrible.
So not evidence based.
It's no
send it to a bunch of people like Rhonda
Patrick and all the doctors and
scientists that I know.
I'm like,
am I wrong here or is this crap?
And on it wrote a piece,
one of the researchers for on it wrote a
piece of essentially saying the American
Heart Association is essentially whack.
It's kind of a whack institution and
they're not on top of the ball.
Yeah.
I just found this with another medical
association in this piece I'm writing
and it's really terrible because what
happens is,
so doctor say that you go to an Hmo,
those doctors,
they go by the recommendations of these
big associations,
so you've got the big associations
telling basically medical fairy tales.
They're continuing to tell the same
fairytale that they've told and people
are basing their healthcare decisions on
that doctors are and then the patients
are listening.
They assume,
okay,
you're wearing a white coat and you went
to medical school and I went to school
of Google.
I guess I'll listen to you and that's
really,
really damaging and this is why I think
Nina Tie Scholtz.
I'm Dr Eades,
Gary Tobbs,
all these people you know who've done
this work to put this put out the real
science,
they have saved an enormous amount of
lives and stop people from having
horrible diseases.
I really think that they're all heroic
because it's been a fight to put that
stuff out.
It's been a big battle for them and they
have people fighting them all the time.
Well,
most people that go to a doctor for
advice,
but the reality about medical schools,
you'd take very little time to learn
about nutrition.
It's a lot of these guys,
whether it's an orthopedic surgeon or
the whatever the specialty is,
the idea that these people are the goto
expert on every single area of the body,
including nutritional absorption is
ridiculous.
It's just not the case and there's a
great many people that know more about
nutrition and especially state of the
art and nutrition.
Then your does unfortunately.
But see if you realize that then you're
already ahead of the game and you can
say,
okay,
I'm going to,
I am going to use you for tests and
tried to sucks.
It really sucks.
I mean,
there are obviously some great doctors
out there in the Ken give you some,
like,
um,
my doctor,
Dr Gordon,
Mark Gordon,
he's also an expert in traumatic brain
injury and uh,
you know,
he's a really nuanced guy and when I
talked to him about cholesterol and all
these different factors and ldl and hdl
and triglycerides and he can give me a
research based sort of point of view on
it because he's doing it himself.
I mean he's eating this way himself.
He's paying attention to all the latest
stuff,
but he's got a voracious appetite for
that stuff.
There's a lot of people that just don't
want to be bothered.
They got their degree in 1982 and
they're done.
I know.
And it's so terrible.
And see if your doctor discloses that to
you.
If they say,
look,
I am really known nothing about diet and
I'm going to give you advice because
they say that I should give you advice,
but really it's not based in anything
other than they printed out some sheets
here.
Then okay.
Because then you're informed.
It's not like your doctor is leading you
on with the white coat,
but most people are being led on,
well,
it's just we have this idea,
you know,
we have this idea that,
what,
what I need to do to be healthy.
Well,
you know,
maybe I should go on a vegetarian diet.
That'll be healthy.
Well,
listen,
if you read fucking cupcakes and
Burritos and fucking cheese doodles all
day.
Yeah,
a Vegan Diet,
it's going to be amazing for you.
It's going to really do a great job.
The question is,
is it optimal?
It might be,
it might be optimal for you and put it
might not be optimal for you.
You know,
might be for me,
maybe it's my thing,
you know,
but if trying and trial and error
becomes really difficult for people
because most people have jobs and
families and obligations and hobbies and
things they like to do.
They don't want to spend time going
through pub med studies and trying to
figure out what the fuck is a good thing
to eat and the bad thing to eat and you
know,
what are the variables?
Is it based on,
you know,
the origin of my ancestors?
Do I have to like,
think about,
you know,
those ancestral diet people that are
really into that,
like,
you know,
like where are you,
where are your people from?
Like where did they grow up doing,
you know?
Right.
Boy,
it's very hard and the great thing is
that there,
there is more stuff out there that's
written for lay people were people who
read the research,
explain it to people in a way that is
very clear and understandable so people
can make more of their own decision I
think,
than they ever could before.
It was also people that are super
cynical.
They're like,
hey man,
I grew up with Dr Susan.
The Food Pyramid was always weed at the
bottom and the top was all this other
stuff,
but now everybody's flipping the food
pyramid and you just taken out the
bottom part entirely.
Like,
and so what,
what's gonna happen five years from now?
You're going to tell me,
well,
high fat is actually terrible for your
brain.
Or,
you know,
it's just people are understandably
tired of all this stuff and it's real
easy to just sort of compartmentalize
and just push it away and listen to your
doctor.
Yeah,
it really is.
And the thing,
the point you made before about the
people who are eating the cheetos and
cupcakes,
Diane,
well of course,
if you start eating a Vegan Diet,
you know,
you're not eating cheetos and cupcakes,
you know you're going to see an effect.
But is that a good effect,
you know,
in terms of your longterm health and you
know,
we see that vegetarians don't have
necessary proteins that you get very
easily from meat with no training
to eat,
like a balanced amino acid profile.
Foods like I know pea protein and hemp
proteins.
Very good keen keenwah
you know,
more than I am.
This I,
this isn't my area because I don't care
about that stuff since I'm not
vegetarian and wouldn't eat that way,
but I see that.
So people like Chris Kresser try to help
people to say,
look,
here's the deal.
And so you can make some choices and
decide,
you know,
is there a way for me as a vegetarian to
get the nutrients I need or am I always
going to be deficient and how might that
affect my health?
So what are the tradeoffs?
Yeah.
But some people they don't think of it
purely as a health issue as well.
They also think about it as an ethical
and moral issue.
You know,
they'll say,
look,
I don't want to be a part of factory
farming.
I don't want to have anything to do with
the death of animals,
which I completely understand and I,
I respect and appreciate what they're
doing is they're trying to leave a
smaller footprint on the world.
No,
that makes sense too.
Well,
I can see that because I,
I mean,
I don't think that animal cruelty is a
good thing and I think animals should be
humanely slaughtered and kept.
And so I think that that's a really good
argument.
I have friends who are vegetarians for
that reason,
who know about eating meat and and being
a healthier way to,
to have a diet,
but they choose to make that tradeoff
and as long as you're making a choice,
a reason choice and you know what you're
trading off,
then I'm fine with that.
Yeah.
No,
I think that's.
And again,
for some people vegetarians probably the
way to go and that's what gets really
confusing.
It's like how do you figure out what is
the right way to go and what is the for
you,
I mean,
you really,
what you're supposed to do is get blood
tests.
You're supposed to do it on a regular
basis.
Supposed to consult with someone who
actually knows what they're talking
about.
Yeah.
And really just sort of um,
just make these choices,
test the results,
and then make an educated decision based
on that.
And here's a problem.
How do you find the evidence based
doctor?
Because I'm in an Hmo so I can just
switch doctors forever and ever,
but I just stay with the doctor and then
read stuff myself because I can do that.
That's what I do for a living,
um,
but for other people who aren't in an
Hmo,
people want to find an evidence based
medicine practitioner.
People will say they are,
but then you hear the raw what they
suggest and they really aren't.
And that's,
that's a really big problem would be
great if there were somebody could make
a lot of money maybe doing a site
saying,
look,
I'm this doctor and here's what I look
at and think.
And um,
so you could choose because we tried to
find one for my boyfriend in Los Angeles
and like,
no,
nobody knows.
Right.
It's hard.
Yeah.
It mean they're,
they're out there,
but it's hard to find them.
Yeah,
because you tried five or six doctors.
You go through them and these are all
doctor appointments.
You have to pay for them and everything
and then you find,
okay.
You don't know anything really onto the
next
incredibly time consuming.
Like when I go to my doctor,
when I get blood work done,
we have a 75 minute consultation.
We have to sit down for 75 minutes and
go over all the various micronutrient
levels.
And all the different levels of,
you know,
everything nice and [inaudible] be like,
what?
And we go over diet and we go over like
when are you eating,
what time are you eating?
Like when,
when are you eating,
before you take the blood tests and you
know,
how much water are you consuming?
Red hydrated are you.
And there's a lot going on me.
If you want to truly optimize your
health,
it's better than ever,
but still extremely hard to find someone
who knows what they're doing.
Let's see.
So the doctor you go to that seems like
a smart if you are going to spend money
because that guy's probably really
expensive,
but if you're going to spend money,
you know,
a doctor who sees you for 72 minutes and
looks at you,
looks at you that way.
That seems like a really wise investment
in your future.
Even if you're maybe somebody who is
not,
doesn't have money to burn.
And that,
that seems a really smart place to put
it.
If you,
even if you have to make some sacrifices
in other areas.
Yeah.
No,
I think so too.
And I think read as much as you can
about not just read books by people on
nutrition,
but read articles about those books,
you know,
read,
I mean pro and con and I've read a lot
of con and you know,
you've got to go over that stuff with a
fine tooth comb.
Look for bias,
look.
And it's hard to do.
It's hard.
It's really hard to do.
Some of the important things are to look
at the sample size,
look at people,
look,
look the limitations.
Sometimes they'll say them at the end.
I always liked those studies that do
that sample size,
you know,
when somebody has had 22 people in this
study,
you know,
that's not the one you want.
Look for,
you know,
and you can't just save necessarily,
oh it must be this number or that
number.
But look for a lot of people.
And what else?
Like if they say something's really
significant,
then I'm always,
I'm immediately suspicious.
Significance,
you know,
well there's this whole argument about p
values and that's probability measure
that's going on now and we'll okay,
let's take that.
Some people are saying,
let's take that out of the equation and
because that's people are using this as
this sort of golden thing to say,
okay,
we had the spiny and it's fantastic and
to look at him to look at the,
the,
the whole study and the findings in a
more nuanced way than just the p value.
It's hard for people.
I mean one of the things that we've
talked about a couple of times recently
that people keep throwing around is
this.
These are the recent studies that show
that people who eat a lot of red meat
are more likely to get cancer and the
issue with these studies is a bunch of
issues.
One,
they don't differentiate what kind of
meat.
They don't differentiate whether or not
you eat it with vegetables or whether
you eat it with white bread and
spaghetti and this huge,
whether you're eating grass fed bison or
whether they're eating some bullshit
burger and you just saying you eat meet
five times
a week.
That doesn't show me what's in your
diet.
These are called cohort studies and I
call them if you see that cohort studies
or observational or population based
observational study,
I call them leap to conclusions after
the fact and they're just like the the
shit of studies,
you know,
because did the person,
like you're saying,
what caused this,
this thing that we're seeing,
okay,
they are there,
you know,
have this effect.
There are healthy foods and it's just,
it's such a,
it's such a crappy way and you see it
reported in the media,
you know,
these,
these articles that say,
oh my God,
everyone should never eat this type of
food ever again.
It's terrible for you.
And it doesn't say that at all,
but the reporters don't know that and
they just don't even care.
It's just click a bunch of hits on their
article and you'll see articles like
that that even in like really
respectable publications that have this
really attractive headline.
And then you read the actual article
itself,
you're like,
wait,
what are you basing this off?
It's really terrible.
And so that's the thing,
what you said to look at studies.
Look at the opposite,
the opposite point of view that's really
important to look at at,
um,
it's just,
it's hard to read some of these studies.
I really appreciate researchers who,
right and clear language.
I think that's more and more important
as people can get studies.
There's a site called sky hub where you
can get studies that are protected,
that the,
that the journals don't let you get.
Um,
and you can find them on professors.
Websites are ways to find these studies
if you want to find them.
Um,
you can use google scholar to look up
the thing.
So it's just a scholar.google.com.
And then you can start finding these in,
try to get them through other sources if
they are password protected because you
don't want to just read the abstract
because they can say the abstracts that
part at the top where they tell you what
the study's about,
oee,
this significant finding and we found
this and that.
And you will often,
not often,
but you will sometimes read a study and
you'll see that the thing that they say
they found is not what they found.
And that's why it's important to not
just be this lazy person who reads only
the abstract and the conclusion,
but to look at the methodology and see
if there's stuff screwed up.
I saw a study done by Harvard professors
where they didn't have a control group
for their third experiment.
And I thought,
did you forget?
I mean,
you're at Harvard,
if you guys don't know,
to put in a control group,
you know,
come on.
That's a study about,
um,
it was um,
a study on,
um,
God,
I'm not gonna remember now it was,
um,
mm shoot.
It was the third part was in a train
station and I can't,
I can't remember what the study was
about.
I just,
I brought it with me in an evolutionary
psychology conference thing,
thinking this will be east or write a
column from.
Because I had a question that kind of
matched,
um,
I can't remember,
but it was in a train station and they
should have gotten done in a train.
They did two,
two of the experiments.
The first two experiments were where
they played videos or something.
I think it had something to do with cell
phones or something.
I can't quite remember.
It was someone trying to borrow a cell
phone,
someone can we borrow your cell phone
and so and,
and I like these professors.
I've referenced one of their,
both of their work in my book,
my next book,
but I'm a psychologist.
Study.
Yeah.
It was social psychology study and I
thought,
you know that why don't you have a
control for third through third
experiment.
And so then I had to do a new question
for my second question,
my column and I was all annoyed too so I
remembered it.
Well there's a difference between
science and then headlines from articles
that are written about science by people
that might not even necessarily be
scientists or really truly understand
the science.
They just want to get an article out
there that people are going to pay
attention to.
Well I'm,
I'm sensitive to credentialism is I
don't have a phd and I started out
giving free advice in a street corner
and Soho is a joke.
So.
But I've.
Since then I started out giving advice
on a street corner,
a little wacky,
broad.
So what we doing?
Well we just had these two friends and
we just thought it would be funny.
So we set up on the corner of West
Broadway and broom with a card table and
some folding chairs that advice,
it said free advice from a panel of
experts.
We've called the advice ladies and like
love and dating and you know,
when,
what year did you do?
This?
Was in the late eighties.
And then in the nineties he just decided
to do this on a whim.
Well,
we thought we'd just do it once.
I act like I'm drunk at all times.
So No,
I'm just a weird person and we did this
and we just thought we'd sit there and
people walk past and laugh because I
always liked making people laugh.
I once went out in an evening dress and
a goatee and a mustache.
I'm just to be funny.
I frightened to child.
Um,
and uh,
we did this and people,
it was New York,
you know,
free.
They lined up around the block and they
didn't just ask us like about like their
eyelashes or whatever,
like,
can I get directions to grand street,
Grand Street?
They were asking a serious question and
I thought,
Holy Shit,
I better know something.
And so I read through all of psychology
and when you're not reading psychology
in school,
you think like,
oh my God,
Freud just made shit up.
It was really crazy.
And I discovered this guy,
Albert Ellis,
who was the father at the same time as
Erin back of,
um,
cognitive behavioral therapy basically,
and then started reading more and more
and immersing myself more and more in
science and going to scientific
conferences.
And then because this thing where I look
for people to criticize me so I can get
better.
I mean not the people who are like,
Hey,
horror on the internet.
But um,
I would ask professors like,
did I get this wrong?
And sometimes they'd say yes.
And so I learned more and more and got
better and better and incorporated more
science.
So now what I do is sort of a synthesis
from across science.
I read a cognitive neuroscience textbook
and I use evolutionary psychology.
I used that as sort of an underpinning
theory to everything.
So I look at social science research and
say,
how would this have made sense in an
ancestral environment?
Because if it,
if there's no sense to it,
then there's something empty and wrong
with what they're finding or what
they're concluding now.
So you started out doing this,
you set up this card table and free
advice and then how did it progress to
you having this column?
Well,
um,
so we're doing this and just because it
was so fun and we got so much out of it
and I learned this,
that basically if you help people,
if you do kindness to other people for
other people,
you feel really good.
So there's self interest in being kind,
especially to strangers.
So,
and that's what we were doing.
And so,
um,
we did this for a few years and sky
walked by,
he wrote for The New York Times style
section.
He belittled teeny piece on us,
like,
and then it got old cut down Eric
Messenger.
And then because I'm a governmental Jew,
I do like five things well,
and one of them selling things.
So what does that mean?
That means like you're in the garment
district,
you're like hocking clothing.
So I can like get dressed.
Notice I don't say like,
you know,
I get dressed,
eat,
not cook.
Um,
what else?
Anyway,
psychology,
that's one of them.
And then selling things.
And so I got us a TV deal with Deniro,
my partners and me.
And then I got us a column,
the Daily News and a book agent.
And one of my partners ended up dying.
It's very sad.
Um,
and so we,
um,
I ended up doing the column myself at
that point,
um,
and then just syndicated my own column
because I thought,
well,
you know,
I'm writing this for one paper,
don't make very much money,
how do I make more money?
And I was an entrepreneur and so I got
it in a whole bunch of papers even
though all the syndicators who do that.
And,
and by the way,
if anyone asks,
it's not possible anymore.
Papers are all going out of business.
But true,
previous,
true,
be there,
they're very,
they're really struggling.
But back then I went to syndicators.
They said,
yeah,
we think you write a really great
column,
but Ann Landers,
dear abby,
of all the real estate,
you'll never make any money.
And so I went to an alternative weekly
newspaper conference in Montreal.
I didn't like the Hooker hotel because I
couldn't afford the real hotel.
And I just went around saying like,
here are my little samples here,
my little samples.
And so paper started picking up my
column.
So I built a business out of doing this,
this out of free advice.
And then over the years became
increasingly science based,
you know,
had to learn statistics.
I have a book I weep reading under my
desk,
biosis biostatistics,
the bare essentials.
I read a lot of stats websites and try
to improve in that area in terms of
scientific thinking and,
and understanding statistics.
So I can be better at assessing studies.
People gravitate towards advice.
They really do the advice columns and
advice like call in advice shows like
people love,
like Dr Laura,
like that kind of shit.
People call on,
you know,
what should I do,
what should I do?
Well,
the thing that I do,
I,
I just feel like I don't have a right to
just give you my opinion.
Right.
So before it was a science base was very
reasoned based.
I always loved critical thinking and
reasoning and logic.
And so now you know,
I'll look at somebodies question and
I'll sometimes think I know the answer,
but I'll always read to see.
Oh actually no,
it's this.
I'll read a bunch of papers and I look
for what's called the most parsimonious
answer because there can be a bunch of
answers to something,
but it's like what is the thing that
most closely narrowly answers this
person's question?
And then also there's this thing,
I see advice columns all the time.
They tell someone to do something that
nobody would ever do.
So I always have like this sort of
bullshit check on there of like,
come on,
it's anybody ever going to do this kind
of stuff?
Well it's like write stuff down.
I write stuff down.
Well you know,
you might do it.
And when people read those books,
self help books,
it says located okay,
right this worksheet and do all this
stuff.
I've never done that my whole life.
And so write things down.
No.
Well,
do you have like a list of things to do?
I know I have,
I have stuff written.
My house is like a,
it's a fire hazard with a bed in an
oven.
It's like a walk in paper pile.
So now I write everything down.
Actually I type everything out.
I,
I'm a blowhard and in print.
Um,
but the thing is that in books,
when they say,
fill out this worksheet,
I like reading,
I don't want to stop and do this thing.
And so I've never done that.
And so in this next book that I wrote,
I have two ways to do some delays.
Yes.
Amy Elk on way or the way that's
actually more efficient and will do
better.
It's the way I changed because I was
this loser with no confidence and I
transformed myself.
And actually it's based in good science.
What I did,
I didn't know that I was just desperate
and miserable.
But I say,
look,
if you make a list of these problems
that you have,
the things you're afraid of,
this will help you,
then you can tackle them.
This is smarter,
but I didn't do that.
I still,
you know,
got to where I needed to go,
but it's just dumb to do it my way
because you can just do a little writing
work and get to um,
tackle this stuff you need to tackle,
give advice that you don't really take.
So like saying like take,
write down all the different things that
you have issue with and then you can
tackle those.
You didn't really do that
well because I didn't do it based in
science.
What I'm saying is that I recognize that
some people will be too lazy to write
stuff down or they just don't do that.
And so what I did is I said,
here are the consequences if you do it
my way,
like it's going to be slower and you
know,
you might not be as successful.
And this way it seems worthwhile.
Like if I could do this over again,
if I,
if I had a time machine and go back and
say like,
Hey,
miserable losers person,
here's what you do and write this down
because then it's going to take you this
many years instead of like that many
years.
I would do that now.
And so what I tried to do is persuade
people to be smarter than I was
basically.
Well,
you're,
you're
giving advice based on your personal
experience.
Like this would have been a better way
to.
Right?
This is a better way.
And I see that based on the science,
but I realized that some people won't do
it.
So you can choose.
This is the thing.
It's like with the Diet,
okay,
you eat that cupcake,
you're going to enjoy it,
but here's the trade off.
Well,
writing things down.
One of the things that's important about
that is it cements those things in your
memory and it puts them in,
especially in my opinion,
physically writing.
I don't know why but like for notes like
um,
I have notes on my phone that I keep
from like comedy sets of like things
that I need to do,
but they're not as effective as a
notebook.
I keep a notebook as well and my
notebook is not where I write in.
I ride on a computer,
but my notebook is where I write things
down that I need to remember like this,
the subject of bits and the important
points in bits and maybe even if it's a
new bit,
I'll go over the important punchlines
and where they fit in and I'll write all
this stuff out.
But that way,
like for some reason when you physically
write things down,
they get cemented in your mind.
The act of putting pen to paper and
moving your hand around
it makes sense.
See,
this is the,
this is the subject of my next book.
It's embodied cognition.
It's that we don't just think with our
mind that our body is intimately
involved and so.
And there is research that finds you are
actually going to remember stuff more if
you write it down.
That's why they say in class you should
take notes in pen and ink rather than
typing.
And so the truth is,
I mean,
I've lived all over my house.
It's just that self help book genre that
I never wrote anything in where they
said to write stuff,
but I think that that's very important
and also for memorization,
um,
that,
that's,
that's an important thing that to write
stuff when I have,
I did a Ted talk and I had to memorize
stuff for it and I can see where I wrote
stuff on the pages.
So I had the type pages.
But then I had stuff where I scratched
and notes and I can picture that still.
Even now,
even though I don't have the greatest
memory,
I don't think the places that I wrote
notes in this colored ink,
there's something very memorable about
that where it isn't with the type page.
Yeah.
I don't know what it is,
but it definitely works.
Right.
Well,
the physical is very important.
You know,
if you look at people who are,
you know,
feel bad about themselves,
they sort of hunched down and
everything.
There's a different way of standing if
you feel good about yourself and good
about where you're going and walking
going forward.
I mean all of these things are very
important.
If you are depressed,
it really can help to take a walk and
this is this kind of thing where you
have to force yourself.
It's like when I forced myself to get on
the bike,
you know,
I want to do anything but that,
but I know that I just have to do it
because I'll feel so much better.
Not just then,
but the next day it seems to,
I see an effect on mood the next day,
you know,
with this thing in Vegas,
I got very just in a dark place that did
that day that happened and I just made
myself get on the bike and it's the time
I've felt least like that.
And I mean like how dumb because all
these people are going through this
horrible stuff.
And I'm like,
oh,
I couldn't get on a bicycle.
But.
But it really is.
You have your own little world.
That's where you inhabit and you have to
take care of it.
And that was what I did to just not.
I didn't want to go into a depression.
Well,
it's also a habit that's a good habit to
form the habit of getting too off your
ass and putting action,
doing something right.
And sometimes it's hard for people that
you know,
you can call it procrastinating.
I saw,
I don't want to do or to think about not
doing it.
You have to get in the habit of just
doing things,
getting the habit of getting up and
doing where there's.
There's no option.
You don't have the option to not do it.
Force yourself to do it.
And if you can do that,
you will appreciate your free time so
much more.
If you people think that like,
well I just like being lazy and I like
relaxing,
sitting around
you.
You May,
I believe you may,
but you won't like it as much as you
would like it if you've accomplished
your goals first.
See are so great.
Because then you feel good about
something.
You've done something,
you feel good sitting on the couch.
I like sitting on the couch.
Sometimes I'm watching TV,
but it's because I work so much,
I get shit done.
So when I put my feet up I can like,
feel good.
I'm not fucking off.
I'm enjoying leisure time,
which is also important.
There's this classic social science
research by this Guy Carl Wyke who
talked about small wins and that's
really important and they talk about
that in a make your bed in the morning
and,
and the thing you were talking about
with feelings,
I'm a big advocate of not letting your
feelings be the boss of you.
That's how I say it.
Um,
and so for example,
I write to a timer because when I sit
down to write,
so my stuff is funny.
So I always think like I'm not funny,
I have nothing to say.
I don't know what the science,
I don't know what the answer is.
That's,
those are those immediate feelings
buzzing around like little flies and my
head and it doesn't,
none of that matters because the time,
right?
Put on 52 minutes on 17 minutes break
and that's all that matters.
How many times do you read a day?
Um,
uh,
it depends on the day because sometimes
there's 17 minutes for break.
Well do that.
And I do.
Dean,
how'd you come to that?
Actually,
I read something,
I didn't even read this study.
It just,
I thought,
oh that sounds good.
There's this thing called a pomodoro
where you do 20 minutes,
but that doesn't seem like very much,
you know,
with the humorous stuff sometimes if
it's hard I have to just keep shooting
the shit with myself and like looking up
things on the internet like oh look,
a polar bear,
okay.
And,
and come up with some kind of joke or
something like that.
And so it takes a while.
And I read this somewhere saying that 50
to 17,
but I didn't even read the paper on it.
I didn't just run with that.
Right.
We'll run with that.
And so what I do often in the 17 minute
break period,
especially if I'm doing something really
hard is um,
I will clean my house and I,
I wish I could,
you know,
no one pays writers anymore.
So I'd actually like to have a team of
maids and a butler,
a little midget butler,
I don't know,
for Nola to save.
Oh,
okay.
A little person.
Sorry,
little person Butler.
Why a little person?
How about a giant?
Because I always love the wizard of Oz.
I think that they're amazing looking.
Um,
so that's probably a terrible thing and
I'm probably going to be happy.
You have people like come after me and
the,
what does this champion would just pull
up?
Pomodoro is,
I've only heard of it and a time
cooking.
So yeah,
right,
right.
It comes out of that little,
the little tomato timer.
It's 20 minutes.
So each 25 minute block of work as a
Pomodoro.
Once you thought it was 24 pomodoros
take a longer break of 20 to 30 minutes.
This will help your brain relax and
refocus before your next session.
So this is default mode processing that
goes on.
What happens is you're more efficient if
you take breaks.
See I'm from the family of the puritan
work ethic.
Jews of like,
you know,
the just the beat the horse and have it
worked for hours,
but that's really inefficient because
your brain does background processing
while you're doing this,
you know,
you're washing the dishes or whatever
and so,
but I find that the thing about not
having a maid and doing the work
yourself,
you like cleaned the base board down
here or take the little
clorox wipe and do something.
You have these small wins so you
accomplished something even though it's
just a little tiny thing.
You clean your countertop or whatever
with bleach that you've done something
and where maybe you're writing,
it's going,
it's frustrating and you haven't really
accomplished much.
He didn't figure out the thing you
needed to figure out.
So you have that elevated feeling of
being,
having done something that you're
talking about.
I've heard a lot of people say they like
to take breaks and walk during the
walking.
That's when they sort of sort out all
the different things they were writing
about and they usually bring a phone or
a recorder and then they talk into it if
they have an idea and then go over that
or you know,
obviously.
Do you use the transcription?
You have a smartphone use at
transcriptional.
I that dragon thing on my phone,
which I really like.
The walking does seem helpful.
Nietzsche walk and I've read papers on
this that walking is helpful and so I do
that also if I have something that's
just where I can't figure something out,
what I do is I go to the bank and get
$20 out just to.
So it doesn't seem like a meaningless
trip there and then come home and go to
the bank to get 20 bucks really?
Well it's near my house.
It's like on Lincoln and I walked back
and you know,
it's a short trip,
but it's enough of a walk that it's a
walk and a symbolic thing of getting the
money out if it has no meaning,
it's just that,
you know,
if I just walked to the bank,
it would feel purposeless than then
maybe I wouldn't do it the next time.
So it feels like I know I'm a weird
girl,
what can I say?
Um,
but I do that.
And that's just such a,
it's sort of alleviate some kind of debt
that pressing feeling of you have.
Like there's not a solution I don't
know.
And you're moving,
you're doing this thing where you're
moving forward.
That's this thing about your brain,
not just,
we don't just think about solutions.
Like we can actually move in ways that
help your brain be more powerful.
And that's that the walking thing that
seems to be one of these ways where you
take some pressure off and actually
that.
And I put things on the wall in my
shower,
correct things,
and I also put up things I don't
understand to look at them over and over
again.
And the other thing too is people feel
bad if they are not instantly geniuses
at figuring something out.
And what I like to do is go over and
over and overthink.
So on this thing that I'm writing now,
this medical care expo say that I'm
writing now.
The research is really new to me and
complicated.
And so what I do is I have a pile of
papers.
There's a step stool in my bathroom.
It's really crazy.
My boyfriend goes in there and he sort
of frightened by the insanity but the
pile of paper.
So I put them on the bottom stool and
then I reread them and I put them on the
top.
So there's like a.
it's like an escalator going back and
forth.
Because when you do it like that,
you get sort of a deep understanding
that you don't.
When you just read it at first.
And I know this from writing that
there's an understanding I can listen to
somebody present their work at a
scientific conference and understand it,
but can I explain it to you?
And that's a whole different level of
understanding that's deeper
understanding that that does make sense.
And when you're talking about walking to
do,
what do you think the walking has an
effect also because it's a mild,
very mild exercise,
so it's not exhausting you,
it's not hard,
but you are getting some good
circulation because you're forcing your
body to pick your legs up and move
forward and your heart starts beating.
And,
and I think it sort of a ignites some
systems.
Yeah.
I think that you're probably right about
that and you feel just the sense,
you know,
because you're going forward so forwards
a metaphor for success and progress and
all these things.
And I think that all of that,
it sounds kind of silly,
but I looked at all this metaphor stuff
and I don't think it's so silly,
you know,
uh,
success is up,
moving forward as progress.
And so our bodies are connected,
our first language as organisms,
the organisms,
they had two things,
approach and avoid.
It's like,
oh look,
a yummy piece of plankton,
I'll approach that,
or oh,
that thing's gonna eat me and I'll back
up.
And those,
um,
it's called,
there's a term called neural reused by
the Sky Anderson and another guy named
dot Haynes said it in different way,
but the,
the idea is that the human emotional
system comes out of her scalp.
They use a term scaffolded,
I don't think they use it right,
but it's comes out of the approach and
avoid mechanisms of tiny organisms.
So going forward,
that's approach going backward,
receiving that's avoid.
Um,
and so if you look at it that way,
it makes sense that walking,
that going to the bank,
I'm going to walk in a little tennis
shoes in my word,
those Asian pullman sunglasses that,
you know,
I'm going somewhere.
I got them from my neighbor,
she's Japanese at a garage sale.
This Asian Pool,
man,
they're like those wraparound.
It's basically like putting a strap,
you know,
how they,
um,
like if they don't want to you,
I identified in a photo,
they put a black bar over your face
that's like the sunglasses version,
but they're huge and they're plastic and
it's like,
I need a car.
Windshield.
I got them at her,
you know.
Oh,
also because.
So I'm,
I'm just like,
I'm related to white out.
And so,
um,
I'm just hoping to not age like an old
Hermes handbag,
you know,
by even California.
So you spray like a sunscreen all over
your face when you do that too.
No,
I use FDA banned sunblock.
Jesus Christ.
Why would you do that?
No,
because I know the FDA,
they're wrong to bend this.
They don't allow the most protective
sunblock,
which is with [inaudible] that they sell
in France,
that no French people have not been
dropping dead in the streets.
They haven't been dying of cancer from
using sunblock with his very protective
ingredient.
The FDA allows the sunblock now to be
sold here.
It's called anthea.
Anthea Leo's.
But it's like with the whatever Musinex
I used to take that they know have
behind the counter and they sell the one
up in the aisle,
that doesn't work.
They removed the active ingredient and
they sell the lesser ingredient in
America.
So if you want to get the Antonios that
actually works.
You have to go to France.
I buy a case when I'm there are other
people bring back a dress?
I bring back $350 worth of sunshine.
You can't even order it online and have
it.
No,
you can.
Well this is a great thing about the
Internet nowadays.
You spell it.
Anthea,
it's a n,
t h
e l I o s and there's a little French
accent.
Excellent.
Accent.
A goose.
That's the only thing I wanted to say if
you were French and Taleah.
Antonio's.
Yeah.
Okay.
So this stuff is just way stronger than
anything you get here in America.
Well,
it's this oral.
That's the ingredient that protects you
from UVA and UVB.
And it's just,
it's really the,
the most protective ingredient.
You can also get it in Canada.
I got someone,
I was in Vancouver,
you know,
but um,
I get it in France because I can get it
cheaper there so I buy a whole case like
I caught you go to a bad neighborhood
and buy it there and some like Yucky
pharmacy there.
So when you're taking this stuff,
like what is the difference between that
and so like coppertone or something that
you would get in America?
Well that doesn't.
I think it doesn't protect.
I can't remember whether it's Uva or uvb
that it doesn't protect against fully
the kind with the titanium dioxide
protects.
But also the other problem with these
sunblocks has set,
you know,
do they affect your endocrine system in
terrible ways?
I don't know,
but I'm so vain that I just don't want
to be,
you know,
like look like a sheep dog by the factor
into consistent.
Well because you're putting these
chemicals on your skin and stuff goes
into your skin.
But again,
I haven't gone outside and a long time.
So that sort of the effect.
So a huge hat like that,
you know,
it could be a witch,
a black hat and that helps to kind of
crazy.
Amy.
I am,
I'm nuts.
It's one of my better qualities I guess,
or worse.
But uh,
that's a,
that is an interesting point about,
uh,
affecting your endocrine system that I
never really took into consideration.
I've been thinking about sunscreen,
you know,
like,
because I was reading this thing about
um,
the great barrier reef being destroyed
by sunscreen and a spray sunscreen in
particular over someone.
Someone sent me this message and I don't
know if it's correct that the spray
sunscreen is the issue with reese and
not the put the rub on stuff.
Good.
I hate to be a feminist.
I don't know if that's right.
See,
see if you could find out.
You did see something.
I remember looking at stuff recently and
it wasn't true,
but I'm looking up again for whatever
reason,
there's something in the Aerosol version
that is more dangerous for reefs,
but it Kinda makes sense.
I mean,
you're putting this fucking skanky
chemical on you and then you're jumping
in the water.
I mean,
where's it going?
Yeah.
Well it seems though that both kinds
would work that way,
but maybe it's because the lotion kind
probably absorbed more into your skin.
Hair goes,
no,
your sunscreen isn't good.
And the world's coral reefs.
Varying studies.
I've found those so that I don't know if
this one is even accurate,
but I found two other ones that said it
is burying studies produced by the sons.
I believe that is it.
Click Bait.
I don't care.
Scroll up and let's see what it says.
Get a little larger there.
Thank you sir.
Swimming that swimmers that slather
themselves and sunscreen or doing their
skin a favor,
but it might not be so helpful to any
nearby coral reefs that claim released
in a recent scientific study sparked
global headlines,
faulting sunscreen for the global
decline of these hot beds of
biodiversity.
It's disturbing idea that something so
necessary for protecting humans from
skin cancer could be doing so much
environmental damage,
but what weight should we give?
The scientific finding?
Not much.
Turns out the authors of the report who
hail from labs and universities in the
US and Israel found that.
How do you say that?
Oxy,
Benzos,
an active ingredient in some sunscreens
that protects against ultraviolet light,
is present in significant quantities
around recent Hawaii and the Virgin
Islands that were favored by swimmers
and divers.
They determined that the chemical has a
detrimental effect on the DNA of coral
in both its juvenile and adult stages.
The study was published in the Journal
Archives and environmental contamination
and toxicology.
The lab,
the researchers exposed core in the lab.
The research is exploring exposed coral
to high concentrations of oxybenzone.
Not only did it deform coral larvae by
trapping them in their own skeleton.
The study found that it was also a
factor in coral bleaching.
Terry Hughes,
director of the Australian Research
Council,
Center of Excellence Crow.
He studies at James Cook University told
Mashable,
Australia,
he thought the report's findings were
inconclusive.
He was paid off.
His particular study was done in a
laboratory,
so they actually used artificial
seawater.
He explained they put tiny bits into
coral in aquaria and then added some
chemicals.
It's not surprising,
the coral didn't like chemicals thrown
at them.
I don't know.
See,
this is a good point and this is
something when you look at studies,
this is one of the things I look at.
They call it in Vivo or in vitro,
you know,
are you looking at stuff,
do they pull out some cells and do
something to them and does that
replicate or not replicate what,
what happens in the human body?
Are there other things,
other reactions going on that are
missing from them?
You know,
when you,
when you do that,
when you pull it out and just look at it
in a petri dish.
Yeah,
I would imagine,
but it seems like in that environment it
showed that the coral does not like it.
I mean I would imagine that that's not
terribly surprising,
but I'd like to know
what are the trace amounts that they're
seeing in coral and can they mimic those
and studies or are they just pouring it
on them and you know,
like salt for instance,
right?
If you put a little bit of salt in your
food,
you're going to be fun.
You eat a pound of salt,
your big dead an hour.
Well,
this is the thing that,
you know,
if you look at studies,
this is why it's important to read them
over and over like that and to really
pick them apart if you want to assess
them any sort of reliable way because
you have to look at those nuances and
think,
well wait a second,
I called this thing to leave the lab
syndrome where you look at something,
they've studied something you think like
that's not how it works in real life.
Why are you doing the experiment that
way?
That's completely dumb and so,
and this is stuff you don't have to be a
scientist,
but you can.
It helps to think scientifically to
think logically and so it's always good
to enhance that thinking so you can look
at that,
look for the bullshit.
Yeah.
But for a lot of people they just see
that headline,
Oh,
coral reefs dying because of Sunscreen,
sunscreen bad.
Right?
And we'd like to blame people and I felt
bad when you've said that.
I felt like I sucked.
Damn it.
I'm out there killing just for my skin,
so will look like an old hag while also
cancer,
lung cancer.
Well,
see,
here's the thing though.
There's so much stuff,
so much is more complicated than we
think.
Am I giving myself problems by not
getting vitamin D the natural way and by
taking a pill because I take a little
pill,
so that's one of those tradeoffs and I
think like,
okay,
I eat a ketogenic diet and then I put on
the sunscreen and you look at all that
and you try to make the best guests you
can.
That works also within what matters to
you as a woman.
I don't want to look really haggard,
you know when I'm 65 or you're supposed
to Scotland or something.
If you look at your students,
you're supposed to be in some marsh
somewhere,
right?
Exactly right.
Exactly.
Guy like a giant sunscreen thing and so
you know when,
when you change these things in a modern
environment,
they call it evolutionary mismatch.
You know,
what are you doing?
Are you screwing yourself up in some way
because you aren't getting this nutrient
or whatever it is,
the way your body evolved to take it in?
Yeah.
It is such a weird thing.
The color of people's skin is really
just because we changed environments,
right?
That's,
that's the whole.
The whole race thing is so thrown out
the window when you take that into
consideration.
The way we look,
the shape of our noses,
the shape of our faces,
the shape,
the color of our skin,
all determined by the environment that
our ancestors.
Great.
And then all of these people who are say
Irish,
they all grew up in this place and so
they are characteristic Irish features
and and it's just an accepting me.
See what what's happened now is we can't
make jokes anymore.
I skated with 20 black guys in New York.
Oh,
I stopped the thing you said about the
football thing.
I thought,
okay,
I earn a living writing and I really
can't do a lot else that if I cracked my
head open,
I might not be able to earn a living
ever again.
But these guys,
they called me white out,
which I thought was hilarious.
Yeah.
And,
and when you are not racist,
I mean it's not,
it's not bad to joke about race,
racial stuff,
but now I mean it's just really the
third rail of everything that you even
say the slightest thing.
You make mention that someone's
different color.
I mean forget it,
but also there's no negative connotation
to being white.
Right?
So when you say you're wide out,
it's not bad.
It's not like a charcoal,
like Ooh,
that people use charcoal.
Charcoal doesn't seem like an insult.
And also black people don't seem
chocolate.
I thought I had a black boyfriend.
He had chocolate.
His skin was the color of Toklas
Espresso or black super black.
Well,
I think that what really dark,
beautiful.
Those people from from Africa.
I do too with that gorgeous.
They're amazing.
Until they started putting plates in
their lips to draw the line.
Weightlifting.
How do you kiss someone like that?
You lick the plate.
Like is there food left on the plate?
Sorry.
Well that's what is.
That is one of the weirdest spanky's.
What's they're called Ubank.
Jeez,
I think the people will like that.
Yeah.
Surrey.
That's the part of Africa that they do
that I believe that seems like one of
the weirdest sort of habits or behavior
patterns that people have ever adopted
where it's weird,
one of the weirdest cultural traits.
It's just passed down from generation to
generation and the larger the plate in
their lip,
the more cattle they're worth when they
get married.
God super twisted.
It's like,
how did that ever come about?
No idea.
I don't know that area down there,
but God,
that's some of these cultural things
that go on are really crazy.
Well,
whenever you see body mutilation or
which is essentially what that is,
um,
I've,
I've read that also being connected.
Um,
and it's very vague now.
I'm trying to remember it,
but I remember it being connected
somehow or another to the slave trade
and that they've made these women less
likely to be raped.
Oh,
interesting.
Yeah.
I don't know if that's true though.
Still.
I probably shouldn't say it,
but I do always hear things.
I don't know if they're true.
I just repeated and let people sort it
out.
Google it,
folks,
don't listen to me.
But when you were saying about white
people before it now actually,
I mean,
you see this probably all over twitter
to this thing of white privilege and
there this,
uh,
I guess I react when I was like 18,
it was like typhoid,
you know?
And um,
and so now if you're white,
you're just guilty.
Yeah.
You know,
there's nothing you can do and you see
this,
there's some,
there was a video,
it was in Berkeley,
some social justice guy and the woman
just,
it was like,
there's basically,
I mean,
that's what she said.
There's nothing you can do.
You're guilty.
I wish I could remember the word chef or
white privilege.
Yeah,
right.
Oh,
odd.
God.
Fun.
I love that.
Yeah,
I.
But it's what,
it's a way to silence people and it's
also a way for you to be guilty of
something.
Whether or not you're,
you know,
you getting to have a clean slate.
You are all on the defensive
instantaneously.
You are,
you are already a guilty person.
So they can virtue signal.
They can decide that you know,
you,
you need to be punished or you need to
be.
Your opinion is invalidated because of
the Melanin content and your scan.
I mean
crazy.
It's the antithesis.
I Love Martin Luther King and let's say
the content of your character and that's
so beautiful and it just,
it's,
it's so terrible,
this thing of you're white and you're
wrong,
and people don't understand.
That's the same thing as the,
the,
the racism that's been done to blacks,
you know,
for so,
so long.
And I mean,
I'm just,
I'm sort of stunned by that and this
idea.
I mean,
basically you're racist is now shut up.
That's what you did.
You pay attention to what went on in
Evergreen State College in Washington
state.
I love that guy,
Brian Steen.
Oh my God.
He's my hero.
And what happened was they were.
People don't know.
They essentially said we're going to
have a.
They used to have a day of absence
of people of color and the idea is it's
a very progressive school and they said,
look,
if we have a day where people of color
or people of varying ethnic people
aren't white,
essentially that's what it is.
They don't show up maybe where they will
be appreciated more and maybe we will
take them into consideration more what
for their absence will be felt,
so then they decided let's flip that
around and force white people to stay
home.
White staff members,
white teachers,
white students,
and Brett was like,
you're out of your mind like this is
racist.
It's one thing that you want to call
attention to the value of people of
color by not being there,
which is also arguably not the best way
to handle it,
but at least you're not saying to
someone that they cannot be there
because of the color of their skin,
which is what you're saying.
By forcing these people to.
And then obviously all hell broke out.
You know?
People were protesting him.
They were.
They were looking for him with baseball
bats.
The whole thing is horrific,
but it's this escalation,
this war of ideas where you're forcing
your ideas and your shouting people down
and calling people guilty before they've
ever done anything,
which is essentially what this is all
about.
And you know,
now he's not at school anymore and then
school is imploding.
I mean,
it's really crazy
and actually I would argue that,
you know,
for,
for people who are of color too,
to make a protest by not going to school
for a day after people fought so hard.
I love that.
That little girl,
the picture of the girls in little rock
going to school,
you know,
were they segregated?
They desegregated the school.
Imagine being a little girl and that's
you going with these police officers to
school or going crazy and,
and to value in education and to not to
skipping school.
Okay,
so then beyond that,
Bret Weinstein said his argument was,
I think this is racist and let's not do
it,
and let's talk about it.
And his speech in the hallway,
they're outside his classroom.
I saw him and I thought,
wow,
this is an amazing guy.
Look at how rationally is measured and
calm and full of grace in,
you know,
there's this mob there,
you're calling them racist and shouting
him down.
Him Down and I thought,
oh my God,
I want to study with the sky.
Can you please do a mooc on Coursera so
I can take a class from you and learn
how to do what you do in a heated
situation.
Nick Nicholas Christakis at Yale is
another one who had people screaming at
him and was just a class act,
you know,
and just as crazy and they've lost.
So you'd lost Bret Weinstein from
Evergreen.
He is.
I mean,
this guy was a valuable guy to have
there and it's so sad that he is now.
It just wasn't safe for him when they're
there with baseball bats.
I mean,
it becomes a circus.
You.
It's no longer about education.
You can see why he couldn't go back and
his wife too.
It's very sad.
Very,
very sad.
But this is what's happening.
That they're not allowing discussion.
This idea,
that accusation of your racist.
This is now just this thing.
It's a just giant muscle.
You're supposed to shut up,
just listen to what it is,
is a giant muzzle just shut up and it's
a way to silence you and it's a way to
force their ideas down your throat and
you bring something up there.
I call it a way to have unearned power
over other people.
And so I think that part of this,
the NPC part is that we have kids go to
college who are not prepared for college
and this is especially true if you go to
some terrible school,
not if you're the child of wealthy
parents who got all the sat training and
everything like that,
but so you get promoted because they
want a certain color face in there.
So maybe you do okay at Duke,
but they send you to Harvard because you
can get in there because they're like,
oh,
we have all these Asian people.
Screw you Asians,
we're going to like kick you out and not
admit you and will admit the craziest
thing.
Racist.
It's so terrible.
So maybe that,
if you could clarify that because people
don't know what you're talking about.
So what they do?
Yeah.
Policies Against Asians,
admission policies,
so Asians,
I mean,
I think it has to do something with the
culture and the family there.
There's um,
you know,
if you're Asian.
I had an Asian assistant before she
lived at home with her mother,
father and her sisters and her grandma.
You know,
grandma answered the phone.
You didn't speak Korean,
she hung up on you.
But there was a very strong work ethic
that you must succeed.
There were very strong family ethics.
It wasn't a single parent household.
And that's what happens to a lot of
these at risk kids.
I speak at a school.
I created a program to try to help kids
make it by showing example,
like saying,
look,
here I am.
I failed.
I slept on a door in New York on two
milk crates.
I'm not from a wealthy family.
You have to be creative apprentice to
somebody.
All this stuff.
Kids don't get that.
They don't get that.
If you're,
if you grew up in a bad neighborhood and
your parents don't model that sort of
work ethic and the possibility to hope
for success,
well why should you think there would be
any hope for you and why should you
work?
Because it's a little off track.
Okay.
Sorry.
Getting off track.
The standards for standards for Asians,
so they say,
oh look,
all of you Asians,
we have too many of these Asian faces
here.
It's so terrible and so we're not going
to admit you were going to take the
standards.
Standards for Asians are going to be
much higher than for everybody else and
so if you get this grade point,
say it's like a three point eight and
you're Asian,
forget it.
You're out.
But if you are this person of this face
color that we want,
we're going to put you in there even
though you know you have the same grade
point as somebody we're kicking out.
Sorry to ramble.
I do that,
but that's what it is.
It's like the.
They have higher standards for
admission,
like they've essentially put the bar
higher for them and it's racist.
It's racist,
it's terrible discrimination against a
minority,
right?
And they are a minority and it's
terrible.
And so what I hear minority than African
Americans and bigger minority than
Hispanics and Latinos.
It's a big minority in America.
I was thinking,
I was nodding and then I thought,
are they?
Oh,
that's really interesting.
so what I suspect,
and I could be wrong,
this is just a guess on my part,
is that when you are promoted to a place
where maybe you aren't capable of
succeeding,
um,
that maybe possibly you,
instead of putting your energy into
succeeding,
you put your energy into protesting and
saying the system is terrible and racist
and unfair because that is the way that
you become somebody and you have power
and everything.
If you can't get it through the,
okay,
I'll work hard.
Um,
the way,
which isn't to say,
so people think that when you say that,
you're saying,
oh,
this group of people,
they're stupider or worse than other
people.
But if you go back to the schools,
if you help those kids,
this is what they're doing with charter
schools.
If you give those kids what they're
missing there,
there isn't.
You know,
we're,
we're individuals.
You can help people who might have been
throwaway people to succeed.
If they just see,
look,
it's possible,
and here,
how do we put the stability?
Or are you.
You're a child of a single mother that
comes with it comes with certain risks.
If you grow up in a certain kind of
risky neighborhood,
there's a whole area of evolutionary
psychology called life history theory
that talks about this.
It's called having a fast life history
strategy.
It's adaptive.
If you grow up in a risky,
terrible neighborhood where things are
unstable to get pregnant early,
if you're a male,
to be violent.
All these these things that aren't
helpful in our modern society,
but they're kicked off by that unstable,
unstable environment where you grow up.
So okay,
if instability is a problem,
we can't just say,
okay,
you're single mothers should go back in
time getting a time machine and go find
a man and marry somebody before she has
you.
That's not realistic.
We can't throw away people and that's
what I see people advocating some times.
You know,
like,
okay,
well we've got to tell people to not get
pregnant without a,
you know,
a family structure,
people that they're not going to
understand human nature and so because
they've done that,
you don't punish the kids.
How do we give those kids to stability?
They lack and I think one of the ways is
to have people going from the earliest
grades and model what,
for example,
my parents modeled for me as these
suburban,
not wealthy,
but just sort of middle class suburban
people work hard,
do this,
do that,
and you will be okay.
Also the problem with the Asian folks in
universities is they don't complain and
the squeaky wheel gets the grease and
these people aren't protesting and
aren't screaming that it's racist.
What they're doing is they're putting
their head down,
they're working and they're working hard
and that's a part of their culture.
You know,
I grew up with a lot of Korean kids and
they're extremely hard working to the
point that I would feel like a lazy fuck
when I was around them and one of my
good friends when I was a kid,
my friend junk,
he was.
He was doing his residency for medical
school.
He was also competing on the US national
taekwondo team.
He was going to school all day long and
then he was training two to three hours
a night.
His kid was a fucking maniac and I would
be around him and I just felt so lazy no
matter how hard I worked,
it was so late,
but he never complained about anything
ever.
And it was the culture.
The culture was to never complain,
just to work hard and never complained.
And you're seeing that in universities,
you're seeing that with their results,
but you're also seeing that with the
that even though they're discriminated
against,
like racially discriminated against by
universities,
no one's complaining about it.
So they continue to do it.
So they do,
and they do it under the guise of
diversity because so many of these Asian
people are so successful in their
academic careers,
they doing so well and getting into
schools,
they're pushing them out to try to
balance it out,
but that doesn't balance out shit and
whatever you're doing is you're
encouraging this sort of weird way of
looking at people.
You know you're not,
you're not you.
You want equality of outcome.
Okay?
If that's not real,
you know,
equality of opportunity is real.
Equality of outcome is not real.
It's just people.
The equality of outcome happens when
everyone works the same amount and this
is the thing about a free society that
people don't like to understand,
but when you have inequality,
inequality is by in many ways because of
freedom,
because you have the freedom to choose
to work as much as you want or as little
as you want.
You're going to have inequality and
outcome and there's other factors for
sure.
There is absolutely discrimination.
There's sexism,
there's racism is always different
factors that play into account as well,
but there's also effort and to deny that
and tonight that effort is a factor in
the outcome is preposterous and it sets
up this fantasy land that so many kids
live in today.
While they're protesting.
Ben Shapiro calling him a fucking Nazi.
That's where it all comes from.
That there's these,
you know,
these.
You have a campus,
these,
these kids that are trying to shut down
Republican speaking on campus by calling
them and these blanket statements.
They're white supremacists and racists.
Like,
okay,
well what about Ben Carson?
He's a fucking Republican too,
and he's black.
There's a lot of people that are black
that are republican is a preposterous
way of looking at the world and it's
this sort of isolationist view and it's.
It's weird.
It's weird that they don't see how
racist it is to discriminate against
Asian people.
It's terribly racist and also if you
look at what real diversity is,
to me,
it's bringing in people who didn't have
economic advantage because these,
the people who have a hard time,
it doesn't matter if they're black or
white,
you know,
I know I have a number of black friends
who are highly successful.
Some of them are researchers and they
grew up in suburban neighborhoods.
They grew up like I did.
They had a family.
Their family was intact,
you know,
they didn't need a leg up from anybody
because they did what I did,
which is work hard.
My mother told me,
so I grew up a Jewish kid in an
neighborhood with no Jews and they like
Egged her house and everything like
that.
My mother said to me,
you know,
there are people who hate Jews,
so you're going to have to work harder
than other people because some people
are going to be prejudiced against you
and try to keep you out.
So that was a message,
not,
oh,
we should whine about this and isn't
this terrible?
His murderer issues my parents can be.
Yeah.
It's.
I don't know.
It would be really beautiful if
everybody just did the Martin Luther
King thing,
right?
Just judge people in the content of
their character,
not the color of their skin,
not the origin of their birth or their
ancestors birth,
but unfortunately we are tribal and we
do have these weird tendencies to sort
of lump ourselves together.
And by the way,
for people that are listening to this,
to disagreeing,
if you're a fucking social justice
warrior,
your tribal too.
If you're,
you're a radical lefty,
you're fucking tribal.
That's,
that's a tribal outlook,
you know,
and we would all be better off if we
were a little,
a little bit more balanced.
Me included.
Well me included to.
I mean,
and if we listen,
what I try to do is to look at the other
side,
you know,
the style side I don't agree with like
you were talking about this before where
you maybe see things,
you see their point or you look at stuff
that you want to agree with.
There was a nick kristoff thing.
I'm a piece on,
okay,
here's what we have to do with guns.
And I looked at it because we all want,
there's this idea of like do something,
we want to do something but something is
not a good thing to do.
And I looked at his piece wanting to
find something in there that would say
yes,
we just do these things in every single
thing in there.
It was all meaningless stuff that
wouldn't have stopped the guy in Vegas.
And so I looked at that wanting to see
something and you see nothing.
And so it's the thing of being honest,
being intellectually honest and honest
when your site is full of shit too.
Yeah.
And you know,
when it comes to something like the
thing in Vegas,
we want to find some sort of solution
when it doesn't necessarily exist.
There's so many different factors.
I mean obviously the access to weapons
is a big one.
That's a huge one.
And to deny that it's silly to deny that
on the right,
like the people that are massive second
amendment proponents like to deny that
the access to weapons has no factor in
someone using those weapons is pretty
fucking stupid.
I mean,
it doesn't make any sense,
but then to say that those weapons
should not be accessible to people who
are not criminals.
That's also weird because you're saying
like,
well,
what if you have.
If we have laws in this country that
allow a person to go and buy a gun for
personal safety and then something like
this happens where people get shot and
murdered by some crazy person and then
you take those rights away from the
people who have done nothing wrong.
That's not good either.
I mean,
yeah,
it doesn't stop it either.
Look at the Charlie Hebdo thing in
France.
They don't allow guns in France.
I don't even know if the policemen
armed.
I don't think they are different
thing.
Right?
Because that's Muslim extremists that
we're acting on religious
pulses,
but they got guns.
They got horrible,
horrible guns that killed people.
I mean it at that.
I think they might've even been
automatic weapons.
I mean I don't want to use that term
because I don't know anything about
guns,
so I probably just use that wrong,
but they don't allow guns in Francis.
They got them and I think that
criminals,
I live near the hood,
you know,
you can get whatever drug you want,
and the coroner.
Can you get that through my adderall?
Um,
you know,
maybe.
I don't know.
Good question.
Access is it's way.
Look,
Australia is a perfect example.
They had one mass shooting.
They rounded up all the guns.
They haven't had a single one sense,
you know,
but Australia also has less people than
Los Angeles and it's huge.
It's the size United States.
So you know,
there's,
there's a,
there's a discussion to be had for sure
and along you know,
the way we need to discuss access to
firearms.
That's a part of that discussion.
But you know,
I talked about it the other day with my
friend Alonzo Bowden and immediately
people were put making articles saying
that we are calling for a police state
and confiscation of the guns.
I didn't say that.
No one said that,
but this is the right wing,
you know,
second amendment proponent,
knee jerk reaction to an instantaneously
demonize anyone is critical of the guy
having the access to 23 fucking rifles.
Right?
And see the thing that that's happened
with the polarization is that now just
saying,
let's think about this,
you know,
because I'm libertarian,
I'm pro second amendment,
but I also think,
let's look at this.
That's not bad to say,
This doesn't mean we're going,
we want to take away everybody's guns.
It means that we want to think about
things as it's ever been a clear.
There's a giant problem with someone
having access to guns like that.
Show it to me because this guy broke
windows in a hotel and shot 500 fucking
people.
God,
if that's not a clear situation where
people need to look at it and go,
okay,
how does this get presented?
And it doesn't get presented by burring
your head in the sand.
It doesn't get offended.
It doesn't get prevented by just going
back to the second amendment and it just
yelling it out,
stomping your feet and pound your fist
on the table,
you know,
shall not be infringed.
That is not how you prevent your
children from getting shot by a fucking
psycho.
See,
I think what's hard in this too is that
we don't have any answers.
There's no.
Well,
if it was just mental health or just
this or just that because it's a
mystery.
So people are just grasping at things
and everybody standing their ground,
they eat the pro gun,
the anti gun,
and they're saying cc and all the
disgusting stuff on twitter.
And people did try to curb this a bit.
This stuff of people using that as a
ramp for their own whatever their views
were.
And that was pretty ugly.
You know,
seeing those videos,
you always have that right?
Will you always have that.
But in this,
you know,
when it's loss of life and it's not
just,
oh,
trump said this dumb thing,
you know,
that's that just barrage.
I saw that video of all the people
running,
um,
you know,
that it was,
um,
there's a,
it's like a 10 minute video and the
police hurting them.
Some people didn't even realize it was
gun fire and you hear that,
that,
that constant barrage when you hear that
for that period of time,
that gun going off so many times and so
many people,
um,
being just that guy's victim,
that was so horrible.
That guy's brother getting interviewed.
No,
I just saw a photograph of the 90 minute
interview
is one of the most fucking bizarre
interviews I've ever seen in my life.
He's so removed from his brother doing
this and he's talking about what a great
guy his brother is and how quirky his
brother was,
how his,
his brother was just.
He was eccentric and he was just talking
about what his brother would have done
in the casino.
People all
knew his brother and to say they didn't
know him was crazy,
but this guy seems like a guy trying to
act normal.
It is so weird.
I mean,
there might be some sort of a mental
health issue with the entire family
because the dad apparently was a psycho
and was a serial bank robber.
I don't know,
but it's some of the fucking strangers
interview where he's not like horrified.
He's not crying.
He's not stunned.
It's,
it's so fucking weird.
And it brings me back to the whole
mental health aspect of it.
You have,
there has to be a lot of shit wrong with
your mind for you to be able to do
something like that.
What it is,
what it is.
I hope we figure it out,
but sure do.
To Jesus.
Amy.
I thought it was gonna be a positive
interview to be a big old bomber.
A crazy girl.
What can I say?
Fine.
This is great.
It was fun.
I really enjoyed it.
Me Too.
Um,
so for people to want to read your
column,
it's advice goddess.com.
Yeah.
Or actually I prefer they read it,
look it up and papers and some of them
have changed it to the name I prefer,
which is science advice.
Got Us stuck concert.
I feel like this chick who is just
pulling out of her butt,
and then I have a new book,
unfuck ology field guide bucket in a lot
of your books.
I know.
So terrible.
This was an accident and it actually
sets a unfuck log,
a field guide to living with guts and
confidence and good manners for Nice
people sometimes say,
fuck.
Thank you,
amy.
It was a lot of fun talking to you is
great.
All right folks,
we'll be back in a little bit with a
Russell brand.
See you.
Yeah.