Dib.
Dib,
Dumb.
What's up man,
thanks for doing this.
Appreciate it.
Thanks for having me.
And thanks for introducing me to your
dog.
Cause I,
I have to tell you that that video of
you grabbing that raccoon and chucking
it down the stairs was easily one of the
most gangster things I've ever seen.
He lets you do.
Is this it?
I had to put a little disclaimer up here
so that you know the animal rights folks
wouldn't get pissed off.
Uh Yeah.
Well that's you're going to,
they're going to get pissed off anyway.
So right now I hear him crying cause
there's no audio on the cameras but he's
like just getting mauled by this thing
and you just picked it up and fucking
chucked it like gangster dude.
I mean you didn't just push it away.
You picked it up over your head,
went back behind the head like you're
throwing a medicine ball.
Cause another angle.
Yeah.
This is the best tackle over the back of
the head and show boom bang.
We're talking to Kevin Rose,
the founder of dig.
I got to say though,
it was a little liquid courage.
I'd had a couple of glasses of wine and
number two,
my intention was to go down there and
just kick it.
Right.
But it was on top of my dog so it'd be
punting my dog at the same time.
It was tangled.
Who's tangled?
So I mean,
you know,
then I grabbed it and it's,
it's greasy and kind of bristly.
Ooh,
so,
but you know,
whatever,
it's kind of,
it's one,
it's your baby.
I know it sounds weird to say what the
dog,
but it's just like I thought he was
dying.
He was getting,
he was howling like he was getting
shredded.
But with this clause,
you know,
so I'm thinking my dog is being killed.
Did you think it was a coyote?
No.
You know,
we had seen recommends in the backyard
before and it was just one of those
things where they always just kind of
like run away.
The second that the lights come on.
And this time I don't know what he was,
I don't know if he had babies.
Actually,
there were some other records that we
saw with him at the same time,
so I dunno man.
Those weird sort of a fringe wildlife
creatures like raccoons and coyotes to
kind of hang around.
Cities are so creepy.
Yeah.
There's a ton in San Francisco.
It's just all over the place at night.
They just dig through the trash
basically.
We'll San Francisco,
believe it or not,
at least the outside edges has a bit of
a mountain line problem.
I've heard that.
Yeah.
They've,
they did this study recently where they
check the digestive tracks of all these
mountain lines and they thought you were
going to find deer and rabbit.
No,
they found mostly pets.
Yeah.
It's like 50% cats and dogs is what they
found.
You don't want to tangle with a mountain
lion.
That's crazy.
Well,
it's just weird that they've chosen to
exist in the periphery of the cities and
sort of feed on these,
these pets house animals.
Yeah.
It's too bad.
It's not normal though that a raccoon
attacks a dog like that,
right?
Yeah.
They typically just take off that.
That's been our experience with them.
And then I proceeded to go on Amazon and
buy a trap.
Uh,
and so then I was able to trap what a
few days later and it was evil.
I mean like I went down there just to
check out the trap and I saw it from
above and when I got down there it was
just
hissing and trying to scratch the cage
at me.
And I mean they're not the friendly ones
that you see on youtube.
Like there's some that are like kind of
domesticated where they,
the people feed them and then they come
and you can pet them and whatnot.
These,
these wild ones or,
or just like the,
I will cut your throat kind of animals.
I had a feral cat for awhile and I love
tats but feral cats,
it is a completely different experience.
Like mine was a kitten.
It was a little baby will,
I mean it was really young,
like maybe three months old at the most
and you couldn't get anywhere near it.
He'd go near.
Anyone would run up the side of the
wall,
tear apart the curtains shit away from
you.
Just get rid of it or no,
I kept it.
I um,
I locked myself in a bedroom with it for
a couple days,
aiming it,
break it.
It's not even that I had a break it,
I just had to get it used to me it was,
it was a real weird experience.
My friend Lanie,
she and her boyfriend lived in this
apartment in west Hollywood,
like us,
like west La,
like Santa Monica area,
and there's these feral cats that had
had babies underneath the apartment
building.
And so they're like,
oh my God,
what are we going to do?
What are we going to do?
All right,
we have to trap them.
And so she knew that I already had two
cats.
So she's like,
do you want a cat?
And I was like,
all right,
fuck it.
Give me a cat.
Yeah.
And if you give those to the animal
shelter,
they'll just terminate him.
I tell him he,
that's too bad.
Well,
it was,
it was so hard to get used to this thing
but with hiss at you.
But when you pick it up it would go,
it would like be the loudest pervs and
he's so happy that someone was touching
it,
but then you put it down just for a
second and be like,
it would run away again.
It took forever and like it took,
it took years before it would let anyone
else get even close to it,
like hiding under furniture and things
like that.
It would hiss at you and run away from
you.
I was the only one that could touch it.
And even me,
I had a little,
I go,
hey dude,
it's me.
You know me,
right?
Yeah,
we're cool and I get close to him,
but he would swing at Ya.
He'd definitely bite you.
About a month ago I was looking up how
to break a horse.
I just thought that because it kind of a
fun thing.
Why?
Why not?
They would be amazing.
The bond he would have.
I know they'll kick your ass though.
That'd be fun though.
Yeah.
I think good like weekend project.
No,
get off the computer.
I could break a horse.
I know a bunch of people that have
gotten hurt from horses.
They're falling off horses and broken
arms and legs and stuff.
It's just,
I know a dude got kicked by a horse that
can be death.
Oh yeah.
They kill like all kinds of animals.
Like dogs barking dogs.
They kick them in the dump.
That's it.
Over.
Yeah.
I mean,
you're getting hit by a telephone pole.
This is fucking,
things are giant.
I mean,
it's an animal that can take a 200 pound
man and run with it on its back for
hours.
Right.
Just there's raw power there.
I was in Montreal and there's this
amazing restaurant called Joe beef and
um,
they serve horse there and it's one of
those places where,
um,
I know the owners through Anthony
Bordain.
He introduced me to them and so they
said,
just let us cook for you.
And so we're like,
okay,
go ahead man.
He goes,
fuck,
fuck them in and you'd just let us cook
for course three ways.
Will they,
that was just one of the things they
brought over.
We didn't know that what it was until it
like they set it down and they're like,
this is horse tar tar.
And we're like,
wait,
wait a minute.
What raw horse.
I've had lamb tar tar one time when I
was in Dubai.
That was a little funky.
It's very fatty.
And so it's a,
it's a lot of like,
um,
film on your mouth after you get done
eating it,
you know,
like the roof of your mouth.
Kind of like a little filming,
not,
not fun.
Well,
I'm a fan of lamb until I found out what
Lam is.
That it's,
it's baby sheep.
That's what it is.
You think of cheap though too,
right?
No,
that's mutton.
Oh,
interesting.
Yeah.
It's like veal is,
it's like the feel of the mutton world.
Yeah.
Um,
and I,
I went,
oh,
babies will really young.
Immature.
Hmm.
Yeah.
That's too bad.
It is too bad.
It is tasty.
It's the most delicious.
Well that's why when you get lamb chops,
it's a very small boat.
Interesting.
Yeah.
We would just assume,
right.
That's too bad.
You just kind of tainted me forever.
Bombed it.
Well,
it's really easy for you to digest.
For some reason lamb is a much more
digestible meat protein wise like for
it's very good for you.
Hmm.
A lot of people feel like it's a more
high quality meat,
closer to like a a wild game than say
like cows and you know,
things along those lines.
How do they measure that?
It's a good question.
They,
I know they can measure protein content
somehow and they know that like some
animals,
like I think moose as like the highest
protein content like per gram.
Yeah.
But I think it's also,
that's probably based on how lean it is
too,
because you would assume that it right
down it's piece of Moose would be far
less fat than an eight ounce piece of
domestic beef.
Right.
So that's probably how they measure it.
Crazy.
Well it looks different.
You know like lamb looks different than
beef when you look at it as like a
redder sort of a,
unless it's grass fed beef,
grass fed beef.
Pretty Rad.
Have you tried to bear?
Yes.
See I,
that's when I haven't tried it.
But I've been curious.
I've heard it's pretty oily though.
Uh,
no it's not.
Oh sorry.
No,
I'm,
well it really depends on how you
prepare it in the field and uh,
what you do with it.
But bear sausage is delicious and bear
backstraps the Loin is really good
grilled,
but bear you have to be really careful
because uh,
you can get tricky gnosis a lot of bears
up tricky analysis so you have to make
sure it's cooked to 165 degrees.
Oh,
interesting.
Yeah.
It's like,
um,
it's actually so there's no medium rare
bear.
No,
no,
you're going,
the only way you could ever do that is
if you got tested first.
You could do that.
Like you'd send it to a lab,
like you take the bear tongue and you
send it out to a lab and they test it.
Or is that a,
I think you might have to actually send
the actual meat itself or a piece of
meat,
but if it has trick analysis is
throughout his whole body.
Is it tough?
No.
Oh,
interesting.
There's weird men,
their bodies are very mushy.
You,
you would think of their bodies like
like an elk or a deer is a very strong
like they're very muscular like a horse
is right,
but a bear is almost like gushy.
Like when they die and when you pick
them up they like a fat person.
It's weird.
Well they hibernate and they have those
big fat stores.
I guess that makes sense.
But they have what you would,
the way you would describe it,
like they have a soft body but the,
the meat is very good.
Yeah.
It's like a,
it's the way I describe is like a pig
fucked a deer.
That's a bear.
Tastes like really cause I like pig.
Yeah.
You would like it to dear.
If I had some men,
I'm having some delivered on Thursday.
How long are you going to be in town for
me and I take off tomorrow.
Next time I'll bring you some a bear
sausage and I'll have it frozen for you
that you'd take it back.
It's really good.
And it's all,
it's,
it's also one of those animals were my
friend Steve Rinella calls them
charismatic megafauna.
Or if you say you eat bear,
there's a bunch of people that have
this,
oh,
this like knee jerk.
Right.
But it's one of those game animals where
it's actually imperative that people
hunt them because they don't have any
natural predators.
So if they don't get hunted,
if someone doesn't control the
population,
they decimate the moose and the deer
because they eat all the Fonz.
Interesting.
They eat,
uh,
all the ground nesting birds.
Then they just,
and then also eat each other.
So I,
I have a friend that collects
butterflies,
uh,
my friend's wife and apparently there
are places in the world where the
butterflies are a serious problem.
Like they overtake and eat crops and
like decimate everything.
Wow.
And that these beautiful like,
you know,
six,
seven inch butterflies,
but she sources them from there where
they actually have to kill them,
otherwise it's going to ruin the whole
environment.
Wow.
I didn't know.
Collects the dead ones.
Dead ones.
Yeah.
So she has him like,
you know,
up on the wall kind of in one of those
those cases so you can see them and when
you first walk in you're like,
okay asshole.
Like you know,
cause there's like all these beautiful
butterflies all over the place.
But uh,
yeah apparently that's,
that's the deal is you have to just
source them.
Well those really,
Really Cool Butterfly Butterfly Pavilion
in Denver is really awesome.
And it's a,
you go there and um,
when you go inside of it,
they have all these mres everywhere and
the entire place is just filled with
butterflies.
San Francisco has one of those as well.
Oh that's cool.
Yeah.
And the lands on your head and then
they're all around you and when you
leave you,
they have to like dust you off cause
there's so many butterflies on you,
but they die while you're there.
I mean there's shelf life or their,
their life is very short,
right?
So they,
they die constantly.
Like you find them dead all throughout
the place.
Not that anybody killed them.
They just die of old age.
Like we watched a couple of them just
sit down on a leaf and all of a sudden
they like,
that's it.
We're good.
Wow.
You're only good.
I mean,
I don't know.
How long has the butterfly live?
It's okay.
Does it say how long a butterfly lives?
Sure.
It's a super zen moments.
Yes.
I say a butterfly lives a week.
Yeah,
I think a week sounds about right.
It's probably a little last week.
I think so I'm looking,
you say a week,
but I'd say a little less than that.
There's so amazing looking.
It's such a strange thing that nature
can create all of these beautiful
designs and shapes and they'll just
different forms of life,
you know?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Especially in bug forum,
you know,
bugs are some of the most were,
I think we entirely take bugs for
granted this,
the idea of them,
they're so common.
What does it say?
A month.
Oh,
they will.
They last a month.
Interest.
Have you done any of that bug protein
powder?
Yes.
I haven't done the cricket stuff.
Tim Ferriss has entail.
Do you like that?
Um,
I like bugs.
I mean,
I really think that's probably because
of my time on fear factor.
I got super used to people eating bugs,
but I liked the idea of it because it is
like probably one of the most ethical,
um,
proteins.
Like it's the easiest to source.
It needs very little like land and
ground and for whatever reason,
even vegans,
most vegans don't have a problem with
you eating bugs.
Like most vegans will slap a mosquito,
right.
You know,
they're not going to let some mosquito
just vampire off right there.
We'll kill a mosquito.
So we have these,
this hierarchy of life.
You know,
plant life is at the lowest.
You're allowed to kill and eat plants
and then it gets up to weird animals
like bear.
We've heard of fruitarians.
Those are even more extreme than just
the general plants.
They only eat fallen fruit.
Yeah.
I had an aunt that was a fruitarian.
Oh God,
that's scary.
She was crazy.
Was she in bad shape?
Because they don't get a lot of
essential stuff.
We haven't talked in a long,
long time,
but she was,
she was crazy when I was a little kid.
She was a vegetarian when I was,
um,
I think I was like seven,
seven or eight and it was,
she only fallen fruit like fruit that
has fallen off the tree,
cause extreme version of that.
I think she probably picked it.
I didn't,
I didn't really know her very well and
she wasn't very close even to our own
children.
She'd have her on the crazy,
I don't think she'd be into it.
And she's probably,
I don't even know if she's around
anymore.
She's probably in her late sixties at
this point.
Yeah.
But she was,
she was a nutty hippie from,
you know,
the 60s had some kids and my cousins
just lost her fucking mind.
Yeah.
Rotarians man.
Yeah,
she was deep in the,
the world of plants,
but she had,
she wasn't healthy like mentally or
physically,
so it wasn't like someone that would go,
wow,
maybe that's the way to go.
It was like,
oh look at this crazy bitch.
You know,
like,
cause she didn't even like her kids.
Like she didn't have a good relationship
with her own children.
It's like,
how am I going to take you seriously
about fucking fruit,
right?
How will you be nice to people?
Crazy bitch.
No,
I mean there's certain,
I think we've all looked at like
vegetarians had been like seeing someone
really healthy and thought,
wow,
you're glowing.
Yeah.
Like I would also like to glow.
Like yeah,
I could see myself doing that,
but the,
the fruit stuffs a little too far.
Well,
before I started hunting,
I had two thoughts in mind.
One,
this was going to turn me into a Vegan
or to become a hunter.
So those are the two things that I went
into it with.
I,
I think there's a lot of health benefits
to eating a lot of vegetables.
I think everybody agrees.
Sure.
100% it's,
this is the real issue is it becomes
sort of a weird religion.
It becomes almost like a,
an ideology,
like a cult.
Like it can't,
there's no variables.
It's like eating animals is evil and
animals are sentient beings in this
despite what they do to each other,
despite the fact that like I had a
friend who's a Vegan,
we had this conversation and I said,
so no animal should be killed ever.
He's like,
no.
Okay,
okay.
I have two words for you.
Wild pigs.
What do you do?
Yeah.
And he's like,
well,
they have to be controlled somehow.
I go,
how the fuck are you going to do that?
You have hundreds of millions of acres
and you have wild pigs.
The amount of wild pigs in this country
is staggering.
Staggering.
It's exploding.
And there's [inaudible],
there's a highway that they opened up in
Texas and they had built this highway
and then they opened it up one night and
then that one night they opened,
they had like 40 car accidents with
pigs.
That's crazy.
Oh,
Texas is out of feathers as Rana pigs.
You can get his pets.
Pigs are taken over.
Nanopay have using seen the nano pink.
Oh,
tiny pet pigs.
They're like the size of a small toy
poodle.
But then they always have those like
didn't,
I couldn't fuck,
I ain't been around for awhile.
But they're becoming very popular.
Especially here in la.
I can't believe you don't.
You haven't seen them in la?
He'll walk them like dogs.
You would think that I would like,
because I live out here that I would
understand this place,
but my interaction with La is going to
the comedy store and the Improv going to
the comedy clubs,
going to where I buy food,
going to my neighborhood and being with
my friends and going to the gym,
like whatever,
wherever I work out.
That was pretty.
Do you enjoy the city then?
Or,
I think there's too many people here.
Yeah.
I just think,
oh look at these little cute little
fucker.
They're cute little bastards.
Look at that little ball.
But that's a baby though.
I mean that's a baby naming a question.
Let's say you get them though.
Wow.
And how big do they get when they're
full grown?
I think just like toy poodle size.
Great pets.
Apparently.
They're really smart.
Look at they look guitars.
Well,
I don't think that's real.
They entertain you apparently.
And it makes for them.
What a little cutie.
They're very cute.
But again,
it's like there's a big goddamn
difference between a domesticated pig
that you raise yourself.
That becomes like a pet and a wild pig.
I'll,
you're fucking scary.
We were in,
no,
this ranch,
this tone ranch,
we were hunting wild pigs were walking
down this road and it was the first time
I had any contact with them.
I didn't see them.
I heard them.
And they were in this tall grass and
they were maybe like 20 yards from us
and they were fighting.
So we're walking down this row were like
tip toeing down this road and we here
and I'm like,
this is like some Lord of the rings.
Shit man.
They have like the full tusks and
everything.
So these are Moore's basically.
Well that's where it's weird.
See a pig is something called sue
Scrofani.
I think that's how you say it.
And that genus is there.
They're all the same thing.
They're like dogs,
so they could breed with each other and
they're the same animal,
which means is,
this is a weird thing about pigs.
If you take a domestic pig,
regular pig,
pink pig,
and you leave them out in the wild,
they transform into that really well.
They grow tusks,
they grow tusks,
their nose,
their nose extends,
their body for gets thicker and more
dense and it happens really quickly.
I believe that transformation starts to
take place within six weeks.
So it was in within six weeks of being
wild and out in the wild,
having to fend for itself,
not having food given to it.
It's body starts to transform.
It's a very strange animal.
Yeah.
Do they know how to fend for themselves
and eat and all of that?
Like I think instincts take over.
They get desperado mean whatever.
Instincts are still left in the genes.
The fasting and ketosis brings it out of
them with,
yeah,
well they made a lot of carbs I think.
Right?
That's what,
but they'll eat everything.
I mean,
that's the thing about,
again,
ground nesting birds get decimated.
Everything in front of them.
I mean,
and for agriculture,
for places where they have farms,
they're absolutely devastating.
It costs millions and millions of
dollars worth of damage.
But the,
the idea that you can leave all animals
alone like,
well you won't be able to go outside,
you'll have a very dangerous
environment.
Right.
Like the mountain lion issues,
a big issue in California,
you know,
and right now it's pretty much under
control.
Kinder,
there's good,
there's good things to it too though.
Like one of the good things to it is
that we don't have deer ticks.
We don't have a lot of ticks out here
like they do on the east coast because
the east coast doesn't have mountain
lions.
Right.
So because of that,
and they don't have nearly as many
coyotes and see coyotes,
kimberly take out a full sized deer,
they can really,
they fuck up the Fonz and they kill a
lot of the babies,
but they can't relate to the big deer's
can kind of fend off a coyote,
but they can't fend off I'm outline.
Gotcha.
And Mountain Lions,
Jack.
So many deer that we don't have problems
with.
Like lyme disease out here.
Like lyme disease is a huge problem.
I've had coast,
I had a friend that got it here a couple
of years ago out here to fun.
No,
east coast.
East Coast.
Yeah.
He's coast.
It's real bad.
They were,
they,
there was some estimate that there was
something in like the Hudson valley
where they did a test of all these
different ticks and some ungodly
percentage had lyme disease.
Yeah.
More than 50% of the ticks had lyme
disease,
which is terrifying.
Yeah.
Cause that'll socks.
It's,
and it's what's fucking devastating to
your immune system.
It really wrecks your body and some
people get it and they keep it forever.
I mean it just fucks with their system
forever.
Yeah.
I had a buddy that had to go on hardcore
antibiotics right away.
The second you get diagnosed with it and
you have to do cycles of those to try
and get it out.
It's really brutal.
Well,
I have a friend who got it and he
brought his son.
His son got it too.
And he brought his son to the doctor and
it was a shitty doctor.
The doctor didn't want to believe that
the kid had disease
and then all of sudden the kid's face
went palsy.
He had bell's palsy where his mouth
started drooling and his,
his,
his lips wouldn't move to that comeback
or is that,
yes.
Hardcore antibiotics.
Intravenous antibiotics.
And they had to do it for a long time,
like a month of hardcore antibiotic.
It's brutal.
Well it's,
it's a scary disease man,
because it also was related to,
um,
there's that more Jerilyn's disease,
which for a long time they thought more
jealous might be some sort of a
psychosomatic disorder where people
believe they had like fiber's going out
of their skin and they're itching
themselves constantly.
And they would,
they would bring these fibers to doctors
to exam and they say,
my body's growing these fibers.
Weird.
Yeah.
But it wasn't really going on.
What was going on was that the fibers
were like carpet fibers and things that
were stuck to their skin.
And so I interviewed this guy who was a
more gel and suffer and he was also a
doctor.
So it was kind of fascinating,
um,
to get his perspective on it.
And He,
and he was very frustrated by the way
the medical establishment treats us
disease because they were treating it
like it's like a completely
psychological disorder.
And he's like,
I don't think so.
He goes,
I think there's a neuro toxicity to this
disease.
And that one of the things about this
disease was a vast majority of the
people who hadn't made more jealous also
had lyme disease.
So what he thinks,
and this is,
there's not enough people that have it,
but he thinks his lyme disease affects
your brain.
There's some sort of a,
of neuro toxicity to this lyme disease
when it gets to some people.
And the other thing he said,
when you get lyme disease,
like you have a,
a tick that gives you this,
this disease and the tick carries it in
his body gives to you.
He goes,
it's not like it's giving it to you in a
syringe and it's a pure form of this
disease.
It's like you're getting a variety of
different pathogens along with that.
And the,
when he was describing it to me,
I was like,
oh,
this totally makes sense.
It's probably just as very small sample
size of people who have this problem.
But the people haven't,
man,
they get fucking crazy.
Do you go out to the east coast at all
then?
Do you avoid all the tapes like I go but
I'll spray stuff.
There's clothing that they can,
um,
that they've designed for people that
are in those areas that you make sure
socks up to like the beltline kind of
thing.
But you can get bit even through socks.
It's really pants and,
and,
um,
boot gators and all these different
things to make sure that they don't get
in the crevices.
And,
and if you come in contact with an
animal that has it,
you have to be really careful that makes
sure those ticks don't come off and get
onto you and you gotta be careful.
It's,
it's no joke.
Yeah,
that's not fun.
What's so scary?
Because it fucks with your immune system
and it really,
depending upon how bad you get it and
who you are and what your makeup is,
you know,
some people just have a really nasty
averse reaction to it.
It's a matter of fact,
my friend's dad got
it from a vaccine.
They used to give a vaccine for lyme
disease and they don't do it anymore
because it could turn into full blown.
Wow.
That's the stuff you always worry about.
Yeah.
Well it's one of those things like,
you know,
it's like the people that get the flu
shot every once in a while somebody
comes down with a full blown for sure.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Well,
that was always the argument about,
um,
vaccines too.
Like people were always saying,
you know,
there's this always this,
this thing like,
hey vaccines give people autism vaccines
do this.
And then there's the other campuses,
vaccines are harmless.
Well,
it's never harmless.
He shoot a chemical in your body.
It's harmless.
The vast majority of the time,
it's beneficial the vast majority of the
time.
But if you're one of those one out of a
thousand people,
there's not that much comfort in the
fact that your brain gets fucking fried
because they tried some experimental
fucking weird vaccine on.
Do you do any of that stuff?
Do you do any of the,
uh,
flu shots every year?
No.
I don't do flu shots,
but I did it this year and I came down
with the flu.
I got decimated.
I'm one of those guys that has a really
strong immune system until I don't,
and then I'm like out for like a month,
you know?
Like I'm like,
you know,
licking my fingers all the time and like
you don't need to just feel invincible.
Yeah.
Like I haven't gotten sick for like 10
months and I don't wash my hands
sometimes and it's disgusting.
But uh,
then I just went down hard this year.
Well,
there's so many factors,
right?
It's like health,
sleep,
diet.
I think I was doing too much cold
therapy stuff.
Cold,
terrible.
Like Wim Hoff.
Stop.
Yeah.
When I'm off stuff too much.
Too much.
I was talking to Rhonda Patrick,
who you've had on the show before about
this and um,
you know,
just too many stressors cause that's a
stressor.
You know,
you have green teas,
a stress or you have,
turmeric is a stressor.
You have exercise as a stressor.
And if you're doing that every single
day.
And I was doing the cold stuff,
uh,
you know,
five,
six days a week along with,
and not,
not talking cryo but like cold ice,
cold showers.
Um,
and then along with exercising and
interval training and everything else,
cold showers,
your northern California,
right?
Yeah.
That's all I'll say is actually in New
York.
So they were really went to my gym has a
freeze.
I don't know why,
but their showers when he turned to the
cold setting,
I'm lucky at home.
I don't have that.
I go to the gym and on the cold setting
I put my hands,
uh,
you know,
as I'm washing my hair,
uh,
under the cold shower and my hands are
numb within 45 seconds.
Like it's really,
really cold.
Jesus.
Yeah.
Well New York has some fucking severe
cold winter.
Yeah.
And you get that cold water in the
winter.
That's real cold water.
Oh I love it.
People call it to talk about cold water
California.
It's kind of cold.
Right?
Let's,
he'd go into a glacier river.
Yeah.
I'm so bummed when I come out here cause
I go and I stay at a hotel or something.
And the first thing I do when I get in a
hotel is on cold setting in the showers
to see what we're dealing with.
It's all week.
Yeah.
You know,
you have to go do proper cryo if you
want to do that.
Well it's great after yoga in the
winter,
like there's,
you can actually get pretty cold water
here in like January in the,
but like
after a hot yoga class it feels
unbelievably cold.
Yeah.
And like you can't breathe.
It's like a probably more of a reaction
even in Cryo.
Oh interesting.
Was cry was weird cause it's cold as
fuck,
but it's dry.
So get in there and there's something,
that's where they talked about the
desert.
They're like,
it's a dry heat.
Like you know,
it's a dry cryo.
Well that's California's heat too in
comparison to like praxis.
I give you ever been to Houston in July.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It's brutal.
It's like trying to breathe through.
It's like you're getting waterboarded
right?
Like nonstop.
Yeah.
It's like a hot fucking wet blanket on
your face.
But,
um,
the,
there's,
there's a definitely difference in that
cold.
That's where you're not getting wet.
Like Wim Hof actually prefers ice baths.
He thinks the ice baths or better for
you and,
and,
and the way he describes it better for
your spirit.
Hmm.
Yeah,
I've done the ice pass a few times.
That was week 10 for me on his,
uh,
his course.
I went and got 10 bags of ice from the
corner store,
filled up my bathtub with cold water and
then put all 10 bags of ice in there,
a submerged myself up to my neck and did
that for 15 minutes.
Wow.
Did you get anything out of it?
You know,
I will say I am a,
I'm a huge believer in just cryo and
cold therapy in general in that,
um,
I would,
my mood is elevated.
It's more than anything else.
It's my mood.
Yeah.
I find myself,
like I'm,
I'm generally a really happy guy.
Like I,
you know,
we all have their ups and downs as as it
were,
but this kind of just raises the bar and
additional,
I would say like 20%.
And so you have a higher high,
if that makes sense.
You know,
always gonna stay up pegged up there and
be like a whole new person.
But it's just different.
It's,
it's,
it's amazing.
It's been a game changer for me.
And so I've gotten really deep on the
research side,
different than Rhonda.
Rhonda goes the science route.
I go into the history.
So I've been researching people that
have done this for hundreds of years now
and their protocols and what they've
done.
And what have you found?
Ah,
I'm not ready to release it yet.
Dare you teased?
No,
I've got like,
I've been doing a ton of research.
I'm either going to put out like a big
pdf on it or a little mini ebook or
something that'll give away.
I don't,
I don't know.
But,
um,
you can't give us a like a taste.
Well,
a good taste would be,
uh,
let me think here.
There's some people in Russia that have
done it for a long time,
hundreds of years,
and I got ahold of their original
documents and had them translated so I
could figure out what the protocol is to
Banja and then for freezing water.
That's right.
Yeah.
Fado or Amelion Inco,
like probably the greatest heavyweight
UFC or mma rather fighter of all time.
He was a pride heavyweight champion,
you know,
he is,
no,
that was his thing.
He would do the Banya when they beat
each other with those eucalyptic
branches.
Right,
right.
I've done that ton of time by the
private other branches,
but I've watched it being done.
It's fast.
It's cool.
It does look cool.
I bet it would be refreshing,
you know,
and get,
I mean,
they're not hurting each other.
No,
they just slap you around with some
branches and they climb from the hot
sauna and the climate to the water.
But when I always thought of it was just
like something that makes you feel a
little bit better.
But when you read and to Rhonda
and her research on Sauna and 40% less
mortality across the board from all
factors,
whether it's cancer,
disease,
heart attack,
all these different things,
you're like,
what percent drop in mortality?
Like that's incredible there.
And then she ducks about the actual
physical measurable responses to Sauna
to extreme heat,
heat shock proteins,
and then also cold shock proteins.
You realize like,
oh,
there's some something really going on
here.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And you could feel it after a couple of
weeks for me,
my friend,
I've had friends do one and they're
like,
I didn't,
I,
it's too cold.
I can't do this.
And I'm like,
you don't understand.
It's not about just that one time,
I don't know about for you,
but it was about week two to week three,
we're all of a sudden I just woke up and
I'm like,
wait a second,
I feel like I'm 16 again.
Or you know,
just like a little bit.
My mood was just crazy.
Good.
Well,
no,
what does she call it?
North northern epinephrine,
norepinephrine,
norepinephrine.
It's a weird word,
nor epinephrin nor [inaudible] nor
epinephrin norepinephrine.
Yeah.
That stuff,
that feeling that you get,
it's very tangible.
It's like a drug.
It's almost like [inaudible] like
getting a little,
just a tiny taste of pot.
Just a little,
just a little text.
Hi.
I brought that up in our podcast that I
did with her.
It was,
it's like,
it's like you're at a concert and you
have like a little hitter and then
you're like,
whoa.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
It does.
It makes the sun feel better.
It just,
it's great.
And,
and also for aches and pains and you
know,
for someone who,
who trains a lot the measurable effect
that they found as far as like reducing
the inflammatory markers in the blood,
you can feel that.
You can absolutely feel the response to
that when you do it like a week or two
in a row.
Yeah,
that's right.
Um,
so do you know that cold therapy used to
be,
um,
like it was used as a treatment for
insanity?
Did you know that back in the day?
So van Gogh,
when he cut his ear off and they put
them in the insane asylum,
um,
they've forced him to do two weekly,
two hour long sessions of cold therapy.
And he writes about it.
This is a little teaser of some of this
stuff research I've been doing.
He writes about it in his letters to
friends and so his letters are
documented online and you can find the
Vango letters.
And then I've dug into all of his
letters and found any mention of cold
therapy and what it's done to his mood.
It's fascinating.
And what was he saying?
He was just saying that,
yeah,
I mean you could look it up.
He was just saying that he was a big
believer and he's feeling so much
better.
And then,
and then I found pictures of the tub
that they used to use.
So what they would do is he would lay
down in a bathtub and they would put
this like wood,
um,
cover over the top,
but just with your head's sticking out.
So almost like a guillotine kind of
thing.
It's a gay teen was the one where they
chop your head off getting okay.
And so they have his head sticking out
and then they would just pour ice cold
water through the tub if for two hours,
twice a week.
Yeah,
it's a,
you can't do anything.
You're stuck them.
And they would do this to treat insanity
and it worked.
And then of course drugs came along and
everything else.
And then all of this just gets
forgotten.
Um,
but that's one example.
Another one is I found some monks out,
uh,
in Japan that study this,
um,
this form of meditation and Buddhism
that where they sit underneath,
I'm waterfalls,
the waterfalls,
and they meditate and I found their
chance and all of that that go along
with that.
So that's something I'm going to put in
this document as well.
So you know,
Hixon Gracie is,
it sounds familiar.
Hicks and Gracie is the grappler Gracie.
Yes.
He's hoists.
Gracie is the guy won the original UFC,
but he had his brother,
his brother Hixon as almost like a
mythical creature in the world of
martial arts because he's universally
hailed as the greatest Jujitsu fighter
of all time.
Okay.
Universally by,
this is the guy they call it the Michael
Jordan of Jujitsu.
Jujitsu is one of those things where
there's so many good guys.
It's so hard to figure out who's the
best.
Like this guy might be that guy and the
next year that guy can beat this guy,
but this is Hickson.
He's also a legit Yogi,
like you practices yoga on a regular
basis.
This guy,
he,
he's amazing and you know he's,
he's actually been on the podcast too
and I had to check to talk to him.
That's the buffets.
Yoga was very buff,
especially when he was young.
Well,
he was a mixed martial arts champion,
a Brazilian Jujitsu champion,
but he was also the champion.
He was in that movie,
the Hulk.
He was,
the guy was teaching Ed Norton how to
control his,
his,
his calm.
A control is a his anger to try to keep
them from turning into the hulk.
But there's this documentary called
choke and it documents Hicks and
competing in the 1994 Japan valley to
doe.
He went over to a [inaudible] 96,
maybe 96,
I don't remember what year it was.
Um,
but he went over to Japan and competed
in this big mixed martial arts
tournament and when he was over there as
part of the time that he spent was
climbing into these freezing cold rivers
and getting out of these waterfalls and
meditating.
Oh that's awesome.
And there's video of him doing it in
like his other family members tried to
do it.
They get in the water for a couple
seconds.
I'm like,
fuck this right there he is.
He's in there doing these,
a yoga,
breathing exercises.
That's what women teaches a lot of that
breathing to go along with.
You have to be really,
really careful.
There's been people that have passed out
doing the breathing exercise cause there
there's so deep and it's really like
giving you all that oxygen.
Yeah,
I put it oxygen meter on my finger when
I do the breathing exercises and I take
it,
I have a right around 98 like no one's
ever really at a 100 all the time.
Some people weird people are,
but I can bring myself up to a hundred
percent and what does it measuring the
oxygen and the level in your blood?
I just pure oxygen.
Yeah.
It's like a,
you know those little meters that they
clip on you when you go to the doctor's
office,
you can buy those for $15 on Amazon.
So,
but how's it did?
Was it tapping into your blood somehow?
Like how it measuring?
It's a little led light that it shoots
into your finger and through looking at
the led through finger,
like the same way,
like your phone can measure your heart
rate,
right?
So this does heart rate along with a
blood oxygen level.
How the fuck does it know your blood
oxygen level?
I think magic and think,
damn,
this what a wonderful world we live in
and it's available on Amazon prime for
$15 not only is it amazing,
it's also will be here in one hour of
use.
Postmates I'm fucking the JC to one
click and I'm so addicted as the fall of
Western civilization.
The people that run those ups stores
that get packages delivered to them and
shit like that,
they did not know what they're signing
up for with one click and came around
suicide rates through the roof.
Like you gotta be hating life.
I guess maybe they just really in the
packages and they love it.
I love it.
Someone who has like a package fetish,
there's like,
fuck you,
I'm more,
Amazon's coming.
People are in a weird shit.
They are into weird shit.
I mean,
I don't think there's ever a one thing
that people have been into where I was
like,
ah,
I can't believe it.
You know how there's those people that
get into video games like Farmville and
all that and they spend like hundreds of
pounds.
There has to be the equivalent of
Amazon,
right?
Oh,
you don't have people that just want to
click the shit out of Amazon every
single day.
My grandfather was dying.
My grandfather,
when he was really old after my
grandmother died in particular,
he was like super depressed and he got
addicted to catalogs.
It's really sad.
They like my dad before he passed away,
he started,
you know,
as he would give us,
getting into his seventies started doing
just more qvc shopping and just stuff to
shows up and you're just like,
damn,
why'd you buy that?
And granted,
I mean he always had you always get cool
stuff.
I was always like,
oh,
that's a cool way to slice tomatoes or
whatever it may be that showed up,
but it was like,
you don't need it.
I think old people,
they just are,
as our brain starts to go,
they just come more susceptible to that
kind of stuff.
That is by everything.
Yeah.
That's why those late night
televangelists are so dangerous.
Super Dangerous.
They are preying on people with faulty
mechanisms and then they call it and
donate $100 or whatever and they think
they're going to save their child from
diabetes or who knows.
You know,
they found a method a few years back
that was really troubling and what the
was is they would pray on the poorest of
poor people and would do,
would explain his late.
They would say,
I know you don't have any money.
I know your bills are due.
I know that you need this money,
but if you send that money,
God will multiply that money tenfold and
they'd have all these people.
They'd say,
I,
you know,
my rent was due,
you know my carpet.
They were going to repossess my car,
but I sent $100 and the whole audience
is clapping and cheering.
I give a $100 to God.
That's all this first,
and then all of a sudden I hit that
lottery ticket and a lottery ticket.
I said,
good Lord,
it's $500 it's true.
Jesus gave me $500 and everybody's
clapping and cheering and they would go
on to another story.
Meanwhile,
this guy's got a fucking f $5,000
suit on.
It's probably driving a Bentley.
It's,
it's dark.
It's the preying on people that have
just faulty mechanisms.
Their brain is not working right and at
their lowest possible point and then
you're just kicking them.
They're down.
It's really,
really sad.
The old ones,
we're worried about death.
I mean death is imminent.
It's on the way the body's feeling and
as body's failing,
here's some guy on television that's
saying a bunch of things that you know,
and I think there's like sort of the,
a window of,
of cognitive function that starts to
close and it's very hard to,
to perceive and you're on the outside.
You have to kind of like talk to them a
lot to see like,
oh,
your ability to think is really clearly
compromised right now.
Right?
And,
but you know,
they talk and they talk and they seem
fairly normal.
But if you're around them a lot,
then you kind of get the full picture of
what's going on.
And those,
those types of people,
like man,
that's what they,
they're going to prey on.
Yeah.
I mean it happens.
This is,
I don't know if you ever get forwarded
those email chains that like people send
around.
My mom is obsessed with this kind of
stuff in her,
in her seventies and it just like,
you know,
people saying that something is a fact,
especially in politics as well when it's
just made up,
you know?
And then it's like,
well I got it an email and it said that
it was from CNN.
I'm like,
mom,
did you click the link to,
to actually take you to CNN?
Did it actually should say that in the
article?
You know,
it's,
it's just difficult because they believe
anything that is on the Internet.
Yeah.
And there's also,
I mean obviously confirmation bias.
Like you could always find a form that
will tell you that the world is flat.
There's a whole flat earth community out
there.
They've openly mock me.
They're angry at me.
Are you serious?
Oh yeah,
they've made videos.
How big or how big is the flat k?
Look,
if you,
if you stop and think about the sheer
numbers of people just in this country,
just let's,
let's go with America.
There's 300 million people in this
country plus,
right?
At least one out of a hundred is a
fucking idiot,
right?
At least.
So you have 3 million fucking idiots
just in this country and out of those
fucking idiots,
you can tell.
I have a friend of thinks here.
If it's flat,
that really fully believe I'm talking to
you,
bitch,
he's crazy.
He's great guy,
great pool player.
A professional pool player thinks the
fucking world is flat.
Who's,
he was arguing with my friend Justin
about whether or earth was flat,
uncle Max.
There's all these fucking pictures.
He goes,
I think those pictures and fake.
So everyone's in on it from the
beginning of time since they started
taking pictures of planets,
all those planets,
The sun,
the moon,
Jupiter,
all that shit just happens to be round
and you're not buying it.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
You just have to feel compassion for
those people then.
Right?
It's circular.
But it's flat.
It's something's not right upstairs.
Well,
I think people love to be the person who
does.
I think there's like a,
there's something going on in the human
brain or the human brain has always been
curious and we're trying to innovate and
it's like there's like a,
a part of the brain that has this
insatiable desire to create better
things and to innovate and to constantly
find a better way in that.
We're always constantly searching for
secrets as well.
Oh,
well if you do that,
then it works.
Hey,
you take this flint and you're banging
it against this steel,
you can make a fire.
So we find these things and then we're
always trying to find the things that
people are hiding.
Like what are they hiding from us?
Right.
What kind of secrets?
And he find out about some secrets that
are true and some conspiracies that
absolutely do exist,
whether it's William Randolph hearst,
whether it's fucking Rockefeller trying
to keep,
you know,
alcohol from being legal because he
wants to protect the gasoline market.
It's like all these like real
conspiracies that you find out and they
fuel the speculation and then they want
to be the one that tells you,
you know that the sky is falling.
Right.
They want to be the one.
There's no way around that.
It's just going to happen until the end
of days,
2000 and you know,
it's a weird aspect of people.
It's a,
well it's also,
but I bet you believe in a few of those
as well.
I mean like what is your take on Ufo
shows?
I don't think it's impossible that we
have been visited by see no evidence.
Don't think it's impossible.
So you do think it's possible?
I think it's absolutely possible that we
could have been visited by a life form
from another planet and one point in
time,
but there's no evidence.
Zero,
zero.
So you don't think any of the photos,
any of the videos and those objects
moving in my possession is the thing
that I've seen some objects that move in
space that are fascinating.
Yeah.
Like some fast.
And you're like,
how did that jump across?
I mean,
that's amazing to me.
I don't know what that is,
but also there's also some weird shit
that's,
that absolutely exists that they can
prove on earth.
Like bald lightening.
Have you ever seen ball lightning?
No.
This video is a ball lightning.
Paul lightning is like sums,
weird phenomenon where lightening
instead of coming down to the ground,
it can fly around like a ball.
Yeah,
yeah.
That's probably half of the videos.
You have a good percentage.
There's a lot of them that are just
stars for people who are just retarded
and they,
they look,
oh,
it's all like move.
Yeah.
I mean there's been firefighters that
have launched missiles,
it stars planets or whatever.
It's like there was something about that
Venus,
you know,
people think the Venus is a spaceship
and I think there's,
there's also absolutely been
experimental aircrafts,
right.
When we were filming fear factor in,
um,
I'm way out in the middle of the desert
and Palmdale,
which is near Edwards air force base and
they had the stealth bombers,
it was like right after September 11th
and you watch those things fly over,
you swear to God,
you're in Star Wars.
Like,
okay,
that's spaceship.
Darth vader lives on that,
right?
He's flying that like this is,
this is not a person in there because it
looks like a star ship.
I've,
uh,
I spent a lot of time out in the desert.
I used to work at the Nevada test site
by,
uh,
area 51.
He did back way back in 2000 and you do
out there?
Well,
I was into technology and uh,
this was,
um,
kind of when I was studying computer
science and so I was working out there,
pretty low level job,
but I had to bounce around between the
different areas.
So there's,
the test side is divided into,
you know,
50 plus areas and like groom lake,
like that area lake is one of them.
That's area 51 that's the best known,
but there's so many other areas like,
and there's different things on every
plot of land.
And so,
um,
there's one called a beef,
which is the big explosive experimental
facility.
Um,
there's a lot of sub critical nuclear
testing has done underground so it
doesn't break any treaties,
but they can figure
out,
um,
the yield based on the test that they
do.
So they can still do kind of nuclear
tasks,
but it's not actually producing a,
but it's still closed off all the areas
when they do it.
Um,
and then there's every three letter
agency you could imagine,
rents out a piece of the test site to do
tests and experiments.
So it was my job to set up all the,
at the time,
no Ville networking equipment between
areas so that they can talk to each
other.
What year was this?
2000,
uh,
just before that,
99,
98.
99.
2000.
What was the year where they had to
admit that that was actually a base
because they had to expand the area that
was forbidden to trespass on?
Yeah.
I'm not sure what,
what was in the 90s,
because they had denied it forever.
They did when I was there.
But it was so obvious,
like you would go into the,
um,
it was weird because they were just,
you would go into the,
well first of all,
you couldn't go to any,
any area unless you had a reason to be
there.
And he also had to have a proper
security clearance.
So I had what was called the q clearance
and then even if I had,
which was top secret,
but even if I had top secret in less,
I had a request.
And then if I went into an area that had
sensitive information,
I would also have to be escorted at the
same time.
But some of the areas that weren't
really classified,
they were just secret areas.
Like,
um,
the power facility for example,
you'd walk in and they'd have the
chilled power clearly going to groom
lake.
Like it would,
you could see the line going straight to
groom lake,
but they would say it didn't exist,
but it would show the line going up
there.
And it was just like,
that's so silly.
Like why would you even show that if
that was the case,
you know?
Well,
I think they probably feel like no one
can go there.
So what are you going to do?
Right.
We just,
it's easier to deny it go fuck off.
It's not real.
Yeah.
The air force took that over,
um,
when I was there.
So the air force was running it.
Um,
it was department of Energy,
which handles all of our nuclear
program.
Uh,
but then the air force,
and then there's another,
there's extra guard gates before you get
there.
So when you head into mercury in Nevada,
you get through one guard gate,
which is show your badge.
Um,
guard comes on,
the bus touches your badge,
looks at your id all if I could touches
it touches,
it has to physically touch it.
I don't know.
It was just a thing.
It was a requirement.
They have one them feel that it was real
because it was just like laminated a
certain way.
So I didn't know what they had to touch
it.
Um,
and then once you get through the,
the,
the front gate there,
then to go and do a further areas,
you could drive out there but you,
there'd be other gates if there was
secret information going on between,
um,
where you left and where you were
headed.
So if you want to get to groom lake,
there was one other guard station just
outside of,
um,
the,
the sedan,
sedan crater.
If you look up sedan crater on Google,
there's this massive crater that was
done via nuclear test and right past
that is one,
one more guard station.
So it's severely compartmentalized.
Oh,
absolutely.
Wow.
And then a in an area can go dark and
then then,
you know,
department of defense can come in and
take it over and just do test there for
three months and then it's dark again
and they just destroy everything they
were working on now,
like this massive crater from the
nuclear tests,
like they're all over the place.
So the test that is just filled with
craters,
that's so crazy.
And you can stand on the edge of their,
they have a little platform there.
It's kind of fun.
Well,
they did some,
some pretty extensive nuclear tests out
there.
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
We had to wear a little dishonor around
our necks and make sure you're okay.
Well it wasn't real time,
sadly.
So you would send it in and get it
analyzed afterwards and they tell you
how much radiation exposure you had
fucking Christ.
But you know,
we were all going in.
It was so mellow back then.
It was already kind of all cleared out.
That's so spooky though.
It is spooky.
There's all these craters all over the
place where they were just like a
warning.
Just drive up to,
yes.
Yeah.
Tribes would like to get out.
Now,
when you were there,
was there anything that made you think
that the government had any knowledge of
extra terrestrial aircrafts?
Was there any whispers of it?
Where's her?
Uh,
there was whispers of a few things,
but they weren't like Iti related stuff.
It was just a,
it was government projects,
like other,
other secret test projects that were
going on.
So you think that's what a lot of people
were seeing when they're talking about,
I think it was five flying.
I truly believe,
even though this isn't,
I never heard of anything,
but I had,
I dunno,
there was friends that we had that
worked out in those areas and I think
they were experimenting just based on
the skill sets that were going out there
on a kind of antigravity related stuff.
Ooh.
So that's,
that's kind of what groom lake wasn't
being used at that point in time for any
more research and development.
I think all that had been,
I think it was all kind of underground
cause a lot of that is underground.
It's an underground base as well.
So there's hangers out there and there's
a really long runway.
But that was all for testing.
That was done in like the,
you know,
the seventies and eighties that were
done out there.
Fuck man,
I would love to go see what an
underground base looks like.
Yeah,
they must raise the state of the art.
You would think that.
But it,
a lot of this is underfunded stuff
really went underground one time in one
of the areas and they make you take this
respirator training before you go
underneath there.
So you have to know how to use these
emergency packs in case just no air in
case there was no air.
First of all it's really cold.
It gets really cold immediately as you
start to go ground.
Um,
and like,
you know where I was wearing a jacket,
like it was,
it was 40,
I don't know,
it was so long ago,
but it was,
it was where I had to wear like a
lightweight jacket,
like a meat locker or like refrigerator.
Well it was once we got down in there,
it was kind of during the,
when you go down into the,
the shaft that was,
that was when it was a chilly.
But once we got in there was a little
bit more climate controlled.
Um,
but you know,
they go down underneath the ground to do
some of these experiments and so that's
part of the reason why I had to go down
there.
Whoa.
The other big thing out there is really
awesome.
It's called the Daft,
the,
uh,
device assembly facility.
Daff you can,
you can go with that one as well.
This is where they assembled nuclear
weapons in the United States,
which is just,
um,
so that was,
that was another fun one to check out.
That was a super,
super guarded facility.
That one was extremely hard to get into.
So these underground bases are
underfunded.
Well,
this one in particular was used for
experiments,
so it wasn't like a permanent thing.
Right.
A lot of these,
so for example,
when they did the subcritical nuclear
tests,
they would have you go all the way
underground.
They'd set up all the test equipment,
they would seal it with concrete,
they would detonate it and then they
would close off the whole,
so it was always locked down in,
just underneath there.
And so that's,
that's Kinda just underground forever.
That sounds like such a crazy way to do
it.
I mean,
they just didn't have the funds or you
know,
they're not going to go in there and dig
up a bunch of busted equipment that
already detonated.
So it's like,
well,
it seems like a halfway thought out
idea.
Like someone goes,
well,
how are we going to contain the
explosion?
Okay,
okay,
okay.
This is what we're gonna do.
We're going to blow it up and we're
going to seal it off.
Okay.
And then they just went with it.
Like nobody came along and go,
hey,
fuck head.
You can't do that.
Right.
No,
that makes that place like toxic for
100,000
a year.
You know,
this is,
this is a facility that's the size of
Rhode Island.
I mean,
it's massive.
There's so many wacky nuclear
experiments that they did between 1940
oh yeah.
Like when they stopped.
This is one of them is the most bizarre.
It's called operation starfish prime,
where they detonated a nuclear bomb in
the atmosphere.
They shot a nuclear bomb up into the Mag
Nino's fear just to kind of,
to see what it had happened.
Why would you do that?
They wanted to see what would happen.
I don't mean,
I don't know what their experiment,
I mean you would have to actually talk
to the original scientists because then
the fact that we know about it at all,
it's fucking insane,
right?
They did this,
but they,
they shot it like up into the van Allen
radiation belts and just launched a
fucking bomb up there.
I don't know to see if they could blow a
hole through it.
This was when they were doing manned
space missions too,
so they might have been trying to blow a
hole,
so to make it less radiation up there
when they're sending astronauts through
it like crazy and who the fuck knows,
but the fact that they didn't know what
was going to happen and they decided to
try it anyway,
just like,
okay,
we'll just shoot a fucking megaton bomb
up into the atmosphere.
The worst case scenario though is really
bad,
right?
Like really,
really,
really bad.
Yeah.
Like fucking a million people die of
cancer or something.
I mean,
who the hell knows?
What does this one asking?
Is that real picture?
It says that operation,
is starfish happened during operation or
would you say starfish?
Starfish prime.
It's called during operation.
Dominic and his picture pops up.
Well,
they,
it's probably real.
I mean they did so many of them.
The one of my favorite ones of all time
was one where they did it in the ocean
and they really didn't know what kind of
a reaction they would have inside the
ocean from a nuclear bottle.
I've seen that one.
They video footage of that.
Thank God.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Jamie.
See if you could see that detonated
nuclear bomb in the ocean to find that,
but it is.
It was beyond what they thought the
impact is going to be like.
They actually had bowel shipstation.
Right.
I saw them.
That'll ship wrecked me.
I don't know how many people died and
didn't know if there was even people on
those battleships.
I think they were telling me ships.
Right.
I thought that was hopefully,
hopefully,
because when it happened,
I mean,
what in the fuck?
I mean that water goes a mile high up
into the sky.
It's insane.
This is not the best video.
There's a way better video where there
is a bunch of ships around it and you
see the ships just get overwhelmed by
the water airs.
One of them look at that like there,
there is a perspective shot cause you
kind of get a sense,
I mean fuck man,
nuclear power is insane and nuclear
bombs are way more insane.
The idea that you're going to split
Adams and it's going to cause a reaction
that is just so almost inconceivably
powerful to the average person.
Like what could be when we have like
sort of a metric in our head about,
okay this is a firecracker,
right?
And then this is an mat.
It's here's,
here's the video.
Yeah this is the big one.
It's so fucking,
it's a mile into the air.
You know,
here is an mat,
here is a stick of dynamite.
Okay,
here's a nuclear bomb.
Like oh well it's just,
it's so,
it's so exponentially more powerful than
anything that we can kind of wrap our
brains around.
And this is also,
you know,
what was this,
what year was this shaming?
This happened.
1950 [inaudible] 58 imagine what they
have now.
Right.
I mean,
the 2016 version of that,
I mean there's just no more water.
Right?
The oceans gone,
you know,
the ocean becomes a Sahara desert.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I mean,
humans are bananas,
man.
We're a weird little animal.
And how long did you work out there at
this test facility that was out there
for about two and a half.
Close to three years.
Were you familiar at all with Robert
Lasar?
Yes.
What did you think about that?
Ah,
I had heard that he was a contractor and
it wasn't,
the story wasn't all that right.
Um,
I heard that the area he talks about s
three I heard that's true.
That is a real thing.
But I,
I don't know about his stories.
His whole thing was a folding space and
time and yeah,
I don't know about that.
Well,
he's a,
he's one of those guys that if you're a
dummy and you listened to him,
I mean you,
you go,
oh well he makes it,
he's making sense.
And he seemed so confident.
Like I listened to him,
I don't know what the fuck he saying
like he's talking about magnetic drives
cause I'm a dummy so I'm listening to
this,
this magnetic drive talk and talking
about these space ships and I'm like,
Oh my God,
this guy is telling the truth.
Right.
Because I don't know any better.
But if,
I'm sure if I was a real physicist and I
listened to him and be like up to this.
That's not how it works.
What you saw,
what?
What'd you say?
No,
that doesn't work like that.
You just have him on the show with yeah,
with exactly.
I don't even know if he gives it
interviews anymore.
I mean I haven't heard about the guy
forever.
Yeah,
he was a,
they were saying he was a contractor
working for,
was it dod or something like that or
I don't remember.
It was weird because he was never in any
of the official like catalogs of books
or anything like that.
So his story is a little bit,
I dunno,
we'll also,
one of the guys is a guy named Stanton
Freedman who's one of the premiere uff
ologists.
He's actually like a highly educated guy
that's very skeptical,
but most ufo claims was still believes
it's possible.
He did some research into the guy's
background and believes that he lied
about his education and lied about like
different places that he worked.
But I dunno,
you know,
it's,
it's not,
it's fun to,
to pay attention to,
but it's one of those things where
you're like,
man,
I'm not really going to get a resolution
here.
Right.
So it's just,
for me,
it's the once a year,
1130 at night youtube video fest,
right.
To sit back and I'm just like,
I watched like three hours of youtube
videos.
I'm like,
oh my God,
Ufos.
And then I go to bed and the next day
and then it happens again in a year.
So,
well I think for sure it's possible that
there's life out there in the universe
that is as intelligent as us.
But it's also possible that we're the
only one.
And the reason why I think it's possible
that we're the only ones,
there's hundreds of millions of life
forms on earth,
but we're the only one with an atoll
where the only one with iphones,
we're the only one that knows how to use
the Internet.
We're the only one out of these hundreds
of millions of life forms on this
goldilocks planet.
It would make,
oh,
you mean that up just our pos planet.
So you were saying out of all planets
were the only ones that use an iphone.
I was like,
well that kind of makes sense.
We kind of invented it,
but I mean out of this,
at this planet,
you know,
it's not like we go into the fucking
Congo and we find some strange species
that knows how to send emails to each
other.
You know,
we're the only one and then again,
dolphins,
they do weird shit with each other.
They can talk and whatnot.
We can only that you can't do most of
that stuff.
Well,
not only that,
we don't understand what they're saying,
which is kind of weird because we're
supposed to be top being here.
Are you familiar at all with John Lilly?
No.
John Lilly's the guy who created the
sensory deprivation tank.
Oh yes.
I've done that.
And he was also a pioneer of
interspecies communication.
He used to do acid and get in this,
uh,
so keep your deprivation tank next to a
dolphin tank and he tried to communicate
with the dolphins and his did that work?
Oh,
who the fuck man?
It sounds like it kind of could probably
kind of good.
I mean maybe at the moment while he was
tripping balls floating and hearing,
he probably kind of got a sense of what
they were saying.
I was in a tank once and I swore that it
was an experience that,
I mean the imagination is a very strange
thing.
You know?
Imagine imagination is very weird
because it's a lot of people,
when you think of the imagination,
you think of,
oh,
he's making things up in his mind that
aren't real.
That's like the standard way of looking
at the imagination and really like
pragmatic hard nose.
People would go,
ah,
all he's doing is sitting around all day
imagining things.
But imagination is responsible for that
clock,
this computer,
the coffee mugs,
how to you ceramics,
microphones.
Every fucking object on earth is all
created out of the imagination.
And I was in a sensory deprivation tank
and I had this experience where I was in
the jungle.
And not only was I listening to these
people speak this strange language but
are still understood.
You were not an Ios guy or anything?
No,
I was high as fuck.
I forget what it was on.
It was most likely edible po edible pod
is my drug of choice in sensory
deprivation tanks.
Cause I think um,
I think it'll pop first of all is one of
the most underrated psychedelic
compounds.
I just think people don't realize that
there is a profound difference between
thc and what happens when your liver
processes it,
which is 11 hydroxy metabolite,
which is four to five times more
psychoactive than thc.
Which is why a lot of people think when
they eat pot cookies that it was laced
and something was in there.
No,
no.
That is,
that's what happens when you eat
cannabis.
That's what's responsible for the vedic
texts.
A lot of the ancient Hindu uh,
documents like all of their,
um,
like a Yogi practices.
Like I was a lot of that was about
eating hash.
Really eating hash has been a tradition
amongst people for thousands and
thousands of years.
Eat the hash like this sticky hash that
yeah,
you can eat that for sure.
I didn't know that that you have to
smoke it because it's already been
broken down.
So it's,
well especially when you cook it,
you cook it in something fat soluble and
then you then,
and then you eat it.
Like that's how you get it.
Right.
And even in candy form,
I don't know exactly how they're making
it,
but you're eating it,
you know,
so it's whatever it is that allows your
body to process it.
But when you do that inside a sensory
deprivation tank,
like on a a pretty decent size dose,
you have some wild ass experience bad.
And one of mine was,
I was in the jungle and I was with these
people,
these,
these indigenous people and whatever,
wherever this jungle was.
And they were talking,
and not only did I understand what they
were saying,
but I was thinking in their language.
It was very brief.
And then I was,
and then I realized what I was doing
that I woke up,
but I could never bring myself back to
that state again.
But I remember that this experience,
which probably only lasted a couple
minutes at most,
was sensational.
It was very strange.
And I was trying to think like maybe
this is like some sort of like a deeply
tucked away genetic memory from back
when you know the great,
great,
great ancestors of whoever was,
you know,
if you have to think any person that's
alive today,
somehow or another,
your genes must be traced back to
ancient people.
Those,
there's only one way.
You didn't get come out of a fucking a
three d printer six weeks ago.
You are a product of hundreds of
millions of years of life.
Right?
So if that is the case,
some of that is probably tucked away
inside your jeans.
Interesting.
And there's this guy named trick.
Well,
I think it's possible that there are
little like you know how sometimes
someone will bring something up,
like a,
someone will say,
hey man,
you remember that guy who went to high
school with and then they go,
oh yeah.
And then all of a sudden you remember
Mike and then you remember Mike's Weird
car and you remember Mike's Girlfriend
who beat him up and had that person.
I've given you that cue.
It would have been gone forever.
I think it's like,
I think there are folders and one of the
reasons why I say this is because,
um,
I have,
I have a very obvious folders.
Like when I'm talking about certain
things,
like say if we're talking about um,
you know,
whatever psychedelic drugs or monkeys or
anything,
it's like my mind has like a bunch of
information that they can draw upon.
But if you bring up something that I
normally would be very knowledgeable
about,
like maybe mixed martial arts,
like start asking me about certain
fights are fighters.
I have to go,
oh yeah,
hold on.
But if I was commentating on a UFC and
it came up,
it would be there for me.
It'd be right there.
It's like that folder would be,
and I'd be able to access it.
So you just take it saying it takes a
little while for the folder to get open
sometimes.
Sometimes like that has to be your point
of focus.
I mean,
I don't understand memory entirely.
I don't necessarily understand how it
works and how it varies so much.
Like there's sometimes where like what
does that fucking word?
What's that fucking word?
And then it comes out and go,
yeah,
how could I forget that?
Worried.
That happens all the time and it's,
it's worse as you get older too.
What is,
what's happened to me my whole life?
I don't think it's gotten any better or
worse.
It's,
it's always been that thing like what's
that fucking word?
And then someone will say it and he's
like,
yes.
Right,
but what is that like?
Why is memory variable?
Like,
why has it come and why is it go and why
is it enhanced by certain compounds like
per acetone and things along those
lines.
Coleen,
there's like certain different things
that will enhance your,
your ability to memorize things or
remember things,
recall things.
But I think that it's got to be possible
that somewhere deep,
deep down in our DNA or genome or
something.
There's some memories like,
and I think those,
a lot of those memories are instincts
like,
um,
rupert sheldrake,
who's a guy who's been on this podcast
before,
he's a,
he like evolutionary biologist or
something like that.
One of his,
um,
theories was about why children who live
in cities or afraid of monsters and he
thinks that there is a deep seated
genetic memory of us being preyed upon
by cats,
by Jaguars and leopards and things along
those lines.
You know,
back when we were,
you know,
less evolved hominids and that we're
living in the trees and that these cats
are jack and us and they do it at night.
And that's why we're terrified of the
night and the darkness and monsters,
you know,
we think kids,
they live in their cities.
They should be scared about bullets and
crime and car accidents and train
derailments and things that are really
probably will be in several thousand
years once we'd like.
Right.
That's becomes a part of the genome,
right?
Yeah.
Who knows,
man.
I mean,
but I,
I,
I found that experience being in the
tank.
It was so real.
That was what was bizarre and it easily
could be marijuana plus imagination plus
sensory deprivation creates this.
Really,
I mean,
that's a good comment.
That's amazing.
Strong.
It's amazing.
What do you think about Iowaska and all
these other,
it seems like that's the hot thing
everyone's doing these days.
Well,
it's time.
Ethel.
Tryptamine right.
I mean,
that's what I would ask is if chemo
smoke that on their own.
Yeah,
I've swiped it.
Oh,
you have?
Yeah.
I've never done Iowasca because I've
never found anybody that's willing to
get it to me without going to the
jungle.
Ah,
you got to do the ceremony.
But the DMT experiencing itself is
unbelievably intense.
And just dmt itself is,
it's,
it's a more powerful version of Iowasca
like Iowasca from what it's been
explained to me,
for everyone who's done it is longer and
oftentimes more introspective and it can
be more profound even because it lasts
longer and you have more time to sort of
take in the experience.
But as far as the intensity of the
experience,
it's not as intense as when you smoke
dmt Andrew's day and smoking dmt is not
as,
it's not as powerful as when it's
injected intravenously.
And that's how they did it with Doctor
Rick strassman under the University of
New Mexico did a series of tests,
clinical trials on plank,
and he documented it in a book called
Dmt,
the spirit molecule.
I've heard about that.
Isn't there a documentary on that as
well?
Yeah,
I narrated it.
Oh,
you tell the host of it.
Yeah.
Oh,
that's awesome.
Yeah,
that's a,
it's a really interesting documentary
because it deals with a lot of
scientists and their experience with a,
with dimethyltryptamine and trying to
understand like what this compound is
and why it exists,
but the trips that people had when they
took it intravenously,
we're like half hour long just journeys
into insanity into this like bad
insanity.
No,
no,
no.
All of them,
I believe afterwards said that it
profoundly enhanced their life and their
perspective and gave them a view of
reality that forever change the way they
look at things about interactions,
life and,
and I,
I could say that about myself,
like my experiences with dmt have
definitely profoundly changed the way I
view possibility because it's so
impossibly dynamic and insane and it
just doesn't seem like anything that you
could have ever imagined.
And what I Wasa is,
is an orally active version of DMT
because DMT is insanely common.
It is.
It's in thousands of different plants.
It's in all sorts of different
ecosystems all over the world have
plants that have DMT,
including a lot of grasses,
like full Eris grasses,
which is really common.
It's rich and tmt.
Hmm.
But you can't extract it.
Well,
you can't extract it for sure.
Absolutely.
Like you have to just know what you're
doing.
If you're a chemist,
it's actually not that difficult.
It's a reason why DMT,
if you know people who know how to get
DMT,
the actual raw plants that's have dmt,
you can't make illegal because there's
too many of them.
Interesting.
It's like you would have to make like,
it's one of the,
um,
there's some scholars out of Jerusalem
that believe that this is the literal
interpretation of what Moses was
experiencing when experiencing,
when experiencing the burning Bush and
talking to God.
They believe that burning Bush is the
acacia tree because the Acacia tree is
very rich and dmt and extremely common
in that part of the world.
So it was Moses smoking most likely,
like if you smoke the Acacia tree,
do you get the DMT?
I'm sure.
I'm sure if you light those trees on
fire,
you're going to absorb a certain
quantity of DMT.
It wouldn't be as pure as like
extracting it in a lab,
breaking it down to the Rod dmt
crystals.
Then freebasing it,
which is what you do.
That's probably way more intense,
but it's entirely likely that there is a
method of doing it because the method
that they found in the Amazon,
it's extremely convoluted.
Like what they did was when you,
when you eat,
if you eat a plant right that has dmt in
it,
your body produces something called Mano
Amy and oxidase that breaks down the
dime.
Ethel tryptamine in the,
in the plant and you won't,
you won't experience it like eating
we'd,
it does nothing unless it's been already
pre broken down,
but even more different because we'd has
to be like cooked in something in order
to activate it.
But if you just eat it straight up,
just like the plant itself,
you won't feel anything.
I don't think so.
You don't,
you're supposed to really good for you
though.
If you eat like juicing,
juicing it like it's supposed to be like
really rich in phytonutrients and it's
supposed to be really rich and CBDS too,
which don't necessarily get you high,
but a really good for you and good for
inflammation.
She was seeing it.
Yeah,
it's a big thing,
man.
People juice it.
It's really,
really super common.
Like wheat grass juice.
But they do it with cannabis.
They take the leaves and they throw it
and choose her.
You get those at like the dispensaries
here?
Um,
no,
but I've seen it online.
I've never actually seen it in person,
but I definitely have seen it online.
So what these people have done when they
created Iowasca and they've been doing
this for,
no one knows how long,
but they believe it's been thousands and
thousands of years.
It's really hard to try to figure out
how long they've been doing it.
But they take the leaf of one plant
which contains harming,
which is a natural Mao inhibitor and
they take the roots or the vine of
another plant,
which has the dimethyltryptamine in it
and they boil it.
So sort of a that process.
So they figured out how to make their
own pharmacological solution to love
absorbing dmt orally,
which is crazy.
Well they say the plants told them how
to do it.
Of course they said that.
I don't know if that's wrong.
I mean,
I just think our,
our view of what
a plant is,
it's like,
Whoa,
I talked to my firm,
it never says anything.
He got a plant that's in a fucking
plastic cup.
I think it's probably analogous to the
difference between that little tiny pig
that's like a little baby pig and a
fucking wild paid who's out there
hustling,
making shit happen.
You know,
there's a picture I met money put up on
my instagram a few days ago of a wild
boar running off of the fon and its
mouth.
And you know,
and it's,
it's a very shocking picture because we
don't think of pigs as being predators.
Right.
But there are opportunities and they
absolutely will prey on something if
they can catch it.
But that image is like as far removed on
the spectrum from that little pig,
that little tiny pig that's got a guitar
on his lap,
you know,
like look at this thing.
Wow.
That bore and that is a,
that that picks that playing guitar.
Yeah.
And that's America.
That's a bore in America running off of
the deer farm.
And it's its,
uh,
its mouth that the spores are big,
they're fucking huge.
They get enormous,
they get enormous.
And you know,
there's ones that,
uh,
they've,
they've caught them or kill them that
are,
you know,
pushing a thousand pounds out there in
the wild.
But I think that,
that,
that is a wild animal,
you know,
and I think these wild plants that it
living in the jungle that are alive in
the rain forest and had been there for
thousands of years and this deep canopy
of moisture and nutrients and plants and
bugs and mammals and cats and all these
different things.
And then you got these people who live
like the,
the Toumani,
they're walking barefoot through these
fucking woods and Bolivia and throwing
fucking spears at monkeys and shit and
cooking them over the fire.
Like these people have been living like
this for thousands of years.
They're eating cocoa leaves and tripping
their balls off monthly fun cookies.
Yeah.
It's supposed to be pretty awesome.
You've never tried it before?
I've had the t yeah,
I've had the coca demato tea,
which I thought was pretty interesting.
I couldn't shut the fuck up.
I didn't like that aspect of it.
The leaves are legal.
You can buy the leaves.
Can you,
you can.
I saw him on a Amazon actually.
Yeah,
they was fucking dea hustle.
Well you need the,
um,
they had the compound to go with it.
It's a little bit of that uh,
lime or these baking soda.
Baking soda.
Yeah.
And then you just chew it and basically
it's like having a cup of coffee.
Well it's supposed to be better for you.
And it also has,
it's actually like a healthy plant.
The phytonutrients,
the,
the vitamins from the actual leaves of
the plant itself actually.
Good for you.
Yeah.
It was actually chewing some with a
doctor friend of mine and he's like,
yeah,
it's great.
I don't,
so you could just order it.
Yeah,
you can just order it and you just start
ordering a Jeremy,
I'm going to do a podcast with a big
fucking baseball sized cha.
That's exactly what you did.
Put like a little wad in your mouth that
it's a like,
you know,
the conversation started.
I think it's entirely possible that
these people that are eating plants that
have psychedelic properties to them,
whether it's mushrooms and you know
there's a lot of mushrooms that you can
eat that and also in the same areas with
a lot of
silicide been.
So they're,
they're chewing these siliciden
mushrooms and they have these ideas of
iconic combined these things.
You're talking about hundreds of
different species of plants and these
fucking guys have figured out how to
take these two and combine them in some
really crazy involved way where you
boiling it and how,
what's the explanation?
There's no explanation that makes any
sense other than the plants gave them
the hints.
Yeah,
I think that I've always believed,
and I've my,
my wife's a neuroscientist,
so we talk about this stuff a lot in
debate it,
but I've always believed that,
you know,
we know about the senses that we've
documented and I think that there's
certain things that we can take the
activate other senses that we didn't
know were there and allow us to do
certain things.
Like for example,
talk to plants or whatever it may be.
It's not going to be the,
you know,
I'm having a conversation and it's
talking back to me.
But it could be a feeling or a vibe or
they know some way of anything else
there.
You know,
we'll do you know,
when scientists first found harming and
a,
I want to say this was in the early 19
hundreds,
I forgot what you,
what year it was,
but when they first found harming,
they wanted to call it telepathy mean
the,
I think it was psychiatry is Veritas.
I think that was the plan that they
found it in.
I forget what the plant,
they found that it was,
but the,
um,
the compound,
whatever it was,
had allowed these people,
these scientists to feel like they were
experiencing some sort of communal
thoughts and so they wanted to call it
telepathy,
but because of the fact that once they
had isolated the compound figured out
what it was,
they realized that had already been
named harming,
you know,
due to the,
the rules of scientific nomenclature and
they decided to just keep that name,
but their name for it was going to be
telepathy.
Raisie yeah,
you want to hear it?
This is a somewhat related topic,
but I,
I have,
um,
someone that I met that has a startup
that catalogs people's dreams,
so they,
they fill out like a little small
questionnaire after they have a dream
and something that they've discovered.
I don't know that they've published this
or come out with any data,
released it publicly,
but people are dreaming the same thing
on the same night.
It's,
it's,
it's a thing.
And so like in like masses of people are
having the same dream.
So what kind of dream?
I don't know.
I,
this is like over a beer that we had
this conversation at a,
at a party.
So I need to get back to them and say
let's get this data out there.
I'm curious as to what it is.
Shit.
Yeah,
that's wild.
Like,
um,
so how many people they're studying?
Um,
it's not as official study.
It's just like an app for people that
like to catalog and keep track of their
dreams.
So he's looking at it in aggregate and
finding these patterns.
So they recorded at nightly like,
yeah,
like you wake up in the morning and then
like you write down,
I dropped about sharks eating dolphins
or whatever it is,
and then they're seeing patterns and
large groups.
It's really trippy,
imaginative dreams or like a gigantic
Sydney Opolis.
And you could pick which movie you go
into and there's a bunch of other people
in the movie with you watching the same
thing.
It's a really weird,
but also like movies,
some thinking.
It's beautiful.
Others thinking it's shit.
Right.
You know,
incredibly subjective.
It's really a truck man.
Crazy.
That is God damn crazy.
If that turns out to be something today,
discover and that starts getting
expanded upon and people start really
bringing this up on a regular basis,
we find out that that's,
that's real hard data.
That's going to be amazing.
What a game changer that would be.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Have you ever taken things before you go
to bed to enhance dreams?
I know,
no.
I'm gonna give you something before you
leave.
Yeah.
Have you ever tried Alpha brain?
No.
Alpha brain is a nootropic and then
there's this company on it.
My company produces coal.
We have double blind placebo controlled
studies showing that from the Boston
center memory sewing that enhances
memory,
enhances executive function,
enhances,
um,
reaction time.
Wow.
Also that your body,
it puts your body in an Alpha state.
It puts your mind in Alpha state.
But one of the big things from it is if
you take it before you go to bed,
it gives you lucid dreams,
like really vivid dreams.
And the way I describe it as an,
I try not to take it sometimes before I
go to bed,
just cause I don't want to wake up in
the middle of night,
freaked out,
have to pay then can't go back to bed.
I like,
my sleep is precious to me.
Like I need at least six hours to be
functional.
Oh,
I'm the same way.
And if I don't get it,
I just,
I preserve that sleep.
I guarded.
Are you tracking it with like a fitbit
or something?
You No.
And just sleep.
But um,
I sleep well but I'm really like
diligent about it so I don't,
I don't fuck,
I don't go online late at night and
freak myself out if I know I have to go
to bed and I'm not going to like watch
animal attacks or some fucking cops
shooting some kid and just tripping out,
you know what I mean?
Oh absolutely.
Yeah.
There has to be a two hour window for me
every night.
I try to not do electronics and get flux
too,
which I'm sure you already have.
What does flux?
It's a for your laptop.
It shuts off all the blue light.
You know what I'm talking about?
Oh,
oh,
so also apple,
just a introduce this in the latest
version of Ios you can turn on and takes
out of the blue light out flux does it
for the laptop.
Oh.
And so at sunset this,
the screen starts to remove all the blue
light and it just,
they're,
they're saying it helps you sleep
better.
And I found that was the case.
Yeah.
There was this,
um,
this,
uh,
this futurist convention in New York
City,
a few back a few years back,
2042,
they think that a,
in 2042,
you know,
that's the going to be the year that
artificial intelligence takes off.
And there was all these Weirdos that
were creating these robots so they could
talk to and thinking they're going to
download their consciousness and
computers.
Well,
there's a bunch of guys who had these
screens over their phones because they
were convinced that the artificial light
that's emanating from phones is damaging
your brain and damaging sleep patterns
and giving you an artificial light
source,
especially right before you go to bed.
Could potentially disrupt your sleep.
Yeah.
That's,
that's the whole theory behind all of
this stuff.
Yeah.
My wife was wearing these wacky glasses
for a while,
like,
uh,
like you remember the Baas Brian
Bosworth,
remember those fucking goes,
those blades that would cover your whole
face is this shoot led light and you're
just like,
uh,
like it's like a orange.
It's like,
and that it was,
the idea was that was,
it would filter light.
So the blockers,
yes.
In a way.
Yeah.
But it was designed specifically to calm
the,
uh,
the interaction of your,
your eyeballs with like,
yeah.
Amazing.
We're looking at a photo of Brian
Bosworth who was a famous football guy
from the 1980s,
I guess with these ridiculous glasses
that no one wants anyone to hearing to.
Yeah.
Let's terminator glasses.
Those were the things right after the
terminator.
But these,
um,
goggles,
these things that people wear,
they wear them and they think that
somehow or another like filtering the
light will enhance your sleep and,
hmm.
Is there science behind all that?
Like the flux thing or is she doesn't
know.
There was,
I didn't look into the science.
Um,
but if apple's adding it,
there must be something they wouldn't
just do that for funsies.
Yeah.
I assume data behind it.
Do you use all apple products?
For the most part,
I have an android phone as well,
just to kind of mess around with stuff
to stay current.
But um,
yeah,
almost all apple.
Yeah.
I have an android phone to,
um,
I think the galaxy phones or they're
probably pretty commensurate.
I mean,
I,
I'm,
when I go back and forth,
I mean it's,
one of them is to get used to it and the
way it communicates with laptops and
other apple people and the ability to
airdrop stuff.
There's like some definitely benefits.
Sure.
But there's also some benefits of the
android platform to,
you know,
I liked the,
uh,
all the new Amazon prime stuff.
Like they're the new TV.
It's great.
Yeah,
it's got all the streaming.
It's,
it's better Ui,
I think the new apple stuff.
Yeah.
I mean Amazon,
I wish that it would catch up and become
like a real competitor to Netflix.
I think it's,
they're kind of closing in there,
creating their own content now and
they're trying,
they're trying to,
uh,
to really become like there are some
options to where you can download the
movie,
the movies to your device,
which you can't really do with Netflix.
So if you're on a plane or something
like that,
flying over the ocean,
you're kind of fucked if you want to
watch netflix.
Um,
but there's,
there's also some stuff that I think,
um,
you can,
you can definitely,
you can definitely make the argument
that it's probably a good idea to
support emerging pot or other platforms
as well.
Like there's,
it's not a good thing for everybody to
be on apple.
Right.
You know,
I think the more android's come up with
more sophisticated devices and more
interesting options and features and
applications more,
it's going to force apple to raise their
bar as well.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And I think that a lot of the Amazon
stuff like the echo,
like those devices in your home,
you can speak to those
are,
those are a lot of fun.
I'm actually finding it pretty useful.
Yeah.
What do you use it for you that you're
seeing there in the kitchen?
You're like,
I ran out of trash bags and you just
say,
you know,
order me new trash bags and then it
looks into your previous purchases.
It knows that you've bought those bags
before.
It knows your home address and as your
credit card.
And I just thought I'd make this ends it
out.
And do you have to press a button to
Santo,
but just say it now.
You just,
you just query the device and just say,
order me trash bags.
That's it.
So you have to talk to the device and
say,
Hey Alexa.
And it's like people get mad when I say
hey theory on the podcast,
because then their phone starts going
off.
Turn that shit off folks,
that,
that series stupid.
She doesn't know what the difference
between a podcast in your own voices.
It's not ready yet.
She's not the vest.
She's not ready.
Is there a Google version of Siri?
There?
It is,
right?
Yeah.
What's it called?
A okay.
Google.
Oh,
and that's what you say it's same thing.
Yeah.
Google now.
So they call ejc.
Okay Google.
And then it just,
the Google one's actually quite good.
I've been wanting to fuck around with a
windows laptop for awhile.
I can't bring myself to do it.
And they got the new tablet and I use it
for about a week and I send it back.
Well,
what's funny is you get it and you're so
excited and you're like,
oh,
it looks cool.
Like you know they've sold me because
they come up with these like fun little
videos and stuff and,
and then you realize you're like,
fuck,
I'm in windows in your backend.
Like it'll reappear.
Like you'll go,
it'll look like this beautiful interface
and you're like,
oh cool apps and all this and whatnot.
And then you go into settings and it's
like,
there's like a 10,000
options and it,
it defaults back to that old windows
feel.
I don't know if they fixed that with the
latest version,
but I mean that was my problem with it.
I just,
I realized this is just windows again
and it,
was this a tablet?
It was a tablet.
Can you still go into dos?
Yeah.
I think he can still go and still in
command prompts.
Yeah.
Which I kind of liked.
That brings back the old school.
It's just um,
there's some new laptops.
Like Lenovo has some,
a new thinkpads.
They are pretty interesting.
Really good keyboards.
And what about the chromebook?
Have you played around with that?
No,
haven't,
those are pretty cool.
Well,
I had a friend who worked for Google and
she had one of those and I was like,
okay,
where do you store things on this?
We can't,
it's all in the cloud.
What?
You can't the fuck out of here?
Like you can't,
you don't have anything on your laptop,
fuck off.
No,
I'm kind of like that now with the
apple.
Yeah.
Why not?
Because then you can smash it.
You can lose it,
whatever.
Who Cares?
You just get a new one and you're back
up and running in like 10 minutes.
Do you,
but do you have any of your writing that
you don't want people to access that's
up there in the cloud?
You just use two factor auth and all
that stuff?
What is that?
That's where it has to send you a text
with a code in order for you to log in
with a new device so that way,
even if they know your password,
they can't get into your stuff.
That makes sense.
Yeah.
So I have that turned on for everything
and then yeah,
everything's in the cloud.
All photos,
all videos,
all documents,
everything.
You're a man with no porn.
No,
no,
no.
Dick pics are floating around.
Spike.
You feel real confident.
You're like,
yeah,
it's in the cloud.
Go ahead and look at pictures of my dog.
Who gives a shit I saw.
Yeah,
there was a sticker I want to get.
Is it like the cloud is really just
someone else's computer,
which is very true.
It is it just someone else's computer?
No clouds up in the sky.
You fucks like why are you calling it
the cloud when it's on the ground?
That's so stupid.
It's just someone's computer.
It's a weird name.
Like why?
Why say the cloud?
I don't understand why you would say the
crises.
Cyberspace.
Yeah.
I guess we don't really use cyberspace
anymore.
That really wasn't that brought up.
But the cloud is,
is weird,
but what would be a good replacement for
what the clipboard,
the cloud,
uh,
expression.
I Dunno.
I kinda like it.
It's kind of stuck.
It makes me think of this like,
well,
the thing about the cloud easy,
it's redundant.
Like you can never lose.
Your data is distributed.
So clouds are everywhere.
So in theory,
so as your data,
which is concerning slash awesome.
Hmm.
Yeah.
But if she,
I just am always in this position where
I say,
well,
what if,
um,
I can't get online and I want to have
access to my stuff.
Most of it is low,
locally cached,
right?
So if you have a,
you know,
icloud on your desktop or dropbox or
anything else,
even if you're an airplane mode,
it's still gonna be there.
You just double click to open it.
You're good to go.
It syncs the changes later.
Um,
you know,
what you're doing it for is really just
a fancy backup.
You know,
in case he ever lose the device,
everything's there.
The fancy backup is a great idea.
But what would it actually disturbs me
is the idea that we're going to get to a
point where you don't have any hard
drive space and so you're not storing
anything.
You're just accessing things that are
somewhere else and you're paying for
that service.
I pay apple probably $150 a year for my
cloud storage and it backs up all of my
devices to have cloud.
Do you do the apple music thing when you
pay the eight bucks a month?
I did play with it.
I thought the interface kind of socks.
Itunes is so bloated right now.
What is cool though is Siri could call
up songs and you just have on your phone
like,
Hey Siri,
play Michael Jackson and it'll say what
song and then you say thriller bitch.
Amazon does that too.
The echo does that.
Yeah.
You can just tell it to play anything
and if you have Amazon prime,
you get access to all their free prime
music and then it just plays it.
They're all doing it now and spotify.
Everybody's doing it.
Yeah.
I feel like I want to fuck around with
other platforms just because I'm just
been such an apple dork.
But then part of me goes,
but that's just cause you're a
procrastinator and you don't want to
work.
You want to start playing with some,
oh I'm but I'll get to work.
Once I figured out how to run this new
lamp option and figured out how to
format my hard drive now how do I de
Frag on this windows device,
what we all do it and then you always
come back to apple.
At least that's my,
I've been in my experience cause you're
just like,
ah,
there's some little things that it
doesn't do right the way you're used to.
And then he'd go back to also apple
keeps getting better.
The devices keep getting better.
They just get it better and better and
better.
And like this one then I have,
here is no his flash drive,
which I'm fucking addicted to.
So it powers on like that accesses data
like that.
I'm just so addicted to that because I
remember the spinning spinning of the
hard drive.
Right.
And if you dropped it the hard drive
break.
Yeah.
These things are bulletproof.
They are,
yeah.
Is that one?
That one's not retina display.
That is,
it is,
yeah.
That is,
no,
it's,
Oh that's a Mac book pro.
Yeah.
Okay.
That's,
yeah.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Rather displays a big difference.
Pretty Slick.
Especially when I had my glasses on.
Yeah.
On a reading.
Like when I don't have my glasses on,
what's the point?
It doesn't matter at that point.
Barely can read text.
I mean I could,
I could kind of like this is in front of
us.
We were looking at it like normal size
type like that.
Right.
Like I have to kind of like opened my
eyes up wide and I can read it but it
um,
it's not good.
I just bought it.
It's hilarious cause I bought a book on
how to correct your eyesight and how to,
is that a real thing?
Yes.
There's bates method,
the base of bates method of improving
your visions to dates method.
Yeah.
It's not like exercises for your eyes.
Katy Bowman,
Katy Katy Bowman,
Katy Bowman who was on the podcast is
kind of an expert and physical movement
and she's got a lot of interesting ideas
about biology and one of her thoughts
about,
about glasses and about,
uh,
when you spend a lot of time looking at
computers,
looking at a screen,
she was like,
you're looking at something that's a
very fixed distance,
which is unusual and the is not really
designed to focus constantly on a fixed
distance for eight hours a day.
Your body's supposed to look at things
that are over there,
things that are up here,
things that are everywhere.
And in that way your body gets this
broad range of things that you're
viewing all of these different
distances.
And when you look at something that's in
a fixed distance,
she likens it to being in a cast like a
year and a cast your,
your muscles atrophy.
Ah,
I hate that technology slowly killing
us.
I love it and hate it.
I think it is.
Absolutely.
You know,
I found myself,
uh,
w first Sandona wake up in the morning
is like going to my phone and I stopped
doing that.
But it's just,
it's taking over,
you know,
like look,
just look around you like take one day
and when you're,
I walked to work in New York and I put
my phone in my pocket and I just walk
around and observe other people.
Everyone is heads down in their phone.
Oh yeah.
Like if we were like visiting as this
planet,
it just observing this species called
human,
like you would say,
oh,
they're being controlled by this little
thing that's telling them what to do.
It looks like we're being controlled.
Well,
what's interesting is people say back in
the day people didn't do that,
but there's a photograph of the subway
from like 1960 or something like that.
The reading papers,
all of them,
every fucking person is in their reading
a newspaper.
I think Peter,
at least it was one tab,
you know,
he was like,
it's like one page,
like these people.
Right.
But like they're not,
there's no tab browsing there but not
jumping around reading the paper.
All of them,
man.
They're not looking at each other.
That's fair.
This,
this idea that we used to be amazing and
we used to be gregarious and want to
turn off tad browsing.
It's,
it's,
that's what's killing me.
Tabbed browsing on your phone just on,
on your desktop computer.
And I always say while leave that tab
open,
cause I'm definitely gonna need to get
the APP tabs that have been open for
months.
How about this?
Have you ever gone back to your email
tab and like there's an email that
you're supposed to hit send all yeah,
like eight hours ago you're like,
oh fuck yeah.
Yeah.
Well you know it's definitely not
perfect but I'm,
I dunno,
I'm a big fan of technology.
I just,
I'm also a fan of self discipline.
I think you need,
you need your own sort of boundaries
that you won't cross.
Right.
Like,
you know,
x amount of time per day,
or six o'clock at night,
I put everything away.
We're done.
That's it.
If you need to get ahold of me,
call me.
You know,
nobody fucking calls me on my phone.
I shouldn't even have a home phone.
It's fucking useless.
Never answered that God damn thing.
Yeah.
Somebody calls me exactly,
exactly.
Why don't I have it?
I was a little bit one.
One was a fire on the right.
You just need to get ahold of you.
In fact,
the neighborhood.
Um,
but there's levels.
Like if someone,
like I'll check my phone in the morning
and I'll see text messages and I'll see
if anything's important.
If someone I care about sends me a text
message,
then something might be important.
That's level one.
Level two is I'll check my email.
That's like next level.
Then level three is like,
I started going into social media,
instagram,
facebook and twitter and you know,
that's,
and then there's level four.
I started googling shit and checking out
forums and reading information about
stuff.
But that's then,
then you're going deeper and deeper into
it.
Then you're looking to be distracted,
you know,
I'll go to dig,
like get that for real man.
That's like one of my main sources have
been for years.
My main sources of wacky shit going on
in the world.
It's still got a lot of wacky shit on
there.
You are you involved in it at all
anymore?
I mean technically I'm kind of an
advisor to the company and now that I'm
out in New York,
I,
they're based out there.
So I spend,
I see the team from time to time.
Uh,
but he was just,
man,
it was so many years of blood,
sweat and tears that I kind of got burnt
out.
I was like,
I can't look at any more cat videos,
check out the window.
It's just a great resource for someone
who's just curious.
Yeah.
Let's see what's interesting out there.
Ha ha ha.
Oh,
okay.
You know,
I'll look at it every day and I'll find
at least one thing everyday that a half
to read like holy shit and I have to
click on it.
But it's interesting because I'll send
someone a dig link and there's a desire
that people have a completely unfounded
desire to be over something.
You know,
like my space,
my space is a good example.
If you sent someone,
hey man,
I want you to check out my thing.
It's on my space.
I've always wanted to bring back my
space or I want to get an AOL.
If I was in charge of AOL I would make
their emails so bad ass that no one
could deny it.
Like just go,
just go crazy.
Do all the encryption shit that people
are talking about.
Do like unlimited space.
Just like make it the most amazing bad
ass email platforms.
So it's like the cool thing again.
So it's like g male plus like taking
everything from like email.
Email's probably the best three email
platform.
Right?
How much better is it than Yahoo?
Uh,
I mean Yahoo has ads in there.
Stuff like visible big ass ads.
Those fucks.
I know.
What about hotmail?
It's still around.
How mill still around hot mill would be
another one.
You could probably turn into something
pretty bad ass.
Yeah.
We'll get all the Microsoft prep out.
Other though they own hotmail,
right?
Yeah.
Mm.
They make you sign on with a Microsoft
account and all that weird stuff like
prefers windows.
Is there anyone that likes us?
They try apple and they try windows and
they go those windows things better.
There's a lot of people out there,
hardcore windows fans,
but are they really windows fan?
Massive country,
right?
Gamers.
The gamers still love windows.
You can't run oculus on a Mac yet.
Well it's also,
some people love all those options too.
They'd love Oculus rift on a map down.
Oh No,
not yet.
That's a game chiller.
Yeah.
Change the game changer.
The video cards aren't good enough.
They're saying whoa.
Really interesting.
Yeah.
Hmm.
Well,
when you play video games on a Mac,
do they have native versions of a,
what?
Do you have to switch over?
Do you know?
Like there's that,
what does that,
um,
application that you can switch back and
forth between windows and Mac?
Yeah.
They had like the boot camp,
they called it where you could boot into
the,
that's still around.
Yeah.
The good news is that it's,
it's all a intel hardware so you can
boot into windows if you want to,
but it's still like the,
the graphics cards are a few generations
behind.
That's a weird,
yeah.
It's just like apple doesn't care.
They don't have really anyone doing
super high end gaming on their rigs,
so they don't,
that's not their,
their game anymore.
Well you remember when Steve Jobs came
back and they killed the clones?
Yeah.
That's when it was kind of weird because
before then,
like you could buy a Mac online.
That was way more powerful than anything
out.
Apple was selling way more hard drive
space.
Sli video cards.
They do an sli video.
He's already done us a lie now that was,
this was before then they had souped up
like,
uh,
processors though and like much more
power.
Much more storage space.
And then,
you know,
apple,
it's like,
fuck you.
Yeah,
but you can't,
you still can't run Mac os on a PC.
It's,
it has,
it has to have this,
it's own rom like a special apple.
Right.
But I know people who've done it.
There's hacks around it,
but it never works,
doesn't it?
Never.
Percent,
uh,
people are going to go crazy anytime
there's like a software update,
they just like patch it so you're not
always running the latest.
Uh,
he was always a war like that.
It's,
it's,
it's really interesting.
It's really,
really interesting the,
the dual platform thing because it kind
of becomes a tribe thing.
You know,
like people get addicted to rooting for
one particular sprites team.
You know,
like I've been with the cubs since the
beginning getting on know we went to
clubs to the end.
Yeah.
You know,
go cubs.
They get that way with windows.
They can take it the way the websites
and everything.
Like you were saying with my space and
all those others,
the same thing with dig.
People were like pissed off at dig for a
while.
It changed.
It's a look.
Yeah.
And when it changes its look,
I got all these people are fucked,
dude.
What are they doing?
I'm like,
well when you're just looking to say
fuck you,
that's what you're looking to do.
It's like you look in to be over
something.
It's not like this is not a rational
disagreement or a grievance you have.
Yeah,
there was a lot of,
I mean there's a couple things.
One,
it's,
we've,
one thing we learned is that people,
uh,
they love when they get into something
and really into it,
they're hesitant to change.
Like anything that you change,
you move an icon or change a color or do
any of that stuff.
I think it's part of the reason probably
why read it hasn't made a whole lot of
big over arching changes to their
product.
It kind of feels the same.
It looks the same functions the same is
because people fell in love with that,
you know?
And it's a hard thing to do.
You make any changes there and you have
a revolt on your hands,
you know?
So for us it was difficult because we
had taken a lot of investor funding and
they wanted us to go very mainstream.
You know,
there was like,
there was always like,
well,
how can we get your mom reading,
dig or whatever it may be.
And I think that,
you know,
in retrospect,
that was the,
that was the wrong approach apps because
we were,
we should have been a loyal to our core
audience and kind of been all about
that,
which the site is today.
It's a lot more like it was back then.
I mean the,
granted the design has changed,
but um,
I think the content is more like that.
And the mistake that we made is we tried
to push into more kind of mainstream
news when really what date may dig so
special is that was able to unearth and
find the really kind of unique,
obscure random stuff from around the
web.
Right.
So that was a,
but it was a crazy ride.
I mean we were,
gosh,
it was probably seven or so years that,
um,
we were kind of riding that wave,
you know,
and like all Internet properties,
it's like if you can last five years,
it's amazing.
If you can last seven,
that's unbelievable.
And if you can last 10 that's like
almost unheard of.
I go to it every day.
So to me nothing's changed.
That's how I,
that popularity,
there's hasn't dropped off at all.
I met,
I met with the,
uh,
the John Borthwick,
a heads up Beta works and he was saying
it's something like a total of 42
million across all platform a month.
Dig still receives.
That's across mobile and desktop and
everything else that they do.
That's still a man,
which is crazy.
It's a lot of fucking people,
man.
It's nuts.
It's just an,
I love when someone can just collect
things for you.
There's some aggregates.
All those interesting,
weird,
bizarre shit.
It's a one stop shop.
This is kind of always going to be in
market for that.
That's kind of my,
what I'm doing now with my newsletter.
I don't know if you saw that.
I launched a new newsletter.
Yeah,
launch a newsletter here just a few
weeks ago and I only put it out once a
month.
Like I hate,
I hate that.
You know,
when I was in television on techtv and
some of the other stuff that we did,
it was always about producing new
content every single day.
And you can never really put the best
stuff out there.
You're always in a rush to produce your
segment.
You're like,
okay,
what am I going to do today?
Blah,
blah,
blah.
And,
and so I create a newsletter that is
basically just,
um,
my favorite stories,
videos,
products,
but things that are fully vetted that
has spent a lot of time collecting.
And I just,
I released it once a month on the first
of every month.
Oh,
that's great.
The fully vetted things great.
Because God,
there's so many,
well first of all,
how many stories do you get that are
completely contradicting something that
was a story just a week ago.
Exactly.
And you're like,
well,
who the fuck is right?
Well now you've got to make me do
research right now.
I got to snopes this and figure this out
and try to figure out who's team Amman
and which articles seems most rational.
And if then,
if you can't do that,
then you have to go into scientific
papers and I'll fucking Christ.
Then you have to contact people and
search forums and see what the people
that are actually studying this shit
think.
And it's nice if someone vents it out in
advance.
Yeah.
So if I,
if I put a product on there,
it has to be something that like a
technology product that I've used for at
least a month.
So I can tell you,
you know,
there's a lot of that kind of like I get
hyped up on something for a few days and
it actually ends up sucking and you've
already plugged it in your life to give
me an example of that.
Like what?
I don't know it just like any new
product that comes out,
like,
um,
when the echo first came out,
the Amazon Echo,
it's like I,
I think it got better with a few
software updates.
So I'm glad I didn't plug it initially
cause I kinda thought it sucked but it,
but it's a lot better now,
but it took some time to get there.
Um,
I just want to make sure that if I'm,
I feel like our time is really precious,
all of our time is really precious and
if you push someone to go read something
or to buy something,
it should be worth their time.
And,
and so I want to put a lot of effort
into that,
so,
well,
that's a great way to approach it for
sure.
And if someone's going to really get
committed to paying attention to you on
a regular basis,
on a monthly basis,
it's probably the best way to do it.
Yeah,
sure.
That you're filtering it out before it
gets to them.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
it's called the journal.
You can set up@thejournal.email.
There's that email domain extensions
down.
Really?
Yeah.
It's a email list.
It's just an email is to put an email
address to send one a month and um,
and you can use it for anything.
You can use a domain for it or whatever
you want.
But they came out with a dot.
Email,
domain extension.
Um,
but yeah,
weird extension.
What does it,
cause usually they're from countries,
right?
Why?
Yeah,
it's normally from countries,
but now they're opening up to
everything.
There's like.wine.
Now there's dots like you know they
have.porn
yet there's dot x x,
x.
Oh,
okay.
And that's all porn.
So expensive tography for my website
there.
Who Do?
Ooh,
look at,
you can gene me.
Dot.
Photography.
Um,
what is something that's really got you
hyped up?
Uh,
the Arrow wifi system.
E.
R.
O.
What does that,
ah,
it's crazy.
So you know how there's always been,
we've had wifi units that it's like one
base station to rule them all.
Like you have one base station and they
look,
they get crazier every year.
They have get more antennas on them.
And this idea of one master base
station,
that blankets here entire house.
It's,
it's great if you have a small
apartment.
If you have a house or two bedroom or
three bedroom,
it's next to impossible to get like
streaming video down at bedroom number
three down the hall.
So arrows like,
okay,
screw it.
We're not going to make one master
massive base station.
We're going to make these little tiny
like hockey puck style little stations
and you get three of them in a pack and
then you just plugged them in and around
the house and they work off a mesh
network.
So they all mesh with each other.
They're not extenders.
They're like using their own dedicated
little wireless signals to do Mesh.
Almost like the way a Sonos would
operate in your house.
Um,
and then you just have universal
blanket,
a high speed coverage and so it doesn't
vary no matter where you walk.
Amazing.
In New York,
I was having issues like trying cause my
Wifi or my um,
cable modem was all the way on the other
end of the house and I have a long
hallway kind of going between the dining
room,
the front room and um,
I plucked three of men all going down
the hallway.
And normally with these boosters or
anything else,
they just kind of like,
they kind of suck.
They just didn't ever work.
Right.
Yeah.
And this one just,
I mean set up on your iphone,
how do you spell it?
E R O.
Dot Com.
Yeah,
there they are right there.
There's a three units,
um,
uh,
on the screen there.
But yeah,
they're,
they're pretty amazing and it's a,
it's a new technology.
One of their investors was telling me
about it.
Um,
I bought them on Amazon and this is
something that I just mentioned to my
newsletter because I had some time to
spend with it.
And,
and that actually really I,
if you have wife,
if your wife works great at home,
don't mess with it.
It's not worth it.
But if you're having issues,
this,
this works,
why does it have a phone there?
They have an APP that we're set up is
just what the phone,
they don't even make you use a desktop
to set it up at all.
So just plug it into your,
whatever you use.
Like a,
some sort of a,
a cable that connects into your router.
Yeah.
You just plug it right in your router
with the first base station and then you
go and take the other ones.
I'm just them around your house.
Yeah,
it's great.
And how does it work with uh,
the Apple Wifi system?
I just got rid of the apple.
I unplugged it all together and just use
only that and that's only use this.
Yeah.
Interesting.
Ooh,
I like it better,
Huh?
Yeah,
it's been getting great reviews.
Um,
you know,
again,
but it's,
if your Wifi is working fine,
don't mess with it.
Like that's,
but mine,
I've,
I've had,
I must've like pissed off some kind of
Wifi.
God,
in a previous life,
I've never had good wifi.
Some issues.
I think everybody does.
The wifi is,
we're two hours a wondered what's going
on with those signals.
Just fucking flying around your house
too,
right?
It's like,
is that good?
I think you're fine.
I think you're fine too,
but I don't know.
It's like that same thing you were
saying about there could possibly be
senses that we don't necessarily have
like that we could measure and weigh,
but there's a feeling that you get when
you're like at the top of a mountain.
If you go hiking and there's no wifi
signal,
it just feels cleaner.
But it also could be the amazing fresh
air could be,
right?
Yeah.
Or maybe we can do some dmt at home and
start reading people's email.
Let's just like by intersecting nursing.
Do you think there's gonna come a point
in time where there is no longer any
privacy,
any privacy at all?
I don't think so.
I think privacy is a hot topic right now
and people are,
are really starting to get into it for
the first time.
Right.
So they definitely were concerned when
you hear about the NSA thing,
the Edward Snowden thing,
and you find out that it's really pretty
easy to access your information and you
know,
people worry about being hacked,
right?
Being fished,
you know,
someone sends you an email and people
were worried about privacy.
But my concern is that it seems like
what what's going on with technology in
general is,
especially when it comes to the Internet
and anything information based is your
access to information is getting quicker
and quicker.
Right?
It's like you have more access to more
data and more access to each other and
each other's data and eventually that
means that keeps going and keeps going
and keeps going.
There's gonna come a point in time where
we're just fucking reading each other's
minds.
Right.
And when that happens,
it's really not going to be a lot of
privacy if at all.
Yeah,
I think that there is,
there's certainly people trying to push
the envelope there and there has been
over the last few years and in startups
that I've seen like a,
there was a startup that at one point,
um,
you would often all of your credit cards
and it would share out socially the
stuff that you were buying with friends.
And so basically if you went on there
and bought a,
a blood,
a sensor on Amazon,
I would see that.
And then I could then use that as a
cover more or less an endorsement from
you and go buy something similar.
It blew up and it went out of business,
but they were kind of pushing that.
But there has to be a trade off,
especially when it comes to free
services.
Like you can't expect to be a private
person if you're getting something for
free.
You know,
like if you're getting g mail,
they are reading your emails and they're
putting ads against it.
Now it's not a human reading them,
but their machines are reading them and
placing relevant ads and it's not spooky
moment when you were looking something
online and then you go and look to the
corner of your,
your website page and it's that exact
ad.
Right?
But that's fine.
I'm fine with that because it's free.
I don't have to go drive down to the
library and look up a book and trying to
figure out what I was trying,
you know,
Google is providing that service and I'm
like,
thank you very much.
Google and I will gladly take your ad.
And if you're looking for like a pair of
shoes and you went and researched a pair
of shoes,
then all sudden that pair of shoes is
staring at you on the website.
It's creepy,
but I get it.
It's terrible.
It's not terrible.
Yeah,
because it's something that you already
expressed intent towards.
You're like,
I want that mct oil.
Right.
And now it's there again,
it's not like sexual deviants shit.
Right.
You know,
sometimes it could be a is it depends on
the targeting.
But if they do that though it,
Google doesn't allow that now.
Yeah,
that would be rough.
Yeah.
Try explaining that.
That's a cause for bitten by the terms
of service.
Must be,
which it's funny because that's where
people draw the line.
It was like sexual pleasure,
like sexual pleasure and sexual
fantasies.
That's where we draw the line.
Right.
But what you can talk about openly and
have,
you know,
I mean you could have a shoe fetish and
you'd be like really into shoes.
Have you ever met anyone that openly
says they have a shoe fetish?
I don't think that that's a,
that's a,
um,
you can tell him.
He might not say it's a welfare sexual
fetish.
No,
but all those fucking Weirdos that are
connect collect sneakers.
You know who you are.
Right.
All those years thinking the Nike
sneaker collectors are also,
Jamie's one of them looking them over
there smiling.
He buys
those Kanye West sneakers.
Really?
Him,
he wants to try to find him,
can't get 'em.
They're sold out.
The question is like how get them any,
how bad do you want them?
Is it like a,
I like to have them or like I will,
I don't know anything.
My friend Brendan,
he buys pairs and then he won't wear
them until he knows he's got to do
something important.
And then you put on a special pair of
Jordans.
I'm like,
you all have that though.
I used to collect old microprocessors.
Really?
What'd you do?
And you actually I have a sealed copy of
windows 1.0
wow.
In the computer history museum.
Says my name underneath it in San
Francisco outside of San Francisco.
Outside of mountain view.
Well that's actually pretty cool though.
That's history.
That's like an ancient leather bound
book that Ben Franklin Rhoda and I
thought it was kind of cool.
It's pretty cool.
Yeah.
I've got an old windows nt that's still
in the box in my house.
3.1141
probably.
I don't know what the a,
the number is,
but it was around windows m e cause I
remember uh,
as making game computers and I didn't
like windows emmy.
Ah,
it's the worst.
Yeah it was.
It was sucky.
And so,
uh,
I had some friends that went with nt but
the problem was you would have issues
with certain drivers for video cards and
you have to be like really hip on the
forums and make sure you get on a irt
and Erc and find out where the uh,
the best drivers are and how to Super
Geeky days.
Yeah.
There was like certain resolutions you
couldn't run things out was everything
that he had to file a format with the
NTSF file system.
Remember that IRC was always weird to so
strange cause you could send files to
each other.
It's like IRC.
Such a strange message sort of
distribution.
The original hashtags where an IRC,
do you remember that?
You could do like pound a channel?
I can eat anything.
That's right.
This is all from my quake playing days.
So that was how clans would communicate
with each other.
Yeah.
The quake teams would call each other
clans.
First People look,
you were in the club now the clan like
tribe,
like you know,
team that competes,
realize that they did call it cleanse
back then.
Yeah.
The comb quake clans.
It's so crazy.
Yeah.
You make that connection.
I was in a clan to yeah,
well I was in a car.
Crazy.
They called it that.
Yeah.
The,
you know,
um,
and we would go to these,
uh,
IRC channels and we'd have like a window
open,
like a lot of guys would run two
screens.
So you'd run a one screen where your
video games playing and then you'd have
another screen next to that separate,
which was your IRC channel.
Right.
And so you'd be communicating with each
other and you had Iq,
remember the instant messenger?
Yeah.
Well Icq,
I see the little flower.
The green flag.
Yeah.
That was awesome.
And so you could send each other a
little icq messages while the mass was
going on.
Super Geeky.
Dude.
This is Geeky as it gets.
I mean,
this was like nineties yeah.
Right.
So like this is stay at this.
This is how deep I was into it.
I lived in the mountains like kind of
high up in the hills of the Santa Monica
Mountains and I couldn't get good
Internet access the best I could get
with isd n right.
Couldn't get um,
cable.
Couldn't get cable modem out there.
It's fucking terrible.
The pings were awful to everywhere.
So I had a t one line installed.
Oh,
you must've been rich.
I was rich.
It does.
Very expensive with deep.
Yeah.
But it was worth it to me.
It's a 1.44
megabit line.
Yeah.
It was worth 10 grand a month.
It was worth it.
That's,
did you really buy a t one line pass?
I had installed in my house.
How did you get the,
how could you he was on TV.
Oh,
you're doing TV stuff?
I was on TV.
Wow.
So it was like,
look,
I could a TV money blows money on coke
and hookers or a t one line stall t one
line in my house.
The people at the whatever the fucking
company I called this do it 18 to year,
whoever did it,
they were like,
what did they have to lay like fiber to
get to your head to do it to this place,
to this place.
We had dog shit Internet.
When we first moved into this place,
they had a chew up the fucking sidewalk
out front because I was like,
this is not going to happen.
It was way more expensive to put it in
here.
This was a drag.
It's like,
what did it say?
Four months.
More than four months to get like real,
but we have a hundred and a hundred
down.
Wow.
Dedicated on.
It's fat.
It's a,
it's an awesome pipe.
But when we first moved here,
we had DSL.
It was dog shit and it's just,
there's certain things that you just
can't fuck around with.
You know,
Internet is definitely one of them.
And when you're addicted,
completely dictated eight to 10 hours a
day playing quake and you go,
oh,
there's a solution there.
What is the solution?
It's a t one line.
Let's do that.
You know,
a lot of people got Trent reznor was
addicted to that for a long time.
Quick.
Yeah.
Well it's amazing.
It's,
and I can't even fuck with it today.
I just don't have any time.
I have children.
I have too many different jobs.
I just can't go near it.
I can't.
Yeah.
But I'm sure that if I just fucking blew
a fuse one night and uh,
drank too many jolt cola us and sat down
in front of my computer and decided to
go online and place of death matches,
I would get right back in.
And just like a dude who has an rubber
band off his arm and shot that heroin is
for awhile I'd get right back into it.
Man.
Don't do it.
It's slippery slope.
I won't,
I won't.
I refuse.
But the new games,
the graphics are so fucking incredible.
It's almost worth it.
What is this doing multiplayer trailer
that just popped out?
Whoa.
Oh my God.
Look at this fast running around.
So people are complaining about how the
play is company cause it's that old
school the way doom used to.
Exactly.
Well,
that's the way it's supposed to be.
Like what are they complaining about
this?
Because it will be fast and stuff like
that.
Oh,
cause they're pussies.
They wanted,
yeah.
They want the fucking people to move
like real people.
That's retarded.
Oh yeah.
Look at this.
You turn into a monster and start
fucking people up when you owe this,
you bite people's heads off.
When does this come out?
It's awesome.
All right.
I just changed my opinion.
I'm in.
I'm back in.
I'm going to keep making you use the
controllers though.
Like I'm the expert.
I can't either.
Useless.
I need a mouse and a keyboard.
That's the only way to do it.
Look at this guy.
He's fighting the devil.
He just punted punching the devil in his
fucking face.
Now he has the devil power.
Oh Jesus Christ.
This is amazing.
You have a c?
I'm not interested in grabbing people
and ripping them apart.
I want to shoot him.
It looks dope though.
Death match like one on one death
matches with that will be pretty fucking
incredible.
He had the perfect setup here for a land
party.
Don't say it.
Stop.
I'm just saying stop.
We still land parties.
Back in the 1990s we used to all meet in
Houston.
Those were a bunch of my friends.
Where are we going to be seeing over the
link them all together and have zero
ping.
That's just the greatest thing ever.
The most.
The most brutal thing we would do
though.
My friend Chad,
he was,
uh,
he had some sort of a tech job,
I forget what it was,
but he had access to his company's board
room and we'd set up everything up in
this board room and these giant tables
and shit.
And then we would start a server and
then other people would join it,
but they had lag and we didn't have any
lag.
Just waste them.
So sweet.
So it's just like,
you know,
shooting chickens and a barrel.
Yeah,
fish in a barrel or whatever it is.
It's probably also equally easy.
Yeah.
I mean it just,
after a while,
but then the worst thing is like you
would find someone who would kick your
ass even though you know they had 50
paying and zero,
you're like,
oh,
well great.
Who is the best player ever.
What was the mortal?
Yes.
I had him,
he was on the screen savers on techtv
back in the day when I was on there and
I played against him.
Yeah,
it's thrash,
thrash.
Next level with immortal was as well.
There's a bunch of different guys.
Who's thresh?
There was fatality totalities the one
that died.
He was really good.
Yeah.
Jonathan Window,
I think his name is.
I met that dude in Vegas.
He's a great guy.
Super Nice Guy.
Yeah.
He,
I think he plays regular games now too,
but there was a kid before him,
um,
uh,
name that his nickname was thresh and he
sort of got out of the competitive game
thing and got into online websites like
reviewing games and game websites and
the business of it.
He's just started to stop playing and
competing.
But there's a bunch of those guys.
Yeah,
I played a few of them online.
Just got to fucking,
just decimate.
Yeah.
Fatality had his own motherboard.
I had his mouse that was like the
equivalent of like being like a signed
by like a skateboarder and something
like that.
There it is.
Yes.
A totality.
There he is up in the upper left hand
side.
That would have been my dream back in
the day to have my face on a motherboard
box.
So good.
I wonder what he's doing these days.
I wonder what he must be involved in
something.
It's what it says is twitch.
He's got a channel.
Is that what it is?
Yeah.
These guys,
they play games on twitch and they make
money playing games.
People watching them.
It's a good life.
Well,
some people have these channels where
they play on twitch and they have
hundreds of thousands of people that are
following them and watching them and
they're playing 40,000
people might be watching them play a
fucking game at the same like,
I mean you've seen the stadiums in
Korea.
Yes.
That's nuts.
The starcraft,
right?
Yeah.
Starcraft,
I think it is.
Fuck man.
See that's not interesting to me though.
Starcraft is boring to me.
I understand it,
but it's like chess.
I'm,
I'm sure it's fascinating to Pli.
I love those games.
It was,
that was my bread and butter right
there,
like command and conquer.
And those those.
But yeah,
it is like chess and it's too much about
build order now.
It's like you have to really get your
build order down and just go really fast
up front.
What's the build order?
What does that mean?
It just means that like,
you know,
you put your power plant first before
your weapons plant,
before your turret.
It's like you have to know your order
and once you build things and then you
adjust that based on what the they're
bringing against you.
So if they're trying to rush you right
away,
you want to get tour,
it's a first look at that.
Oh,
that's the same as this weekend at the
MLG tournament.
That's where this is.
Oh my God.
This is like 15,000
people in dollar tournament.
I think my,
no,
that's insane.
All those dorks.
How many of those guys have ever gotten
lane five?
Raise your hand.
It'd be fun just to go to one of those
to go to one of them as a reporter,
I would like to interview those guys.
I saw that the uh,
the rock was back in the ww wwe,
he was just back in,
it will wrestlemania like a few days
ago.
I wanted to go do that would be fun.
If you've ever been to a wrestlemania.
Oh No.
It's like a male soap opera.
You just go there and you drink beer and
you yell and then you leave.
I mean,
you know,
just to experience it one time,
I'm not into it.
I don't know the characters.
I don't watch it ever.
But just to go and experience that kind
of environment,
it's not interesting to me,
but I get it.
I get how it would be interesting,
but you got to think that like,
I'm already,
Whoa,
what's that?
How many people are there?
Yes.
It was the record.
What?
The hundred thousand wrestling,
fake wrestling.
Fake it.
Fake wrestling.
Oh,
100,000
people.
Oh my God.
You know,
that's the arena that the UFC has been
hoping forever to do an event in,
but we would have to have some crazy,
unbelievable card to fill that place up.
Oh my God.
Can you believe that many people go and
the tickets were 500 to 3000 that's
incredible.
It's like basically like the super bowl,
the amount of money they must've made
from that fucking thing's insane.
And it's all fake.
Yup.
I mean,
not that they're not athletes.
So there's those things are serious
athletes,
acrobats.
I mean Cirque de Solei.
It's fake too.
Yeah.
And that way it's not an unimpressive,
it's very impressive.
Yeah.
I just,
you know,
thought of the slaves fake,
but I,
you know,
I do commentary for mma.
So for me that the reality of MMA is so
intense and so it's so powerful that
like,
I can't,
I just,
I've seen much.
Yeah,
that's fair.
It's like a phase one guy going down.
I'm like,
I can't,
like,
I'm more going for the,
I'm not actually like into watching dad
as much as it would be just the
environment in general.
I guess.
I go into a monster truck rally.
I'd love to do that as well.
I don't want to do that either.
Definitely not hanging after the show.
People good to cry all together.
We can make you cry over that fist bump
and fucking go our separate ways.
Empty and talk shadow.
In other words,
we're getting a separate cars and even
like rustling,
he said fucking cry.
Those fake.
Yeah.
I uh,
I mean,
I get it.
I understand it.
I just,
it's not,
there's not enough time in the day.
I know.
I mean,
if you,
if I,
I,
that's why I don't follow baseball,
basketball,
football or hockey as people try to talk
to shit a game and I go,
no,
look at me like I just sucked a hundred
dicks.
Like,
no,
look man,
I don't have to walk like what you like.
Right,
okay.
Just because you guys were all in the
football.
You didn't watch the super bowl.
No,
I didn't want you to superbowl.
Yeah.
Was that okay?
I never watched the superbowl.
It's probably a good time day to go out
and get shit done.
It's,
I was at Disneyland.
We always get emt.
People caught on,
used to be used to be back in the day is
to take the kids on Disneyland was a
good one.
Um,
some Jewish holidays.
We're good.
Yeah,
he definitely wouldn't get like you'd
eliminate like 99% of the Jewish people.
So that would be a good,
like 30% of the people at the park or
whatever it fuck it would be.
You can catch like days like that.
Like if you're,
if you want to go to Disneyland,
it's probably a good idea to plan.
You got to look really plot that thing
out,
right.
Because if you try to go on like a
normal day in the summer or something
like that,
good fucking luck.
It hasn't been easy land forever.
It's awesome.
Is it though they have this new star
distinguish rod.
How do you what?
Either Quito,
Turkey legs.
You do Turkey legs there.
Yeah.
You're saying,
dude,
I'm disciplined.
I full Kido now I can,
well I did a little cheat and when I was
in Mexico I had some uh,
tortillas,
but that was still around.
Yeah.
But I did it just because I was on
vacation.
I was like,
I'm,
I'm going to enjoy myself for a few days
and then get right back onto it.
But I like the effect of it.
It definitely a noticeable effect on the
way I look and noticeable effect in the
way I feel.
And I think there's some undeniable
cognitive benefits as far as like the
clarity of your mind.
Like you don't feel foggy and tired.
And I was like,
I'm just sticking with this.
Yeah.
And plus I bring,
I don't have any here.
Well this is the,
this is just some cream.
This is Quito cream run to try to get me
on this stuff,
man.
That's stuff's not,
that's not,
wait,
I had this one.
It is sweet.
It's got the Stevia in it.
That was,
is that the one?
That's the one I gave it to her.
I gave that shit to her.
Um,
I also gave her some Quito Ios,
which is something you that he'd dumped
in water it same company right now it's
a different company,
but it's a ketones.
Um,
but exogenous ketones are good.
Yeah.
It doesn't kill Canada.
Quito can is great.
I have that stuff that's good to like
keep you going.
And then there's,
um,
dom d'agostino who's where,
one of the reasons why I was first
intrigued by the Ketogenic Diet.
I'm listening to him on a Tim Ferriss
podcast.
So if you haven't heard it,
dom's awesome,
amazing,
super fucking smart guy and so dedicated
to the pros and the benefits of a
ketogenic diets and staying in Ketosis.
So I was like,
well,
this guy is obviously on the fucking
ball.
I've got,
I've got to really look,
look into this.
There's gotta be something to this.
And so for me there was a few like
undeniable benefits.
One of the big ones is the way I feel in
between meals.
Huge.
Oh yeah.
There's not any type of crash.
Have a constant energy.
Well,
not only that,
the constant energy or the know crash is
good,
but also my hunger is not the same.
Like I would get fucking famished where
I would eat something and then four
hours later,
five hours away when I was ready for my
next meal,
I would be famished where my body was
crashing at all my God,
I have to fucking eat.
I literally don't get like that anymore.
It doesn't happen.
So I recognize that I'm hungry.
I realized that I should probably get
some food in me,
but I'm not,
I'm not compromised.
And in that state,
I can still have a very good workout.
Right.
Which when I was on a carbohydrate,
glucose based system,
my body was just not operating like
that.
I would,
I would have a shit workout if I was
tired and I hadn't eaten anything.
I would have to have some fruit before I
worked at.
Right.
And so those two benefits,
but the big one was,
um,
the way my brain works,
it just feels,
it feels less foggy.
Yeah.
It's a cleaner state,
I think.
Yeah.
Well,
it's undeniable also that eating all
those carbohydrates has an effect on
your insulin sensitivity.
And you know,
your body's just processing a fuckload
sugar.
You're all that bread and pasta and all
that stuff.
It's a lot of sugar.
And if you are blowing it out all day,
if you're some crazy fucking ultra
marathon runner or some,
some dude who's doing crossfit four
hours a day or something like that,
you'd probably get away with it.
You know,
again,
probably be fine,
but I think there's some real benefits
to staying in Ketosis.
Yeah,
I,
I've,
I got really hooked on it so much so
that I was testing my blood probably
three to four times a day,
which you fine.
I was just testing after I would eat
certain foods.
So you know,
I would,
I would go in and say okay,
I am,
you know,
two and a half millimolar is right now
keep telling wise if I have a big salad,
but I put a ton of fat in there as well.
Will I stay in Ketosis?
Like pushing the edges to see what we
kicked me out.
Right.
So you know,
I,
one thing I did find is I,
I like to have a glass of wine or two
with dinner and so I really wanted to
see what wine we do with ketosis knocks
you right out of it.
Right.
You know what,
actually I'm a really dry champagne.
I could stay in,
which is weird because you wouldn't
think champagne would keep you and you
think like something with a,
it has definitely.
It has to be on the drier side,
but I was thinking initially like a,
a red wine would keep me in more than
say like a
champagne.
I would,
I would drop down,
but I'd still be,
you know,
around 0.8
to 1.2,
somewhere around there.
Do you worry about that?
Do you check that on a regular basis or
do you just go on the way you feel?
Uh,
primarily in the way I feel.
I could always tell when I got kicked
out,
I could tell when I ate something I
shouldn't,
you know,
I'd be out and about and it would sneak
up on me.
You know,
you'd have like a salad with like some
kind of dressing that I wasn't sure of,
but it doesn't taste too sweet.
And then all of a sudden I would get
this really bad crash if I got fully
kicked out of Ketosis.
Yeah.
Wow.
You must be like super sensitive.
I was super since,
but I would also get pretty deep pretty
easily.
Like I could fast and get up into two
and a half,
three millimeters within 24 hours.
Um,
I had a real problem with those God damn
blood meters.
Why?
Because the things that they use to
prick your skin don't get through my
skin just said it's like a level eight
or whatever.
I had to take it out of the thing and
stab myself.
Yeah,
that's weird.
I lift so much kettlebells that my,
my skins are all,
it's all calloused and thick.
Right.
So I'd like try to get in there and I
was going to actually go with the top of
my skin,
you know,
like maybe that's the better way to do
it,
but it just seemed so fucking gross.
So I've tried it all over the place.
I've done it on the sides before.
What's the best way for you?
Uh,
for me it's,
it is the tips of the fingers,
but like,
you know,
it's kind of Russian roulette like one
and I've ever,
10 is going to hurt.
So when you're doing it like five times
a day,
you would always kind of try and yeah,
different spots.
You know,
it got annoying.
I was like,
this is annoying.
Jab Myself.
Cause I had,
I used to try the punch thing and it
just wasn't doing anything right.
I would go right to the tip chunk.
Did you squeak Bush even when you were
at that thing?
Huh?
But is years of,
you know,
lifting?
I like kettle bells or just so it's a
fat piece of iron and your hands.
Are you just constantly getting roughed
up and I'm using powder right on chalk.
So it's was all this grit.
It's all very thick.
It's like the coding.
It's like the bottom of your feet stand
on top doing the top stair.
Is there a better way?
I mean there's the piece takes,
but they don't really didn't work that
well.
Um,
but you know,
for someone like yourself that's falling
a pretty strict diet than just once a
day is fine,
just check it,
check it first thing in the morning and
don't check it anymore.
Yeah,
it doesn't matter if you know you're in
your end,
you'll feel it.
Well,
I always feel like,
look,
what am I eating?
I mean eggs and Avocados and meet,
and I know what I'm eating and I'm not,
I just want to feel like I'm feel right
now,
like if I could just keep this whatever
this is.
Yeah.
This is great.
You know?
I mean,
I don't want to,
I don't want anything that I would have
to obsess on.
Right.
Oh my God,
I'm in 2 million molar is I'd like to be
at three I,
how do I get to three?
Well,
I'll have to eat,
drink fucking gallon mct.
Oh,
now I've got to shit my pants.
It's right.
Yeah.
For me it was like,
okay,
what is going to kick me out?
Just so I know the boundaries and once I
have the boundaries that I'm fine,
I didn't need to do it anymore.
So like,
you know,
I know that I can have,
a half a cup of brown
rice along with some fatty foods and
it's not going to really do anything.
So it's like,
I just wanted to see it as a cup kicked
me out.
Oh yeah,
I kept does.
Okay,
dial it back,
you know,
that kind of thing.
Right?
And when you get kicked out,
how long does it take you to recover?
A half day.
Half Day.
Half to three quarters of a day.
Intermittent fast at all.
Oh yeah.
And how,
how many hours do you do?
A 16 hours.
16,
12.
And I guess it's not enough.
I'll do 24 a couple of times a month.
Real?
Yeah.
Two,
three times a month.
And why do you do it?
Just because I keep,
you know,
he listened to ron as podcast and she
starts talking about like all the guests
that she has.
I'm like doctor,
dom and others.
Um,
you know,
when they talk about how if you're doing
a full 24 hour fast,
like it can actually help clear out the
non precancerous cause kind of cells.
They haven't fully gone cancer.
And then interesting.
It's crazy,
but why not?
You know,
it's like this is something fascinating.
Been around for a,
a obviously a very long time.
It also puts me in a nice kind of
meditative state.
Um,
you know,
it's,
I interviewed the trainer.
I haven't released as podcasts yet,
but I enter interviewed the trainer for
Hugh Jackman that helped him get
shredded revolver.
He did tell you about the steroids.
Uh,
he did not tell me about this.
Oh,
well he didn't tell you everything then.
Yeah,
he definitely told me about the
intermittent fast about the steroids.
Is this real?
I'm a hundred percent confident that
that guy did steroid.
How do you know?
Look at his body.
He's fucking jacked.
Hugh Jackman got fucking jacked and he's
40 years old.
You don't think he got checked?
Well,
I mean,
well,
it depends on what kind of,
I'm sure that he was on a wonderful
diet.
He was on a wonderful diet,
intermittent fasting.
He was without a doubt,
manipulating these hormones.
What do you think he was using?
I know friends that have done movie
rules.
Look at him.
Come on,
son.
Shit.
That's a lot of photoshop.
Photoshop,
that's a skill that might be a still,
but the,
this is scene in the movie where he gets
up out of bed and he is fucking jacked.
I mean,
is it possible to get that big without
steroids?
If you're 20 yeah,
yeah.
It war.
If you are a fucking maniac and your 30
and you're in the gym all day long and
you're completely and totally dedicated.
Yeah,
it's possible.
But it's not likely.
But I have a friend who was a,
he was doing,
he's a movie actor and he was doing a
role and in the role he had to be jacked
and they just,
without any,
they just come in.
Yeah.
We have a guy,
we have a guy and this guy's gonna hook
you up and if you follow his protocol,
she's just gonna it'll be healthy.
It's like,
well,
this what we're gonna do.
We're gonna,
you know,
do this and do that and add this and
that.
And he was like,
whoa.
And uh,
you know,
it's,
it's really kind of in some sort of a
weird gray area.
You know,
it's,
there's some stuff that you,
first of all,
there's some stuff that you can get at
like Gnc and some of those places where
it is steroids.
Really.
Yes.
Like what stuff?
Well,
fucking shitload of them.
We had Jeff Novitsky who was the guy who
busted Lance Armstrong and he works for
the UFC now.
He works for Usada and he um,
they have a website and then the youth
side of website,
there's all these different supplements
that contain products that are illegal
products that will get you kicked out
because they are steroids in their
performance enhancing drugs while you,
the u s Ada website has like,
you know,
alphabetically listed a through z and
each letter has just fucking shit loads
of different supplements that you could
buy at any store and he local vitamin
Shoppe that is likely to be filled with
steroids.
That's crazy.
Well there's this stuff that I take,
I took it in like the early two
thousands was called Mag 10.
They,
they made it illegal.
After awhile it was 100% steroids.
I mean 100%.
This has to be really bad for your liver
then since all most of them are not
good.
But you know,
when you see someone did gets that Jack
for a movie,
why would they be concerned with not
doing it the right way?
Like if the,
what's the,
what's the goal here?
The goal here is you have to look like a
goddamn superhero.
Right?
Okay.
So are you pr,
are you prepared to not totally looked
like a superhero and tell everybody,
but at least I did it naturally.
Right?
Fuck that.
No,
they're going to,
they're going to do dead lifts on
testosterone and take human growth
hormone and the reward is pretty high
too.
And that you get paid $15 million or
whatever it is for any looked awesome.
I mean I'm not hating it at all,
but anyone who thinks you're going to
achieve that kind of results without
some sorts,
especially like,
like I said,
like how old you Jackman isn't he like
40 it's like 42 or something like that.
I mean it's,
there are some outliers,
there are some people that mean,
but in the UFC when you find these guys
and they just look unbelievable,
they like unbelievably ripped and huge
and they get into their late thirties
and then they get popped and then some
on the,
some of the,
they just randomly test them and then
eat.
Cause w the way that UFC is set up now
with Novitsky,
they'll show up at your house at six
o'clock in the morning,
wake up,
dude,
wake up dude.
Yeah,
we need some blood to p crazy.
And then they test them.
And then,
you know,
there's a lot of these guys that are on
something that hasn't,
it's insanely short half life.
Like they'll have something that a is
only a shows up in the system for like
seven hours.
So what they'll try to do is they'll try
to take it like right before they go to
bed and then we'll get the benefits of
it and then,
but they'll fucking wake you up,
man.
They'll wake you up.
That's insane.
Well,
it's because they want to find out
what's going on and we've exposed,
or I shouldn't say we have nothing to do
with it,
but they've exposed,
uh,
tremendous underlying sort of just a
standard operational procedure of
testosterone,
steroids,
all,
all sorts of different ways of
manipulating the system.
Epo,
that stuff that Armstrong got caught
with or actually didn't,
he never got caught with anything.
Right.
He had to confess.
That's right.
But a lot of those cyclists take epo,
which jacks up your red blood cell
production.
There's just so many different ways of
enhancing the way the body functions
both naturally,
you know,
like with Ketosis and a lot of other
methods and you know,
and then with exogenous chemicals,
did you see the documentary on steroids?
Which one?
Bigger.
Stronger,
faster.
I had those guys here.
It would you think that's great.
It's interesting.
It is interesting.
I've become friends with those guys.
Um,
and um,
it's just when you find out what,
you know,
how many different different types of
steroids there are and how many
different people and totally different
athletes are taking them and you like,
especially throughout bodybuilding and
things.
I mean if you can call that a sport,
I guess you can.
It's kind of an activity more than it is
a sports kind of dying out though.
I feel like is it at least the,
the crazy,
I had a buddy that they competed,
um,
and he was definitely choosing,
uh,
and he was,
he said that the big bulky kind of crazy
over the top look and they're going more
for a more natural appearance.
That's kind of the hot thing now.
Like Frank Zane or something like that.
Yeah.
Frank Zane was famous in the arnold days
as being like the most symmetrical and
also like the more realistic,
like as close to like a Lee Haney who is
just just walking mass of muscle.
Right.
Whereas Zane was more,
it looked more sculpted.
It will look more like a,
you have a photo of them there.
Oh,
Jesus.
Who's that guy?
Oh yeah,
he was on what touch point.
Oh,
oh yeah.
Well this guy is a crazy guy.
He's sort of a bodybuilder,
but more of like a personality.
He has an eight hour arm workout where
he works out nothing but his arms for
eight hours.
Wow.
His arms are massive.
Yeah.
He's everything massive.
He's is a cartoon.
There's definitely some drugs there.
No way,
dude.
That's totally legit.
Yeah,
no,
he's,
he's brought it to the tits.
Um,
but lou,
Google,
Frank Zane,
and you'll get an idea of what a lot of
people thought was like one of the
perfect bodies.
So like Frank Zane,
I firmly believe that that is a body
that is possible.
You can attain that body without
steroids with strong dedication and
good,
uh,
knowledge of nutrition and the right way
to lift weights.
But Frank Zane never got ridiculously
big like that is a regular size guy out
a lot of gyms like right there,
right.
That's a regular size guy.
And a lot of like high level gyms like
that might not even be the biggest guy
there.
It looks like there's drugs there
though,
right?
I mean,
the shoulders are popped maybe most
likely,
probably.
I Dunno.
Um,
no,
that's attainable,
man.
Yeah,
that's a terrible without drug little
lines.
But that just means he's a very lean it
those little lines.
Striations.
That's totally attainable.
Without drugs.
There's a level,
I mean,
you'd have to be really dedicated to
training,
but he's,
he's not,
he's not that big man in comparison to
some of the people of today.
Now look at him.
Okay.
Now Google Dorian Yates,
Dorian Yates who was a fucking,
and he's or Dorian is a really
interesting guy because he's super
honest about it.
Like that one right there,
right?
No to the left of that right there.
What in the fucking Christ look out.
That's insane.
That's all drugs and dedication and
focus and lifting a 100% I mean,
you don't have,
you just took Jay counselor.
You've seen Jay Cutler's legs,
right?
Yeah.
Type in Jay Cutler that those guys are
ridiculous.
Yeah.
Or Tom Platz ever seen that guy's legs.
Tom Platz has the most ridiculous legs
ever.
Jesus Christ.
I can't.
I just got some.
Yeah,
that's all like horses.
I mean,
you have to be a maniac in the gym on
top of the log of that fucking picture.
That's insane.
Yeah.
I mean,
I think this is also,
this is also like a mass movement of
body dysmorphia because it's not just
that these guys are trying to get as big
as they can.
I don't think they see themselves the
way other people see them either.
Cause like sometimes they freak out when
they're not in perfect shape and they
want to cover their bodies up with
sweaters and stuff and they don't want
anybody looking at them.
It's like an anorexia thing in a way,
but it's still like better than 99.9%
of humans on earth,
even when they're not in peak shape.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I mean,
but to them,
you know,
they're,
they're used to judging each other.
So harsh,
laid,
they have a little bit of extra body
fat.
They start to freak crazy.
Yeah.
I mean back to Hugh Jackman and this,
uh,
this training thing.
Yeah.
I mean I think that's,
it's a fantastic way to get your body
really lean.
And that's one of the things he was in
that movie was super lean.
Yeah.
So he was on a ketogenic diet.
He was doing the intermittent fasting.
And so he was doing 16 hours a day,
every day,
every day.
Hmm.
Interesting.
And then on a ketogenic diet as well as
I know about that.
No,
I don't think he was saying Kenogenic.
Hmm.
And what was the benefit of doing that
16 hour fasting without a key leading
up.
Just leaning up.
Hmm.
I would wonder if that would affect
without getting your body into a state
of ketosis.
I wonder if that would affect the way
your body put on muscle mass.
Yeah,
I'm not sure.
I don't know enough about this.
You know,
there's also a problem that for the
longest time doctors were calling
bullshit on fasting and they just didn't
have a lot of information.
But they were like so quick to poo poo
it and like,
you know,
like fasting has no med.
I remember this guy telling me this,
he was a doctor goes,
fasting has no medical benefits.
Your body exists on nutrients and when
you deny your body nutrients and you
think you're somehow under their
cleansing,
your system is just a bunch of bunk.
Meanwhile,
he was wrong.
Right?
And he's a fucking doctor.
That means almost all doctors are five,
10 years behind the science though,
right?
Um,
a lot of them,
well the,
the thing is how much education did they
actually have on nutrition,
right.
And two hours that it's really small.
It is like that it's like,
you know,
a quarter of a semester or something
like that.
Something really,
so when you're talking to an oncologist
and the oncologist starts poopooing the
value of phytonutrients and certain
vitamins to combat cancer and he doesn't
stay on top of the cutting edge of it.
I mean,
people are so weird with what they know
that they believe that what they know is
all there is out there.
Right.
Like I had a discussion with this woman
and she just did,
she was,
um,
we were talking about um,
uh,
this animal that they found the Congo,
it's called the Bondo ape.
It's like this enormous chimpanzee
documented like hundred percent.
They have DNA photos,
camera trap pictures of it.
They have,
they've got the skull of it,
they know it's real animal.
And this woman was like,
try it.
She was mocking it.
Like,
what could kind of fringe things.
I went to school for anthropology.
Like I go,
oh well you're obviously not on the
ball.
Like maybe you went to school 20 years
ago.
And then I told her,
go,
go google it.
Go Google,
check it these websites.
And she was like,
I'm not going to,
I go,
you're not going to,
I'll,
but I'll do it in front of you and then
will you shut the fuck up and I show you
photos cause this is giant chimpanzee
that they found this one rare area of
the Congo that's of really old photo
though,
man.
That's one of the phones.
That's a better photo look at the size
of that fucking chimp.
I mean that thing is goddamn huge.
They have a,
there's a guy named Carl Amon who's a
Swiss wildlife photographer who set up
some camera traps and he got a picture
of one of them walking,
standing on the side,
the balls on that huge nuts.
Huge.
And that's not even a good picture.
That's a kind of a blurry picture.
There's some better ones have it.
But,
um,
it's an enormous chimp,
it's a like a subspecies that,
uh,
turns out to be,
enjoys walking upright as well.
They see the far right far right upper
upper deck.
Yeah,
that's the camera trap photo.
That's one of them walk,
go full screen on that,
uh,
does work.
That's one of 'em walking upright and
they said that fucking thing was six
feet tall.
Like that is an enormous chimpanzee.
But the point is this woman who said she
went to school for anthropology was
mocking this when we were talking about
it and I was like,
look,
I'm telling you,
I mean,
it's not something I'm making up.
I'm not going to fucking
cryptozoology.com
like this is national geographic.
This was,
you know,
like there's a bunch of different
scientists that are studying this thing
and trying to find out how many of them
there are and they don't have any of
them in captivity.
They don't know how many there are.
And it's a really dangerous part of the
Congo where it's warlords and fucking,
you know,
shootings and killings and rapings.
It's like he's a very dangerous spot to
get to and they're really,
but the point being when someone gets a
certain amount of information on a
subject and then they don't stay up on
it and they still want to cling to that
old information,
like this is all there is like you do a
real disservice to the other people that
you
to be the one who's the voice of
information.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
The fascinating thing is a,
I think it's starting to come around
though.
I have a buddy that just,
I'm just beat cancer.
He was a stage three lymphoma.
Whoa.
And he went in for his first chemo
treatments and you know,
you just get totally sick when you're
doing chemo.
And there was some research that come
out and talk about fasting prior to
chemo and how it helps with the,
with the therapy.
So he started fasting two days prior to
doing chemo.
So you do 48 hours and then go into
chemo and world of difference.
And so it was this doctor,
um,
put out a bunch of papers and you can
even watch the videos on youtube of
these rats fasting prior to chemo and
that the difference between the fast and
group in the non fasting group is like
night and day.
The group that fast,
it is like running around,
eating,
drinking afterwards,
like after they had the chemo treatment,
the other group is just on its side like
deathly ill.
Wow.
That's really crazy.
That's amazing.
There's benefits going into chemo too,
which is,
Rhonda was talking about that.
She was talking about Doctor Rhonda.
Patrick was talking about that there's
some pretty significant benefits,
not just for combating cancer but also
for dealing with chemo.
It's just amazing how many tinkers there
are out there.
Like Dr Dom D'agostino guys who are just
super fucking smart but also tweaking
their own body.
Like
if you had Peter Attia on the show yet.
No,
he's,
he's another one that,
uh,
what's his law?
Dr Peter Attia.
How do you spell it?
Uh,
I'd have to look it up.
Att I,
Yay.
So that he's been on a Tim ferriss show.
He's another body hacker slash kido
person.
Really,
really smart guy.
He was just on,
Rhonda is a podcast as well.
Oh,
okay.
I'll find them.
There's so many of those people out
there and I know these doctors that are
also into physical fitness and you know,
exercise is like,
one of the things about a Tim Ferriss
podcasts was dom d'agostino talking
about fasting for five days.
Then doing like 500 pounds of dead
lifts.
Just insane.
It's like what?
So crazy he would think of someone who
hadn't eaten in five days.
It just being a barely alive thing
clinging to life,
you know?
Yeah.
It's um,
it's really fascinating how we're
learning also that the body has a bunch
of different ways that it can acquire
food,
that it can acquire food through
carbohydrates or fuel rather through
carbohydrates or through fat,
you know,
or,
and it can go back and forth in between
those things and just the reaction that
your body has that we think is normal to
common everyday foods that are just
really fucking terrible for you.
But we all eat them,
you know?
And you know,
he could deal occasionally every now and
then.
But I didn't when I,
um,
when I really committed to it was when I
met Mark Sisson and I did the podcast
with him and I really started talking
about the,
when he really started talking about the
benefits of it and I just decided,
well,
it's worth a shot.
Let me just give it a shot.
And within five or six days,
I knew that this was going to be
probably the way I eat for the rest of
my life.
And
one of the things that really hit me was
how bad I felt when I wasn't taking in
sugar for a few days.
And I was like,
God,
have I got a headache?
I feel like shit.
And I realized,
Oh,
my body is addicted to this crap.
Absolutely.
Sugar is the devil.
It's so bad for us.
I mean,
just,
I,
I'm sure you keep up with the data as
well,
but just like every,
it feels like every few months was
another report that comes out and talks
about how toxic and evil it is.
But it's so yummy.
It is.
Yummy.
What have a fucking weird biological
trick.
Yeah,
but we never used to eat it like that.
We didn't refine it to the level that we
do now.
Well,
it's still,
I mean,
you know what's interesting too,
is it sugar is yummy and ice cream is
delicious,
but fruit,
fruit is like one of the best tasting
things you can get your hands on.
Like if you have a nice ripe peach is
one of the most fantastic things in so
underappreciated,
so underrated,
you know,
like that is the way you're supposed to
get your sugar.
It's really the only way.
Like if you really want sugar,
you're really supposed to eat like a
fresh orange.
Right.
And they taste amazing.
Like that should be our dessert every
night.
You know?
It's like,
it's just as good as chocolate cake.
It really is.
It's just you have it in your head.
The chocolate cake is that dessert.
You know that frosting and look at it,
it's moist.
I love chocolate and I've started to eat
100% chocolate,
so no sugar added.
But here's the funny thing,
the 100% chocolate that you've ever
tasted or anyone else out there has ever
tasted is the baker's chocolate.
It's the stuff that you get at the store
and it's made exclusively for baking.
It's super bitter and harsh and nasty
and burnt.
And the reason I was talking to a
chocolate maker,
this guy that owns a fruition chocolate
out in New York,
and he said,
well,
they just beat the hell out of it.
Like they overwrote it.
They don't,
it's not for consumption like that.
So they don't care.
He makes a hundred percent chocolate bar
that is actually palatable.
Like it's,
it's,
it's a ship.
What's it do?
They ship,
ship,
what's the name of the company?
Fruition.
And they make 100%,
uh,
no sugar added chocolate bar.
And I do,
you know,
like a little quarter piece of that.
And it's just,
you feel amazing.
Chocolate is a great,
it's a great little pick-me-up.
Has a little bit of caffeine in there as
well.
Well,
that's why it's bad for dogs.
Yes,
yes,
it,
I had to have my dog's stomach pumped.
I'm dead serious.
It's horrible.
My,
my poor little labradoodle.
Let's gone through raccoon attack and
everything else.
We live of those.
Sweet,
sweet.
Oh my God,
he's so friendly.
We left a,
I'm one of those uh,
chocolate bars,
the whole foods like dark chocolate,
like 80% and he just,
we came home in the rappers like all
over the floor and I'm like,
oh my God.
It's like I called,
I called the vet,
they're like,
bring him in right away.
Brought him down there two days in the
hospital on Ivy.
Whoa.
Like six times the lethal dose or
something like that.
I mean,
he's a small little labradoodle.
And did they put charcoal in the stomach
and we had to give him charcoal
afterwards.
Towels really brutal.
Well apparently just jacks your little
hearts.
Like that's what kills him.
The little harder.
Do seizures and they have all that.
So it's really bad.
And chocolate chocolate.
That's like the only saving grace of
like a Hershey's or something.
They're not really chocolate anymore.
They're like 2% or whatever.
You know when dogs,
when when I called they're like,
well what type of chocolate?
You know like,
cause if it's like a Hershey's bar,
they didn't want me.
They're like,
oh he might throw up but be,
well I don't know if it's Hershey's
bars,
but you know what I mean.
Like the lesser like almost all sugar
bars with milk don't have a ton of
chocolate.
Not like an 80% dark,
organic,
free trade artists,
anal bar from whole foods.
It's a whole nother level that's,
that's a real chocolate.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's,
that's a good chocolate though.
I love those things.
A little cocoa nibs,
you know,
the little nibs.
Tasty.
Yummy.
Yeah.
I tried to,
I'm just trying to avoid everything.
Sweet.
Other than fruit.
Yeah.
My,
so you do fruit in Ketosis?
Well it will not be sharing out.
I'll do blueberries.
Mangos occasionally they knock you out,
it'll definitely knock you out.
But it's not as bad as refined sugar
though.
It's fruit,
fruit toast versus secrets.
Right,
right.
But see,
I'm not necessarily a hundred percent
concerned with getting knocked out.
My concern was like what is the,
what is the Diet that my body functions
the best on?
How do I feel when I work out?
How do I feel?
Like just throughout the day and for me,
no sugar.
That's the big one.
Avoid all that.
No Pasta,
no bread,
cut all that stuff out and uh,
no rice.
When I do this,
do that.
I,
it doesn't seem to fuck with me too much
if I have like a pear or a little bit of
this,
a little bit in yogurt,
you know,
if you have like a large bowl of yogurt
and blueberries,
realistically you're getting too much
sugar,
you know,
but too much sugar for what it's not.
It doesn't fuck my body up.
Right.
But it's gonna knock me out of Ketosis,
but then I take exogenous ketones and I
should do,
because I want to get knocked out.
I'm in a slump.
He just take exogenous ketones.
Casino has his own brand now,
if the kid can have staff and now he has
his own brand.
Oh,
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
Key Key technics.
It can,
I just bought it.
I just had it delivered.
I haven't tried it yet,
but I've been doing Kido s which is
another company,
they need to come up with a seminar for
these products.
Like everyone's like,
what's the key to Cana?
I Dunno,
who cares?
I don't give a fuck with it.
Call it is poured in the water.
It's great,
but they taste good.
Yeah,
we can't count as good.
But I heard some of them are really jet
fuel.
He Nasty.
Quito s is fine.
I mean it's not the best taste and stuff
in the world like Gatorade,
but it's not awful.
Right.
It's fun.
It's just like I said,
my main concern is predominantly making
sure I'm eating healthy stuff.
Just making sure that I,
and then I also have to really vet out
some of the information when it comes to
increasing the Mitochondria in your
body.
Like is that all real?
I don't know.
And I need to find the pros and cons are
the detractors of these ideas because
there some of the things that system was
saying.
There was like,
Ooh,
I gotta,
I gotta look that up.
And Kyle Kingsbury,
who,
a friend of mine who's a former UFC
fighter is a very,
very smart guy who was also been Quito
for a couple of years now.
I have a few friends that are athletes,
like real high level athletes.
My friend Danny proper coast,
he's a former,
a Jujitsu world champion.
He's been ketogenic for the past year.
He's really dedicated and he takes that
a Kito Kana stuff,
but he's just a hundred percent
convinced that's the way it's the way to
go.
It's funny man.
How many people like fight like cats and
dogs about this online?
It's almost like a Mac versus pc thing,
you know,
I think it comes down to like,
just how you,
like you said,
how you personally feel on it.
Like for me,
I was always having that,
okay,
you know,
it's afternoon,
I'm in a slump.
I'm mentally a little foggy.
Like,
you know,
I attribute a lot of that too.
A lot of the refined carbs.
I was eating 100% and sugar.
You get rid of that stuff,
uh,
and you just,
you're just sharper,
sharp.
It's like,
you know,
like I said about the cold therapy and
the mood,
the 20% boosts,
it's like a 20% boost in just mental
clarity and sharpness.
Yeah.
For my own personal experience,
my own experimentation,
that has been the biggest factor.
The biggest factor has been cutting out
sugar,
cutting out sugar,
cutting out refined carbs,
all that had a massive positive benefit.
So then you know,
a little fruit in a lot of the,
I just don't,
I think fruit is your advice though?
My Vice.
You have anything?
Like,
do you ever do pizza every once in a
while?
No.
I mean,
like I said,
oh,
I went a good solid 55 days strict until
I went to Mexico.
And then when I went to Mexico I just
had some tortillas.
That was it.
Yeah.
But even then I chip seal bet.
But I tell you what,
man,
after I ate the Tortillas,
I had some dessert there when I was
there too.
I felt like shit.
Yeah.
Boy,
when you don't have it for,
you know,
almost two months and then you do have
it.
Like all my God,
it's like I ate a brick.
Did you skyrocket out with like some kid
can I like to have when he was down
there and bring any with me now I just
roughed it.
I just decided to look,
I'm going to be down here on vacation
with my family.
I'm just going to drink Margarita is and
go fishing and have a great time.
I'm like,
I'm not giving a fuck about anything.
I and I needed like a mental break
because I do,
I have like three,
essentially three occupations and um,
I managed them consecutively and it's,
they're all fun.
I enjoy them,
but I think that just the sheer rpms
that I'm operating at all the time needs
brakes on.
I'm learning as I get older to get
better at just shutting all that shit
down.
So I'm like,
I'm shutting everything down.
Are you good at saying no,
I'm great at setting.
No,
that's good.
I'm good at,
that's an piece of it is just saying no
to a lot of things.
After the last like four years,
I've gotten better and better at it.
I'm really good at that.
I see,
I say no one to like really good stuff.
He knows it.
So why do you ever look on your calendar
and think like,
Oh God,
I committed to that thing and I'm not
anymore.
I did.
I used to.
Yeah.
That was my entire career on fear
factor.
It's like,
fuck,
how is this thing still on the air?
Shit.
You know,
how many years was that on the air for
six years?
It's crazy.
148 episodes.
And then we came back and did it again
for six more episodes.
Um,
but yeah,
now I don't,
I do it less and less now.
Almost everything I do,
I really,
really enjoyed doing and that,
that helps.
That helps a lot if you can,
but it's hard.
It's hard,
you know,
for a lot of folks,
that's not where their money is.
Their money comes from things that make
them uncomfortable.
Yeah.
You know,
their money comes from things that they
don't enjoy,
but they just happened to be good at it
or understand really well.
It's,
it's such a treat in such a huge
blessing in life,
although I hate that word blessing.
But it's such a huge positive.
If you can find something you actually
enjoy and that is actually how you make
your living God so lucky.
So lucky to be able to do that because
so few people have that where they can,
the one thing that like they don't,
like today,
my day was I worked out and I said,
oh,
I'm going to go talk to Kevin Rose
today.
This is going to be fucking awesome.
I'm psyched.
So that's my day,
you know,
I mean,
there's no negative to that,
you know,
and then,
um,
you know,
go have dinner and it's like all normal
stuff.
It's like it to,
to have that as a job.
It's like,
it's beautiful.
Yeah,
I see that a lot.
You know,
I spent the last,
uh,
gosh,
probably eight years doing technology
investing,
um,
you know,
at Google ventures and a in on my own.
And,
uh,
the people,
the entrepreneurs that go after things
that they're really personally
passionate about,
they're the ones that actually win in
the end because they just,
when they have those shitty days,
it's not like,
ah,
man,
I got to give up.
It's,
it's their,
it's their baby,
it's their life's work and they can push
through that.
And that's,
that's,
I,
I find that,
uh,
that's,
those are the hard moments and only the
moments that you can get through if
you're truly passionate and into what
you're,
what you're doing.
Well,
I have a lot of varied interests,
but I also have a lot of,
uh,
interest in other people's interests
even if I'm not interested in their
interests.
What I mean is like if I'm listening to
a guy talk,
like say if he's like a,
he makes custom kitchen knives like,
and he's just really into it and he
talks to you about this
of steel,
it he uses and how he prepares the same
way.
I'm man,
man,
I'm in.
My last podcast was interviewing the guy
to talk about the absolute best paper
notebooks and we geeked out for like 45
minutes on like stationary.
What's the best?
The best is a couple.
Well,
domestically and fans most get it are
the worst.
They're the worst.
What's wrong with them?
You got to listen to my podcasts.
I can't do this anymore.
Multiple world's filled with lies to
mole skin.
They source their paper from China.
J A bad paper,
which I was bad.
The paper you write on it,
you could see what you wrote.
Now he goes a lot deeper than that.
Anyway.
Needless to say,
uh,
two brands out of Japan are the best.
Okay.
What are they a I'll forward you my,
my last,
it was in my,
I don't,
they're like mural stuff like that.
Is there any one that I can bother me?
Known her in the US?
So field notes,
field notes are,
and uh,
uh,
let's see.
It was a,
let's see,
there was one other,
um,
it was rough.
I'm going to,
what's the name of the sorts of the r
eight on the lovely mole skin?
How can you hate on this?
Look at this.
I mean it's a beautiful,
oh look,
I got a little rubber band at that.
That is super legit.
It's all marketing.
It's paper.
It's paper and you're right on.
I made with cancer and I says,
no,
I just made that up.
Sorry,
can,
I just didn't know.
How dare you.
There's nothing wrong with this.
This is a good little notebook and look
perfect size.
I liked that.
A rubber band thing.
Baron fig also domestically made with
it.
I know.
Check up there.
Can you pull a baron fig forum real
quick?
Baron fig.
Yes.
This is an awesome little book.
You're going to,
you're going to fall in love with it.
I don't know.
I'm all skin.
Oh look at this.
I'm all skiing in the wrapper.
Would you like this one and give it to
recycle it?
You should resign.
I can't believe you're most gang guy.
What's wrong with it?
Look at these.
There's baron fig,
the seer.
So click on the click on the confident
down a little bit further down.
A bunch of dorks don't really get
anything done.
Ooh,
hold on.
Got Pretty hand crafted from scratch.
Keep going.
Okay.
What am I looking at?
I've been,
it's flat.
You know how there's always that like at
that opens flat.
Okay.
I'm gonna see if this one opens right
away.
This is just maybe with some awesome
guys at in New York and see does open
flat but a high quality paper.
I'll work with any pen type that you
throw at it.
Um,
great dimension.
It's like,
it's just,
what's the name of this company again?
Baron fig.
Spell it.
Be a Roa.
Ron Fig.
This is one that I would say was the fan
favorite one that I pulled on.
All right,
I'll check it out.
They have all sorts of different sizes.
They have a little one like this,
like this.
Most candidates,
it fits in my pocket.
Also.
It's Rodeo is the one I was trying to
think of.
R H O dia.
Rhodia is the one that one his best,
not domestic pick or not domestic,
but just one that's um,
that's easy to find around very
stationery shops.
You know what I like to those ones with
the black and white speckled covers that
you buy at the supermarket?
I could,
oh,
those old school,
one of those kids are like in mead ones
like the,
well it's like a black band around the
edge.
What the fuck is those are those called
composition books?
Composition books?
Yeah.
Those are cool.
Those are okay.
I will.
It depends on whether you want,
the thing is at the end of the day,
none of it matters.
Like we're,
we're,
we're running on staples right now.
Who cares if you want them to stand the
test of time,
if you want them to be archival quality,
if you want them to work with fountain
pens,
it's Super Geeky.
I wasn't really into this town in Penn.
Lose my number.
I do not have fountain pen.
If you one of those guys with the
fucking a feather with a jug of ink on
your desk,
tap,
tap.
No,
no,
I'm not.
I do not have a fountain path to go.
I'm taking a calligraphy class at five.
Yeah.
There's something about really nice pens
that is attractive.
You like to geek out and stuff.
You were saying that,
that's why I brought it.
I'm only giving you a hard time.
I'm going to get 100% of the way.
I mean,
I could totally geek out about paper.
I Geek out about paper,
about coffee stuff.
Oh,
like he got about coffee.
Yeah.
Do you do your own at home?
My home.
What?
Pour-Over ports or pour over like where
you grind your own beans and you pour
water on top of it.
It's always okay.
Yeah.
I don't know which means you have like
a,
like a Chemex or no,
I use a French press.
Okay.
Let's find too,
it's okay.
I mean it's,
it's very nineties,
but that's right.
It works great.
I'm just kidding.
It's by this Guy Peter Giuliano,
who's a real legit coffee expert,
travel the world.
And uh,
he um,
you know,
he said French press is what he uses.
I think the aero press is great.
Uh,
I do the v 60,
which is what you got there,
Jamie.
Oh,
there you go.
Yeah.
This is a little clover station.
Is that from cane fan?
Caveman.
So Caveman coffees.
So one of the companies that we work
with company wow.
Locally sourced,
um,
everything comes from Colombia.
It's a single family,
single origin.
They uh,
get it in Columbia and then they bring
it to New Mexico process it,
very small company.
All these are made in Colombia.
All this stuff here is probably made in
New Mexico.
It's beautiful stuff.
It's awesome.
Well,
caveman coffees.
It's a buddy of mine's company and it's,
it's his passion.
My friend Tate and um,
uh,
Keith Jardeen and Lacey Mackey,
the other two people that are involved
in the company and they just,
it's a single origin,
single family,
single source company where they know
the people that are grown in this
coffee.
They go to visits also in Columbia.
It's like you're getting it from the
source and when you open up the
bag heaven,
the aroma of freshly roasted coffee and
it's got a roasted date on it,
you know,
they'll let you know when it was,
when it was picked,
when it was roasted.
Fantastic stuff.
There's a great coffee shop that I've
been to in Tokyo and it is this guy,
he's,
he's like a,
I call him like the Gyro of Coffee
Nocero this Sushi guy.
So he does something,
he ferments his coffee beans.
So he ferments them for I think three or
four months.
So they're not fresh and they're really
pungent and oily.
And then he does a 20 minute like water
pour over in front of you 20 minutes.
So they don't speak English.
You walk in there and all you can say
the hill,
understand his old beans.
And then he literally sits there for 20
minutes and does the slowest drip
pour-over you've ever seen in your
entire life.
And then it's done and he serves it to
you with like two hands.
Super a baby.
Like
it's a baby.
Wow.
He presented with the baby.
And how was it?
Phenomenal.
It's really good.
Did you pour sugar and cream courses?
Slaughter.
Did I put my ketones in there?
Well this is ketones.
No,
I know.
I just,
kido cream stuff is so sugar email.
Well it just,
it's got Stevia.
They wasn't be on the show.
I know,
but only has four grams of sugar per
share was like for me it was so sweet.
When you don't have sugar for or sweets
for a long time,
it just like really hits Ya.
Well I bought this stuff and I've never
used it.
It's one I was saying.
So I would say Jamie,
one day I'm going to use that and then I
don't fucking,
I just keep drinking this butter coffee.
Um,
have you ever had copied the walk?
No.
You don't know what that is?
Oh wait.
Yeah.
That's the stuff that shit's gay.
I've had actually like really?
Yeah,
that was really good.
I heard you're begin to bulletproof
coffee.
Well that's what this is.
No,
but the,
the brand bulletproof.
No,
no,
I'm just kidding.
Well that turned out to be kind of,
unfortunately,
that's name is a great name.
And Yell or Mark Formula,
which was created by Robb Wolf.
Really,
by the way,
I didn't know that.
Rob Wolfe wrote about putting grass fed
butter and mct oil and coffee in like
2004 or something like that.
Easy.
He wrote about and published it and well
that's that guy's ideas.
They're not all bad and some of them
aren't bad at all,
but the pride,
one of the things that Rhonda Patrick
had a correct does.
He gets things wrong about the science
behind things because he's sort of
reciting other people's work.
It's not actually doing work and he's
not really a scientist when it comes to
that stuff.
He's just a collector of ideas and then
redistributes them and puts that word on
them,
which is fine as long as you actually
hire a scientist like you know,
double and triple check everything
you're doing well.
The motors is a brilliant marketer.
Yeah.
The motivation was very deceptive
because is motivated.
He was trying to sell everybody on this
idea of mycotoxins and coffee's coming
here to band is completely abandoned
that.
Okay.
That was the one reason why you're
supposed to buy his coffee as opposed to
anybody else's.
Completely unsubstantiated.
And then we spend a shit load of money
trying to find out whether or not that
was true cause it's expensive to test
coffee for mycotoxins.
We tested all this different coffee,
random coffee,
you whole foods,
coffee,
starbucks,
bean,
coffee,
nothing,
nothing.
And then the more I talked to actual
coffee experts,
the more they're like no,
they figured out how to stop that in the
80s it's the difference between the
climate in Ethiopia,
which is an incredibly dry climate,
which is where all coffee comes from.
And this is another thing that we found
out from Peter Juliano.
All coffee came from Ethiopia,
all of it.
And then they started growing it.
And these other climates we can South
America.
When you think of Colombia and Juan
Valdez and the coffee,
well that coffee,
the problem with that is that that's a
moist environment.
It's a moist green,
lush environment,
not dry like Ethiopia.
So they would try to use this same
drawing methods and it didn't work cause
he's beans would get moldy and then they
would develop these molds,
toxins.
And so that became an issue.
But then they figured out a way to wet
process.
So the wet processing became the
solution for dealing with,
um,
the,
the mold issue.
They solve that a long fucking time ago.
So some of the single origins that you
can buy it,
some of the fancier places,
uh,
are still dry process.
I wonder if those with eop coffees.
Yeah.
Ethan Coke,
Ethiopian coffees are still very,
very popular and really delicious.
It's one of,
I think Juliano brought us in was your
guest chef.
How do you say it?
What does this stuff either Ethiopian
coffee,
your,
your chest.
Okay.
We're not gonna get it right.
I know which of the two of us,
but it was like a,
almost a sweet,
not sweet,
but a lemony.
Yeah,
I've had a,
Oh,
it's amazing.
Amazing.
Really,
really interesting stuff.
Do you have,
we have some.
We might.
Um,
but the,
the variables and the variations and
flavors,
I think it's really interesting how some
flavors it just have like who is like
bold,
almost like,
like dark taste to them and other ones
like almost like you're drinking
flowers.
What are you drinking these days to you?
Do you go and buy a certain brand or a
caveman signs is different stuff all the
time.
But uh,
cause it's my friend's company and I,
and,
and I know,
I know how ethical they are and how they
source it and how they have this great
relationship with this farm in Columbia
and it's all like direct relationship.
It's like it's,
to me it's the easiest way to deal with
it.
You know,
like,
and they have,
if you go to their website,
they explain how they do everything.
It's,
it's just awesome.
It's just the cleanest way to go about
it.
And they also have this nitro,
this nitrogenated coffee.
You ever heard of that at stumptown has
a cold night.
Tro.
Do you want to freak out?
I want to figure out right now.
You want to get,
feel like you want to run through a
fucking wall.
Give you one,
270 milligrams.
Caffeine.
Yeah.
Do we have any handy to have like a,
just a little taste or dot.
Drink.
A whole gallon.
Yeah,
man.
Bring you can do,
you can waste some of it if somebody's
been coughing a lot more.
You're already getting out a couple of
the groups I've been drinking this the
entire show.
Yeah.
We try to come up with a new name for
it.
Oh,
sorry.
His name then what do you call it?
It's called butter coffee,
but it's what it is.
It's coffee with butter in it.
Caveman nitro.
It's just too bad that the guy's a dork.
No offense.
I should've done that in front of the
mic or you could hear it.
But a lot of his products,
a lot of those bulletproof products,
it's still,
it's really mild.
They're still very good products like,
uh,
his,
grass fed whey and a lot of his other
stuff.
Nothing wrong with it.
That's great coffee.
That's great.
Right?
Yeah.
270 milligrams of caffeine in this
little tiny flank.
Ooh,
good Lord.
That's a lot.
A lot.
Normal Cup is like what?
One 30?
Um,
something like that.
Yeah.
I think a Venti starbucks is 200.
I think that's what we established.
This is,
I feel
so we're winding this bitch up.
It's about to end.
All right.
Anything to say before we go?
This is a lot of fun.
Yeah.
Thanks for having me.
Enjoy it.
Yeah.
If you're ever in town,
man,
open invitation.
Appreciate it again.
I,
it's,
I'm a,
I'm a fan watching your show.
Thank you.
And uh,
it's cool to actually be here cause he
normally see this stuff on video.
It's a weird,
since the space,
you guys have a physically here.
No,
I like it.
It's,
it's got a good vibe to it.
We've been here for a few years now.
I got to eventually buy a place and move
into it and try to recreate this or new,
something new,
I think.
Maybe,
but this is,
this has got little Buddhas over the
place.
Too many Tupac.
It's great.
CONOR MCGREGOR,
awesome.
Many conor mcgregor.
Many Tupac.
Yeah,
it's a good spot.
I'm enjoying it here.
Um,
you're not going to do your podcast
anymore.
You ever going to bring that back?
No.
Dig Nation is going to,
you know,
the fans want us to bring it back.
We had a lot of fun doing it the day.
Uh,
but I think that we'll get together at
some point and do it.
I see Alex lives here in La.
I see him every few months and it's just
a matter of trying to find a venue and
we want to do a live show if we're going
to do it.
Oh,
in front of an audience.
We see really crazy like 4,000
person live shows kind of nuts.
Why would you want to stop that?
Uh,
you know we did for so many years in our
show involves a lot of drinking and so
we were just like,
I killed my liver.
It was just like,
do you have to do drinking?
Why?
Cause that's kind of the show.
The show is two guys sitting on the
couch getting hammered talking about
dumb tech stories.
And it was just like,
it was our thing for so many years.
Um,
replace it with pot.
Uh,
I don't know.
I think we'd just be too dumb.
I just,
I don't love that you think would get
done.
You know what,
bring this note,
the Nitro does kate upper take Prasad
Totem Alpha brain neuro ones than that
from you before I let you get some.
Awesome.
Do we have any here?
Well,
I'll get you some either way.
Um,
figure out a way.
But yeah,
I'm doing the journal,
a newsletter,
a the journal.email
if you want to send up there.
And there's a podcast that goes along
with that.
Um,
and it's the most random weird guests on
it.
It's not,
there's no theme every month.
It's just something different.
Like who did notebooks and then Rhonda
Patrick that month before nine.
So it's like,
um,
I'll probably have tim on at some point.
If you're ever in New York,
I'll have you on something fun to do.
Okay,
awesome.
Cool.
Well thanks Kevin.
Appreciate it man.
It's a lot of fun.
Good to be on the show.
Thank you.
All right,
folks.
We'll be back on Thursday with Rick
Doblin,
uh,
the director of maps,
multidisciplinary,
something,
psychedelic studies.
He's a drunk guy,
an awesome drug guy,
a guy who's trying to promote the
legalizing,
very beneficial psychedelic compounds.
All right.
We'll be back soon.
See you much.
Love.
Bye.
Yeah,
thank you.
Yeah.