The joe rogan experience.
So we live in strange times.
Greg Proops.
It's amazing,
isn't it?
Exciting part is like I'm ready for
a lot of the old stuff to go away.
Yeah.
I think,
uh,
I mean I have tradition,
obviously I write with a
piece of paper and a pen.
Do you really?
Yeah.
I feel like I can't
write as fast that way,
so the ideas slip away from me,
but I do write it down before
I go on stage because when,
especially new stuff,
I feel like if I don't physically
write it down with a pen and a paper,
I don't remember it the same way.
I,
that's exactly what I was going to say,
Joe.
I've done a survey of every comic of
talked to him the last two or three years.
Every club I played,
I make everybody get their
book out and show me how I go.
Where do you keep your
ideas and everybody?
Yeah.
Book a little book with your lists on it.
Mine minor on hotel rooms,
stationary.
Thousands of them,
thousands of pieces of
paper I write and I say,
why do you do it that way?
Do you ever write it on your phone?
Yeah.
Uh,
if I think of a one line,
then I ride it,
you know,
did it today.
But do you write your Heloc to the phone?
No.
In the end I have to put it on a piece
of paper in red and I just think it's a
mental,
yeah,
that's the really old
fashioned part of performing.
I have a note lists of
set lists on my phone,
but I'll go to like right before I go on
stage sometimes if I want to make sure
that I remember some new
shit that I'm working on.
But when I write I go,
when are you going to that luck trance?
I can do that so much better
when I'm typing because I can,
the,
the words just appear like I
can type a word in a second,
whereas it takes,
but can you remember if you type no,
but I can write better so I get the
trance out and I can get more information
out as I'm writing.
But then I go back and I'm like,
fuck it.
Right.
That I remember writing that.
Like I'll,
I'll laugh at some of my
own shit and then I'll go,
okay,
I got it.
That I've got to keep that part.
Cause I don't even remember
writing because that'll
have five hours of writing.
How much do you actually remember?
But the act of actually
scribing it into a paper,
a piece of paper.
There's something about that that's like,
it just really like,
it just stores in your memory that's like,
it's like a,
we humans have been doing
it that way for so long.
It's like
it's been five,
seven,
10,000 years since people started writing.
Yeah.
I think it,
there's a real profound
connection with the paper.
Yeah.
Have you ever thought
about releasing those?
Like with your,
um,
like with a special,
like when you release a special
release your notes as well.
Wow.
No,
I haven't.
One time I did a fun
article for Filter magazine.
The guy came over to me and he said,
how do you,
he saw me fumbling with
my notes and I said,
it's all different pieces
of hotel stationary.
So I asked my wife to pick it and he goes,
well that will be the article.
Just I want a picture of these,
you know,
notes atlas.
And uh,
I said to my wife,
you pick it out.
I give her the folder full of shit.
So she picked out four random ones.
It was one from like,
Paris went from Minnesota,
one from one place.
I didn't remember being
terrible and somewhere,
you know,
and then there was another one
and then it just sad like Clinton,
you know,
uh,
corn,
whatever the fuck was on the list,
the Olsen twins and I kind of went
through the list as the article.
I just went like,
yeah,
I was doing Clinton jokes in Paris,
you know,
I,
well I think I slept.
Really,
it's always 92 when I rock the Mike Rock,
dumb luck or whatever,
you know,
like,
uh,
that there is a weird insight
into kind of like what's going on.
Exactly.
Then with all your setlist
cause the different notes
you make on them and stuff.
I don't know that there's a
that much to be garnered from,
I mean,
I could probably remember some
of the debts and stuff like that.
So just something that might be cool.
Like if I was a fan and I got it.
Yeah,
yeah,
definitely.
Just see my old song,
I put it up on design or something.
If you just put the photos online.
Well you ever see that?
A website called letters of note?
No.
Uh,
and there's another one,
something of note.
Um,
but letters of notice letters
people wrote to each other or even,
oh,
I think there's one called lists of note.
And um,
the list of note is just different lists
that famous people wrote or anybody you
know,
notable.
Like the one I remember
is Thelonious monk,
cause I read it on my show at the monk,
you know,
uh,
he had different mental
problems and stuff.
You know,
if you've ever seen him play like he
played and then he started to get up and
walk around the stage,
you know?
Yeah.
And he's extraordinary.
And then he was given drugs
and they didn't quite work out.
But anyway,
he's a genius.
And he could both compose and arrange
and extemporize and his band was,
you know,
of
putting the position of
having to deal with his,
his personality,
right?
Like,
cause he wasn't like a regular guy who,
who,
hey,
let's,
you know,
I'll be there at five,
he had to kind of be
pushed around to places,
but then when he could play was so he
wrote a note and on the net it's just how
do we address tonight,
sharp as possible.
Underlined.
Right.
And then,
uh,
if you're,
the drummer I think is something,
you know,
like there's all this
like really broken down,
like the thoughts you have
before you go on stage.
Like about the band and how he
wanted the band to play and look.
And I would,
I would read that out sometimes.
And so I would say on the show,
how do we adjust tonight?
Sharp is possible.
Oh yeah.
Right.
So there's lists of note
and there's letters of note.
And then at the last letter of note,
someone sent it to me,
uh,
was,
um,
Jackie Robinson went to a luncheon
or a dinner at Ike was speaking at,
right.
And Jackie was an executive.
Yeah.
Jackie Robinson was an
executive at chock full of nuts.
Coffee,
right?
Like he got a job in the corporate
world because he was an intelligent,
capable and famous person.
He became an executive,
a chocolate nuts in New York and
show he went to this like banquet and
Eisenhower Spec and it was a lot of black
people there who are in business and
Eisenhower said,
you've got to be patient,
right.
You'll chime will come and all that.
This is the city's.
Wow.
So Jackie wrote him a
very respectful letter,
but also very pointed about your patients.
You know,
and I'm not doing it any justice.
It was just,
you know,
Jim,
Mr President,
having recently attended the lunch,
or I have to say that on
behalf of myself and my race,
the time for patients is long pass.
You'll find that over the past
several hundred years we've endured,
but countless indignant,
you know?
Right,
right,
right.
And then the repository
is the next letter.
Eisenhower wrote him back,
do you Mr. Robinson,
thank you for your letter as I take on
board what you said and I profoundly,
you know,
Blah Blah Blah.
I'm like,
Oh wow,
this exchange in a very civil
and high faluting language,
not the language that we use now,
but like formal letter writing language,
uh,
with the idea of very explicitly expressed
that he no longer had the patients to
wait,
that he felt that why shitty weight.
Right.
And why should you have to go
to a dinner with the president,
told him to wait when even the first
fucking black guy in the big leagues and
they get a job and fucking
business and you know,
trying to run his life and shit.
Right.
Yeah.
And Eisenhower like,
he will,
you know,
one day schools will be integrated and
you want to have to drink it another
faucet and you know,
you don't want to hear that.
And so those kinds of letters I
think to me are like fascinating.
Yeah.
So letters you've known
enlisted node are quite good.
If you want to just,
you mean you don't have
to read everything on it,
but it's,
it's different letters to people
and to that's fucking bad ass.
Yeah.
I will check that nobody
writes letters anymore.
In,
in future it will be your setlist of note
and your emails of note and your blog
of note the probably be a letter.
Yeah,
it's going away.
The physical act of writing is going away.
If I didn't have to write my set lists
down or occasional like fill out a form,
like when I go to Canada
or something like that,
I wouldn't,
I don't really write anything.
I do.
I mean,
I read it,
I write on my computer,
but I write in a book
too because it's fun.
You're a fucking human being.