I get the comedy store,
never cashed the checks.
So how'd you get into comedy?
We are alive.
We'll answer bad childhood.
Everybody's freelance.
If you didn't get into that for that
reason,
you probably have a shitty act.
Yeah.
That is so true.
Because it lets you,
it lets you weren't seen as a child or
heard as a child and have this
insatiable need to be seen and heard and
understood.
It's definitely a deficit.
You can't be funny.
Dude.
What the fuck were you doing in Vietnam?
Because this is one of the reasons I
didn't want to talk to you about this
before that I didn't want to see you
before this.
I just wanted to get you in and I'm glad
we didn't talk about it before,
but I went to your instagram page and I
saw these pictures of you working with
these children that have cleft palates
and I saw these photos of you in
Vietnam.
So tell me what are you doing?
Um,
so there's this charity called Operation
Smile and I'm usually working in animal
charities because people I think are
usually the problem.
And I had been helping people just seems
to make more proliferate and uh,
and in terms of charity stuff,
like I think that just why I started
wanting to get more involved as like,
I'm going to be perfectly honest,
I started not liking the person that I
was.
I started realizing I was the person who
was like,
God traffic.
It's like crazy today.
Like,
oh my God,
starbucks is out of soy milk with the
puck.
Like I was just like,
whoa.
That is jus.
What did,
what,
what made you feel like you were going
to a place that you didn't like or
becoming a person in life?
I think it's like,
um,
you know,
doing like working with animals and
like,
you know,
going to sort of,
um,
parts of town that I wouldn't normally
go to to rescue animals and dogs.
You start going like,
oh,
there's a real world outside this.
Truman show that we live in of the fake
sets and the fake this and the fake
people and the fake,
you know,
makeup and the fake close every.
And I was just like,
oh,
like that.
I live in a fun house,
you know,
sometimes when you're in this business,
I mean,
stand up keeps me,
you know,
a real person because TV shows that get
you.
I think it's TV shows,
I think it's writing fake scripts about
fake people and fake lots and fake
houses and you know,
fake edit bays.
And uh,
I just was like really?
I'm concerned about and knowing,
you know,
way more than I do,
but then what I do know about neurology
is that our brains acclimate to whatever
environment we're in.
And I was like,
I'm in this environment all the time.
My brain is just going to start
acclimating accordingly.
Right.
So it's like,
you know,
I find it a little ways,
like,
you know,
if I,
uh,
if I have a small purse,
I only need a small purse.
If I were a big purse,
all of a sudden I filled it up with
shit,
you know,
it's like you kind of acclimate to what
you have a.
and so I was like,
um,
yeah,
I don't,
I don't like the things that come out of
my mouth.
I don't like my inner monologue.
I don't like the fact that I get annoyed
when,
uh,
you know,
my uber is,
not on fucking time.
Like I just,
I was like,
so I kind of wanted to get some
perspective and like really get out
there and not just like giving money for
my own selfish,
like guilt,
like I'm just going to give money.
And so I went to Vietnam for two weeks
and did this.
Um,
I went to Tokyo for a couple of days
before then,
which was actually really interesting.
Uh,
and uh,
when I got to,
you know,
wash the surgeries and uh,
it was also cool because I don't know if
you are at this ever went through this,
but um,
I think I got sick of myself.
Like I just kind of was like,
I'm sick of my voice.
I'm sick of my making jokes.
I'm sick of being funny.
I'm sick of like.
And uh,
there's something about being around
people that don't speak English,
that kind of strips you of your persona,
you know,
of your,
all the things that you.
Just because some.
I mean,
I,
I just,
I don't want to go through life like a
sleep walking Zombie who's just like
doing a bad impression on myself every
day because it's so easy to do and I
find,
I felt like life was a little bit
groundhog day bud,
get up,
workout jokes,
jokes,
bits,
you know,
insecure,
and I got a little bit sick of that
rhythm and I was like,
there's gotta be something more deeper
and uh,
you know,
were seekers and I was like thinking
about my next special and the next thing
I'm going to write.
And I was like,
I don't want to just.
And I felt like my brain was,
had this,
there was like patterns and rhythms that
I was like,
I keep going to the same place for
creatively.
And I was like,
I want to go to a different place
entirely.
So I got to like challenge my brain and
throw some new shit at it.
Um,
and being around people that don't speak
English is really,
first of all have no idea who you are,
which is another experience when you're
used to people knowing who you are and
having expectations of you and thinking
you're going to be funny or you know,
when you're known,
all of a sudden you have the power
whether you wanted or not in a room,
you know,
you walk into a room and you have the
power whether you're interested in
having it or not,
you just do,
right?
Joe Rogan walks in,
everyone's like,
be cool and everyone's trying to impress
you.
Everybody changes,
right?
So you never get to see people's
authentic self because you inherently
affect them with your presence.
You know,
there's some,
I can't remember the,
a term in science where it's impossible
to measure the thing because the
measuring tool affects the amount.
Is that.
Yeah,
exactly.
So you never know how people really are
because your presence actually affects
them.
But if they've never heard of you,
which in Vietnam known for me,
not a lot of fans over there.
And,
uh,
so you're just like,
you know,
you can't rely on any of that shit that
we've become used to relying on.
Um,
and talking to people that don't speak
English,
all of a sudden you're like,
oh,
I can't use all my goto strategies,
charm,
manipulation,
jokes,
like no one cares.
Um,
and so it was really pretty,
pretty cool.
Um,
Vietnam in general,
we'll talk about,
I'm sure you have your thoughts on Asia.
I'm mine,
I think are kind of probably going to be
polarizing and get me in trouble because
I think it's a fucking mess over there.
But there's also,
I think that when,
you know,
I mean,
you have kids,
you have more of a insight into what's
real and what's not.
Like.
I also noticed that when,
um,
both of my parents had strokes,
which was awful obviously,
but I liked the person I became after it
happened.
Like I was like,
all of a sudden when something tragic
happens to you,
things become clear.
Your priorities become clear.
If someone asks you to go to lodge that
you don't want to hang out with,
you said,
no,
you're not like,
sure.
I guess I'll switch.
Like you're just.
Everything becomes very black and white.
Do I want to do this?
Do I not?
Is this an effective use of my time?
It's just not.
Um,
so I was like,
Oh,
if I just exposed myself to a little bit
more,
not tragedy,
but maybe you know,
um,
and stop hanging out with a bunch of
people with fake problems and hang out
and surround myself with real problems.
Then maybe I'll stop thinking I have a
bunch of problems I don't really have.
I always love talking to you because
you're probably one of the most
ruthlessly introspective people I know.
Really?
Yeah.
You don't,
you don't think you are,
you don't see,
you're pretty brutally introspective.
I just,
I thank you.
um,
I don't want to be as somby.
I don't.
Most people are just sleepwalking
through life and uh,
that does not happen.
Yes ma'am.
Do you have,
you had very many psychedelic
experiences.
You know,
what I have
event and I was going to do Iowasca last
year,
but I had been on antidepressants and
yeah,
and I only went on them.
It's such a bummer and I'm actually want
to talk about this in my next special
because they were,
they were given to me because I was
having trouble sleeping.
I had insomnia,
which I recently learned about how
insomnia it sort of came about and it's
actually really important.
Um,
and I wish that there were doctors out
there who studied shit like that,
like insomnia.
Usually people are insomniacs fucking
thousands of years ago,
people in the tribes,
like tribal life before streetlights and
alarm systems.
There were people who were responsible
for staying up all.
Everybody else slept.
They were like,
they called the night watchers
basically.
And nightwatch would breed with night
watchers and s essentially.
So you're a nightwatchman.
I could be,
that could be my.
Because you know,
there's some people who are like,
I just can't fall asleep till three in
the morning.
I know who never says that.
Who Farmers was never say that actually
fucking work true.
Do to dig holes all day today.
I know the most I'd employed people.
They're like,
oh,
I cannot sleep.
It's again because you haven't done
shit.
Fucking well.
Yeah.
You have three kids,
right?
I feel like my insomnia is going to go
write something there.
I feel like as soon as I have kids or
something,
mine's off.
It'll probably still stay there.
Really?
Oh,
I guess I'll be a mother so I'll never
sleep the.
That's an issue,
but it's also a mental loop thing.
Like if you go to bed and you have a
mental loop,
like,
oh,
I gotta get this.
I gotTa fucking get my shit together.
I really have to do this.
I really got to start this diet and
really going to start a journal.
There's a book that I need to write.
I know I need to write it.
I need to fucking start.
Should I get out of bed right now and
start writing it and then that loop will
fuck with you and keep you up.
Especially someone like you who's so
hyper ambitious,
you always have like 15 irons in the
fire
and you've got a fucking fireplace,
bellows.
You're stoking and you're on the phone
at the same time.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We'll do that.
We'll definitely do that.
We've almost got like too many points of
focus where I imagine that your brain
getting down to a neutral point,
it probably has a very difficult time.
Yeah,
and I've also done a couple things,
but also our brains are not designed to
see the amount of light that we see.
Like we're like the screens and our
phones,
like our brain produces cortisol.
When they see it,
it's like,
wake up.
Our brain thinks our phone is the sun
basically.
Wake up.
Have you seen the new feature on iphones
were turns it down at 10:00
PM?
You could set it.
No,
but mine is now in black and white.
Oh Shit.
Just going back to go back to the phone.
Black and white fucking typewriter.
If someone sends you a picture,
then it's,
you know,
it's gonna be very hard to see.
How did you give her your phone?
I've turned a black and white because
you do that.
I didn't even know that was a of
settings.
Yeah,
because the colors in your phone,
a trigger,
a bunch of chemicals to be released in
your brain that actually activate you
and entered entered.
So ironic.
You have a flower as your backdrop.
Flower,
black and white.
See what the fuck George O'keeffe.
I mean our big.
Yeah.
That.
Yeah,
that's a really.
That's an octopus vagina actually that
flower.
But yeah,
I'm super into a like,
you know,
just if you understand how the brain
works,
you can usually hack,
get a little bit.
So it's like when you look at your
phone.
So my phone,
I actually,
I used to be so addicted to it.
Now I just have no interest in it
because it's black and white.
It's just like,
it's not giving me the dopamine and the
chemicals that you know.
Really?
Yeah.
Color.
What color?
Turning your phone black and white makes
it less attractive to you?
Less addictive.
Whoa.
Yes,
because I'm like phone,
phone,
and a lot of it is just the color,
so it's just like,
oh,
cortisol.
Adrenaline read produces adrenaline and
cortisol,
dopamine,
and then I'm just like,
no.
I'm just like,
ugh.
It's so.
What is the setting?
How have you changed?
You go to.
I'll tell you.
Hold on.
I'll never do it.
By the way.
Why not try it?
Try it for a day because I'll have a
little thing called discipline didn't
see.
I just want to have sex with that now.
I can't do it.
Can't do it.
Listen,
it's not easy and I've learned how to do
it.
I've learned how to do it so.
But I've rules that might not be your.
What gives you dope?
Me.
Oh No,
it is.
No,
look,
I could sit down there.
I get up in the morning and take a shit
and I'll look at that thing for fucking
three hours.
What are you looking at?
Reading?
I'm reading articles that I don't need
to read.
I'm fucking just becomes like a cancer,
but what I do now is if I do it,
I look at the important stuff.
I'll go over,
do I have any work emails that are
pertinent to check my work?
Email?
Yeah.
There's nothing to deal with.
Do I have any text messages that are
other I need to deal with?
Nothing to deal with.
Yeah.
Shut it off,
put it away,
walk away.
You and I though might have a different
idea of what I need to deal with them,
but I doubt I sometimes,
you know,
get sucked into stuff that's completely
unnecessary and frivolous.
That's also an addiction.
I'm texting about a fucking baby shower
that I'm not even going to and I'm just
like,
what am I doing?
You know,
I'm difficult to get ahold of your,
but you're very self contained.
I'm a little more and I'm in recovery.
We talked about it for codependent,
so I sometimes struggle with the
discomfort or perceived as comfort of
others,
so I feel like I need to take care of
people's feelings sometimes.
So it's harder a caretaker and a lot of
ways.
That's why you love dogs,
dogs and dogs.
Only the voiceless.
Only people.
Only like people that are can't help
themselves.
If you can help yourself and you didn't,
that's not my problem.
I've learned over the years that I only
have a certain amount of,
not just time,
but a certain amount of focus and that
the less focused I give two things that
I'm not really interested in,
the more focused I'll have for things
that I am interested in.
Yeah.
It's like a real issue with my manager
because I just fucking vanish for days.
I don't answer phone calls.
Jamie,
I just got the same thing.
I had the same thing just happened with
a manager who hadn't heard from me
because I went to Vietnam and I got back
and I was just like.
I recently learned that when someone
calls or texts you don't have to
respond.
Like I,
you know,
I think we get in this obligatory sort
of thing.
We have to respond to everything and it
was actually interesting going to Japan
because that culture is,
so.
I'm using this word probably a
inappropriately,
but for lack of a better word,
codependent,
it's so like having to take care of
everybody's feelings.
Like I was talking to this guy on a
plane.
There's so much respect for other
people's feelings and status.
I went,
I'm on the plane on the way over.
I sat next to the super interesting guy
who creates a tools for animators,
like I know like the stuff that makes
cartoons,
like I,
I can't even,
I don't even have the vernacular to
explain it.
Um,
but he said it's really hard to do focus
groups in Japan,
you know,
focus groups is when you go around and
say,
is this working?
Is this not working?
Right?
Because no one will respond until an
elder response and everyone just agrees
with the elder.
You're not allowed to disagree with
someone older than you.
Uh,
which was,
uh,
there was an article about the,
um,
a lot of the,
I think it was a couple Malaysian
airline flights that went down.
They say it was pilot error because the
copilot was afraid to disagree with the
pilot.
The pilot was wrong,
but because of the inherent respect for
your elders thing,
he couldn't say like,
dude,
we're going to crash if you can do that.
And the plane went down.
So it's so interesting.
And I came back and I was like,
Oh God,
at least I'm not.
And I mean in,
I mean I think I was a little bit
horrified,
not a good word,
the right word.
Saddened by this culture of like,
shame over there.
We have it in different ways,
but it's like if you disgrace your
family,
you just jump off a building.
I mean it's just.
And
there's so many people were jumping in
front of trains that the only way they
could get them to stop jumping in front
of trains when they shame their family
was saying if people jump in front of
trains,
we're going to bill your family for the
cleanup.
So that got them to stop because they
were like,
well,
why don't my family to have to get this
bill?
Because that will disgrace them even
more.
So they had to use their shame against
them as a way to get them to stop
committing suicide.
I mean,
apple in China,
apple had to put nets around the
building.
So many people were jumping off it.
Well that's a real issue in and unto
itself because Apple's paying these
people and they're living in this
building,
paying dog shit.
I mean,
they don't have these factories over in
China because it's an awesome place to
build phones.
They have these factories over there
because they could pay people virtually
nothing and have them work all day.
China,
I've been to China before just in
general,
like,
and I'm,
and I want to come from a judging place
because we obviously have our problems
in the states,
but uh,
it was just a really.
I feel like when I went over there and
was like,
Gosh,
you're just going to love it.
Like everyone's,
like,
India is amazing.
It's like it's really poor and people
die of dysentery and yeah.
And there's,
you know,
I'm a baby girls or have their head
smashed on rocks because of the dowery
system.
I mean it's like there's,
you know,
I feel like there's this.
Yeah,
there's a documentary on I guess itunes.
It's about infanticide in China and
India because the dowery system.
So basically to have a child is a
fortune.
I've had time,
sorry to have a female because you have
to pay someone to marry her.
She can't work at your dad's family.
And she's basically just like a
financial drain,
um,
which is just terrifying.
So that goes on in China.
Still a terrifies me is that that's
probably an ancient way of thinking and
behaving.
So like we look at today and we look at
this world that we live in today and
obviously we have a lot of issues with
equality and we have a lot of issues
with racism.
We have a lot of issues with homophobia,
but whatever issues we have are nothing
compared to the,
the echoes of our past.
And when you look at something like that
and when you know,
there are hate crimes,
that's an individual person against an
individual person that's not like a
socially accepted thing.
Smaller the Nazi,
I'm not endorsing hate crimes,
but if you know someone,
a beats up a gay guy,
most people think it was bad that he did
that and they go to jail.
But it's one person who's fucked up,
not entire country.
That's like,
yeah,
that was a good idea.
The last echoes,
the last reverberations that our way is
better.
I'm not saying you guys have to become
America,
but it was just a little bit like,
oh,
this is like,
well,
I like fact that they're not America.
I liked it.
There's all these different cultures
because I think it's fascinating that
there's different parts of the world
where people have figured out a
different way to behave and they follow
this different pattern.
They've carved this groove and all the
young people follow into this groove,
give or take,
and I think that's amazing.
I mean when you look at different parts
of the world and you experienced their
culture or you look at how they're
behaving and how they dress and how they
speak and how they live their lives and
their traditions.
It is absolutely fascinating.
These patterns of repeatable behavior to
repeating,
repeating patterns that exists all over
the world and that they're so different.
They're different in Thailand and then
they are in Germany.
Totally different parts of the world are
associated with like having more humor
or less,
more or more,
you know,
more discipline or more artistic
freedom.
It's,
it's,
it's so and it's.
And then,
you know,
I mean I always forget how young of a
country we are.
I mean we are a minute old compared to a
lot of these countries do you now,
so this is,
they have thousands of years of history
that we don't have and,
but it's like how can you hold on to the
really cool traditions and patterns and
then release the more backwards once and
evolve and grow,
you know,
it's like,
it's just wild.
I mean in Vietnam and it from Vietnam is
so beautiful you're going to love it.
And I was like,
yeah,
it's definitely beautiful.
But I see poverty and air that no one
can breathe.
Everyone's wearing masks because they
can't inhale.
There's no emissions regulations.
Everyone's on.
Like,
I was like,
oh right,
white trust fund.
Kids are like Vietnam,
beautiful.
And they say because they can come back
to,
you know,
Williamsburg,
Brooklyn or whatever.
That's the thing that why people love
talking about Brown people being
amazing.
It's like look like you're not a better
person because you think Vietnam is
amazing.
Me Just admit that it's,
it's in.
We need to.
I mean,
I know we,
we fucked it up a lot of,
it's our fault of what we did in the
seventies,
but it was like,
it was,
um,
gave me a lot of anxiety,
you know,
because it was like,
I mean,
it was just like the hospitals.
we were in a hospital and you know,
we needed four of this machine that puts
babies to sleep.
Pediatric anesthesia is very different
than regular anesthesia and it's
essentially bringing people to the brink
of death and then bringing them back.
It's like incredibly fascinating a job.
And they had one of the machines that
they need the pediatric
anesthesiologist,
like we need four and they're like,
we don't have,
we just don't have them in this country.
We just can't do surgery on babies.
It's just not in our purview.
It's not own our,
you know,
so.
So back to,
to the,
you know,
the kids come in with cleft palates and
cleft lips,
which the baby is essentially,
they have trouble breastfeeding.
It's um,
and cleft palates just,
you know,
just kind of this opening here in a
separation as a malnutrition in the
womb.
It's,
yep,
exposure to genetics,
uh,
exposure to pollution.
I'm sure all that napalm we dropped in
the seventies didn't really help.
Uh,
but yeah,
and in America it still happens,
but it's handled right away.
It's handled.
It comes out three months later.
It's fixed,
no big deal over there.
Sometimes it's never fixed.
And when you see adults,
you see men that are 50 come in with
giant,
giant cleft lips and palates and
they've.
And it's even worse in third world
countries,
especially African countries because
there's such a stigma attached to it.
Not only is it,
you know,
in our brains to go,
like he's different than me and
ostracized or stigmatized someone,
but I'm a lot of more religious
countries.
Think you're the devil or your,
you know,
you can't get a job.
You're completely sequestered.
You're thrown out of your family.
And you know,
and I think,
and this is gonna sound Super Corny.
Um,
but I guess for me,
I,
I connected so much to maybe it's
because we're comedians.
I was like,
look,
life,
if you.
It's one thing to grow up in a third
world country.
It's another thing to deal with poverty
and stress,
but if you can't smile like the basic,
the only real medicine we have,
you know,
everybody has universal medicine of like
laughing and smiling.
That's how we connect to people.
It's,
I mean,
that's fucked.
Like that was frustrating and uh,
it's so easy to fix.
That's the other thing that's
frustrating is it takes like 30 minutes.
You're Joaquin Phoenix.
Look at Joaquin Phoenix
it.
Yeah.
He has a cleft lip.
Think Stacy Keach.
Isn't it weird that Joaquin Phoenix got
it mean he's like a
be genetic.
I mean,
yeah,
but also America has its history was
fucked up.
Shit,
you know.
Um,
you know,
we're by no means squeaky clean.
I mean,
we're exposed to a lot of.
We are the exact Mirka Mirka.
Um,
uh,
you'll like this.
Well,
we talked,
we talked about this last time,
just sort of like how we essentially
always had to drink alcohol when before
we had pottable water,
people were just,
you know,
what people drank wine and of those
flats they carried around to keep from
getting travelers disease for water.
That's what he would call it.
Yeah,
so it's completely,
um,
so yeah,
what people were such assholes who were
just hammering,
everyone was hammered.
I mean actually when you think about it,
it's a miracle that someone.
I mean Ford built a car,
like it's like as if you were sober,
you got to be like Rockefeller.
Like I feel like the couple people who
were sober just basically became like
the biggest sober people who drink
coffee.
It literally took over the world,
uh,
because I mean everybody was shit faced.
Um,
but yeah,
so it's crazy.
I mean,
have you ever seen a surgery?
I love it.
I've never been in the room,
have had a bunch of surgeries,
but I've never been in the room.
I've had one,
two,
three,
three joints.
Yeah,
mostly.
Mostly joints.
My nose were constructed.
I have had
my knees done.
Thank you.
What was in it was internal,
more like,
I would never know.
Externals so fucked up.
It's all broken up in here.
It's like there's all these sharp edges
underneath.
His skin would break open pretty easy
because is it cartilage on the end and
then bone up here.
This is all cartilage,
this stuff is all pretty much intact,
but the inside of my nose that was all
smashed and so it was all closed off.
I didn't have any,
any breathing out of my nose.
No till I was 39 and you're like,
yeah,
my whole life.
I couldn't be that in my nose.
No bullshit.
I fell down a flight of stairs when I
was five and I broke my nose pretty bad
when I was five.
A cement flight of stairs,
a smash my nose and get you an operation
smile.
Well,
it wasn't just my parents just like,
ah,
yeah,
he's alive.
I'm alone.
Like there was Dr Tripp's.
I broke my arm.
My Mother didn't believe me.
I had to lift it up and it was like up
and down.
It was so broken and then she's like,
break dancing.
It's just,
you know,
back then it was just a different world.
Like people were basically like monkeys,
you know?
My parents were like,
monkeys,
they're like,
monkey have the Internet.
Don't touch that.
Don't understand things now.
Yeah.
But I think there's a little bit of a
pendulum swing to the other way of
helicopter parents.
You.
There was um,
I was reading this thing about how this
designer who's making more dangerous
jungle gyms for kids because they've
gotten too safe.
So the daughter broke her arm of jungle
gym.
Yeah.
You should call this person.
They're not,
they're not safe.
Like jungle gyms are just more
challenging or something like,
I don't,
I don't remember.
Like it was something about real problem
with jungle gyms is you need to
understand what your capabilities are
and the only way to find that out as to
fall.
You're falling on these metal bars.
You could fucking die.
Like kids that break their arm easily.
Kids don't die all the time.
Or they do know they do.
Kids die all the time.
When you have kids,
you sort of pay attention to that kind
of shit and you realize like,
oh,
kids fall on their head and die.
Like it happens all the time.
If you're not paying attention and the
kids get,
they don't understand boundaries and
limitations and physical as a parent
because I'm obsessed with this because
I'm already like,
I'm not too close to having a
child.
I froze my eggs.
So if anyone wants to send some sperm,
Jamie,
now that you're getting,
now that I'm,
now that I'm learning about your,
that's why I'm asking where are you
from?
Okay.
Where are you from?
Slovenia.
Indiana will come in a cup for it.
I'm really just trying to ascertain
everyone's like DNA and how strong it
is.
But uh,
is that um,
I'm reading.
I just read a book called the continuum
concept,
which is like a parenting saying about
like babies.
They can be held by anyone.
It doesn't have to be their mom
necessarily,
but maybe we should always just be being
held and sort of were designed to men
and women kind of weren't supposed to
live together like we're supposed to
kind of fuck.
And then you go off and then all the
women lived together and help raise all
the kids.
Um,
so uh,
uh,
so there was something interesting in
that because I'm the first three years a
childhood's a,
I'm sorry,
a child's ability to believe in their
own faculties essentially to trust other
people and to feel like they're are
heard and seen.
Depends on how much eye contact and
physical touch they get.
Wow.
Yeah.
Cause basically touching is going like
you,
I see you,
you're here,
you know,
and the less touch that eye contact they
get,
the more invisible they feel and the
date more dangerous they feel the world
is for them.
Oh yeah.
And there's this great.
You'll love this.
I'm John Bowlby's theory of attachment.
Like when babies crawl,
it's the same as for noble apes is
they'll crawl a foot and then the look
back and see if dad still looking at me.
He is,
I'm going to call another foot.
He's still there,
right?
Babies turn around and check in and then
if on the fourth foot I turn around in,
data is looking at his phone,
I go,
that's as far as I can go.
And then it's dangerous after four feet,
that's as far as I'll go where he'll
still be there for me.
So then we also are sort of world in
comfort zone is designed based on when
your child loses your eye contact.
So I've just been sort of learning about
that,
especially in lieu of like cell phones
being the new alcoholism for kids.
I feel like parents
just on their phone while their kids are
on the playground.
Yeah,
it's,
it's crazy.
It's,
it's amazing how many people just don't
pay attention to anything but their
phone.
I mean I see it constantly and I see it
when people are by themselves.
I see it when people with their
families.
I see when people with their friends.
How many times have you gone to a
restaurant?
You see a table full of people and
everyone's on their phone and no one's
talking to the people right in front of
them.
Did have you done like colleges
recently?
I stopped.
I stopped more than a decade ago.
Wow.
I stopped.
Uh,
I think I did.
University of Miami was the last one I
did.
I did with Joey Diaz,
I think the coconut Grove Improv.
Just.
Yeah.
Oh,
thank God they closed because there were
so many fights breaking out.
It was so bad.
I literally told them that I would never
work.
Here again.
I go,
you people are so dominant over work
here again.
And they were laughing.
I got you laughing.
I go,
I'm serious.
This is the dumbest fucking audience in
the country.
I watched a guy do cocaine.
I was opening for like Steve Byrne or
some like Craig's shoemaker,
like someone,
someone was opening for like 10 years
ago and someone was doing cocaine on the
table while I was on the call.
I believe it will they.
What happened with that place is they
started giving away free tickets and
when you give away seconds.
Yep.
Fuck yourself.
Always,
always.
Those are bad,
but you paper the room,
you get terrible audiences.
So
for awhile I was trying to give free
tickets to people who couldn't afford
them,
so I'd always say my comps,
like I have 10 comps in like the middle
of nowhere.
This actually happened in La Jolla and I
would tweet out like,
hey,
so if you can't afford to come to the
show,
send me an email telling me why and I'll
get you tickets and I would check it
myself,
you know,
the Whitney Whitney,
some email and one time this guy emails
me just a testament to exactly,
you know,
give an inch,
take a mile and emails me and gives
me this long story.
He's a vet,
you know,
he's in a wheelchair,
he can't drive down,
he's going to have to get a cab and he
can't afford to come.
And the,
you know,
the health insurance that health
insurance is a joke and I'll all this
whole thing.
I was like such a no brainer.
I was like,
Yep,
you got it.
Two tickets can't wait.
And literally he started the email with
like,
this probably isn't even you.
So Whitney's assistant like,
you know,
no problem and I'm such a big fan and
Dah,
Dah.
All right,
back to tickets.
All set.
Don't hear back from him at all.
I'm not checking it again.
Right before the show,
I'm looking through my emails.
It's 7:45.
The show's at eight.
I can email back from him.
Hey Babe.
Hey Babe,
I'm running a little late.
I'm running a little late and where do I
park?
It went from like Ajit,
like total,
like all and like respect and adulation.
You're probably not even going to check
this and like I'm sure this will never
have to.
Like I became his assistant.
It's a microcosm of a relationship.
He was courting you.
Then he got me and like went from
literally and then I was like,
oh,
okay.
You know,
do you need me to come out and meet you
in the dynamic?
Totally switched.
It's like as soon as you give someone
something for free,
they stop respecting it.
Well,
you have,
it's,
it's hard when you're communicating with
someone just through email because you
have to sort of ascertain,
is this person crazy?
Is this person Super Nice Person?
Completely delusional.
Is this email going to be received
in the way that I intended it?
Okay.
Is it gonna?
Be like,
Hey,
nice talking to you.
Glad you liked the show.
Appreciate it.
Good though.
So what do you.
Oh,
that's cool.
You do that.
That's interesting.
Well,
Hey,
nice talking to you.
Is it going to be just like,
oh,
I had a cool conversation with a guy,
or is it going to be open up the door to
a wacky person now?
The wacky person as Whitney Cummings.
Yeah.
Oh,
he still emails all the time.
Hey,
let me know next time you're in town.
I mean,
it's like.
And he behaves as if I'm doing him a
favor.
I also had a great,
um,
a Heckler,
a guy that I got front row seats and
like paid for everything.
Started heckling.
It's always the people you come tickets
for.
This isn't La Jolla lawyers always,
you know,
it's very sketchy.
It's such scheduled.
There's no fucking.
All the security guards are open to
anyone.
Bless their hearts.
They're stoned out of their fucking
minds.
Like,
I mean,
it's just,
it's so unsafe.
It's.
And there's a lot of tension down there.
I don't know if it's because there's the
navy's down there or there's a lot of
militaries that,
it,
there's a of money.
There's a lot of entitlement,
beautiful area,
but for some reason the Hoya,
it's like always,
I don't know,
there's always a fight.
There's always a fucking girl who's
like,
fuck you,
like a couple breaks up.
I'm like,
what the fuck is happening?
Um,
I always have to kick people out of
there.
And so this guys in the front row and
Kevin Christie was opening for me and
Kevin's very incisive,
like,
he's very,
he's kind of used to this comic,
you know,
and he's like kind of quiet and it
doesn't speak a lot,
but when he does,
it's just exactly,
it's just the truth.
Like he's just so real like that.
And uh,
he said something once because he was on
the road with me for awhile and like 35,
40 minutes into all my sets at the time,
a guy would just snap and start yelling
at me and he's like,
I think what happens is they're like
loving it.
Funny,
funny,
female comedian,
funny.
It's funny,
but like 40 minutes and you just become
their wife or the girl that wouldn't
fuck them or their mother or something.
And they just see you,
it's like all of a sudden you just
become a woman who's yelling at them and
they're not allowed to talk back.
One guy just we'll snap.
It always happens.
And I had one guy like storm the stage
at me once and be like,
who the fuck do you think you are?
Like,
I was like,
and it didn't feel like it was about me
at all.
It felt like a very old wound,
dark,
sad and [inaudible].
I could tell right away.
This has nothing to do with me and what
you're talking about.
Well,
I'll tell you,
I can.
I do remember what the.
This one guy in the front row that I
comped was he sitting in the front and I
was like doing it.
And I did this.
This was like my first special.
I was getting my first special.
I did this joke about how every guy,
somewhere in his house or apartment or
whatever has like a jar of coins or like
a bowl of coins.
You know where you guys put your change,
like a change jar,
bowl.
You're red.
You probably just have a fucking throw
away trash,
just put it right in the trash it away.
Oh my,
that's amazing.
So do you remember,
I mean there was a point in your life
where I'm sure you had one pennies up to
make dinner.
You guys have like a,
you know,
um,
they're changed our.
And so I just said it and it was like
whatever.
And then the guy went from like
laughing,
and then as soon as I said that joke,
he just looked at me and he went,
that's so we can pay for your shit.
I was like,
uh Oh.
And from then on out,
it was just like everything I said,
he'd be like,
well that's fucking,
you did it on.
And it's because if you didn't fucking
spend so much money,
he's literally,
he's in the front row lawn and you know
that loan by himself,
by himself and you know that moment
where someone's heckling and you're
like,
if only I can hear them,
I'll keep going.
But if the audience can hear them,
I have to do something.
So I finally had to,
you had to go.
But at the lawyer comedy store,
there's like a window into the street,
so he went outside and just stood in the
window and stared at me for the rest of
them.
Remember he was just standing there and
it was like,
you know.
So I think,
I think comedy can really trigger
trigger people.
Sometimes it's you're drinking,
you're out.
You have someone talking about a guy
that's willing to go to a comedy by
himself
though.
Sit in the front row already have red
flags.
Just kick that person out right away.
This is the guy that emailed you.
So you got different guys.
Oh yes,
yes,
yes.
He emailed and yeah,
good point.
So you,
you have a connection with.
He's probably thinking he's going to be
in love with you.
He's going to straighten you out.
So you're a little too mouthy.
He a little too talkative.
You have too many opinions.
And he's like,
yeah,
I'll fucking.
I know Yo Berko girls love that.
Well,
you know,
there are people that think that people
need to be put in check and that people
like it.
Comedian.
I'll tell you,
I'll tell you the story now,
but I'm not going to tell you who it is.
Okay.
Can I guess.
Yes.
But if you get it right,
I'm not going to know until after if I
get it right,
just go.
Don't.
Because now I'm probably gonna do that
anyway.
Um,
there is this thing,
I think that exactly what you're talking
to them.
Um,
I do think there is this thing
the same way women sometimes meet a man
and they're like,
I can fix him when he's probably not
broken and is happy and fine or like
I'll whip him into.
I hear my friends say it all the time
and I'm like,
no,
he's fine.
He's,
he's happy.
You don't need to fix him.
He doesn't think he's broken.
And uh,
I think sometimes guys with me or like
I'll tame her,
like I'll break her,
you know,
like I'll,
um,
and uh,
there was this comedian who sent me a
message on,
I guess it was when I was on facebook or
wasn't my space.
It was one of those who I would always
see around and I'm pretty elusive.
Like you and I,
we didn't get,
we don't haven't got to hang at the
comedy store that much,
but like I kind of,
I'm in and I'm out less,
less,
less so now like I would hang now
because like cool people are there now,
but when you were gone it was kind of
toxic in there and it's intense and not
like fun.
Now it's little more fun.
Um,
and so I just get in and do my set and
leave because I was trying to do a
couple sets of night and um,
uh,
I would just be like,
Hey,
what's up?
And we wouldn't flirt,
but it would just be like,
hey,
and you know,
the kind of person who wants to give you
tags.
They're like,
you know,
what you should say there and it's like
a.
and I get this message that was like
rage,
like a rage rage email that was like,
you know,
you don't know what you're like,
the basic jest of it.
I don't remember how it started,
but it ended in like,
you don't know what makes you come.
I can show you what I know,
like it was like,
I was like,
I obviously accidentally actually say
that in come.
I'm sure I still have the screen grab of
it because I said,
you know,
I said to dad,
how do you know what makes me.
I don't like it was just,
but it was like this Alpha thing,
like it was like a Alpha reaction I
think,
or something like I just need to make
you shame you or something.
I don't know what it was.
Yeah,
well that's an alpha.
Like what is that?
What,
what would it take for you to say that
to a girl?
The crazy person who usually it's self
obsessed,
like delusional,
delusional narcissism or something
that's true.
Narcissistic to just to reach out like
that to you.
That's,
you know what that is.
You are an accoutrement or you are like
a,
you're a piece of wardrobe in his life.
Interesting.
And you don't want him to try you on.
You know what I'm saying?
Like you like he's upset like you're in
my life and it's not.
Why aren't you doing what I want you to
do?
In my life,
my life,
clinical narcissism is that everyone is
an extension of you and if you're not
doing what I wrote,
you're acting out.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
Okay.
Well,
there's a lot of people that feel like
that.
I mean,
that's a classic example of why
Comedians don't like to work with other
good comedians because they don't want
anybody else doing well.
Yeah.
You know,
they don't want anybody.
It's got to be all about them.
Like how many bad comedians do we know
that take the fucking force people on
the road with them.
The worse,
worse,
worse.
It's so bad that you go,
okay,
do you hate your audience?
People I think were the funniest because
I,
my audience is paying money and you want
to laugh to want to have fun.
I have to watch them too.
Exactly.
It doesn't benefit me to have less
talented people around me.
I'd actually do the opposite to a fault.
I feel like I tried to hire people who
are more talented than me in every area
of my life,
so that it makes me look better.
Well,
that's again,
you.
You're weirdly introspective in that
way,
but there's a lot of people that get
into comedy because of all the scars of
their childhood,
like who we're talking about and they
don't.
They don't heal those things.
Instead they just find workarounds.
They find a way where they can sort of
express themselves and and so it's
almost like,
see,
I told Ya,
I showed the world like they never come
to a neutral point.
They never get over the childhood where
they go,
Oh,
okay.
Well what am I doing?
Is there a benefit to what I'm doing
here?
Should I just stop?
If I'm healthy now,
should I just stop what I'm doing or
should I use what I'm doing and just
enjoy it and have a good time?
And then you realize that I probably got
here because of an unhealthy obsession
or because of a bad childhood or
whatever,
but now that I'm kind of moving past
that,
maybe I could use this position to just
have some fun
in exactly what you're saying.
Like you just made it so clear to me
what I was not being clear about in the
beginning of the,
you know,
if you bring unfunny people on the road
years really funny comparatively,
and so all of a sudden you've created
this little world for yourself where you
become this king of the idiots,
but if you were to step outside that
world,
you're all of a sudden at the bottom of
the food chain,
like you create a world where at the top
of the food chain,
which is why it was important to me to
go to other countries,
be around people that have no idea who I
am,
that I don't pay that don't think I'm
funny.
That can you understand what I'm saying?
It's just very humbling and then you're
like,
oh,
who am without all this stuff
without achievements and money and car
or what a car,
whatever it is,
you know,
because I'm afraid that I might do that
by accident.
You know?
Because if you have people around you
who are paid,
who are afraid to say no to you,
that's how you stop getting funny.
Everyone around you is like,
like I saw Chris Rock at the store
wants,
I'm sure you have this where he was
working on,
I don't know,
like not the Oscars or something.
And he got on stage and he said
something that was just like,
Hey,
I'm sorry I'm late.
I've,
you know,
my car was,
I couldn't find a spot for it.
Never was like,
ha ha ha.
And he was like,
that wasn't funny.
Please don't laugh unless I say
something funny,
please treat me like I'm normal.
Yeah.
He was like,
that's how comics stopping funny is
because people enable the and you know,
they use it when you get so big like
you.
It's like,
you know,
people stop as.
I mean your audience I'm sure is really,
you know.
Well we can all be guilty of it,
you know,
I think just what you're talking about
is like navigating all these landmines
that success can setup for you.
Put It,
you know,
which are better land minds than
failure,
but still landmines and the landmines of
fame or particularly intoxicating
because when someone has a bunch of fans
that say,
oh my God,
you know Mike,
fuck faces here.
Yay.
Oh my God,
it's Mike.
And they go run up to you.
I can't believe you're so amazing.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Take a picture with me.
I'm cool with God.
You know,
and it's.
It becomes this thing where you,
you,
you get accustomed to that
so myopic and you forget that there's 6
billion people that don't have
any fucking idea who you are.
And if Mike fuck face is around Tony
Mcdonald face and Tony Mick,
Dick face is more famous like Tony
Minute dictations a movie out now.
Then Mike Fuck.
Face gets really mad.
Like Tony Big Dick face.
Exactly right.
You ever seen those guys before?
Both
represented by Barry Katz.
I think they just left.
Yeah.
They're doing his podcast.
They just wanted the three yards,
but it's.
But is that sort of.
I literally found myself,
because it's also,
if you do achieve anything,
it doesn't matter because you're just
comparing yourself some with more
achievements.
So I'm recreating this feeling of
failure at every level of success and
recreating this unhappiness at every
level where I have no real problems.
You know?
It's like,
yeah,
I have my bullshit problem.
They're fake problems.
It's like,
you know,
it's like,
yeah,
my parents are sick.
Yeah.
I have a lot of,
you know,
real things,
but it's also,
it's like,
you know,
I can pay the bill to get them.
Like I literally am going through this
thing where it's like nursing homes and
care for,
for older people.
And I'm like,
the fuck,
do people pay for this?
I have to go on tour to pay for it.
I mean I have to,
you know,
thank God I get to do that for a living
and the casinos and shit.
But it's a fortune.
And I'm like,
oh.
And my dad is,
you know,
is a vet.
And I looked at the vet facilities and
was just like,
are you fund
this?
This is where vets go.
The guys that fucking lost their limbs
for our country,
this is where you're putting them.
I mean that's her dying fucking
facility.
We had to do these.
We did these benefits,
these events called fight for the troops
and we did these for the intrepid in
intrepid,
center for excellence,
which is sounds cool and establishment
that they.
They've the,
these facilities,
they're creating these state of the art
facilities to deal with people with
traumatic brain injuries and so they
showed us all these guys and it's
unbelievably heartbreaking.
See these people like with their wives
and their children and their families
and they're trying to rehabilitate them
and then going through all these steps.
But what was more disheartening than
anything was to realize that all this
stuff is privately funded because the
United States government just.
They don't allocate enough money to
treatment of these troops when they get
home.
They just don't.
So we have to raise all this money for
these people.
So while we're doing this,
like they wanted us to talk about it at
the beginning of it and I have to
measure myself because it's on
television and it's what I want to say
is this is fucking crazy that we have to
do a fight to raise.
We're going to give people brain damage
so that we can
no raise money for brain damage and
raise the money for all the weapons you
that they really seem to find money for
it,
but not for the humans that use the
weapon but these guys.
But it's so ironic in a lot of ways
because these people are fighting.
Okay.
And if they're fighting.
So like a bunch of people got knocked
out in the show.
So they got some brain damage and I mean
obviously they're competing,
it's their decision,
they're,
they're going for glory.
The trying to make it as a fighter,
but were the end result is they're this,
they're getting pounded on so that we
can make money.
It's crazy.
So they could help people who have brain
damage.
It's a must.
That is the most Chinese finger trap.
Oh my God.
It's like the amount of brain damage you
get from MMA is so minuscule and
compared to an ied,
but it's also,
why the fuck do we not set money aside
for this?
Why?
How could there be what?
Find out what every congressman gets.
Find out what everybody's.
Every senator gets.
Chop a chunk of that shit out and send
it to the intrepid center.
I mean,
there's gotta be a way that there's
gotta be some fucking red tape and
bureaucracy that you can cut and you
could send some of that money to help
take care of these people that you are
forcing to go overseas and fight these
battles.
A friend of mine who was in the army,
he told me that the statistic on vets
committing suicide,
it's insane.
It's insane.
I want to say yours,
what I want to say.
What's one every like seven minutes.
Oh yeah,
it is.
It's something like that.
Yeah.
Well Jamie can look it up,
but it's fucking insane.
It's more people die of 22 a day.
Oh my God.
Twenty two a day in 2012 more US
soldiers committed suicide than were
killed in.
Yeah.
I mean it's like,
what do you mean?
It's just,
it's,
it's too crazy.
And um,
yeah.
And then I'm like,
Oh God,
where is my soy milk?
I'm amazed.
It's only 22 a day.
I thought it was.
No,
I thought it was one every seven minutes
or something.
But that's an average.
Maybe it is some days I don't like
throwing statistics around on this.
No,
no.
Talking about people that have served.
I just know too many.
I know too much of it.
I've talked to too many guys and I,
I've,
I've talked to too many people that,
you know,
the reality of it is so bleak.
And also,
uh,
from what little I know about it is that
um,
and then the drone guys are,
is a real nightmare because there's all
this Ah,
you know,
normally when you are in combat and you
come back,
you do a physical neutralization period.
Like you go to Germany or some for like
five days and like they chill you out
before you go back to your family and
kids after you've just been combat.
But these drone guys,
not only is the technology is so
advanced that they're seeing all these
women and children,
they're not in the fog of war,
right?
They don't just see like threat threat
threat because when you are getting shot
at a kid is might as well be a guy with
a gun.
So,
so these guys are seeing these people
getting shot super close up.
They're not able to.
They're seeing their own guys get shot,
like they're seeing it and then they go
upstairs to their wife and kids and
there's just no period for their brains
to acclimate to it.
And it's,
there's a serious atrophy of a drone
pilots and they're just raise the wages
of it so that it'll attract more because
so few people want to do it.
Really to doing it in your basement like
a video game just,
um,
is actually even more traumatic oddly.
But also the suicide rate.
Apparently it's even worse among the
soldiers that didn't kill anyone.
Anyone,
because they have guilt and shame about
it.
Whoa.
Yeah.
Well,
from what I've talked to with guys that
were in the seals are rangers,
special operatives guys,
is that those guys have way less issues.
Seals and rangers.
Okay.
Because first of all,
mentally they're going to be the most
durable.
Yeah.
It's never the strongest guys.
That's always the most.
Yeah.
Well,
those guys are terrible.
Mentally more durable.
They have a better understanding.
They have way deeper and more intense
comradery than the average person does.
And then on top of that,
they're,
they're proactive.
They're the ones who were hunting down
bad guys.
They're not waiting for people to attack
them.
They're going after that.
So it's a totally different kind of
thing.
Like if they plot a mission and they're
going to go fuck somebody up,
like they're,
they're,
they're hunting.
They're not being hunted when you're
being hunted.
That's where the stress comes.
Food,
I wanted to send you this,
you probably already read it.
It's called Sapiens I think.
And uh,
it's essentially,
it's about anxiety and this a book you
just touched,
that was a different one.
I realized I had been texting you too
many books.
Yeah,
both can fill out to say most girls
said,
you know,
naked photos,
new tags.
I said science books,
like,
no wonder I'm fucking alone.
Uh,
and uh,
it's about anxiety and everyone's like,
I have anxiety,
I have anxiety.
And it's like anxiety is actually talks
about sort of the origin of it.
And there's,
it's two pronged.
One is because I had a lot of shame
about anxiety too.
And anxiety,
shame about it.
Like why am I anxious?
It's like we're actually supposed to be
anxious,
you know,
just as by the laws of survival of the
fittest.
The fittest were the ones that were
anxious,
you know,
thousands of years ago,
the anxious,
hypervigilant people were the ones that
were like,
well,
there's fucking tiger we should move.
And the ones that didn't have anxiety
just got eaten alive.
And you're definitely one of the
watchers.
Yeah,
I think I've definitely,
I've had anxiety.
They come and watch sleep.
I know you're up at night.
It's why we've got weed.
Yeah.
You're also a scene of a comedian.
So you live a night life.
Yeah.
I have adrenaline,
uh,
people who grew up in hectic homes who
produced Adrenalin young usually have an
adrenaline addiction.
Oh,
I definitely have that.
Yeah.
Because your body is producing so much,
John.
It's addictive.
You must huge.
Also,
to your point just now is there was.
I never thought.
Of course I hadn't thought about it.
I'm not smart enough to,
but I have never known that humans are
not designed to be at the top of the
food chain.
We're only at the top of the food chain
because we have weapons and the reason
we have weapons is because we had really
large brains,
which was actually not helpful at all.
It's really inefficient and uneconomical
for energy because I guess our brains
burned like 25 or 30 percent of our
calories or something.
So chimpanzees and apes head smaller
brains.
They were able to climb trees and avoid
threats.
Like a big brain is like a disaster
except that we invented tools,
so we sort of not based on merit.
We superficially,
once we embedded tools jumped to the top
of the food chain,
but we don't deserve to be there because
without weapons a lot of species would
kill us,
but we can figure out weapons.
So of course we deserve to be there
totally.
But as soon as the weapons are gone,
we're vulnerable.
So vulnerable to animals.
Yes to a lot because we're not truly at
the top of the food chain.
We only are at the top of the food chain
if we have a weapon.
So there's that anxiety.
A turtle without a shell,
but the second you drop your weapon,
you're in the middle of the food channel
and drop it.
Bitch.
I'm not as agile as you fucking weapon.
That's how you stay alive.
That's what.
That's the anxiety.
Hold the fucking weapon.
Don't drop it and be and keep your shit
together and keep on fucking high alert
because the second,
if your back is to Elian and the weapons
pointing this way,
you're still gonna die.
You know the lines are problematic.
Even if you have a weapon,
it's like,
yeah,
they eat Bolus for fucking breakfast.
This balance of the second you run out
of bullets,
it's over.
Well,
you know,
when,
when you think about what made a human a
human,
it's really fascinating because it
becomes like what came first,
the chicken or the egg,
like what were we like when we will
Australia pacificus,
you know,
they have these depictions of us and
what we looked like all hairy and
with fucking sloped foreheads and shit.
We were pretty close to people but not
really people.
And when you really look at the fossil
record,
what they understand that these were
only talking about this kind of person
like you and I for a couple of hundred
thousand years.
Yeah.
That's so recent.
So recent.
It's so weird.
I have an extra bone in my foot.
What I have.
What's your foot doing?
My feet are webbed.
Is that a turn off of all those foot
fetishes?
Um,
you know what's so funny is that I'm
wearing flip flops today.
It's real power move.
You know,
there's human.
You really have webbed feet.
No,
I don't.
I'm joking.
But there are these foot fetishes,
however you.
Hi.
Hi Guys.
There's foot fetishes.
It's out there and like if you google
me,
I think when you come me his feet is
like the second or third one,
which I um,
you know,
I mean that's for most people in the
public eye,
like feet is always like to like google
charlise Aaron don't do it and just see
what the,
see what they come up,
you know.
Um,
so I'm,
I'm really afraid that if I had met
this,
although I'm going to lose my foot
fetish demo,
but I had this pain in my foot and I
think we're probably a little bit
similar you much more so.
But um,
I have a pretty high tolerance for pain.
He just learned it,
grind and go to doctors growing up.
It's just like suck it up.
That's what I caught on fire.
I went to school,
like that's basically like how my family
was.
You just suck it up and you man up.
So I had this pain in my foot or my,
like my big toe and then my third toe,
like once every two weeks,
like real bad and it would be like,
it's just a stabbing,
awful pain.
But I just was like,
oh,
that's my foot,
like once every two weeks my foot has
like a spasm and it lasts for like,
I don't know,
like two minutes and then I get through
it and I was in a writer's room one day
and my feet were up on the table and
then I was like,
had the pain came and I was like,
and I'm like screaming,
and two minutes later I'm like,
anyway,
so,
uh,
act three,
what should we.
And everyone's like,
what the fuck was that?
I was like,
Oh,
I have this thing,
I have this foot spasm that happens once
every two weeks.
It's just like my foot.
And everyone was like,
no,
that's not a thing.
That's not a,
you have to get,
go to a podiatrist.
First Time I've ever went to a
podiatrist and he gave me an extra and
he's like,
Oh,
you have an extra foot.
I'm sorry you have an but even extra
bone in your foot between your second
and third toe.
And he's like,
it's basically just remanence of being
an android
really.
Now is it?
It's not bone spurs like a broken foot
quarterly,
just like an extra.
You can't really see it.
It's just like an extra bone right here.
Whoa.
Like one think.
Hmm.
You know,
because we used to have more bones in
our feet and you're just like,
that's fucking real.
Like it was not that long ago.
Why would we have extra bones though?
What was it?
Something about the uh,
uh,
I'll find out for you.
It's something about the webbing or
something.
My friend Steve Rinella went to Bolivia
and he stayed with Toumani,
the tribe,
the tribe and Bolivia.
And they don't wear shoes and they live
in the rainforest and their feet,
their feet are splayed out.
It's interestingly,
our feet are like this and that.
Kinetic or is it worn from rights?
Worn from writing all the time.
So let's just walking constantly
barefoot.
But like our feet are like this where
their feet are spread,
like their toes are spread out.
Women's in America,
like all.
Yeah,
they're all getting old.
So many girls I see in their feet,
their toes are taken left and right.
They're just trying to run away from
each other.
These fucking shoes that don't show.
They're not shaped like a foot cocktail.
Shrimp who's fucking feet are shaped
like that Asian bound.
That's like they have to do it.
Right.
That's what these Toumani people.
Rinella was there and he was walking
through the woods with these people and
he was like,
this is incredible.
Because they've never had shoes.
They don't have any shoes.
And if you give them shoes,
they try them on.
They're like,
what the fuck?
And they throw it aside and they have
these thick,
thick soles of their feet.
Sure.
Confirm.
Just constantly.
That's my.
That's exactly like you keep saying my
goal,
like you're,
we acclimate to where we are.
So I want to have the thick,
thick sole in my personality.
I want to be that person as the.
I don't want to be the one who has the
Pha is like can fall apart.
Yes.
I don't want to be this like,
oh my God,
do you have like Stevia?
Like I don't.
I,
I started realizing I had all these
fucking needs.
Don't you think change means that we see
around us constantly because it's so
socially enforced.
It's so like coconut milk,
soy milk and did a $6 latte and it
becomes normal after a while and I was
like,
this is not fucking normal.
Also comforting to like behave in these
patterns that we've already seen before.
It makes you feel like you're a normal
person and it makes us feel like because
we're designed to be part of a tribe and
to fit in and standing out,
it's like produces,
you know,
stress because it means we're less safe.
And I was like,
I do not want to like,
because you drive around and you're
like,
oh this fucking asshole,
this whole asshole.
And you're like,
I'm one of those assholes.
Right?
I've got to remove myself from the
situation and go watch kids have surgery
for,
you know,
a lot of that,
these asshole things like the fucking
bro rage and all that jazz.
A lot of that goes away when you're in a
small town.
Tell me,
that's interesting.
In Boulder,
one of the things that I've found,
and I was only in boulder for a few
months,
but one of the things that I've found
when I was there,
I was like,
people drive way more polite.
They're way nicer,
like they let people in and they don't
cut people off as much stone.
No,
no,
no.
That too,
but there's less of them.
There's only 100,000
people in town.
So when you have a small community,
first of all there's less diffusion of
responsibility because you and that
person is probably going to see each
other again.
So if I give someone the finger on the
highway on the four or five,
what are the odds I'm going to meet
that?
Do it again?
Zero.
Probably there's less like accountable.
We can be more anonymous and more.
You have more responsibility as a
community.
Like if you see someone pulled over the
side of the road,
you have more desire to pull over and
help
dumb.
It's like tribal.
I mean that's really like a tribe
mentality.
Like there was these people that were
pushing their car the other day and they
were on the side of the road and I was
thinking,
fuck,
shut,
get out of the car and help them push
the car.
And uh,
I think I watched them do it.
I'm like,
yeah,
they're okay.
They got it.
It's up on the hill there,
there it's up on the,
uh,
the curb there.
They're going to be okay.
But I was thinking like if this was a
small town for sure,
I'd pull over and I was thinking that at
that moment,
because of the time that I spent living
in Boulder,
I was,
I was amazed at how polite people were
and also the less people like in the
town,
like when I was in this town in the
mountains,
they would wave when you would go by and
people lift their hand up when you would
drive by,
he'd pass each other and everybody and I
got used to doing it and we all did it,
you know,
as you were driving this way or that
person driving that way,
you will lift your hand up and you wave
to them because there's not that many of
you see in La.
I think they're so fucking many people
that we lose the idea of value of,
uh,
of our fellow humans because our fellow
humans become a bird fight.
Yeah.
Become a burden.
There's too many of us.
And so there's a lot of benefit in that.
Like for guys like you or for people
like you and I,
it's great because there's so many clubs
we can work at,
you know,
there's so much variety as far as like
restaurants we could eat at are places
we can go and so much culture to see.
But also you're dealing with this
massive volume of people and it's hard
to keep your perspective.
It's hard to keep your perspective just
with the sheer numbers and I think in a
lot of ways it mirrors what we're
talking about with even with celebrity
or fame or with wealth that it's hard to
keep perspective.
Like for people,
people need adversity,
difficult situations that we need things
in order to keep our perspective.
You know what's interesting?
Have you been to Tokyo?
Yes.
So Tokyo is liked hectic.
I mean there's not as many.
It's not as much of a car culture,
but there's a weird.
I wonder what part of it's cultural,
whether cars play it because it's
really.
Everything is times square.
Totally.
That's like a big time square,
but there's like this concept of space
and it's not like when I go to New York
it's like fuck you,
fuck you,
excuse me.
You know,
and it's like you're just like in a rat
race.
Whereas in Tokyo there was this weird
harmonic sort of.
It's almost like choreographed,
so less of a like I don't know what
that.
Less aggression.
More respect.
Yeah.
Maybe it's.
Maybe it is that cultural thing we were
talking about earlier,
but it's less of like I get it.
Maybe it's maybe it's because we live in
a capitalist society where it's all like
we're competing with everybody too,
but they compete in a very different way
than we do
compete with.
They have a lot of honor and behavior
patterns and this is expected to follow.
It's a very different world,
but I was amazed how polite people were
in Tokyo.
I was just literally,
I got.
I mean I accidentally was rude so many
because when a cab picks you up,
you're not allowed to open the door.
The door opens and it's considered rude.
If you open the door yourself,
close at
driver gets up and opens and closes it
for you.
Yeah,
like it's rude to do something for
yourself and it's um,
it's weird because I just,
it makes you feel like you're going to
be robbed because everyone's like,
how can I help you?
It's like the service is like,
you know,
as you said,
it's all about honor and dignity and
taking pride in your work,
which were all about fucking shortcuts.
It's like,
how do I know all about doing something
the most difficult way,
like doing or the most painstaking
gains.
Like Samurais there was never seen an
actual Samurai sword.
Now of course Joe's got one in his
pocket.
Guys.
Cheeses from the 15 hundreds.
Okay.
The Real Samurai sword from the 15
hundreds,
like legitimately.
And if you look at that blade,
that blade was made by some guy,
so turned on right now.
Steel pounded it,
folded it over,
pounded it again,
pounded again.
It takes for ever for.
You can see if you look at the actual
emily line.
No.
Well,
that's so much more humanizing.
It's like if there's just an assembly
line that's making these,
you know,
as a human,
you just feel like a robot.
You feel like you are robbed of your
individuality.
Right.
You know,
this is like,
you can take pride in your work,
but they did a different than anybody.
They did it different than anybody who's
making swords.
I mean they,
they had sword making and sort of get
your core feel on point for this.
The real deal.
Is this to actually kill people or is
this the Samurai fight?
Probably killed people.
What do you think it feels like to stab
someone?
I bet it's not easy.
Easy.
In what way?
I mean,
you're way stronger than me.
That's a good.
So if you're,
what's the stomach?
It's probably pretty.
You need to create a replica of what it
would be like to stab someone.
Would it be like watermelon?
No.
You kill a deer.
Oh yeah.
Get like an animal that's not obvious,
but like ribs,
ribs stop it.
No ribs can if you're weak,
you know?
But it depends on how heavy the blade
is.
Like does anyone ever tried to stab
someone?
It's like the ribs just stopped the
whole thing from for sure,
because that's what ribs are for.
To protect your.
Yeah,
I mean a weak person who stabs you in
the wrong spot with a small knife is
probably not going to get it in,
but somebody who stabs you with that
fucking thing,
the odds of that not going through your
ribs,
pretty small.
If you're a strong person,
most likely you're going to penetrate
their entire body,
but it's also mirrored in archery
bowhunting.
That's like one of the most important
aspects of bowhunting is to have a
heavier Arrow that has a sharp blade
with a powerful bow.
So it goes through bone,
so it goes through the ribs,
doesn't go through the rows of it,
stops at the ribs.
Then you just have a wounded animal.
Where are you on bone marrow?
Tiny thing.
It's good.
My nails,
my hair,
like it's like that.
In that same book,
it talks about how bone marrow,
um,
human brain,
uh,
exponentially went up when humans
started eating the bone marrow of animal
because they couldn't have their own
animals.
They had to eat the leftover bone trash,
right.
But that's actually where all the
vitamins negotiating with.
There's so many questions and so many
theories about what caused the doubling
of the human brain size over a period of
2 million years is really a fascinating
subject because they just don't know.
There's all this speculation.
There's something that was the,
um,
the ability to throw the throwing arm
because it's one of the most unique
aspects of a person.
There's no other animal that can take a
rock and throw it with accuracy like a
person can.
So like ground nesting birds,
things along those lines.
That hand eye coordination and like a
chimpanzee can throw something but
doesn't mean it's going to hit the
target.
It doesn't have the synapses,
it doesn't have the connections and it's
mine that allow it to be like really
accurate at distance.
Like a person.
Like think about like a pitcher who
could throw a fastball.
How many feet is it to plate?
Sixty to 62 feet.
I think that's also,
we were evolved to see underwater,
right?
Like fish as first started.
So we're actually,
our vision is I wonder,
well if you ever read the theory,
so please,
if you ever read the aquatic ape theory.
Nope.
The aquatic ape theory is really
bizarre.
It's very controversial,
but the idea is that human beings come
out of the womb with so much body fat
and we're so different than chimpanzees
in that regard.
Like a chimpanzee baby is like a
chimpanzee adult.
It's just little ds,
but a human babies filled with fat super
fat.
Most species are born ready to go.
Ours are born completely helpless,
just helpless,
but fat like covered in fat.
And the idea is that we were in water
and that we developed and we possibly
evolved around water to the point where
babies like if you throw a chimpanzee
baby in the water,
they fucking drown.
They just the day breathe water and they
drown.
You throw a human baby in the water.
The instinctively hold their breath
because they're basically fish until
they're born.
Like the Nirvana cover with the baby in
the water.
Yeah.
Like when my kid,
my kids learned how to swim when they
were babies,
we taught them when they were really
little,
we got them instruction.
But one of the things you realize like
people,
it's a very natural thing to hold your
breath and go on to walk.
Yeah,
it's totally instinctive.
And so the aquatic eight theory
theorized is that at one point in our
evolution we were primarily water bound
and that may be we went into the water
to get away from predators or that maybe
we figured out a way to develop in the
water as lower hominids do,
so no other animal holds their breath
either though about no other animal,
but I know that other primates don't.
Other primates just fucking drowned.
Webbed at some point is,
is that for swimming?
Didn't we have web?
That's true because chimps don't.
I don't know if that's true.
We might have.
I mean we certainly don't.
Some go wait,
but every now and then have webbed feet,
but that could be just an aberration
lip,
cleft palate.
Yeah,
that's true.
I don't know why you'd have a web.
I mean maybe it,
maybe it makes sense.
Here's a controversial thing,
we kind help you swim.
Right?
But it didn't get in the way.
If you wanted to like do shit,
it would.
It'd be a problem.
But I mean they weren't texting,
but again,
the way from your instagraming lot of
things is climb trees.
Oh yeah.
Like stupid.
Well making tools.
I think it maybe we'd get in the way it
makes your fingers less agile but not
webbed hands.
Would it be helpful if he would help?
Because our toes can't do anything or
toes are useless for swimming flipper,
but there's something about our fingers
to.
If you think about like the,
the dexterity and the control that we
have over our hands.
It's so unusual in comparison to any
other animal and our fingers that when
our fingers get all wet and what does
that wrinkly.
There was this interesting study about
how fingers after being in water for two
hours could pick up more marbles then
dry hands.
Huh?
Which kind of means that we must have
needed to be in the water a lot.
Does that what it means or is it just a
side effect of just your fingers getting
wrinkly?
Yeah,
but why would they get wrinkly if it
wasn't useful for something?
Or is that just why?
Why do people get cancer?
Don't get me started on turnover.
That is that.
Is there a benefit to that?
How many things are a benefit of things
are not designed to live past like 30,
right?
Well we definitely didn't live past 30 a
long time ago.
Very often.
True.
No,
I like it.
I just,
I'm such a Klutz seat like I'm afraid.
I'm just thinking just like slapped his
fucking head.
Just didn't happen.
Scientist think they've answered with
the skin on human fingers and toes
shrivels up like an old proven.
When we soak in the bath.
Laboratory tests confirmed that theory,
that wrinkly fingers improve our grip on
wet or submerged objects working to
channel away the water like a rain
treads and car tires.
You know why it makes sense because the
rest of your skin doesn't do that.
Like if your elbow got all wrinkly.
That's true.
So a evolutionary neurobiologist and his
colleagues just that wrinkling being an
active process must have an evolutionary
function.
The team also showed the pattern and
wrinkling appeared to be optimized for
that.
Providing a drainage network that
improved grip makes sense.
So maybe we were trying to get fish or
some shit rocks.
Well,
you know,
it totally makes sense.
It does.
That doesn't happen when you sweat.
Does it know mostly really just fuckers.
I'm sure you've talked about it a lot.
Um,
I think activity is good.
I think exercise is good and I think,
you know,
those people,
a lot of them are
very fit and.
But I think that like a lot of things
when you take certain aspects of
physical activity,
like Steve Maxwell,
who's a good friend of mine and he's a
strength and conditioning coach,
he said it best that physical fitness,
like I'm lifting weights and engaging in
exercise activities he doesn't believe
is a sport in unto itself.
He thinks it's good at getting you
strong for other sports.
Now when you turn into a sport like who
can do the most clean and presses,
who could do the most,
uh,
you know,
whatever,
a dead lifts in an hour,
he doesn't think that that's healthy
because in this is he's far more
qualified than I am to answer this.
So I'm using his rationale.
He thinks that power lifting and
bodybuilding movement or powerlifting
and weightlifting movements like dead
lifts or like cleans and presses,
you shouldn't do them for like sets of
30 and 40 and 50,
and having these competition to see who
can do the most.
He's like,
it's just not beneficial.
It's not he,
he's of the school of thought that you
should like strength lifting exercises
are strength producing exercises.
Should it be done with a low repetitions
and you know,
you should take breaks in between them.
And it's about building the physical
strength of your body.
It's not about performing them in a
contest.
Now the crossfit people,
I think if I could speak for them,
I think they think of it as a healthy
lifestyle and that this competition,
it makes them work harder and they all
work out together and I definitely see
their point.
And if you follow crossfit people,
ms.one
of the things about crossfit people that
they say like if someone's a crossfit
and they're a Vegan,
what do they talk about first?
Because.
Have you ever seen that?
Because it's like a meme.
I think it was on like a,
it was like a chalk board that was in
front of a coffee shop.
Yeah,
well it's,
it's one of those things we get excited
about it like vegans the most
proselytizing vegans and you'd talk to
them like one of the things I've found
because a lot of vegans get really upset
with me because I eat meat,
but one of the things that I've found
with a lot of them is that I'll go to
their instagram page after the shit on
me and I say,
I just found a bacon fucking sandwich
that's four months old.
So it means,
how long have you been a Vegan?
I've been Vegan for three months.
It's three months.
It's opened my eyes up.
I found my favorite person online the
other day.
He's a Vegan.
Who believes the earth is flat.
It's a flat rate to eat.
Um,
oh yeah.
The flat earth,
flat earth people.
There is a lot of people out there that
believes the fucking earth is flat.
They believe that it's all a hoax and
then NASA is a hoax and that satellites
aren't real and that there is airplanes
that are flying high and that's where
we're getting like direct tv from and
then it's all a giant,
vast conspiracy.
And here's my favorite part.
Gravity's not real and that the earth
exists.
The reason why we're,
we're staying put because
electromagnetism,
I mean
I don't,
I'm not even going to.
I don't even know how to respond to
that.
Just just be headings.
Think of how many astronomers and these
are the people having kids.
These people are just procreating all
day with other people that they think
all these people were in on it and they
think that if you look at the horizon,
like there's,
there's videos,
there's like a video that shows like the
200 reasons why they can prove that the
earth is flat and it's so fucking
stupid.
Hurts my feelings.
Really.
It,
it,
it makes me.
So maybe it's my mind nightwatch or
fight or flight thing,
but like when I hear that I just feel
like I'm in danger.
But you are like,
it's just like a stupid people make me
feel unsafe.
What it is is there's a lot of religions
out there.
Religion actually serves a.
I understand the neurological purpose it
serves.
Um,
but you know,
don't be.
What else can I say is there's
religions.
I mean the word religion,
let's just ditch it.
Let's just.
What is the,
what's the mental pathway that one's one
follows when they adhere to an ideology.
And I think we're all guilty of it to a
certain extent.
We all have them.
We need.
And I think there needs to be something
in place.
It's like don't kill people like guilt
and shame used to keep societies
controlled and have a sense of order.
Sure.
Guns and before prisons and before shit
was organized,
it was like God's going to get.
You had to come up with something to
keep people from raping each other and
murdering everyone.
Right.
And at least stopping it.
Don't do it again.
Yeah.
Like,
you know,
let's,
let's nip this shit in the bud.
Let's figure out what the business
opportunity.
It was like,
oh,
I can charge for this.
Well,
you know,
I mean,
look,
there's,
there's countless examples of people
creating these behavior patterns that
other folks are forced to follow and
these ideologies,
they will.
You see the way people think and I think
to a certain extent,
there's a lot of like really what w,
what people called the regressive left.
Like when people get mad at a white guy
for wearing dreadlocks and they say this
is cultural appropriation.
You taking black people's culture.
Like that sort of same thing is a kin to
religious people that want to force
women to dress a certain way or want to
force gay people to act a certain way.
There's there's parts of certain
ideologies that literally exists because
someone is trying to exert control over
other people and they think they can
because it's a rule too.
I try it like the like the other.
It's a bad example that I used about the
dreadlocks because it's so fucking
stupid because first of all,
vikings wear dreadlocks.
The Greeks had dread locks.
It's a white thing to a dirty hair
thing,
you know?
It's just,
it's a scale.
Only had dreadlocks until it's so.
It's so stupid,
but it's.
It's a new way that people can get upset
at certain groups and the left like
especially like what people.
Like a lot of people get upset with that
term.
The regressive left,
but it's a good term and the reason why
it's a good terms because they're,
first of all,
they're attacking straight there all.
They're attacking white gay men now for
having privileges that I've wrote this
whole article about white gay privilege
as opposed to black men and people of
color who are gay,
who don't get to experience the same
freedom that white gay people do that
live in white neighborhoods and have,
you know,
adopt white babies.
It's easier for them.
I mean it's,
it's attacking it,
this constant,
but we love.
I think it was you.
We were texting about this.
People love being outrageous and I don't
know what the creational outrage.
They love complaint and I think it is a
form of bonding and I think it has
helped people connect to each other and
like,
you know,
organize and stuff.
People love being offended.
They love being insulted.
They love,
they love racism because then they get
to complain about it and began to take
the moral high ground,
get to be sanctimonious and they get to
be,
you know.
Right.
And it's just like,
I think that sort of thinking,
I don't want to call it religion because
I think it's a pattern and patterns of
these ideologies.
I think it's problematic when you label
it like this is because of God,
this is,
but it's these,
these patterns that people force their
mind into,
well some people force themselves into
these patterns where everything is a
fucking conspiracy and that this is how
you get to this like delusional state of
mind that would allow you to think that
the earth is flat or that,
you know,
the government's run by Reptilians.
But to me intelligence is kind of
someone being able to go,
I think this is how it is or not,
or not being married to your idea.
Just like I could totally be fucking
wrong.
Like,
you know,
I think it's just like what?
Like what is this?
Like all my,
all my self esteem and identity is
linked to this lie.
It's like how sad and lonely is that
person that they need to attach to some
idea that it's just,
it's just so odd to me.
I mean I think comedians are brains are
a little.
We like we can go through our set and
say argue a point,
argue against our own point,
go back on.
And then someone had called and it's
like,
well that's a good point.
Like,
I mean,
I,
I feel very lucky that we have brains
that are able to see everybody's side
didn't.
That's kind of what we do for a living,
but it's very shocking to me.
It seems so suffocating and isolating
and weird to just be stuck on one thing.
Sure.
It's easy to be.
It's so common.
It's obviously easy to them is their
home,
you know.
And if you think something and someone
proves you wrong,
you will be angry and you will defend
that original idea as if it's a part of
someone's trying to steal.
Yes.
Why are you insulting me?
I take from me.
Yes,
it does.
People react to it.
Like stealing.
That's so intense.
That's when you can see right away that
there's an issue.
Yeah,
because people take it very personally.
If you don't share that belief
are the ones that detached from their
belief systems the fastest,
like doctors and scientists like mirror
neurons.
It was all about mirror neurons like a
couple of years ago.
Right?
And then they recently just debunk that
theory and scientists.
I'd be like,
oops,
we were wrong,
you know,
that's what science is all.
But I didn't mind who's a doctor.
I was like,
because he's always like,
oh,
and then I'm at my practice.
And I was like,
do you guys feel like it's weird that
you call it practice,
you know,
do you want to call it good at,
nailed it or the game time?
I'm at my game time championship game.
And he's like,
no,
it's called practice because the
medicine is doing the best we can with
what we know.
There's lots of we don't know.
You know,
and in 10 years we're going to be doing
looking back.
And they were like,
I can't believe you fucking did that.
That was dangerous.
You know,
that's like what medicine and sciences
like you're wrong every five years
there's a new fucking piece of
information.
Did you see the latest thing that I
tweeted yesterday that they've given
approval to people?
Do you stem cells to try to regenerate
dead people's brains?
Love it.
What was just so fucking horror moving?
I mean,
that's what everybody was tweeting just
zombies with is how it makes zombies to
bring people back to life or put their
old brain into a new person's body.
I think.
Well,
there's that too.
To find out.
Here it is.
Biotech company granted ethical
permission to attempt to use stem cells
to reactivate the brains of the dead.
Catch their killer or like.
No,
I don't think so.
That'd be crazy to like,
hey,
who killed you?
Alright,
you,
but go back to sleep.
I want to see what I want to know what
the conversation was because the,
the.
They've been granted ethical permission
by an institutional review board.
I didn't know there was an institutional
review board.
That's not a real company in the US and
in India,
India,
they're going to take the brains of the
babies.
They smashed into a lot of alive people
in America.
There's a lot of people in dumb people.
Yeah,
exactly.
Use Twenty brain dead patients for what
a shorted be.
Okay.
Buried in comas or comatose or
something.
Look what they're calling it.
The reanimate project.
Oh,
fucking Christ.
Sounds like an enema.
What are you doing,
Jimmy?
This is it.
Oh God.
A second chance at life.
Oh my God.
Magnolia.
It's also,
by the way,
the worst thing about this is it's a
shitty website is terrible.
I'm not going to.
I know if my.
If I had to do this on like a family
member on squarespace.
Totally guides.
You've got like,
this is like comedy central site,
proven scientific concepts.
This is insane.
Exploring the potential of cutting edge
biomedical technology for human neuro
regeneration and how much,
how much,
how much is a consummation neuro
reanimation is.
So when you see reanimator,
I think of that fucking movie reanimator
movie where they brought the monsters
that brought the people back to life
when they were monsters movies.
Reanimator like some mad scientist
ladies.
Hold on.
Is it exciting?
Is it a private thing?
Like if I'm like,
I want to reanimated one invest.
Yeah.
No,
that's all you're doing right now.
I feel like you probably have some
fighter Fred's who could use this.
Oh,
I know.
We both have a couple of my
fucking inject some shit in there.
Fixing.
Well,
Brian has never been hit.
He doesn't even have any real excuses.
Oh,
I'm sure his wife said I'm sure,
but he likes to box lately.
Brian's into boxing and I think he is
way worse for you,
isn't it?
Well,
it's all bad for you in fucking soccer
gives you brain damage.
Your head's not to get as opposed to get
jostled around too much,
but goes every direction except it goes
right except down.
I have a buddy of mine who's a professor
who's 49 or 50 and he kicked boxes.
He's bars and I'm like,
but you know,
you understand this like you're into
this,
you know,
he's a history professor.
Like you understand that this is
dangerous for your brand,
but you get so much enjoyment out of the
thrill of being primal actually been in
their sparring.
Let me ask you a question.
Did we,
we didn't talk about this last time,
that calcium storico thing in Italy once
they bare knuckle football with bare
knuckle boxing.
Insane.
So I was going to go to about that
documentary.
Yes.
And Pete Berg I think ended up making it
anyway,
but we were like just broken up and I'm
like,
why am I making a documentary with my ex
boyfriend?
This is really self abusive,
but it's apparently the,
the month that it happens,
violence in the area goes down.
Of course.
Yeah.
So there's something interesting about
these guys who want to go spar.
Like maybe they're sexually harassing
less women at work.
Maybe they're having less bar fights.
This calcium storico.
So it was invented in the 16 hundreds to
entertain kings.
It was stopped because so many people
were dying.
And then I want to say 1916,
they brought it back.
They keep it low profile because so many
people get concussions in sick group
kickboxing.
I think 20 on 20 a the only rule is no
two on one.
These are grown men.
These are not young like athletes.
They're not professional athletes are
butchers,
they're lawyers.
Whatever.
Exchange partners like guys just moved
and a new guy moved in and they just
touched hands.
Like one guy was duking it out with a
guy and then for some reason they
changed it.
Bare knuckle.
Yeah,
it's also by by region,
so it's like neighborhoods against
neighborhoods.
So a lot of it's like fathers against
sons,
brothers against brothers,
the change teammates,
like two guys were fighting and then
another guy steps in and takes the
place.
First of all,
these guys have dogs,
good
skills,
but it's no,
these are not a guy just stepped in.
These professional athletes,
these are literally guys that have other
jobs once a year.
They just agree to fucking just gets
pretty far.
Which one is this?
What?
What number minute are you in?
Oh,
well first.
Okay.
So Paul to.
Here's what you should see the ball.
It actually the goal is to get the ball
into the other side,
but when you dog shit skills and so
funny.
I've just allowed me that when the
person scores they get so hit so hard
that no one wants to go.
Like everyone's
like,
no,
you do it.
You do it.
Because as soon as you said
score,
people just pummel you and then you see
these guys in the corners with
stretchers.
They just carry people off the field the
entire time.
So this guy's holding this guy down.
She could grapple to.
Yes.
The only rule you can bite,
you can kick the ball.
You can do anything.
The only thing you can do is to,
on one,
that's the only rule you can bite.
The only rule is no two on one.
You can kick in the balls.
I'm sure.
I mean maybe that's like a general.
She is.
Two guys are the only two guys that are
humping were these two guys.
This guy's got this guy's back and
there's a lot of people fucking lolly
gagging cherry pickers.
You fucking pussies.
Could they make get out there?
And they're like,
what the fuck am I doing?
I have a family.
Just knock these guys out one at a time.
What the fuck are we doing here?
Oh,
that guy,
oh,
someone got smacked in the head.
He goes down,
he's got the ball and went down.
Then another guy took his place in.
Guys just sort of avoiding the whole
thing.
This ball guy looks gay as fuck.
No,
all.
Oh,
see,
this is the guy gets knocked down.
But look,
as soon as he gets knocked down,
another guy steps in and fights the guy
that he was fighting before he got
knocked down.
Oh,
what a bizarre,
stupid.
Turns into just like a melee of madness
and it's just,
it's actually interesting to watch the
clusters happen.
Like the energy going into one place.
Only one black guy.
Yeah,
I know.
That's why.
That's why it's so boring.
Nobody wants.
And these guys,
they're not professional professional
athlete.
It's like they trained for it.
Like it's,
it's almost like a.
what's that thing the iron man?
It's like a voluntary thing that they
do.
It's tradition.
If you do it,
if your dad did it.
Oh God.
Yeah.
So stupid.
And so rediculus.
Uh,
but there's a lot of tradition in ed and
see everyone wears like joker uniform.
Sure.
What does that guys that are humping
this still is bothered.
Just like,
you guys got this guys back,
but he's not doing anything by the way.
You should go out there when you're the
commentary where all the black people,
this guy's fucking gay to more buckeyes,
getting happy now.
They just took them off the bed.
Another like maybe just a Sicilian.
This guy's annoying.
You've got dark shit skills.
Well,
it just seems like a.
You mean a few of these guys are pulling
people off going on.
See the yellow guys in yellow.
That's when people get fucked up.
Yeah.
They just get taken off the field and
then they have to play.
I think it's 2:20
minute quarters and then the winter,
the winters have to play again the next
day again that three days in a row,
the championship is four days later and
the winning team,
their prize is a cow.
The Cow.
You get a cow,
a cow,
get money.
You don't get endorsed.
The thing I like about it,
that attracted me to it,
there's no endorsement deals.
There's no.
Nothing's been promoted.
It's just people that want to fucking
fight each other.
What our stand is.
Where's the leg kicks?
Do you guys not understand about leg
kicks?
Italian.
Yeah,
but they're not.
There's a few kicks being thrown,
but Noah's Tony Lake kicks.
They're standing right in front of each
other,
but there's no take downs.
So there's no takedown tabs.
It's just shitty boxing would the
occasional kick.
It's this is.
It's basically just like a giant street
fight.
Right?
But these guys have a little bit of
skill.
Like I'm looking at the way these.
A lot of the legacy.
Here's a takedown look at this,
but nothing happens so you can take a
guy down.
But look at the way these guys are like
standing in front of each other.
Like chicken.
I think they probably get out there and
like are like,
wait,
what am I doing?
Let's just like pace around and see if
we can just get through this 40 minutes
without.
It's so weird because they just exchange
partners.
They move back and forth like they,
they,
they square off and then they decide I
don't want to fight you.
I'm going to fight your friend.
Well,
it's so interesting because think about
it.
It's like these are not trained guys,
but it's like if you put 20 people
fighting,
there's no pressure to do it right away,
you know?
It's like when do you decide it's time
to take you to,
you know,
oh Jesus,
this is this guy.
But guy with the ball's going to go
through.
It's got to get through.
Yeah.
And then they're just talking shit like
that.
You look at that kick,
like how do you get.
Does no one know how to kick?
No.
I think most people,
unless they're in Thailand probably
don't.
I went and saw those fights in Thailand.
Doesn't want to watch those,
but the point is there's less violence.
So maybe your friend who is getting
brain damage at his gym who has no
business clown.
Oh well Brian,
Brian,
if Brian didn't get box,
I would be terrified at the things he
was doing in the city.
I think he needs to be in a gym getting
punched in the face a couple of hours a
day.
It's good for the people at crossfit.
No,
I mean I'm not,
I'm not negative about crossfit,
but the kind of people who have to get
that energy out,
I worry where that energy would go if
they weren't getting it out in competing
or fighting or boxing or whatever.
That's valid.
I think people feel better for sure when
they have that sort of a release and I
think there's a cathartic release and
any sort of like severe exertion,
but I think you can get the same
cathartic release from Yoga.
I really do.
I mean it's not as this really exciting
for a man.
It's not as satisfying.
It doesn't give you.
This sort of.
Channeling doesn't give you the
confidence.
Like Jujitsu is my favorite because you
so you can go full blast and you get
injured for sure,
but it's not the same kind of injuries
that you get usually from like
kickboxing and stuff like kickboxing.
Sparring to me is the most problematic
because I've seen how hard some people
can kick and I just know that if you zig
when you should've zagged and someone
decides to kick you harder and that
fucking Shin bounces off your head.
No,
I just know what can be done.
I've seen too much.
So like when I see that I'm like,
you are your bms.
BMX jumping with no helmet.
Okay.
Hopefully you're going to anything.
The Jungle Java.
It's just,
it's not about if it's about when.
Yeah,
well especially kickboxing.
Kickboxing to me is like.
I feel like even boxing is more.
As long as you're sparring with people
who you know are not going to hit you
hard least you've got a little bit more
control of this situation.
I mean I dunno.
It really resonate or like was profound
to me when you said that you know,
you have to fall to know you're not your
limitations,
but you know,
don't know how far ramifications you
have to understand that when I broke my
shoulder it changed my life.
Like it was actually something that
needed to happen because I've pushed
myself way too hard.
I had no respect for my body.
Like I just routinely abused it with
every,
in so many ways,
uh,
the people I surrounded myself with,
the things I ate,
the way that I lived.
I didn't sleep and it was like I needed
to be proven the fragility of my body.
Yeah.
Vulnerability.
Yeah,
totally.
Yeah.
And being able to go,
you know what?
No,
I don't think so.
I think I'm going to try to think like
more than two hours ahead right now and
not do that dangerous thing.
Well,
think about your body as if this
longterm thing and people have given me
a hard time about that too.
Like go,
like especially like lifting weights.
I've been wondering why your body is so
fucked up.
Like [inaudible].
I'll put like a video on instagram of me
working out my trainer,
but that the only way you can keep your
body from getting into sounds so
counterintuitive.
The only way that you can prevent
certain injuries is by making your body
strong.
Of course,
only way you can make your body strong
as you gotta lift heavy thing.
I'm also.
Do you have any interest or an
hypermobility?
Yes.
Hypermobile.
Hypermobile,
which I didn't know,
which means I lift things.
Everything from a weight to a Coffee Cup
with my joints,
not my muscles.
So I was using the term wrong then.
I know maybe I am too,
but it's um,
so western European trash,
which is,
I am basically just like alcoholics with
joint problems,
like a lot of western European genetics
means you're hyper mobile,
which is useful.
You're picking things up,
putting a lot of strain on your joints.
So when I pick something up,
it's my knees and my hips and my lower
back instead of my thigh muscles and my
glue.
Well,
that's one of the best things about
Kettlebell training in my opinion,
is that they're so awkward,
but it forces you to understand how to
use your body as a unit.
There's a lot of people that do
bodybuilding type workouts and the
isolation exercises,
although they make your muscles bigger.
Yeah.
They don't allow your body to
synchronize and use itself as one
individual.
Yeah.
Interesting.
That's how you get non collision
injuries.
Like when you hear about people who are
50 and they're like,
I sneezed and threw my back out.
That's because they've been putting
pressure on their joints instead of
their muscles for the longest time.
And I didn't have an ass.
Like I never use my glutes just walking
around and walking upstairs and picking
things up and whatever.
And uh,
and then I had to like relearn how to
walk and Shit.
I had to go to this fucking police thing
and like it was so fucking boring.
This was like three years ago was a
fucking nightmare.
Like literally,
you know how to walk.
You need to relearn how to walk and
you're like sitting in bed.
You can't sleep.
Fuck,
I
need to learn how to walk.
I'm going to do a documentary.
I'm going to write a book about how to
walk.
I'm going to learn how to walk.
I'm going to get.
I'm going to get fucking awesome it
learning how to walk.
I'm going to teach people how to walk.
That's what I do.
I'm going to go to China and teach kids
how to walk.
By the way,
that's my schedule for tomorrow.
Thanks.
Thanks for reminding me.
I mean you are one of those people,
like when you call me,
I say I'm doing a documentary on fucking
horseshit.
You walked over to them and if they lied
to you,
I know.
We don't know what it's like to be a
woman.
We believe lies,
so it's shit.
Yeah,
the world's flat.
Your Dick is huge.
There's a lot of lines going around it.
But someone telling you.
Right.
I was in a writers room once and I was
like,
thinking of this story where this,
these characters were going to have sex,
but then they didn't and I was like,
oh,
I have an idea.
What if the guy is allergic to
spermicide?
And everyone was like,
oh God.
I was like,
you know how like some guys are allergic
to spermicide so they can't use condoms.
Yeah.
It's like half of the guys I've dated
guys,
I was like,
they can't use condoms because there's
so allergic to it.
They were like,
you are the dumbest.
I was literally like at,
as I was saying,
and I was like,
oh wow.
Well I believe that some women are
allergic to spermicide.
Not only that,
but I've heard that some women are
actually allergic to different partners.
Sperm.
Interesting.
I think that's true.
Please Google sperm fertilizing eggs
frozen.
Then it's really bad reaction to our
cooler.
Something frozen eggs are fucking living
an amazing life in Hermosa beach.
They have a great view.
It'll a fault.
Yeah.
Like,
hey,
keep them cold.
I guess it's Cryo freeze.
I should probably just keep them down.
What if the power goes out?
I think about that all the time.
Greg goes down.
Is that one of the things in the middle
of the night that.
No,
they explained to me the generators and
all this stuff.
All I ever think about is when I'm in
hospitals.
What if the fucking power goes out,
know 33 and how many eggs did you store?
Where your eggs are still good?
Yeah,
they're really good.
Good.
For like another six years.
I just see an allergy ruined my
marriage.
Holy Shit.
Fourteen months after we were married,
I was diagnosed with humans seminal
plasma hypersensitivity and allergy to
seaman.
I'm taking,
oh my God,
I met Simon at a girlfriend's wedding
name changed to predict identity.
The faithful day changed my life in more
ways than I could've ever imagined.
So I wonder if she's allergic to some
dudes loads and not everyone's like,
where is it in her?
Is the allergy happening in her vagina
or in her face?
I just the that someone's wondering,
but I just am curious where like a her
throat itchy.
Well,
I wonder like what allergies guys have.
Are some guys allergic to eating pussy?
Okay.
Sperm analogy sometimes seem analogy.
Seminal.
Plasma hypersensitivity is a rare
allergic reaction to proteins.
Founded a man's semen mostly affects
women in the vaginal area.
Oh,
that's not good.
Pain.
Itching and a burning sensation of
vaginal area.
Oh,
that's awful.
Yeah,
it sounds not good.
Oh,
that's a bummer.
Mostly affects women.
Why?
Because mostly women catch loads.
Let me ask you something.
Well,
I'm always like,
what's the evolutionary purpose of
something?
I mean,
there's got to be an evolutionary
purpose to every allergy.
Is it?
There's just eliminate people.
Well,
that's what I'm saying.
Maybe evolution doesn't want this woman
to procreate that way.
It's random mutations and adaptations to
environmental changes.
It's what if this,
if,
if the,
uh,
yeah,
hold on.
They don't prove beneficial sample.
Right?
So,
pheromones,
if you're a fairmont smell good,
that means we should procreate.
Right?
And if they smell bad it means we're
probably related somehow.
That's when.
So to have a vagina flare up when sperm
goes in,
it is that nature's way of being like,
this woman has garbage.
Genetics may be the dude has weak loads.
Maybe if a man has some like fucking
stout loads get in there and your
vagina.
But like I'll tell you this.
This is good.
Yeah.
Maybe it's just bad loads,
but that's your area.
I don't know.
I'm going to not cast.
Was it Chris Ryan that was explained,
explaining,
write a book called about loads slow.
It's going to be my new podcast forward
by Brian.
I'm just going to talk about load.
Slept three hours twice a week,
so I'm really interested in loans.
We shouldn't have to do my first sexing
actual sex next week.
Yeah.
And more.
And let her literally.
There's so much time and energy has gone
into.
Where does his Dick go?
Where does,
where does everything go?
When is it for a t shirt?
It's very shallow.
So it's going to be a lot of people in
the set.
Yeah,
I mean they'll probably minimize
unnecessary people that day.
Like you got a dude who was friends with
who did a sexy with a girl and they're
making out and she goes,
if you want you could go ahead and fuck
me.
And he was like,
nope.
It was like the moment you said that,
the type of girl that says like,
if you could fuck me a b movie,
it wasn't even a b movie,
you know,
it's like some no name nonsense
production.
And they were,
you know,
making out.
And she just said,
you can go ahead and fuck.
He's more.
He likes them to say no more.
Return on down.
He can fuck me,
please let me.
Well,
I bet he was probably terrified of not
being able to get it up in front of all
those peoples.
Well,
well,
yeah,
that's.
I mean we were kind of trying to figure
it out because we're like,
okay,
there's going to be an erection.
Do we just might not be.
You say there's going to be,
but there might not be an erection if
there's not one job,
I will be crying hysterically that he
will get loud because guys are into that
during the crying.
Yeah.
I did an episode with Chris about this.
Um,
one time he was crying and the guy I was
trying to interaction like red flag you
like week with sad women.
There are some people that have a hard
time with someone who is not insecure.
They're insecure.
So if they're insecure and the woman is
confident,
they panic and then they could get,
they could have a problem getting an
erection.
But if the woman like all of a sudden
needs comforting and she's insecure,
then they assume this position.
Oh yeah.
Interesting.
So I should be brilliant.
Secure.
I will be anyway.
Well,
I don't know.
Like what is like I was thinking about
this the other day,
there's two voices that are just
absolute bullshit that just don't work,
but we,
we know them as archetypes and one of
them is like,
one of them is like the spooky voice,
like no one's scared of this spooky and
no ones.
And then the sexy girl call one 800,
suck my pussy.
You know what I mean?
Like that.
Fuck,
please don't ever stop.
Got Anyone.
Everyone's different.
But,
but you know what I'm saying?
It's like,
you know,
hey boys doing that doesn't work on
anybody can do it.
So men can.
Men can pretend to be what I mean.
Like I don't know any women who were
like,
well,
you know what I mean,
if you're just seeing those commercials,
those late night phone call,
commercial call,
late night commercials at 2:00
AM or not guys like you that are guys
who are probably more susceptive who are
Beta males who need someone even more
Beta than them.
So maybe that's why they have to be
like,
but it's the naughty girl.
Do you want to call Ashley Madison?
Come?
Yeah.
It's like,
why are you whispering?
She wanted to be not.
Well,
maybe it's because they know that the
wife's in the next room and friend.
I'm like,
Hey,
just call fucking nine already.
That's not sexy.
Not Suck my pussy.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Why didn't you call me?
He was like other archetypes,
right?
Like the Strip club,
Dj voice,
the top 40 Dj voice,
those archives,
the politician voice.
That's an archetype,
right?
Annoying wife.
Yes.
Voice.
Sure.
I find myself in.
I stopped doing this because I realized
I'm exacerbating the problem.
I get very triggered and annoyed by
stereotypes.
Like the stereotype that guys are dumb
really annoys me and I dumb.
No,
I don't think guys are dumb.
Guys are you're designed to only.
Most people are.
No,
I just mean like in terms of why don't
you remember my friend Audrey's name.
You've met her three times.
It's like guys are only really
remembered designed to remember things
if there's some kind of threat attached
to it and it's just your brains are
because like we're designed to sort of
in a team way for me to be hypervigilant
and be like,
there's a fucking lion and you go break
down everything to like some primitive
tribe that is always think there.
People find things memorable because
they're interesting and they're
fascinating people.
Things that are totally unthreatened.
Is Andrea interesting or fascinating
too?
I don't know.
Algeria,
so maybe she is.
She's cool as fuck.
Yeah.
Maybe Dr Audrey Ph day,
but I just mean like some benign friend
of your girl or whatever.
Um,
and got.
I mean and then because it's also,
that's something that I love about my,
a man.
Like if you're fixing something,
I want you to only be focusing on that.
Guys.
Don't multitask in the same way.
You know?
I just think they call guys dumb.
It's just as glorifying a neurotic
multitasking,
you know,
overworked or glorification of busy
type.
That's the new thing.
Guys that are just like simple.
You know,
I just.
People are so varied though I'm really
more hesitant to generalize.
The older men or women are crazy.
Men are stupid.
That thing is just to me,
so I'm general.
It's just a generalization that I think
is really not helpful at all and
annoying.
It makes people comfort.
It gives them comfort to sort of
classify people.
Totally.
Yeah.
Like you don't have to look at it.
Oh,
what happened with Debbie?
She's a crazy bitch.
It's like,
it's easy to say she's a crazy bitch.
Instead of say,
well,
I was raised kind of fucked up,
but I really don't like her because she
didn't,
she wasn't heard his child secure
stronger than I did and it's just,
it's got.
That'd be the dominant one.
She's smarter than me on this too much
already.
Why did we get on that topic?
There was something.
Oh,
the Beta males loads.
We're talking about stop loads coming in
hot load stone.
It was something about the Beta males.
Uh Oh.
And the archetypes like dump because Oh,
this is it.
I've found in my stand up,
I'd be like into.
My boyfriend was like,
Ooh,
what are you doing?
And I'm like,
guys don't sound like that.
What am I doing?
You know?
But it's funny.
Point taken.
Nevermind it.
Sometimes I'll put a girl in my acts.
I'd be like,
yeah,
oh my God,
I know that girl exists.
Yay.
I just feel like a prime.
Most species under attack,
right?
So know how to walk.
I pick things up with my joints,
knees,
and my back is just gonna like break and
have extra bone in my foot.
Hey God,
I'm allergic to that and get it away
from me,
from my frozen eggs.
Freeze them with my eggs.
I side just in case you can combine it.
Some stories that all you need is come
and eggs.
You want to freeze an embryo,
which means the,
uh,
the sperm fertilize.
Say,
Hey Joe,
can I ask some of your sperm,
fertilize my,
then put it in the freezer and then put
it back in.
My body seems so creepy.
Zombie demands total science fiction
embryo gets frozen and then you could
turn that into life.
But it only healthy choice dinner.
Yeah.
But it only works like,
okay.
So an embryo will eventually become a
human being,
so that little embryo was already
fertilizes.
The egg gets fertilized and you could
freeze that,
but you can't freeze a 13 year old.
Nope.
No.
What I'm saying know like there's a
cutoff period.
Should we could at some point just not
yet.
I think we could.
Yeah,
I think it's going to happen.
I think these fucking [inaudible] guys,
these assholes that are shooting stem
cells and the DM people's heads,
those fuckers
look lot of alive people who need that.
But um,
yeah,
that is a crime I,
I mean I imagined it because it doesn't
have a brain and blood.
It doesn't have to be warm.
Like
Maria's not be warm.
Humans I guess have to a certain body
temperature.
I mean,
I mean that's like some Austin powers
shit,
but even a sell to me,
I mean it was an individual cell.
Like if the egg has been fertilized and
the creative one sell the idea that you
could freeze that fucking cell before it
divides and becomes a full on human
being.
The idea that you could freeze that one
cell and then regenerate it.
That was crazy.
Honestly,
I don't know how people do like,
it's so.
I guess that's why I tried to read so
much yet because I'm like,
I don't understand how I can't even
understand what these people are doing
and I'm not even doing it.
Well,
it's so standard today too.
I mean,
which is so really fascinating because
if you brought this concept to someone
200 years ago or even 100 years ago,
they think you're out of your fucking
mind,
but it's,
it sounds fucking crazy.
It does sound like I'm sucking them out
of your fucking over.
I'm like,
okay.
Do you remember John and Kate plus
eight?
Of course.
Remember that crazy lady.
They shot the fucking those chemicals
inside of her body to make her more
fertile and she gave birth to six kids.
Yeah.
Yes.
OCTOMOM.
Yeah.
What the fuck?
Optima optima have a lot of money.
I think the only reason I remember that
because people on twitter say I looked
like her,
uh,
when they're just being mean.
But uh,
yeah,
it's,
I mean it's a,
it I've never felt like more of a
science project,
you know,
it's like the human body that kind of a
miracle.
But when he's this sort of intersection
between technology and life or like
mother nature is so weird.
It's like he's in there and he's like
with a wand and it says this with the
soul and now you're going and what,
uh,
the,
yeah,
it's not a very sexy or romantic
process.
It's very clinical sort of rough and
he's and in my ovaries are on a high def
television.
It's just like that for those two things
to be in this like intersect.
It's just so weird and you're just
looking at all your follicles.
And I was convinced for the first couple
of sessions that it was just like a
feed,
like everyone saw the same feed because
I was like,
there's just no way you can see inside
my body.
Like,
I mean
I just,
I like,
this is just a video tape you put in.
Everybody comes in.
It's the same thing.
There's just no way you can see inside
my body is dark on the inside obviously.
Like I intellectually,
I can't fathom it.
Like it's just to,
um,
to have to.
Obviously everybody is.
I think it seems like all my follicles,
he's like,
this one's a different size.
I'm like,
how the fuck do you know that it looks
like a haunted house to me.
I can't understand anything.
It looks like paranormal activity.
I mean it looks like a fucking
nightmare.
And uh,
and then I go and then I'm sure enough
you get like four.
I looked like I was like four or five
months pregnant,
you know,
and I'm doing these shots every day and
I'm like,
it was like,
this is so fucking crazy.
So it makes your stomach stick out more
because I had 18 big swollen ecs.
Yeah,
I have a picture of it somewhere.
I'll send it to you and I look like five
months pregnant and it's just like,
Whoa,
you know,
it's usually caused for our alarm.
So to spend money to look like that.
And then,
uh,
yeah.
And then you go in and they suck them
all out.
Now what made you decide to do that?
You know,
like one day have a kid,
I am going to one day have a kid.
What he said to me was this,
he was like,
look,
because I was like,
I know my next year and a half,
two years it's gonna be a little bit
hectic and I'm probably not going to
get.
He was like,
this might not be for your first or
second kid.
It could be a for your fourth.
Like when you're 44 and you're like,
you don't have to have one more.
Or like I'm going to have a surrogate,
you know?
Oh Jesus.
It was literally just like an insurance
policy.
A adopting.
It depends.
So adopting is a kind of a nightmare.
A lot of my friends have been going
through it.
You sign up for it and you're waiting
for the baby to be born and the mother
might change their mind.
So the mother has,
I think two days to decide whether she
wants to keep the baby or not after she
gives birth.
And that's of course when her brain is
fade and oxytocin after having it and a
lot of couples go down to nine month
journey and don't get a kid.
But if you do it from a different
country,
it's a little different of a couple of
gay friends.
The hard surrogate.
What is it,
a surrogate surrogate even for gay
people?
Yeah,
I guess they use their own come.
I don't know.
I think just a cooler shot it into a
Turkey based.
It had to have been one or the other.
I don't think they knew.
Anyway,
they paid this woman for the last 150
grand.
They paid her for a year and then when
the baby was born she decided to keep
it.
No,
that's the.
That's the lawyers fault.
There must've been something.
She's decided to keep it.
I don't think you could force a woman
to.
You might be able to force her to give
the money back or some of the money
back.
Well,
you could sue for the money back,
but I don't know the.
You could take the baby away.
That's insane.
In California,
the mother has.
I think all the rights,
I think once the baby comes out of her
body,
she's probably like,
well listen,
that's my fucking baby.
How do you want to make this work?
Yeah,
I mean it's really a total chemical
bonding thing.
We'll also.
The might've been like some severe
desperation in her life that made her
take this position as being a surrogate
mother in the first place and the money
gave her.
Might have alleviated St Louis problems
that were causing
her to be so desperate that she wanted
to have a surrogate baby.
That's very interesting problems.
Dark for them.
It was like really breaking.
It was heartbreaking,
but it was also like,
wow,
well it's all so fucking baby.
I mean,
she grew in her body like
logically.
So have,
you know,
friends with surrogates and and you.
It's very stressful because you want to
micromanage what they're eating if
they're sleeping.
But something that was helpful that I
learned was that if a baby's not getting
the nutrients it needs it,
we'll take it from his mother's bones.
So if you're a surrogate is eating
McDonald's,
your kids
be fine.
You're the carrier.
Is the one that's going to suffer a
little parasites just sucking and
fucking suck calcium out of your
babies?
Totally.
They suck up brain cells from the mother
to.
I mean,
they're fucking vampires.
So dominant.
Ten percent of their.
No,
they're just tired all the time,
I think is what it is.
They're duplicating.
I mean it's like,
it's a metamorphosis.
It's like a fucking piss.
A lot of work,
but a nightmare.
Yeah.
It's just crazy that that's the energy.
It's the ultimate buyer of traffic.
The thing that we look forward to the
most,
the thing that sells cars and fucking TV
shows,
long legs and sax and hate.
And what is it really?
It's about coming in someone and making
a person in their body.
I mean,
it's really like this ultimate
biological trick of replication.
Do you,
uh,
have you ever heard of this book called.
It's a stupid name,
but cubits poisoned arrow.
It's about what orgasms do to your brain
and the whole sort of theory is to not
have an orgasm unless you're going to
actually procreate because of the
chemicals that are released.
It's,
it's,
I don't know who wrote that book.
What kind of monster?
Yeah.
Sex addicts that.
No,
that's the best way to clear your mind
is to shoot a load.
I know,
but it's something about your golf and
your thought process is so much clear.
Like there's so many times that I've
told my friends like,
you know what?
I wanted to do mood.
She's pressuring me.
Jerk off first.
Then think about it.
Just go jerk off man.
Tell me after you jerked off,
if you want to deal with all this
emotional bullshit that's being thrown
at you.
Um,
hold on.
Will you,
I'll send this to you.
I remember reading it and while I was
reading I was like,
yeah,
this makes a lot of sense.
I mean,
I don't want to live like that,
but it makes a lot of sense.
Well,
it's something about how if you want to
stay in love with someone long term,
because if you have too many orgasms,
if you produce dopamine and then after,
because essentially we're designed to
procreate like you said,
and then the female starts producing
oxytocin,
but the mail starts being less
interested in the brain is like,
okay,
now you have to go procreate with
someone else because our brain doesn't
know that are 6 billion people on the
planet and that we don't need to fucking
broke rate with a lot of different moms.
Uh,
so it's something about if you want to
be in a relationship for a long time.
So it's like a tantric type thing.
It kind of,
you know what,
I'll send it to you.
It's like it's basically about.
I stopped reading after like four pages,
so I was like,
I'm never going to fucking is.
It's about keeping Oxytocin,
the bonding chemical alive with couples.
Oh,
that's crazy.
So they're trying
to hack couples.
Yes they are.
That's ridiculous.
How much does find someone that you
actually like,
that's too easy,
but it's Kinda in La.
Is that possible?
Of course.
Can Be done everywhere.
Who would you be doing?
Who Do I think you should do?
I don't know.
We'll find somebody.
We need to find you.
Somebody.
I'm dating somebody,
but it's not working out obviously.
I'm just curious.
Who Do you think I should date?
Curious.
Like I've cure.
I'm just curious.
I'm curious.
You're a.
You always have interesting balance.
I think the person I'm dating
that idea but I'm sure a lot so I think
and I mean that in the best way,
but you're very smart and you're very
ambitious and you're.
You're interested in a lot of different
things and you have to have someone who
is similar in some ways,
nightmare.
You know,
that know someone that I honestly
believe that in order for someone like
you because I think you're an outlier in
a lot of ways in that you're a liar,
liar.
That outlying aspect of your personality
because you're.
I think you have to.
Someone has to be an outlier in some way
of their own in order for them to
appreciate you because otherwise they're
just gonna think like,
I can't keep up with this crazy bitch.
This is too much,
you know,
she,
she doesn't sleep,
she gets up in the middle of night,
starts writing books and learn how to
walk again.
It's like,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
I'm like the guy,
the grandpa from Charlotte and of bed.
Well there's a lot of benefits to your
type of behavior.
Obviously.
That's why you're so successful.
It's a lot of benefits to what you
think,
but the negative side aspect of it
though,
the where I would say it's going to be
problematic is someone has to like for
companionship.
Someone has to be able to keep up with
you or understand you or accept you and
what the way you think and the way you
approach life is extremely different.
It's not the way most people do it and
not the way most women do it for sure.
And if men are used to this certain type
of patterns that some women follow and
then you have this pattern,
you know,
they're going to be like,
oh,
it's just,
I don't want.
I just want to grow.
Complains about starbucks,
you know,
coconut milk,
camel milk,
what do we do it and goat's milk.
I think,
you know,
when I hate saying stupid shit that
people repeat,
but I think this,
this repeated thing is when you're
ready,
you'll find something.
Yeah,
that's.
you're right.
Because I.
and I think there's like.
I think a relationship really doesn't
work unless you yourself are ready for a
relationship too.
That's a really good point.
You have to be someone that someone
would want to be in a relationship with
it all the time.
I'm like,
how about stop focusing on the other
person?
What I want to date me once I get into a
place where I would want to date me or
marry me.
Yeah.
And people think they're going to find
someone,
a person is going to calm them down and
then they're going to be someone that's
worth dating.
Yeah.
That's often calm yourself down,
right?
Solve your own problems and then.
Yeah.
Hold on.
I've been fucking song and dance for the
first couple weeks of the relationship
until like a buddy of mine had this girl
that he was dating for a while and then
his car broke down and he needed her to
help him.
Like he,
his tire blew out and uh,
I forgot the whole story,
but she helped him in some sort of a
way.
Like she came and got him or something
like that.
And then she stayed over the house and
then the next day she texted him like
five fucking times in a row and he
didn't text her back and then she left.
That's crazy message about now she's
going to need therapy and she has trust
issues.
And so it was like,
just what the fuck he was working all
day.
He's like,
I'm just working all day.
I had one day where I tried to put my
phone aside and concentrate on my work
and you're just blowing up my fucking
phone and I didn't text you back.
Now you need therapy.
Like there's certain people that you
enter into any sort of an intimate
relationship with them and you're taking
on the burden of all this,
which is exactly why I all this self
shed.
Maybe it comes up super masturbatory and
like narcissistic,
but I was like,
I'm done being crazy.
It's not crazy by saying I'm done being
crazy.
That's crazy.
But here's the thing,
I don't it.
It's cute in your twenties.
It's not cute in your thirties to text a
guy five times in a row.
I don't want lack of awareness.
I do not.
Exactly.
So I want to be able to go,
oh,
this is my shit.
This has nothing to do with him.
Like I have abandoned terror and data
and like solve my accounts.
Terror,
terror.
It's called abandonment.
That expression before infant maternal
disruption.
So I have a band Materra,
which means I didn't hit the brakes,
were always in here and it doesn't.
As soon as we start winding down,
I'd throw out some shit like that.
Like sperm allergy,
environmental disruption.
What's going on with your foot?
Nice talking.
I can't get my fucking tesla.
Get outta here.
No.
Uh,
when you didn't get enough eye contact
as a kid,
basically you have infant maternal
disruption,
like you weren't able to get the
connection.
So when,
um,
when you don't get a text back or
whatever,
it starts triggering really old
abandonment terror.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
So that girl is broken like something
happened from the ages of one to three
that now is manifesting in five text
messages,
you know,
but you have to get control of your own
shit.
You got to clean up your own yard.
You got to fix it.
That's why I'm in 12 step programs.
I'm in,
I do Emdr,
I'm in a fuck.
I'm on all sorts of shit because I'm
just like,
I'm not gonna just be a puppet of this.
What happened to me when I was three for
the rest of my life and I'm not gonna
punish the guys.
I date for it.
It's not your fault,
but even talking about as punishment.
Well,
I don't.
So in pro and I know that we're not even
dating and me talking about,
it's like
instrument to me so fast with me.
So in program we don't go to the problem
for the solution,
so it's like if the problem is you're
not texting me back,
I'm not going to go to you and say,
Hey,
text me back,
I'm going to go figure out the solution
and then take the solution to the
problem,
to the relationship.
Well I'm a big believer in the path of
least resistance when it comes to
relationships.
And if someone doesn't want to text you
back,
you probably shouldn't be hanging out
with them.
It's pretty simple.
So like to like chase after people.
It's an instinct.
People have it like God,
why didn't they call me back?
But a lot of us.
How come you didn't text me back?
You fuck a lot.
I guess we're not texting back and visit
a Sikh people whose approval we don't
have her whose attention we don't have
because we didn't get it or why I think
text messages and even voicemail
messages in a,
in a way or weird in that like you send
somebody something and then you wait for
them to respond and you hold and the
like,
all right,
come on out there.
What do we got here?
It's like send a raven to fucking scroll
attention because it's like if I text,
you know,
text me back and then I see that you
posted an instagram.
There's this whole fucking thing.
Which did happen the other day.
Joe,
now Joe Jogi definitely.
But there's this new thing of how I can
see all the other things you're doing on
your phone instantly.
So I'm now all of a sudden like,
well you fucking responded to three's
these tweets,
you know,
stock from fucking Ronda,
but you didn't text me back.
It turns into that shotgun,
Rhonda.
So I'm not going to start with her.
Love her very much.
Which one you're talking about?
Oh,
oh,
have the doctor.
Rhonda.
Rhonda Rousey Rousey,
I thought you were just making people's
names.
Oh No,
no.
I just was trying to think of someone
who you might tweet with it or tweet
about or something.
Um,
but uh,
but yeah,
so now I think with all of these other
things,
it makes things,
it makes it harder to just solely focus
on the purity of did he text me back or
not?
It's like he didn't text me back,
but he did all these other things on his
phone.
It was just human beings enter into
relationships.
Even friendships like.
And when I say relationship,
I don't mean sexual,
just like any time that you're relating
to other people,
it's the person that you're hanging
around with.
They change how you are like you,
you are who you are.
You have like this base and then you
might be lighter around certain people
or friend.
Totally.
There's like a chemical reaction that
you have to people's personalities.
Instantly.
When I see a comic I stopped trying to
be funny.
It's the best thing.
Like I,
I'm not like don't ever make jokes,
but as soon as I'm going to comment,
I'm like,
ah,
I don't have to try to make you laugh.
Oh,
okay.
So you feel like when you're around
people that aren't comics,
like you're almost obligated because I
know you're funny.
Yeah.
It's like your thing about,
it's just different reactions.
Certain people trigger different things
and it's like that may be your own
expectations of what you think people
want to be.
Could be or it's like the performance or
the show or the costume I put on to
avoid intimacy or to having to really
connect to somebody.
Do you think that like with every day in
every hour and every time you obsessed
and all these things and all these
different paths that you go down,
like every day gets a little better
every day,
get a little better at it,
get a little better at life.
Yes,
yes.
And if I haven't,
I'm like,
you know,
but it depends on also what comes up
because it's like,
you know,
sometimes you're like fucking nailing it
and then a trigger comes along and
you're like,
I didn't even know that was a trigger
that was weird,
you know,
or like a totally new stimulus.
Dynamic comes along.
The instagram is invented.
Like I'm nailing it with guys they can,
they don't have to text me back.
I feel great.
And then they put up my shit now
instagram was fucking invented and now I
have to see what they're doing and that
I have to compare,
you know?
So it's like,
it's,
our environments are changing so fast.
It's hard for our sort of emotional and
mental progress to keep up with all
these new sort of curve balls unless you
turn your phone block and should off
just all like have you ever.
Oh yeah.
If I have to put so like a chastity belt
on my phone,
I like,
it's,
I,
I have to protect and when I drive I
have to put in the backseat because I
will text and drive in the back seat.
I put it in the back seat because I
don't trust myself because I literally
will just look,
I'll just be driving and I'll look down
and all of a sudden I'm on my phone.
I'm like,
what the fuck?
This is so dangerous.
It's so you go unconscious.
Yeah.
And I rear ended somebody like.
And it wasn't like email.
I literally just looked down at my
phone.
I was like pulling up to a stop sign and
I thought I was stopped and uh,
you know,
they say that uh,
uh,
texting is now worse than drunk driving.
More people die from texting and driving
and driving and I don't even think it's,
I just,
yeah,
I just think it's not going to happen to
me.
I don't know what magical fucking addict
thinking I'm doing,
but I literally will just like look down
at my phone and I ran into this guy and
I was like,
I'm so sorry.
Totally my fault.
And I was like,
that's going to be my rock bottom.
It wasn't bad at all.
It was like a little ding and I was
okay.
That needed to happen.
I need,
don't you think that your ideas of what
is going to happen or based on what's
already happened and nothing's happened
yet,
so you assume,
well,
I'm in the car,
I'm driving.
Nothing happens when I'm driving,
I'm finding the valley.
What's the,
what am I going to die in a car
accident.
I mean it's like,
that's not the story I wrote for myself,
but no one gives a fuck about that.
No one has that script,
right?
Everyone's isn't.
Everyone isn't running around,
you know,
trying to make sure I stay alive
and that brings it all back to like you
go into Vietnam and you experiencing of
another possibility that like you or I
were both really lucky they were born in
America,
were born white,
wealthy people in America too.
I mean not born it but you know,
I wasn't either but we're lucky.
We're lucky as fuck.
Like this situation with this situation
wasn't possible.
Literally live in Vr.
I feel like what I realized is like know
because when everyone's like,
I'm tired.
Like everyone's like this.
Just like people love being sick to love
it.
They fucking love it.
I don't feel good.
I have a headache.
I have this.
I have a thyroid thing.
When you think about having sicknesses
are just distractions though,
right?
Lyme disease or whatever.
The fight if you really.
Lyme disease.
I'm so sorry.
Tim Ferriss.
So sorry.
But I mean,
is lyme disease?
He had it.
Yeah,
it was like,
I think really bad.
Um,
but like,
I mean everyone's like,
I'm tired.
I think I have lyme disease.
I'm like no,
people really have lyme disease or
people are like,
I'm allergic to gluten.
I'm like,
do you have celiac disease?
Are you,
do you just need to be sick because it
gets you attention,
like you know,
and then you go to a place where people
are actually saying and actually have
problems and it just,
it just really changes your perspective.
Did you ever see that Louis C K bit
about being white?
Probably,
but it makes me think of the one cause
I,
cause I was thinking this isn't a bit I
do obviously,
but I just remember after being in
Vietnam,
I was like,
we should just walk around all the time.
It'd be like,
that's awesome.
This is so cool.
Like we should.
It should just constantly be like,
oh my God,
this is water in this bottle.
He has this amazing bit where he's like,
you could go back to any time in history
and it would be amazing.
He's like,
that's the thing about being white and
it's like being white is great.
He goes,
you can go back 200 years ago.
You don't have to worry about being a
slave is like
just white people.
Irish people didn't have it so good for
awhile.
While there's definitely some mean it's
a joke,
but take that low.
What about the Irish found little
debunking your bit,
but he also.
That thing about everything is amazing
and all we do is complain about the,
about the flying and people.
Like my flight was $45.
I went on this hunting trip in Prince of
Wales Island,
which is in Alaska and it's unbelievably
rainy.
I mean we were just drenched for six
days and I just thought in my head for
some reason that you'd be dry when you
get in the tent.
I'd be like,
well,
once you get the tech,
it'd be dry,
but you never really get dry because the
air is wet and there's mist everywhere,
so everything's wet.
You're sleeping bags soaking wet.
The only thing that saves you and keeps
you warm is the fact that you're wearing
wool.
Wool retains body heat even when it's
wet.
Unlike cotton and a lot of synthetic
fabrics don't do it.
Oh,
interesting.
But wool is amazing.
It's an animal,
right?
Yeah,
an animals.
Exactly.
So like when you have wool socks on,
even if your feet are wet,
you're still warm.
Wool is.
The Shit is just so important for people
that are in the outdoors,
like wool undergarment probably.
I think wolves get them more than the
cold,
but I mean.
Oh,
good point.
Okay,
got it.
Sorry.
I was like,
I thought you meant wolf hair.
wolves have.
Whoa,
whoa.
That's their.
Their hair is a wall.
Sorry.
Point was that,
um,
so six days in this soaked environment,
just every day,
just being just completely wet,
everything's wet.
Everything you do is what your face is
like.
A sheen that you could feel it on you,
it's like you're just wet and cold and
that came back and it was sunny and it
was 80 and I was like,
this is amazing.
And I was driving around in La and I'm
like,
I love it here.
It's so.
And I called my friend Steve.
Same Guy,
Steven Alan.
I called him up and I go,
dude,
I am so fucking happy.
I've never been this happy,
but it's because I was miserable for
those.
It's so important
to have it.
Every shade it.
Yes,
I was in,
in Vietnam,
like I said,
they wear masks.
I went for a run with this motherfucker.
Who back to your point about flat feet.
He's like the marathon guy who was like,
you're supposed to run barefooted.
Right?
So he's barefoot run guy and this was
the first non barefoot Ron who's done
because it was in Vietnam and there's
just like,
you shouldn't last nightmare and just
dead animals.
It was dysentery.
Just babies by the way.
Also just kids everywhere.
I'm like,
do you have a parent?
Like,
I mean,
there's just like three year old
toddlers just running businesses can
literally like,
excuse me,
like,
do you work here like you literally will
do,
so I'll send you some of the photos.
You'll see a kid just at a store alone
and you're like,
what is avenue?
So fucking dangerous and uh,
and everyone's in mass,
they can't breathe the oxygen there.
And we went for a run and I came back
and I felt like I had smoked four packs
of cigarettes and I came back to La.
And even just doing that was like a
little mini miracle.
Did you ever see that?
There's a story that was written about
Mark Zuckerberg who was in China and he
went for a run during like one of the
worst days,
one of the worst pollution days.
And he's out there jogging around and
you know,
you look at the air behind them,
it's like,
Ugh,
you're jogging into like an exhausting
pipe.
Could he did,
he just doesn't see.
I mean it's,
it's hard.
Can you wanted to experience it because,
you know,
just to know.
I mean,
he's an interesting guy.
he's obviously very thoughtful guy and I
think that maybe he wanted to experience
it was just because
just to know those people,
I can pay for it.
Whatever happens to me so we can get new
lungs,
I'll just get some fucking stem cells to
regenerate Brianna Mahon,
my lungs.
But uh,
but yeah,
I mean,
and that's the,
I think.
And I also like,
once you see that kind of pollution,
it's like,
you know,
because it's,
there's so many charities and there's so
many fucking problems.
You can't try to solve all of them or
be,
you know,
such a small part.
But I was like,
oh,
this is the first time that I was like,
I needed like only Dubai,
you know,
there's like carbon neutral companies
and companies that,
you know,
put less emissions out and stuff and
you're like,
yeah,
I should start voting with things I buy.
And you know,
it's the first time I got this app that
tells you what companies don't emit as
much pollution,
you know,
stuff like that.
And I'm like,
I never really thought about that before
until I was breathing in like viscous
toxic air.
Well,
it's interesting because just being a
human being,
just by the nature,
the nature of our existence,
we consume constantly and we're
constantly using things that are
detrimental to the environment and
people will concentrate on certain
things.
Like,
Hey,
I ride my bike everywhere.
So my carbon footprint is less.
Yeah,
but you're still using plastic
motherfucker.
That shit goes into garbage.
Totally,
totally.
Wastes refilling.
What are those called?
The landfills to landfills.
They wind up getting into the ocean,
like all the stuff that we do has an
effect all of it.
100 percent.
Like this idea that you're immune
because you ride your bike everywhere or
because you have an electric car.
That one drives me fucking crazy because
by the way,
those electric cars,
those fucking minerals,
those cards has apparently.
Cause they are not recyclable right now.
Well,
not only that,
their conflict minerals,
a lot of the batteries,
they're getting the minerals from places
that are like,
they're there.
There's a real issue with where they're
getting this,
these minerals to make these batteries
like that's one of the big things about
Afghanistan,
like one of the big things about Canada
and they found trillions of dollars
worth of lithium in the,
in the mountains and they believe it's
one of the reasons why we're there in
the first place.
There's,
there's all sorts of.
There's all sorts of natural resources
that the Soviets wanted out of
Afghanistan.
The natural gas pipeline.
It's one of the main reasons why they
believe that some of the neo-cons we're
very interested in protecting and
invading Afghanistan is not just the
poppy business,
which is huge.
Look,
it's a giant fucking business and the
idea that,
well,
we wouldn't have anything to do with
that because it's not illegal or because
it's illegal.
Well,
that's not true because if you look at
what happened in Vietnam,
Vietnam,
a big part of the reason why people were
in Vietnam,
why some people supportive being in
Vietnam is because they were profiting
off controlling the heroin trade.
That's a fact.
There was a fucking trillion dollars
made during the Vietnam War from heroin
sales and where it was made and why and
who got the money and where the
corruption took place and where the
money was being handed out.
That's all open to speculation and
research and maybe someone will
eventually have it all figured out one
day,
but the reality is there was a massive
amount of fucking heroin that was being
moved.
Whoa,
Jesus Christ.
I'm getting crazy heroin.
Nothing happened.
I got lucky dude.
So like that.
Your coffee is made of like coconut oil
and butter that it's like white barely
move your coffee.
It's like,
it's like,
it's like lava.
It's thick plastic like my stout loads,
but my point being that these batteries
that they're making these fucking car
batteries out of there.
It's like Afghanistan sits on
$1,000,000,000,000
in minerals.
You're telling me that they're not there
partially for that or that someone is
not looking at that as saying like,
hey,
maybe we should figure out how to suck
those fucking minerals out of the ground
and make a trillion dollars.
Like the idea that we're not.
It's crazy the idea that that's not a
part of the equation is utter complete
nonsense and I think that the amount of
minerals that are in these fucking car
batteries is something we really need to
look at because I was reading this whole
piece about conflict minerals and how
non-green electric cars actually are.
Have you stop and look at it like.
Yeah.
As far as like our environment.
Yes,
for sure.
They definitely pollute our environment
less,
but if we look at the actual
repercussions of creating these things,
like how are these minerals being
sourced?
How are they these batteries?
What,
what are the,
what's the adverse effects of creating
these batteries?
It's not clean and free.
So people run around saying,
I drive my electric car and you know,
and uh,
I only eat organic and so I'm free of
any
know you're free of bullshit.
You're free of your own,
your own bullshit gal because.
Yeah.
But business being a fucking human,
being a human,
you're using things were consumed.
Yeah.
We should all consume less,
most certainly,
but like even people will only
vegetables and grains,
God damn large scale green operations
destroy massive amounts of wildlife,
habitat,
displaced animals killed.
Those grain combines are completely
indiscriminate.
They chew up rodents and fucking deer
fawns and ground nesting birds and
forget about insects.
Can you get me started on the bees
bugs?
Just bugs alone.
I mean,
what do we have a hierarchy of what we
will and won't allow being killed.
We have these ideas well,
well like animals exhibit fear and
emotions and react to our environment so
we shouldn't kill them.
But bees or insects like a mosquito.
Well that's a different thing because
that's life but it's not
no fees.
It's like be the source of everything
but like mosquitoes,
mosquitoes,
mosquitoes carry diseases and they
checked the.
Yeah,
they mosquitoes make sure the population
stays low,
but arguably like insects are probably
one of the best sources of protein that
we could ever get stalled.
I felt like there was an insect protein
movement happening and it just sort of.
Well,
I think it's a perception issue because
I think a lot of people have the idea
that one,
when I was in Mexico recently,
they they serve crickets like the hotel
we were at.
They will.
They have these like they look like
they're stir fried
crickets and they left him in our hotel
room.
It was like a snack was covered with
Saran wrap.
Nobody ate it,
but me,
of course I fucking fear factor you
guys.
It was literally eating,
but you've seen all that,
but they all ate them like regularly
there they were eating these because
it's like we'll eat snails lead frog
legs.
It's like,
well there is a very weird line.
Maybe in our line is different than like
the Yulin dog festival line.
Don't we can talk about that.
Fascinating.
But yeah.
But when I was in A.
Yeah,
in Vietnam,
the stuff that they was like jellyfish
and squared,
it was a lot of,
I guess what's available in that region.
It's probably 100 percent,
but yeah,
there was so much more.
Uh,
we feel like a meeting,
a jellyfish,
willing to them.
They're just sucking jellyfish.
I know
bugs to me are really a fascinating
thing because one of the things that we
found out when we were doing fear factor
is that our ge,
so like if you have an allergy to
certain shellfish,
you also have an allergy to Roaches,
Huh?
Yeah.
So,
uh,
we found that out the hard way lawsuit.
But bugs
are an excellent source of protein and
people don't have the same emotional
attachment
to a bug,
but we have a visceral negative reaction
like repulsion to them.
Right?
But if they did something but it was
ground up in some sort of a protein
peddling cricket protein is real.
You've ever cricket bar now?
Protein bars are good.
Oh,
here we go.
Look at this.
Expo crickets.
The future of protein,
soy,
dairy,
grain and gluten free.
Paleo and environmentally friendly.
Yeah.
I'll eat the shit out of some crickets.
Do they taste like anything bad?
It just tastes like soy protein or
something.
It's not like you're eating lobster,
but it's not like you're eating shit.
Cricket bars.
It's not like you're eating lobster,
but I wonder.
It's not like you're eating shit because
there's the ultimate debate.
There's a lot of people that are like
really strict vegetarians and they're
not eating vegan because they want to
leave the least amount of footprint
possible.
I totally understand all those,
but I wonder how they would feel about
crickets.
I wonder how they feel about perception
issue,
you know?
Well it isn't.
It isn't.
You know what I mean?
We perceived dogs to be cute and Catia
Labor.
So when we perceived crickets to be like
gross and dirty,
but like,
but it's there and they're still alive.
When would you be willing to eat a bug?
Like if you're not willing to eat like a
deer,
would you be willing to eat a bug,
you know,
gets a live bug.
No dead bug.
Like someone like maybe someone who's
vegetarian and they do it for ethical
reasons or they have a concern about
being about bugs.
They don't have a lot of meat.
So I feel like I'm eating just a little
skeleton.
I feel like it's eating a scale.
I feel like I'm meeting a skeleton and
not like a meat that I can sort of
disassociate from their head.
That's fucked up skeleton.
When you grind that shit up,
it's actually pretty high in protein.
No,
it's both.
I mean,
yeah,
but there's something.
There's something just kind of Ooh,
ugly about it,
but I also think that we're.
Sorry to bring this back to the way
we're trying.
I think that were designed to squirm and
bugs because everyone's squirms at bugs
because I think they carry diseases,
poison and more than diseases,
so we're evolved to go to bugs,
which has probably saved a lot of our
lives.
You know that we're not running around
eating them since there,
other than lyme disease and malaria.
Malaria is a giant one.
Of course.
What else does carry what other diseases
who are allergic to bees?
Wass.
Sure.
Stuff like that.
There's spiders,
black widow,
spiders or those are poisons.
Oh yeah,
sorry.
Seizes lyme disease.
A big one.
Malaria's the biggest malaria has killed
a fuckload of people.
Yeah.
I have a buddy's got malaria right now
for the second time.
CICA and should not seek out.
What was the one before that?
What was the one who.
How do you say it?
Did you say Zika?
Is it whatever it is.
I watched.
I saw it on Fox News so I wouldn't go to
Mexico because of it.
But they're scared.
There's.
What's the other one that was before
that?
Not Anthrax.
It was just tap.
Ebola was.
That was that.
That's from spit isn't a
monkey.
Somebody fucked a monkey.
Someone to talk to her.
That's right.
Always.
Monkeys.
Diseases.
The diseases that come from bugs.
Oh boy.
There's a lot of foot and mouth or
what's I'm a look at this one.
Chaga is disease and look at the vector.
Various assassin bugs,
fever,
lung,
heart or mucus membranes.
Symptoms.
What the fuck's in assassin?
Bug.
Have you ever heard of a mild symptoms
and chronic heart or brain inflammation?
What the fuck?
Mild relative of the Ninja bug.
Whoa.
Plague the flea is subfamily of a try.
A total fucking assholes.
Assholes do not give a shit.
Well,
they're the biggest,
um,
biggest argument for decreasing deer
population and also intrigued
reintroduction of predators.
In the summer areas,
like some people are talking about like
bringing in a coyotes and wolves in a
certain area like saved yellowstone.
The reintroduction of wolves didn't
really,
oh,
that's a very controversial subject.
The shape of the river,
that guy that said that,
that guy who made those amazing videos,
the wolves changed the course of that
guy,
George to build,
I think his name is.
I forget how to say his last name.
He's fucking crazy.
Really in a good way,
but it's like when I found out the coney
guy was like a pedophile.
That crazy guy,
that guy.
He was super depressed and was like
suicidal I guess,
and was was in his midlife and was
wondering what's the purpose of life?
And got fascinated by the concept of
rewilding.
He got fascinated by this reintroduction
of predators,
keystone predators,
and to areas like yellowstone,
which they definitely have their purpose
and they're definitely important to the
health of the environment.
The,
the weaker of the thing.
The problem with things like wolves is
they can get overpopulated as well and
someone needs to manage them and that's
where things get weird.
So wildlife biologists have established
these guidelines when biologists,
but for humans,
so who nobody was chaos.
Chaos.
First of all,
there was a lot of different animals
here.
We're talking about like 10,000
years prior.
There was all these different kinds of
animals like the short face bear,
short nose or short face bear.
There was an enormous bare.
There was a step lion that existed in
America like a long time ago that was
way bigger than the African lion.
There was all these birds and fucking
crazy predators,
terror birds.
So we'll.
We'll go back.
Thousands and thousands of years.
Even like millions,
like when the when bulls first and
there's a bunch of different kinds of
wolves and some wolves like the gray
wolves.
They left and left North America and
migrated across the bering strait and
then the red wolves and some of the
other wolf stayed.
That's why those wolves,
those are the ones that interbreed with
coyotes,
but coyotes is actually a wolf or a
coyote is a kind of wolf or coyote is
what's called.
They used to call them prairie wolves.
It's,
ah,
there's a guy name Dan Flores who has
this amazing paper that he wrote called
Bison Ecology and bison diplomacy and
I'm really groundbreaking paper on
Bisons and livestock and the wild
animals rather,
that live in North America and lived in
North America,
but he wrote this new book on coyotes,
coyotes,
and just what the planes used to be like
this.
Why this George Guy,
this antibiotic guide or say his name
is.
Yeah,
the wolves change rivers.
Guys,
he wants to reintroduce megafauna to
Europe like lions because he's saying
that at one point in time,
lions and hyenas used to live in Europe
and that we could use these are large
segments of unused land and let these
animals loose and reintroduce them to
this area.
He's out of his fucking mind.
Sounds like a horrible idea.
Well,
it's,
it's engineering,
so he doesn't want to just take an
animal that was extra painted because of
human intervention.
Right?
Wolves were taken out of the wolves were
poisoned.
Well,
this is what they used to do.
These to take a carcass.
They would shoot a buffalo and while the
animal is still like barely alive,
they would inject strychnine into it's,
it's,
uh,
it's arteries and that way it would the
poison we get through all of the meat.
Then they would take a wolf that they
shot and they would rub it set all over
this carcass so that the wolves knew
that other wolves had been there.
So it was safe.
They knew it was dead,
it was a dead carcass.
So they would eat it and they would kill
them and they almost extinguished.
Wolves almost like came really close to
extinction wolves in North America.
They couldn't do that with the coyote
though the coyotes are too fucking
smart.
They're too clever because clever.
Well,
it's because of wolves.
It's because the gray wolves,
when they returned to North America,
they were killing coyotes.
So the red wolves were interbreeding
with coyotes,
but the gray wolves were killing them.
So the coyote learned to adapt to the
gray wolves.
So they learned to move to the furthest
areas.
They also want.
You hear coyotes yelling.
Yeah,
they're doing a roll call the trinity.
And when they find out that someone's
missing,
it triggers the females to have larger
litters.
What?
Yeah.
So
I got it.
I want to send you this podcast,
this podcast with Dan Flores.
It's going to blow your.
I hate coyotes burrowing in my yard.
And I have dogs.
Yeah.
So I had,
I mean I woke up,
they had dens they made dens in,
in the back of my yard because I have
like land and then I have this part up
top that don't really go up that much.
And my dog used to just come back with
fucking like half plate.
I was like,
what is going on up there?
I think what she did,
I think that she's up to now.
Um,
one's even bigger,
but one's a pit bull.
I think what she did was she would chase
one and then it will go under
the.
Because you realize the vampire they can
fly.
I mean they can,
they can clear Julie's to get a coyote
fence in your yard.
It has to go three feet into the ground
in seven feet tall.
They can,
they can jump.
I've seen it.
I actually stole my chicken and I want
you to jump over the fence with chicken
and rice.
The coyote stole a baby and I think
Arizona off of the porch.
I mean,
they're fucking barbarians.
And uh,
the by two encounters one time I,
they were drinking out of my pool and I
came outside and I literally opened the
door and they just looked at me like,
what?
Whoa.
I had to chase them.
Okay.
And I saw one jump over my fence.
I mean,
it's gotta be five and six feet tall.
it's totally boring.
And I literally said cards.
It's fucking Wiley Coyote.
And then I was like,
Oh God,
I gotta call animal control.
I'm gonna have this fucking dead broken
coyote on the other side.
I go in the other side,
it's just gone.
Flew off.
And Oh,
they were explaining to me.
I was like,
well,
look,
if there's a coyote,
I'm going to hear them,
you know,
killing my dog.
I'll be able to hear it,
you know,
I'll just leave the door open.
He goes,
oh,
no,
no.
You don't understand.
Coyote is work because they're so
cunning.
The way that they kill a larger animal
is they befriend it first so it'll play
with your dog for 45 minutes and then
the other five will descend around it so
it ingratiates it knows I need to
ingratiate myself with you first and
then kill you and they tire them out,
so this happens a lot in runyon canyon.
People's dogs.
They'll just see him chasing the coyote
and then the coyotes will just run and
run and run until the dog is tired and
then everyone will descend there and
they're hungry and they're desperate and
there do not give a fuck.
A friend of mine up,
Heaney was walking his dog like a small
dog and a saw a coyote face to face and
picked up his dog and the like had to
like flex on it to get it to run away.
Started walking again back to his house.
He was like 20 feet from his house.
He turned around.
The coyote had come back with four other
coyotes.
They are just fearless and they live
amongst us a little fucking monsters
live.
I mean,
I have like compassion for them.
If it's between my dog and a coyote,
I'll,
you know,
kill a coyote with my hands.
But it's,
it's really sad when you're like,
yeah,
dude,
I'm so sorry this was your fucking
house.
But it's not.
It's never been really.
It's just constant domination.
The rats didn't own it.
They're killing rats.
The Rats House,
the code is a killing.
The rafts are stealing.
The rest of was trying to convince me
that rats are really smart.
Rats are pretty smart,
but coyotes eat them.
If we didn't have coyotes,
we would have way more.
Rats.
We would have a huge rodent problem all
throughout Los Angeles.
Rods in my pool all the time.
My daughter.
There's a balance that has to be
achieved and that's why wolves are
really important.
Like the people that think that we
should re extra pate wolves and wiped
them out.
Definitely not.
But if you look at some of the things
that have happened,
yes,
gray wolves do gray wolf,
gray wolves don't interbreed with
coyotes,
but red wolves do.
So gray wolves killed coyotes.
So where they've reintroduced wolves.
That's another interesting thing about
yellowstone that you reintroduced the
wolves to yellowstone.
They dropped the coyote population down
50 percent because the gray wolves were
killing the coyotes,
but because when you kill coyotes and do
the roll call thing,
the females are larger letters.
They rebounded and now are more coyotes
in yellowstone than were before they
reintroduced the wolves.
They're so fucking adapted.
Their amazing.
Well,
I mean I also just love that dogs were
wolves wants and just they just.
Some coyotes survive.
Survival is can still breed with dogs
just like wolves can.
Yeah.
It's just survival of the friendliest.
They realized like,
Oh,
and then so wolves evolved to be dogs
and then realized to protect us.
They could survive and now they protect
us against wolves.
Yeah.
How the fuck did that ever happen to.
Like I said,
Neil degrasse Tyson did his,
his cosmos.
He did that thing about it.
That was kind of short but sorta.
But you still like God damn it.
Yeah.
How did it become a poodle?
Whoa.
Fuck.
Did the Afro,
like how was it was like a genetic
mutation.
Then we really latched onto,
well I think it's also the cutest ones
are the ones that survived.
Right,
because they're the ones.
Yeah.
Cute.
Sweet.
And the ugly ones are the ones that got
weeded out.
Yeah,
but the balance that this George
Monbiot,
I think that's how you say his name,
like his,
his take on wolves,
turning like the people love that video
because he's English and he's got a
beautiful voice.
Fascinating story.
And it's interesting.
Yeah.
Well there's a lot of truth to what he's
saying.
Like it's important to have keystone
predators because they keep the
populations of these game animals or you
know,
like wild undulates,
the keep them healthy because they
control them.
But when wolves get to populated,
they get crazy and they do what they
call surplus killing.
Like they killed 19 elk recently in
Wyoming and they didn't need any of
them.
They just went on this butchering ron
and just kill.
It was.
They were.
They come over the top of a hill and
they see a herd of elk.
Have you?
Have you ever seen a herd of elk are
amazing.
Sometimes they're huge.
Sometimes a herd of elk,
maybe a hundred,
200 strong and it's amazing.
You'll come over a hill.
I've only seen maybe 30 of them
together,
but it's quite a sight.
It's amazing.
Like you're just fucking 30 of them
together.
And we were,
we came over the top of this hill and we
were like,
Whoa,
look at.
And then she's heard of my old,
you know,
500 to a thousand pound forest cows that
are wandering it.
Look,
there's a
good.
I saw Moose in Jackson Hall and I was
like,
that's rare because those are all bowls.
Female smells around amongst them.
So wolves.
I saw Moose,
Moose,
and the guy,
the guy that was.
We were doing a little thing on the
skull.
The Snake River,
I don't know.
Jackson hole was explaining how most cal
bears.
You kick them.
It's so fucked up.
I think he said there was a video
somewhere of it.
I,
I'm too terrified to look at it.
That they wait because they obviously
can't fight the thing.
They wait till the bears.
Yeah.
Running up on them and they just wait,
wait,
don't get the last minute.
Just basically knock their head off
their bodies.
Fifteen percent of all wolves that die
get killed by.
That's
amazing.
Yeah.
Fifteen percent.
That's the mortality rate of wolves.
That's fucking crazy moves.
Don't give a fuck.
They don't give a fuck.
I didn't realize how big.
I mean they're just like tanks.
Oh my God.
They're fast.
They're huge.
Yeah.
You're just like,
what is the first time I saw one?
We were hunting them in BC and we saw
this female and it was like that seem
drastic park.
When Jeff Goldbloom sees the dynamo sore
for the first time,
we were like maybe like five or 600
yards away from them and we opened up
the window,
looked outside and there were huge
wandering through this field and you
know,
they're living in a dark,
dark place where we found one that had
been killed,
a calf that had been killed by wolves
and it would have been,
had been killed hours earlier.
It was fairly fresh.
It was a crazy scene.
I put it up on instagram and it's such a
strange scene because there's this
carcass,
but there's hair everywhere,
like everywhere.
They just show the hair.
You can find it.
Jamie was like a probably a year old.
It's old instagram picture,
but the picture was,
it was when we got there because we saw
these,
um,
these crows,
some circling.
It was all crows and there were
squawking and we walked up on it and we
found this thing just devastated.
But it's so eerie to think that there's
these wild roaming.
Pat Canadian wolves are just wild as
fuck.
They've never been extricated.
They've always.
These are the same rules that they
brought into yellowstone were actually
Canadian walls that gray North American,
uh,
United States gray walls were actually
smaller than the ones they brought from
Canada.
Because mammals,
when mammals come from colder climates,
they have larger bodies.
That's why move somewhere away.
Again,
this is a bare fucking gangster,
sir.
As barbwire on the fence,
this thing climbed at 12 foot high.
They don't know how it did it.
Come to 12 foot high fence.
Got fucking Koala bear.
Oh God.
Just seeing that thing like,
Huh,
zoo,
I thought it was fucking saved.
That thing should be in the fucking zoo.
Like why is that how you got out?
No,
fuck that out.
And got in their lives.
It's an la celebrity even before
becoming a lead suspect and quality
killing.
Just a month of poison.
No,
it's pretty recently.
Just it doesn't have a collar on because
they're touching it,
right?
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
It's got a collar.
Yeah.
Yeah,
they,
they are tracking it.
His name is [inaudible] to give him a
name,
like he's a fucking prisoner.
How about Cuban name for Fred Before I.
Oh God,
don't.
Koalas was missing.
You're sad that the parents are not even
from the same fucking continent.
What is,
what if,
can you imagine this call has never seen
a fucking mountain lion and it's life
probably.
Oh No,
definitely not.
And it's like,
what the fuck?
You probably saw that one game of
thrones.
Yeah,
exactly.
That's true.
But um,
before the fake poisoning of it,
maybe I'm conflating it with something
else,
but I was probably other ones who have
been poisoned or something cause they
were saying,
stop putting poison out on your lawn
because fucking kill monsters.
Yeah.
You're your into Kelly's awesome.
A broken murderers.
Um,
is that uh,
okay.
So a friend of mine was hiking in
Griffith Park and her dog came back
covered in like innards of it,
like deer enter.
It's like,
like,
I mean like literally had like,
like in trails up all,
like wrapped around it.
The nose and the mountain lion had
killed deer and the dog roll around in
it.
Why does a dog roll around in a dead
animal?
They always do that.
Those are fun.
A dead squirrel in the road.
Get the scent on it.
I'm not really sure because it actually
makes me think it would make another
animal one to attack you if you smell
like blood and in or it's.
I think they know you're not dead.
But I do know my dog.
Another dead body is awesome.
Same outline.
It's got poisoned but it didn't die.
Okay.
So I'm not a total.
Poster
cat for California's rat poison problem.
Well,
you know,
there's two options.
You poisoned the rats or you invite more
coyotes to lived near your house.
You know,
they say when they eat dog cats.
Tony too.
It's also in the damn floor.
His podcast.
He talks about how when they eat dogs,
they're not really eating dogs because
they want to eat them for like a meal as
much as they want to eliminate
predators,
like competing predators,
especially with cats because most of
what they eat like a coyote,
Z,
like a lot of bugs that eat a lot of
grasshoppers.
They eat a lot of rats.
They ate a lot of rodents,
rabbits.
But they.
The cat's compete with them because cats
are a fucking murderers and now.
But they this shit about how many cats
do you see that off my instagram page,
this article that I posted,
but how many fucking birds and mammals?
Cats kill the US alone every year.
Just cass house cats there.
There's billions in the b.
look at this.
Responsible for the deaths of one point
four to three point 7 billion birds and
six point nine to 20 point 7 billion
mammals every year in the mammal.
Squirrels,
squirrels,
whatever.
When I was a kid,
I had this cat and he,
um,
he killed a squirrel and he was walking.
He,
we lived across the street from this
park and this cat killed this squirrel
and had it inbetween his.
He had a bit.
He bit his neck and had its body
underneath his body.
So he's walking with this weekend at
Bernie's,
dragging it,
holding onto it and like having to walk
around the.
Oh yeah.
We called this kitty like my cows named
kitty.
Like that was his name.
Like we had a name for my name to him,
like Conan the barbarian.
The comic books had like a lion that he
has had a Jaguar as a pet.
I forget what his name was.
I named it that my like,
shut the fuck up.
So you know,
no one in my house.
So it became,
his name was kitty,
but Katie was like,
I had a big black hat.
Cats are sociopaths.
Murderer ever.
See when,
uh,
when Tippi hedren came out,
because remember she like raised lions
and Melanie Griffith grew up with lions
and shit in the house.
Oh yeah.
Google Tippi.
Hedren lions.
Yeah.
What the fuck.
And she recently came out and was like,
that was a horrible idea.
That was a mistake.
It was super dangerous.
Like one of them I think cut up Melania
Griffin had to have surgery on it
because one of them bought her like,
yes.
So she grew up with these things in her
hats.
Melanie Griffith?
Nope.
That's Tippi hedren her mom.
What?
So just go through it.
Which has a fucking pet lion.
No,
she had tons of them here.
Keep going,
keep going.
And you'll see more and more.
So how do they do that and not get
killed?
These motherfuckers will,
you have to raise them from infancy?
Look at their.
I mean they have tiger because they're
part of the pack or like a pride.
I guess it would be.
But what if they just decided to play
with any moment at any moment,
at any moment?
Look on the kids.
They could.
And they did.
So they try to make a movie out of it
and one of the cameramen got his face
ripped off and they were like,
nevermind.
Anxiety.
I know.
Because you know that there sociopathic.
I think if he's not social
pathic,
they just natural.
That's the look.
They have all of these reward mechanisms
that are built into their DNA.
They feel good when they chase after
things and kill them.
They need to hunt.
That's part of the problem with zoos,
is it these things?
It's like,
it's like extracting a guys come through
a straw.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Like,
oh,
I know you need to get rid of your
comms,
but you're still horny.
Does that make sense?
Part of that,
yes.
That's part of the like hunting and will
you got to.
I'm with you.
I'm actually with you on that.
This is crazy.
It's crazy.
It's fucking crazy.
And she came out recently and was like,
Nah,
nevermind.
I'm really don't endorse doing that.
How did she get rid of the lions when
she still has them?
You know what?
I was trying to organize going to her
because she has like a sanctuary and she
tries to raise money to save lions.
I mean because you know now like an
Africa,
there's more animals in captivity than
they are on the wild.
Like it's such a problem.
Yes,
but.
But that captivity,
we're talking about high fence
operations that are sometimes a hundred
thousand plus acres.
Yeah.
Many,
many,
many square miles.
So you look at the actual range that
aligned would inhabit and oftentimes
it's much smaller than what we're
calling like a pejorative way.
It's like they're not safe.
Well,
they're fenced in.
Let's see.
One of the fucking crazy catch 22 is
about Africa.
Is that Lou?
Do you know?
Louis through documentary and I've
listened to him on your show.
Did you watch his documentary on African
Hunter?
It's fucking crazy.
But many of the animals that people hunt
in Africa,
we're very close to extinction just a
few decades ago when they put value on
them and they set up these hunting
camps.
Now they're in there in higher
populations than ever before,
but they're in higher populations
because people go over there to hunt
them,
so they have these places where you go
and it's kind of fucked up.
Like there's a waterhole,
you sit it in front of a waterhole,
they have a blind,
you hide in,
the blind animal comes down,
you shoot it,
and it's all trapped in a.
well,
I mean it isn't.
It isn't.
It's certainly not like target practice.
It's more that than anything else.
So it's.
Is it,
is it better to go and get a steak from
an animal that lived in captivity or is
it better to shoot an animal as it goes
to get water?
Well,
it's not as good as going to the woods.
Like you go into the woods,
you go shoot a wild elk.
That elk does.
It might not even know what a fucking
person is,
hopefully doesn't even see you coming
and you shoot it and kill it.
That's like the ultimate goal is to
instantaneously and this wild existence
that if you didn't kill it,
it would be killed by bears or wolves or
something else.
That's the idea,
but or they freeze to death or they kill
each other.
There's a lot of killing each other.
These,
these,
these antlers.
They're not like for digging for fruit.
That's why they have them and each
other.
I mean,
that's why they have them.
you see this deer,
that's why he has it to kill other deer
so he can get all the pussy.
That's literally what it.
Therefore,
it's a knife that grows out of your
head,
so it's not fascinating.
But what's crazy is these animals were
worth nothing and they were being
slaughtered by poachers.
And then you go,
well,
these poachers,
man,
that's fucked up.
Yes,
but they're really fucking poor.
So what do you do about that?
Because you have these people that are
living over there that there have to
risk their lives to try to poach these
animals for meat,
for food.
And then there's the fucking,
the horrible trade like rhinos and
candles.
I mean,
it's like it's like saying to a drug
addict stopped doing heroin.
It's like,
well you have to replace it with
something in the narcotics anonymous or
another drug or something.
So you can't say stop poaching without
like,
okay,
there's no other way to fucking make
money.
Exactly.
There.
The poverty is insane.
I have had friends that have gone over
to Africa and one of the things that
they say is you just like my friend
Justin Wren,
who he goes to the Congo stays there for
months at a time and he's building wells
over there.
He's amazing guy.
He's the guy who just got malaria for
the second time.
It's like you don't even understand what
poverty is until you see how these
people live.
These poor people.
So I don't blame them for poaching.
I mean,
and if it becomes,
if it goes,
if it's between selling a rhino horn and
feeding your child,
it's like fuck man.
Not Online.
Like looking at the statistics about
animals.
They're literally,
it's just it.
Taylor be killed.
They're barely making it.
I mean,
I am 100 percent against killing rhinos
for their horns.
Make no mistake about it.
I think it's horrible and it's
disgusting.
But these people that were calling
poachers,
you know,
you,
you add that pejorative,
you know,
you,
you give them that label and you take
away.
They could do it like,
like a poor people.
They're desperate poor people and
they're not making that much money.
The people actually kill a rhino.
They're not making much money.
They were making a few hundred dollars
or whatever the fuck they can get.
They're selling it to someone else and
that other person is making a fuck load
of money and it's all gross.
It's gross and it's all scary.
But the Louis Theroux documentary does
the best job of highlighting how fucked
it is over there.
And it's one of the things that the guy
who runs the camp says to them,
because Louise like constantly
pastoring,
I'm badgering him as what does,
why does it plays?
Well,
how are you doing?
He's like giving them all these
questions and finally the guy snaps and
he's like,
after I got,
he's fucked.
You don't understand Africa,
he fucked.
He goes,
if these fucking animals are not worth
something,
they'd be gone.
Do you understand this?
This really crazy moment where you
realize the problem is not as simple as
why do people want to go over there and
hunt?
The problem is this breakdown of what we
call civilization in this area where you
have people that are impossibly poor and
they're surrounded by animals and the
only value of around them as animals.
It's so crazy.
It's so crazy,
so fucking crazy.
So it's either you're involved in the
tourism business that has people coming
to look at these animals or you just
have to fucking kill.
And by the way,
the tourism industry is not as fucking
profitable as the.
It's just not because it.
If you want to go over there and kill a
lion,
it costs you $50,000.
And what's really fucked up is these
lions now in Zimbabwe where that cecil
the lion was killed.
They're killing 200 of them.
They're just going to poach them,
not poach them,
just going assassinate them because they
have too many and now the lions are
destroying all the unduly population.
They had a balance that they had created
through hunting lions down there like
coyotes or will like here with the
fucking lions.
Look,
they're amazing.
Lions are incredible.
Look,
I saw that thing you posted of the lion
king.
My fucking phone.
Look again.
I'm jumping off that thing,
but look at this.
This is my phone that I'm fucking lying
on my phone.
I mean we have to go to Tippi.
Hedren some fascinating by.
I don't think anybody should shoot
lines.
I don't want to shoot a lion.
I don't think.
I don't think it's cool,
but they're in the car with teeth.
They're terrifying.
There was a beautiful article that was
written by this woman who lived in
Zimbabwe right after the Cecil,
the lion thing,
and it said in Zimbabwe we don't cry for
lions,
and it was explaining how they
terrorized her village,
how they killed her loved ones and how
people were.
When they would go out into the bush,
it would be a very real concern that
they would be killed by a lion and it's
not that the line is bad,
it's just that that's what lines they
fucking do and I can't have too many of
them.
You can't.
You can't have too many of them and the
only way to control their population is
human beings and so that thing back to
like we are not the top of the food
chain.
We're
just not.
We're not very simple,
but we are,
but we are with A.
With a weapon.
We are a caveat.
Yeah.
With a huge caveat with it.
You have to be able to first of all know
how to shoot a fight like me and that
machete or Fucking Samurai sword.
I'm not the top of the food.
I don't know how to fucking use most of
the weapons out there.
A drunk person who wasn't,
couldn't walk that good.
You fuck them up with that.
You know what I mean?
That's all.
Depending on what's the level of the
threat.
Since I have no ability to even
understand how anxious it would make me
to be in a room with the lion,
a lion is probably faster than me
picking up a gun and shooting it.
I'm dead by the time I pick it up where
you would have to first of all not just
know how to shoot a gun.
You would have to have experienced
shooting a gun under pressure to manage
your anxiety and to shoot it.
I went to a shooting range and I was
like cool.
Like I could not even.
It was like.
It was ridiculous.
I was so bad.
I was like,
shooting guns is really hard.
You have to be strong and you have to
focus.
You have to.
It's a skill.
You have to learn how to do it,
so it's like most of us don't have that.
I mean a lot of people,
even that skill you're shooting at a
piece of paper that's not going to move.
It's not going to attack you.
This is a thing that wants to kill me.
Exactly.
Knows how to get around my gun,
but I'm going to go to an intermediate
place,
go from the piece of paper that's not
going to attack you and try to shoot a
wild pig that you just.
You're gonna eat like it's nerve
wracking.
It's like what they called trigger panic
where people get on the PA or target
panic there.
They're about to shoot and they can't
keep their guns steady.
They can't keep their.
It's even more difficult with bow and
arrow.
You can it steady.
It's like it's insane.
You don't know.
You're like,
you just want to get it over with.
You just want to shoot it.
What was that noise?
The few of us together when it started,
but there's this panic where you just
want to get it over with.
You're so overwhelmed you can't breathe
and you just want to pull the trigger in
and most people miss like the vast
majority of people that sure bowhunt
miss or rifle hunt,
miss.
It's a matter of controlling anxiety and
I'm sure that exists in the navy seals
one of their training as you know,
they put a bag over their head and take
it off and disorient them so that they
can quickly focus their eyes because
when something's moving around,
it's just like it's a muscle to be asked
to,
you know,
well,
just dealing with adversity,
dealing with anxiety,
dealing with the moment is here now
you've been training,
you've been preparing,
ready crisis on.
You see that with fighting all the time.
There's guys that look amazing and the
gym and they get to a fight and they
can't perform.
You can't really simulate that
experience.
Right.
There's no way in practice to really
simulate it.
Even in practice when you have like you
go a lot like you have simulated fights,
there
would have like an audience and shoot
his room,
his practices and talk a lot of shit.
Talking Shit puts a lot of pressure on
you too.
That's a big thing.
Like guys do that.
Bowhunters do that.
They talk shit to each other while they
practice.
It's a big thing.
They'll have competitions and during the
competition they're talking shit to each
other and the idea of it is you're just
trying to disorient the guy and it helps
them like guys welcome it because it
actually helps them concentrate on
blocking everything out because the
moment when you're actually having to
shoot an animal,
so your hardest fucking take it in the
air and you freak out.
So it's nothing like that for someone to
talk shit,
but at least it's better than you being.
Some players do that.
I'll do that.
Yeah.
They like fuck with each other and you
know,
try to throw each other off.
I guess it was probably not the same
thing,
but it's more of like,
you know,
distract the lawyers get in their heads.
Is that called sharking?
That's what the.
A real a shark is not like,
you know,
people think,
oh,
he's a pool shark.
It's not what it means in the world of
pool players.
Someone is really good at pool.
You would say someone who hides it.
There are a hustler,
someone who doesn't hide it,
they're a player,
but what a shark is,
is actually a dishonorable thing.
A shark is someone who fucks with your
head,
tries to get you to miss.
Like they might do things on purpose,
like drop their queue as you're shooting
or they might,
um,
they might make a noise to distract you.
That's what's called sharking like,
just to try to psych illegal.
I don't even know.
I mean you can't get where you agree or
not agree,
but some people just do it.
But in tournaments sometimes I feel like
right before you go on and they're like
weird crowd when we were talking about
Doug Davidoff,
Mark Marin
or that,
or I'm the worst is when they're like,
great crowd.
So if you go on and do well,
it's not because you were good at just
the crowd was good.
Well sometimes it's a good warning
though.
Came off stage at the Improv the other
night,
I and he was getting off stage and I was
walking in the room and he came up and
gave me a hug and he goes,
dude,
worst fucking crowd.
Ever I'm like,
really?
And I was like,
maybe for you bitch,
and I went up there and they were
fucking terrible.
Doing crowds are weird.
It's such a testament to our group.
Think for a whole crowd to unify as
Shitty as just really warm in the room,
first of all,
which is always bad.
Never read something about hot.
That makes me like what the week was
Wednesday night,
Wednesday nights.
Weird too,
because you've got to go to work because
you've been there for.
It's at comegys show.
It's fucking midnight.
No,
no I won't.
I will not go on past 10:00,
but it's good for you.
I can't.
I cannot do it now.
I know.
It's just.
I know what this is.
Everyone's tired.
They want to go home.
They're looking at their check.
I'm.
They're good.
I think those experiences are good in
the beginning for eight years.
Yeah,
I agree with you.
like I paid the fee.
I mean I used to do standup at lucky
strike on
highland and I'd have to time my jokes
knowing a bowling ball was about to hit
some pins I'd be like at.
Anyway,
so then he called me and then I never
called him back like you had to time
your jokes.
I did a road gig once at a restaurant in
Massachusetts where the inner calm that
the restaurant use to call people's
tables was the same system as the
microphone that I used on,
so it'd be in the middle of talking
about something.
Johnson party of your table's ready.
Fucking great.
It was the only time they ever did
comedy there.
It was.
I was the only one.
It was like a one person show too.
I just went up there.
I was like this be.
Did you ever.
Do you remember Miyagi's on sunset?
Literally do.
It's a Sushi restaurant.
It's not there anymore.
You would do.
There was like a stage Taco now.
Exactly,
and there was a stage and then there was
a bridge with like a creek.
Yes.
Fucking fountain between you and the
bridge and like a coy gardens,
like a little Chinese garden and then a
bunch of people and then they always had
mtv jams on television.
There were televisions on every wall and
people are just watching TV and then
you're just yelling.
I remember one time Duncan trussell got
on there and we couldn't even,
we didn't even know people could hear us
and I was like,
I don't think anyone could even.
I like I did we,
are we bombing or can they hear us?
And then done controls.
I got on stage and started basically
yelling the most offensive things
imaginable and nobody responded and we
realized like,
oh,
they just can't hear us yelling.
He was just like yelling and everyone
just kept eating crazy as me.
August is across the street from what
used to be Dublin's wasn't.
I didn't ever do that.
I remember that was like the Hashtag
Dane Cook.
Yeah,
I got it.
I missed my thing already.
I mean I'm just,
I have to get my hair back to Brown.
Why?
Because it's for your sexy and so real.
Yeah,
exactly.
I want to distract anyone.
I don't want to become a sex symbol.
Uh,
I don't need that stress and that
pressure.
Now I have to go back to Burnett.
This was sort of a just because I'm
working on something and they just don't
want it to look blonde,
I guess.
Fuck,
I'm bleeding.
I'm not a blonde.
That's not my brand.
I did it.
Um,
this is gonna sound weirdly
narcissistic.
I for some reason what they're a little
spurt where I was getting recognized a
lot.
I was and I was touring and I was like,
let me just dye my hair and see what
happens.
And nobody had any idea who I was.
Soon as you went blonde,
as soon as I went blonde I was just
completely invisible.
So you have a love hate relationship
with being recognized?
I don't not like it.
It was literally more like,
let's see what like,
uh,
let's see.
It was like a,
it was like a,
it doesn't,
it doesn't annoy me.
It doesn't bother me.
I'm super grateful.
I see people that come up to me and
airports as like my boss,
like they're the ones that don't say
that.
The fucking guy who sent you the email.
That's right.
That dynamic.
But it's outside window probably.
He's going to hear about this.
No,
I think he's shooting.
He's an Amy Schumer van.
He's done.
He thinks I sold out years ago when I
did a sec.
Um.
Oh you did.
So I just,
I was like,
I was just stressing out it was causing
anxiety because I never feel like I'm
able to give people what they need and I
just,
you know,
and I was like,
I don't know,
I'm going to airports and I'm just like,
um,
and I was dating somebody and I was
getting recognized when we were on dates
and it would just like make things weird
and awesome.
Don't.
I just tried us like,
and I don't,
I'm not working on it.
Let me just change it up.
That's it.
And nobody fucking recognizes me.
And then I'm like,
hey,
excuse me.
I don't know if you know me,
like totally having this like,
hi guys.
I don't know if you,
do you have hbo go?
I just,
I'm so that.
It was interesting what happened when
nobody recognized me and then I felt
invisible and I was like,
oh,
this isn't Chicago dealer.
You know?
It makes you realize when you get
accustomed to stuff,
and so god,
how much attention do I fucking need?
It's so embarrassing,
and on that note,
on that note,
I'm going to go cry in my lithium
battery battery car.
This was a lot of fun.
You're the best.
It was really good.
You are.
I always had the best time with you.
It was great time.
Three hours was so flattered when you
want me to have my friend who is always
a good time.
Alright fuckers.
We'll be back tomorrow with a UFC
bantamweight champion.
Misha tate.
Paula.