I mean with Rohn, ladies and gentlemen,
this is a cluster fuck of a podcast,
but it's going to be awesome.
Or this is a lot of fucking people here.
But this is a fight companion podcast
brought to you by on and go to o n and it
used Kohler rather save 10% off
any and all supplements. Oh Shit.
Human optimization time. Listen, we got
to fucking Stackhouse house to my left,
the master, my brother from another
mother, Mr Eddie Bravo's here. Ian Mccall,
his friend, Kemal Corinne,
Corinne Gamal, Abdul Jabbar.
I knew it was one of those, uh, just
met him. Uh, Ian Mccall, of course,
one of the baddest motherfuckers
on the planet earth next to him.
Big Brown is in the house.
Bitches. What, what? No,
no, no. Just in the fucking world.
Preparing for his next big
fight with Travis Browne.
Gotta be very confused and calling
that groundless. Pick Brown. I mean,
Travis Browne is her and next to
him, of course, my other brother,
Mr Abi Marcus Warrior, poet
us on Twitter. Follow him.
He puts out great links and
his Gal Whitney right below,
she's here at fresh off
of a Jujitsu lesson, just,
just competing in a turn of herself
pretty and fucks pitches up. And uh,
we're about to start the very first fight.
If you've ever heard one of
these podcasts before, um,
don't expect any like deep insight
to the nature of the universe.
Most of it is people getting
drunk watching fights. So we did,
we got off the plane all up in his
bitch. We got boxes, son. We got,
we got God damn. Look at that
booty. You just get a half a brain.
You would get a fucking mad rush of
human neurotransmitter's. All right,
first rounds about to start.
They just touched gloves, man.
The good shit time says four 55 right now.
So if you're sinking up,
the thing about the internet, if you're
watching it on the internet, it's, um,
we're about maybe 10 or 15 seconds
slower because there's a lag between
uploading to Ustream and a,
we're watching it right now.
So it's very first round
of the very first fight.
It's Diego for what is
the fight Diego for rarer.
Hold on a second. I'll tell you
any minute now ladies and gentlemen
do, do, do, do, what's that? How much?
What did you,
these mother fuckers are gambling Diego
and Ben Neale dairy. You wish, uh,
I do not know much about these gentlemen.
Ben. He's a bad ass. I've rolled,
I've had the privilege of rolling with
him a few times. Uh, Ben [inaudible].
If you go on Benny Benny and who was the
gentleman in the black shorts here is
undefeated. Yeah, I've seen Diego
for air fight before monster.
He's got very good Jujitsu to very good
Jujitsu. Good striking too. Like throws,
throws hard shots but nasty
Jujitsu. A couple of years ago, he,
Benny went up against a chron
and lost by decision by advantage. I
think you saw the fight. If you saw it,
you would have seen that would
be advantage given wasn't,
wasn't a legit advantage.
Uh,
there was a sweep that was that he
wasn't given that Benny wasn't given the
points to a really, really
good fighting. Real quick.
My boy and Neil Magnum won his
fifth straight TK the gazelle.
That's five this year, five in
a row. That's pretty amazing.
He's just not as flashy.
So a lot of people don't talk about them.
Like you said you, you didn't even know
any of that is, I mean, I, I don't want,
I barely keep up with anything now I
know why. The why is the smell on it?
I'm going to hear him. Check, check,
check, check. It wasn't, oh, I'm sorry.
Were you saying that he
didn't know what I think, uh,
I think that there's a chance that now
it's really loud reason why there's two
maturation of the UFC.
I think that was done on purpose,
so we wouldn't watch anything else.
I can barely keep up with the UFC.
Why the fuck?
How the fuck am I going to watch Bella?
No, you know what it is. I'll
tell you exactly what it is.
There's only a certain amount of fighters.
There's hundreds and hundreds of fighters
and if you just let those dudes just
run free, they get scooped
up by other organizations.
And the reality is there's
a lot of fucking top talent
out there. There's a lot.
If you want to have an organization
that has 300 fighters on contract,
you've got to have an ass load of
events press plus the ideas just keep
spreading this shit everywhere.
But on fights everywhere for the
card international two at a time
we'll talk about on the Internet all the
time. It's, it's a known subject. Uh,
what's up with the, the saturation
with the over saturation in America,
in America internationally,
it's growing.
So it's like this is it good?
Was there a plan to oversaturate
because not that they don't believe it's
oversaturating the spot. No, they don't.
They don't believe it's oversaturating.
They're putting on good fights.
So just trying to put on as many fights
as they changed it and it's tougher for
them to get famous fighters to the
show man show. Look at Conor Mcgregor,
the motherfucker got famous to me. Now
you're talking about the exception, right?
Neil Magni, we go five years ago,
he's five and no, he, you know,
he's on the front cover and
fighters only doing shift managers.
Good decision every time he know
he just walked by t killed tonight.
He won his last fight by Tko
talking about five [inaudible].
He's got mad skills cause he was a
train part of mine. Other than that,
I wouldn't be doctors.
And I'm saying it's like
him who's been winning.
How come he doesn't get as much as much
like John Fitch?
Don Fitch was on popular fighter.
I mean it depends on what he was.
He was successful. You still
probably a little tough for a title,
strong walkout song, but you don't have
very strong rusty chains. Come on son.
But he wasn't exciting so, so people
want to see him lose. I like to stock.
Well I let you, that's what I like about
it. The staff style test people, you know,
he's unbelievably tough.
He fucking on guys.
He grinds. Dana White said though.
Ooh, let us move a bunker. Lewis is,
he lost his eyes.
Got Your cut.
Craziest thing that Berkman bout
him is how nasty. This is a good,
a good top gay man. Real
good balance. Oh Shit.
He trains a standup with Hafael. He's,
he's awesome. How about Damien Maia. Dan,
John [inaudible], John
Fitch. He John Fished Donkey.
John Fitzjohn fit true.
Holding onto monkey fucking a
football. Oh Shit. He'll hook.
You won't get caught in that
forever as good say never son.
Yeah,
his knee is so flexible.
All I would go for knee bars like walked
all day on him. He's twist out there,
be twisted so far back and his
coach a text. Right? Crazy.
What is up with dudes who have like super
flexible joints? I don't know, 20 years.
Whaler I think told that you remember
when oiler Fuck Sakharova arm bent the
fuck behind his back.
You're for sure it is.
Or 100 years and years of Jujitsu.
Is it like starting as a baby?
I think Jujitsu helps. Like Eddie
Bravo. I mean your show like you're,
you're so flexible down there.
Don't you think you were born that way?
Were you born flexible? Whom? I disagree.
Everybody's born man. You look stiff,
walked by and you are not born.
You look super stiff
rocking then I'm with it.
I think all babies are born in flexible,
but some just keep using it and some
don't use it and they lose it. It's about,
it's how you grow up. If you
don't use it, you lose it.
We gotta be real careful about not talking
over each other. Sorry, and for me,
I used to like my, my toenails with my
feet. That was my bad habit I did that.
Kept the flexibility while all the kids,
I did the exact same
thing when I was a kid.
Being a disgusting Tufts private
though I don't do it anymore. My mom,
because my boys didn't have locks.
You have to make sure your
mom's not going to walk.
We're both hands on your feet or like,
did you Bria? I bite my toenails.
Flexibility, flexibility,
something you can achieve.
Flexibility that a lot of people,
a lot of people don't work hard
enough at it turned into this son.
I agree with that jumps out at the
same time. That's a little bit,
some guys are freakishly,
he's been doing it forever though.
I'm not that flex.
Not like explosive.
It's not like that and that's
a different animal and brand.
Anybody can get flexible if
you stretched rubber guard,
he knows that when you walk
into a kickboxing school
you can't kick to the head
to
Das and eventually you'll be able to kick
it ass to that fucking shot was sweet.
You roll with that guy, he just
doesn't quit. It's freezing.
It's supposed to stop good isn't
it? You know, but I think man,
I think there's people that just don't
put in the effort and they just accept
the fact that they're not flexible.
Remember that dude that we had,
the big player guy who
got stupid flexible over the course
of the year. He had terrible flood.
He would some stuff stretching
and he got mad flexible in a year.
He was like a soldier.
Some people get get to load.
The goal is to get to the huge, he
was built like you said, giant dude.
He's like two 50 we used to call it riding
the ball when we were in fucking roll
with that guy
and you were going to take
him under your wing and, and,
and you hooked him up with a kick boxing
trainer and he came up to him, said, hey,
I can't kick to the head man. I don't
know what to do. What would you tell them?
Retire.
He's the pessimism of dude.
Oh.
Oh
Damn. I would say beat it. Nerd Benny
just cracked him with that neat dude.
He was dominating them on the ground too.
I was really surprised by how he took
them down and then got his back and was
hanging onto him. Where's
this kid from? With the son?
He started with the Bruno.
Matt mood at a health Gracie.
Nice half grace. He makes
a lot of killers. Yeah.
He's got a lot of killers up
there in northern California.
You had Cameron real up there.
He had a lot of dudes up
there. Right. David Tarell,
he's out of there. Dave camera.
Rio De Camera, animals, animals,
animals up there. Dude.
Gumby Scott Mouth. Well,
how was mad at Bj when Bj left
and went to Nova Uniao right.
Remember that column? A trader
details of that. Hopefully. Yeah.
Hopefully they worked it out,
but I'm talking about the one in his
body kick off Tustin. Oh, where's,
Oh, who's teachers there? That?
Bruno Mahmud. Oh, okay. Yeah. Yeah.
But he also trains at the Hafael
now I had a king. Oh, okay.
Hockfield Cordero yeah, he's a
good guy, man. He's so, yeah,
I tattooed him and his wife a bunch
of times. Awesome. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He better be otherwise it
just says something vulgar.
Then his wife have been
a weird [inaudible].
You got to keep that shit quiet.
[inaudible] information.
You gotta fucking be a little shy
about that. Hey you do you guys party
being great.
You're death to host absolutely nothing.
She had no idea what that meant.
And we were at,
we were by ourselves at a club
and Taco and some couple comes up,
all cook out of their board and you
guys party, you want to have fun.
And I'm like, no, no, no, we don't.
We don't party. That's a diff rather.
Yes,
50 with it just just perfect,
just perfect. Cemented like five year
old tits with a tiny little dress on
the trade off. Never works.
It never works. And then,
and then of course later we look at him
at another table and there have swapped
and another couple with women on
cocaine makes things happen.
Just does she want to switch
strong because they're all,
they don't a fuck dude.
When I
was in Tampa
I was doing stand up in Tampa and they
were all ugly. There was like 40 of them,
this couple, 20 on each side, 20 guys,
20 girls and they were all swingers
and they wanted to take us to a swinger
place is me and Maddie Kirsch
and we were like, what?
Look at you fucking monsters. This is,
it's like that scene in the fucking,
you're still ugly.
Fear and loathing in Las Vegas.
When Hunter Thompson's on assets checking
into the hotel and the lizards are
fucking blood on the floor.
Tell me about the golf shoe
ever. One of the best things that
I think when your dad, you know,
you're fucked up and you're old and
you're a swinger, like you're just a mess,
you'll just fuck anybody. Anybody's
fucking these put lipstick on. Good.
We're good.
We're good pile drive my wife for
30 years so it doesn't want to fuck.
You know, there's like 10 years where
you, you might be thinking about it,
but you won't pull the trigger and
then after like 20 years like dude,
they shit on it.
That'd be like a fuck someone else.
All I gotta do is let
her bang or the dude's
sick of bang in their life.
There's
the regional motion,
the books you get to keep your
wife and have sex with others.
You heard about the key party,
all you got to do
these to do those in the 70s everybody's,
everybody puts their 20 years in a pile.
You guys,
you guys don't have headphones on,
right?
So you don't realize what
a cluster fuck this is.
This two separate conversations going on
at the exact term is about a key party.
Second Party,
he saw swingers,
swingers party. They would all throw
keys into a a a bucket and whoever got,
you know, you just pick whichever
person going home with. Yeah.
Well tell people the keys. Just
some gay warlock like yeah. Tough,
tough actions. Life. Hopefully it hurts
her pussy. She doesn't want anymore.
She goes back to your regular deck. I'd
act sick as sick when you look at that.
Wow. Who's that? Oh Damn.
They got someone with boots.
Had Brazilian girl.
I have to have an ass to be a
presumed Jenny Andraj Allie,
she's built correctly. Number true. Yes.
Mouse and that left die
man like seven years ago.
She had a beautiful body look
at is look at his left eye man.
What Ha what had he caught a bunch
of shit in that round, right?
Did he get tagged a good, a couple
of Nice, good defense to man.
Oh came over the top there.
But that was a lot of energy and not
a lot of results. Good. Good defense.
And he landed a vicious fucking
leg kick right before that. Flory
those kicks are way too
slow. Powerful. Ian,
Ian Mccall hummingbird like speed
cause might be a little fatigue.
Yeah, well for I just went
of for a big, big charge. And
how'd he say his last name?
Darvish. Deruge. Yeah he
blocked. Most of that is nice.
Is Nice Cardio with guys.
Fucking incredible. Ooh,
nice knee to the body by error
for how do they keep going?
The pulsing, breathing coaches,
those are so important.
Those moments right in the scramble
and it take down to the guy lands,
the hard shots.
Yeah.
Like especially those hard knees to the
body if you could time it just right,
right, right. Yeah. You know
there's going to be that opening,
you know this is going to be that brief
window to get something in scrambles,
everything scrambled and it tells like
who is in like really tip top shape and
fucking is really driven and wants it and
who is looking to take a little bit of
a break,
who's looking to like maybe not push
as hard to capitalize on those moments
because those moments are going to
gas you and if you're tired already,
it's a mad scramble. And is that
pause? Do I take a breath here or boom,
do I fire the shot and then a
high level in those scrambles,
you're going to have this small
window attacked or die. Yeah,
you're never too good. And
Anderson Silva, Stephan Bonner,
there isn't that scramble.
He landed that fucking vicious
need of the body and that was it.
Most submissions you see at a high level
or during the scramble in the Ama guys
have that good point. He fucking knee. The
body knows. Got a really good one. Okay.
Oh boy. Yes. Cowboy. He's got a
beautiful one off that left leg.
He keeps guys from coming in.
You know as you're charging in,
he's pawn actually with the jab and you
come to close that distance that catches
you with that body. Knee, boom. Over.
He's got a vicious one. Two troughs.
Brown's ain't bad either. It's
not bad, dude. Overeem is just,
it seems like he's just having the
hardest time taking punches these days.
It's just not the same guy forever.
They hit in his face too. It hurts.
It just puts him out. It's crazy.
Well, the only against Ben Rothwell.
I never defend Ralph over him ever
because he's done so much steroids.
However, when he five Ben Rothwell, he got
hit behind the ear. So people that, oh,
his chains out of control. When a two or
six five pen man hitch behind the air,
it's going to fuck you up man.
He just is so I don't think it's
a matter of a chin in that fight.
Look up Cain Velasquez takes bombs. Junior
carnival right behind me. He went down.
He wobbles you. They're not now,
but they're wobbling and get Tko.
Yeah, I, you know,
I just feel like you go back to Overeem
versus Brock Lesnar and you are looking
at may be the scariest fucking
heavyweight of all time. Right?
What I 100% of the pounds of just 263
he weighs in at two 63 and he looks like
our God damn cartoon he
does. And he was like, yeah,
it just doesn't even look like a real,
you can't respect that though, man.
You and now now give all of us
the same supplements he was on.
Let's see what's up.
That's what I'm proposing.
I'm proposing everybody of
this nature get bullshit, bro.
Why don't we all go back to not training?
Well,
what the fuck are we talking about?
Don't try to get better. We all go. Yeah,
I'm done. I'm talking about everybody
being on steroids. I fuck it.
Let's just do this. Don't
make this a fucking, uh,
main page article and when you're goofy,
fucking 100 websites and pretend I'm
being broken ones don't believe that
everybody should be on steroids were
already you were drinking. You said it.
I would like to say that on a broadcast.
So fucking everybody get on steroids.
Obviously.
I work in pride.
Vandelay Silva is banned for life.
That's fucked up. That's fucked.
What he's done for the sport.
Crazy. Unbelievable, ridiculous.
You can't run from a drug test,
but I can't support that
spending first benefit here,
spending for a year
without even testing them.
I'm a hundred percent down with that.
That sends a very clear message to guy.
Can't earn money fighting for a year.
He's got to go and do seminars.
All that said,
oh,
for where we're going to tag that
same eye to his hand was on the mat
touching out.
I was already swollen up,
but I just think that a year, a year,
a year, and maybe a hundred
thousand dollars fine. If
you want to make it Steve.
Wow. That's steep. Yeah. Well
he got 60 grand and Brandon,
you boy fucking Beny Beny,
Beny derash through.
He's a bad motherfucker.
And this is his first UFC fight, huh? How
many other guys got like four or five?
No,
no.
Last year I was at an event corner and
he loved it and he was on a smaller show
is the headline and a small show.
Yeah. He's done for these. This is a,
this is a fourth one in the UFC. He, um,
he's, he lost wants to ram key. Oh Wow.
He got killed by Ramsey. I mean, I'm
so impressed with this guy, man. I'm,
I'm surprised that Ramsey got him. What's
his overall record? How many has he won?
Good question. He is, uh, six,
eight one and o eight one and, oh, so
Ramsey's, you only got to beat him. Wow.
I'm,
I'm fucking super low brother.
Did my reflexes are still
busted with celebrations and
everyone's getting busted. Do you think,
uh, very few guys are doing steroids now.
Uh, I think it makes it tougher
but it listen professional sports,
it's part of the game. With
your, in the Olympics, NFL, NBA,
it's a part of the yield.
It can be up.
How many fighters do you think,
do you think that there's that 10 UFC
fighters that just got off it because they
didn't want to get busted
and now quite a bit.
And I wish I knew anything so they got
off. I think that, you know, there's,
they got busted.
I think some guys were just getting off
to get off because that's like you said,
that was part of the game.
A lot of fucking people just
air rights in every sport. Like,
I mean you go to any sports. Do you
think it is personally in MMA? MMA maybe
turned off. Sorry, I get distracted
that she called that bitch.
She's a beast. She is she fun? Sacramento.
She's got those 50 tree trunk legs.
50% don't do starlets I lead.
Depends on weight class it true.
I wasted it cost all the way.
The storage is a prominent 85
why the weight class has an issue
with Lacey? Why that would be, I mean,
I mean look at the guys. If you just
look at people who've been caught,
it's usually the heavier weight class.
It's true when that,
when that Allie bug attain off got caught.
That Russian dude on EPO.
What the fuck? You're 125 pounds.
What are you going to take?
Anybody with mighty mouse and he's,
his game is very kinetic.
If you don't have the cardio at 125
pounds, you got to a GPO for sure.
Just go do something and
you know what it is. Oh Man.
I think it's first fight that
he's fighting five rounds.
Probably worried about that
and also he's very physical,
like everything he does like hundred
percent where mighty mouse is loose.
Fuck, I know. I hear you. I get all
this. These are all great points.
You're 125 pounds. Yeah,
you're right. You're right.
100 apps audio four days
and I don't give a fuck if you're 300
pounds or 200 pounds or you're not
supposed to cheat. Okay? So
he cheated. He fucked up,
he did a bad thing and he
cheated. And when you're
cheating, it's not just that a,
everybody's doing it.
Here's the deal.
You're going to be able to do damage
that you wouldn't have been able to do.
Let's just be honest that your opponent
is going to suffer if you cheat.
The reality is it's not like football.
It's not like you're getting
across the line quicker.
You're going to land shots that you
wouldn't have been able to land. I mean,
all speculation aside about individuals
that we can see pre and post getting
popped when we visited.
Plenty of examples to draw from.
We don't need to talk about any of them,
but the reality is they're,
they're bad because your opponent can get
hit when they might not be getting hit.
But this is the problem is the training
like Vituro, Belmore spinning heel kick.
Well, if he's on steroids, he's
gonna be able to practice that. Yes,
500 times more thousand times before.
So it's going to be in his wheelhouse now.
Now it's well in his book of tools.
So what was crazy on steroids?
My patio one a hundred cards.
He got legal testosterone,
which is so squirrely. The fact
that they allowed that for so long.
So squirrely. Look, the shit works.
And especially when you're on like
[inaudible] de Devito or had 1475 was his
blood level.
A normal person's like 600
that's like a healthy man.
Not In training. When you're in training,
you're worn out. You're beat down, man.
200 300 yeah. So when you're
jacked up like that, yeah man,
you can make some gains. You can
make some shit out. Welterweight now.
I love the train would be sort of good
guy. He looks like you're welcome.
[inaudible] not count them out. Hell no
striking. It's nasty in the
fucking head is striking is nasty.
What if he goes down really
easily? Afraid to death. Terrified.
Then they'll drop. They're going to just
say, I'm going to stay on. If I get off,
I'm going to get crushed.
So I'm gonna stay out of trouble man.
Cause Weidman's not on that shit.
And Wyman is a fucking monster.
He's a total match up. Even if
he was on steroids, so horrible.
And now you've been fighting on steroids,
you're off of them and you've got
to fight five rounds with kids. Why?
There's any guys that are on steroids,
but they're really,
really vocal about being anti steroids.
Oh Scott.
Because most guys that are on,
that's like gay dudes who
are anti gay preachers.
They always exist.
Exactly.
Mother fuckers.
Most one of the fighters are almost all,
have you seen the African?
I'm like God,
Awful Macaque. Oh man, look at that.
Macaca was in this dude's corner.
Macaca was still rocking
it after all these years.
Macaca knocked out Jocko Ray
and Jack Gary's first MMA
fight, man. Yeah, that too.
It's been all round.
He had wars with Palae back when Paleo
was the fucking man with Paleo was the
shoot the box man palae
brought in Anderson Silva.
Apparently that's the word.
He was a bad ass back then. Wasn't
married when he knocked out Matt Hughes.
That pains. Goddamn Palae
was, he had vicious moy.
Tai Vicious does that. Drake, Jake,
Jake is, his name is Lucas
Martine's. Both of these,
both these guys are tough as shit.
Darren Elkins is just fucking
country tough straight countries.
He's one of those dudes. You fucking, you,
you meet him in some dirty honky tonk
with saw dust on the floor. Come on man.
You to do this. Do this outside. I'll
be right back. I'm gonna knock this
first part. He hit him in the forehead.
You're handbrakes. He smiles at yellow.
You still wanting to do this,
didn't you?
Doesn't get tired. It takes
bombs. But he's got fight. Drake.
Drake makes shit rhyme. Really
good. 25 sitting on 25 mil.
He's a good wrestler to those wrestlers,
man.
Get guys who have that background in
fucking amateur wrestling is so used to,
I went into a wrestling room the other,
uh, the other day, my kickboxing coach,
Jennie part in Rumiyah Danza,
he's got a handful of titles are shit.
His daughter's a freshman
and we're sitting at the pool
and bell rings. I'm like,
oh, this has got, you know,
wrestling practice. And I was like,
what the freshmen at the fucking high
school so about like we're going to the
room and go in there and
check all these fucking kids.
And I realized why I'm so fucked up.
The wrestling,
that's what fucked up your
head. Oh, it just made me crazy.
Sitting some hot ass room, fucking
getting tortured and getting beat up. My,
my coaches are world champion and
17 from Iran and then he left.
He left the country and then
couldn't wrestle in the Olympics,
which she probably would have won
because he didn't have his green card.
So he would bring in all these super bad
ass as to just kicked the shit out of
me. My whole high school career, they
have a deep, deep background in wrestling.
Man, they fucking tortured me. Iran.
It's just, remember the iron sheik?
Yes.
She legit wrestling.
She was legit wrestling.
I had them in a car. Not Kidding
you man. He was a world class.
He's a good dude, man. Is he came on
stage with me in Toronto. I did this.
We'd start this. We'd show
in Toronto, they do the show.
It's like the underground comedy show.
They do it in a weed store and the the
weed store is up like a bong shop in the
front and a comedy club in the bag.
And you go into the back and you
can't see 10 feet in front of you.
You are in the clouds. Man. I'm
not joking. It's ridiculous.
It's the worst hotbox ever.
No ventilation whatsoever.
Every now and then again they opened up
the back door so nobody dies. That's it.
There's no air. You're breathing, you're
breathing in, breathing out weed. It's,
the whole room was filled with wheat
and the iron sheik was in there getting
high as fuck.
And he came on stage while I was up there.
He came in and he fucking this,
this is all your video of it online.
It's hilarious.
And me and him
talking on stage, but yeah, Iranians.
So imagine me at 15,
16 cut weight and I fucking Sana and
I have some 40 year old Iranian dude
massaging me,
read my backend and credit card down all
my sweat and people looking at us like,
what the fuck?
Why is that man
making a choice?
Sweat boy cracks him sir.
You can't buy him that way.
He'd be muttering to meet the Farsi.
You can't just scan him Sir national
clash over. If you want to fuck him,
you're going to have to hold him down.
I realized the same 24 hour fitness we
always went to in Aliso Viejo was a gay
hangout hollow. This is
getting ready mapper. Eddie,
Eddie and I worked out at 24 hour fitness
and there was this dude who was the
manager. There was a cool guy.
We just talked to him and uh,
they had sent him over from
the Santa Monica Place.
He was like a real personable, real
friendly guy. Like he, you know,
real easy to like. And so, uh,
the Santa Monica police brought him in
because they needed to get that place
cleaned out because it had basically
become just a fuck house closed the shower
hose him down everywhere.
It'd be common condos,
all mark comm. But my buddy up
working, that's how I find out
I, but I ended up working at the same
place and they used to have to trap dudes,
gay dudes that were fucking in the sauna
and stuff and raped the cops told you
until the cops came because there was
[inaudible] stations. How people die, Bro.
Don't trap me in the assignment.
So
are you ready?
You Ready? You Go. Let
me out of here, man.
Take a picture of you with the meme.
Don't make me fuck my way.
It me,
me of that place.
Just a blurred out.
Oh Shit. That's funny. Oh
Shit. That's funny. Fuck
this dude is doing such a good guy.
And he was telling us that basically
the gay guys had just had a run on the
place. They would just dominate in the
place there was cause it was all of them.
And they realize,
I don't think he's an administrate here.
Rock out with their cocks out.
I mean,
I guess they had probably had some gay
managers and they had to clean that shit
up and they brought in our friend.
I had to work out there once.
The gym that I normally worked out,
they closed it for filming
and I was with Larry.
This is back in the Larry
Days and let her go do,
let's just fucking go to the West
Hollywood when I don't do it,
I'm not going to the West Hollywood one.
I've never been that.
You just hear the story.
I heard these stories.
I had to get that workout in and then
he talked me into it and go, fuck it.
Let's just go in there
real quick. This, this,
this guy our chest on and get the fuck
out. I swear to God, I was standing there,
me and Larry were working on were like
benching like a 45 player on each side
and a guy next to me had nothing. I just
had the everywhere and he asked me, no,
he just asked me this.
What is this for?
I go to for your chest and your packs.
Why does it make my boss
wanting to be filled
your chest? I'm like, okay, fuck, this.
Just sounds like they're having a good
time and someone fucking hated on him.
He's a snitch, man. So, well, there was
one straight dude who worked out there.
They're like,
can we get his dick sucked in the sauna?
Bullshits my fucking home jam up.
I'm just looking at this apartment
is a gym right next door.
The guys from Wisconsin that doesn't
know shit about fucking Santa Monica
Boulevard here. It looks really
fit. I guess I'm in a fit community.
Everyone's walking
around with Jean shorts.
Jean shorts is, might be the case thing.
There's a million things right here.
You have to,
you have to be sucking a dick while your
roller to make it carrier Darren Elkins
probably happen.
Yeah, it's happened for sure. Someone
sucked a Dick while rollerblading.
100% a hundred percent yeah.
There's probably been a dude that
was mounted on a dude's face,
like he's a flying triangle
while they were
open his face,
whether we're rolling
down Venice Boulevard,
it's probably happened in all the years
that there have been blowjobs and roller
blades. It's for sure it happened.
What percentage of flights,
domestic flights have
gay sex going on him. 1%
they're all gay during
which ones?
Cause I got a day love fucking anonymous.
You know what? If, if we were all gay,
we would all be under the same shit.
Gets guys were guys would
be [inaudible] be as tight.
What are they known for?
Anonymous sex in bathrooms and,
and uh, uh, bath houses and all
that. That's totally normal.
That's how we would all be if
we were all good. If I was gap,
probably be doing the same.
My question is even if you're not
getting down to that kind of stuff,
here's a few gals out there that just
don't follow the rules and a lot of women
give rules.
I don't think I'm with you buddy.
I'm not trying to cock block here.
I'm just trying to let you know how the,
how the gals were looking at it.
I would take one of these bitches
is fucking ruining the curve.
That's why legalize prostitution moves
into a country. Chicks just get married.
Like look, we just kind of lock this down.
We just, let's just, this is what it is.
Lost value
about to legalize prostitution.
The,
the overall consensus of women that
might have been worried there on the,
and understand like some
girls don't even care.
Like I don't care what it cause
don't you see what this means?
Do it start calling
Debo of horse. They just locked
up. They be like God damn it.
Like hey do not want to
see daisy chain like crazy.
Zero power and countries like in Argentina
they're just, they have zero power.
There's nothing. Well that's not a
good thing. Conquering countries.
That's what it was like the
back of the Gingiss con days,
feminism is what's keeping prostitution
is illegal because of who came illegal.
We just blocked them all on Twitter.
We'd never have to hear a word
of [inaudible] over there.
Why are feminists listening to your shit?
Cause I got,
I got talk shit to you for awhile by
some feminists. You know what man,
I'm a homophobe or jam.
Not, no, you're not home.
I'm not into anybody WHO's only
into one gender. Look at this.
He shouldn't go with Ninja trick right
there from the top. They're like, oh,
I get it around. He had his elbow like
in front of it instead of behind it. I,
you know what I feel like,
man,
I'm not into dudes who are
in the men's rights either,
but guys who identify themselves as
really beat, he's going for it again.
And the other side of you guys who are
really into men's rights, like I'm,
what do you mean this
groups? Men's rights. Happy.
I was insulted by feminist and
commodity an Mra and I did it.
I didn't even had a conversation with her.
She misconstrues my point.
I'm not a men's right. I didn't even know
what a Mra was, so I had to look it up.
I thought it was like one of those meal
packages you get when you were in the
army Mre. Yeah. But it was a, um, it's a
fucking bomb that hasn't been exploded.
It was the fucking men's rights
advocate. And I went, no way.
Is that what she's saying?
And then I'm like, wow.
How ironic is it that a feminist would
be mocking a guy who's into male rights?
Like are you telling me that the men
don't have any, like what does that mean?
Men Don't deserve rights? Like how
could you be mocking someone? Oh,
you're one of those dumb dumb Mri or
Mra is cause some of the shit that
[inaudible] very sexy to that picture.
Qut.
Good day on the Camry stud
muffin look perfectly bronzed.
Yeah, man. You know, I'm, I don't,
I think that a lot of feminism feminism
is women who identify themselves with
being a feminist and as soon
as you start doing that,
it becomes like a thing you do. Like
I'm in the car. Yeah. I in the fucking,
I love bowling. You know, find something
like feminist blogger. Okay, well,
you know,
I like to play pool
now. It creates, it's like you're
trying to like break that wall down.
Now you're creating a wall, a
door and shit like that, you know?
Or it lets you know not hanging out
with her. It's just too much work.
Boyfriend, no guy's gonna
put up. Yeah, those guys are
put it flopped you there. No,
no guys.
I know there's a lot of social with
it called social justice warriors.
These social justice warriors. Yeah,
White Knights. It's, it's all men that,
you know, under normal circumstances
would starve to death. They would,
if we were all in the hunting parties,
we would there be limping back there.
We'd send them when people
like that should be fucked up.
There was something bad would
happen if I'm eating it, but
they don't cities
about
good or bad. It's good. Right?
Good. Stop. And why isn't,
why isn't vitamin water?
Cause they used to get,
why didn't they blasting
that for some reason?
No one knows that you Stevia,
Stevia,
the sugar to other stuff too.
But they use Stevia but they don't.
You would think that they would set, man,
we're missing a good fucking fight, man.
For sure. I was getting
blown up. It's not good.
It's got good shots. Yeah. No he will.
He's landed. He can take it, man.
That's part of the style.
Oh, that head rocked him.
And that was behind the ear to
oh on the chin with that one.
He's just so damn tough man.
So hard to finish that dude.
That was why it was so impressive
when he, uh, he lost a Mendez.
Mendez lit him up, man. Mendez look like
a monster in that fight. Who's taking men?
Does anyone taking Mendez?
Nope. I like you guys' style.
Going to have a coffee you guys style.
He says it's a little bit like a
drag racer though. Fucking well.
So it was all done by the way.
All those are three round motherfucker.
And then the last two rounds he like
Ricardo Lamas was on top of him.
I'm beating his ass in that fifth round.
And that's reality.
The thing is they say all the strides
he's made, which done him wrong. He has,
he's not TJ. He's not going to move
like that. Beat his more power.
I feel like though. Oh, she
definitely does, but I just don't see,
I think all those two good.
And I think although has always
been better than Brown anyways,
technically because he's so,
he's so precise, you know,
or browse on moral child and good.
But I think that I don't, yeah,
I don't think Chad can
eat, although I think it's,
I just think that, uh, that, you know,
he's, he's, he doesn't move like Tj,
he's not gonna. He's not gonna
outstrip all though, which I think he,
he thinks he's got a master splinter
in his corner though I was wrong.
I was going to get beat
up so I wasn't on there.
What do you think about fucking Dominick
Cruz? God Damn. Did he look like a beast?
Proud of him, man. Oh my
value on the Steven Bro.
I brought in Daniel Cormier eight, then
my camp. Yeah, I saw the photo. Yeah.
And he brought in a, uh,
Dominic Cruz with them.
How much trying to show us this footwork.
He's like the shop.
This is what you gotta do is show
me in DC like real quick, man,
your waist smaller than us.
That stuffs,
it's just not going to fit our wheelhouse
because it's trying to do that shit.
Travis. Travis moves a
lot like that, I guess.
I mean that's like saying yeah and I
throw a right hook like Mike Tyson.
Yeah, we both throw right hooks, you know
what I'm saying? It's like, Geez man.
Paul said it's pretty good at that
Dominick Cruz thing. He's all right. Oh,
I mean it's a far cry from the original.
Dominick Cruz took it to another
Dominick Cruz level the other day though.
I've never been so happy for another
fight of that. That's I don't train with.
I was so happy for him.
That kid showed zero hesitation too.
He came out guns blazing.
Just got them tough guys too.
That's all east.
I know you're Riaa finished him,
but he got his back and choked him and
you know Mitchell [inaudible] and not
just not the same kind of grapple you're
riding and it was all pro bring in DC
into the camp. Don't look
at that fucking Combo. Yeah,
I'm sure. I'm sure it's here. La. Yeah.
What is it like working out
with him and how's his knee?
Because he's 100% yeah,
it's this pressure he brings.
I've never seen anything like it.
I've trained with a, you know,
I've trained with a ton of guy.
That's cane dude. The pressure,
he just keeps coming and keeps coming.
Keeps coming. That's him and came man.
Those guys. Two werewolves. Yup. Who
keeps coming fucking seeking each other.
I brought core man for my camp and he's
a monster. Watch them spar. No, I wish.
I'd love to see that. I've
seen some videos and them
spar is goddamn ridiculous.
Watch is for war chaos,
eating each other's style,
the same style,
knowing me get ground the same style and
both guys are going 100% I mean they're,
they're fucking going to war and I
wonder about that man. I don't, I don't,
you don't. There's obviously
you can't fuck with the results.
Cain is the best heavyweight
next to fade or ever. Right.
I mean there's fate or him and that's it.
And I would love to see
the two of them together.
And who knows what the fuck would have
happened. I didn't. You know, who knows?
If you watched the two junior dos
Santos fights since the first fight,
you wouldn't think that
junior could knock 'em out.
But junior knocked him out and anything
can happen. Fader was a risk taken.
Motherfucker feto would,
he would get wild on your ass and bricks
on the end of his hand through those
casting punches. Yeah, he was.
He's never scared, never scared.
He waited in ferocious.
So that guy could,
he mean he literally could have beaten
anybody when he was at his badge. Okay.
Keynes injuries. It's kind of like, yeah,
well he keeps beating the
shit out of his body. No,
100% they're going a hundred percent man.
I,
I've told my sprawling down in my career,
I'm 30 now and I'm old,
but I've just been fucking injured a lot.
Well,
there's a lot of people to think that
the sparring is one of the unnecessary
aspects of strength and conditioning
that people overdo because you're so,
you're beating each other up so much
and there's so much trauma that you,
if you just as you reach a
point of diminishing returns,
like yeah. Are you tough?
Yeah. Can you mentally deal with it?
Cause you're dealing with a regular basis.
Yes. But could you be 2% better if he
didn't do that? Could you be three,
maybe five? I don't think you can
take it completely out, but you can't,
you can't take completely,
nope. No Way. No chance.
You can do like a Manny Pacquiao spars.
Only the last four weeks of camp,
a really, really spot or the last
six weeks of camp. I do a, we cannot,
we only spread the last six weeks of camp.
And how much,
how many times a week do you spar?
Once, once a week. That's that.
Once a week we're bringing
some hell raisers, man.
As long as you launch the songs,
you're simulating scenarios using
techniques that are going to come up in a
fight and win them over. You know,
Eddie always talks about this,
about how if you just fucking,
everybody loves to roll,
but if you just drilled more,
it would make you so much more
successful at your roles and it's really
essentially the same way
with any martial art.
I mean with kickboxing you if you just
beat the shit out of each other all the
time.
Yeah,
I guess you're probably going to get
better because you're putting a lot of
attention to it,
but if you work out with a really good,
like rob came in type coach or Duane
Ludwig type coach who takes you through
very specific drills.
Once you're actually sparring and
you land that left to the body,
it's like your right leg is coming around.
Whether you think about it or not,
it's just there.
It's just a part of your,
your your body's memory and I think that
we still don't know what the right way
to do this shit.
You guys are.
Do you two guys are like experimental
projects 10 years from for Real, right?
You guys are the new breed of them.
Amazing.
Yeah.
Little spider man.
He's jacking off and shit.
Not every shop you like one of those
fucking killer chimpanzees they found in
the car in the Congo,
six foot tall dick
trying to fuck me. See the same world
as you know about those no devil nuke.
They have these over the last like since
like the 90s they found these chimps in
the Congo that they've
always talked about.
They had a photo of one that was shot
and like the early 19 hundreds they call
him the Bondo ape.
It's an enormous chimpanzee,
a completely different genus stands up.
They stand up and they have a crest on
their skull just like a gorilla does,
but their chimps and they
sleep on the ground. They
don't give a fuck. No. Locals.
Locals call him lion killers.
They say there's two.
They have a video of one
apparently eating a leopard.
They have two different types of chimp.
They call them tree beaters and lion
killers and these align killers and there
are giant six foot tall,
350 pound chimps and they
sleep on the ground like this
lump in there,
Dick,
why they pass out and everything just
fucking steers clear of these crazy fucks.
Thank, I think of a chimp how strong a
chimp is and they're like 150 pounds.
This is double the size,
six feet tall, super smart.
They have pictures of them all
over the Internet, like walking,
like walking like a person there's,
or this Carl Armand is ago,
Swiss wildlife photographer.
And he found photos of them and
like spent years looking for them.
But apparently it's an incredibly
remote part of the Congo that's super
difficult to get to.
But just now these people that are
fucking risking their lives in this crazy
shitty part of the world, these
aggressive, oh, of course they are.
One of them.
There's a fucking great story about
these scientists that went down there and
one of them made a fucking a bluff charge
at them and it just, they didn't move.
You can't move.
You're dead anyway.
So just you got to stand your
ground because if I move back up,
if you do back up there for sure. Gonna
fuck you up. They rip your nuts off first.
Oh yeah. They know the
genitals base. Yeah.
They know what works. They know
what you like. Early UFC rules,
they're smart as shit.
They're like halfway between
a person and an animal, but
ripping balls off. You had, if you
had a monkey, there was 150 pounds.
He wanted to fuck you up.
You'd be in a giant problem.
He would probably kill you
most likely to rip you apart.
Imagine something twice that big twice
that big and super aggressive and the
locals call them lion killers and we
just barely know about these things.
They have DNA from them. They have
some photographs and some videos,
but they barely know these fucking things
exist in a very difficult spot to get
to.
It ended up as the pet
training partner. That
monster, well I your mom,
Bondo Abe's to train with
next podcast.
He trained with Bondo a take babies
and then train them and bring them up.
They can't take them. If they're
already adults, forget it.
Hannibal Lecter masks on their face.
I get crazy in the middle of
training time. He doesn't buy it,
but what he bites it would be a hammer
fist and a wheel kick at the same time.
Can you imagine if you taught
a chimp how to do a gay teen?
Pop your head off, especially with a big
giant ones. Dario, throwing a decision.
Holy Shit. Brazil. It's stuff to do. Wow.
We were barely paying attention.
Now let's be honest.
We're talking about a month
is biting dicks off son. Yeah,
I still thinking of that.
You tried to fuck everyone.
You're trying to fuck that bondo way,
but who's going to get,
who have failed those son Joseph Havi.
Who's he fighting?
He's fighting someone good. That's right.
Nate Diaz coming back in at that shit.
Nate Diaz coming back. Joe
Sanchez is a monster. Yeah.
He's tough as shit, dude. I can't
believe knocked out Henderson.
That was fucking nab cowboy. Yeah, he
beat kicked about it, man. He's a beast.
He beat a couple of guys.
He's beating quite a few really good guys.
But knocking out Benson,
this fucking huge man.
Fabio Maldonado was always fun to
watch Human Zombie history before.
I see this is paper view. The old
body shot, Maldonado don't play.
He's got really good left hook man.
Look how smooth his boxing
and he's a perfect example.
The the exact opposite of a guy like
boggle teen off. He's a big guy.
I mean he's fighting,
you know,
two oh five but yet he's like super
light and relaxed with his punches.
He made a big mistake. Fucking Steve
Bay though. Boy Did he have a choice?
No, I'm saying he asked for that
animal. Look at that picture up there.
That's the bond.
That was one that they found that was
one they shot in like the early 19
hundreds so you can get a picture of that,
a better picture of that.
Cause they show like it's whole body.
But if you look at the other one, Jamie,
there's one that they shot
at an airport recently,
these two guys and they're
standing in front of it.
So you get a perspective shot.
Thing is in that picture you're talking
about and the airport. Well there,
that's a different one. That's one
of the caught on the camera trap.
But this picture of one that they shot,
it's actually dead and these dudes are
standing with this thing and you look at
it and you go, they kills that. I
probably could have. They could.
I mean they were living in the Congo.
They eat Champps there.
They eat whatever kind of meat they
can get. I saw you're a real sports.
No, that's, that's another image in
one two. You have the real sports? No,
there's just look up Bondo ape. And if
that doesn't work, look up [inaudible] A,
B I. L I a Bondo. A shop
training partner. You'll see one.
There's an image search.
You got it.
The one with the does a dead one.
There it is.
Look at the size of that fucking thing.
Look at the size of that fucking thing
back up so you can see it's balls.
Back up a little.
Look at that Stack Zack and
cock.
How'd they kill it to shatter your,
they didn't kill it with a fucking
wiffle ball bat. I'll tell you that.
You better shoot that thing. Look at this
fucking muscles on that goddamn thing.
It's gorilla. He's smiling
to deliver. Are they bigger?
Grills are bigger,
but that's,
that's the real aside for a
chimp that is fucking enormous.
That's like a really big man. That's a set
of tits on him. He's got his arms, dude.
Those are like your legs.
Just Dick.
He can look at that fucking package.
It's just all but solver.
That's all up in your face
thing like his leg to the left.
That fucking picture. She
frees me up, man. Left stomach.
That's his CAC at this cap
rate. That's easy. Well,
they don't have big dicks like
people do, Bro. People that have
big balls because the ball's side,
this is actually scientific fact.
That ball size of directly proportionate
to the amount of promiscuous females in
the region includes human beings and he
in villages where human women are more
slutty. The human men grow bigger
balls. Swimming. That's your huge
ego balls
important.
My girlfriend, I just, I was
like, you know what, to call
this out of state. Exactly.
Go out of state.
Small town girl.
Well, there's too many people in
Orange County. They have to fuck.
There's too much traffic. They just
do it. It's true. It's just fuck.
Can't wait for my boyfriend to get here.
Come on over.
He's stuck in traffic
for the next two hours.
So Fabio Maldonado versus Han stringer.
Anybody know anything about stringer,
stranger, stranger to know in the UFC?
Is it strange with the Black Zillion?
He's about to get punched.
The fucking another lens.
It's going to be a standup boy for sure.
He has a couple kids,
a victory over a fence and Mark
Barroso and one of the fight nights.
Third round decision. Hmm. Well done. Not
was a fucking bad ass. Oh, he's a beast,
dude.
His boxing is really slick.
Remember when he clipped Glover
Glover's lightened him up, dude.
Lighten them up and then he catches him
with a left hook and as Glover doing the
chicken dance. But he's
just so tough, man.
So this is a guy you don't want to
have a conversation with when he's 70
was too tough. He, those guys are too
tough where they take them postman,
you're like stop this.
Yeah.
When he's 70 and he's drunk and you and
him are sitting there and he puts his
hand on your need to tell
your story and does that clamp
the clamp on your knee when they
spent time, Bro, I fucking told him.
I told him I'm not going down. I'm not
going down. Tells the same stories.
Are there any,
are there any legends have speech.
No comment.
Or it could be like that old dude that
beat the fuck out of that young boxer
with the long hair.
Like
you never see that video. Oh my God. I
was like 16 he fuck with a old man back.
He had old man back
hunch shrimp,
shrimp and I was like,
Oh fuck this guy screwed. Screwed.
Yeah. When he slipped the Jack,
the Jack God damn world. Ah, Ooh.
There's that.
That level of boxing you get to where
your eyes are open as the punch hits.
You ever seen those
pictures of like old school?
Roberto Duran is a photo of
him as a punches hitting him.
His eye is wide open and he's throwing
a counter shot cause the punches hitting
him. He's turning his head
and planned. I mean those,
when you hit that level it's just
you're so relaxed. And that old man,
old man was used to getting punched.
It wasn't a new experience.
Fuck hey did.
He didn't have to one out.
He was going out and bad boys been around
for fucking ever and it hadn't seemed
like they've really,
you know why?
Because so many dudes tattooed on their
body to go look, we've got to keep kids.
Are they making any Mary
Horn as a bad boy tattoo? And
you know what,
if you think about it,
that really is like the coolest thing for,
I'm a bad boy.
Everybody wants to be a bad boy.
Girls like bad boys
coming to Jitsu or like a Brazilian thing.
Cause I remember in like 88 I remember
I had like a pair of shorts and it was
rude.
Boy
got with like spiky Johnny Bravo here.
Come with like a spiky like this. Probably
those bands back in the 80s.
Rude boy that I remember.
Do you remember when that was
first and that was born in the 80s.
So I don't know how he gets all fucking
old Dan. Daniel born in the 80s.
Fuck Pussy. When you were coming
out of pussy. Yes. Hollow.
I be your father
speaking.
It could be your father
if school I made 84 84.
It was when I was just starting to get
fussy so I could have fucked up and shot
one into my girlfriend. Jesus
Luisa. Speaking about shooting one
powerful genetics. Here
we go. If anybody's to us,
they take our don't like Brazil
and that's why I'm not there.
It couldn't be more further
from the truth. I love Brazil.
Escalate the ground right away.
I love going to Rio. I just,
I didn't have the time this week
and I had family obligations.
I just couldn't make it. I had to how to
stay in town. Damn kids. Well it's that,
um, there's no things I can't talk
about, but a lot of stuff going on
out on the grounds. Got a bad ass
hole dudes. Was that judo video?
Real amazing.
Mine too.
Have you seen that video? I took your
fucking mind Jamie. Pull that shit up.
That old dude video of a,
the old dude doing judo.
These guys are trying to toss him and
he's moving like water just flowing around
them and he's like in his sixties and
other old dude in his 60 when you know
you're almost dead, you give zero
fucks. You're not protecting your ACL.
He's just out there letting it hang,
you know? And I tried to fucking,
I got to fucking rotator cuff injury. I
just going to let this dude take me down,
wipe off my back more times in a row.
It's amazing. It's amazing. It's amazing.
The guy's technique is just
stellar. It's also, there's,
this is a potential of watching that
video that they're his students and
sometimes when you row with your students,
the students almost have like a give up
on the Quito death touch and have those
guys and just like flipping this is
different. Yeah. What are they about?
They're all crazy. Don't brainwash.
Totally brainwashed. Yeah.
How about your boy hunt getting the
title shot? Fuck yeah. Do you know why?
Do they make an agreement like Bunko with
it and do they talk about it or is it
unfold
or these like a cult thing.
You know what I'm saying?
Drink this Koolaid so never
really sat to [inaudible].
Cool. Right. I don't even think I've
ever talked about that. Let me think.
You have to do that.
That's an important fucking seminar.
Again,
good right off the guys that would do it.
You can't go back to the fucking check.
You call up the assholes
who are going to fall down.
I would never be able
to pull that word off.
I don't even know what I knew what you
meant. Like right when you said I go,
I seen that online.
I never really played that game.
I mean I did a few times,
but not enough to call her Duke and Fabio
is getting tagged with that elbow at
the top. Big Old Dutchman.
Brazil is not happy. Big Brown.
When you get into half guard
position in this spot here,
do you ground and pounded you try to pass.
I looked for submission from half guard.
Most most guys,
most guys like to ground and pound here,
especially wrestlers cause you can
really control. Got To half guard.
Especially in MMA. True. I agree.
I like,
I like to give them this Sunday like I
did with metro and I give him the under
hook and I looked for my doors.
I looked for the neck or that come up
now his dark especially at heavy label.
Look at this, look at this. Nice with
the hooks man. Nice with the hooks.
Oh beautiful job. Beautiful
job. Good control.
Yeah.
I don't care.
I think mounts overrating them and
man I'll show some amount of you.
You'd be fine.
100% just slide data was Shankar.
When did you try to regain half guard?
Yes.
Why or or create a scrambled number.
Why would you try to regain half
guard if cause I can get up.
Even the viewer and how the model
was a deep half. He would stay,
he was pacing is on top,
get out and I don't know what it meant.
What I'll do is I'd create a scramble.
I give him the under hook to a
scramble to get their neck or and all.
You hear what I'm saying?
I see what you're saying.
If you don't want a mouse because it's an,
it's worse than being in someone's half
guard. Then if you were being mounted,
why would you put them in half guard?
You would. You should just leave it.
I think it depends on the style.
Depends on who.
It depends who you're fighting too.
That makes it fighting for doom.
You don't let that
motherfucker mountain know.
I don't think he let anybody fucking
mountain you ever when you're in the
mountain, naturally as a fighter
you want to recover half guard.
At least it depends. It depends who
you're fighting. So there's guys,
guys mouth to create
scrambles, but you, you have a
pretty good just for awhile.
So if you were mounted on a purple belt,
you'd be pretty happy with it. Right?
If you were mounted on the guy who just,
maybe he was a notch below you,
you would take that and you'd stay there.
It was an MMA fight, right? Yes.
So the difference between that
and the guy was really good.
Is it that your mount is not
good enough or is it, no,
I think in MMA because when the strike
in the show, because your grape vine,
right? And you find the guy out if
you're not going to get heavy strikes in,
right. So you were kind of just sitting
there or if you're of a doom guy,
you're looking for some issue
that cross your feet underneath,
like a guard from the top amount,
like a mouth guard.
If you're doing guy, you'd
go for selection. Okay,
let's listen to Ian because everybody,
what's your philosophy on it?
I'm just better at punching and passing
and everybody else in my division.
So it's, it's not, it's easy for an amount
pass mount. You're trying to recover.
I'm going to try them out again. Try
and Matt again. Why do you want it?
Why are you trying to get to the mountain?
It's a dominant position and I can punch
you from there and I can get you to,
the person gets tired, you know, they,
they start to panic and they start a
square and I take their back and do
whatever, but I can kind of
float above somebody in the,
in the belly punch elbow and I mean they
get that guy to work so much when you
can float over him and hit him with needs
of the body or whatever it is you're,
you're hitting the guy that you can't
do that from half guard. He can,
you said you couldn't scramble
that amount. You're on neon belly.
You let them turn. I'll do
like the, you know, the, the,
the cross my feet,
if I get locked them down a lock
them down and then just punch him,
elbow him and look for a submission.
But I don't mind it that people are,
if they're starting to scramble
like that and I'm on top of him,
it's such a dominant position. I can
just, I just hold people down. I agree.
And they just said no. I'm saying when
you, when you place your feet like that,
you're not finishing and guy was strikes.
You mean when you butterfly or when you,
when you bring up finishing
high level grappler from mountain.
He's going to get out guys. But dude,
there's some guys when you grapevine,
there's things that have like a
crazy hyperextension in their back.
I've seen guys who flattened guys
out with great flatten them out,
but they can still fucking blast
from the top. There's a few guys,
lot of games when there's no nasty,
you gotta be able to sit up. You got to
have a calculated game going on. I agree.
Like what are you doing when there's
not punches in the mountain? Big Brown.
Why are you not trained with Eddie Bravo?
You need to get your fucking ass over
to 10th planet. Get a couple of lessons.
Just talk. Don't talk about it. Be
about in Venice, man, he can't make it.
That's incredible dude.
It's a total drunk.
He can't be expected to Lawrence County
a wrestling reign training center.
That was the first time we met.
I was still hanging out.
There's a lot of 10th
planet Jiu Jitsu down there.
Tony Ferguson transcend a header a heater
on, right? Everyone knows this. Yeah,
I got a crush on him to do it. How to
do it with you. I got a question. I'm,
I don't want to go down to Orange County.
Listen what you're saying.
Everything you're saying about
the Verdomme guy. Yes, correct.
But everyone should strive
to be the Verdugo guy.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
I'm striving to be the redeemed guy.
I'm with you. Jujitsu is
my passion. I moved here.
When you get out on Travis Brown,
he's not getting that.
He's not a Brendan shop on the ground,
but to do that to everybody. I agree,
but it like whoever Brazilian,
why everyone. I'm still,
if I'm going against a high
level Brazilian and I can
get them out, I'm like,
if you've got damn mountain and go, Holy
Shit, I'm dominating this fucking with,
you know, if it's there, but I,
I'm never going to stay in half
guard if I can get them out.
I want to get to the mount because you're
in some deep shit and the mountain.
There was a lot of games with
your brother. But what happened?
Punk Shit in half guard. Well,
you're just nasty. Overall.
The overall and MMA have
you look at all the fights,
not that many fights and from you
put all the time a fight is in,
in half guard, top happen. MMA most
of the time nothing's happening.
It's at the boring shit. And that in
that respect, in that same argument,
most of the time when you're in guard,
it's bullshit. And I agree with nasty.
I agree with his half guard. His fucking
top game from half court is very good.
He's a very shift. That's a beautiful
thing. His is, he put material on asleep.
That's a beautiful thing. You know,
half guard, Doris, half guard, uh,
Japanese Necktie, half guard
guillotine fuck your half guard.
That knee bar to hell. Yeah. Hell yeah.
But also all sorts of gain from
side control. There's a whole,
for sure the loves and the
whole system from the mouth.
And then the back is a whole nother book.
No fights.
All that in front of Dina and he's not
watching. He's watching the Monitor.
It's a weird thing. He's watching the
Monitor. How dare you, Eddie Bravo.
But it's weird thing you do.
Sometimes the fight is on in front of you,
but you're watching a monitor in front
of us and three screens and we're talking
about we're talkers in Argentina,
but we're still watching it.
I'm still watching it. Still awesome
chance given to punch people.
Maldonado is just fucking excels.
I understand what you're saying.
Sneaky take sexually strong.
He's got a little extra,
especially at heavyweight other,
you know what I'm saying?
The show exposed to that heavyweight.
I, I would say they're less explosive,
happy way.
I disagree with the explosive guys who
guys, I can't, well, I completely agree.
Like really know because guys his size,
how many I'm playing football.
I'll do a solid zero.
How many of them to play football?
He was like the star people
destroying,
destroying it.
Fucking weight shop.
When I'm with the back to the mouth talk,
I've got a question about cops,
man.
They outlawed those tie steel cups in
a lot of grappling competitions. Right,
because you can fuck a dude up with a cup.
So why can't you do training in MMA?
It's an MMA.
Like when I remember one time I will
pause that was wearing a man. What
the fuck? Maldonado's given some big
look how calm
you got to shoot. You got to shoot the
perfect devil's pool on top of you.
And then when they come back with that
wizard, you come up with them right to,
he's not looking to do that.
So I need to have that skill set.
Maldonado was looking to
just fucking fire ups.
Anderson Anderson up there with them
Anderson's in his corner. Come on,
come on son. Dude. Bald to know. But
you know, you could learn something.
Watching him punch like everything was
very precise and it like 70% power.
Whoever the fuck he wants, he can
do whatever you want. He's in Rio.
They give suck each other's dicks.
He his,
his striking from any position
is so fucking pinpoint and
it looks like it hurts.
He had extra snap on it. Like the timing
was right, the main boobs. He just smooth.
So here's the question.
If you could fuck a guy up with a tie
steel cup in a grappling competition,
like it's a, it's an extra lever.
Like if you catch a guy on a knee bar,
two inches, it's metal and it hurts.
I was rolling the Amir Renovar,
he's the only guy I've ever rolled
with that rolls with a tie cup on it.
He would mount you and stick that fucking
tie cup right in your solar plexus in
grapevine years death. Cause it's
terrible. I never thought of it that I,
I've always worn one. Yeah.
Well this won't be the nuts.
You're going to fucking kick it. Have you
ever fucked with those? My question was,
have you ever fucked with those
like diamond cups? You ever,
what do you think about what's better?
Diamond or like a steel?
I wore it once and I liked it.
I just,
I think it broke and I never want
another one was how long ago was it?
Um, a while ago. They better
at it now. They did it,
but they've done a bunch of changes
to them. They're pretty dope,
but they were awesome. But
I, and I actually put a steel
cup inside of mine. Ooh,
that's very smart because I liked the way
it's set up, but I don't trust plastic.
Plastic.
Give a fuck about shaped in a steel is
a little bit different and especially
like they'll say like, oh look, there's
a video of someone kicking you. Okay,
we'll let Melvin Manhoef
kick you in the nuts. Let's,
let's let someone who knows how to kick
cause I'm watching this kick and I'm
like, I'm not that impressed. Yeah. Fuck,
let me kick you got proofs that
and let me get you. Exactly.
I'm only 125 pounds.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people that say like,
hey man, I eat low. Kicks her out.
He kicks like you'll eat some kicks,
some kicks you can eat,
but a Pedro. Yeah, exactly.
That's the perfect guy to bring up
breaking my coach homework with him.
He was a patriot as though striking
coach said he kind of hold myths.
One can have bad from it kicks on,
so you just have to put them on a bag.
I sent her warning him,
kick a bag at Beverly Hills Jujitsu,
fold those motherfuckers Yurts uh,
Marco and Marco studio on Oneso just
says the guy who folds fucking bags.
And this is true. Yeah,
I can do that shit too.
That's why I'm telling
you she had a normal,
there's certain dudes that just
have a weird power and you,
you've either and shit. No,
your hips. It's a little bit
of, it's a super flexible.
So it's his own size too,
dude. It's a weird, it's shape.
And that's one of the main problems that
I have with transgender fighters that
fight over in, in women's MMA
I should say. Only if they let,
if they don't let them know, like that
was the issue that I had with Foul Fox.
Shouldn't,
shouldn't divulge because she didn't
think she had to because it was a medical
issue.
If you know that a chick used to be a
dude but it's now a check and you fight
her up to us on board,
I think it should be legal to ride bulls.
I think it should be
illegal to jump the Umax.
You should be able to do
whatever the fuck you want to do.
I think 135 pound chicks, she'd
be able to fight 135 pounds. Dude,
I'm think of Ronda Rousey
and Bryan caraway talked to
nef shit and they decided
to go at it. I don't, I don't
have any problem with that.
If they both agree to it,
I'll go up and wait and fight Ronda,
but there's,
there's the size of the body. It's the
shape of the body that's different.
It's not just the density of the bone
because black women have the same density
of bone as white men. It's very
similar, almost the same. Very similar,
but you know,
obviously pro athletes and the guys who
strength training are going to have more
density in their bones and the
average person, if they're measuring,
it's a significant difference.
But the big difference is the
mechanical advantage of the male frame.
You don't find a female
with super wide shoulders,
narrow waist and the same
size hips and the same shape.
Hips is a man and when you
have that kind of body,
you could just generate more force.
I can look at a dude and tell you whether
or not he could be like a man hoof.
There's some dudes that just have that
just stupid fucking power and you could
look at them and go, well
he might, he might not like,
there might be like a Bobby Lashley.
He looks like a fucking brick shithouse
but he's not like a shame car went true.
But Shane Carlin's,
a Shankar Shankar when had that stupid
fucking power can't tee up course
Jesus Christ.
Fuck with a wig on.
She fucking bitches. Soon as he
stopped when he was in three, four,
five in a row and regular MMA like,
dude,
I'm going to lose weight and
fucking chop my balls off.
You maximum the that bed,
all you would have to do is Holler,
dive Schick and punch her in the
back of the here and it's over.
His hands are not going to shrink
and then if they do shrink,
what are they going to shrink in 10 years,
all the champions in
women's MMA will be former.
Dude,
that's so true. Just a
stoner question. What do you,
what do you, what do you
think that's, I like this.
Do you think aliens each
strictly Gmos or are they vegan?
Oh, good question. What do
you, what would you think?
They'd come down and we find
out aliens are really hang down,
come flying through space.
Would they laugh at vegans?
Do they have planets within, are there
are designated for organic farming?
Do they have like planets? Oh the, I think
they bring like farms, like in their,
in their ships, do they just absorb
energy? You know what I mean?
What would they say? What would they say
was wrong with the Vegan thing? They go,
listen,
this is the truth.
As long as you're getting all the
vitamins and minerals and essential fatty
acids and amino acids in a pill form,
whatever your weight,
your body's going to adjust. These
bodies can, we can digest anything.
It's all about the vitamins, minerals,
amino acids, and essential fatty acids.
That's it.
You're,
you're discounting the possibility
that they might not even be biological.
I mean, we're getting so close to
coming up with artificial skin.
They're talking about
artificial intelligence,
the ability to download someone's
consciousness. Who knows when,
I mean a hundred years from now,
a thousand years from now,
whatever the fuck it is, but downloading
your, your, your mind is a computer.
So you think you were looking at these
aliens. We're assuming they're biological,
but they could easily transcend biology.
If you talk,
if you talk about people that
lived a million years ago,
like, Oh, uh, you know, uh,
was Australia piff guess, right?
Yeah. The oldest version of human.
If you took one of them
and showed them an iPhone,
they wouldn't know what
the fuck to do with it.
It would basically be as
ridiculous a comparison,
the way they live to an alien being
some sort of a biological creation or no
artificial creation.
If they come up with fake cells and then
they come up with fake body parts and
eventually fake Bot,
and eventually maybe it won't enact the
same biological processes as a brain or
as a, as a, as a Human Bonnie.
But it might be something that replicates
it in a way where it can be just as
conscious and justice productive.
So consciousness would have
to be something that could
be downloaded in a sense,
right? A replica. Yeah. Replicated. So
you'd make, once you figured that out,
she said you'd make
fucking copies of yourself.
Like you didn't make at least 20
copies mail him. You're fucking your,
your relatives about
this look like aliens.
They all look the same because the
hard drive, what are the files?
Get corrupted then that's how you die.
That's how you kill ever seen alien who
got to get their fucking master file.
Well, the thing about
the killer, everybody's,
everybody's version of the
alien is essentially the same.
It's always a big gray
thing with black eyes.
Like what if they just all agree
like, look, let's just all look ugly.
No one's allowed to be hot. We don't
have Dick's anymore. So who gives a shit?
It just the warm that we
won't even one pussy one.
Let's just go.
Because after a while people hold onto it.
You can hold onto the the to hold.
Let's do a real fight and we should,
we'll fight. That happened yet so we
can still touch Phil. Yeah. Phil Davis,
this fight and go is this homemade?
Slowly you want to shut that
hormone off if you don't,
that's the thing that kills everybody.
That's number Whoville. How fucking life.
I'll take this live with the food, but
you know what? You could turn it on,
turn it on every now and then.
Every now and they can go in there,
turn on the sex drive, boom. And they're
like, damn, I want some to alias alias.
You turn it off. They can figure
out a way to transcend sex.
I mean we say if they don't have sex,
fuck them,
but what if they come up with
some shit that's way better than
just thinking about what five your
mouth and not as doing tonight.
There's no way you want to transcend that.
That's going to be beautiful.
What he's doing, he's going to do a
hundred times and keep forgetting he it.
Did I do that? Yeah. The over under on
sexual partners for Fabio Maldonado,
very payment. I've known, I know
famous Brazilian, very famous,
not going gonna name any names,
but they're crazy. Buck wild.
They'll just disappear in your,
there'll be with you in an airport,
don't meet her chicken airport
and just get another flight.
Take off with this chick
and be gone for a week.
This guy is super hardcore and he also,
you gotta think like MMA
fighters for the most part.
You guys could testify to that
very impulsive, wild fucking mean.
They're not entering into the cage
because the fucking accounting gig didn't
work out. I get time off. I get
tattoos. I do weird shit. I buy cars.
I do weird. He's got a
muscle car. American muscle
cars drive. Prius's I just,
I know you have a portion of
BMW we tell talking about.
I'm getting an American
muscle cars. Yeah, I dunno.
Thinking been thinking a lot lately.
I'm thinking I'm missing that in my life.
Get a cobra will. I used to have
a Shelby Shelby gt. $500 there.
Fucking real quick.
I'm just trying to figure out what
you got a new one or an old one.
Will real dolls or fuck
robots ever gets so good.
Better than the records actually
pimped have one and that have never,
you know what it does.
It's going to be so good.
It's not going to be this dude's house.
You go dude's house and his girlfriend
is in lingerie and she's cleaning up and
you go, gee, we'll
go outside
due to pick up $2 million.
Did you get like the ultimate one where
you can tell I gotta write that down.
Stepford wives go admin.
If the the robot wives and they clean
and do everything they want them to do,
look it up,
but look it up,
it's going to get that
what's going to happen.
Women Joe's while I
watch all that bullshit
that like three d simulation thing
eventually change the porn industry.
It already is.
They're already starting to do them.
First person porns with those things
aren't supposed to be insane hold or right
after the show and he's like,
I'm in.
Where does this for research
purposes or knowledge?
Well,
it'd be Eddie.
You could do Jujitsu with that that you
could put on an oculus rift positions.
You could go through positions.
What is the dog?
I'm teaching girls Jujitsu.
I got to do this with a girl and the
only way the cameras pick it up as is
everyone's naked by clothes
and this is a triangle series.
The lighting has to be good for him.
Yeah.
We're working on the north
south position right now.
Fun Green suit with all
these electrode balls.
There's no one there. Do you see
anybody there? There's nobody there.
There's nobody that I look up taking
pictures. There's nobody there.
There's nobody there.
Have you been on that Joe?
Developers? Can I say the new
way, the alien game on that?
They haven't been to the new one.
Terrifying.
I heard the alien game is so scary that
people think that it should be illegal
and you're, you're in the world and pay
apparently that worried, legit concern.
People are going to have heart attacks.
I'll give you, you're an old man. Okay.
If you're in your fucking seventies
and your video games, there's a lot of
big brown again. Why?
But they're fun, man.
If your fucking wife doesn't
want to have sex anymore,
I playing video games,
put me down,
fucking retired. We had
mad good. It can leave.
You got to go and it Brown.
If you don't,
I'll give you $500.
It alien comes at you and you just,
it just mean mugging
fucking give you $500.
I want to do it trustless ass.
He's got back to this kid,
this aliens and when the alien,
when your gun fucking jams like minded
and the alien comes at needs your fucking
throat, like your body
just reacts. It's crazy.
No, you're full in full on just the
whole story out on with the game. How?
How's it work?
But you get nauseous as fuck cause
there's some kind of delay so you get bad
motion sickness. He can't play
long, but that Shit's scary.
Too intense for me, man.
That's serious. Too much.
Come on. 500 bucks to
take the challenge and the x now. No
more hard. Oh he's to do the heart.
He gave him the x now.
Shit.
Here we go first round.
Yeah, those are dope. Right? Pro Bars.
I found out about those a couple of
weeks ago. Jesus Christ, they're awesome.
You should try the, there's a superfood
one with like soup Greens and shoulder.
He wrestled. Can Dude jumped
around? Phil? Phil's my boy too.
And Gloria has some really good
fucking hands, man. Fuck yeah.
Wow. Clover looks good. Scary guy.
Phil had a real problem with rumble man.
Rumble Johnson matches up poorly
with a lot of people. I agree.
But talk to take everybody.
Yeah.
Tough to take down and fucking
throws ball. Essentially. Phil Davis,
we'll have six striking and
he got in there. You just
got to keep going way back.
Actually he's going to, he's going to
figure it all out. It just takes a years.
Well he looked great.
He met glass and he's in,
he's got someone that's fucking
scary in front of them. So yeah.
Hesitating event and so tough man.
Man Trains with Chrysalis and though,
well you know that whole camp man
alliances, how great fucking camp.
There's so much talent down there.
He coaches two.
Fuck yeah dude and good dudes too.
A lot of good dudes down there.
Yeah. I need to go down there more like
friends of mine so I need to go hang out
trained,
keep moving and Phil Dude clover,
it looks real was one of the guys that
just keeps coming forward. Man. Holy.
Two of yours just land one of his,
it's weird. He looks really good too.
The ways of seeing everything.
Just slide right out of it.
It's like Phil's throwing the shots.
He's getting just offline. Just offline,
but looking for his openings.
Super patient, right.
It's trying to get them against the cage.
Keep moving sale like that.
Daddy's gonna be tough to take it
down, man. Look at this, ma'am.
Bill Davis might have to pull guard.
It's crazy to see these like super
high level wrestlers like Phil Davis,
like as you know,
you're working on your overall MMA game.
You're not doing as much wrestling
and it's not just a wrestling match.
When you start throwing
in punches and stuff,
there's some guys you just haven't
have a really hard time taking down,
even if you're as good as rested
at wrestling. As David says,
he's so fucking good. The distance is
different. Is that what the big thing is?
Damn. Front kick and a punch
behind it. Slowly. He's going
to be an amazing strike.
Oh, hey, here's a really
good, good team, man.
That's not as hurt shoulder
either. Come on, do this.
Phil's Phil might habits to old defense.
Oh shit son clovers.
Got some dope defense. Look,
give me just, Oh shit. No,
you walked through that to 40,
bringing into the camp. I mean,
chuck used to bring in so many fucking bad
ass dude. So glad we got so good. Yeah.
We uh, well he was the guy
who like for six years,
everybody wanted to get in
the UFC but his visa problem,
my rounds while he's
getting ready for Mitre,
where Leo Machida and Glover Teixeira
whatever would come in and he was 240
pounds shilling. Holy Shit. For sure.
If I look at this slide and get this,
look at this, look at this, look at
this and you're this or that. Go.
He'd let it go. But look
at them. They get slipped.
This is how it feels going to win.
He's going to wear them out when
by decision cause well, you know,
I know that I've just been fighting.
You see it's also a lot of people were
wondering who glow over was training with.
Oh, he's getting hard. Hard shots by
hard shot. Oh he's, he's eating. He's
trying to get her right here
too. He's hurt man. His hurt,
his caliber on your back, man. David's
through Samba bombs right there.
He's a bad ass and he's not
put the hooks in and chuck,
he likes his condition. Can't you
can't eat those shots man. Yeah,
he's going to get wrestler
upper cut it the fuck up.
He's getting wobbly. Look, I know who
Ian Mccall is rooting for my friend.
I like feel too, I'm just better
friends with Glover, whatever, bro.
I called you out,
get up Bro.
Going for clover.
How many times have you
heard about someone that you
thought was your friend and
they're rooting against you because oh
of cause they're one of their buddies.
It's like I take it personal and I,
it's super personal.
Is it happened a few times.
Oh yeah. Cause it happens.
I'll find out like a certain media guys.
So you think are your friends and
then for a reason I have to fight.
They're like,
yeah,
why didn't we call it picked mitre owned
to Wayne or Travis Brown and when I'm
like, cool, I won't do
interviews with them anyway.
Have either one of you guys trained
with Eric Dolphy Arrow? Yeah.
What are you thinking about him?
And I've known Eric for,
I fought for total combat, a
lot of shows. Great coach smart.
The whole group is a really smart guy.
He tried to put it down to do Phil.
It's good at, and he keeps
Dak tagging him. Look at this.
Oh Shit to fill.
This is how you feel you're wearing.
His head is getting rocked back on
these shots. He's a serious shots. Yeah,
it feels hit him hard. He's going for
it. Even if go over, gets to this round.
He's taken a lot of punishment,
man.
Really hard shots to the head
wearing them out. I mean he's, he's,
he's blocking these
oh shit.
Big Round. Phil Davis,
huge round. Oh Shit.
I feels gas tank pretty fucking good.
Totally exhausted.
But he comes out strong then you
know he's done his cardio right?
Cause he looks totally exhausted.
Even if he is in phenomenal shape,
you're gonna be tied that first round.
You're supposed,
he's supposed to be talking
100% and try to fuck him up.
He's supposed to be tired. It's all
about recovering. Yup. That's recovery.
How fast in this would be a big
victory for David's man. Dude,
if he beat the old machine in Brazil,
let's say he wins this fight.
Glover Teixeira in Brazil, the hell
you also be Fabio in Brazil. We,
I think we were at that fight
for the Stephan Bonner. Oh,
front kick up the hand behind it. That
was cool. Matt. These are bad though.
Those are heavy. There was a few of
them that really snapped his head back.
That one. One of them we really
got wobbled in the second exchange.
Look at powerful Vito Belfort. He's
not mad at his wife. Never happened.
Ever happened acting. Yeah.
Well she's like talking about the
Brazilian Pam Anderson or something.
Something like something
along those lines. So
these ridiculous Ham Anderson it. She
did a fuck load of squats on a staircase.
Yeah,
I'll blow out as just off the charts.
Bootae those chicks have big acids
there and they're getting fake
asses. If was in those, that's your
books to just a modern necessary.
Eventually they will be, I don't
like him. Eventually they will be,
but right now no guy is
accepting. Fake out. No, no,
not right now. It's too early. I do not.
I would not have a flat no ass
having crossover conversations folks.
Sorry. Big fucking fight going on. How
about acid? Sorry. Yeah, fake asses.
He comes up to the front. Kick to the
face. Good. I don't keep moving Phil.
You got to keep moving, man. I
don't think women are aware of that.
That we will not accept that. You better
hide that shit. You can't fail nobody.
It ain't like cities.
I can tell you a whole factory by your
dad will help you with the down payment
and all that. Good shot. Good shot. Asked
you about to keep that. Wait a minute.
Whose Dad's going to help her?
Chick with a down payment.
What are you talking about?
[inaudible] how many
times at the Strip club?
Orange County. It's beat. You're
here all the time but not now.
Big Switch.
You got to respect the dam.
I don't know. It doesn't look like
he's got a justice grip. Right?
What kind of grip does he have
here? Nothing. Kung Fu grip.
Oh Nice. It didn't look like he
totally had a gripped up. Right.
How many more gay teens you think we'd
get in the UFC if we had no gloves?
How many more submissions? A lot
more. A lot more submissions, right.
Is I brought this up before it.
Do you think that it would be actually
be better if he fought with no gloves?
You think about what you can
elbows, those rubber gloves
and the doctor's like, why
have anything? If you think
about just gloves,
dishwashing gloves,
so I've been thinking of what's the big,
you still have no ankle support, no
wrist support, no gloves, no nothing.
I think if you fought with no gloves,
we would realistically know
what punches do in a fight.
Right now we don't because right
now we have padded up gloves,
have hands that are wrapped up together.
We have, they do enough changes.
It's enough that most people would
wear them if they had the option.
It helped bring your hands,
you break your hands way easier
with without gloves here.
I think it makes a big difference too in
what's effective striking because your,
your your knuckles like
they don't dig it as much.
Your risk buckle a little bit on shots.
Whereas if you're wrapping your
wrists up and taping it down,
you're making it like artificially
stiff and it allows you to get, yeah,
it allows you to punch harder.
I think we get an unrealistic sense of
the value of punches because of that.
I don't think people are wa I see what
you're saying but I don't think people
are watching it for that.
I think but I don't know if
talking about people watching it.
I'm talking about for
the majority of the sport,
exactly.
Talking about the spirit of the
emotional brain make grappling better,
hyper analyzing everything and I always
do that but I mean like he was getting
rear naked chokes man.
Getting rear naked choke is a big
difference between clothes on and stuff.
That's an MMA that's pretty Dang.
This is retarded.
Like go home you if you touch,
if you touch the ground that you can't
need the face, that kind of stuff.
There's so many laws that just won't.
They never change them and just like you
can't wear tight. You can't the laws,
you can't have your calf
covered because it actually,
it's so dangerous. It's crazy.
It's illegal. Phil is tired.
You have to have the pope to the eye.
Damn.
I was just about to say that Phil.
He blew out so much energy
in that first round.
He's beating the brakes off of him. He,
well, he did a lot of fucking damage.
Rick Inglis's. Right. Then
you sent the Fernandez when he was 27
Mcgregor's got a pink shirt and tie.
Of course he does. I love
him. My new favorite fighter.
She likes cockiness. Wow.
Powerful Aubrey. Good choice.
Oh God. Right in the eye
with that. Got It. Hate dogs.
She's going to be bidding against
them. I hope it. Here's another thing.
If we're going to have gloves with them,
if we're going to have gloves,
why the fuck don't they cover
the tips of the fingers?
Why don't they figure out a way to
do that? Because if you're putting,
it's kind of help the fingers, man.
It's not that much. No problem.
It's a big problem, man.
I think it's a huge every,
how many John Jones fights have
there been? I pokes fuck everyone,
but even if the fingers were covered,
can't you still poke someone's
eye but the nails not there.
John's pinky fingers,
little hover condoms.
You're not going to be
able to dig in one condoms.
They'll still fuck you up. Let me look
and see me. I would have finger condom on
open up point. You'd be like, damn,
I know he got fingered
conduit or somewhere to,
my daughter accidentally poked him in
the eye the other day and I saw sparks
gloves on. Like, what's the fucking
difference? If they grab their balls,
if that grabbed their ass, what the
gloves on and they wouldn't do that.
They're or, Whoa, Phil
Davis is a big takedown.
Take your gloves off the rear
naked. Every order. New Glucose.
Nope. Too High. It's the sink got too
high. She's got to drop his hips done,
but he doesn't want to lose a position
when it doesn't wanna get fucked off.
Standing end of the round
two there a short time.
I thought it was going to do
nothing for Phil. Yeah. Fuck yeah.
Emma May takes off the gloves.
Football takes off the pads and helmets.
[inaudible]
you guys see that rugby thing with a dude?
Kao The dude on the field.
He grounded him.
Did he hit him with a right hand?
Dropped him and then fucking
pounded them out from the mouth
at a karate tournament.
Who takes out both competitors?
He's the RAF and he's tried to break it.
He's trying to separate them,
but like a Russian rep
dude, he made karate, looked
beautiful. It was a real fight.
He was trying to separate them and
then you just want blah, blah, blah,
and then he kicked the guy.
Look days. It's amazing.
Name of the video of nursing that
maybe if you youtube search karate,
karate, Raf. Fight Ref
everybody, right? He's in my,
it's like a three second video. It's
amazing. Okay, then watch this real quick.
This is about three seconds.
Fucking truck.
Camera Guy.
Fucking nuts.
Where was Jenny's ass? They were
fucking screaming in the headphones.
Why didn't you show Jenny's ass? You
showed her face, you her walked down.
She's very beautiful.
If you had an opportunity to shore up,
we need that for a Camaro.
American needs that Phil Davis two rounds.
He got clipped right though.
Oh Damn.
Clover knows it's [inaudible]
took over is on fire right now,
but he knows it's do or die,
man.
These two rounds in the
whole damn big push.
Big Push a Louis and sham. Well,
he's built like a goddamn superhero
is his back. His legs are retarded.
They're just so goddamn big.
Go full screen on that shit. We're going
to watch a fight look like, hold up.
Positive, positive, positive, positive.
We'll watch that shit after
this fight that's happening.
We'll need some downtime while there's we,
I want to fucking kill an animal to
someone to take their clothes off.
Take that whole big takedown for Phil
was the best light heavyweights in the
world. A cue up that rush and beating
the shit out of these two guys from 1982
that's fine.
As long as he had those shiny pants on.
I used to love the kickbox and pants
that lace in the front like a sneaker.
I remember that Shit. Chuck Norris. She
used to wear them. I have those pitches.
I had those. I love Chuck Norris so much.
I wore those for my taekwondo pants.
Oh look at this. Phil Davis
gave it up. Oh look at that.
I like how you hook the leg. That
was nice. That was very nice.
Cradle baby. Phil Davis,
10th grade wrestling man.
And my big brother used to do that to me.
I hate it.
But you remember how Bas Rutten used to
tap guys with some fucking crazy cradle?
He would,
he would be in that bar chart.
Press the bar. I still use. Yeah.
It's not that I'm asking assisting gay
headlock on one side and he hooks your
leg and the other side and he fucking
flexes and just separate the head from
your body sharp machine.
He's
so God damn strong.
But especially in his prime boss was
so damn technique dash to make you shit
yourself can make you shit
yourself. Yeah. We almost,
well almost saw wants in the UFC.
I forget who was gone for it,
but I almost forgot it
existed. And then, uh, Joe, uh,
Joe Silva actually reminded me that's
that Bas Rutten thing. I was like,
that's right.
Damn Phil Davis run in it.
That's insane. Running it, man.
Another dog. This is a big job.
Big Punches man.
Phil Davis looking as good as ever
against a fucking legit killer. But yeah,
best performance of, yeah. Well, you
know what? He came off that rumble fight.
He knew he had to take it to the next
level. I, you know what? I'll be honest,
I would like to see him going
for the finish. He's trying
man now. I mean submit,
submit duties. Sylvie's beat
the shit out of him. I mean,
he's got two minutes ago and he's
beating the shit out of Glover Bat.
Did he mean he's hit him with
30 or 40? Done. Answered Shock.
I'd still one handed the one harm.
Comoros was him wanting the wonder bar.
Very high level. What
he's doing to Glover, man.
I know he's making it look at these,
but this is not,
this is sick dude.
Glover's an animal animal straight.
I wonder how much of an effect,
if any,
and I'm just throwing this out there
because I have to look at that.
He's on his camp to the camp in Danbury,
Connecticut.
Had as opposed to doing like
American top team, you know,
like what kind of sparring partners
is it yet? And I don't know.
I mean maybe he had a bunch
of guys flying in tomorrow.
This is an awesome wrestler though, I
would imagine. Yeah, no, Phil is awesome.
Oh there we go. Look, it's still going on.
Glover could still catch them when one
20 to go. I wanted to finish. Right.
Deep breaths hearing cause this going.
Ooh.
Ooh. Tude over the top. Oh, you heard him?
He heard him with that one man
that was clean on the jaw. Whoa.
If he comes back now. So there
you go man. Nice dropdown.
That single kicks chasing them new.
He's just to stay on that dude.
Yeah.
And if he drags me to the ground and
shit is all his, oh he came over,
he recovered. He
recovered. Look at that as
his grappling. Cardio is different than
striking cardio cause it's striking.
Cardio's more labored. So when you
see him standing up and he's tired,
he's still like moving, kind of labored.
But when you see him on the ground,
he looks fucking sharp as shit.
Even when he's tired,
he's gassing all over the place and
recovering all over the place. Gassing,
recovering, but his wrestling, like
he doesn't gas when he's grappling.
I mean he's,
he's breathing while he's doing it.
I mean,
you could tell he's taking some big
ass deep breaths. His mouth is open,
but he's fucking dominate.
He can do this all night.
They could go five rounds of
this. He didn't do this. I
mean, he's got a burn hot.
You have to burn hot in order
to where a guy out in the open,
I mean he's got to wear himself out.
So we're,
we're getting a view of his
cardio over putting his hand up.
That's called an ass whooping.
So
what happened is that San
Diego about swooping in
Brazil, that was pretty good. Now that
was crazy. I'm strong, real concrete.
Three rounds, three
rounds, three rounds a day.
Look like that after the
first round. Remember? Yeah.
That's a big victory right there.
I'm just calling a big victory is huge
because if he looks I fucking quit.
Quit my MMA, Bro. I'm going straight
to pro wrestling. Dan, what's up?
Power bomb everyone. Big fucking loss
mentality. You need to get to that point.
I Phil Davis is that cap?
Yeah. Tressler coming off
it again. Damn. That was a nice move.
That front kick right hand he does and
he throws the right hand like a jab.
His right leg is forward when he throws
it, but he's got a lot of pop behind it.
He catches you like it cracks you with
it in the end he and you're gassing all
over the place constantly and recovering
constantly. Right. That's just gas cook.
If you went gassing all over the place,
you ain't pushing yourself hard enough.
Exactly. That's how you break people.
Yeah. That's just, yeah. We just saw,
we just saw a film,
break him shit about cardio my whole life.
I always heard people talk about cardio.
Tito Ortiz,
we talk about Cardio Radica too.
They're talking about cardio and I always
thought cardio was how long can you go
before you get really tired,
like your like huffing and puffing.
That's your cardio. I've got like
eight minutes of Cardio I got,
that's what I always thought it was.
No one really explained it to me at all.
I never trained like a
professional athlete until
Metamorris. Yeah. And once I,
once I, I decided this, of
course he, of course you weren't.
So I just decided what am I going
to do for Cardio? I was, you know,
I was lifting weights,
I was doing a lot of Jujitsu.
I was training with John John
and I just decided, fuck,
I'm going to do sprints and
I'm gonna go to the pool,
the 24 hour fitness and I just,
I'm going to figure this out by myself.
I just drove to the fucking pool.
They had a big clock and I just,
I never did this. I'm
not a professional. I go,
I'm on a sprint 20 times across the pool.
I've done sprints before in the past
20 times and as soon as the clock,
the big clock in the pool hits the 12th
that's when I'll take off and then I
might finish at 25 or 30 and I'll stay
at the other side of the pool until it
hits 12 again.
It hits 12 and go boom sprint again.
I just made this up and I did it 20 times.
The problem with doing cardio and the
pools that you don't get to read your
heart rate. Do they have like a cardio
monitor that works? This is what I did.
I kept it simple.
I just wouldn't fast as I fucking can
and I didn't even know the coaching me
because cause I,
my law was I'm only going to arrest until
it hits 12 again so I better bust ass.
So I was racing across the pool
so I can get that time to rest.
And what I learned about
myself is holy Shit.
Every time I on a across I got really
tight. The first three were easy,
but when I got the 10 to 12 my plan was,
I just said 20 cause metamorphosis,
20 minutes.
I go,
I'm going to do 20 and do that at 10
1112 I was dead just on the edge of the
pool.
Barely Gal was dying.
There's all these old people
at the pool and should they go,
what the fuck is this guy doing? I just
made the shit up, but what I learned,
I learned it.
You could be dead tired and
recover within 30 seconds. Yeah,
that's what I was learning and I'll be
dead when they hit the nine I'd be like,
we're at the table, but when it,
by the time we have to 11 I'd go,
let's go again. Another sprint.
The Ama, you get across, boom.
I ended up with 30 seconds of rest.
Same thing.
So you learn that Holy Shit,
you can recover over and over.
If I didn't know this, when I'd get
to that point in grappling, I would,
I would go, I'm done. I would break. I go,
I'm done. Understand I have to do more.
Yeah.
Oh,
someone needs to talk to them.
They already know you're the
champ taking the beaver effect.
When he put that shit on, everyone
goes, knowledge is great, man. Yeah,
look good man.
Let's show that karate video.
Let's shut up karate video calling
out Anderson's our full fill.
Did he call it airs and sold on Anderson
Silva? He did. That's what he said. Yeah.
He goes, I'd be like resistance, but
there's only one I want to fight next.
That's a mind. God is fighting
Nick Diaz. Why is he saying that
now? He talks a lot. He's got a got a
triple, not in that time. Think it's fat.
He knows what he's
talking about. It's watch this shit. So
the dude's or karate, Duke in and out.
Watch the raft once the rough.
He's just a fucking each other up
and try while they're gone off. Man,
where is this taking place? Check
this out. Where's this taking place?
It's a gymnasium for sure,
Dale.
Oh Shit.
Took out that guy to fucking went like
cop. No one. No one's
stopping him either man.
Genes at the circus where the
animal just goes fucking crazy.
So he tries to push and
what they don't push away
fake guy and look at this guy.
He gets caught.
This guy is tore to [inaudible] is
tore up. That's insane. He fucking
camera crew that will, they're filming
today. That's why we're watching it.
The competitors like what the, like this
is someone's memory. That was a sketched.
Maybe somebody was filming in the
making of a movie. I don't know. Wow.
That looked like a real fight, man.
It was a movie that was a real fight.
Those guys were really hitting each other.
That was a good technique to,
where'd that take place Jamie?
Looking at?
It doesn't necessarily say it
looks Russia. Russia. Yeah.
That looks like something would happen.
Have you seen that?
The amateur boxing fight that the guy
after the fight it takes you to off and
goes over. Beats the shit out
of the raft. It's bad. Yeah.
I think and watch that.
It's an old guy.
It's fucked up and you see a chase the
guy out and they get a fucking shit.
Help the old man, but he's fallen over.
It's like, oh fuck. Yeah. It wasn't funny.
Now looking at the graphics on
these Games, I know that looks good.
That looks like a real dude.
Look at this. By the way.
It doesn't like that when you play,
it
just doesn't,
I mean it looks close,
but this is the [inaudible] enough
clipping and weirdness to it.
The frames per second that they can
achieve and these previews they do,
they can just make it look a lot
sweeter where a couple of years from
indistinguishable from reality
though probably on those games.
Well you're going to be able to have games
where you use the oculus rift and you
play out like a video.
You make a video of things that are
actually happening and instead of a game
engine,
just have them do it like a hundred
different fucking ways where you know,
have them repeat the same scenarios over
and over again from all these different
angles so that no matter where you are,
where you're moving,
it feels like you're actually doing it.
You know,
you could turn to your
left and the fucking, it's,
it's really just like as
if you turn to your left,
like there'll be able to program those
in the same way they do it with like stop
motion animation where you have
to do each individual frame.
They'll just have different
possible scenarios that they have.
People actually act out to the point
where they cover the whole room, like a,
like a fan,
like one of those folding fans.
Every ounce of the room gets
covered with a possibility.
And then you have these head headset on
and you're in this room and you can take
these possibilities.
It's already been planned out as
a video and then you watch it,
you play it out and you fucking shoot
aliens like in real time and you fuck and
you Siri ships every everyday
you get it going to happen. Man,
that has that electro stem you down
when you put electric stem on it,
like causes collapse, you know? So if you
get hit somewhere, it'll just cramp up.
You know, they don't have it yet,
but it's going to happen. Yeah.
So that frees you up one side.
You have to like limp through.
They have those things already.
Those, those stem machines,
people use them already. They supposed to
help recovery. Yeah, the complex machine.
Yeah. If you added that
shit too, like a suit,
something bites you, you feel
it. Teeth clamp in your body.
You could have a virtual
lab on your pants.
What's given us give up
some predictions here.
What do we think is going to
hold Kot though? Mendez decision.
Although when you say Aldo, like how
quickly a first round, second round,
third round, third round Mendez
decisions has been says second round.
Tko second round. Tko says for
your poet he gives zero fucks.
He's making calls. Yeah.
Eddie Bravo. I'm going to say
dammit. Dammit. I don't know. I'm going
with them and I don't know as well.
Kareem Abdul, check them all. What do you
think? I don't know man. It's a tough one.
It's a tough one. Great Pink
stolen. It's really fun. Yeah.
This side of the table takes zero chance.
Here's, here's my take on it. Aldo is
fucking incredibly difficult to take down.
Like one of the most difficult
to take down until he gets tired.
The problem is by the time you get
him tired and you take him down,
you are eating some of the fastest
fucking leg kicks in the business.
That combination, the Duchy, the left
hook to body, and then the right leg kick.
He throws that motherfucker as good as
anybody that's ever walked the face of
the planet. If it Mendez is throwing
that against pads every day,
that's part of looking at things.
It is.
It is possible that Mendez can win
this fight. Don't get me wrong,
Mendez can knock out anyone on the
fucking planet if he connects the way he
knocked out Clegg Weda the way
he knocked out Darren Elkins,
if Mendez cracks you,
he can fucking put it on you.
It's the hardest hitter in
this unbelievable athlete.
Ridiculous Freak athlete hits
hard to it's, it's a wild fight.
I don't, I don't know what I say earlier
that I have no idea. I have no idea.
Mendez can win this fucking
fight. Don't, don't get me wrong.
No doubt about it and
he can win by knockout.
I think he could do that to anybody.
The question is if you watch their first
fight and you watch their second fight,
how much has he improved and that's the
only thing that we're going to find out
tonight. We're going to find out how
much he's improved and whether or not,
although is in any way regressed, you
know, whether or not his injuries,
he's had a bunch of injuries.
He said like a nagging neck injury.
He said all sorts of different things
that have you know, fucked with him.
He's had kidney stones that
he's gotten that either are,
it's weird who you talked to.
It's either it's genetic or it's from
weight cutting. There's a lot of,
a lot of people that believe it's,
it's an either or thing that you might
be genetic and you get it get exacerbated
by the way. Cutting huge. He's a big guy.
He's a big guy and he struggles to make
that one 45 and I think that's one of
the reasons why he's been having a hard
time in the later rounds. But God damn,
to get through those fucking rounds,
you've got to go through hell son.
That beating he put on your
ride favors leg. Holy Shit Dude.
He's something. He something
man, he's a lightning fast,
ridiculous striker who was
also world class at Jujitsu.
His jujitsu game is fucking real good.
You just don't see it. You know you,
but occasionally you do see it like in
the Mike Brown fight when he got brown on
his back and he sunk those hooks in and
that is a legit black belt back mount to
smashing. You know, he's, where were
you at that your I fight with him.
That was, I was out there. It was fucking,
when all that came out to the, uh,
I'm going to run this town tonight.
Yeah.
That was the only person in
Sacramento going, Oh my God. Like,
what are you doing? I'm like, he's
going to fuck your boy up. Wait,
ed sores told me about that before. He
was so excited. His manager is like,
he's got to come out to that Jay z song.
I've run this town tonight.
And we were like,
Oh shit.
He's going deep expressions in Sacramento.
It needs to be a scamming combo.
Gary Combo with the elite wrestler with
Chuck Liddell striking like that was a
nightmare. Like what the fuck are you
going to do? You might get shut off,
there's a good chance tonight you're going
to get shut off. You know what I mean?
But the Combo of black belt in
Jujitsu and vicious striker,
damn, that's a whole
different dimension. It is,
right is the ground game
is a more dangerous ground.
You're trying to get this guy to
the ground, but he might choke you.
There's a very good that he's better than
you on the ground. So
what now? And it opens up.
You're going to do now it opens up pos.
Wrestlers in this day and age are not
really just rustlers pretty much everybody
has some ground game knowledge,
but you'd be amazed at how many guys
are fighting in the UFC that you know,
they really don't work
on certain positions.
Like they never work on
being on their back. Yeah, I,
I've rolled with some people that are
in the FCM like I'm fucking tiny and I
just followed you up like, and it's
you guys and I've been, I've been,
everyone talks about my wrestling,
but I'm not a world class wrestler.
I'm just go to that main wrestling.
I mean I do beat up kids in college and
stuff, but I never accomplished anything.
Yeah. But it's all, it's a shit. I've
been doing Jujitsu for just as long.
I'm only a purple belt, but that's
because my coaches, my coach and he won't,
I don't wear a ever. Yeah. Well
that's probably, Jeeva is very like,
he's amazing. You know. And she did
too. But you can put it on a Gig.
That's how you,
that's how you get your belts.
Don't get a bravo started
on the game please. I'm
safety. It's got a comma
where you came from. I know.
I just love the fact that we were in a
fucking hoists Gracie tee shirt after all
the shit you guys have been talking to
[inaudible] you haven't talked to any
shit? No. I'll put some in.
Somebody comes up, I'm like,
I talk shit.
In a funny way.
Those meetings are shitting in the angry
when he's really mad at he hates me.
Get Mad at you man.
And a funny one.
You've been nothing but fucking
praising of him from the jump man.
I mean we both said that
if it wasn't for voice,
we would have never been in any Jujitsu
in the first place. He just needs to sit.
He's also, he's a proud guy and just
he needs to sit down and realize with,
with uh, with Eddie and just
get the two of them together.
If they spoke for more than half an hour,
hoist would realize like Eddie,
he's never disrespectful. No, he
would never realize he's beating.
Your brother never realized that
he needs an Iowaska
trip more than anything.
It's unfortunate because a lot of people
were upset at him for this whole thing.
I mean, I've read a lot of forum threads
about people with like legit arguments,
like the,
I used to be a hero to them and then you
hear him saying shit like this is like,
this is just not what my hero would say.
Like why are you saying that?
Even the MMA websites
we're talking about that.
I understand what he was saying
about pot. I, I, you know,
crazy way. I know this isn't a
sound insane, but I appreciate it.
Like he's, he's thinking about me.
That's fucking nuts. That's crazy.
I'm going to see saying my man. That's
crazy. Yeah. It's the ultimate use legend.
I think it's, I think it's pretty
cool. It's flattering. I wouldn't even,
I like it.
I'm like [inaudible] he thought he would
punch my nose if I looked at him and
rubber guard. He would punch you in
the nose. Moist with Beltour. Yeah.
He signed with belts or he's
going to do not as a fighter.
He's going to be Alexa ambassador.
You know,
Scott Coker is a friend of uh,
the UFC.
He used to own strike force.
I think it's going to be different
relationship with Bella tour.
And I think fuck yeah, it's, it's
always good for the sport. Look,
they know what they're doing.
You know,
they know that they have a
B level organization is not,
there's nothing wrong with that.
There's nothing wrong with having a beat.
They have some great fights, a
lot of fun fights. But you know,
they've got a manual Newton,
the UFC has John Jones,
John Manual. Newton is a very
good fighter, but he's not
John Jones. And you know,
they had uh,
they had fucking Hector Lombard who
might be the mother fucker at one 70.
He might be the motherfucker scare.
Yay. He might pay every month to talk.
Everybody's scared of that.
Too Tiring with,
uh, really interesting. Thanks. Anyway,
I want to do it.
I'm just going to take some time off.
Thank the sober and you know who's
scary than Woodley physically.
Woodley's a fucking beast.
They're Lombard. Exactly. Can
you take a scan? We take a sale.
It looks like a centipede.
He's got dudes
a bigger scarier that like a buff dude
in a real old old cartoon where that'd be
just like a dude who just like
really buff and it looks fake.
His ass legs just don't talk about
this as a tail piece on them.
I thought it was brushing
bodybuilding spray painted sweats on.
I'll do.
I was like the ass on that cows.
He's just all judo the fuck out.
Yeah. We haven't had asked for days.
We did have some gay talk. Okay. We did.
Okay, so we're all a little bit town.
Just the tip.
Remember we said that if we were
okay with this place would be a mess.
We'll be having an orgy.
There wouldn't be no fight companion.
We'd be under an orgy
watching the fight to win.
You'd pull your dick out and be like,
what? Darren Elkins one right back
be like loads.
You got another one.
Your neighbors
when you look [inaudible] bro quit.
He called Quinten. Is that but
someone got called them out mountain.
There's 10 minutes left. I got another
one bro. Let time pass per, okay.
Let's hear what it sounds
like when they introduced it.
I can't go higher than you want
to hear what it sounds like.
You thought you said light cause
you're a volume button on that.
I want to hear this when they introduced,
although that place is going to
go fucking Shit House insane.
Give it a good crank Jamie cranked
up bitch. Where the fuck up?
Look at the size of that place.
Jamie gold. Craig it up Jamie.
I just love hearing the
Brazilian fans scream.
You ain't seen Aubrey's been there dude.
It's like no other place in the world
when it comes to the enthusiasm of the
fans.
It's
clearly the charts. Listen,
listen, listen. Here is
so far.
Sounds like fucking Stephan bottles.
He never it
from, he grew up on the outer side but
Conor Mcgregor in Rio and then I fought in
Dublin and Dublin was in Rio was amazing
but Dublin was it fucking insane.
They're just drunker. Oh
they're drunk rather wild. Wild.
At first I got the, and I was kind
of like, fuck this kid Connor,
like kind of annoying.
And then as I'm sitting there watching
him like psycho analyzing the whole thing
and just kinda just
watching it all unfold.
Like this motherfucker is crazy and
everywhere you go in Ireland they're like,
oh you're already here for Connor.
Yeah, I guess so, right? I guess
that's why I'm here. Here we go.
Mendez moving forward and as
they kicked me this Mendez,
he did his face right away.
Boy. Dwayne movement there.
Look at this. Nevermind.
He does look like Tj.
I lied again to good, good shots. Totally
dude. Aldo demendez looking at, Ooh,
I live in all. Look, it's ghetto like that
kicked by Mendez right there though. Oh,
you still might not go to the snow.
This is going to,
someone's going to sleep I think.
Oh check that one.
So that one coming to come after.
Good Jab, right hand by Mendez.
The more it can make all the work,
like this man man has got a little
bit of a mouse in that left eye.
A little bit of a mouse.
And if men
he's rocked. That was a big
that. Who? Who's wobbly son.
Left Hook
uppercut.
Holy Shit
going south pawn.
I'm occasionally fearless.
Good.
Jen Mendez looking to get this
fucking title man. Are you kidding me?
This is fucking exciting.
Fuck yeah, it is.
Ooze on looking at uncork right
there in that right hand. Oh,
I'll throw lands one. You don't want to
let with creating monsters. Seriously.
Well we kept but look now
Mendez is right in front of him.
He doesn't want to do this guy
days until it got you there.
Got To get on your bike, man.
Yeah. Well you know what?
You get that feeling like you might finish
this fucking guy and you're standing
right in front of her.
No catches people.
That's how although catches people,
you don't want to be
standing in front of them.
You want to go right back to
what got you to that spot.
I mean he's definitely recovered by now.
You've got to assume he's recovering
the fly flying near right,
but he hasn't been recovered.
Maybe it doesn't look the same hard.
Maybe Mendez knows he heard him like
right there and I didn't look like it was
like boom, body shot. Nice.
Oh like kick.
He's going to go high with it.
Eight eight 11 looks like it hurt
him a little bit. I left her son.
Good defense by Mendez to although so
goddamn sudden he could just end shit and
everything he throws is perfect.
Perfect technique,
Mendez just standing
right in front of all the,
who the fuck would have
thought this vicious left
dude.
Nice Jab by Mendez.
How much better to his fucking striking
get wait mode when fucking Ludwig is a
wizard.
He really is a goddamn wizard.
A crazy OCD wizard.
Nice left hook. God Damn. Oh,
oh, oh, oh,
okay.
Damn. He was like, no more knees. Please
kick. Oh, chow on the
dude. All those lit up.
Look at his face. Oh, I'm
chuck over the top again.
It's awesome.
Oh
Shit. One 37 to go. Damn.
Holy Shit. What a fucking
fight. That's it in the crowd.
Now just miss with that advocate.
They're screaming at you. Oh,
you can't just heat that kick.
He just ate that one thing.
The crowds ate a jab right
there too. I bloke. Come on,
man. They worked it out. Don't
give them a chance again.
Back to the foot work son. Yeah,
he's got it. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
I hope Duane Ludwig screaming that out.
I'm right now
trying to stay on him, but you know,
although deserves his fucking rest.
If it's a legit, I poke. Let's
take a look at it right here. Yeah.
Kinda hit his eyebrows in Aurora,
Colorado. That's not an iPod.
Okay. So let's look the, the consensus,
he's probably taking a little
bit of a break right here, right?
100% veteran move 500% right? Yep. And
there's nothing wrong with that, right?
This isn't his first Rodeo. Yeah. And it
look, it legitimately did go in his eyes,
so he's taken a little bit of a break.
Maybe it hurts more than me. He's like,
yeah. And he's allowed to say if he's
allowed to. It's not really cheating.
Did I get poked in eye? Yeah. He's
probably not even say anything. Huh?
It went my eye. Are you
okay? When my eye. Ooh,
right back at it.
Oh my hand. Oh, I love her clip.
Let's take some down. Look
at this. Scramble matches
keep down.
Lot of times we'll have shit finish and
finish him. Oh Man. You got to finish.
Got to get that knee across.
Oh,
18 seconds to go.
I've got
no heart attack.
Or they say
Mendez work. Oh my God. For some awesome.
Oh good.
Holy Shit. Covered. He'll recover.
What a fucking round. I mean things
like a movie coming out of this bucket.
Two gyms together just turn into amazing.
Oh my God.
What a fucking round Bueno says.
Oh look at the end of the fight,
boom at the buzzer.
He relaxed.
Just beat,
beaten up the first and the minute you
see the girl in the background shaking
her finger. How has that
made you? Let me know.
She's going to get on a, on Twitter. I've
got fired. Watch has got to be mended.
His girlfriend.
Yeah.
No Brazilian check's going to be wagging
her finger or if she is she saying you
showed her message shit. He recovered.
He's fine. Yeah, you said it fine.
You crazy, dude. That guy's a
fucking the fine. Fine, fine.
He might be concocted outside
birdies. Dude, look at him right now.
It's not the only one. No knows right
now. Right now it's Chad. That's it.
He's the only one who knows. Look
at is, I know he's glazed over.
Even if, yeah. Even if
he does recover well,
that was a stunning patch of the footwork.
I sometime I look at him dancing
around like an angel dude,
like a tiny little Buffy angel.
He took a bunch a bunch of fucking
punches off of his clock right there.
It looks beautiful. Look at that.
If he gets, if he gets hit again,
he's going to be for sure his Chin's
going to be diminished by that.
Are you crazy? Look at that as
a slip and slip. No rock though.
Eddie Bravo's given up
on doing commentary.
Chad just looks better. He's not moving
on that left everyone at every level.
He's buying time with his footwork.
Oh.
Oh No. He could hear that. He
was trying to hit it with a knee.
He was trying to catch the jab.
There we go. Yeah. This one does.
Yeah. Unless the fight ends here. No,
weird shit's happened before. Let's
take a look at it. Oh, split wrong.
Strong foot tables. Okay. Now Ian,
if he's got a metal cup on,
how much difference is it for the front,
the deck and the ball's bees and
for beans, frank? Yes, it's fine,
but it's the undercarriage. The called
the table shots still hurts. That hurts.
That one sucks. I wasn't. Yeah,
in the teen area and then underneath you
still go up into your junk and it hurts.
I got kicked in the Dick the other day.
I align brews down half my deck.
And what circles is that conversation
come up? I got kicked in the Dick.
I called her. I'm like, well you
got something to tell me. Like
I got hit in the Dick one so bad.
I just went and started wearing
a cup for Jujitsu cause my Dick,
I took my jacket off and it
was filled with blood. Oh yeah.
And so I was thinking,
God damn it,
do I go to the emergency room and
then I decided what would I do?
That was my nose. I like it was
my nose. I wouldn't go anywhere.
So I just went home and I jerked off
cause I w I figured dash got hard.
I didn't have to worry and it was okay.
It's weird how we're on the seafront.
I piss blood for a few days though.
Oh,
it was just a guard pass to
somebody was passing my garden.
He shoved his knee
right into my dick hole.
So as a girl I get nervous about that.
I just wish y'all would wear cubs all
the time. I made kids after that though,
so it's all good.
Back to this fucking awesome
fight. Shit. Oh there's a hard one.
That was a hard one.
And he shook.
What did he shake his finger because
he checked. Checked it. Yeah.
Yeah.
Tell us.
Well this is the thing about Aldo.
Everybody knows that in the second,
third and fourth round he starts to slowly
begins to taper off and oftentimes in
the fifth round is just not the same
fighter for the first couple of rounds.
He's a motherfucker. Ooh, that
rocked him. But there was,
this was a crazy first round and
here we are in the size of body care.
If Mendez might be start
wold, I wasn't going, man,
this might start to think that
he's, uh, he's getting into him.
But you know what?
Men Is,
has not been known for his cardio
either because he's such a Beasley dude.
You know those Beasley guys,
the lombards and the Woodley's and
there's so much muscle involved,
so much fast twitch too. It's
not that slow. Endurance runner.
Nick Diaz type muscle. Yeah. That
guy. You never see him tired.
This is a fucking great fight though,
Huh? Cause this is where it gets weird.
It gets weird if you can get into
the third, fourth and fifth round,
especially if Mendez starts getting
loose. Who won the first round? For sure.
Share fucking crazy round. But I've got to
say, although, although had them almost,
how cold? Yeah, yeah, yeah. I got
a job twice instead of one. Yeah.
The last one was giant. The
last one was just Jen. Oh,
nice body kick. Oh Shit.
Mendez getting loose.
Oh Shit. Oh ooh. Check.
We owie Owie owie
right hand over the top to
the body by all them. Wow.
All the loves that left Hook.
He's got a fucking nasty whipping one too.
No matter how much adrenaline you have,
when you get,
when you check a leg kick like that shit
in the shit, it's still hurts, right? Oh,
the fight.
Well,
unless you're on one of those tie dudes
like Malheur pet that just see ever seen
Malpais fight where it kicks guys shit in
the Shin on purpose to break them down.
We just had Yeltsin client or at our gym,
God,
145 pounds kicking a bag. Like, oh my God.
He's a ferocious guy, man.
One of my shitty partners
just beat Mallee pet reeling.
Shane Blonsky fighting boy shit dude.
Yachts and Clive fought in Lyon fights
recently. Holy Shit. Is he good?
He thought whether that Indian guy,
yeah.
I love watching pure tie like
those short typewriters like him.
Like mammopad Yeltsin cries the mother
fucker though, man. He's got like,
he's 30 years old, right? And he
has like some ungodly my fights.
Some that's so crazy. Him Sand shy,
super bond guys like that. Yeah,
because then when they all come over
they come and stay with him and like hang
out in my coach.
Oh do they really amazing rules.
The most hardcore they allow them.
Yeah.
Well they allow you to clinch up and throw
each other on the ground as it pretty
much on the, on the ground.
You could throw him and shit.
He had left foot drop on.
How does that bedrock old
fights. Yeah. Draco they used to,
they used to have [inaudible]
Draka these to have a takedowns.
Most Smith fought and that shit is that
those Ho taste them again at the end of
the week since sweeps and like kind of,
it's the most hardcore Mendez. Strike it.
I'm thinking about the taking
the time I oh, drag him into the
hole. Punch and kick it
still be more hardcore. Yeah,
I think so. I think it should
be more Tyrell's. Yeah.
I like my lion fights better rules.
They'll allow
more tide. They clinch up, they
hold onto each other for awhile.
They ragdoll each other and
needed a body elbow over the top.
They don't even have elbows and glory.
Glory is all kickboxing, like Dutch style.
And we have some amazing Americans right
now. Yeah, I mean you got Kevin Ross,
Joe Schilling, Romeo,
Don's a chi and back like,
and these are all guys that are
up, you know friends with. It's,
it's to watch him fight as fuck.
How bout shillings fucking
fight in golden glory again.
So what does his name Marcus,
oh my God. And then he fought.
So that was an extra rather fight
fight. Another fight. Three rounds.
And then he went and fought in the
finals and fought in Fatuma decision.
Incredible. With arm and arm to
quit fucking bad ass mother fucker.
He's so talented.
You see that spinning and spinning
backhand that he hit him with the slip.
I just loved the way he fights too with
his hands down. It was like a snake. Ooh,
Mendez coming at him. Now this is the
round. You pick it up. Yeah. This is the,
look at this. He's already, he's got
to show the, she you. That's the game.
It's a soup now.
Things are looking way better for Mendez.
You digging into the third,
fourth and fifth rounds?
Traditionally you're dealing
with a different Aldo. Oh No, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
That's the anywhere where we are a sad
group of fucking non fuck AA or gee
haven't dude. Have you had
someone cut their, your,
your eye with their finger of your
budget. Cut your eye before. No,
but you've Winkeljohn
story, right? Yeah. My Shoe,
the great trainer from Jackson's
academy went blind because the guy,
he was holding pads for his toenail went
into his eyeball slices eyeball but it
was like Ooh. Oozing out into his
hands. Like fell out. Yeah. Oh Man.
So it's like a bad one. You ever ever
hear of Sean Sean bias, Sean bias,
crazy fucking fighter from nor cal.
We were wrestling season tickets back and
he would just grab my head and skipped
his finger up my eyeball.
I was bleeding.
That was one of the scariest moments ever.
But also it hurts so bad.
Okay, here we go. They're back. They're
back. Cause he going to take a point away.
No, I said next time. Next
time. Just take a point.
Let's see. Mendez, good
defense. Oh, tagged them.
He tagged him tagging with
that left. Whoa. What the left.
Oh,
right hand of all those.
So Dan is such a sweet right hand.
That's the one he heard him with the
end of the first router. Yeah, Dude.
Although still here man. Great,
great endurance. And the shark,
I wish men does get through
his wrestle a little bit. Yeah,
they show it to him like can you
make them work?
But I think he's worried that
if he makes them work like that,
then he'll be too tired to do what he
needs to do to stay safe on his feet.
Right. He burned a lot of energy
earlier and that he knows,
but he wants to definitely be able to
have the speed and movement. This is the,
the Duane Ludwig style strategy stuff.
You know what's most interesting
about this Duane Ludwig approach?
He didn't use it.
No
toilet. Straight floor drains the
first guy to slow it straight.
Dwayne had nasty counters.
No this and no fucking no slop
in any of his movement. Yeah.
Like when he knocked out Jonathan Goulay
with that right hand. That's shit.
He's backing up and that right
hand comes off like a piston.
That's how great Dwayne is.
If he knows oh shit.
Oh Shit.
He knows that uh,
the best possible style will be
stuff that he doesn't, isn't, oh,
hard ice chat tude although fucked
him up with that Jab. Nice inside.
Like Carlos Mendez is trying to win this
fucking fight he got when he gets hit,
he's getting angry and he's like digging
his heels in and say no, not tonight,
not tonight.
And she's a couple of times been tagged
and then come back and rocked all though
because he's just determined to
win this fight. Straight title.
But man, that's where you gotta be
careful when you're moving towards Aldo.
Those counters come so sharp.
Who Do you thinks winning so far?
That's a good question. I think
all those up, all those, yeah,
I'll definitely when the first,
I think in the second round
I would say it's close,
but probably all though, right? I
would have to go over that again. Oh,
that was definitely sure.
Yeah. She knows it all.
I don't know about for sure.
What about this 100%
although he's hurt. Wow. He's, he's,
he's throwing the cut.
He got hurt back and forth. Oh,
that Meagan. They heard each other.
Oh,
he is fucking tired.
But he's still dangerous as
shit. It throws so hard. Oh
God. Damn Dude. Good
sprawl by Aldo too, huh?
And now man is head shots.
Just trying to recover her. I
keep punching him. What did,
I don't know why you're
fucking stolen out.
Doesn't want him to complete that
single right. Oh, lefthand. Oh,
he's bad son. Look at this.
Wow. Mendez is in the cruise.
Shit. Foot stops looking at, he's going,
Marco, who? I wonder why more people
don't do that. Does that hurt Brendan?
I, yeah, don't do it to
me and I want to do it.
It's kind of like, damn man, come on.
It's the split stop.
And then the front knee kick is horrible,
but he's not putting much
into these needs. Right.
Because he doesn't want to
commit. Oh, those are hard house.
I love those who he's getting missing.
Oh, that's a hard one, man. It's okay.
You're going to break my boat there,
right in front of each other and pinky
talking and talking shit talking. Oh Shit.
I wonder what he said. Oh yeah,
they're laughing at each other. Oh,
that dropdown now plumbed the plum
baby. Look out for that. Nice.
I said fight of the night.
Oh,
he tagged him with that
left Hook. Wow. Ooh.
I'll go
back and forth around the Mendez
because of that. And then the,
because of the end and the end,
the fact that he got that
takedown got ahold of them,
but 10 although did crack him right there,
but Mendez recovered.
Is that all of a fight is
a hell of a fight, man.
It's close like that. Ron
was close. Forgot about huge,
although dropping him there,
it's close.
But I think Mendez was controlling the
end of the fight and tag them at the end
of the fight.
I give a lot of credit to the end of
a round or not the end of the fight.
The end of a round. I'll give a lot
of credit to the end of the round.
I give a lot of credit to the end
of a fight because I feel like,
and this is a stupid way to look at it,
but in a street fight,
it doesn't matter if
it got kicked your ass,
if the teachers pulled you off of him,
you won. You know what I'm saying?
A guy can hit you with like a one
two punch kick you in the leg,
punch you in the liver,
you're getting fucked up,
and then somehow know that he slips and
you want up on top and you punched him
in the face and the teacher pulls you off.
Most people are gonna think you want,
right? Yeah. Who was on top of the
end? Oh, Danny was on top, Bro.
He was going to kill that kid.
You fluctuate their guard. Yeah.
Sometimes Pete.
Well that's a different one.
It depends on who's watching the
fight. Yeah. Damn all it looks big.
I put a lot of muscle on Disney. I was
about to say it looks skinnier than usual.
I thought he looked real muscular.
All right, here we go. Dig Deep.
My friend Goldie, the homeless
had an aneurysm right there. He
switching up a lot, man. A lot of
a southpaw movement. That's again,
Dwayne, Dwayne, Aka Dominick Cruz.
Fourth Round is deep water for all though.
This is where shit gets weird with him.
Super Bad.
I swear mark than ever to mark
harmonic was on top of all of those.
I'll never forget that.
And Mark Hall make a very good striker.
That was the fifth round, right?
Yeah. Very good. Well, yeah,
a mouse living in his house. I didn't
know. Mike's been a hard iced tea.
It's like someone's store,
a can of pineapples and his forehead.
Oh, Mendez is still sharp
though, Dude. Mendez still sharp.
He's in good shape for this
fight. That's a fact, man.
Good head movement to still
switching up a lot, man.
And he's not backing off his pace either.
They're both.
These guys are like not committing though.
They're getting real close with their,
they're touching, touching. They're
looking for that fucking burst.
Favorite.
Right hand over the top. I Mendez
almost mint. Maybe it wouldn't. Again,
leg kicks off, shade way down,
although just shook his head.
They're talking and he's mad
because that's sweet. Upper cut.
Oh, he's fucking him up, man. He
fucked him up at that left hand too.
What was the last time we saw all
those face busted up like this?
This is unusual.
Barely missed that.
Holy Shit. Dillashaw style. Fifth
Round head kick. K. Oh well listen man,
he's putting a pace on, although in this
fourth round and although his coasting,
he's not doing anything and this is
where all those usually been in control.
He caught him with that left hand
over the top. What is he doing?
He's complaining that the heads are, oh,
he can't complain. That's a weakness.
He knows he's getting fucked up. You
can't, can't complain over Shit like that.
You know what's going on, man?
All the look and the wrestling,
all I was going to get ghetto.
He just starts throwing fucking wild heat.
You know what?
What he's throwing is not hitting. He's
getting them on the end. This shit.
It's not having the same impact and
Mendez has had in this round. I mean,
look at the faces,
although is broken up, man.
Mendez is doing some
fucking damage. Oh, guns.
When you see your opponent
has blood, yes, it does. It
bleeds. We can kill it. It's
fine. It's so fucking good.
We'll move movies. A Predator.
Predator, Bro. I don't sports a nigger.
He just did a swap.
Synagogues all equipment.
The right at the very end of the
punch though. Look at all those faces.
Fucking bloody. Oh God.
He throws, I think. Wow.
Yeah. Oh, he got poked. He got poked,
man. Okay. He's just going to go right
back in. I was out there. I see it.
He's got better. Oh, back to the leg kick.
What if he gets leg kicked it down?
That would be hilarious.
But then it's too late for that.
Then you've got to do some real groundwork
and those fucking first few rounds.
Or are you just go out and Edson
Barboza. I'm here. Edson Barboza he hit,
might have one of the nastiest leg kicks
in all of the UFC right now. For sure.
Oh, by far. Nasty. He's one of the only
guys who stopped to people by led cakes.
He stopped a Hefei Alo Olivera and he
stopped, uh, one of his earlier opponents.
Oh Man.
Hard right hand by Mendez.
U of c seven. Yeah, man. He was
the one who showed everybody.
What's up Paul Varland son
chopped down the polar bear.
Remember that shit? Oh yeah. 17 Marco,
who was the king of the foot stomps to
Paul violence. Hit me up on Facebook.
Weird message. No Shit. Weird message.
What's up bro? Yeah, we had met. That
was a hard check. Heart check there.
He setting up something.
Javin that chest trap fighting
to him.
I don't want to hear about that weird
message from a 359 dude lives in Alaska.
Oh,
this round.
Just buy shit like that. He's so fucking
athletic. It's crazy. Although, although,
yeah, it's so violent and awesome.
Oh, much at FIS. 10 seconds.
Go the right hand over the top.
I'm Chad.
They must be yelling at
him to turn it up here.
I wonder if he can hear Wayne and
his fucking crowd. I got it to two.
I think it's, I think it's a,
I think it's too too as well.
You think it's three Ronaldo?
Three one Aldo.
Oh look at that upper cut shit son.
So you think all the one this round,
how did it all the last round Chad one.
This one I
know about the land.
The last one was kinda close but I think
the last one she had definitely one.
This one.
I think the last one they're going to
give it to all though cause he rocked him.
And you said the end of the round.
I think all those going to
win that round in Brazil.
But the end of the round was
Mendez winning the round hit him.
I mean I dunno.
I Dunno either which Strunk talking shit.
That's so folks at homes that a
fucking like you like, Ooh, well good.
I could do commentary.
Guess what? You could
at least have exactly like you watching.
This is fucking Ian Mccall,
one of the best flyways on the planet
earth spinning through space and he does
commentary just like you. I don't
fucking know what, we're not that cool.
We're not that smart. This, there
was a couple times, this is on air.
You know there's a couple of times
I'm also sober though. Oh Man,
look at all those eyeball, Bro. Holy
Shit. There's a lot of limited visibility.
This is the fifth and final
motherfucker wins this round ones.
The fights might be APP. I swing in
Brazil to see some crazy shit, man.
Some crazy shit. You Jazz. You
know Chad's going to bring it.
I'll just got to turn this shit up.
Oh,
Mendez would've left hand switches
up to sell hard left. Fuck God damn.
Woo. We got any punch
final fuck numbers, dude.
I don't want numbers.
Oh,
love her sneaky left hook as
a writer out of the guard.
Yeah, he whips it. You know he
whips it to the body as well.
They like each other, man.
They're having fun now.
It's a lot of respect now
after this fucking crazy war.
I mean these dudes know each other like
nobody knows each other. Take Down, take,
take it down and he's fucking tired too,
man.
This is going to be hard to shift to get
back up from here. He does get back up.
He's exhausted.
Now you strike someone.
Mendez is go Roulo strong at
one 45 that dude is a beast.
Who the crowd bill. This
is the, if he wins, dude,
this is the last Brazilian
to hold the title. Yeah.
Every fucking champion will be American
if he wins. So she does she show?
Say they should know better.
Don't be a terrorist.
Everyone chant USA Corvette Corvette's
should just send them all cars.
Just that'd be say American as fuck, but
it's the dry run. The core of Epi again,
she chaired Hellcat. How do you like it?
It's dope. I love it. So doe love it.
707 horsepower.
Fucking Chrysler [inaudible]
drove it when I was in Denver.
She drove for the whole weekend.
They gave me one of those. I might,
I might get one of the only like let's,
I just want to get an American muscle car,
but I'm thinking about in 1969
Mustang. Yes. Nothing's been in your,
nothing's going to be better to drive.
It's not going to handle the same,
but it'd different. Oh Shit. Yeah.
They'll know. Pushes him off.
That was my brother's first cause
of 69 Mustang. It's a great car.
So pretty aesthetics. The way it looks is
a, you're onto something with corvette.
They take all the,
the UFC champions
put commercials together and American
as, fuck. That's a commercial.
Oh Shit. Just go dude.
Although connected here,
man, this isn't good.
This is not good at all.
Let's see that associate. So what about
that, you know, finished them here.
What if he uses was usually so we could
stick on him to finish here and my
friend was to planning time two 42 40
and he's used to having your eye are
crawling around on him taking the
bat. That's true. And up up again,
get out since that's the
thing about those guys,
they all have fucking wicked
guillotine defense. Oh,
kick knockout are still in front of
each other. Different 75 each other.
Anything can happen in this kind of
fight and that's why I just stepped back.
Stepped off. Oh yeah. Step off
again. Keep moving. Keep moving.
Light on the toes of really thrown that
money. Leg. Resting an hour, one hour,
he says over, you did a lot of
training. Oh vicious over the top.
And left to the body first.
Oh Shit.
Oh my goodness.
Oh,
fucking Pez dispenser.
Jesus.
Oh Shit.
Buckle up.
That's so sad
though with that left. Right. Again,
although being very conservative
with the kicks to men,
very conservative with the kicks.
Oh my God.
Who the fuck is going to win this fight?
This is this 90 seconds might be,
here's the fight. I just looked up at
the clock. This might be left hand,
but he was moving away from that.
He was sliding to his left.
This law. Ah, fuck again
with the knee. No, no, no,
no. It's incidental.
Oh my God. What time? He can't. He
can't be taking any breaks here.
They're going to give it to all
though. They might not. Amen.
This is a goddamn close round.
Anybody they give it to all
the high agrees. 50 seconds.
Anybody could win this round.
Anybody wins this round with one
successful friends right now.
Been a big hit. Yeah, I mean, but,
but nothing stunning. If all know,
stunned him here with something and
had them wobbly. He did when he did.
It just happened. But not like
before. You know what I'm saying? Much
cause he stunned Aldo too.
He snapped his fucking head back with
that jab and he's looking at that upper
kind. I loved that. And
Saba shit. 20 seconds, man.
20 seconds. Oh body kick. Come on.
Breaking out. 1515 oh check
it. You're fucking crazy.
You think the Brazilian judge was going
to give us the Oh, right here by all go.
Go, go, go. The exchange. Right
hands. Oh Jesus Christ. I sweet.
Oh
Man.
I don't know.
I do not know you give
it to all still around
then more of these probiotic things
out there that does a bunch in the back
because you're fucking delicious.
They're really good. They're really good.
I love it. God Damn
valuable fight. Oh my God.
What do we think here?
Although I think all of those goals,
everybody thinks all though one.
I think if I had to give anybody the
last round, I'd probably be Aldo. Yeah.
You know what? I think men does this.
When he snapped his head back,
that was one of the most significant
show going to give it to all dumb.
It was close enough where they were like,
you know what,
I'm just going to give it to them. I
would like to see the numbers, you know,
cause we're watching it and having
fun. That took, that was early.
That was the first round. We get the
numbers. It's all though all day.
If you look at the number, but she looks
up damaged. Yeah, that's true. Right?
You significant strikes.
It's going to be all to all day.
Oh look at that right here. Oh
my goodness. Oh my goodness.
He walked back more seconds. I could have
been a finisher left hook to the body.
So fish and replies, you know how
powerful the replies are for the judges.
They're looking at the replay. That's
looks like three rounds to all though.
Right? Faster. The crowd
sways judging Mendez.
Oh Jesus. Critics at the replays and
go, if that's what they're showing,
they thought, okay,
but let's look at this.
Look at the mean that that is a big
goddamn round. So that was around three.
So round three was definitely Mendez,
right?
That was the one he really heard them.
That was the clearest round for Mendez
round around three rather around four.
It was like,
who the fuck knows?
So round three was definitely Mendez
Brown Ford was, who the fuck knows?
And round five.
You know
Ralph, I was so close.
Who fucking knows man?
Who the fuck knows? Great fight though.
So you guys think all Dubai decision,
their bias, right? Whoever won,
whoever won what a fucking fight.
Yeah. Jesus Christ was amazing. Amazing.
Wow.
Unbelievable.
What a fight.
You know how much shit Conor McGregor
is going to talk after this fight.
I don't think he wants any idea what some
of this you got picked up by a midget.
Imagine what I'll do. Tiaa
split decision. Hold on.
I imagine what I'll do to you.
I'll do, what did he say? He's out.
He'll knock his head clean off.
I'll knock his head clean off
all the way back to Dublin.
Ananymous decision. Yeah.
They're very happy in Brazil.
Very, very, very, very good
fight. Great by fun. Wild fight.
You know,
that's like everything you want to fight.
Two elite fighters going at
it. Uh, changing direction,
changing the tide back and forth.
Both guys get tested.
Both guys have to overcome
fucking amazing fight.
Powerful, big, handsome Brian Dan with
a napkin coming out of his pocket.
They tried to get me that shit.
I'm like, put that God damn Napkin.
It's not going in my fucking pocket.
You haven't where it sits though? Yeah.
I don't wear the jacket though.
I gave up on the jacket.
They used to make me aware of the jacket.
They got me all these beautiful suits.
They had them custom made from my bridge.
Troll body.
They fit great. You always have to
wear long sleeve shirts. No, I just do.
I don't know. It's just, I
don't want to be distracting,
so I don't want to show tattoos.
That's why I wear long sleeved.
Mostly on stage too.
It's just distracting.
It's one more thing for
people to think about. Damn.
What's he saying? He's all caught up
to look at it and left eye. Holy Shit.
I go,
no.
Wow.
Well, Hey folks, uh, what a fucking
fight. What an awesome card.
So a powerful,
Phil Davis does a big victory
for Phil Davis. Yeah, I was huge.
He looked like a monster. That was
like the best Phil Davis of all time.
Especially after that last
performance with that. Yeah.
Fucking amazing.
Returning really throwing leg kick fan,
although did not throw that many. I
mean he got lit up, but some of his own,
I mean of a Mendez is right off the back.
But this was a fucking test man
and he survived a really motivated,
really well trained Chad Mendez.
But what a fucking close fight.
What a great fight
it just stained division,
man.
I don't even know how he can say he
thinks he deserved to win, you know?
I mean he won.
You know what,
why I say I think I deserve to
win your you fucking one man.
It wasn't based, I guess so.
I mean, it was a close fight,
but Connor, everybody in this
room thinks that he wants. Right.
But isn't that kind of a common
thing when someone walks away?
Way more damage than
the other. Yeah, sure.
But you know that damage can come from one
exchange, right? Yeah. Like, um, Chris,
Jerry, when he beat that,
uh, that provide Niqab Guy,
he got lit up in the first round closed.
I almost completely shut and then outboxed
him for the remainder of the fight.
You sit in a tremendous, tremendous job.
And some people have more scar tissue.
Some people take damage along. Worse
than now. There's from Leiter's strikes.
José although mother fucker right there,
that's the motherfucker.
What do you guys think in
the pound for pound thing?
Like he used to get tossed
around as being as possible.
Do you still think he is after this fight?
Number one pump them. Really? Yeah. No,
that's what you think Joe. No, no.
I think it's probably mighty mouse.
I really do. I mean, I think mighty mouse,
yes. She's better than mighty mouse.
He hit my car might be better
than mine if you beat him.
I really think that you probably
deserve pound for pound best.
I just think that if I look at
technique for technique, okay.
And I look at what he's been
able to pull off in title fights,
he's like flawless. You know, I think
there's other guys fighting tougher guys.
He might be right. And
there's, that's the,
that's the thing about like 2005 and
that's why Jones comes into Jones.
Jon Jones, Jon Jones, he
is maybe it real quick.
You put all those guys in the room and
came back and twist everyone's heads off
and don't even don't, I hate when people
put Rhonda in their pound for pound.
God will put Ron's house category.
It's hard to do it with a woman.
I don't agree with that at all.
I think pound for pound,
she's number one of all time.
And then how about women ever to walk the
face of the planet? She's number one on
the list.
There should be anyone else is probably
some crazy Mongol bitch though from like
pound for pound bales there
a few males and females.
That shit ain't fair.
Ronda Rousey's the ultimate chick ever.
And I agree that puts her on that power.
The pound for pound means that weight
doesn't matter. You know what I mean?
But I but male put Ronda
Rousey in there with Hanan.
Barao he was so crazy. Do you have any
idea what TJ would do to her? It's silly,
man.
And so this is about, but we're
talking to and morale would beat.
We're talking around about pound for
pound. They're the same weight. Yeah.
Do you see that fight would be,
there would be a ruthless wife beating,
which would be
horrible if you go pound for pound.
Are you talking about the
toughest man in the world?
It's usually the heavyweight champ,
which Jon Jones, I rolled with Rhonda La.
Oh No, no, no man. They had to roll
together. It's a different scenario,
but they don't,
they have to MMA fight and when you're
talking about kickboxing Hanan Barao can
do shit you can't do,
it's not going to go,
but look,
he's a man.
He's a strong man and he can
fucking kick ridiculously hard.
He can punch ridiculously hard.
He can hit you with a standing
knee like a front kick.
He can see you in the face.
She might or she might wake up
with a flashlight in her face. Be
Stupid to include women.
And she says that by on,
Rhonda says that,
by the way.
I know they asked her and she's like a
woman fighting a man. It's ridiculous.
It's just stupid and it is stupid.
It's solely no hanky.
Brian Stann Hanky Goldie
wins goes. No, no, I see.
I give Brian Stann the wind cause
Goldie has that three piece suit on.
I hate the three. Which one
has more makeup? That's the
real question. Go. Sure.
Goldie. Oh the three pieces. She
needs a nap in a drink of water guys.
Conor McGregor is next
while now ever, right? Yeah.
If he beats Dennis Seaver
and Dennis Seavers.
No fucking pushover tennis sneakers. Got
that sneaky front. Like roundhouse kick.
Good match for beats frank.
Yeah, it's shorter. It competes.
Look,
if cub beats Frankie by substantial
margin or Frankie beats cub by substantial
margin, like whether by decision
submission or knock out,
they probably, in my opinion are
ahead on the ladder. Dylan profitable.
Miss Connor puts ass is in seats.
That's why you saw his fucking picture
and he's hanging out with Dana white down
there in Brazil and a lot of people like
that. Here we go, Swanson and Edgar.
This is my opinion.
This is the real number one,
number two title fight
and a contender fight,
but it doesn't mean that I don't think
that McGregor is up there with them.
I think he definitely is. But here
we're looking at a guy like cub Swanson.
It has a fucking litany of broken
bodies in the UFC to his career.
I mean, he's looking at what
he did to Dennis Seaver.
If Connor Beats Dennis Seaver. Okay,
that's great. That's a good fight.
Look up what cup did to Dennis Seaver
cub lit Denisey were on fire come most
[inaudible]. I know. He's fantastic.
Frankie Edgar's a motherfucker and he
never stops moving. He cuts crazy angles.
He's got ridiculous wrestling.
He's got more heart than any fucking
human being that's ever walked the face of
the planet.
He workcover's covers better from a
beating than anyone I've ever seen in my
life. It's not about that though, is
it's not about Connor's entertaining.
People on seem fight.
So then he just had the title shot.
But how about this in New Jersey,
Frankie Edgar versus Conor Mcgregor for
the number one to 10 that's slam dunk.
That shit.
Do that Shit in New Jersey or even better.
You do it in Dublin, you
know, fucking soccer stadium
dub. They didn't even have to fight
for the title. You know what you do?
This is what you do, man. You'd
go to Josie. Aldo don't go. Uh,
I heard you hurt your foot.
Fucking
thousands. Can you just
say, Hey, listen, my film,
we're talking about an interim title.
We're not talking about the
real title is peeling off cash.
Can Juliana white should fucking shit
everybody throw your cell phone in the
bucket and we'll go into
this room and shut that door.
Joey Diaz doing Conor McGregor was a cock
sucker. I'm the number one contender.
I put asses in seats.
I'm the guy.
Nobody wants to see you fucking
faggy. So cal Caltech tools. Oh,
I like palm trees.
Get the fuck Outta here.
I'm from Dublin motherfucking
island. Okay, you're from California.
He's sitting in the fucking Hov Lane.
And Electric car got stuck
on a horse on a horse.
It's raining out all day and I'm drunk.
I'm a number one contender dog, or I'm
going to fucking fill up a soccer stadium.
That's what he would say. But Joey would
be, he would leave after he said that.
Why you were laughing? Fuck this
shit. Fuck up the door. He would,
we would be hanging
around the comedy store.
He would say some shit like that and
they just walk away on the punch line.
Just walk away. He's like, you just,
it was just a such a master showman.
Walk away on punchlines.
Well this fucking podcast is over
folks. Yeah, Josie all goes to shit.
Chad Mendez is a motherfucker
that was a goddamn awesome.
Phil Davis came back strong tonight.
You'll Bagby five in a row,
son. Okay. What do you guys think about
hunt and verb? What about that shit?
Doom.
The deadly and elevation 7,500 feet.
If you remember when any UFC fight ever,
and if you remember mark cut fight in
Denver and we fought Rothwell yeah.
Might have been the worst
heavyweight fight in history.
They won't come back to
Denver, but heavyweights on
the car do so bad. Wait, title,
heavyweight title hold. You have
three weeks. Oh, you weigh 305 pounds.
That's everybody division right now.
He's got to lose so much weight to,
he's got to lose 30 pounds.
You're crazy.
Just fucking,
I like just seeing hunting when well,
but also like every day
if we're doomed wins.
He speaks really good Spanish.
They reschedule it again.
He fights in Mexico against
Kaine. I mean, God, Hey,
if King Cup comes back, they're
going to get my mail again with cane.
I think they want to learn to gamble.
It depends on how well this card does.
This card does really well in Mexico.
It sells really well,
but now the problem is canes,
not the headliner anymore.
They even said like Dana
White said publicly like,
we can't go to Mexico without cane and
Diego's hurt to go to the big draw this
out. So Diego's out by Amazon.
The other, the Mexican kid.
What's his name? Eric Perez. I don't know.
I went, God, is he out too? I
don't think he's that bomber,
man. All these guys getting injured,
but it's just the weight division. Oh,
big ball. He travels Brown.
What's up? What's up?
This is what I wanted to ask you
guys about you two guys especially.
What did you think and get the soft,
what did you think about the only thing
that's a situ situation that was really
weird. I got popped allegedly
for high growth hormone. Right.
And then they say that
the test is ridiculous and
there's a bunch of people who
weighed in on it that are apparently
experts in the protocol and the way
everything was handled and then the UFC
for the first time ever rescinded it.
If it doesn't fit,
you must acquit.
It's tough enough to really get that
picture of come lean like, oh wow. Yeah,
you're not on protein in,
you know what I'm saying?
Cause he's in his forties and he never
looked for them. We've seen that picture.
It's insane.
He makes like one of those grill as
they should brought up there and all of
those aims jacked and shredded it.
Just pause for the HGH.
But he also got his ass whooped, but he
didn't get to do have you work for HGH?
He tested for elevated human growth
hormone levels and they don't have a
baseline for him.
That's the problem.
They don't have like people have weird
and dodginess levels of all sorts of
hormones. There's certain people that
like, like if there was a reason why Pete,
some people were depressed,
why are they depressed?
They have a bad low levels of serotonin.
You know some people that have had head
injuries have low levels of testosterone,
so he might just naturally have some
weird thing when he hits 40 gets super
shredded. It's on 20 pounds of muscle
and that's how it goes like it's true.
I'll look at the pictures of him.
See that's normal.
That's when he hit 40 we
all look like that man.
He does look retarded coming in the
next expendables live. He's done.
Kung Fu since he was three.
That doesn't look like a real APP.
If I had an APP like that,
I would quit working out forever.
Just take pictures and shit.
I did it. It's tiny. Made the best
tabs of all time. Suck it. I'm over.
That's a best abs maybe ever. Right.
I'm not mad at him. He's a cutie pie.
No, but no bullshit. Have
there been better abs? No,
there's been different ABS.
I agree. That's a set of ABS. That's not,
that might be the best abs and MMA
fighter is ever exhibited. And Lee,
because he's such a kicker like that's
kicking is all your core and your abs.
Your obliques to help them though. Did
it great if it's the Olympia. Yeah man.
Dude, he hasn't fought in a
couple of years and he fought
Bisbing who is a cardio
machine. Bisping has a 34 till you
have like a 38 beats per minute.
Look at that big brown,
a heavyweight with a 38 beats per minute.
Resting heart rate.
Same as Michael Phelps.
What was me in the pool swimming though?
That's why his heart rate's so low.
Exactly.
He's just not even sure it's taking
a test. I hate that one. Happy.
But I was 37 yesterday, yesterday,
two days ago or 100 pounds. My friend.
He just kept me. Nah, that's impressive
man. How much do you walk around that?
Seriously and not in fight shape.
Like 50. Oh that's not that small.
So one 15 you dropped down
to one 25 how much water,
how much of his water with 10 12 pounds.
That's a lot though.
Your body weight per percentage.
You've got to think about it as
opposed to like a heavyweight.
10 pounds ain't shit. But when you
get down to like one 25 10 pounds,
I'll do
okay.
Got to Ireland at 18 over I think
high e but it was just like,
it was the easiest kind of her hat
cause my diet and all this stuff.
I mean I've got my super
tuned in everybody. This
company makes all my meals,
it's called the gorgeous mix.
My buddy makes all my meals fit.
It's 15 meals a week that are vegan and
then I eat meat because I am not um,
Vegan, Vegan. I was going to make a
root cause they use sexual use. Gluten.
I hear there's a lot of gay people
that like hot dogs. So I don't think,
Oh shit I can do you.
But do you eat gluten? I try not to. You
try not to. You try not to too, right.
I uh,
I did gluten free from my last camp.
I can feel that much of
a difference to the guy.
Like you were either one of
you guys is burned off so much.
God Damn Glucose in a day.
You know,
you're burn off so much sugar that I
don't think it would hurt to have like a
little pasta in your diet.
I just don't think we're talking
about a regular person. Yeah.
It's not that I think about a hippie.
I get some pasta maker gummy bears.
Before I hit miss thing,
I was like fucking Anderson Silva for
reals man and a bag of gummy bears.
Someone gave me a small bag of
gummy bears, right. For training.
I don't know what it is.
Where their marijuana gummy bears or
where they gummy bears that like my candy
gummy bears, gummy
bears. I don't know. Oh,
for before someone
gummy bears.
So just the sugar. You
need sugar sugar avenue.
It's not bad to have some simple sugar
if you're working out the way you're
working out cause you're burning
off so much fucking calories.
You got to think about just grappling
workout what your body feels like when
it's over it and they say the best thing
to drink is chocolate milk because it
has so many different things.
It has the case in the
armory would know the ratios, especially
if you've got raw chocolate milk.
Then you have the enzymes in
there to help break down the milk.
Where do you get Rami Khouri response
because it's hard to break down when it's
pasteurized.
Yeah.
When you had raw chocolate milk that would
be so he's saying if I had a cow suck
the
get you can get raw milk from some health
food stores like sprouts has pitch and
just take some on it. Protein now dude,
I'm telling you raw raw milk if you've,
if you're like a non a
non milk Trican person,
I have a totally different reaction
between drinking regular milk and drinking
raw milk. Totally different reaction.
I don't like any of that shit.
Raw milk just seems to have no,
my body has no problem with
it and just digest milk.
Milk is not milks weird fucking water,
but it's not bad for your milky ass if
it's sweetened, unsweetened almond milk.
Oh, that's sweet and gets
a lot of sugar. Dude,
Duncan Trussell call me up the
other day. He's like, dude,
I found the best thing almond milk. It's
so healthy. It's so good for you. I go,
I goes, it tastes really good.
He goes, yeah, I go, that's
sugar. And he goes, really?
I go, look at the fucking look at
the label and he goes, oh my God,
18 grams of sugar per serving.
I go, yeah, sweet. Yeah,
you're drinking water like it.
Yeah, but usually if it tastes good,
it's sweet version.
Unsweetened tastes like ass.
Hold milk tastes like they just get a
little sour, but you can make your own.
It's really easy. All it is is you just
take raw almonds and you blend them up.
Same with making hemp milk. You take how
much you eat. Almonds and drink water
ossification actually creates the mill.
Right, but is there a benefit in that?
I'm also vacation like they better health,
but I mean if you're making a smoothie
or something and you need the liquid and
you want to get that flavor
time than blaming up
all means on your own.
Being one of those weird owns it's soaks
almonds and tries to get some of your
own almond milk. No benefit, no benefit.
Is this going to make you dig, wrote no.
It's going to make you smarter. No. Is
it going to help you recover faster?
It's gonna remind you how awesome milk is.
Some coffee and cocoa pops at that shit.
It's raw milk guy like my
daughter has rheumatoid arthritis.
Would it be good for them?
Raw milk and milk or raw goat's milk
would probably be even better. Okay.
You shouldn't pasteurize goat's milk is
way easier for your body to digest and
cows.
Yeah,
you want to limit the inflammatory
response and the problem with anything
pasteurized is it kills all the natural
enzymes that help you digest it.
So it's going to cause a greater
inflammatory response. So rob,
we'll help you out with it.
Is it about goat's milk that makes it
even when pasteurize more digestible.
Why goat's milk? Yeah, something with
the composition of the actual milk,
human milk, goat's milk, human milk and
goat's milk or more closely affiliated.
Then bovine milk, it's just a little
bit closer for whatever reason,
come on down to the level of growth
hormone in it. Somebody was like, Yo dog,
can I get that breast milk?
You know what I'm saying?
You'd think that'd be huge.
It's into the supermarkets,
the human mouth.
This big ass last room is really great.
You mentioned that we were really taking
a hard look at that because that's the
first milk that comes out and
that's the most nutritious.
Every mammal produces colostrum and she
loses though when it breaks down into
like a powdered form,
cause I know they sell like powdered
claustrum need to pour into smoothies and
shit,
but like what is that even really,
it's like a freeze drying process usually.
So I think you lose some,
but you still get a lot of you to do.
Right. Even with Greens or with anything,
once you break it down to a powder,
whatever benefit you get,
it might be substantial,
but it's definitely less than it would
be for fresh destroys nutrients more than
that process though. So it's
better than, you know. Yeah.
That's rising it. So, so powdered is
better than heated generally. Yeah.
For most things. Wow. That's
weird. Right? Let's go eat.
Let's get something to eat. Can you
eat late slate? It's pretty late.
Baby
story time with [inaudible] cues.
The walls have ears. Big Brown would
lose his job. He tells a story.
We have the best podcast of all time
or, but yeah. Well it would just,
that's the way you go out in a blaze
of glory. Like God damn. Bon Jovi Song
staying.
Last question. Bisbing Rockhold no, no.
You gotta. You gotta you know I
trained with bisman. He's a beast man.
He went five rounds right now. He's
in shape all the time. All the time.
That's a big factor, right? Yeah. But
his, uh, think his eyes. Big Factor.
I think Rockhold big. I think
rock holds on monster. [inaudible]
MMM.
They've been talking about shit.
Right. That's what they do. Yeah,
but Bisping's used to it. Yeah.
Brisbane told me this. He goes, man,
I just want to fight
more. So I thought, shit,
the guy's giving me a response so I
can get fights. He's a journalist.
All of us want to fight more. So you
just talk some shit, Joe Civil. He goes,
oh yeah, that's cool. There's
that match up. There you go.
When he talking shit to iron sheik,
make that shit happen.
All these stories and shit.
No, he can't even walk.
He support guys shot.
All right. Fucking podcast
podcasts over Master Eddie Bravo.
Give us your information.
People want to get ahold of you.
10 Planet J j.com premium deluxe
Komal Newport tattooed Newport beach.
Give me your full name. Curry Messer.
Ronnie. He hit me up on Instagram.
Corinne Tattoo hollow uncle.
Creepy MMA.
Uncle creepy on everything. MMA.
And what is your next fight?
How's your hand doing? You had certain
in hand. It's all better now, right? Oh,
like oh it looks good.
And is that where it goes?
I think that makes some sort of a fist
now as opposed to before poke straight
out and hit people with it.
It's fucking awesome.
That really is never going to straighten
out. You purposely making a crypto.
Yes ma'am. That's what he does when
he starts punching a wolverine,
claws starts to come out and get it fixed.
How many operations?
Three operations and uh,
one infection.
Two breaks. And like this break was one
more. I'm glad your girlfriend's here.
I ask you rude questions about your
fingers, what you do with them.
Do the math,
a big brown versus Travis Browne.
December, December 6th, one 81.
Finally the kid podcasts.
Yeah.
Glorious. When I got for you,
that's it at Brendan Schaub.
Aubrey Marcus Warrior, poet us on
Twitter. Uh, the Onnit podcast,
of course, the warrior poet project.
Is that what you call it? Yup.
Warrior poet project and I, human
documentary. Oh yeah. Medicines.
Amazing documentary about psychedelic
experiences in the Amazon.
I played those fucking egos he gave me,
I played them with my
car when I'm in traffic.
That brings me to a special place that's
awesome. And Miss Two jets, right?
Ms Two jets on Twitter. All
right, folks, fucking things over.
Go do something with your time productive,
because if you're still listening
to me at this point, get a light.
Okay? Can I see it? Please?