Lots of,
lots of challenges growing up and then
all of a sudden when I was actually away
from all of the stuff that else familiar
with people that were familiar with me
with nice to be able to be in a setting
where uh,
I was actually excelling and achieving
things anonymously,
you know,
there was things that were happening
that all of a sudden I was shining in a
way but not a,
you know,
none of my people back in the where I
was from knew anything about it.
But I was doing really well.
Discipline and resolve and doing any
difficult endeavor is so important for a
young man.
You know,
and this is one of the sort of themes
we've brought up on this podcast many
times is it,
is there's no coming of age rituals in
our culture anymore.
And I always thought they were retarded
when I was young.
Like,
you know,
what are these fucking idiots hanging
themselves by their tits and you know,
or you know,
putting their hands in the bullet ant
bins.
Like,
what the fuck is wrong with these
people?
Why would they like,
I'm 18.
I'm a man.
Done.
No,
no,
really.
You really need to go through something.
You need to,
you need to,
you know,
you need to have.
That's why so many cultures have either
a psychedelic experiences that young
people go through or what we talked
about this yesterday or deal poisons
where it's,
it's not a psychedelic because it's not
in their area,
so they take something that almost kills
them and then when it's over,
they're just so happy to be healthy
again and alive.
And they sort of realized they've gone
through a tunnel.
They made it through a passage,
they've,
they've reached an actual new level and
we're missing that man.
We get out of fucking high school and
then we're just lost.
Were panicking completely terrified.
We're going to starve to death.
Is clinging onto the first job or the
first opportunity for some sort of
security that we can,
you know,
uh,
the only good thing that I could ever
think about having sort of some sort of
a mandatory military experience for most
United States citizens is to two fold.
One,
so people could understand what the fuck
the military is really all about and of
this nonsense,
raw,
raw chicken Hawk bullshit where people
support this idea of sending our fucking
trained killers to these places where we
don't know anybody and fucking them up
in the name of justice or whatever the
fuck it is.
We would get a better idea of what that
is.
No,
it'd be harder to pull the wool over
people's eyes because it's so easy for
all these people that will have nothing
to do with shooting anybody ever to say
we support the troops and support you
are heroes and you're the reason why we
can be free and nonsensical statements
that mean the reason why that shit flies
is because we got a nice blanket.
This blanket of security,
the USA,
whatever the fuck it is,
throw it over your head.
You know,
you don't really have to think about the
actual horrors of military.
If we forced people to join,
and I'm not saying we should,
but that the only benefit that we would
get out of that as it people would kind
of get an idea of what reality really
is.
Yeah,
I think it's a fine line you.
There's no way to really kind of,
to really be able to direct that
experience.
It's really as an individual and an
individual thing,
there's going to be people that figure
out a way to make that work for them in
terms of being lazy.
Um,
I got out of shape in the army when I
got,
when I went in because back when I sold
the system,
when they,
when I went in,
they uh,
they wanted people in so they weren't
really pushing people to heart and
within a period of time when we didn't
have a lot of obvious conflict going on,
so it seemed like everything was sorted
itself out and why am I going to the
military other than just getting a
college fund out of it and then it's
fucking off.
Uh,
but,
you know,
so they were kind of like kind of
lowered the standard a little bit to
kind of get more people in.
I think it was a mistake,
but you know,
I still learned a lot of.
What year was this?
This is from 80 to 85.
I came real close to joining an 85 when
they got into high school,
it was a,
they had an army taekwondo team.
They would,
uh,
you would get a Shitty,
easy just job,
but they would pay you to train and they
give you a or they told you,
fighting the train,
see what they did.
The Bait and switch with me too,
like,
oh,
you want to be a map maker?
Oh,
that's a great because you're an artist.
Awesome.
Let's bring it on down.
Let's sign up and get you there.
And then like you get on the bus and you
drive all the way to Detroit and they
get you there and they go,
oh yeah,
that one's full.
That's the full.
But you know what you can do,
you can run out and catch bullets.
Yeah,
I had a fucked a do that,
competed on the national team,
this guy bobby cleat,
and it was out of the US army team.
He was the one who was getting me to
think about doing it.
He always freaked me out because he was
really religious and when I was 18 I was
such a,
a godless loser that I really.
Religious people scared me.
Like I was.
The one thing I was scared of competing
against was religious people.
Like when I was,
I wasn't scared of black people at first
until I beat my first black guy and then
it was a,
it was religious people because I would
see them sitting down like reading the
Bible before they'd fight and I'm like,
motherfucker,
students get godness side.
Like he's Kinda gotten us.
I don't even fucking know what's in the
Bible all.
I went to Catholic school for one year.
All I could think of was this fucking
guy's gonna have Jesus on his side.
He's gonna kick my ass.
But this Bobby Clayton Guy,
every time he would fight,
he would,
he would sit down and read the Bible
before we would go out there and he was
on the U.
S army team came real close to fall.
That dude's footsteps.
He was a couple of steps ahead of me and
the tournament scene and I was looked up
to him.
So I was like,
wow,
maybe that's the move,
maybe the army.
And I looked back on it now and that,
that,
that weird feeling of indecision than I
had when I got out of high school.
It makes me so sympathetic,
you know?
And that's why whenever anybody tries to
criticize the actual people that are
over there,
the actual troops,
I'm like,
man,
that is crazy.
You know?
Well they're there.
They're the one that is actually pulling
the trigger.
Then the one like,
man,
you don't even know what kind of
momentum is behind being a part of a
machine like that.
And being a 20 year old man or an 18
year old man and you know,
and wanting to respect and admiration of
your peers and you're fucking,
your ceo is telling you whatever the guy
is,
the head guy is telling you that they'll
give you an extra leave if you kill a
guy with a knife.
And have you ever seen those guys?
The describing this,
there was a video,
I don't want anybody to look at it right
now,
but there's a video called American
soldier throws away his metals.
It's one of those,
um,
Iraq veterans against the war videos
where this guy talks extremely candidly
about his time in Iraq and killing
civilians.
And I mean,
it's intense shit because,
you know,
this guy's not proud of this.
And he's swallowing his words and he's
talking incredibly honestly,
but it's fucking his chief officer,
whoever the fuck it was,
the head guy told them they'd given four
days leave.
They killed a guy with a knife.
So they had an extra incentive to kill a
guy with a knife.
And you're like,
wow,
America,
fuck yeah.
Fuck yeah,
freedom.
Yeah,
it's a,
I think,
you know,
everybody in some way I think,
I think you're right about trying to
figure out a way that have some,
some more perspective on,
you know,
just putting the situation,
putting people in this situation where
they have to kind of go through that for
themselves and kind of discover your
inner warrior in Michigan.
That kind of becoming a person.
I'm a male or female,
just trying to figure out what that next
step for you is separating from the nest
and becoming your own person and you
know,
to uh,
we can,
we can talk around it all you want,
but at the end of the day there are
monsters in the world.
Um,
most of them are us in,
you know,
that's,
that's what comes in,
you know,
we are,
we have the capacity for amazing,
wonderful things.
We have the capacity for some
horrendous,
awful things as well.
And I think part of that having that
warrior awakened in you is,
is more about understanding the monster
in you and understanding how to keep
that at bay and understand how to keep
that in check so that,
you know,
making it a global,
global perspective.
And I am in no way am I a hippie or you
know,
I'm delusional about like,
we're not just going to have world peace
someday.
It's not,
it's just not the case.
You know,
you hit the,
we're going to be struggling with our
inner monster forever.
And some,
you know,
there are monsters that are just out
more in areas.
And the reality is we have to keep that
in check.
Well,
we lack any sort of a logical use guide
for being a human.
You know,
we,
we're essentially go on the experiences
of people before us and occasionally we
get wisdom.
Like that poem that you read or that a
excerpt that you read,
which is genius and brilliant from a man
who lived 200 years ago.
Yeah.
But you know,
more than likely you get a fucking Moron
for a dad who pump bullshit in your head
until you're 18.
Then you leave and you're like,
these fucking niggers are trying to take
jobs and like fucking kid.
He's in.
Here's a shovel.
The job for you.
Oh,
you're quitting.
There you go.
It's,
it's,
it's a,
it's a weird thing I've tried to hire
your nephew is they keep morons,
are allowed to raise more and you're
allowed to homeschool them to you.
Allow it to sit them down and teach them
the same idiotic nonsense that you
learned and keep the same pattern of
fear and ignorance going.
It's,
it's very strange.
It's very.
And there's no way to cure that either.
I mean,
who is any man to tell any other man in
until we have some really incredibly
sophisticated ways of measuring
convenance that are just rock solid.
And uh,
you know,
like,
like a litmus liquor.
I'd used to do a joke in my act about if
you could find out if you were an idiot,
as easy as he could find out if you're
pregnant,
you just go and lick something and look
at and go,
I'm a fucking idiot.
There's no way this is broken.
You throw it away.
There'd be a pile of idiot detectors up
to the fucking moon and you'd be like,
bullshit.
Fucking throw it down and grab another
one until that happens.
How do you say a man can't have a baby?
How do you make,
say a guy,
you know,
uh,
can't raise a family and teach it.
It's on his own values.
He can't.
I think there's not going to want to get
all 1984.
But I think in terms of like say for
example,
health benefits,
if the,
if you go in to get some kind of,
you know,
something for your cold or your,
you're just basically sick now you know,
your,
your arm chopped off.
Okay.
That's,
we understand that.
But as far as just general health,
if uh,
if for some reason you go in for that
kind of general health stuff and they
just,
I think they should be able to run your
credit card statement to see if you'd
been to Mcdonald's lately.
You've been at Mcdonald's,
you know,
drinking coca cola or eating the candies
are hitting,
hitting the,
hitting the fast food.
It's like,
no,
you don't get anything.
I've had this idea for a long times that
the way to strengthen America is really
to make less losers.
So anytime there's any sort of a
situation like that,
there should be some resources dedicated
to pulling people out of that in a,
in a,
in a really enthusiastic way.
The same way this research is dedicated
to rebuilding Iraq after we blow it up.
I mean there should be a way to like let
people know the infrastructure of
America needs to be rebuilt to that
infrastructure of humanity.
The infrastructure in the age of
information with all the,
all the stuff that we know about what
it,
what,
what's important about being a human
being.
We shouldn't invest some resources into
that and developing human beings in that
way and if you're going to provide them
with free healthcare,
should also provide them with some sort
of an education and some sort of a,
some actually acceptable form where
they're going to really absorb it of the
fuck you're doing to your body stupid
and taxpayers shouldn't be paying for
this.
And you know,
we might have to put you in a state
where everybody eats big macs for magic
force you into some place.
You know,
you're gonna,
you're gonna have to move to South
Dakota because that's the big Mac state.
You want to keep eating big macs.
All right,
well you can still be on the government
nipple.
I was writing a at one point,
but
that was kind of like that where it was
some detective and he starts realizing
that there's some people just keep
disappearing and you know,
it's kind of a missing persons case and
that kind of turns into like a lot of
missing people.
And he started kind of looking over,
you know,
kind of put the board up.
They got their faces up there and
realize all these people that are really
large and then all sudden it turned into
this total saifai thing where it's like,
actually the aliens have like kind of
infiltrated the government.
They've like engineered this and hear
this.
The corn products saw the syrup and
they're basically like,
the government's like,
yeah,
for,
you know,
for whatever technology will will take
this and we'll feed our people this and
the aliens are harvesting the fat people
put in their rocket ships to
tailor our,
their rocket ships like whale oil or
fossil fuels.
Like we'll just kind of harvesting why
not orange people?
We had this,
uh,
I said Rob Wolf yesterday,
the author,
author of the Paleo Solution,
brilliant,
brilliant guy,
but what he was talking about government
subsidies and corn and the reason why
there's so much corn out there and corn
syrup and it's used in so many different
things and it's so terrible for you.
And it's like.
And it's not even economically feasible.
He's like,
the government is actually paying these
people to grow this shit because there's
not a lot of profit.
And growing it like somehow or another,
some hustle has bitten,
been put into place and the direct
result of it is a billion fat fucks and
its harvest.
It's amazing they're coming,
they're going to suck us up,
they're going to put us in a fucking
engine.
You know,
the twist would be,
you know,
like all of a sudden there's a very
large family and they're not being
harvested like what's going on?
It's like,
well it's just,
they're genetically.
That's their,
that's their genetics they had,
they,
they haven't been fed the corn syrup,
so they're,
they're just being passed over.
So it has nothing to do with actual,
like large people.
It has to do with people that are
specifically like gorging on the corn
syrup.
Well,
if we really do encounter alien life and
that alien life actually eats biological
matter,
we're going to be fucked just the same
way.
Pigs are fucked.
The same.
Pigs are fucking smart man.
I stopped eating pork for a couple of
months once a couple of years.
Actually,
like a nightmare.
It was pretty rough time.
I saw my brother's keeper talk to you
anymore.
I know.
Talk to you anymore.
Have you ever seen the documentary?
My brother's keeper.
It's about these slow.
They were slow.
They had some sort of a mental
retardation and they ran a farm and I'm.
One of them was accused of a murder or
something heinous and probably most
likely been pinned on them because they
were slow.
Well,
these guys running the farm,
they went to kill a pig when they pulled
out the shotgun,
the shotgun and the pig is fucking
running left and right.
Trying to get away from this guy.
It recognizing the gun and freaks out
and filing.
He gets out and shoots and I'm.
I remember thinking,
man,
pinks are fucking so I can't be in pigs
because you could shoot a cow in front
of another cow and then the other cows
barely react and be like,
look,
I don't,
I don't have a problem with that,
but I'm like,
shooting that pig is kind of fucked.
The aliens are going to treat us just
like all due.
Respect my,
my boat.
You know my,
my pig brother,
Bacon dude.
Apparently the slow cooking method,
robb wolf was explaining is the shit
you're supposed to put a grill electric
grill on 200 and cooker for two hours
and the Bacon becomes insane.
Yes.
I'm not ready to commit to that.
The crispy sounds great.
I feel like an asshole.
Like he said,
it'd be like an incense.
Almost.
Your whole house would smell like bacon
for two hours while it cooks.
Yeah.
That's a good way to become a fat fuck
twitching,
but if there are aliens and they are a
million years more advanced than us,
they're going to eat the shit out of our
folk law for the stuffing ourselves with
all this fast food and car and it's
we're grain fed cattle.
Cattle aren't supposed to eat grain near
neither people and those are.
That's what they had.
They finished them on that shit.
That's all nice and fat and juicy
furniture finish him.
Are you still working on a perfect
circle at all?
Are we ever going to see another album?
Because I know for a while you were
working on something and then it kind of
dissolved into.
I don't know even know what happened,
but um,
but you never know.
There's always,
there's always possibilities.
My ex girlfriend had a perfect circle
tattoo and I always had to look at it
every time it was right on her butt.
So every time I,
I'm not very comfortable.
So let's go back to when the power went
out,
man.
We were talking about Hicks.
You guys put Hicks on,
uh,
you thanked him on a cd because you got
ahold of one of his,
uh,
cassettes and you enjoyed it and,
but you never,
you guys never actually toured together.
But you know,
we closed,
we planned on it.
It was basically a plan.
We were kind of setting into motion in
like mid 93,
uh,
talking and that's when it's time when,
when he came down and it was kind of
part of why he was coming down.
We're trying to figure out what we're
going to do.
Comedians and rock musicians like that.
It's a,
it's a weird combination of bobcat.
Goldthwait did a lot of work with
Nirvana.
He opened up for them.
We come in here and he told some
hilarious stories about them just
fucking and shit at him screaming at him
and fucking murder in their eyes.
Fucking state.
He's friends with them and they want him
to go out there.
It's like,
yeah,
like I,
I actually approached,
uh,
David Cross a couple of years ago,
hey man,
we're going to do another.
You.
No,
I would say no to.
I wouldn't want to.
Yeah.
You don't want to eat dick in front of a
rock crowd.
Right?
To with coins and stuff.
It was all weird combination.
It's like you're not providing them what
they're there to see you.
You've got to train me.
Might work.
I've seen guys do it and pull it off.
And it works with.
It works with pulsifer.
Yeah,
because it's just,
it's just that the nature of that
project,
because it's,
it's just that there's just all this
different stuff going on.
You've got film and you've got your
video and you've got animation,
you've got wheat for one to where we had
neil hamburger opened up for us.
Oh,
that's awesome.
You know.
So that's just.
And then in the middle of our study
would come out and interrupt and go,
I forgot a joke and then you know,
just from the audience out for a minute
and then wander off and that can take my
drink and my chair
and sit down and like in my spot and
take up space for western Europe.
What was the song that you guys did
where you filmed the video?
Inside of a trailer?
It's sort of a condition or conditions
of my parole that's fucking song is
great.
Is that you're really your airstream.
Is that your personal?
So jealous.
I want to buy one so bad at talking
about getting one as a portable.
A podcast studio.
No,
we should do,
do that.
And then come to people's towns and do.
Because we could have a four G,
four g connection for verizon.
That's pretty Goddamn sporty.
If we just find a place that can support
the show,
we would have to have a.
We would have to have one for each show.
Like we'd have to have a contract for
each show because then we'd go over our
data.
So it would have to get like 50 of them.
We would have to get a sponsor.
Will this team ting wants a sponsor of
something new,
some new rather cell phone company.
Maybe they could do that.
Oh,
that's cool.
So you,
you,
um,
when you got into Hex for me,
I was a young comedian living in Boston
and I was working at the comedy
connection.
I had been doing it probably about a
year,
so it was probably like 1989.
Would you live in Boston?
I live in Newton.
I live in Davis Square.
How did you really?
Oh,
cool.
I used to work at Boston pet center down
on leach mere.
Oh really?
It's not there anymore.
Nice.
Some awful something there.
Boston is a great place to grow up,
but a terrible place to die.
And I felt like I was dying there.
Yeah.
It's like the people are cool.
They're smart.
It's interesting.
It's cool.
It's a real town,
but it's too fucking cold.
It's just too fucking old.
I feel like it's,
it's like I kind of feel like there's a
parallel between San Francisco and
Boston in a way.
As far as that bitter cold.
Let's take San Fran everyday son.
I'll take San Fran all day.
I like San Fran have maybe 100 times
better than Boston,
but I and I,
I guess like,
yeah,
I'll take that.
I just,
I think the sand France had just changed
their licensed places.
Say you're doing it wrong.
Yeah.
You think they're doing it wrong.
They just know what you're doing.
No matter what you're doing,
you're doing it wrong.
They,
they,
they go over the deep end,
but they go over my preferable and that
goes.
They go over the lefty deepen,
which seems weird coming from like a
cage fighting commentator type dude.
But I don't,
you know,
I,
I like people that are kind and I think
that even if the people on the left are
doing it the wrong way and even if
they're crazy and self righteous and
pretentious,
I think the idea behind it is they're
trying to be as kind to as many groups
of people you know and offer a
commensurate environment for as many
groups of people as possible.
So I support that even though I think a
lot of what they think is nonsense and
it doesn't go along with human nature
and behavior and Alpha them sometimes it
grabbed their neck and shake them like a
fucking child and we'll get it to go
that bitch do some squats,
have a fucking stake.
You're,
you're on planet Earth Bacon.
Get up,
bitch up.
Have a fucking shot of whiskey.
Let's do this.
I just a Boston is just a,
a Boston is liberal in the same way too,
but just angry.
Oh yeah,
there's,
there's definitely some.
There was some Irish anger going on
there and ugly cold.
Yeah.
I got really in trouble once I toured
there and like it was like one of my
first times back in Boston.
It's like,
back be back in Boston,
dry capital
world.
Crickets.
Like no,
as many fans as we were like,
yeah,
we're not,
we're done there.
Capital of the world.
It's hard to find a good one in Boston.
And when you find a good,
when you cling to them like a cork in
the ocean,
please keep me afloat,
please.
Um,
I saw him at the comedy connection and
uh,
I saw him because he was on the Rodney
Dangerfield special and uh,
you know,
I was an aspiring comedian.
So I went to see everybody was on the
Rodney dangerfield special when they
came through town and Boston was one of
those pit stops.
It was like Chicago,
Boston,
you know,
there was places where people would come
through and you know,
you would guarantee that they would be
in your town eventually.
And uh,
Hicks went up,
he went up at the comedy connection,
or the first time I actually saw him was
at Nick's comedy stop and he went up
after this guy was incredible hack.
The guy was like cop donut jokes,
cartoons,
smoking pot and make them all the most
hackneyed obvious premises.
And he was killing audiences,
filled idiots.
Nobody knew who Hicks was.
Me and maybe 50 other comedians in the
back of the room at a 300 people who
were in the audience places packed by 20
minutes into the show.
Half the people have left,
you know,
I mean literally cleared out at least 50
percent by the end of it,
it was maybe 100 people left and it was
a 50 audience members in 50 comedians.
And we.
And he didn't give a fuck.
He never came.
I was,
one joke would go wrong for me.
I would go into a tailspin.
I would panic,
I would go,
Duh.
I would rush my jokes.
I would say fuck too much.
I would just,
I would,
I would not have any confidence.
He's in the middle of this bit about how
Satan fugs John Davidson,
who don't remember John Davidson,
was the host of.
That's incredible.
It was,
was the,
you know,
one of them,
it was like the Internet before there
was the internet,
so it's a demon with his thorny cock is
fucking John Davidson in the ass and
John Davidson swells up and the off
season because he's pregnant with
Lucifer's baby and he shits out Oprah
Winfrey or,
or Geraldo Rivera depending on where
Hicks was at.
And so hicks is standing onstage
shitting.
So he's pausing going,
I mean it's fucking minutes,
10 minutes of just just straining and
people just getting up and leaving and
he looks up in the middle of it goes.
It's usually clears the room.
We're
just flying in and I got to see him bomb
horribly but yet still kill for 50 to
100 people.
And then I got,
I got him.
You kill for the whole,
the whole crowd.
But what an interesting guy.
It's like he was doing something that
nobody else was doing.
He was like,
he was injecting Noam Chomsky and,
and,
and philosophy.
And Terence Mckenna.
And it was like,
whoa.
Like I didn't even like when I first saw
Kennison kinison was the first time I
ever thought I could do comedy.
I was like,
you know,
I saw these guys rolling up their
sleeves talking about did you ever
notice?
And it's like,
well I kinda Kinda could do that.
I guess I kind of could do that if I had
to do that.
But then I saw kinison and,
and you know,
fucking came and I was married and he
was angry and it was funny and I was
laughing.
I was like,
maybe that maybe there's a comedy for
me,
maybe I could find my comedy.
Right.
And then when I saw him,
so I was like,
oh,
this guy just flipped the whole fucking
thing on its head.
Like now it's now it's,
you know,
it's about formulating a philosophy on
life and that there is a possibility
outside of the direction that we're
going in.
And then it is possible for the human
beings and the,
you know,
the,
the human civilization to rise up and,
and,
and be about love and be about
understanding.
It'd be about intellectual curiosity and
to be free of judgment.
I was like,
this guy's a fucking comedian.
Like this is the craziest Shit I've ever
seen.
It's almost like his jokes were an
afterthought to inject this philosophy
into the audience.
I think partly.
Yeah,
absolutely.
But I've loved.
I,
you know,
I kind of like a spend a little.
I spent all the time in that little
comedy world for awhile,
was very always very inspiring to me to
watch comedians like him basically just
stick to their guns and finish their ach
without getting that nervous sweat.
I mean,
it was always inspiring to see that.
And it's always my favorite comedy clubs
to go to were the ones that,
you know,
you end up if you're sitting out front
of,
uh,
the Mann's Chinese,
they give you tickets to go to this free
comedy club,
go then because if it's a good comedian
on,
he can like take bets to see how quickly
the room's going to clear.
And we had a,
I think I remember one time he had andy
kindler did a whole thing where he
brought everybody he knew down there to
kind of have like a little,
a side side seats with all the comedians
that he had an abyss leave and they did
a whole,
like a debunking comedy,
like a,
like a hack hack a class and they had
everybody come up and just do like the
hack thing in front of this audience and
this,
all these people that just kind of one
tickets from,
you know,
got tickets to the man saying isn't
there just,
I don't understand.
Like that's funny.
Why is that hack?
That's funny.
And then,
you know,
that whole thing went on for like an
hour,
hour and a half.
I was just,
I'm in the back of the room,
just peeing myself.
Them go through this.
And
then some dude gets out after them as
their act and does everything that they
just went through and the audience is
like,
oh that's so funny.
Can I have another break?
And then David Cross gets up and then
just clears the room was awesome.
Opening line,
just,
you know,
I saw Schindler's list the other day,
Schindler's list finally saw it.
It's not that funny.
This whole table of people just get up
and out the door like,
and it just,
every joke that he said,
it was like,
we're watching like me just set off a
bomb there.
He just set off a bomb.
They cleared the room.
Was Crosses,
rarely credited,
but in my opinion of watching it all
happen,
he's the originator of the idea of
alternative comedy because I saw him do
an alternative comedy in 1988.
He was in Boston and Cambridge.
He would go up and he would do,
I remember one time he was doing this,
this,
uh,
exercise video where would teach you,
teach you how to stretch.
So you've played the exercise.
Video districts.
I really do feel a stretch and he was
like doing this like long and people
like nervously giggling and not showing,
were not sure where it was going and it
never went anywhere.
It never went anywhere.
But it was amusing.
I felt,
I felt he was like a better version of
what I'm Andy Kaufman was doing because
Andy Kaufman would get up in front of
like colleges and like read the great
gatsby and I was like,
well that's Kinda fucked.
It's not really funny at all.
Like this is kind of crazy.
Like it is now.
It is now.
Yeah.
It's like a delayed reaction to like
witness it as great longterm absorption.
But Cross was.
He was funny while I was doing.
It was,
it was weird.
He was just so silly.
It was actually funny while he was doing
it.
Do you like comedy?
I like music because I'm completely
unmusical.
I don't have any skill.
I don't have any talent.
I don't have.
I don't understand it.
I don't see those bars.
That might as well be Tibetan.
You know,
Sanskrit.
I don't know what it is.
So when I see someone perform music,
when I,
when I'm in awe,
it's like,
to me it's a beautiful,
wonderful experience.
Do you feel the same way about comedy
because you don't do comedy?
Do you watch comedy and just get a free
sense of enjoyment that you might not
get from watching something that you
actually,
I generally enjoy more scripted like a
film comedy when I see a group of guys
who have figured out not a formula,
but there's just a,
there's a rhythm to their comedy and
they've actually created a character
behind,
you know,
that actor brings something to the table
that you want to look at.
And then their timing in this scenario
where it's clearly there are just play
acting.
It's like,
hey,
we're just playing dress up pretend and
you still laugh because the writing
solid,
but the,
what they bring to the table with their
writing is solid.
So like,
you know,
when you're seeing things like,
uh,
the movie super troopers,
it's just like,
those guys had to have a lot of fun
making that film because everything was
just like,
the writing was perfect.
It's a quotable film.
It's like every step of the way.
It's every,
every scene is quotable and they're
having fun.
And then you see,
you know,
almost almost any will farrell brothers,
those guys just.
Yeah.
Uh,
John C dot reilly's,
like just a master at just bringing his
thing to the table and then making your
script come alive.
It's just a great.
That to me is like,
and I,
and I look at that and I go,
what the fuck did you do that?
I have no idea how they did that and I
have no idea how to be funny.
I just saw I'm watching them just like
nail these things out of the park.
Like you could put all that script on
the paper and show it to me and I would
just go,
which I don't have where to start.
Like,
you know,
how is this funny?
One of my favorite all time Comedians is
Mitch Hedberg and one of the reasons why
Mitch is one of my favorites is because
none of his stuff was funny on paper.
It didn't make any sense.
Like you would see that he goes,
it was somebody asked me do I want a
frozen banana?
I said,
no,
but I want a regular banana later.
So yes.
Now if you saw that on paper and be
like,
why is that funny?
What the fuck is,
I might have butchered his joke.
I don't think it was pretty close,
but I,
I love that.
I love that he redefined comedy in a
certain way to.
Because he,
he made,
first of all,
I was a heroin addict and he had only
clean comedy.
I mean his stuff was squeaky clean.
Meanwhile he was gang green and his leg,
because he was fucking shooting in this
same vein too many times.
It was really a strange guy and his
material was all so odd and if you loved
Mitch Hedberg it was awesome.
But like Mitch Hedberg would go on after
these guys that would like sing and
dance and do song parodies and you know,
they would close with a rap and he would
eat dick.
He would eat dick so bad that the club
owner would try to switch him with the
Middle Act and say,
listen,
the Middle East has been doing stronger.
We're going to have him close.
We're going to give him your money.
And then they're,
you know,
his manager would call it and it'd be
like a big problem.
And it wasn't necessarily that he was a
not a,
not a funny comic,
it was like it was completely the wrong
setup for his type of comedy.
Whereas it's a delicate environment
where you could take a guy like Kennis
and it didn't matter who went on before
him,
when he stormed out of this fucking room
has changed.
The environment has changed.
Hedberg would get up there with
sunglasses on,
you know,
and it just goes,
bear never played tennis against a wall.
They're relentless.
You would just start giggling and it
would,
it would be a slow build.
And he was one of the rare guys that
would have a nonsequitors.
Everything was being nonsequitor every
single bit.
I'm sorry,
what is that drawing on the wall?
That's a vagina.
That's what a child would draw like in
high school maybe.
And in Walsh's a drawing of what he
thinks Barbie looks like.
And it's right next to Pam Anderson up.
We had an artist on one of our other
podcasts to interrupt you,
but I just kept screaming at me.
This whole place is a giant distraction.
Look,
there's a flashlight right here.
Are former sponsor fucking cats all over
the table.
Super Mario brothers behind the
appointment.
There's a mannequin tit stormtrooper
helmet.
Ron Paul's in here somewhere.
Where's Ron?
Ron?
Paul's over there somewhere.
She's leaving.
Yeah.
It's a.
This is a weird little setup we have
here.
What is what?
That fucking painting,
man.
That's what I've been wanting to ask.
Yours burned that thing.
If you look far away,
if you.
If you look at it far away,
it looks like a naked girl.
Shit.
Thanks Joe.
Thanks a lot man.
Appreciate it.
I only said that for humor.
I really mean that.
So I have.
I have questions for you and it's a
regarding Anderson Silva.
I want to know what you think is coming
next.
So this,
you're gonna.
Are you on the inside of that?
Is it a what's happening?
Most likely it will be one of two
things.
Depending on what they can talk them
into.
Anderson is a very rare position where
he sort of gets chooses opponents for
the most part.
It'll be there,
you know,
based on like he didn't want to fight
Chael Sonnen because he talks so much
shit.
He didn't want to do it,
but he also did because he wanted to
silence them,
so they just had a financially motivated
them.
It will most likely be either this kid,
Chris Weidman,
who's the best up and coming 195 pounds
or one of the best.
He hasn't fought a lot of guys,
but he's a,
I think I've heard about stamping.
Pretty solid dude.
Just destroyed Mark Munoz who's also a
top 10 contender.
And the way he did it was just so just
complete and total the way he
anticipated all of his moves countered.
I'm almost strangled them three or four
times the first day.
Pretty Young Kid,
right?
Yeah.
And a spectacular wrestler.
So it's him.
He might get it,
but he's,
he's a bit of a tough sell because,
uh,
there's a lot of folks in the mainstream
that don't know who he is.
He's more of a,
someone who he.
He can beat Anderson Silva.
I mean,
look who the fuck knows what's gonna
actually happen.
But it may be possible that he could
pull it off.
He has the right set of skills,
but he's not known as well.
Um,
but the other option is if George St
Pierre Beats Carlos Condit.
Okay then,
then they have some fucking crazy Susan.
Is that the guy that they mentioned at
the end of the fight when they were
saying so are you going to fight him?
And he went to find him.
Oh No,
that's John Jones.
Okay.
John's right.
Yeah.
You said he doesn't want to fight Jon
Jones,
but Jon Jones really isn't a totally
different weight class.
Not just Anderson has dabbled in the 205
pound weight class,
but really he makes one 85 pretty
easily.
He doesn't have a problem making one 85
a and John Jones could never make one
85.
John Jones is six foot three,
240 pounds to 30 least when he's walking
around.
And then he cuts down to two.
Oh,
five slowly,
you know,
over his camp.
You know,
cut.
Probably cut my loses the last probably
10 pounds in water weight.
He's just a way bigger guy.
He's way bigger and he's a really strong
wrestler and stylistically he's a
nightmare and apparently they have a
mutual admiration for each other.
That's it can,
it can be bypassed,
you know,
with the right amount of money and both
guys probably agreed to it if the right
amount of money on the table,
but right now,
you know,
they both stated their admiration for
each other and they're probably number
one and number two,
pound for pound fighters in the world
right now.
People would like to see that.
But honestly I think George St Pierre
and Anderson are more physically the
same size.
It's closer.
Okay.
George has a struggle to make one 70
whereas Anderson is a,
uh,
he makes one 85 pretty easy.
George could make one 85 and be the
basically the same size and that would
be an amazing fight that I think if,
if George can get through Carlos condit
and that they believe they're going to
fight in the fall,
depending on George's recovering from an
acl surgery.
Okay.
So yeah.
Yeah.
I've had to.
And if George gets through that and
everything's cool that,
uh,
and if he beats Carlos Condit,
which is an f,
you know,
Carlos has really good,
he's a very tough.
But if he beats him then they go to
probably a Dallas stadium,
probably doing that big giant fucking
60,000
square foot.
That'd be awesome.
That'd be.
I'm just looking forward to the next,
you know,
on the community with what happens next
because I was,
that was a pretty amazing Anderson's a,
uh,
he's a Ninja.
I mean,
he really is.
He's a real master martial artists in a
way that like what,
what he does,
there's maybe a,
a tiny handful of human beings on the
planet who can move the way he moves.
And so I think going back to some of
that,
you know,
that relaxed state we were talking about
before,
I just,
it's really watching him,
watching him operate.
It's,
it is like Jordan at his,
at his top,
top of his game.
That's just the panther,
this,
this art,
this ballet movement.
Uh,
just,
just a fluid.
Yeah.
And a connected.
Um,
and I think a lot.
I think a lot of that's just,
it seemed like a lot of that's missing
from the UFC these days right here.
Any mixed martial arts forum that seems
to lead.
There's that,
you know,
there's the awesome gladiator go,
you know what to do is bang it out,
but there's that art that I just kind of
missed from the earlier days of watching
it be the,
that the bracket system where you had to
kind of,
you know,
suck it up and get through three dudes
in one night.
You know,
the old wrestling days.
Well,
what Anderson is,
is so much better than everyone else
that you get to see that art.
Whereas like you see a couple of dudes
that are really close to each other,
go at it.
You don't eat.
They don't have that,
that,
that giant skill level above their
opponent.
Whereas Anderson does like when it comes
to striking Anderson's,
the most accurate fighter we've ever had
inside the octagon.
Like no one has been as accurate with
him and he's,
he's so,
he's so fluid in the way he moves.
He does things and its opponents don't
even realize he's done them until they
land and you're like,
what?
He's like the master of like sneaking
shit in.
It's a really unusual dude and the
reason why he's able to do that,
as you know,
mixed martial arts as a whole is really
only been around since 1993 and we're
seeing this constant evolution of it,
but Anderson represents at right now
what's possible the furthest,
furthest evolution of the game as far as
it's ever gone.
But the reality is in his individual
disciplines,
he's not as good as the best guys.
There are better kickboxers therapy,
better Jujitsu guys like him and it's
like one day we're going to see a guy
who can do to Anderson Silva,
what Anderson Silva could do details on
it.
I mean,
we haven't seen it yet,
but we're going to see a guy who has
hixon Gracie Jujitsu and bought her rate
type striking.
Right?
You know,
and when that happens,
I mean the man and that's.
It's inevitable.
It's the sport is moving in that
direction.
It's like this constantly accelerating
process and right now it's the only
people that are successful are the
completely fanatical and obsessed.
You can't get by and sheer athleticism.
You see some basketball players that
they probably don't work out as hard as
they could and you know,
they maybe don't,
but,
but they're good enough to get by and
they have enough gifts to get by in the
pro basketball player,
tall and arrogant.
When you get to the,
when you get to the top,
the upper echelons of the ultimate
fighting championship.
There's no room for anybody but the
fanatical.
obsessed and the Rory Mcdonald's of the
world,
these young guys that are coming up that
are just insanely good.
And every time you see them,
they're much better than they were six
months ago.
That's the future.
And that's one that's inspiring because
it's,
uh,
it's definitely that,
that chess game that we spoke of
earlier.
I feel like it's more interesting to
watch because although I don't have
necessarily the frame of reference for
what's actually happening,
when you actually go back and look at
the tape and go click by,
click and go,
oh my God,
that's exactly what you're talking
about,
John and your corner just going this and
this.
It's,
it's a chest moves and it's millimeters
and with a guy like Anderson,
there's no one to tell him to do that
because he's that guy.
You know?
Anderson really doesn't have it.
I mean,
he has guys that coach him and Moitai
and coach them in Jujitsu when it comes
to mma and nobody always going to tell
editors what to do and knows exactly
what to do.
He's at the top of the mountain.
It's beautiful to watch someone who's at
the very best of the,
the like the,
the peak,
the apex of whatever that is right now.
You know,
whether it's fucking motorcycle racing
or whatever it is,
gymnastics.
When you see a guy who was at the,
there's a quote from the movie vision
quest.
Did you ever see that movie?
Matthew Modine?
Remember that moving good fucking movie,
man.
Why are you laughing right now?
Why am I laughing?
That's a great.
Because I forgot all about it.
I haven't watched it lately though.
In event held up,
we should watch it now.
We should list.
What's the girl's name?
The girl with the black hair.
It was hot as fuck.
I'm member.
She moved into his house and he was
caught smelling her panties.
Sylvester stallone.
Yes.
I'm.
Anyway,
there's a scene in the movie where the
guy is a google that now the kid is the
top and you know,
he's like one of the top wrestlers and
he's about to face a state champion
wrestler and is huge thing and he's
blown away by it and he's working as a
delivery man at a hotel is working as a
room service guy and one of the cooks in
the hotel and him have this conversation
about the guy seeing a Palae or I think
it was Paleo,
but I've seen some incredible soccer
game and seeing this guy do something
that just for that one moment you.
You rejoiced in that guy's movements in
his ability to do something astounding.
And for one moment I like it.
Raised the entire group of people that
were watching it.
For one moment we were above the apes
were above.
Right?
The Shit chucking monkeys.
You know Linda Florentina.
Oh,
she was so hot.
Soon as ridiculous.
Whatever happened to her sex change.
She.
Nelson.
Yeah,
she's awesome.
She actually doesn't look that bad.
Now you got to Google photo over.
I mean for being a target semester.
Ostalgie Candle Light One candle.
Corner of the room.
Don't see that much.
Everybody's good.
I apologize.
Linda.
You don't want to wrestle.
Storm Susan Dogma.
Weird.
Weird that you even know who was in dog
ma?
Did you see dogma?
Dogma?
I win.
Okay.
Who doesn't even know?
What's the,
the old uh.
Oh Man.
I'm going to blow this.
All right.
So,
uh,
so has John Travolta Greece.
Oh yeah.
Have you seen Greece?
Yes,
I watched it all the time.
I have not seen that.
Marine Greece.
Did you reject it?
I think it was one of those things you
kind of went by and then all my friends
were like,
oh,
we,
you know,
green screen,
and I'm like,
you know what?
I've decided I'm never going to see that
decision.
The,
the doors movie in Greece.
Oh,
the doors.
Maybe movies.
The season finale of lost was mine.
I said,
you haven't seen that one thing and then
up to like the season finale,
he decided not to,
so he doesn't know.
Why's,
why's he got me enough?
You made it hit me with enough nonsense
books.
Yeah.
You were a wise man.
What did you just bring up as an
example?
What was the other one?
Doors,
doors moving.
I don't know,
just one of those things.
I just all of a sudden just didn't watch
it right before val camera went to New
Mexico and grew his head.
He became Jim Morrison for a little bit
and his head apparently like on the set,
he was like,
so that he was like,
you know,
being Jim Morrison and did a great job
of Jim Morrison thing.
John Malcovich,
the John Malcolm x play,
Jim and the words of a Marlin Brando.
Why don't you just try acting?
Yeah,
that's A.
I love that he said that the whole idea
of people talking and character.
I read once that Angelina Jolie and Jon
voight used to get on the phone and they
would have full conversations father and
daughter in character.
And I was like,
that's a crazy bitch.
Okay.
And she's broken.
He's broken.
He fucked up raising her.
She's a mess now.
I was talking to a friend of mine like
a.
We were somehow Jennifer Aniston came up
and we kind of segwayed from Brad Pitt
off into Angelina Jolie and we both were
like,
we kind of paused for my one.
Fuck Dude.
How crazy is that?
How,
how like Brad just got to be kind of
sitting there like,
just kind of going.
It's just for the press because this
just like you say that,
but I bet chief,
fuck the shit out of him.
I bet she sent him for a,
uh,
in a,
in a sexual ride that Jennifer Aniston
is completely incapable of.
I bet she's way too self control,
self conscious to controlled too,
you know,
too reserved.
Angelina Jolie had billy Bob tattooed on
her fucking arm.
She fucked billy Bob Thornton,
tattooed his name on her arm and then
carried his blood in a vial around her
neck that bitches loked out to Jo.
Lee's got some big old.
Hold that up.
Pull that video up.
You remember?
That was a fucking great.
That was a great science.
That's just.
And I think for some reason maybe I
Lindsay Lohan.
I don't care.
I don't care what kind of bell rope she
tugs.
I just,
I think the crazy just completely
outweighs any of that.
Just the drama that's attached to any of
that stuff I think is just like not a
part of my world.
My friend Tony always said it best.
He said psychotic and erotic are next
door neighbors and they really.
They're so close to each other.
I could see that.
And the craziest girls I've seen,
the craziest girl I've ever dated was.
This is Lindsay Lohan,
some big ass tin cups,
cups.
I'm trying to get in your ass Nigga.
Sweating.
Pennies can day.
This is a different song now this is
just remember the chorus which got some
big ass.
Today's it goes into it.
I need to see them.
Do you see this is a different version
of man.
I'm telling you this
different version because the other one
was more sing silent.
Angelina's Xiao Li gas on a big ass
titties.
It was like more rhythmic.
I think these guys bit them big problem
in the rap community from,
in the comedy community,
which brings me back to bill Hicks at.
Uh,
I didn't,
uh,
I was a big,
huge fan of Denis leary for about six
months until I saw Hicks and then I
went,
what the fuck?
You guys doing the same jokes?
Right?
But,
and,
and uh,
and no disrespect to bill,
but I think as you've probably seen
mostly in that comedy world,
uh,
the,
the beauty of Hicks was that,
that was his world.
He was staying in that world.
This is,
this is his whole purpose is to do this
thing,
right?
Most people during their,
during that period of time where there
were,
there had,
it's like animals had their eye on the
Johnny Carson Position,
Oh yeah,
do this and then you do this and you get
to show and then you did this thing and
you get to be Johnny Carson,
somebody kind of like,
uh,
the subject of a shakes the clown and
like watching everybody tried to be,
you know,
being,
binkies trying to get that position and
our shakes and all that and you know,
but I feel like Larry was,
you know,
whatever you want to lay on him as far
as like,
you know,
biting that style.
It doesn't matter because as it went on,
what he ended up doing with all of that,
he ended up becoming.
He making his own thing.
So even though it kind of,
maybe you know,
it clearly just clearly carbon copied
that.
But in his defense I feel like,
you know,
back then it was war,
you're trying to make your make your
way.
And I think,
Eh,
I don't give that.
I don't give him that.
It was really,
he could have,
he could have come up with his own shit.
Yeah.
But I think,
you know,
I had the same problem with them for
many years,
but like,
just let it go.
I let it go because he's funny.
Yeah.
Some of those watching the rescue me,
there's some,
there's some tasty bits in that.
In his movie he did A.
Oh man.
Where he was a burglar and he's stuck in
this house.
John Lovitz in him.
Is that what it was?
No Man.
He could eat shit and spiderman then.
Did you know he wasn't.
He wasn't in spite of the suck and
Spiderman is just stupid.
Why is he in that movie?
Someone needs a dad.
Like you couldn't just get anybody else.
I'm not a fan when I find out you're
full of shit.
I'm sorry.
Right?
Yeah.
I can appreciate that.
He does well at some things,
but until he comes clean about being
full of shit in the first place,
he can go fuck himself and it's not
interesting.
Yeah.
Not Interested.
I'm going to get him and Bill Murray in
the same room in a minute.
Do some correct.
Is Two guys want to know where the three
guys were,
know where they were when they died.
Rich,
Jenny,
because it was just so crazy.
The Camille committed suicide,
a Kennison because he was my first
influence.
And then Hicks.
I was at this club in Connecticut,
Hartford,
Connecticut and me and this other comic.
We're in the green room and this girl
came in and goes,
Bill Hicks just died.
We're like,
whoa.
He may die.
He bit.
Yeah,
it was like overnight and I was in.
I was in a hotel in Detroit or flying to
Europe the next morning and uh,
I woke up in the middle of the night,
like just bolt upright at whatever time
that was.
I can remember at the time was.
But like I basically was awake and then
we got up the next morning and my pager
beeper got a message from Dunkin is
manager and it was like bill pass last
night.
And the time that was quoted he passed
was when I woke up in bed and was pretty
creepy.
Your stomach actually via wherever he
was,
through Detroit to tap me on his way.
I was like,
dude,
I'm sorry to make you go to Detroit.
It's probably a really quick trip when
you're in hyperspace.
It's probably right next door.
He reached over and press found out
about his.
I found out about his problem because I
had an awful nightmare when we were.
I was at a one of those kinds of motels
where you get the you can pull your car
right up to the outside and it was kind
of like the two stories and you kind of
walk through the breezeway between the
thing.
He's and there was like a hundred people
there and everybody's bawling their eyes
out and bill wasn't there and I was
like,
what the fuck is this dream about?
So I called the.
I called his manager the next day and
I'm like,
I had this fucked up dream about bill.
And he goes,
yeah,
I can't really talk about it.
And nobody,
because nobody knew yet that he had
pancreatic cancer.
I had this fucked up dream and I called
his manager and went,
what the.
I had this weird dream about bill,
what's up?
And he's like,
yeah,
I can't really talk about it.
We're,
do you believe mean there's no way that
was coincidental?
No.
No Way.
No,
no way.
What is that?
What's going on there?
Yeah.
Is there a zero,
zero,
zero dimension that is next door
neighbor that you can tap into that I
have no idea.
Edix.
Diarrhetics what the fuck is that?
Yeah.
I don't know,
but it was,
it was pretty
and I had a couple moments like that
with him over that time.
That's what I'm saying.
Like when he died,
like I was just,
you know.
Yeah,
of course they woke up in the middle.
I never,
I've never had anything like that
happened to me,
but I absolutely believe it's possible.
Well,
yeah,
it was a weird.
It was a weird time.
They see the most provable form of any
sort of psychic phenomenon is the
ability to know when someone's looking
at you,
they said that statistically you can
prove,
you know,
you can have people stand and have their
back facing a group of people and they
can statistically tell with,
you know,
certain amount of uncertainty,
guesswork,
but you could show on a graph that
people can tell when people are looking
at them,
if that,
if that is possible,
valid than these other things.
Definitely on some
level valid because it's energy.
Have you ever heard of the work of
Rupert Sheldrake?
He's this guy who believes in the
morphogenetic field and he's,
he's done research showing that dogs can
tell when their owners are coming home.
He believes there is some sort of a
frequency that we're all tuning into
that all of our consciousness connected
to some type of grid and you can
recognize when that's in motion and you
can recognize things and events,
things that are happening and it,
it's just a matter of us being sensitive
enough to tune it in,
you know?
And that's,
um,
I think that's really one of the
weirdest things about being a human
being.
I'm like,
no,
no.
He's not doing that.
I don't think he is.
He might be.
I doubt if he does,
he'll be okay.
He's just a mess.
He's from Ohio,
you know,
I rescued him from Columbus.
Um,
I,
I want to believe that we're slowly but
surely moving from the phase of grunts
to language to written language to
internet,
to psychic ability to communication.
I mean,
I want to think that it's.
But there's so much room for fuckery.
There's so much room for fake psychics.
Oh yeah.
So when I hear a story like yours,
like,
ah Ha,
I have no reason to lie about that.
It's not like it's going to make or
break my career,
you know?
So what does sound cool?
It sounds pretty cool.
Pretty bitchy to bring up at a party,
especially if you're in front of a fire.
Touch me.
Yeah.
Everybody wants to fucking claim
psychic.
Everybody wants to claim it.
It's so hard.
Trust people,
I don't take no shit.
That's,
I think,
the,
the problem with all of that is that
we're not probably on some,
you know,
a universal level.
We're not really allowed to completely
be able to tap in and rely on it.
Although I do firmly believed that each
one of us has to kind of really
listening to the,
uh,
the intuitive side of ourselves to kind
of just follow your heart and know what
path you're supposed to choose because
we all kind of have a role to play at
second and you kind of have to find that
happy medium between like making
yourself happy and making sure you're
fulfill,
but also kind of doing,
doing your part,
you know,
they,
they work.
The intuitive is such an interesting
point because your intuition depends on
your respect for your consciousness.
Respend.
It depends on your respect for your
honesty about your own actions and your
own thoughts and your own ideas.
And I find that when I am the most at
peace with my own actions,
then I am a much,
a much better in tune with other people.
And I've,
I've met people that were completely
full of shit.
And like,
how does this guy not know that he's
full of Shit,
not know that no one's going to buy
this.
I'll tell you how,
because he's lying to himself because
he's lying.
He's lying
in a way.
Positive reinforcement for his negative
actions.
If he keeps winning,
yes.
Even if it's negative,
that's just going to reinforce that and
reinforce that big
when I'm most honest myself is when I'm
get the most intuitive reads off of
people.
I had one friend,
my friend,
Brian Cowen and I used to,
he was like the worst guy for like being
involved with friends that would turn
out to be crazy and idiots and thieves
and nuts and worst,
the worst,
uh,
connections with girls.
And I would always,
I was like a big brother.
Me.
He's worried about you doing coke,
doing coke.
What's in your hand?
Oh,
bud light.
No.
Oh,
it is powerful.
Yeah.
If you wanted to come down tonight,
who knows?
Maybe some of them won't show up.
But uh,
it's mad flavor.
Aka Joey Diaz.
Brian redband demand to my left.
Uh,
Josh mcdermitt,
our good friend from that show,
30 and fucked in the ass or whatever.
And me and a 10:30
here.
ICEHOUSE.
Fascinating.
Did you ever experience or experiment
with any drugs?
Did you ever do like mushrooms or
anything growing up?
Do you know?
This is on the Internet.
People can hear this to be careful what
you said.
I'm just
Jesus Christ.
I'm like,
Oh wait,
I'm not supposed to talk about something
you looked at me like what?
I mean I just slit your chair on far
younger when I was like [inaudible] 93,
I went to Lollapalooza and I was really
a hippie kind of back there.
And then in a tool was one of the.
Because I used to be at nine snail fan
growing up.
Then it became some hippie and I never
remember seeing tool and going like,
why am I not so 1992?
I'm moving on [inaudible] 93 of them,
but a lot.
I always wondered that because I mean,
especially a year old,
uh,
old videos sober,
you know,
just the visuals on that was just
amazing when you're on mushrooms.
But,
uh,
did you ever play with any of that kind
of psychedelic stuff or never,
never,
never do.
What was the song that you did to the
FIBONACCI sequence and now you're on
drugs?
He's,
he's,
he's beautiful.
It was beautiful.
And what he is,
you can't fake a Brian.
I mean,
he is just that,
that's who he is.
Yeah.
There's no,
it was a song that you did to the
FIBONACCI sequence.
Um,
uh,
I believe it was foggy mountain
breakdown really?
No,
no,
it was one of those songs,
one of those songs.
Yeah,
whatever it is,
you can find it online,
Google it.
But um,
the,
the FIBONACCI sequence,
I watched a documentary about it once
where they showed pine cones and
pineapples and sunflowers and all these
different things show that there's some
sort,
some sort of a mathematical code to
nature.
Right.
And I,
and I think the funny thing is like
people
myself actually trying to like force
those numbers on a song.
It's kind of,
it's kind of funny.
It's kind of clunky because the song is
that any song is that,
so,
you know,
to Kinda
like,
it's like,
you know,
my kid blocks like,
Ooh,
look through square.
And they stack,
um,
the uh,
every,
everything is that.
So it like actually like write your
faces,
force that into a song is a,
as a little a sophomore.
So I'm,
I'm reprimanding myself for being a
little silly.
Oh,
you're not,
you will.
I thought it was an homage to the,
uh,
the,
the order of the universe.
I didn't think there was silly at all,
but that's as a fan.
I enjoyed it,
but I,
it was just short for fanatic and I have
to go now.
That's why you know,
you look at someone with a nose job and
you go,
what the fuck is going on here?
Some of these ruined the sequence.
You've ruined the FIBONACCI sequence.
Now you gotta make you gotTa.
Make Lemons into lemonade.
You gotTa,
you gotta make soup out of the Ham hocks
and the beans that you've been given.
It's just,
just is what it is.
When,
when,
when you really find out that there
truly is a mathematical sequence that
the whole universe is based on it,
it's one of those things that really
makes you step back and go,
we are,
man,
we might as well be fucking cave men
because even though we like to think
that with our four g connections and our
satellite dishes in our cars that we
somehow or another have elevated from
the biological.
Like Bob was,
so it was still so base.
We're still so stuck in the Rut of the
mud and you know,
we,
we don't.
We really,
really have barely wrapped our heads
around how complicated and insane and
diverse this whole thing really is.
The FIBONACCI sequence.
To me,
it's like one of those real,
real mindfox.
It makes you just pause and there was a
particle physicist recently or
theoretical physicist that was talking
about when they study quantum mechanics,
they find that there's some sort of an
embedded code to it all.
That it's not just an embedded code.
It's a recognizable code that is used in
mathematicians and they said,
look,
fucking the whole universe is a program.
It gets a program,
you know,
whether you call it,
whether it's a biological program or
whether there's intelligent design has
been done by some engineer from pro
beefiest movie,
whatever it is.
There's a program to this.
I was always playing around with just a
story where you actually day on the way
to time travel would be to somehow
connect into the base of your DNA and
there's actually a time code in the DNA
and you have to like reset it so that
all of a sudden you just end up in this
other time zone,
but then you would.
Your software wouldn't be compatible,
so this whole script fell apart just
before my eyes.
Imagine if you did decide you were going
to go into another dimension and you go
into the the other dementia,
you would just be engulfed in complete
madness because you don't have the tools
to deal with that new.
Right?
That's like that.
Like you go to,
you're going to hit enter and you're
like,
oh,
I forgot a zero.
Just fucking kaleidoscope
until the end of time.
It's like that movie or the twilight
zone episode.
When was at Burgess,
meredith was all just all he wanted to
do was read and just leave me alone
leave and he's in inside of a library
and a nuclear explosion happens and
everyone's dead,
but he's surrounded by all these books
and then he breaks his glasses.
He's like,
oh,
fuck it.
Just forever in this downward spiral of
inability to perceive his environment.
I'm worried about him.
He's all right.
I was worried about him for the first
five years.
I knew it.
When we got into,
we got into a groove and I know he knows
exactly what he's doing.
That's the only way to kill the hanging
over.
You just start.
When he starts slurring,
you're going to get nervous,
but it's.
He's okay.
Yeah.
He's always looking at you,
man.
He's got monitors too,
so even when he's not looking at you,
he's looking at you through monitors and
what you really need to think about is
the fact that out over a sold out show
tonight at the thing.
Yeah,
the Ice House.
The ice.
He'll be up there.
He's a comedian.
He's got some funny jokes.
You should come tonight.
I'm working.
Yeah,
you should let people invite themselves.
That way you don't get rejected now.
I'm actually pouring wine tonight at
the.
Oh you.
If people want to go see,
where is it at?
It's a every Royce.
It's an old,
old Pasadena down the street here.
I've heard crazy stories about you with
these at signings A.
I've heard shows.
There's shows,
shows that you've done when you tone
your entire back to the audience during
the entire performance.
Have you done that?
Have really an awful sensitivity to a
flash.
A flash.
Cameras flashing.
So if I,
if the,
if you just can't,
people can't control themselves.
I just have to.
I can't,
I can't focus on what I'm doing because
I'll actually go into a convulsion.
So I have really had to take an
epileptic convulsion.
I can't finish the set.
So I'm sorry I have to turn my fucking
back to you.
I didn't know that was even real to my
friend.
Jim's wife is epileptic and my message
board would have these avatars that
would fly and that's basically nobody's
business.
So it's like,
you know,
I,
I asked you to fucking put the camera
away to maybe if you told them fucking
seizure me,
mom,
they get right up in your face because
then you got the asshole who was a who
still into nine inch nails from 92 and
he's going to do the flash thing because
he hates me.
He hates you for leaving them.
So you buddy.
It's abandonment issues is pointed at
you when he said that,
do you,
do you know Trent?
Do you do work with them ever?
I,
we've met several times,
probably more than more than several,
but I haven't talked to him.
He grew his neck with val kilmer.
Grew his head.
I haven't,
I haven't seen him for awhile as it is.
He's huge.
He started bodybuilding,
I think.
Yeah,
I think yeah,
that was.
I think he did start lifting,
but I don't know.
It's a weird thing for a musician,
right?
It's like a one point in time musicians.
We're always sort of one of my favorite
fucking scenes.
I almost forgot this is you,
uh,
some guy jumped on stage,
you hip toss them and they took his back
and continue to look at him like he was
ready for it.
I got it.
Yeah.
Got It right there.
What,
what was that about?
What was going on there?
I mean,
you obviously you didn't hurt him,
so you sensed that he was friendly.
Uh,
yeah,
it was,
uh,
it was my stage.
Like if you're up there you get choked.
So beautiful.
You give them links to the arm around
and when you thought you were like the
garden,
do a,
uh,
like an Faq.
So beautiful.
But the thing is the guy didn't even try
to fight that art look.
He throws his arms up.
He was just thinking Dick against his,
his,
his boats.
He's like,
ah,
this is the best.
I'm going to have a baby,
but I'm a tool base to have a baby.
And he painted blue.
Pretty rare situation where you got the
perfect retarded fan and I have a dozen
fight hard.
And how cool was it for him though you
were singing while you had his back?
Well,
the,
I think that's a,
you know,
there's not,
there was no footage online that can.
It shows me everything that happened.
We actually had a guest singer come out
on that song,
read it right during that.
So like not only the kid like have to
deal with,
you know,
me doing that,
but he had to sit through this other
singer doing a thing to show you.
Just held them back control.
I had the wrap the cord around his
and continued singing
[inaudible] that's slack.
So every time he would go and check the
thing.
That's so beautiful.
Look at me.
Was He talking to you?
Well this is going on.
I get my backup to.
No.
Can I see a little pat on the back end
is where the security was going to leave
you alone back then at it.
You'll see there's the guy coming out to
sing.
It's a,
it's Haitham.
He's a friend of ours.
He's going to do resist going on 97,
64,
64.
Let's see.
Back when you didn't get sued for Shit,
right?
Yeah.
Because that happened.
Now you'd be.
You'd be fucked.
I can't do anything.
Would you not do that now?
You probably do.
You would just do it anyway.
Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know what you're doing.
You'd be crazy.
You never know.
That guy that killed dimebag Darrell.
I did it once when I was young.
Rewards words for you,
John Lennon.
I did it once when I was younger at a
wing concert and now I look back at it.
I cringe just thinking the fact that I
fucking got up on stage and they
actually had to stop there like they
were in between songs and then I jumped
back into the audience,
but I was like,
it just makes me sick to my stomach and
I was like 18 at a wing concert,
but I can't imagine doing that now.
Who makes you feel any better?
If I was right next year,
I'd be like,
dude,
pussy man,
it,
they'll be fine,
man.
This happens all the time.
Like some bands like,
like it,
like I remember mighty,
mighty bosstones nip slip,
slip,
mighty,
mighty.
Bosstones,
you still like almost welcomed people on
the stage,
if I remember correctly,
so I think that's why I did.
I was like,
oh,
all bands are like this,
you know,
it's a social event.
Yeah.
I'm not trying to like convey a thing.
Jump on up.
What's up with your music not being on
itunes?
Is that something licensings bullshit
crap owns.
I'm sorry for asking them questions like
for a perfect circle around it.
Oh,
they are?
Yeah.
What the fuck are you talking about son?
Well,
I,
I recently went through a thing where I
sold all my cds,
a lot of my cds and I babbled rebuying
them on digital,
but yeah,
I know keep them.
I know higher quality.
I know his cd much higher quality a
while now that they've got.
There's a new version of,
you know like MP,
MP four a or whatever they are there
that are pretty solid.
It's a pretty solid and it all depends.
It all depends on how you use
compression because there's ways to do
it where the new digital formats are
actually pretty bad ass.
Joseph,
as good as CD quality,
it's pretty.
You would never notice the difference,
especially when you're listening to it
on this fucking thing like that
Portlandia episode like let's have on
these little speakers.
Do you have one of those artists that
emerged through the digital takeover of,
of music.
What was that like for you to watch that
happen where all of a sudden your shit
was online and you know,
to go through the,
you know,
the whole,
the whole scene with a.
well,
I mean some people just kind of tried to
fight it and there's other people that
did know,
had to do whatever they had to do to,
to kind of embrace it.
I know there's one thing I know for sure
you cannot download my wine.
That's right.
Not a digital format.
Not yet.
Not until we have those printers that
can print out your wine show.
Crazy as that sounds retarded.
Just five years ago.
That sounds more walking around with a
phone that's not connected to anything.
That's funny.
Yeah.
Jay Leno has one of these three d
printers in his shop.
He puts a video online of him making
parts for old cars with it.
Yeah.
It's fucking amazing.
I mean,
you just run it through a scanner and
next thing you know it's.
There it is.
Yeah.
And that's the beginning.
I'm loving this wine now.
I actually,
I actually see that's the problem.
His problem is it's okay.
It's like at all the problems in the
world,
you know.
When was the last time you were at the
Olive Garden?
A lot longer.
You motherfucker,
you did it.
I would have to go there for me to be my
first time.
Oh,
you have never been.
I'm not snooty.
Is it hard to find good restaurants in
Arizona?
Yeah.
Where we are,
there's a,
there's a handful of pretty awesome
places,
but there's not as many as we would
like.
Uh,
how far are you away from Phoenix?
Two hours to Tucson worth four hours
from Tucson.
And then the other area of note is
Sedona,
right.
That's where the donor has.
Even Sedona has only a couple places
that are really good,
but you'll take that just for the small.
I just cook myself.
Yeah,
you know,
I just do my own Ravioli's and we know
we have our own gardens and orchards.
Yeah,
that is a cool thing.
We have a cook.
I just started doing that this year.
Grow my own vegetables.
We'll have like a salad made out of her
own vegetables.
There's something cool about that.
There's something hunter gatherer that
just so and it's anybody and even in a
big city like this,
if you have one of those apartments that
has like a little bit of dirt near you,
you can make your own food.
Any any square,
five square feet of dirt near you and
you're in this community.
You can grow enough stuff that you can
get with your neighbors and the trade.
That's my ultimate goal.
Do the garlic and I'll do the potatoes
and tomatoes and then you're just
trading.
You're happy.
When I see a cue,
like do something crazy like start a
vineyard,
you know that that to me is far more
complicated than what I ever wanted to
accomplish,
but what I want to accomplish,
find a way to live sustainably of one
piece of land.
Whether it's a farm,
a small family farm or what,
you know,
livestock,
just as romantic as it sounds,
it's not necessarily that feasible.
I mean,
there was,
there was a lot of draw.
There's a lot of things that just,
you know,
nature will nature will school you,
it's,
it ends up really coming down to a
collaboration.
It really does come down to,
to not just hunter gatherer,
a cultivator,
but also community.
You have to kind of work together to
make any of that work.
And that's,
that's the reality.
There's a lot of people that have that
romantic notion of like,
I'm just going to go out to the woods
and just,
and just live off the land and you're
going to live a very short life.
That's where a cult comes in.
That's where the coal comes in.
So by the land.
Yeah.
So there's definitely,
it's definitely possible to do those
kinds of things.
But as far as quality of life and the
longevity,
longevity of life,
uh,
the collaboration ends up actually
fitting better that community,
that village ends up really,
really working hard to find that though,
isn't it?
It's hard to find some likeminded people
that you can enjoy it,
but it's already happening.
There's an entire,
there's entire,
even where we live in Arizona,
there's entire communities that have,
uh,
you know,
the garden garden communities and uh,
we're making pasta is now,
uh,
that are from 100 percent Arizona wheat
so we can grow wheat,
we make the flower and I can actually
make pastas for you to go with the wine,
which we also grow.
But the things we can't,
I don't have,
we don't make salt,
you know,
there's like spices you would like to
have and that kind of thing.
So it's ends up being your back to the
trading,
trading your.
Whereas with other communities and
that's great.
But then just all the nutrition that you
just get the basic,
a fulfillment of that homegrown stuff.
It resonates on a microfiber level in
your body for sure.
Yeah,
it's pretty bad ass.
And Arizona is a tricky place to because
you guys don't get a lot of rain.
We get a little bit of rain and uh,
it's a matter of.
Yeah,
making sure you're planting in the right
spot where the rain gets to
the cisterns.
Cisterns,
yeah.
Do you have water storage?
Carry the rain water and figure out a
way to move it.
Yeah.
It's um,
if you ever thought about living
somewhere where it rains a lot,
is that like a better option?
No,
I,
um,
I just loved the Arizona is just where
I'm supposed to be.
Just,
you know,
I grew up in Michigan,
so that's pretty moist and it's got
those mosquitoes and deer fly and the
humidity.
I just can't,
my body doesn't resonate in that place
and uh,
I just get attacked by every bug and
every creature known demand and in
places like Michigan in Seattle or
Washington state and all that,
but in an Arizona free and clear like
there's,
there are scorpions.
I see them now and then I've seen the
rattle snakes have none of that stuff.
Bugs me,
know that none of it goes after me.
My Dad lives in Michigan,
he's in Michigan,
like none of that stuff bugs him.
The deer fly the mosquitoes and stuff,
it just kind of like bounces off him.
It's fine.
Comes to Arizona,
immediately gets bit by a brown recluse
walloped by tiger.
Chased by a fuck
rattle snake.
You know,
like all this.
Arizona just went,
what are you doing here?
Get Out.
He got bit by a brown recluse.
That's no joke.
Yeah,
like a big hole in his leg.
Oh my God.
Yeah.
Have you seen that discussed?
There's nothing they found,
uh,
with uh,
Arizona is um,
a Jaguar's coming across from Mexico.
There's a,
there was a show called monster quest
where there were jaguars.
No,
no,
no.
The animal.
Yeah.
It's leopard in the Africa,
right?
Jaguar in South America.
I think.
So they've started to see Jaguars in,
uh,
in,
in Arizona.
Hunting.
Republicans are.
No,
no.
Yeah,
just after a pio,
they just,
after that Joe Arpaio Guy,
that's gotta be a weird thing
representing your state.
You know,
when you,
when you tell people you're from Arizona
and they go,
oh yeah,
that's that fucking guy that makes
people wear pink.
Yeah,
it's a,
it's a wonderful
state to live in because it's the last
state of the union where the 48 state,
so we're kind of the infants and we're
kind of the mavericks in a way.
So there's all this unresolved like
archaic shit that goes on there,
but there's all this amazing,
beautiful stuff as well that we actually
get to do because we're not kind of part
of the east coast.
Like this is how it's done.
We have been here for 200 years.
It's actually,
we're kind of still finding our way in a
way.
And so there's,
there's the good and the bad that goes
with that and there's probably a lot
more bad that always it.
But I don't,
I'm not exposed to it because I'm good
on that note.
Uh,
you know,
the wine industry in general is,
was met with like,
you know,
that's,
it's alcohol,
it's wine,
it's,
you know,
the religious right in the room,
in the conservative Republicans
initially were like,
what are you doing?
But now we've changed.
So we completely changed the
agricultural and economic landscape of
that state with what we're doing with
the vineyards to the point where the
governor,
God bless her,
has actually gone on record with the
municipalities and said,
support what he's doing,
get behind them.
That's how that's.
So to have a conservative person who was
like probably teetotal or anti alcohol,
all that kind of stuff.
Or have somebody like that who you
already know her story,
like to have them support.
What you're doing is you're.
We're definitely making a mark.
Interesting.
That's a beautiful thing.
If you're governor wasn't a fucking
moron.
That chick scary dumb.
She's.
So,
if you've ever seen some of the debates
with her holy Shit,
where they asked her questions and she
just locked up and just stopped talking
and you're like,
you're not allowed to do that.
Not a lot of stop talking and then she
still won.
Whatever that means.
Yeah.
She supports you.
The,
it's,
it's an amazing.
It's amazing thing to witness the kind
of the naysayers coming around to like,
you know,
having to like explain to them over and
over again.
There's like these small communities in
Europe that they weather whatever storm
you throw it out and they don't care
who's king or dictator frozen it.
Third small communities,
they're small community to grow their
own food and the and the cornerstone of
their,
of their economic stability is our
vineyards and you know,
something that takes dedication and time
and focus and commitment to a long term
thing and then everything around it can
then sustain itself based on that being
the hub.
Do you ever recognize how unique this is
for someone who has achieved your
position as a musician and you know,
has some,
has so much cultural influence to have
this sort of radical change and just go
off and start a vineyard and become a,
a small local business?
No aid.
The community like that.
I mean,
it's a really kind of an unusual
departure.
Well,
I mean it's only a departure if you're
only looking at the part of my life that
had to do with music.
If you're looking at the part of my life
that came before the music,
you know,
I was,
I was part of the military.
I was accepted to west point it become
an officer and I chose not to go to,
so to go into the arts.
Um,
so I was in some way already doing these
kinds of things in a way,
you know,
you got your military and you get your
politicians.
Um,
I was kind of part of that part of that
structure to begin with organized
sports,
military ballet.
So you've,
you've pocket pool,
you've managed to really be your own
unique individual.
You've really managed to not find a
pattern to fall into but rather fall
into the pattern that you felt
personally
drawn to kind of like,
again,
going back to just following your
intuition about what your decision.
I mean when you're standing there and
you're having to make a decision,
like when you received that appointment
in your hand going,
okay,
I'm going to be an officer,
I'm going to go to west point when I get
out.
I see.
I can see my future all the way to the,
to the end.
You know,
classmates of mine are now like kernels
in charge of several divisions in
Afghanistan.
So that would be,
that would be what I'd be doing right
now.
I mean,
you know,
I can't say that for sure because I'm
not nearly the day dedicated soldier
that those guys are and that kind of
vision.
But as far as that part of that
corporation,
that part of that company,
that's what I was what I was,
that's my path was laid out in front of
me.
So to see that and go,
I can be a part of that whole thing or I
can follow this feeling in my stomach
right now and go,
I think I'm going to go to art school.
So to actually make that decision and
have all your friends and your family
kind of go,
what the fuck did you just do?
And that was long before you'd ever
heard about me and to know that that's
what I was supposed to do.
And to follow that against anybody
else's advice.
Um,
you know,
that's,
that's a strong,
a strong statement when it comes to
following one's intuition,
do you realize how inspirational that
is?
I mean to,
to a guy like me or two,
especially two guys coming up that may,
you know,
or,
or they have a vision,
they have an idea and they see someone
like you that they admire,
that has done that and really has so
obviously carved out the life that they
really wanted to live based on their
intuition,
based on their idea which so few people
ever actually do.
We recognize that influence me because
that's a,
that's a huge thing for folks.
Yeah,
always.
It's always going to come down to what
you,
what you were going to decide for you.
Uh,
it's Kinda hard to.
I had a,
my old,
uh,
back in,
Michigan.
I went to a church.
I did go to a church that's,
I might disappoint you,
but uh,
she had up.
I went to a few,
a minister,
a pastor,
I should say.
Uh,
and the only reason I went to this place
because the guy made this guy made
sense.
Super Low key,
awesome speaker.
He told stories,
had no judgment.
I mean,
you know,
there's one point I was having problems
and you know,
people or thought that it was way too
into kiss and Alice Cooper wanted to get
to talk to the preacher and he called me
in the Avi and I kind of went into his
place and he went,
he shut the door and go,
so tell me all about this band.
I was like,
I can eat freely and as a small look,
and he just listened to all of that
stuff.
Then he started kissing,
you know,
can you do,
can you say that with your pants off or
nothing like that.
And it was nothing.
He was just into like,
so what is it about this that like
resonates with you?
What is it?
What is it that inspires you about it?
And I was like telling me stories.
He goes,
I'm a storyteller.
I like that you'd like to tell stories.
You should tell him more stories.
And I started writing poetry.
I started writing stuff based on that
conversation with him.
So you know,
out of that.
And they used to tell the story that I
thought was very pertinent,
you know,
you'd go off to camp and you'd have some
experience there and you come back and
uh,
whatever you experienced out there,
whatever,
whatever camp that was you went to
metaphorically and you come back to the
general populous,
it's you.
He would always tell the story about
Moses coming down from the mountain and
having his mountain top experience and
then coming back down to the rat race to
where people,
he's a changed person.
There's something different in his eyes
and he's watching everything that's
happening and there's no possible way he
will ever be able to like explain to his
people that he sees daily what the fuck
happened because they didn't happen to
them.
It happened to him.
He saw it and it just has to kind of,
you know,
his life on that and not be disappointed
in his,
in his friends and family and his
community because they didn't see it.
So it's not,
it's not their fault.
They didn't,
they didn't experience that.
But he has to like not.
He has to kind of understand that a,
everybody has to go through that
themselves if they're going to go
through it.
Like the other thing we talked about
with kids going into the military and
having that like that moment where
you're on your own,
you know,
you stick your hand in the jar with the
ants and you know,
that kind of thing.
You're talking about that coming
becoming an adult,
a Houston.
He would tell that story and it was very
important,
very important lesson for me to go,
okay,
you're on your own with these decisions.
You kind of have to have these things
and not everybody's going to get it,
so don't worry about everybody getting
it.
Just as long as folks though to have
that sort of confidence to branch out
independently on their own with the
vision that are terrifying.
It's terrifying,
but that's the only way you really.
Yeah.
You can find your own path.
That's so hard for people to accept and
so on.
It's not what people want to hear.
They,
they,
you know,
it seems.
It's so terrifying to be completely
independent of all the people around you
giving you other advice,
but
so I want to do it and if you see it,
you know that's,
that's how,
that's how things happen.
You see something that's not being done
or you see something that's your you
want to have happen.
If it's not happening,
go do it.
It's got to.
You got to be honest with yourself as
well to it.
You have to actually know what you
really truly want.
A lot of people will talk themselves
into things that they want because
there's maybe security in it or they
could see a connect the dots future.
But Dude,
thank you very much for coming on this
podcast and been amazing.
It's a.
you've got an awesome story,
man.
You're a bad motherfucker and you've
done a lot of cool shit and it was
really fun.
We enjoyed it.
Thank you for having me.
I'm really sorry about Brian.
Wrong with.
Sorry.
I was nervous around him.
It's natural.
Sure.
I will wear pants next time if you ever
come back.
That
was.
That was kind of awkward,
but like I got over it.
Oh,
thanks for the wine.
The wine is fantastic.
People want to get a hold of it.
It's just you have to caduceus and the
other one,
American vineyard market vineyards and
they can get them at most fine wine show
available online.
Uh,
yeah.
we have a website,
a Vino dot [inaudible] dot org.
We're going to start taking preorders
but no problem living in Arizona is we
can't ship during the summer at all.
It just gets too hot and everything that
we ship goes through Phoenix and sits on
a hot truck at 100,
10 degrees overnight.
So a kinship there and you have to wait
till October to ship stuff.
Oh Wow.
But we have some sort.
How does that work?
We had some pretty awesome stuff coming
out on,
you know,
going to be available to the first week
of August for release in October.
Awesome.
So,
uh,
that's when people.
Is there a stuff available now or is it
you have such limited amounts that
places like silver lake wine or mission
wines or Kennel wine merchants to a lot
of those guys have stuff that we've
distributed and across around the
country at 10,
you know,
we're only in a very,
just a handful of states.
We just.
Our production is so low.
Again,
people want what they want,
but when it comes to the wine,
there's only so much that's going to
come off this site and we have very
limited amounts and it's a very special
thing,
so we're not gonna.
We can't even if I wanted to increase
the production on some of these things,
we're just never gonna have enough to
just basically be in every grocery store
around the country.
It's pretty obvious that you take great
pride and satisfaction in your work.
I mean,
when you're talking about your one,
you have a certain feeling about you,
like this is something you're really
happy with.
Yeah.
It's a,
it's a,
it's a very fulfilling endeavor.
It's a,
it's a,
it's an art form that's like no other
and it's kind of connected.
Grapes are a very special being.
They're special.
We have some website.
I really enjoyed this podcast very much.
Thank you very much for all this and
thanks everybody for tuning in.
Thanks to a alienware MMA for sponsoring
all of these different fighters,
follow alien ware,
mma on twitter,
and that stay hooked us up with this bad
ass laptop and Brian's as well.
Thanks to on.com,
O n n I t,
makers of Alpha brain,
new mood,
shroom,
tech,
sport,
true tech,
immune and bone strong.
That's bone supplements,
son,
you need to get your bones strong.
Get yourself some kettle bells and
battle ropes.
Use a codename Brogan.
Save 10 percent of any and all
supplements coming soon.
We get that hemp protein.
Shit's coming out soon.
Dvds instructionals on how to lift
weights and get all fucking manly and
swole.
All that's coming.
Thank you to James Maynard.
James Keenan,
getting him on twitter pacifier plus
suffer,
suffer.
And my direct one is the Mj Keenan.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Everybody we will see you next week with
Tito Ortiz.
Oh,
Tuesday.
Yes.
And uh,
we also have Tom Rhodes,
my friend.
Great.
Tom Rhodes
comedian week on Thursday.
So we'll see you guys next week.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
See you tonight.
Oh.