I'm a psychoanalytic thinker.
And what that means is that I believe
that people are collections of some
personalities and that those
subpersonalities are alive.
They're not machines.
They're there.
They have their viewpoint,
they have their wants,
they have their perceptions,
they have their arguments,
they have their emotions,
they're,
they're like low resolution
representations of you.
You know,
when you get angry,
it's like,
it's a very low resolution
representation of you.
It only wants rage or it only want
something to eat or only once,
only once water only wants sex.
It's,
it's,
it's you,
but shrunken,
focused in a specific direction.
And,
and those,
all those motivational systems are very,
very ancient,
very archaic and very,
very powerful.
And they you up determining role in the
manner in which we manifest ourselves.
As Freud pointed out with the kid,
we have to figure out how to take all
those underlying animalistic motivations
and emotions and civilize them in some
way so that we can all live in this same
general territory without
tearing each other to shreds,
which is maybe the default position
of both chimpanzee and humanity.
So,
so I take that seriously.
The idea that we're a loose collection
of spirits and that that that,
that you know what it says in the Old
Testament somewhere that the fear of God
is the beginning of wisdom and
I think this is akin to that.
If you know that you're not in control
of yourself thoroughly and that there are
other factors behind the scenes,
like the Greeks thought that human
beings where the play things of the gods,
that's the way they
conceptualize the world.
They sort of meant the same thing.
They meant that there are these
great forces that that move us,
that we don't create that were,
that were,
that were subordinate to in some sense,
not entirely,
but we could be subordinate to
them and they move our destinies.
That was the Greek view,
and there's something indeed it,
it teaches you humility
to understand that,
that,
that there's a hell of a lot more
going on behind the scenes and you're,
you're the driver of a
very complex vehicle,
but you don't understand
the vehicle very well.
And it's got its own motivations and
methods and sometimes you think it's doing
something and it's doing
something completely,
completely different.
You see that in psychotherapy
all the time because you know,
you help someone unwind a pattern of
behavior that they've manifested forever.
First of all,
they describe it,
then they become aware of it.
Then maybe they start to
see what the cause is.
They had no idea why they
were acting like that.
You know,
they have to have the memory that produced
the behavioral pattern to begin with.
It has to be brought back to mind and
then it has to be analyzed and assessed
and then they have to think
about a different way of acting.
And it's extraordinarily complex.