Nodoz
motherfucker,
my voice is froggy to like get them.
Thank you for.
I gotta go tenor.
Okay,
good tenor.
Thank you for having me.
We were talking about opera before we
started the podcast and that I was
saying that those people are like
aliens,
like what they can do with their voice
is so far beyond.
I kinda like I could look at someone
doing a backhand spring and I was like,
okay,
I bet if I practiced for a long time I'd
figured out how to do that.
I would need some help but it takes some
time but that doesn't seem
insurmountable,
but what I hear,
yeah,
I hear these fucking dudes or
I can't imagine it.
That has to start with some kind of
natural gift.
I guess it's maybe it's just like
getting them when they're really young
and then developing those muscle ups
talking totally out of my ass.
But you know who used to opera saying
Jim Jefferies did really.
Jim Jefferies was like a legit opera
singer apparently that crazy.
I know Jim very well.
I'm surprised I didn't know that at all.
I didn't either thing he told me on the
podcast,
I thought it was coke guy.
Got a family?
No,
he's a general.
He used to sing opera and uh,
apparently he had like,
what was it,
like nodes on his throat that he had
gift cert polyps.
Polyps.
So you had to get surgery on his throat.
A gym.
If I'm fucking this up,
I apologize.
But uh,
he had to get surgery in his throne and
killed his singing short is opera
career.
Well,
I don't know if he really wanted a
career in it and who's doing some acting
stuff and shit too.
I mean he's a guy like,
you know,
he's like this,
he's,
he's at his best doing stand up.
Everybody wants to chase other shit on
top of the stand up.
Sure.
But when it comes down to it,
like the standup is the most fun,
it's always going to be the most fun,
you know that.
And I do think radio in a capacity as.
Oh yeah,
there were similar,
like a similar beast.
Well,
what this is cool is like it allows
someone who's not near us to have a good
time talking to a guy like,
you know what I mean?
It's like,
no,
absolutely it does.
It brings people in.
You know,
your is great.
I think.
I think it feeds the same beast as
comedy.
It's also when you're live it's like
immediate reactions to like as soon as
you're done you check social media or
anything and people like the feedback is
immediate.
Just like when you're on stage,
you know?
Yeah,
there's definitely that.
Definitely that aspect of it.
But it's also cool aspect because it
allows people to kind of work out ideas,
workout ideas in the sort of open forum,
you know,
talk about stuff and it's.
So.
There's so many different places that
people don't do that though.
They really just stick to the 25 minutes
they were so on and just do forever.
Yeah.
Well as far as standups.
Yeah,
that's brutal.
I mean that used to go across the board.
I was such a fan of comedy growing up,
but I remember like you'd see people in
like five,
six TV shows and you're like,
Holy Shit.
Like I know their act.
Yeah.
That was a problem in the early days,
right before the early to mid.
Like I guess like all through the
eighties.
I think in a weird way,
def jam really did like make comedy,
have to step his game up across the
board,
not as a comedy on that was always that
great.
But I mean like it brought it back until
like,
you can't just be like,
you know,
standing there with your blazer sleeves
rolled up and,
you know what I mean.
You might have to like just show a
different version of comedy act.
Really attacking the people with it,
doing comedy at people.
Yeah.
There's a few examples of that,
right?
Like,
Kennison was definitely an example of
that.
Kennison came out.
I remember,
um,
I've probably have told this story.
I apologize.
Have you heard anybody listening?
But,
uh,
I found out about Kennison through a
girl that worked with.
I was 19.
I was working at the Boston athletic
clubs,
like this little health club and that
was a teaching people how to lift
weights and shit.
And uh,
this girl who worked at the front desk
was hilarious.
She was just like big volleyball check.
She was like six feet tall but fucking
hilarious.
She was like,
she had gotten into standup.
This girl was really funny and she was a
fan of standup and she knew that I was a
fan of standup too.
So she told me about this guy who was
doing this bit about these dead people
getting fucked in the ass.
She said,
she said his name is Sam kinison and how
she did the bit she laid on the Sam
candidate had an all time classic bit
and it was about a homosexual.
Necrophilia acts was about gay guys are
paying to fuck dead bodies and she did
the bit in the parking lot of the
athletic club.
She got down on her stomach and she was
like,
oh,
life keeps fucking in the ass even after
you're dead.
It never ends.
And she made me laugh so hard that I
couldn't imagine what this guy was like.
So he was like a mythical creature by
the time I saw him on a vhs tape,
I got a hold of a vhs tape.
He wasn't even like,
I don't even think blockbuster was
around then it was like this little mom
and pop places or places that had a name
that I don't even remember.
I got a vhs tape of Sam Kennison and I
remember going,
Holy Shit.
Like,
this is comedy too.
Yeah.
Whoa.
He was.
So yeah,
for me that that person was dice.
I always say he was the guy where I was
like,
oh,
this is.
I loved stand up comedy and like this is
a different thing.
It's funny,
my dice is,
you got to watch him age from like a
young guy to like where he is now.
We lost Sam Kinison so young,
but he always looked 40.
Like Sam kinison never looked here.
You always have like a 40 year old,
like your uncle who will come over.
But his star appearances were like
legendary.
Well he was.
He just went for a man who was such a
pioneer.
It's,
it's hard to imagine,
but all guys like us,
like those guys,
if it wasn't for them,
we will be so far behind as far as like
what we can and can't say what we can
and can't get away with what,
what is and isn't taboo and what,
what and also the,
the,
the recognition that when someone's
saying something fucked up like that,
he's,
he's doing it for humor.
That's it.
It's no different than someone making a
movie about someone shooting people.
They're not actually killing people.
Like it's not like the intent behind it.
Intent behind it is humor and
entertainment,
which people do have to get a grip on
better.
But I also think that like,
even like that def jam version of comedy
should pay more homage,
I think to like Sam kinison dice very
much because that was like,
to my knowledge,
we're the first braggadocious comedy.
Most comedies brooded in such like self
deprecation with dice,
but Sam kinison till was never a belly.
He never talked about being like a big
fat guy or it was always outward.
Yeah,
I know,
I know the answers and you idiots got to
listen to me and dice was more of like,
you know,
how great he is and everything,
but that is like,
that's the,
I think the main difference between like
that black circuit comedy and like the
mainstream circuit because the
mainstream circuit is not white comedy,
but the black circuit comedy is its own
kind of beast and that still has all
the,
you know,
I got a big old Dick and I'd be choking
the bitches with it because one bitch
last night and you're like,
wow,
who are you relating to?
All these black people in the room.
Well it was also the rap culture,
which is very braggadocious as well,
you know?
Sure,
yeah.
There's like a bunch of things going on,
a bunch of different elements,
but for sure just as the art form for
the art form as a whole dice is super
important and kinison and super
important.
Yeah.
Because both those guys came out with
like really controversial acts.
There was a lot of blowback,
there was a lot of like a.
and if you could listen to some of the
stuff like that era,
like some of the stuff in the eighties,
it's really homophobic.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
Like in a mean,
nasty way,
which is where I always seen it for
sure.
Yeah.
But we don't do gay jokes like that
anymore.
Like gay jokes today or like it's kind
of a geek.
It's,
it's sort of wrapped around the idea
that you could completely accept someone
being gay,
but it doesn't make it not funny if a
dude is sucking the dude's Dick.
No.
Yeah,
exactly.
Funny Concept.
Yeah.
No,
without a doubt.
I think people are coming.
I think we're actually leveling out
where now the pc police are running
rampant of course funding.
But they are funny.
But they really,
uh,
the best point is like the person.
You're joking,
supposedly offending rarely offended
that person.
Right.
It's always a white college girl who
wants to like write a blog.
Yeah.
Well that,
it's also the choosing to be offended
recreationally.
You know,
that this is something that's a hot
topic.
So you know,
this big Jay Oakerson guy eats.
I'm going to take him down a peg.
I keep after him.
I can't fucking believe.
I've never had blowback at all.
I'm just probably.
My name's not out there enough,
I guess,
but there's comics like a little lower
down the totem pole than me.
They just happened to be performing at a
night where there was a blog writer and
that goes viral and that becomes a whole
thing.
But,
um,
I've never,
I've had some like viciously offensive
jokes,
but I think that,
um,
again,
there is,
there is a weird x factor to comedy.
I've talked about this recently too.
It really is.
I've got on stage and said horribly
heinous things,
right?
There's somebody who just got oozing.
All is like the most benign jokes,
like the crowds too much.
I've said terrible things and those same
people are laughing.
It's just like,
it's a lot of that is a process.
Not even talent.
I'm talking about very talented guys
getting a weird reaction for something
not dirty or offensive at all.
It's just,
there's a,
some people when you get on stage,
there is an organic thing where you
don't like Kurt Metzger,
who's brilliant,
brilliant comic.
Like I honor his jokes are the testament
to how good his jokes are is that he
kills because they don't like him when
he gets on stage,
like right away he just like,
whatever it is,
they just don't want to like um,
a Mike Vecchio is on the great comic but
looks like a state trooper,
you know?
So when he gets on stage,
I think people are kind of like,
who's this asshole?
For some reason I think when I get on
stage people are like,
oh,
I want to like this guy.
I think it's like my game to lose
almost.
Well that's an intangible.
It's something you could learn going.
You're an easy going looking guy.
He looks like you're a guy that be fun
to hang around with,
you know?
Yeah.
People actually think I'm much more
liberal than I even am with certain
things.
Oh really?
I mean I'm liberal overall,
but I mean like,
I'm not like I think people will be
like,
I've had a lot of people might just pull
out coke in front of you start doing
coke and I still get like a man that's
drugs.
That's why we get a reaction like that.
That's not a liberal thing though.
Right.
That's just A.
I'm just saying,
I think people just think that I'm much
more like,
you know,
that I am and I'm really like a,
well you wouldn't be getting anything
done.
Yeah.
You know,
that's the problem when you're doing as
many gigs as you're doing and then
you're doing legion of skanks and you
know,
you just recorded a comedy central
special.
If you were really just doing blow all
the time,
none of that shit would get done.
But so many people have done blow all
through.
I mean I don't think Kennison ever
stopped and he's got a couple of
specials.
Well,
he supposedly did for a while and then
they tested him when he was dead and he
had coconut system and they'd said he'd
done some coke when he got married
because he had apparently just got
married.
Yeah,
I think that's the story,
but the story was they tested him and he
had.
He had done some.
Dice is super straight always right?
Yup.
Pretty much.
He likes edible marijuana now.
Helps them go to sleep.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
No,
I know.
Yeah,
I know he's like a weed guy,
but I local guy dices a new dice though
that's almost like now.
I mean when he was like the height of
like,
you know,
the John Travolta hair and the whole
thing like that was a,
I think it was super straight.
Yep.
Just smoke cigarettes.
That's it.
Yeah.
And then for awhile he used to take a
cigarette on stage with them and not
smoke it,
you.
And then he said fuck it.
And went right back on stage.
At one point he just let it one day.
I think so,
yeah.
I think it happened at the store.
Ms Dot [inaudible].
I still oddly just have never met him.
Oh really?
Yeah.
That if
I just say that's like my comedy hero in
so many ways.
Oh Man.
I had just assumed that you knew him
because you were at the store all the
time.
Dude.
Fuck,
you're leaving tonight.
Yeah.
Uh,
well I would love.
I would love to set that meeting.
It was funny when a Ari was at my house,
here's my house for Thanksgiving,
like maybes last Thanksgiving and made a
bunch of people were smoking weed in my
bedroom and including him.
Everyone that was there was like eight
people in a circle and he gets a phone
call and everyone's kind of in their own
conversations,
you know,
two people at a time and he answers his
phone and he goes,
oh,
hey,
dice and I ever.
No one is paying attention,
but I'm like,
wow,
that's crazy.
He's like,
yeah,
dice.
Okay.
Like almost like annoyed by it,
right?
Or whatever it is.
So I start just doing a dice impressions
like about Thanksgiving.
Oh Hey,
are you having enough fucking Turkey?
He'll con and a good goddamn do it all
day.
That's really good.
Um,
Gary
and uh,
no one's laughing.
I keep doing it.
Then people start making weird faces at
me and then hours later we're just kinda
sitting around and I go,
that's so crazy.
That dice just calls you already.
And so everyone was like,
dice called you and I'm like,
did you guys just think I was just doing
weird dyson pray?
That's what I was looking at me.
Weird.
They just didn't know that.
Always on the phone with them.
So they started broke into like loud,
obnoxious,
like interrupting conversations.
Do your act.
Hey everyone.
Troy a Turducken you'll fuck.
Have you ever done them on stage?
Dice?
You do.
You should do dice on.
Um,
I think,
but maybe I can pass it,
but I fuck it up.
Yeah.
I love the easiest thing to do.
It was,
it was the bonding of me and my
stepfather when I was like 12 years old.
He let me watch,
uh,
the one he did the Tla dice man cometh.
Wow.
And I just thought it was like I went to
school the next day and I was so much
funnier because I was just regurgitating
like his shit,
like saying what he said.
I just thought it was the greatest thing
ever.
Then we just had tapes made its way
around all my friends
of his first cassette and I listened to
it in the car with this girl I was
dating and we were fucking howling,
howling,
laughing.
I couldn't believe how funny it was.
And so like to be friends with them now
and hang out.
So surreal
still knows the uh,
he so good.
There's so many different levels of
standup,
you know,
like have the skill of it.
I mean,
and he's so good at the comedy of words.
That's what I've tried to learn from
him.
Just picking the right word.
Like the one who got me on this last
thing was just like,
I heard a lot of the jokes already that
he did,
but like,
and then he just goes in,
this chick's down their club or in your
balls.
Clobbering such a great word to pick
their.
Well he is also,
he's deiced too,
so it's like you come to the show
wanting that.
Yeah,
I mean it's its own thing.
It becomes a,
like Mitch Hedberg was sort of like
Mitch Hedberg had a special thing like
you would,
you would hear his jokes and coming
from him like you couldn't imagine them
coming from anybody else coming from
him.
They were hilarious and that's sort of
the same with dice.
Like anybody else that would say that
you'd be like,
what?
When he says that it's just,
he's just got that thing down and you
know what that thing is when you go to
see him.
I think every special starts with the
formula of like,
so I'm doing this thing with some chick
in a place where it shouldn't be
happening at a time.
That's weird.
So everything starts off.
It goes,
you know?
So I cut the throat fucking this broad
because you know what it's like when
you're a board in Anaheim at Burger King
on Valentine's Day.
A tag on like another like,
but it's just like I want to hear every
one of them.
Yeah.
And you look forward to it like it's a.
and here's the thing about Ford.
Fairlane was great.
I loved Ford Fairlane.
I don't remember it honestly.
But here's the thing about dice that's
like about his act as opposed to
everybody else's act.
You want to know the jokes and you
repeat them like with those nursery
rhymes.
He Ha.
He tapped into some weird rock and roll
thing where people would come to the
show.
What's in the
fucking place?
Inter rubbed.
It was like killing the harder.
You couldn't kill any harder and it,
it,
uh,
it gives you the thing where it's like
where you say it's rock and roll was in
Rockford.
Nobody wants to go hear the band.
You love through the new songs.
They want him to do the jokes.
They know.
Yeah,
exactly.
If a band has a new science,
the trust sneaking in between hits
people like,
Oh,
what is this?
I still get excited when I listened to
dice rules ever because that was the
second big specialty garden.
And he goes,
you guys studied and learned the poems?
He was.
But I wrote some new poems and it's
like,
it's like 20 years ago now,
you know what I mean?
So it's like,
here's the new poems.
It's like,
I thought these are still the old poems,
but they're so.
They're so bad day.
The laughter died is so brilliant.
Oh,
the data left who died,
if you've never heard it,
folks,
one of the best comedy cds ever,
and one of the most like revealing of
what a real comedy show can be like.
It's so great.
It just has to go on spotify and listen
to the track and our back.
That's one of the funniest things I've
ever fucking heard in my life.
He,
um,
he went to,
I actually had a cool opportunity to
speak to Tony,
who's the owner of danger fields.
It was rod these partner and that's
where he did it.
He said dice came in on a Tuesday at the
sun or the older Tony?
Older Tony.
Oh yeah.
He told me that.
I'm totally cool with Andy Kaufman story
too.
That was never a fan of his.
But it's pretty funny story.
But uh,
he said dice wanted to come in on a
Tuesday,
no announcement,
whoever's there,
like late night on a Tuesday and just
recorded an album.
And they said,
yeah,
they didn't make any announcement.
He came and he said it was like,
I think the biggest,
he said it was like 20 some and the
lowest it was 18 people and he
just went in there and started like
talking shit to them and they were not
interested.
They didn't know he was coming.
He just bullied
crowd.
He just,
and he just makes up a phrase an hour
back.
He goes,
I'll give you an hour,
an hour back.
And then he just keeps going,
get it.
He says,
get it like 50 times the thing.
And then he goes,
you don't even know what you laughing
at.
He says to them,
they're stupid for laughing at like,
you know,
they're not laughing all those jokes.
And he just keeps borrowing this thing
into their head and they start laughing.
Well,
you should point out to the,
at the time he was selling out arenas.
Oh yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So dice is such a maniac.
He makes this album when he's selling
out Madison Square Garden,
he's selling out the Nassau Coliseum.
He's selling out gi and places like I
think to this day it's like Kevin Hart
and him.
I like the biggest.
As far as like the most successful John
Kevin Hart's done like 60,000 seat
places and say yet.
I mean he's,
he's,
well,
what's the new trailer?
Philly?
It was like $60,000 of travel
now.
What's next?
It's insane.
I mean,
he's a insane.
Literally.
And I said I think I toys for his phone
bill or electric bill.
One point was in my name because he was
so like he asked me if I could put it my
name.
They we're going to turn the electricity
off.
Wow.
Back in Philly.
That's crazy.
Holy Shit.
Yeah.
Like nuts where he's at now.
Wow,
that's crazy.
It's great.
My Mom's still has no scope of that at
all.
Sugar out in La.
She goes,
tell Kevin we said how I'm like,
I'm probably going to see him.
He's probably in Bulgaria doing a
fucking covered by bodyguards via riding
a wave of diamonds,
wearing his own sneakers.
I had a genuine a bum out,
like I felt bad about it too,
and it was before I was having a rough
go.
I was headlining the Sacramento Improv
or punchlines Sacramento punchline,
which I love that club and I was
headlining it and I felt pretty good
about headlining it.
I'm like,
you know,
seven show week or whatever it is,
but I'm like,
this is great.
I'm headlining the punchline.
Sacramento.
Kevin was in town doing the Arco arena
where the Sacramento Kings play.
Oh my God.
He goes,
hey man,
come to the hotel and hang out.
I go,
absolutely,
and I go to the hotel were outside for
30 seconds,
but I get the hotel.
He's coming out of like the hotel gym.
It's like around the corner and I meet
him and we're walking to the hotel and
this 100 foot walk car stopped.
People pour out of buildings.
People start yelling and screaming.
He turns around and gives him one way.
If we go into the hotel,
we go up to his suite.
That is amazing.
It's got a whole bunch of his boys
there.
They're playing a xbox three 60 time it
was,
and he goes,
you want to watch the,
um,
used to watch the intro for my special,
right.
It was not.
This one's out now,
the one before where he's got the
pyrotechnics going off.
He's like,
yeah,
we got pyro and it's going off.
He's showing me this crazy,
like insane trailer for it that's just
like mind blowing.
And I was feeling so good
about,
oh,
I'm sorry.
I should preface this story by saying,
um,
when I was talking to the cab driver
bringing me to calves hotel,
he was like,
what are you going from a hotel to a
hotel for?
And I go out,
you want to hear the story is pretty.
I said Kevin Hart's here and um,
uh,
he's all buddy of mine,
so I'm gonna go hang out with him.
He's a gaggle.
Yeah,
I'm in town.
I'm a comedian too.
I'm playing the punchline.
And he goes,
oh,
that's amazing man,
because can I get tickets?
And I was like,
yeah,
I could like put you on the list for
some tickets if you want to show you
when it comes to shows and there's
somebody goes to shows at the argo
arena.
And I was like,
oh no.
He goes,
Oh,
I'm sorry man.
I thought he said I want to take it to
Kevin Hart show.
I was like,
okay.
He asking you for Kevin Hart's tickets.
So that's how that starts.
That's how this thing starts.
And he gives me his card,
this cab driver,
he goes,
call me when you're done because I'll be
right in the area.
Okay.
I go up.
So kept showing me the pyrotechnics.
Yeah.
Do you want lobster?
We're all getting lobsters and shit and
I'm not even exaggerating.
It's like this Kinda hang and I'm like,
this is fucking crazy.
And uh,
and his buddies are all playing the xbox
and I said try to find some sign of like
old Kevin there,
you know what I mean?
Not,
not that he's,
he hasn't,
just personalities,
not shitty or anything,
just like,
you know,
connect on some level of what our
friendship is.
I'm like,
you still bring your xbox everywhere
highs.
I still do that too.
I pack it up in a like Schlep it with me
everywhere I go so I could do something
during the day and he goes,
oh no man,
because every time we land we sent a guy
out to buy an xbox for the day and then
we leave it for the maids.
And I was like,
I gotta go.
I left like in a weird short amount of
time and the guy picked me up in the cab
and we're driving back to my hotel and
he's me this question like,
how was it man?
How was it was fine.
I'm like,
I,
I wasn't that in when like a contest to
meet.
I'm like,
I know.
He's like,
Oh man,
he's so funny.
That's great by the way,
because I feel like a dick.
I'm,
I'd love to.
If the offers still up,
I'd love to come to one year shows this
weekend.
I go,
yeah man,
absolutely.
Let me know.
He's like,
my wife would love it,
man.
He goes,
I'll bring her out because I looked
really cool.
I'll be like,
hey,
I know the comedian stuff and I'll be
like,
yeah man,
whatever you want.
So it's just a before get out of the
car,
just tell me what show would show you
want to go to and we pull up to the
hotel but you know,
it's kind of a quiet 15 minutes ride and
I'm getting ready to go.
So hey buddy,
what's your name?
So I'll put you in for tickets.
He goes,
honestly man,
I'm not going to come.
Why do you keep building me up to hurt
my feelings?
Let them fuck them going out of his way.
Yeah.
That was the saddest.
Like,
and I was headlining the punchline.
I was excited and I was.
And then all of a sudden I was like,
Jesus man,
I either call like I've made phone calls
back home,
like why am I so like just fucking
awfully green with envy.
I
just showed it all over my ass in that
room.
You just,
first of all that cab driver wasn't
helping anything that kind of put you in
a weird state of mind.
He was an idiot.
So you went,
you went to Kevin's place,
you were driven around by an idiot and
you're going to see the most successful
comedian of all time.
Who is your friend who you helped with?
His electrical bill and you get in there
and they're thrown away x box.
I got to assume you're a high as fuck,
right?
Will you hide when you went over there?
I maybe had to be there.
Those guys aren't really doing anything
like that.
But you probably did before you went
over there for sure.
Right?
I know I would.
Yeah.
That scared the fuck out of me to ranch.
I got to get away from him.
So I just had a meltdown.
I'm like,
hi.
They go,
well,
you know,
he's.
I don't understand how a guy like that
couldn't work as much as he does.
Being meaning,
I don't know.
Not that I don't understand that these,
that ambitious.
I don't understand where the time comes
from.
Several is several movies I think still
coming out.
Well it's a,
it's also stand up and it's also.
I mean he's just on top of it.
Social media is social media is like a
business to him.
It's a really interesting guy,
man.
Like super,
super awesome.
Well,
the new,
uh,
the new trailer for the,
for the new special says he goes,
uh,
comedies first ever.
Mogul gas sort of.
I guess so.
I mean for sure.
Well,
whatever.
Who gives a fuck about first ever this
or that he's about to say.
But what other comedian was a mogul you
think was a real,
like Jerry Seinfeld running a bit.
The,
the branch.
I mean,
Kim's got sneakers.
Does he?
He's got Nike sneakers.
Yeah.
Oh Wow.
Yeah,
I would assume.
I would say he's the first.
Well,
he's first of all the quickest ascent of
stardom.
If you look at him like to where he's
at,
where he's at.
I mean there's.
So it's me and him,
it's almost 18 years.
How long has he been famous for?
Ten years.
Household.
He's been known from about,
without exaggeration,
five years in [inaudible].
He was working like a lot,
but he didn't even,
he didn't even move to New York.
Me and him and Keith Robinson would go
up to New York every day and uh,
he never had to move to New York.
He jumped right.
He got the Montreal festival,
got a pilot with Judd apatow and moved
to La.
It was like overnight where he was in
the business working,
making money,
you know,
surviving.
Well,
I'm sure there were peaks and valleys in
that,
but I mean,
I remember I did a show he hosted like
beatty's one mic stands,
like a comic view season.
He hosted that,
you know,
at that point I'd say he was still like
famous,
like in the black community.
He did,
um,
soul plane and all that stuff.
But I'd say like a household name maybe
like six or seven years now.
But I mean,
so think about that international world,
famous gun from,
but six or seven years to like these
50,000,
60,000 seat arena.
That's incredible.
Isn't a um,
I wonder if he had any doubt in his mind
that data,
they would fill that fucking room
eagle,
the Eagle stadium,
but he's from philly and everybody knew
it was like a big event.
Yeah.
You know,
I think uh,
I think he knows what he's doing.
Obviously it worked,
right.
But I mean he's got,
he's got the production things where he
produces specials for other people.
That's great and all that shit.
So I don't know where a guy like that
has that kind of time.
So it seems,
seems like I know how much I work and
I'm like,
God,
this guy works like twice as much as me.
How's it going know where you find the
time to do this podcast?
I mean really it's like,
it feels like you're running around for
UFC a ton and then it would have up.
Yeah.
But the standup,
is it night podcasts during the day?
I don't have a real job.
The UFC stuff like the stuff in studio
where I do like countdown shows and
stuff like that.
That's the only like once a month,
the events,
they're not that often,
twice a month,
three times a month at the maximum.
Then there's stand up in between.
So it's not that hard.
It's just appears harder than it is.
It appears like there's more going on in
there,
but you know.
But if you're doing a television show or
even more so if you're doing a movie,
you're fucking gone for 16 hours a day
here.
Committed,
you know that that is the big.
The big trap is the movie trap.
I mean it's awesome if you want to make
a shit ton of money,
but it is not nearly as fun as doing
standup.
There's,
I mean I think it be fun.
Yeah.
I think.
I think in general,
I don't know,
it was never a reason why I got into
comedy,
which just takes too much time.
But the hold I did a scene a,
me and Doug Benson and Louis j Gomez did
a scene together for Jim Gaffigan show
we,
it was a 15 second dream sequence he
has.
And if we were there,
I mean just the 15 second scenes.
So they shot it even like eight times.
How much filming that is.
We were there for like nine hours,
nine hours that day.
Didn't do a thing.
Got there at like 4:30 in the afternoon,
didn't do a thing until 8:30.
And you're just like,
I don't understand the point of that.
The laziest I ever got with my standup
was when I was doing news radio because
I was,
when we first started out we were um,
there was a lot of struggles in the
beginning and when a show is trying to
find its legs,
you know,
writing wise and story wise and the
networks notes versus the producer's
notes and all that shit has to get
worked out.
We were doing like 12,
13 hour days.
There were long ass days and everybody
was exhausted and I would just do no
stand up or if I did something I would
do like a spot on the weekend and I
wasn't writing at all because I was
never going up.
I did a show for two seasons on IFC
channel and it was so like I was still
no,
not established enough in my mind in the
clubs in New York that I would like
really it was a killing myself.
It was bad for her.
Like I was still doing standup and I
wouldn't go onto comedy central tool.
That was back when the show is ran on
the weekdays to like three in the
morning.
So I'd be getting home at like 3:30 in
the morning and like sleeping til 5:30
in the morning going right to set.
Oh I didn't do it every night I try to
pace it like to be every other night.
So one that I'd go home and I'd fall
asleep like right after filming which
could be like 7:00 at night,
you know,
and just pass out for the night.
So I try to pace it but I couldn't walk
away from it enough.
I just feel like especially in New York
and they really let you feel like
there's someone waiting to take your
spot in a heartbeat.
And there is.
And there are three comics thanked me
for being on the road so much now
because it clears up some of the
weekends.
But you know what I mean.
I,
I get that.
What was the show that you were doing?
It's called Xerox on the IFC channel.
It was fun.
It was a,
we,
they kind of let me have the reins as
far as like kind of telling them like
what comics,
like stamps,
we should have like guest star on it.
But what was the premise?
It was about a band called [inaudible].
They were a real band at the time.
They,
um,
it's just their story.
They played like they try to become rock
stars at night,
but during the day they would play kid's
parties,
like kids' birthday parties,
which is a.
So it was like a sitcom.
Yeah,
it was a half hour show,
but it was a,
what are they called?
Like the single cameras,
you know,
whatever.
Like Marin.
Yeah.
And it was um,
it was fun because it was curb your
enthusiasm style,
scripted outline only.
Oh,
you can just make up your own lives.
And they had a bunch of Maitland
caplets.
Patrice was on a few episodes.
Geraldo got on a few episodes a why
didn't get them all?
I mean,
but he was on a few episodes.
I'm Geoff Ralston and episode Kurt
Metzger rallies.
It was,
it was pretty crazy.
So tell,
uh,
tell.
Acting is fucking so great and I
couldn't make up his own lines to.
Can People Watch those now?
The other one.
Amazon.
What's again?
Xerox.
It was fun show.
It was just,
it was,
it was a little ambitious too.
Like I said before,
these guys were mostly read at the
director of production team is mostly
reality show guys.
He,
you would think that doing a show like
that with a bunch of comics completely
ad Lib style curby enthusiasm style is a
great idea.
You know what guys like Joey Diaz or it
did well in the show actually did very
well.
It just like it was arguments between
the production and the uh,
network.
Yeah.
See it's always that way,
man.
It's everything I've ever done that's on
television.
There's been some arguments between the
production and the network and it's
always weird shit later.
Like why can't we have coke cans sitting
facing camera on the show and was like,
when I was on news radio is infuriating
because you would watch these guys come
up with these ideas about like we're
going to bring in a love interest who
want to do this and that,
and the writers would get so pissed off
to be like,
look,
this is a really good show.
The,
the fucking problem is you guys keep
moving it from time slot to time slot,
but then the network is like,
no,
we're going to do this or we're going to
do that and we're going to bring a hot
girl and we're going to bring in a hot
guy and we're going to.
It was just so goofy,
so goofy to watch all these different
people battle in a lot of the people
that are putting in the input.
They're not professional creative
people.
They're executives.
Yep.
And then they have to take those notes.
Seriously.
I,
uh,
I used to get a note a bunch better,
a pilot that I wrote my stop pitching it
even because it was just getting so
frustrated with my.
We definitely wrote like a funny thing
right here,
me and to me and Lewis and Dave actually
we wrote a funny thing that can be maybe
stretched to movie length or a pilot.
I liked it as a pilot.
It was something to live in a world of
like true stories that I have.
Cause I said I used to do a job ironic
with the xerox story,
but a real job where I drove strippers,
escorts around at night to gigs and then
during the day the same company was I'd
go dressed as like elmo to a kid's
birthday party,
so it existed in that world.
We were a really funny thing and then
they just start saying things like
having a strong female lead.
I'm like,
just fucking funny.
I promise you there's women in the show.
What about diversity?
Big J.
just like.
Yeah,
it's like one of the friends black or
something.
The most important thing right now.
Big So ridiculous.
Every body has to be completely and
unique.
Yeah.
If it's a black show,
you have to have a wacky way.
You.
Yeah.
It's.
Those kinds of conversations are very
weird because there's nothing wrong with
having a strong female lead,
if that's what you wrote.
Yeah.
Whoever the person is,
it's writing it or the group of people.
You got to leave them to their own
creative visions.
As soon as you start saying,
you know,
let's have a black guy do this,
so let's make this a Chinese lady like
stop.
If you have a really funny person,
like leading the charge,
like a comic who was like,
you wrote something and they have a
picture in their head.
That's kind of the confidence I've tried
to build and stand up.
Like I feel like if I say it like I'm
trying.
I'm trying to make myself laugh first
and foremost.
So if I say it,
I think it's funny.
I believe it's funny,
right?
I believe that I just like didn't convey
it to you the right way.
You know,
you didn't get it fully or you're being
tight.
Asked about some other reason.
You know what I mean?
So it's like that.
But they don't put that kind of faith
like the networks never put that kind of
faith in the complicated gill.
If you make my vision with how I've seen
this in my head,
if you give me the tools to create it
the way I see my head,
it will be funny.
I think with day worry about is the
consequences of anything that you might
do that could fuck their career up.
Absolutely.
Green light a show and you go off the
deep end with something completely
ridiculous.
It makes social justice warrior news,
but you're one.
Yeah,
but I mean,
you know,
you like,
you know something's good fast.
I'm talking about just someone who's
particularly me out of the picture.
Just if you trust and someone that's
genuinely funny,
right?
If you let Dave attell make,
given the endless funds to make whatever
his vision is,
it's going to be funny.
Well,
that's what Louie did.
Yes.
Right.
That's his show was exactly
that.
That's why he directs it,
produces it and everything.
He was editing it all on his fucking
laptop in the beginning.
I don't know if he kept doing it that
way,
but she's as Christ,
but that's why it was so good.
I mean it's,
it's a single vision.
It's from his mind and so like the dice
thing,
louise got the Louis thing and you know
what to expect when you go into watch
the Louis thing,
so it makes it even more funny.
He knows exactly how to do it and when
you watch that show that's like,
it's so clear that that's right out of
his mind.
It's his perfect presentation of what
his thing is,
but that's never.
That's such a rare story.
Super Rare.
It's super rare,
but that's why television is not going
to make it.
It's just not going to make it.
If it keeps going this way,
it's just the only people that are doing
it.
Right.
Like comedy central.
Take some crazy fucking chances.
They take crazy chances with their
roasts.
I was at a roast battle last night.
They took grazie chances with that.
I mean that is a raw buck wild comedy
clubs show.
Yeah.
No Shit.
And comedy central apparently is going
to air it.
I was downstairs last night from that
night,
so I heard all the chaos.
It was madness.
Fun though.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Earl Skakel crushed when it gets Jesse
Joyce.
Dude,
he crushed as hard as a person can
crush.
Really?
A person can't crush any harder.
He hit every note.
It was like it was scripted.
Oh my God.
And then there was adlibs that were
perfect to.
It was.
It was madness.
He didn't have a shirt on.
He threw water all over his head and
threw the water under the crowd.
Silver pants on the triple h entrance
was the.
He had a fur coat.
You tell me a fur coat on with no shirt
and a silver pants.
Oh.
And he did it.
He did it.
Uh,
what I judged a few weeks ago,
he came out and did the trip go triple h
entrance.
He came out and like ran to the audience
and climate on tables and water and
threw it in the audience.
Madman.
He's a fucking madman.
And so he'd beat up on Jesse Joyce,
who has to help me write jokes for at
midnight tonight.
Well,
just joyce is really funny.
Jesse crushed him out of the box.
The first one was brutal.
Who is a joke about him opening up for
Rob Schneider,
but then earl just opened them up and
fucked his mouth.
He just,
I'll just,
I'll just smashed him.
It was crazy.
It was so much fun though.
It was Dane Cook,
Bobby Lee,
me and Jimmy Kimmel was there too.
He didn't judge,
but he was like in.
They gave him a microphone and Jeff Ross
running the whole thing and Brian Moses,
who the perfect host for that thing.
God Damn,
that's a good show.
So she could show me grow waves.
Hilarious.
Good.
So good.
Everything about that show.
It's the.
It's the most wild show in all of La
because there's a version of New York
caught a roastmaster is at Lewis hosts
and it's.
It's like sanctions sanctions.
Wrong word,
but like Jeff Ross signs off on that one
and they run it in like New York for
some reason.
Some great rose,
some great writing,
like amazing actual battles talent wise.
But it is missing that thing that like
the,
you know,
just the insanity,
the noises.
I mean they have a Dj and he does his
thing,
but you know what I mean,
like that room,
it's like,
it's like A.
Yeah,
if you guys know for sure.
But it's also like everyone,
everyone's just so in tune with it.
Like it's not talking about that last
night,
like,
uh,
when was it,
I forget who it was with somebody.
Somebody crushed so hard that I was Jeff
Ross and I were clinging to each other.
We're clinging to each other because the
joke was so fucking brutal.
I don't want to butcher the joke.
The suicide job.
It was so goddamn brutal.
We were like hanging on to each other.
Like this is the only sort of
environment where that would be even
justified because everybody's completely
smushed in there.
The belly room at the comedy store is
only supposed to seat 70 people.
They get 100 in their shoes and
everybody's smashed in like this.
And when everybody is smashed in,
like this is.
So there's doors,
there's four different ways to get out.
So it's not like a trapped,
because like literally four different
exits to Rome,
it's an easy room to get out of.
So it's not dangerous,
but it's so intimate that when people
laugh and they'd go,
oh,
like the people behind you a high,
everyone's high fiving,
everybody all squished in together.
People like slapping people in the head
and then when they're doing it in New
York,
it's going to be the grammercy theater,
which is not intimate.
Oh,
he can't do that all.
Yeah.
I'm curious to see how that goes.
You can't do that.
That's Jeff's doing that.
Jeff's version of it.
Oh,
why didn't they do know the one in New
York,
the show they do.
The biweekly show is actually is at the
stand.
That's actually a good room for that.
So yeah,
it's really small.
But the one and uh,
but the one for tv they're doing at the
gramercy theater and that's.
They always wanted to do.
They always want to take something
that's awesome when it's intimate and
move it into a big giant place.
The seller would be great for it.
But uh,
or even like they have the,
a room or in the corner now to village
underground.
Yeah.
Oh,
I saw a video of you from there.
Yeah,
that's great.
That looks like a very cool role and a
good size stage to walk around on.
It's very wide and long and they
basically recreated the cellar down
there,
but it's just a bigger room.
Wow.
It's like 200 people maybe.
Oh,
that's cool.
And that's the same people.
Same.
Our new one called the comedy cellar
still.
Oh no shit.
That's awesome man.
I gotta check that.
I don't want to get back there.
That stage looked amazing.
Like the setup of perfect.
Oh,
it tells you.
Is it for several things.
Used it for his hotels underground show.
No Shit.
And I think you'd use it now for a new
thing he's doing.
That's awesome.
Bobby Kelly did a special there,
I think.
I think he did.
Yeah,
I think you're right.
it gets used.
It's great.
I got to check it out.
Check it out through their live podcasts
there.
Oh,
they do?
Yeah.
I didn't know they did it live.
They just did one recently.
It was there,
been so stressed for a show in life.
They had four girl calm.
I don't like turning over control.
I like having control in the comedic
situations and uh,
we performed five minutes.
It was like five or six,
six of us.
And then for girl comics,
like just straight off your comedy,
would they fuck you or not?
Like they,
they,
you know,
with,
with comments about it.
And I was like,
I hated it.
I was,
I did well.
I did fine,
but it was like A.
I'm actually hasn't worked out good for
me really.
But like going into it,
I was like,
I did not like that.
I haven't felt that in a while where
it's at now.
I guess every night we're being judged,
but like you do stand behind your wall
of comedy.
This just seems like they're going to
tell me if they'd fucked me or not.
Like no matter what my comedy was on
pure looks,
you know,
it's interesting.
That wouldn't be something that you
could do with a woman.
Hell No.
That was the joke of it,
I think.
Yeah.
No,
you'd be there.
Your blogs would be rolling.
Yeah.
That's acknowledging that there's some
sort of an imbalance in their approach.
They.
It's not that they don't want you to
insult them and be sexist.
They just,
they want the exclusive right to do
that.
And when I say they,
I mean only people that think that way.
I mean you if you don't think that way,
but a lot of people that think that's so
cool.
It's cool as shit on a guy and and knock
you down by your looks and your five
minutes of material.
If a woman did that,
like if you had a woman get on stage and
tell a joke and a bunch of guys like you
and me,
we're sitting around deciding whether or
not we would fuck this girl based on how
funny her jokes were.
There'll be brutal show.
Oh yeah.
Well it's funny that the nerves have a
show like that.
Is that like if it got into some kind of
like,
you know,
wit battle.
Not that they wouldn't say funny things
are shit on me in a funny way.
I just feel like I could probably be
meaner
and probably make them more upset than
they can make me.
Well,
you also have a lot more experience.
More like what would that kind of thing,
but just,
you know,
I mean just,
but you should always just kind of like,
you know,
what it gets to the core of like,
uh,
making a woman pretty upset if you want
to go for it.
Yeah.
And they with us also,
but I'm just saying for some reason like
were just a little thing.
Not always,
but I feel like just a little thicker
skin.
So just having the kind of take
whatever.
And there was the comments like,
but it was a fun show the other day,
but I don't want to take the show down
at all.
I love rich and body.
But um,
there's comments that are like,
you know,
the backhanded like,
and I,
you know,
I've,
uh,
I've fucked a few like,
you know,
fact guys before,
so I could probably,
you know,
it was like,
that doesn't bother me at all.
So you're like,
right.
You know what I mean?
Like that feeling,
you're like,
oh right.
And it's like if I said anything
remotely like that,
yeah.
Any of them.
Like they'd actually might be a phone
call later,
you know what I mean?
Like,
Hey,
what would you.
It would be an issue for sure.
I mean I guess we could take it better.
That's why,
that's why it's okay.
It's sort of like implied that their
sensitivity is a bit more delicate.
Yeah.
Ends.
So you could take it looked at.
I got four would fuck me.
It's.
Thank God.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
That's beautiful.
But um,
but it's weird that pumps me up.
But the thing is if it,
if it goes bad,
like I said,
that's why the,
the,
the lack of control I meant was that
like almost I have to keep my own
control myself and you're like I don't
want this to get where I don't have the
crowd that turn because then I'm just
going to be mean to these four girl
comics,
you know?
And then it's going to be,
it's just going to get ugly and I think
are actually fighting.
He actually got a weird,
was one of the judges,
I mean it wasn't like super bad,
but like she added the gates was going
to say no because like they just had
such a weird back and forth.
Oh,
they knew each other already.
Oh yeah.
We knew all.
I knew all four girls but have been
again,
even though I know them,
it's just a still a thing.
Like you can't cross a certain line,
you know what I mean?
Like there's certain things you can't
say.
Yeah.
Well that's one of the weird things
about roast battles in general,
but at least with rose petals are doing
it back and forth to each other.
This seems like you have to do your
standup and then they shit on you.
Right?
You really,
you really can't ship back too much.
That's the problem.
I mean not as bad as you would.
I guess what I'm saying.
You always have to be like Kinda like
keep control over yourself.
Made a good point in that it's a
controlled environment.
Like,
so kate,
like what you do,
they set up these artificial time limits
and rules.
Right.
The artificial thing being not by
artificial,
but you know,
they just decided five minutes stand up
and then the girls get to decide and
then they talk like this is the rules
for the game and they set up but well,
what is that then?
Because really what you would do is you
would just play it out as long as it's
entertaining and if you were just going
to play it out as long as it's
entertaining and give you a microphone
and give her a microphone.
Well they did.
They did.
I mean I had a microphone for sure.
I had listened to.
There's options there to just haul if,
if they,
if they shit on you,
you could definitely haul off on them.
I'm just saying it's a position where
it's like it's almost asking for you to
get made fun of and then you're just
kinda like,
well alright.
But I really can't make fun of them back
the way I would make fun of them.
Yeah.
Well I dunno.
I guess I could do it,
but I'm just kinda like these four girls
who were like,
you know,
quote unquote friends for the most,
some of them closer than others,
but you're like,
I don't want them to be all upset them.
They'll say whatever they want to be and
I'll let it roll off and who gives a
shit,
you know,
if it stings for a second,
it stings.
But like these are phone calls later,
you know what I mean?
Where it's like,
Hey,
well why would you bring that up?
That the thing you know about me?
I'm like,
I don't know.
I thought we were swinging for the
fences.
Yeah,
man.
I don't know.
It's just a,
it's a game.
You know,
you're playing a game and it's a fun
game,
you know,
that's what it is.
But it's,
it is,
it is kind of weird that you could never
do it with a bunch of men judging women.
No,
no,
no.
It will be.
I mean,
you could,
you probably could do it 50 years ago if
he,
if he could probably do it today.
You know,
you know that Mike favor man story,
right?
If you flip that story around just the
guy girl roles in that one that goes
like it goes nowhere.
Nobody gives a fuck.
I don't give a shit.
No one gives a fuck.
Girls could,
you know,
um,
girls can make fun of a lot of things
about a guy and it's totally different
than the guy doing it about a girl.
I've got all my newest.
A few jokes since special are rooted in
respect.
Like women,
like I said,
I,
I'm all,
I'm so pro women as far as the equal
pay.
And I said everything that they want to
possibly do in the world,
achieve all your goals.
Just like a dude,
I don't care.
But like manhood is being stripped down
big time.
I mean,
like I said,
the example I use,
it all came up from a speaking to my
girlfriend and my buddy about UFC.
It was a conversation with the three of
us.
I never knew.
My chick thought this way.
She goes,
I'm doing,
but the UFC guys house together.
They did that whole documentary about
the domestic abuse problems running
through now and my girlfriend goes,
oh,
I would never want to date a guy like
that.
Like if he could just like,
lose control,
like he just beat the shit out of you
and it's like I could beat the shit out
of you.
Control.
Do you,
are you,
do you think that I can't do that?
Like why would you say that to me in
front of the friendly.
Of course they can beat the shit out of
you.
I just don't do this.
Like she thinks she's at.
She would have a shot.
Yeah,
I think there really isn't going to
affect.
Oh,
just dumb guys.
You know,
Reagan used to have that great fucking
joke by the commercials,
you know?
And then the guy's like stuck in the
mini blinds.
Like how do you work this crazy thing?
It's like,
my husband's so stupid.
That's why I have pop tarts.
Joker ethic isn't like you really think
that manhood is being torn down though?
I think uh,
yeah,
I think masculinity is like attacked
more than anything.
Probably.
I think it's attack,
but I don't think it's effective.
I think that I don't think it's having
an effect on whether or not things are
still masculine.
It's real problematic for two reasons.
One,
because it's okay to be really feminine,
so if it's okay to be really feminine,
why is it not okay to be masculine?
Like there's a big difference between
being masculine and being rude,
being mean,
being homophobic,
but they are.
They shouldn't be.
No,
they shouldn't,
but I'm saying,
but they are in that regard,
so that's what I'm saying though.
It's like being pretty and feminine
doesn't mean you're a cunt who stuck up.
Sure.
Those get lumped together too sometimes
too,
but that's just dummies and it's the
same dummies that are attacking
masculinity for just being masculine.
Like here's one of the.
This is this crazy fucking phrase that
these dummies like to throw around
lately.
Regressive left.
People like to throw around this phrase,
toxic masculinity and they're blaming
toxic masculinity on this guy.
Shooting up that gay crowd in Orlando.
This was this article and they were
using the term toxic masculinity.
That's first of all,
that's not real.
There's no,
there's no amount of being masculine
makes you toxic.
Yeah.
Okay.
And there's nothing.
If you're a shitty,
nasty person has nothing to do with
masculinity.
If you're an evil person,
obviously it happens at mass shooters
are almost exclusively men.
Yeah.
But that's not toxic masculinity.
That's a fucking psychopath.
That's what that is.
It has nothing to do with masculine or
feminine.
It's not gender determined.
That guy was already chemically off and
then he was like a,
you know,
a repressed homosexual by all accounts.
Yeah.
So it's like you can't.
Yeah,
that's not,
that's nothing to do with masculinity.
So was the guy,
they call it la apparently the guy that
they caught in la who had one of his way
to the explosives.
Yeah,
an arsenal in his car.
They caught him on his way to the gay
pride parade.
Apparently he is allegedly bisexual as
well.
I think there's a pride parade,
crazy fucks out there in this world and
to start breaking it down by gender or
masculinity and femininity,
it smacks to me of like some sort of
ulterior motive.
And I always feel like the ulterior
motive when you see these guys were
writing these articles,
they're weak people,
they're not,
they're not like powerful forces of
genetics.
They're weak people and I think a lot of
times weak people they want in some way
or another to even the playing field in
one way to do that is by pulling down
examples of masculinity that they can't
possibly approach.
Well there's,
yeah,
there's a type of guy.
Exactly who stands behind the feminist
issues,
like really like vehemently like
bitching at some guy.
Exactly.
It's called virtue signaling.
Somebody gets that man.
If you like it,
you know,
a joke or something that you say were
you included were like,
oh these dinky broads over here.
And they go broads really brilliant.
Like dude,
like,
come on,
fuck off.
Yeah,
just get Outta here.
I know what you're doing there.
Just the virtue signaling phrase that
Michael Shermer uses is a great one.
He's got this interesting point of view
on.
It is like what they're doing is they're
just trying to let everybody know that
there are more ethical than you.
They're more moral than you.
They're a better person than you look at
me.
Look at me.
Yeah,
exactly.
It turns it on there.
They're just looking for.
Even if they don't even,
they probably don't even know whether or
not it makes sense.
They just know that it's an effective
stance to take to look like a super
progressive person.
So you just go after it.
You go after the hardest levels of it.
Yeah.
There's a lot of people like that.
These days they're doing that.
It's because of social media.
It's given morons and opportunity to
blurt out and to get reactions from
their blurt outs,
even if they haven't really thought them
through and they're almost always
exclusively insulting and mean and
nasty.
So these people that are trying to
proclaim their virtue,
they can't even like argue a point while
being just a decent human being.
You can't even like say what you feel
about something without being some sort
of an insulting,
like nasty,
condescending,
defining that.
Define you like big Jay.
You're a sexist piece of shit.
Like Tj,
I said the same thing where it's like,
you know,
clap for handicapped people.
Well,
you know what?
I mean like it's the same like,
uh,
you're supposed to feel a certain way
about something and it's always attacked
like whatever it is.
It's what you're saying,
right?
He's like,
am I getting that wrong?
No,
I think we're both too high for this
conversation,
but I know what I'm saying.
Just it's,
there's,
there's some sort of like dishonest
communication that's happening with some
of this.
I think a lot of the outreach is not
real.
I think what a lot of it is they're
acting outraged because they know they
can.
Of course it's not balanced and it's
also what I'm saying is it's really
shitty and insulting.
Like when you get to a point of view on
something and there'll be really shitty
and insulting about you and your point
of view,
like an intelligent rational person
that's examining the thoughts and words
of someone that they're not involved in
a conversation where they come to you
and say like only a racist would say
something like that.
They define you and some sort of a weird
way.
If you have a point of view that they
feel like they can attack or you start
with that one,
I'd say if you say a a bad neighborhood
or even black people know you're talking
about a black neighborhood,
that's a racist to say it's like as
black people,
if that's a racist thing,
it's just kind of a thing,
but it's that.
It's never.
I've never been called racist or or
massages.
Massages.
I've been called by a woman before but
never been called racist by any one of
color of any sort.
Well,
congratulations on that as well.
So you've got four flux use.
You're not a racist.
That's beautiful.
Oh No,
but I'm saying I've been called.
I've had people get really upset with
like racist jokes or anything.
They've deemed racist.
Right.
It's always like a white paper.
It's like the same point,
dude.
Yeah,
yeah.
Or,
or,
or a woman with a guy behind them going
like,
yeah,
Kurt Metzger gets into those things all
the time.
Was a guy behind him,
but backing up some stupid point I,
I get,
I got a bunch of shit for coming against
the naked shows.
They do comedy shows.
What?
Naked shows they do these naked comedy
shows in New York sometimes.
Yeah.
The whole audience is naked.
No,
just the comics.
Uh,
what the fuck I'm doing this.
We're doing this thing,
this weekend's Skank fest for two days
for Legion of skanks and at the creek
and the cave in Long Island city and
we're having a,
a naked roast battle.
I see the novelty in it.
I argued with a girl comic who's talking
about like,
this is about getting over things and
you know,
there's this artistic back to it.
I go,
whatever you say,
I'm just telling you.
Every guy goes there to see pussy.
And she's at her argument was just like,
no,
like people want to see like,
you know,
the social experiment of it and see what
I go.
I'm going to look at Pussy and I'm
telling you that I am Joe average in my
thoughts.
Like I am common guy,
but she'll run into a guy who argue
against that,
but I don't go there for personalities.
I like to hear these people talk.
So she came on our podcast with a dude
who would.
Yeah,
just say the whole thing goes.
No Man.
It's about like,
you know,
getting over fears and Cochran like more
just so excited to be with a girl like
backstage with a girl and everyone's
sitting there with your Dick and pussies
out.
Yup.
We used,
me and Kurt used to do a Gig in
affiliate was where you could do comedy
once in a while at a burlesque place
called the five spot for less like a
leg.
They did dancing with their clothes on.
They get down to the pastries and
everything and the and the goofy
outfits.
But me and Kurt would do this once a
month.
We'd be like,
do comedy on that show.
In between.
The first time we did it,
we were bags and we were blown away
because it's.
You never do it.
Well,
they go,
don't be weird.
Backstage dogs.
He knows the theater technically.
So the girls are running around naked
know they're changing so they're just
naked a lot and sometimes they would
just sit around naked smoking cigarettes
back there,
butt naked,
sitting down and chairs.
Pussy all mashed up and me
and me and I shouldn't even care throw
curtains under the bus like this.
I'll speak for myself only.
I was just staring at tits and pussies
nonstop.
I just,
I'll speak for Kurt when he was doing as
well.
I was staring at him and then the next
week and the next time he came in,
the next month it was a.
There was like they put partitions up
for the girls and I'm like,
yeah,
but I'm not gonna.
Pretend that I wasn't back there to look
above what you want me to force myself
to look into your eyes if you're that
comfortable being naked and be
comfortable with me staring at you.
Buzzy.
That's what I'm saying.
Yeah.
That's be a t shirt.
It should.
It should,
because it's about to go to a nude beach
and look at it as like for me and Jeff
Ross were in Australia and we were just
staring at the topless girls on the
beach and they go,
well,
they go,
that's,
it's very common here to do that.
So it's not a big deal.
I'm like,
well,
it's not coming from me and we're going
to stare at this girl's tits for awhile.
Like I think it's fucking great.
She has them out.
Who gives a shit?
But you would you stare at someone if
they had clothes on?
No,
and I don't stare in a sense the same
way.
Yes.
If a girl was wearing jeans that a great
ass and I like moments to take,
you know,
to pick,
to look at her ass shit.
If she knew that you were staring at,
you know,
where you avert your gaze.
I never thought that.
Uh,
yeah,
I would.
I've never thought,
uh,
I was being like the girls who had their
pussies that I think they think like
thought that I was staring at them.
I was trying to be as tactful as
possible.
You being slick,
but I was constantly looking and enough
so that like I couldn't be slick enough,
I guess that they figured it out.
Well,
if you just have like a,
a quick scan of the room,
that's one thing.
But if you keep looking in the general
direction of naked people,
even if you looking over their shoulder,
they're going to know what you're doing.
Oh yeah.
But I've been that like I was that
little fat John Candy Creep from splash.
Remember when John Candy was a kid,
like dropping the quarters to look up
skirts and shit.
I don't remember that.
That was his big thing to draw who
dropped by quarters and then go down and
look up scrutinized clash with Tom Hanks
and what's her name?
Daryl Hannah.
Damn.
I never,
uh,
I never did like a obnoxious,
like look up a girl's skirt,
like getting on the ground or pick
something up.
But like if I'd go to like a,
like a rock concert when I was younger
and there's,
you know,
on the lawn and there's a girl sitting
like very purposefully,
like,
you know,
she's naked or body painted.
And her pussies out.
Same thing,
like a posture up at a place where I
could check her pussy,
eating her pussy out.
Like someone opened the door,
let a cat out
out,
close the gate,
pushing a out.
It sounds like it's a trap.
Shit pussies out.
It's wandered around the neighborhood.
But you have a girl just comes to body
painted naked.
Like yeah,
I'll get in a position now where I can
check it out.
Of course you should.
And so you should.
And that's part of the game of being
outside naked.
They want you to see it just part of the
way you are.
But someones watching you watch that and
go on like a piece of shit up
objectifying.
That's what I'm saying.
I'll come to that and you're like,
no man,
I'm just being honest.
Some girls but some men will do that.
But those men are almost entirely week.
All of them.
Yeah.
This wise,
mind wise,
there's just.
Yeah,
well they're the ones you find out
there's like,
you know,
pedophile porn on their computers at one
point when they die or they're just
socially retarded and they just don't
know how to communicate with girls and
this is the,
by being incredibly virtuous,
they've picked up this extra personality
trait that they think's gonna ask them
over the top and whenever you're looking
to find,
I think the connection to fund with a
woman when you do that,
you're not going to find,
you're not going to find it.
She did not gonna you're not gonna find
that or you're like,
you know,
repressing something yourself because
there really is like the,
at the end of the day,
like most women,
I've never speak for all of them.
Do one a man.
Yeah.
And most men want a woman.
But yeah,
I mean,
you know what I mean?
A manly man in whatever way.
I'm not like a handy guide necessarily,
but like my girlfriend feels like secure
with,
you know what I mean?
Like I'm a guy with a wild run away from
her.
If we get held up or something,
you know,
I don't try to fight for myself or like
she feels like secure with me in several
ways.
My manhood is in whatever ways they are.
Have there been like,
I can't fix cars.
I don't know how to do any of that shit.
You know what I mean?
The problem isn't that there's men and
then there's weak people and that
there's inbetween.
There's women and weak women and strong
women.
The problem is when people lash out
against one group that has nothing to do
with something that happened in the
news,
like if you talk about masculinity,
toxic masculinity in this fucking
assassination,
that guy was mentally unbalanced,
crazy,
fuck,
tormented.
Evil,
sociopath,
psychopath would,
whichever you want you want to call it,
who did a heinous thing has nothing to
do with masculine or feminine.
It's just a stupid argument,
and just to start that,
to start that conversation conversation,
you're like,
you're separating the teams.
You're making the left and the right.
You're making the cowboys versus the
raiders.
You're doing something there.
You're,
you're,
you're establishing boundaries.
It's just people that suck.
That's the problem.
This world has nothing to do with
gender,
nothing to do with sexual orientation,
and as soon as you make it,
those things,
you confuse the fuck out of the whole
argument because if you can't make fun
of any women or you can't talk shit
about any women,
well then you're admitting that women
are weaker.
Just like if I can make fun of men,
but I can't make fun of women.
If I make fun of women,
I'm going to massage this.
If I make fun of men too,
I hate myself.
Like how does that work?
It doesn't work,
but that's,
you know,
you gotta speak to her old friend Jamie
Kilstein about those subjects.
That's what he means.
Well,
I do too,
but I'm like,
he seems like a different human being
than the one that I knew.
You know,
over a decade ago,
people change big j.
They sure do.
They eat a lot of granola.
Alfalfa.
So bizarre.
Yeah.
Listen man,
it's exactly what we're talking about.
It's,
you know,
they just see people go too far,
sometimes the ideas because there's
nothing wrong with being gay.
There's nothing wrong with being
straight.
There's nothing wrong with being a
woman.
There's nothing wrong with being a man.
The problem is when people are shitty to
each other,
that's all it is.
That's the only problem.
It has nothing to do with anything else.
So the.
There is definitely a problem when it
comes to mass shooters being all men.
Yeah.
That's probably looking at what the
fuck's going on there,
but don't just jump,
don't just jump and assume and Delta put
it out on the other $150 million men
that live in the country.
That is the dumbest fucking percentage
point ever.
Mass shooters and the rest of the men
motherfucker come.
Yeah,
but.
But they'll jump on this thing,
man.
People jump on this gender thing and
they jump on you,
which you got as a religious idea.
Logically poison psychopath.
That's what you got.
That's interesting.
Ted Talk Right now.
I did not.
His Dad says some things where he was
like,
you know,
was like,
I'm,
I'm appalled at what my son's done.
Like God will work out the gaze himself.
You see,
he comes from like,
you know,
it doesn't always start,
you know?
Yeah.
With the fucking story.
I wonder when they a autopsy that guy
will ever have.
I'm still waiting to find that.
I always heard Charles Whitman,
right?
He was the guy who climbed the tower and
started shooting people in Austin.
Yeah.
Um,
they said if he was a like all tops,
if we have the same like science,
like now that we had that back,
if we had the same science then we have
now they would have found out he had a,
a temporal lobe
tumor that was pushing on it.
So he was,
he woke up,
he would have been found guilty of
something,
obviously murdered people.
But like I wonder how that would've gone
legally because he woke up not his
fault.
Pure rage.
Like he killed his dog.
I think he killed his,
his own girlfriend or something.
He killed,
I think,
people on the way to the tower,
just like everyone.
He kind of came across,
he just did something to him killed.
So it's like,
they're like,
he might not be found guilty,
sentenced to life in jail anymore,
or something like that.
I would've always wondered for something
like that there because man,
pulling a trigger on people's.
I mean,
you're,
you're just at a totally different.
I couldn't even wrap my brain around
what that is that can make you do that,
you know,
the columbine kids and everything.
You're like,
it's not,
I don't want to get in the same kind of
Bill Maher trouble where he said,
look,
you know,
that 9:11 suicide bombers are cowards.
You know,
you've got a lot of trouble for that.
But I,
I,
I think I got what he was saying where
I'm still kinda like,
man,
that's it.
Fuck it.
It's really,
I think seeing somebody get shot with
like affect me for a long,
long couch.
The wrong wing allowed to fucking coward
is the wrong word.
Being being,
uh,
having the ability to go and just like
spray down a bunch of people,
but it's fucking like,
it's an intense thing to dive in.
Oh,
it's a foolish thing to call them
cowards because I think when you,
whenever you call a murderer cowards,
you,
you like set your,
your looked challenging.
The manhood of other murderers.
Yeah.
Really.
You know what I mean?
Like you're calling me coward.
Oh No,
I take five.
You want to the other one up.
You after you insult them.
Comic Little Dicks after they do
something.
Yeah.
You feel better with your little Dick
now tick thing.
Oh my God.
You know,
it's just.
This may be the shooter had a little
Dick.
Like,
whoa.
Really?
I've read that on twitter.
Men like a little Dick thing.
Yeah.
Coward.
So psycho.
Yeah.
Coward is the wrong word.
They're evil.
That takes a lot of balls to fly a
fucking plane right into a building.
Like,
you know,
it's over.
Oh my God.
But you're definitely,
you're going sideways to your banking
hard into the building.
Oh,
let's watch it.
Let's watch a real quick video just to
freak me out.
I'm freaking out right now.
I'm thinking it's going in the building.
I'd say it's too tough.
The beginning of,
uh,
most of most of that footage.
The underneath one.
Oh,
you just see the building swallow it.
Yeah.
It's fucking bonkers.
I remember watching it on tv that
morning
just watching the plane hit the building
over and over and over again.
Just going,
wow,
how am I even seeing this?
Is this even really?
Am I seeing this?
The second one was one of the most like
tense moments I've ever had in my life
where I was just like,
wait,
because that's when you knew right away
you're like,
oh shit,
this isn't an accident.
Yeah.
Because the first one they were still
kinda like,
there must be some kind of radar issues.
There's still a hell of a radar issue.
They flew to fucking planes filled with
people in the buildings.
That is one of the craziest moments in
human history.
And it happened during our lives and
then after they did it,
we imploded the building with our seven.
Look at this.
Boom.
That is so crazy.
Oh my goodness.
Scale,
scale.
It's like so far away because it's so
high up that you can't like how big that
was.
The people in that bill.
You know what I'm saying?
Like the actual,
like six.
You know what I mean?
The situation that seems
like it's so,
you know,
just like finger lengths away from him.
He said,
but I mean like it how huge a fucking
jet play on the floor,
on the floor of a building.
This.
We're looking at the video of the tower.
The second plane crashed the World Trade
Center from the,
uh,
from the ground looking up.
It's insane.
It's still insane.
It's still hard to believe,
man.
Still hard to believe.
Yeah.
This 15 years.
It really,
it still is that,
that was in our lifetime in New York
City.
That the thing about those,
that,
that's,
it's so.
There's so much scary going on,
right?
Because there's the scary of someone
that has the conviction of fly a plane
right into a building that's fucking
scary.
There's the scary that they will take
hundreds of innocent people with them.
That's scary.
There's a scared they're going to fly
into a building they know is going to
kill random people with kids,
with moms,
with Dads,
with best friends with,
you know.
Yeah.
They don't give a fuck.
They're going to fly right into that and
kill all those people.
And then the damage to the building of
course was killed.
Who knows how many people.
But the whole thing is just bananas and
will never have.
I mean,
you know,
give them a turn to debone it.
Well,
but I don't know how much that,
if it could ever happen at gathering,
people will never.
If you jumped up on a plane,
I think now to say,
hey everyone,
I like to say I'm going to propose to my
wife like,
hey everyone out before someone's going
to fucking mall like the temple you.
I'm taking it out.
Somebody told me to look up
how many pictures there are people like
hog tied on planes,
a lot of pictures of that because like
they just freaked out on a plate and get
tied up because people get so nervous
now.
Yeah.
And rightly so.
My I am,
I am surprised at the amount of people I
will say who got hurt and killed in
Orlando because I'm surprised there
wasn't like this.
A lot of people in tight quarters may
think he just got swarmed at some point.
Yeah.
I don't know what happened.
I don't know where he was.
He might've had a vantage point where he
could shoot.
Nobody could get behind them.
Might,
you know,
he might have scattered some people
really quick and they might have done a
lot of the damage themselves.
I've fallen on top of each other.
You got to realize that a gun like that
you could squeeze off 50 rounds in
seconds.
So he killed 50 people and wounded 50
more or something along those lines.
I mean like that.
Just go like that with your finger.
Go.
Don't,
don't,
don't.
That's what that gun can do.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10,
11,
12.
You've already shot 12 people.
Thirty,
40,
50,
60.
You know,
you keep going.
Twenty one,
22 through to divert.
Some of them are the ones where it's.
So it's got,
it's got to be a trigger pull for every
bullet,
most likely,
unless he made it a automatic.
I think there's some guns you can alter
that.
You can turn them into a automatics most
likely.
And Ar is one of those.
I don't know,
I'm not,
I would be speaking out of school,
but I know for sure it has a
semiautomatic function and when you pull
it,
it's just every time you pull your
finger treats a bullet.
Single Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo
Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo Doo
Doo.
I mean you can literally shoot faster
than you can say the numbers.
One,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six,
seven,
eight,
nine,
10.
You shooting way more than that.
You just fire them off man.
And you would hear people that cell
phone,
you could hear it in the background and
it's quick.
It's terrific.
Terrific that someone would have that in
them.
And so it's like there's no like,
uh,
like Orlando,
Florida.
Yeah.
Well you hear about the alligator that
had a baby yesterday or no in Orlando at
Disneyland.
No Shit.
Yeah,
alligator ate a fucking baby.
One year old baby snatched them,
drug them into the water and they,
they,
they won't say killed the baby.
This is how weird the news is.
They want to say it took the baby
underwater.
Yeah,
no immediate ate the baby today.
They feel too.
That's so rough,
dude.
You can't go near water and Florida,
man.
You can't go near water.
They are infested.
I used to live there when I was a kid
and we used to feed them.
I used to live in Gainesville,
Florida,
and we used to go to Lake Alice.
There's this little pond and we'd throw
marshmallows in the water and the
alligators would come up and it was like
they were harmless.
They were always laying around like you
would walk around near alligators.
Really fucking so strange.
Now that I think about it like I had,
I had a crazy dude on many occasions.
I was within 20,
30 yards of an alligator.
They'd never fucked with people.
They never did anything,
but it was because they were endangered.
They killed a fuck load of them.
So when people first got to Florida,
I guess they just started slaughter and
alligators and they slaughtered them so
much that they became protected.
So when I lived there,
I guess it was the seventies,
it was protected.
He couldn't kill alligators,
but now there's guys who have like tags,
like professional alligator hunters.
They have 500 tags so they can go out
and shoot 500 alligators and really they
can't put a dent in the population.
They let these mother fuckers take root
and they're everywhere.
Do you see that 15 foot one that was
walking across the golf course the other
day because they figured out that was
real.
Yeah,
it's real.
There's two different angles.
Do you see the new angle into.
I go,
dude.
I mean it's a dinosaur.
It's a dinosaur to new angle to really
close to it.
They're like,
you know,
like less than 30,
40 yards away from it looks depending on
how strong their zoom is on the like
crazy tall two huge.
It's enormous.
It's walking.
It's like it's not.
I thought that would kind of dragged on
the ground,
this things walking because you're
almost like,
what do you do it?
You just kill that.
So that piece is off the earth.
Well,
it's going to kill things.
Whatever.
Whatever it gets a chance to kill.
It's going to kill.
I mean that.
There's not a whole lot that's going to
get away from that thing.
It's not that fast.
They run like about as fast as a person,
maybe a little faster than the average
person.
Have they tracked it or was it bar?
It's a good question.
I don't know what if they stayed up with
it at all?
Those things scare the fuck out of me.
Those are heartless lizards and they let
these goddamn things get to a really
high level of population.
I'm not saying we should make them
extinct,
but they definitely need to chop them
down.
There's way too many of them and there's
not a lot of people that are interested
in chopping them down like they used to
be like you'd have to send a lot of
people out into the.
In the everglades they found Nile
crocodiles.
Really?
Yeah,
they have a kill on site order for Nile
crocodiles.
They found them all because they're
super aggressive and they found a bunch
of them so far.
They're huge.
Those things get to be more than 20 feet
long.
Just the ones that need water buffaloes
and shit.
Is there a video,
a video of a world obese get me by.
Oh Dude.
You never seen.
No.
Huge abandoned initial attempt go to
Nile crocodile eats willdabeast.
There's like thousands of videos because
these things can go under water for
hours at a time,
so what they do is they slide into a
pond and they move closer to where the
hubs are.
They,
they hear the sound of the hoods and
they get in the water and then they're
underwater lying in the mud for fucking
hours,
just waiting for something to come up
and take a drink and when these things
come up and take a drink,
they just get snatched.
No,
five.
There's some close ups,
man.
There's some really good close ups.
I don't know if this is a good one.
I haven't seen it before.
So the crocodiles,
we'll wait for these things and just
decide all right,
time to eat
and they're all in the water.
They have to make these treks across the
rivers.
I don't see any crocodiles.
Jeremy [inaudible]
just mother fuckers.
It was just a racist way.
Better videos is way better videos where
it's like really close up.
Left
there
either watch other side.
Jesus.
Yeah,
just drags it.
Sorry.
They're sad.
Yeah.
That's why I go see
Jesus.
Nature stuff never makes me sad,
but I'm always taken back by how
even when I watched one the other day,
it was just,
I don't watch a lot of those shows.
The nature shows when you see when it
was like a or.
No,
it was on world star hip hop.
Actually.
It's why I watched it.
It was like a,
the Emerald Wasp zone Africa,
uh,
how it kills cockroaches.
It's like hit me like a zombifies them,
like grabs him.
It does a whole process that rips off
the antenna and then sticks it to kind
of paralyze it and it doesn't paralyze
it.
It just makes it woozy.
And then,
and then genesis,
second thing into the brain and just
like liquefies the brain than just like,
it's much smaller than the cockroach.
And then just lowers the cockroach back.
Wow.
Just take some back.
And this thing,
it's this big.
It just sucks.
It's brain out.
Yeah.
And then it just brings it back and just
throws it on the ground for the kids.
Holy Fuck.
There's so many weird bugs,
man.
When you really pay attention to all the
different kinds of species of bugs,
it's very scary because we're just so
lucky.
They're little.
They give bugs.
Were like a cow sized.
We'd be fucked.
We would be fucked.
Oh yeah.
If we ever fucking VF ESX server,
we're lucky.
We're so lucky.
Their little man,
you know we are,
but we are no match for so much shit in
nature.
Like animals and stuff.
Like we couldn't.
You couldn't fight that and crocodile
for sure.
No,
there's so many weird bugs to where they
have like weird things that they somehow
or another figure out how to do.
I'd say there's some parasite that takes
over a grasshopper's body.
It burrows into its body,
takes over its brain and hijack set and
talks this grasshopper into committing
suicide by jumping into a lake so that
he can spawn out of its body and it
bursts out of his body like an alien.
What is this one,
Jamie?
Oh,
sorry.
It's going to kill itself.
Okay.
Well these grasshoppers,
they killed themselves and then this
aquatic worm comes out of their body.
There it is.
It talks the grasshopper and the killing
itself so they can give birth to this
warm.
I mean,
look at this.
It grew in this thing's fucking body and
it's long,
like many,
many,
many times longer than the than the
grasshopper itself.
How fucking strangers that just.
It's like it is pure evil.
So there's so many creatures that are
just like,
it's.
But it works somehow or another.
There's probably too many grasshoppers
and nature figured out some sort of a
way to weed it out,
thin out the herd.
I mean,
think about all those asshole
willdabeast crossing that stupid river.
Of course we need crocodiles.
What do you want?
Like an unlimited number of willdabeast.
You can't go anywhere.
You're trying to get on a highway,
there's willdabeast everywhere,
but is that interestingly sort of like a
parallel between like a
bit of a stretch I guess,
but like the order of the nightclub
shooting thing,
it really is an emotional creatures like
pack,
herd creatures like that.
Uh,
just like one of them is just getting
killed by a stone cold killer like that,
that crocodile.
You said they're,
they're not emotional boy.
You couldn't teach a crocodile to love
somebody.
Yeah,
but that's not an aberration.
That's like standard crocodile behavior.
When a person is doing it,
it's like this crazy aberration.
Is He,
at least today,
it's a deviation for sure,
but I'm just saying there is.
He's coming out of a praying mantis now
and going right into the water so this
aquatic worm can fuck with everything.
Look at this.
He killed the praying mantis and he's
escaping through its body into water.
This is fucking nuts,
man.
What a strange animal.
Look out.
Big Pine comes near them and uh,
he yells,
the mountain lion goes away.
And then the mountain lion was like,
fuck this bitch.
And He makes them mad.
Run out of them and the guy sprays it
right in the face with bear spray and
scares it off,
but it's fucking terrifying.
It's a terrifying video because you
realized that a hundred and 50 monster
was trying to eat this dude and if you
didn't spray it in his face with some
chemicals,
he would've been donesville this guy.
We watched a murder.
We watched like a cat murder a guy.
I mean this is,
this is what happened.
Like Gimme Gimme some volume on this.
Jamie.
I was expecting quite honestly for them
to just stay in the bush and watch me go
by.
There's a quote here that's okay.
We don't have to watch the news version
of it,
but
that capital right out.
I like being an ecstatic to seeing them
too,
being like really scared
and those things will fuck you.
Fuck you up.
No danger of like when they all go out
to a bunch of the comments [inaudible]
of Joshua tree and shoot a lot of them,
a lot of them.
They're making a lot of noise.
They'll stay away.
Yeah,
because cat doesn't know if you have
guns or something like that and they're
naturally wary about people.
They know that people occasionally have
guns,
so they sort of program to be scared of
people.
Stay away.
Yeah,
but if you're running that's a problem
because running seems like you're trying
to get away,
so it excites them.
Just like rolling a ball of yarn front
of a cat and excites them.
Like if you were hiking and that same
person hiking probably wouldn't have as
much of a an attractant to that.
Cat Bikes are bad too.
They see try and take off on a bike and
they realize that's pretty fast.
Motherfuckers going to get away if I
don't have to just start sprinting
towards.
You see the video of the guy on the
bike,
he gets to get kicked by,
its gets kicked.
What's the animal?
He gets knocked off a bikeway gazelle
maybe.
Oh,
I have seen that as jumping on me.
It just wasn't.
That guy goes flying so far off the
bike.
The thing just like hit him going 50
miles an hour sideways,
right?
Yeah.
Even the guy,
it's like a buck or something.
Right?
What kind of animal is it,
Jimmy?
Oh,
Jesus.
He got fucked up.
It was like you should have went high
fived and other,
uh,
of what is it a gazelle,
right?
Yeah,
yeah.
It goes.
He goes now,
like I told you,
motherfucker,
that was their jackass.
Three video.
The Gazelle community.
That's their jackets.
Three.
Oh,
nailed them.
Oh my God.
Look out and look at the gazelle.
Just sort of bounces off of them and
runs away.
Easy campaign.
How,
how powerful animals are over us.
We'll look at that through the air.
Look,
I mean it's probably 250 300 pounds and
it's throwing itself into the air.
You know,
that's a big ass animal.
It's pretty impressive that we dominate
the earth to considering that like we
are not even anywhere near the most
powerful.
Just the smartest technical are so much
smarter than those dummies sit.
We can shoot them from a distance that
you could make a,
an antelope.
You could turn into a steak,
eat it.
Exactly.
All you have to do is set up a bi-pod.
Get a nice clean rest,
relax you breathing,
squeeze your fingers and boom,
a bullet goes through its body.
You go pick it up,
you it,
you open it up.
Take the organs that are edible,
chop it down,
throw it on the grill and you're eating
it in like less than an hour.
But if you're in like backed in a corner
against the wall,
you're fucked with any dude in the
world.
You have a,
you have a puncher's chance of getting
out of that thing.
Okay?
But as a gazelle is just going to murder
you quickly,
you're fucked.
A fucking ran that aren't even that big.
They'll just fucking pulverize you.
I liked my chances with Ram,
it's take chess.
If I got a knife and a Iran wants to get
crazy.
I know if I'm talking about straight,
oh,
straight,
like just choke him.
I think I could joke around.
I didn't take his back.
First of all,
I feel like if I break one of his front
legs,
he's not going anywhere.
Right.
So I'll.
I'll just dive on a Kamora.
Are you using using Dalton's theory from
roadhouse man's leg?
I'm going to slide under him,
so when he raises up,
when he raises up,
I'm going to get that part.
I'm going to push it forward and then
I'm going to get that double wrist lock
position.
I'm going to crack that fucking leg.
Then I'm going to roll into mountain and
once I get into mount,
I get ahold of his handlebars,
Bro.
Probably hit me and knocked me 30 feet
into the air.
Have you ever seen the video of ghost
write a book for you?
Joe Rogan shows you how to defeat
animals,
feeding wildlife with,
uh,
just go through each animal.
Obviously.
Don't try to fight a buffalo,
but um,
there's a video of a ram and a cow
headbutting.
It's fucking crazy because it's ram as
only like,
I mean,
I don't know,
it can't be more than like 150 pounds.
So it's not that big an animal.
And the cows a fucking huge cow and they
collide heads.
The cow was trying to get the,
to stay the fuck away from it.
So it charged it and headbutted this ram
and the ram and knocked him the fuck
out.
Knocked the cow out.
Yeah,
just on the couch.
His legs up.
Watch this.
Watch it right here.
Right here.
The ribs coming up.
The cows like,
oh,
I fucked up the rams woozy.
But it gets right back up.
Like what I liked.
I liked that a cow just because of their
build has naturally has a knockout arms.
Where were.
They're still snoring.
What was that video?
They're going to show a ram running over
a biker.
There was.
It was up next.
It was playing up next.
That's my thought was so crazy was
jackass guys like when it got into the
thing with a ram and just let her rams
nails a bunch of crazy.
Those guys.
Well,
how about when he,
you johnny?
Knoxville stood blindfolded in front of
a bull for.
Oh Shit.
It just ran right into his bike.
On the back of the ram.
Yeah.
What is that about?
Why is there a Gopro on the ram?
This is stupid.
Don't give these people any.
How dare you put a go pro.
People were abusing wildlife,
but in Gopros on Ram.
That's ridiculous.
Extreme though.
It is an extreme ram because that's what
I needed to go pro.
And you become extreme.
Yeah,
no shit.
You put one on your head.
It's extreme.
Did you,
are that mcconkie documentary on?
No,
what is
it about the guy who was like,
he was an extreme skier and that he's
got wait until the wing suits and base
jumping and shit.
And uh,
they got a guy,
I don't know if it was him that passed
away like this,
but I remember in the documentary,
yeah,
there's a base jump,
uh,
somebody does illegally,
you know that you can't,
they're not like,
okay to do anywhere really I guess.
And he does a base jumping like a state
park when he lands the park,
police were ever start chasing him and
while he's running from them trying to
get away,
he dies like in the jumps in the creek
and the water takes some or something
and he ends up drowning or something
like that.
Oh.
So then they stage is why I stay away
from all this shit.
Then they stage a,
uh,
like a jumping,
a protest jump because the police should
take some but their fault somehow they
chased the guy,
he jumped into the creek and uh,
so they staged this jump where
everyone's going to base,
jump off this mountain and then when
they land there,
know,
willingly getting arrested and by the
third person who did it,
you just see the bike just go.
Pumps,
smacks the ground.
Like shoe doesn't open because someone
dies again doing it.
It's like idiots.
This is dumb.
The dumb thing to do,
she's as Christ.
We all,
my radio show we were talking about,
uh,
like run.
I'm all for amusement park rides,
roller coasters and everything.
But you do hear the numbers of people
who have died on ones you've road is
pretty crazy,
like pretty,
pretty fucking great.
But we still keep getting on it.
But maybe people die every year.
Have you had to guess?
We're going to google it.
I'm going to die every year.
And rollercoasters around the country.
One hundred hundred.
Yeah,
I say less first day that the first day
of one of them because they didn't
realize there had to be a height
regulation for two tall seven people in
the car or something like that.
I'm totally like seven people the first
day.
Oh my God.
That must've been on one run.
You know what I mean?
Like s seven tall people just got the
cast,
so seven people.
Then they kept the ride.
I haven't been to an amusement park in a
while,
but yeah,
I haven't.
I haven't been to an amusement park in
awhile,
but they now have height limits.
Like you can't be too tall either.
What's up Jim?
There's not that many.
Actually.
I said 13.
You said 100.
What is the actual number point two?
Seven deaths per year.
Oh,
that's it.
There's only been 52 since 19.
Between 1990 and carnivals and
everything.
Rollercoaster rollercoaster carnivals
and the amusement park desk.
Because some of them things aren't
really.
Rollercoasters has all sorts of
different shit.
Like those like drops.
Let's create.
People have died in those things.
Oh Man.
We watched her legs and some of those
fucking disasters,
but the willing to go into it,
but I don't know for some reason I think
there's a much lower risk of amusement
park rides than like Scott.
A guy called us in and went skydiving.
He said they,
they even let him cut corner.
He was like a bigger guy so they didn't
make him wear a certain kind of harness
and he went into
street clothes,
you're not really supposed to do that.
And he said he went out.
He says fucking shoot,
like got wound up.
Like it got like he literally,
he hit the ground and they got fucked
up.
But like,
uh,
but it kind of opened like really late
and so he still hit the ground like
hard,
but like,
you know,
not hard enough to like kill them.
You know?
What's crazy is that Disney has probably
the safest rides and the safest ride
record.
They have huge amusement parks with
amazing rides,
wild,
crazy shit,
space mountain tower of terror,
all that stuff.
Yet they let a fucking dinosaur live in
their resort.
This allegation,
this kid did,
they had a dinosaur living there like
they didn't check the lake for
dinosaurs.
You know how fucking crazy that is?
I mean,
imagine if you had a lake behind your
house and you were pretty sure dinosaurs
lived in that lake and you had a kid,
but he kinda came out of a lake so that
it wasn't little upon there.
Like any body of water,
man,
they'll crawl across the highway and
jump into a swimming pool.
They don't give a fuck.
They find them and people's pools.
Really?
Dude,
there's so many of them.
There's so many of them.
Then there's the everglades.
The everglades are infested,
infested with alligators.
There's so many of them.
People would go fan boat and they have
all kinds of crazy shit in there now
though,
they have pythons and alligators and
like you said,
Nile crocodiles,
there's all sorts of ways to place dump
a body.
Oh,
it's my last con.
El gives you get it like that.
There was a lot of fucking.
And then they have wild pigs.
There's a lot of shit going on in
Florida.
It's a terrible place.
Florida,
I was just there last weekend in Miami.
It's like,
and by the way,
I had a great time and fun people place.
The actual place itself is just like
that.
Humidity is the grossest thing I've ever
dealt with.
Well,
it's also,
there's an echo of the past in that
state and the entire city of Miami's
like almost entirely funded by cocaine.
That's how that city became Miami.
That's why it has more banks per capita,
allegedly probably Google this because
I've said it too many times more banks
per capita.
I think I found it on.
Um,
Billy Corbin's movie cocaine cowboys I
think was talking about that.
Maybe not,
but it was all coke saw people running
coke and that fucking per se,
just like a bunch of clubs and
restaurants and doing blow shooting
people and all the crime that was
wrapped around coke and all the murders
and the violence and all the police
corruption.
Dude.
Did you ever see cocaine cowboys?
Yeah,
that was good.
Did you ever see corruption?
Do you ever see the 75?
I had Michael Dowd in.
Oh really?
Yeah,
he's great.
He's hilarious.
Yeah.
You should get them on legion of skanks
for sure.
He'll do it.
So you're not a terrible guy.
No.
Really?
I mean saint.
Yes.
I enjoy his company.
He did some crazy shit for sure.
Everybody was doing blow and he was out
of his fucking mind and went to jail.
He did his time and now he's just trying
to figure out what he's doing.
He's selling cigars and doing a bunch of
different.
I've always loved the wives when they're
just kinda like.
I thought it was weird when we were
going to Fiji on a beat cops salary.
They're just like,
they don't know.
They just want to believe so bad.
Yeah.
He's driving around a red corvette.
He's like,
everyone's like,
what the fuck is.
They were maniacs.
They're maniacs,
but it's a great movie.
It's a real a testament though to like
the same personality is extreme
personalities that want to become like,
you know,
just go fucking full blown.
Outlaw is the same.
God said,
I'm going to protect everyone.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's a really isn't.
And one companies be Lord to the other
side in a heartbeat.
Well,
he slowly but surely got chipped away at
and I think also like he was talking
about how his very first days on the job
he experienced like intense corruption
where guys were talking about killing
people that snitched on cops and they
were like kind of openly admitted that a
guy fell off of a roof that snitched on
cops.
And he's like,
uh,
you know,
that's what happens.
And he was like,
okay,
got it.
We're good,
you know,
and became over time corrupt.
And he's pretty honest about it,
man.
I mean,
he doesn't hold anything back.
So it's pretty.
I mean,
it wasn't good times.
He wasn't a good guy.
No,
no question about it.
But it's a question of,
well,
yeah,
they were like looking the other way.
What people did get killed.
I want to hear a story,
you know,
I mean,
I think it's an important story.
There's not a lot of cops that have gone
bad that are approachable.
Like Michael Dowd,
he's the most approachable and
interesting and you know,
and he doesn't get along with the other
guys that he was uh,
involved with the time because I guess
they at each other out or one guy ratted
him out.
Kenny,
one of the guys on the show apparently,
or in the movie,
but it's a great fucking movie that,
that guy that he's a talking to in the
movie from where's he from?
Nicaragua or something like that.
South America,
the Dominican Republic.
Maybe that guy in him or making cigars
now.
Oh really?
Yeah.
The Guy who was in the movie talking
about killing people
disappeared.
Yeah.
It was like the main drug dealer guy.
That was basically his partner.
It was his name again.
Okay.
But it's kind of funny.
They get,
they get in with them with all those
corruptions stories where they get in,
like with the drug deal,
but there's,
they're almost like Newbie guys like
this is all kind of scary for us to.
So what are we know?
But we went in,
we'd love to get a part of this money
and then they start getting the money
and then it says they start coming like
whacking people around and stuff.
Hey Pablo,
is this your new guy?
Just like drag him across the face.
She'll make me a big.
Well you jerk off will in this case it's
actually kind of like a,
a,
a happy ending drug dealer story because
the two guys are still friends.
Like they're older now and the two cops
are still friends.
No,
the car and the truck dealer.
They're buddies.
Like Michael Dow visited the dude to go
save and put pictures of the two of them
hanging out at his instagram page.
So in that sense they kind of.
What was the other car?
Him and his partner,
but the partner and him don't get along.
The partner.
The testified against him.
Yeah.
The partner wore a wire for him.
Right.
So yeah,
the parties,
we set them up to be like,
hey,
we're going to let this lady get killed.
Yes.
Yeah.
And then it all fell apart.
It's crazy.
It's imagine being those guys in that
time.
It's crazy.
I wonder with this length of time to
get,
because you're going to be on edge no
matter what.
Whenever you're starting something that,
you know,
it was like bad,
like you know,
it's like uh,
how,
how long from starting it,
like,
where you're nervous.
Do you just be like,
this is just life and then one day it
just all fucking gone.
But you do eventually forget that day is
coming.
I don't think he ever thought it was
I think he was just a cooked up maniac.
I think when you do a lot of coke you're
just always.
And then you try and get some sleep and
then you wake up in the morning.
He not planning your future,
you just,
just red lining every day.
I've never been to coachella ever.
I don't even know.
He never done it.
I did two lines ever.
Your two lines ahead of me.
I did both of them.
I was just like,
I stopped.
It was like immediate guilt of both.
Just being like,
I don't want it.
Like,
this is like so out of my range of like
wanting to get involved in like,
what if it's great.
Now I've got a whole fucking thing with
this now.
If it's great,
like I don't want to get into that shit.
Dude.
You're exactly like me in that regard.
I took us,
I drank some tea once that was made out
of coca leaves and uh,
it's a real pick me up.
But the problem is for some.
I mean I was on mushrooms at the time as
well,
but I couldn't shut the fuck up.
I like couldn't shut the.
I was with Stan hope and I was talking
to him.
I was like,
dude,
I'm really sorry but I can't shut the
fuck up.
I don't know what's going on.
I want to be annoying.
I don't know what it's going out with my
mouth,
my mouth.
I was just diarrhea.
Just wouldn't stop.
I haven't,
I haven't taken a whole lot of shit.
That some weird stuff.
I've tried.
I tried adderall.
How is that?
Um,
I was just awake for like,
that's how it affected me.
A girl out here,
actually,
when I came to visit one time a friend.
This girl kept me awake for three days.
Tell me what you know Rick Shapiro?
Yes,
it was Rick Shapiro's ex-girlfriend.
Oh,
good Lord.
Who is a comic also.
It was a friend of mine.
She just let me crash at her apartment.
It was just doing that are all together.
She was just like,
you want to try to add A.
I'm like,
I never have.
I'm sure I'll give it a whirl and three
days she kept me awake and talking to me
about the genius of Rick Shapiro and
making me watch video clips of him and
everything.
Like clockwork orange eyes up my eyes
and she was like,
just adderall be with that and maybe
watch Rick Shapiro,
which is not what other.
I mean I love Rick,
but that's not what another comic wants
to do is sit there and watch Rick
Shapiro mapped doubt check.
She is also an adderall math adderalls
meth visit.
Really?
Oh yeah,
it's math.
Oh Wow.
Yeah.
I mean I don't know how much she was
really gone by the time I saw her.
She was a,
well that's one of the reasons my gals
like it.
Yeah.
It keeps showing skinny,
but uh,
yeah,
I did adderall.
I've done,
uh,
I did ecstasy once.
I did it once to Jamie.
Pull that up.
Whether or not adderall,
like what's the division?
Adderall in math,
it's like a very minor difference means.
And it depends which one you take.
I'm pretty sure.
But look it up at there's more than one
kind of adderall,
different kinds of outer or adderall.
Like things.
Yeah,
because generic form is and it's very
similar things.
It's fucking pill pill head kick in at
once or twice and I got a different one
each time I took it,
so that's good.
I'd hate to say that I enjoy from time
to time a,
a like a Vicodin or percocet?
Yeah,
like vary from time to time.
I tried one or the other.
I don't remember which one it was.
I think it was Vicodin,
but didn't agree with me.
Yeah.
Yeah,
just like just,
I just was really out of it.
Okay.
Chemically adderalls and mixture of
several amphetamine salts specifically.
It's a con.
It's composed of equal parts of
amphetamine,
aspartate monohydrate,
amphetamine sulfate,
Dextro,
and Dextro Amphetamine,
Saturate.
I'm don't know what that means.
Sounds like,
what's the difference between adderall
and Meth?
Because,
uh,
just what's the difference?
What's the difference between were so
folks shouldn't be.
You guys want to take adderall?
I guess we're getting is metro.
Let's organize.
Let's,
uh,
let's build a fort the.
I have a 13 year old daughter now too,
so that's always the thing,
you know,
got a buy to go try out a bunch of new
drugs now.
Seems like a bad idea.
Okay.
Chemically the are very closely related.
Adderall contains dextroamphetamine
salts that psychoactive chemical is
amphetamines,
meth is methamphetamine.
The difference between the two is the
molecules is one methyl group.
So they're both amphetamines,
but one is a different kind of
amphetamine,
but they're very close.
Hmm.
Interesting.
Okay.
For taking it for those three days,
I'd never felt like a itch to go back
ever.
Some people love it,
man.
No,
some people fucking love it.
I absolutely think you got a lot of
energy.
You're,
you're uh,
you're always like a,
like a fucking upbeat sort of a dude.
Some people I don't think have that kind
of energy and maybe whether it's health
related or not a little pick me up like
an adderall gives you a little
feeling of getting shit done and
apparently it's great for school.
Kids that are in school are cramming,
you know,
keep you up and stuff like that.
Those things that like,
you know,
any of the.
But I know it's the like it calms you
down or ramps you up.
Freaks you out.
Yeah.
It doesn't make sense to me.
I don't get how that it is like how
different could it with chemical B and
people.
Obviously you have queer retarded.
Clearly not scientists.
I wasted one of these lab coats.
I'm not convinced it's even,
I mean I know it has some sort of an
effect on people,
but the way it's been distributed
like that,
when they're giving it to kids,
like it's one of the most controversial
things of giving these psychoactive
compounds to kids.
Not Knowing the longterm effects of it.
And so many doctors are just so willing
to jump into it and give them,
give these kids pills the as long as
their parents are into it,
they'll just fucking order it away to
keep asking about documentaries.
Did you watch the thalidomide one yet?
No,
that's gotta be terrible.
They gave it to the moms.
Right.
And then they say,
I'll see I see it on Netflix but I keep
getting nervous to watch it because I'm
like it's gonna that's gonna be a bum
out.
There's some crazy drugs that they gave
people that they had an idea of some
risks but they didn't know either.
I don't think they really know until you
give it to like a million people and
then you find out like oh this can
happen too and this can happen too.
And then by the time it's too late
you're dealing with these horrible birth
defects with thalidomide.
It's also funny how much like the stuff
like,
you know,
they just keep adding for legal reasons,
stuff to those warnings on ship.
But they don't really like that.
If you ask like specific things to the
pharmacist,
because I remember like Lexapro the
first time I went on tour with like corn
and Rob Zombie so and like a bunch of
bands,
so I was like,
I wanted to smoke weed,
maybe drink a little bit.
I'm not a big huge drinker but I'll
drink on this a little bit and smoke
weed.
And I'd asked the pharmacist and I was
like,
it says here do not drink with us at
all.
And they were like,
no,
it's just because like that's just part
of the thing is like,
you know,
so you don't.
If you're taking some of the
antidepressant of sorts,
like why would you take a depressant to
bring it back down?
And I was like,
but I was like,
but it's not for like in my mind I was
going to be like take a pill,
drink a beer,
like explode like a seagull with an
episode.
But my fear was is that work a seagull
with Alka Seltzer.
I video ever video of that,
but that was the thing when I was
younger.
If you give Alka Seltzer with seagull,
they'll explode.
I remember vaguely hearing that.
I don't know if it's an actual thing.
Yeah.
I don't know either.
Exploding seagulls.
So what we want to know the Lexapro.
Did we talk about this before?
I'm not sure I got super like a physical
reaction to anxiety that I've never had
before in my life.
I never,
I never really thought I had anxiety.
Um,
and then right before I was going on
tour with those bands,
I got very nervous on top of like having
a crazy,
a landlord dispute out of nowhere.
I think they just read,
they get charged more for our place and
so they were like,
Hey,
you've been great tenants for a year,
but,
you know,
get out.
And um,
my daughter was in school still and we
just kinda like.
So we sent a letter just sort of asking
like,
Hey,
can we hang in there for,
you know,
gives like three more months.
Just like she finished the school year
and they just served us with court
papers.
Whoa.
So we ended up winning that,
which was fine,
but it was very tense.
I mean,
like they called the cops on us a bunch
just making shit up.
Oh God.
This old Asian lady bit.
My ex wife's.
This was one of the landlords.
Yeah.
Oh Jesus.
Shake bitter.
It was because she was just like trying
to film us,
like going into the house or something.
So my ex wife to women's getting shitty
with each other and one doesn't speak
English.
She's filled,
they're filming each other.
And then the lady I bit her hand while
she was telling it got like that
volatile in one day.
Uh,
I was on the computer watching something
and I'm just like,
it popped back on whatever it was,
like my hands went numb and I've never
had it in my life.
And I just,
uh,
wigged out and like try to go to bed.
I'm like,
I'll sleep it off or whatever it is is,
you know,
I'm sure I'm okay.
Woke up in the morning,
didn't feel better.
And then after like a month or two I
ended up doing on what's going on
Lexapro.
Wow.
So it was just a combined anxiety thing.
All tests.
Yeah.
Apart in that.
But I've never been right since that
day.
Oh no shit.
Yeah,
like anxiety is like a major issue in my
life.
It wasn't before then now.
And it always manifests into my new one
now is that I smoke.
So I know it doesn't help at all,
like cigarettes.
I mean it doesn't help it at all,
but I feel like,
uh,
if I pay attention to my breathing,
I have to like extra fill my lungs.
Were they,
it's all just like,
it's involuntary,
like mental shit.
Wow.
Yeah,
it sucks.
But uh,
what have you tried to do to get,
get over it?
And exercise helps always.
Um,
and just trying to like distract,
you know,
it is like,
it kind of all the symptoms that I feel
the fake whatever they are [inaudible]
the little pings and pangs it.
It's a,
if they happened long enough and I don't
die from whatever it is I think I have
or whatever thing,
I'm like convincing my body that I have,
it just goes away because I'm like,
well,
it's not a real thing.
Right?
Like I used to get like at its worst
when I got it really bad then and I was
going to the hospital a bunch.
Like it was like all limbs going,
like tingly,
numb.
It was just scary,
you know what I mean?
And your heart starts beating fast.
Just panic attacks.
Really?
Wow.
But I've never,
I've always been someone who would laugh
at somebody would have panic attacks,
I guess.
Not a real thing like get your shit
together.
And uh,
and then I had it.
I was asked to make some apologies.
I was like,
man,
this sucks because,
you know,
you walk into a hospital knowing you're
like,
just tell me,
you know,
we have to the machine and tell me that
I haven't had a heart attack and
everything again.
I know I haven't,
but like I have to come here like
compulsively I have to come here to make
sure.
Wow.
It's crazy that those things like blew a
fuse almost in your head.
Yeah.
I asked a,
a psychologist,
that is why I said I go is can someone
just pop one day,
like,
just hit a level and pop.
And he was like,
absolutely.
Yeah.
Wow.
Nobody thinks that.
Yeah,
I don't usually think that they think
that you can just bring it back down.
You'll be fine.
Get it back.
Yeah.
But it's a,
it's a constant thing.
Sure.
What kind of exercise you're doing at
the DDP Yoga?
I've been doing a lot.
A fucking great.
Yeah.
A diamond page for like if you don't
like what's DDP?
The double penetration would have
fucking these guys doing.
DDP Yoga is a former pro wrestler.
Dallas diamond page is put together a
yoga program.
Yep.
Fucking really difficult program.
Gets a lot of people in shape,
man.
Easy.
It's nice.
Long sessions.
He does and he has a couple of short
ones you can combine,
but it's doable.
It's a good sweat for sure.
I want to start like now it's like warm
again and hopefully I have a few weeks
at home now.
Like I want to like I miss like lifting
any weights of any kind.
It's good for the body.
It's really good for you.
And as an yeah.
As a man.
Especially as you get older,
you're going to lose muscle tissue,
your bones going to get weaker.
That's the best way to keep that.
One of the only ways.
I mean your body's supposed to be doing
stuff,
you know,
we have these weird lives we live where
you can just all day long have very
minimal movement.
It's not natural for a person.
I think we did talk this before by the
crossfit for a little while and that's
just like a lot of injuries,
not an advocate.
Well,
some people love it.
It's good for them.
Some people push each other and they
love it.
I get it.
Yeah.
Well I'm going to you.
You kind of already have to have A.
I don't think it's.
I don't think it's a good idea to jump
into like fat person who has not worked
out at all,
but I'll go try crossfit.
It's Sorta what I did.
It worked in every sense of like I lost
weight.
I lost a bunch of weight and so that was
my major weight loss was like 70 pounds
and I've kind of like always plateaued
around there since then.
But it was like a definitely like dense
muscle growth,
you know what I mean?
Like I felt better.
I looked good,
I felt better about myself,
looks wise when I did that over the yoga
or anything like that that I do.
So what's the problem?
Speed.
Weightlifting.
Men destroyed.
Like I am just starting to get to a
point now where I don't wake up and
still if it's cold out or if I sleep
with air conditioning,
like in the morning,
like my back and just be shut off for
like 15 minutes.
I have to really work on it to like.
So you hurt your back.
Wipe my ass.
Yeah.
I'm just,
you know,
they go,
hey,
for 15 minutes,
let's go over with a pvc pipe.
Had a do proper snatched lifts and then
they go,
all right,
now do it as fast as many as you can in
eight minutes,
you know.
And uh,
and this is the guy who was the fastest
and don't be the slowest,
and then it's like,
you know,
you're rushing through it.
You're going to lose form every time.
Yeah.
This has been some pretty unfortunate
accidents because of the.
Oh hell yeah.
I mean,
but it is.
If you are in great shape and you stick
the form and do it,
it's one of the most amazing workouts of
all time either.
Well,
you could definitely get a good workout
in.
You're definitely gonna burn off a lot
of energy and things along those lines.
And some people love it.
I don't do it,
but I do similar exercises.
I understand what they're doing.
Kettlebell stuff.
I love Kettlebells,
but I'm more of the proponent of um,
especially now I've been listening to
this guy,
pavel tattooing,
you know,
he is,
he's the guy that brought kettle bells
to America and uh,
between him and I learned a lot from
this guy,
Steve Maxwell's on my podcast
a bunch of times and they are more
proponents of lifting heavy weights for
lower repetitions.
And then there's this other guy named
Keith Weber who's got a totally
different approach,
but it's just an endurance workout.
He's got this thing called extreme
kettlebell cardio workout.
You could do that with a 35 pound
kettlebell man.
A little light kettlebell.
Yeah.
But it's so much work and there's so
much body weight involved.
You just fall and he does it with you.
And he's a stud.
He's in incredible shape and handling
other workouts.
There's a bunch of different ones.
Um,
he's got a bunch of different ones that
work your upper body lower body,
if I remember correctly,
the ones I usually do is off the first
video.
He's got three videos now.
The ones I usually do off the first
video I think are about 40 minutes.
Someone like your dad by the time that
was 40 minutes is up 42 minutes maybe.
Or they can do those in the house.
Yeah.
I just need one kettlebell you need.
That's a big thing.
So I was like hot potatoes,
being standing rose,
switch the hands and you just keep going
and going.
It gives you like little breaks.
But then you just keep going and so
that,
wait,
that 35 pound weight just feels like an
eternity.
It feels like.
I just fuck it.
It feels like you lifted 75 pounds by
the end.
Yeah,
I got into doing like as much.
So you'll go on the road a lot too.
It's like trying to find out like hotel
room.
I don't like going to the hotel gyms.
Okay.
I don't know.
It just never enjoyed guys weird.
The equipment is always kind of like
junk.
Anyway,
Jamie and I were in San Francisco.
They had an equinox.
It was the shit.
It was great.
Oh my God,
it was amazing.
So go on the road to the hotel gyms I
don't like.
So I've found a bunch of like,
there's some great like just hotel room
workout so you can give yourself a good
beating for sure.
Oh for sure.
Yeah,
you can do one that's like the middle of
the workout is 70 burpees.
Oh really?
That's like,
that's a motherfucker.
Oh fuck.
Yeah.
I mean,
you definitely get a lot of work done in
a small space and like you know,
the whole workout,
it's a 100 squats,
90 sit ups,
80 lunges,
70 burpees,
and for a big guy like you,
100 squats,
bodyweight squats is a lot of work.
Yeah.
That's jacked.
I'm sure my calves are shredded from
kettering.
My body,
my whole life has probably kick a hole
through a wall about how much weight he
carries all the time and he's still,
you know,
he's got a big ass legs.
You got to assume that your body has to
carry around that much when he gets a
certain kind of a fat person because
there's definitely people who get fat
where it's like their limbs or doe,
but I wasn't necessarily that kind of
fat and I'm not that kind of fat now,
but it's always my legs for some reason.
I've always been like just jack from
just carrying around the body weight of
course.
But I mean there's obviously just get
those big crazy legs,
but my legs have always been oddly
muscular can then my body's weird.
The human body's very strange in that
you could change it,
you can move it around,
you see a rhino,
it's built like a fucking rhino,
but a human being can through
weightlifting and diet and you know,
just concentrating on stuffing your face
with calories and constantly hitting
like heavy cleans and snatches and dead
lifts.
You can get way bigger.
Oh yeah.
You just gotTa keep doing it.
You just got to keep doing it.
Going backwards.
This is the hardest thing.
That's why that a gay pride parade was
Sunday,
right.
That was the day I got here and I went
over to the comedy store and just
walking when I went to eat dinner at the
rainbow bar and grill and it's right
next to that one oak place which was
having I guess a big gay blow out and
they were all outside and like cutoff
shorts and shirtless and just fantastic
bodies.
Every one of them and I was just like at
sucks.
I'm just passed an age and the damage
I've done to my body just from being a
fat kid growing up,
it's just like there's just no,
I'll never look like that ever.
It's always a bummer.
How come you never looked like that?
I'm just the morning of the body over
the years had
to separate game of thrones.
I've modeled myself the fourth emulate
stretchmarks,
uh,
just loose skin.
They would be like,
we keep referencing.
Lewis was funny.
He said,
I never referenced on the show before.
Now I've said it 50 times.
Louis j Gomez was 300 pounds at one
point.
Low.
Got into a great shape,
like really great.
She a few years ago was like abs and
everything,
but still like A.
I have a friend rob who,
same thing was a heavyset guy.
Now he's in really good shape.
They put on a bathing suit still on both
of them.
You see like ecological,
just the jiggling the body.
You know what I mean?
Louis will always have stretchmarks no
matter what.
But here's the thing.
You could,
I could look a thousand times better
than I look,
but I'll never.
My point just being,
I'm never going to be like this fucking
these statues that these guys are,
you know what I mean?
Just like jacked fucking Tan ad guys.
I'm like,
I just bummed out that I never knew what
that was like ever or being,
or being a thin kid or a kid in high
school that could,
uh,
you know,
just where all the clothes that were the
coolest clothes that just having to get
like big and tall ship.
Um,
what do they do?
They cut your skin,
right?
That's one way they deal with that.
When they do,
you're always going to be.
I've seen all that stuff,
man.
And I would get it.
I would get it.
But you're always going to be
frankensteinish [inaudible],
you know what I mean?
You're always gonna have like,
I've never seen that car.
To me that's the decision of fake tits.
Really.
It has to be.
It's like you are like a part fake and
there is marks to show how fake it is.
You know what I mean?
There's always going to be like,
the nipples are always weird.
You're just stretching the body and you
put it into something else.
It's not supposed to be,
but those don't seem to mind even a
little bit.
Um,
no,
not the.
Some.
Some guys hate fake tits.
Yeah.
I'm not a big fan of those crazy like
softball ones where there's a big split
in the middle and that's all with that
shit.
Yeah,
that's an awkward look.
It's like the,
the canyon between titties.
Yeah.
That's unnecessary.
I just rib cage in between it.
It's weird.
It's a long stretch with one going like
northeast and one going northwest and
they're just like perfect circles.
Yeah,
let's just odd.
Well it's,
they went too hard,
you know,
like if you try to go to many cup sizes
over like some of these girls like
really lean and small girls and tits or
just like fat bags golf at.
Yeah,
I mean they're beautiful fat bags.
This doesn't say you have to like,
you know,
forget to put your foot in the middle of
their chest and like stretch their tits
skin health or wrap around this thing.
It's so gross.
Men,
have you ever see an operation when they
go in through the armpit and they got
like this hook and they're digging
underneath the armpit and they're
creating a cavity and then they have to
stuff that cavity with his bag and then
fill it up with water and they just
squeeze her tit for half hour.
I guess they're hard.
Not Hard,
but solid bags now.
They're not like a bag that they fill up
with water now.
I guess the more popular one is like a
softer fully formed thing that sits in
your body and you have to always worry
about your body rejecting it to.
Oh,
and the real issue.
There's a.
We were looking at Dick Enhancement
surgery's not too long ago and they
actually have where they put a fucking
piece of plastic in your Dick.
Like make it like try to actually
lengthen,
lengthen the hang,
which advised to pick a Dick Surgery.
That's the one I'd pick,
but uh,
it just seems like the risk versus
reward on that one man.
Well,
they,
they have to experiment on Dick's in
order to perfect that surgery.
It's not like there's a lot of donating
their dicks Dick lengthening science.
They've got a practice that shit on live
people.
I don't know how they get approval.
I've never seen that go like,
uh,
the only videos to like any kind of
dicks surgery go well.
It's always fucking crazy looking.
Yeah,
because nobody wants to admit it.
Nobody wants to hear,
hey,
I had a four inch deck,
but now I got a six look,
check it out.
This is what he did,
but it never even ended up being like a
forced it to become six.
That'd be great for people.
I'm just saying it's like you had like a
five inch or four inch like regular Dick
and now it looks like this weird,
like fucking,
it looks like a wiggly worm or whatever.
He used to grab it and it scored out of
your hands.
That's what it looks like.
It's just like big fat,
doughy thing.
It doesn't get really hard because it
looks like it looks like it got stung by
a bee or like,
it's like there's a problem with off
with poison ivy.
The best surgery ever was at bucket
where they put out that Baba Guy's Dick
back together,
remember?
Yeah.
And really just had the Frankenstein
staples across it.
Yeah.
He's making a face like across your for
this doing for people listening.
Yeah.
That guy fucked after that.
Like he got his dick to almost work.
He did porn.
It's so weird looking those still.
Huh?
What a crazy story.
That was that guy recently who just got
a.
He just got Dick Transplant,
right?
Yeah.
First ever effective.
Dick's plant transplant,
the United States and he worked at the
bone and everything.
That's a good question.
So one question.
No one's followed up.
It's an older fella to.
Yeah,
he was in his fifties.
And why do you need.
He just lost his Dick and stepping back.
Why didn't need it?
Why do you need yard as well?
No,
it wasn't.
that wasn't getting his dick back.
He goes,
oh no,
he got a new Dick.
Yeah,
it was a transplant,
but what happened to his old Dick,
I want to say a car accident with his
Dick,
who's was driving with his foot.
He had a boner in two cars just because
he was getting his dick sucked while he
was driving.
Hit the brakes and the car accident and
that has happened and guys before,
you know,
bitten off,
I don't know about bitten off,
but definitely bitten.
Oh yeah.
Because we've gone to the hospital with
their dick all fucked up because the
girl hit down on it when they were
driving their car.
Where you ever seen those videos when
the dicks like break when the girl is
like riding a dicon and comes down to
hard with tape.
It's my.
That's what I'm talking about.
Anxieties I live with.
That one freaks me out when the girls
rotting your Dick and she's vigorously
going up.
I literally have to be like,
you are going to hurt me if this goes
haywire,
like please settle down with him.
It's actually a his penises amputated
after he had penile cancer.
Oh Jesus.
You got.
That's a pretty good reason to get.
You know,
I think the first guy that ever got it
wasn't an American guy.
That guy may be the one that I was
thinking of that had the car accident.
There was a,
there's one in South Africa to 21 year
old who had.
I'm seeing this lost it.
It said he had complications after he
had to have his penis for complicated.
Yeah.
Circumcision complications that happens.
People lose their dicks every year from
circumcision,
probably more than die rollercoaster
rides.
When I was in DC,
uh,
recently we went down by the White House
and there was a big rally.
Anti circumcision rally.
Yeah.
Yelling out facts and I don't know if
they're facts.
It says circumcision confirmed makes the
penis smaller.
I don't know if that's true.
I don't know if it makes smaller,
but definitely makes it less sensitive.
It could probably make it smaller.
Who knows about all that?
Are you circumcised and you wish you
weren't?
Um,
no.
I'm okay.
And you don't give a shit either way,
but I don't think we should keep doing
it.
It's definitely barbaric.
It's pointless.
It doesn't do anything good.
There's nothing healthy about it.
It's.
It's an ancient tribal ritual that
people are trying to justify.
The only thing that has done for the
aesthetic aesthetic.
Yeah,
but that's ridiculous.
I've seen porn.
We're dudes of uncircumcised dicks.
Look Fun.
Just like a dick with some extra skin.
It looks foreign.
Yeah.
Did he ever got bombed out of the girl's
pussy with extra skin?
Does that bother you at even?
A little bit?
No,
but I've definitely talked about those
more than others.
Like them.
I'm.
I'm in the Norton camp.
A real beef.
You want like a meaty one?
I don't mind at all.
I don't mind the meeting when I don't
mind it,
but I'm always like.
It's interesting how it looks like real,
real flappy.
I don't give a fuck.
It doesn't bother me at all,
but the idea that they trim those is
horrendous.
Like that's crazy.
Flips trimmed to get them cut off.
It's their lobbyists.
Surgery lab,
a deck tummy or maybe plasty.
Oh,
it's awful.
It's terrifying.
At one point started putting like frozen
in whatever plastic and Houston mafia
Houston,
but meanwhile that was her pussy.
Part of her appeal,
that's what a lot of guys liked about
her shadow a pussy,
like a moose mouth,
like
probably in the eighties through the
nineties.
I could tell you five picture.
Who's porn stars like matched up to the
pussy.
Really?
I'm pretty sure at a time.
Tara.
Patrick,
Jenna Jamison.
Pretty Telltale.
Pussies,
yeah.
There's.
I guess there's some iconic pussies out
there that that's where the flashlight
came in.
Remember of Vanessa del Rio had that big
fucking donkey dick have a clit.
Yeah,
I think it was huge.
Yeah.
There was some gals that have a very,
very endowed.
I liked that in porn.
I don't know if I would show a dig that
in person.
Yeah,
and porn is dirty and real life.
You'd be like,
Ooh,
I don't know if these are the genetics.
I want my seed to swallow up.
There's never posted.
You've seen that.
You were like,
ah,
this one's pretty awful looking.
I'm not saying you don't fuck it,
but you're just like,
that's pretty.
Oh,
in porns I have,
yeah.
I'm going to spend some money.
Whoa,
whoa.
What's going on down there?
What is that disaster?
What the fuck is that?
Something happening here and it's not
good.
Well,
you know,
you've got to think by the time you get
to do porn,
a lot of things have happened or
haven't,
but very possibly a lot of things have
happened to you in this life.
The northern Leslie.
Yeah.
Those things have an effect on
everything.
I mean,
if your face looks all stressed out when
you like had a hard life,
I bet you push it looks.
Look was stressed out.
I mean it only stands to reason.
Old Miner.
He's got fucking hands that are made out
of.
It's made out a clay.
He's getting card calluses and furrowed
brow.
The girls 23 plus.
He's a hard 52
are pussies.
Yeah,
exactly.
Her Pussy comes up with black lung.
She's smoking cigarettes.
Get worried about our bills.
I dated a girl one time.
I had one of her pussy lips,
like ran all the way down there where
bud hall was weird.
That's definitely weird.
Not.
It wasn't like Pussy Lips,
the wrong word for it,
but like the line that her pussy lips
was on where it is geometry fan came
around the hole and then it continued.
The wrinkle continued all the way to
where bud.
Hold on.
That was weird.
That's definitely weird.
Yeah.
Otherwise we would all be going,
oh,
I've seen that.
Someone out there.
It's close up to the butthole.
Yeah.
That's a weird thing,
huh?
The butthole and the pussy are so close
together.
Yeah,
but bizarre design of nature,
nature,
such a bizarre fucking creator.
Who's the total nutrient?
It's the Lord.
Hello.
Could you keep saying nature created?
You won't evidence you have a neutral.
Created
the same proof you have that you know
God created it.
Well,
this is a different type of vagina for
every guy out there.
I think we could safely say that
testimonies of people leaving a chick
because I just didn't like to wear
pussy.
Look,
I've definitely
heard of that before.
Yeah.
I have a friend and her ex boyfriend
told her a story about getting together
with some girl going down on her,
pulling her panties off and she has a
clit that's like a pinky.
Any panic had a male.
He panicked and he made up some story
about picking up his brother,
the airport,
and he ran away and he said that he knew
that the girl knew that he was
bullshitting and they both just sort of
agreed to go along with the charade.
She'd probably had seen other guys like
look at her Dick,
her vagina or whatever.
Her clit clit Dick Freak out.
She just unfortunately had an enormous.
According to him.
I mean he might've been a baby.
You.
I might've been like a little tiny
little baby thumb.
I'm like,
come on,
get over the baby thumb.
Does it really bother you?
That wouldn't shake me as much as like
really awful tits.
Isn't it funny though that like there's
a line,
the cross as far as like inches wise,
like here like this,
like let's,
let's go with this finger.
Like this is no big deal.
Somebody deals with big clip.
Hey,
what's going on there?
Everything.
Okay.
I have to move it like not even a whole
finger joint.
Not a whole lot of like,
this is okay.
What the fuck is that?
What is this?
What is that?
And then that's insane.
Yeah.
If you got up to the next knuckle you're
doing like.
I mean what is that?
Like an inch.
If it's an inch clit,
fuck that better than she was a runaway
and if it's a whole finger,
you're.
It's a dick.
You got to go look at pictures of huge
cliffs.
See that's why they show will never be
on a network.
So curious how big they get a of all
things.
I have google.
I've never googled that.
Bodybuilders when girls take
testosterone,
get enormous.
I used to be so Jamie's freaked out.
I'm not gonna.
Share it on Youtube.
Okay.
Don't know Jesus Christ.
Seed.
Those are dicks or Dick.
Those are dicks.
That one with the girl's tongue on it
down on the bottom left hand side.
That might as well be a dick.
Yeah.
Well this is.
Oh,
what was the one up top?
Those ones up top are dicks.
That's addicted.
We'll get that one that the girls
spreading it out.
Okay.
What?
Now did they say,
is this a bodybuilder?
Because that we're looking at what?
It looks like a two inch Dick,
but I'm talking about a train wreck.
My stepfather.
Jesus Christ.
That's a dick.
Okay.
That's a deck.
That is 100 percent of the Dick Ball's
coming off of it.
Yeah.
What is going on below that monster?
What is that?
Very big clits.
See?
How do we know that this is real?
We just might be.
Well,
that's fake,
but I mean there's some.
It's fake.
I think there's some genetic
differences.
Dominations.
Yeah.
What's that one?
The upper right hand corner where it's a
snail laying on a table.
Go large with that police.
What the fuck is happening?
That is not real,
is it?
She get her pussy eaten by a frog.
Oh,
that's a rubber Dick that's attached to
a table and she's rubbing on her clit.
That's what that is,
but it looks like she's
giving birth to a snail.
That's
hard to explain.
Yeah,
there's.
Okay.
That's a hermaphrodite fake.
It's a fake picture.
Might not be,
man.
That's what's weird because some of
these clips are like,
what?
That.
What was that one?
The upper.
Just feel like we would know who that
person's name is.
If it was a real thing where you have a.
I wish my Dick had that Kinda hang it's
rod number.
Thigh
on the upper upper level.
Okay.
What is that?
Real?
It's hard to say.
What's real.
The problem is with the Internet,
you just don't know what's real.
Did you?
Did you look up doing.
Did you google the word real big?
Hey.
No,
just huge.
Clits.
Real huge clits.
Oh Jeez.
We're going to hit another.
Oh God.
Those are dicks.
There's a lot of dixon there.
Well,
what you got to wonder how many of these
people are hermaphrodites?
No,
wait,
you said you don't mind med pussy,
but go pick your five on the top row.
Oh,
that's not meaty.
That's a.
it's like a butcher shop.
See?
But that again,
is that for real?
Is it 100 percent?
Couldn't be real.
It's got that,
that inside Pussy feel to it.
Just that a gritty skin feel like she
got dragged by a truck on her pussy
postseason on her way here.
You know like tripe.
It's got a texture.
What is that thing that's got three
levels of Pussy Lips,
like aliens mouth to the movie.
Aliens with the little mouth comes out.
It's got eyebrows.
Look.
Follow the eyebrows down to the.
I mean that is like a.
that's an orangutan
orangutan.
It does,
right?
It looks like a duck bill.
It's really a wow.
Pussies can be ugly.
Huh?
Fuck.
Look at that thing.
We all thought,
man,
there's no pussy.
I'm running away from.
Listens,
diseased.
Turns out I could just be misshapen.
Well,
if you look at like WC fields knows and
you fly.
That sort of morphing possibility and
potential to a vagina.
You got a Lotta of it.
Could be ugly.
CanNot be our secret code.
If we had a girl say she had a nice
chat.
Chat,
chat,
chat.
That was Jimmy Durante though.
Same thing.
Yeah.
That's actually better.
We'll go with Jimmy Durante.
WC fields that a fucked up knows,
but I think Jimmy Duranti probably had a
more fucked up,
knows what is that knows come from
alcoholism.
Not always.
My Dad's not a drinker at all.
My Dad started to get a little bit of a
bulb that will get that note.
I mean not like,
oof.
That's a big one at church.
He used to call themselves,
got a clip.
Like that guy made a career of having a
big giant nose look.
This girls kissing his knows.
How strange is that?
Like he became a celebrity for having a
giant.
Well talented comedian as well,
but that was his thing is that he had a
giant.
No,
that's not real,
is it?
No.
That's added onto it.
Yeah.
It seems like it wasn't that big.
Do you think he was.
He didn't get famously was like older.
I don't know.
I'm just not.
Not totally aware of the history because
you always got to wonder what that thing
like that did it.
How much did it affect is like getting
an ass as a performer.
He was famous.
You probably stuck that right up there
as well.
He's got a choice 69 and it's going in
your ass in your ass.
He's the person who's really upset.
The pussy is so close to the Esol,
my leg,
it might be one of those guys that likes
it.
When you got to knows that big,
who knows what you're smelling.
You might be smelling things like a dog
dog.
Dog seemed to enjoy really fucking
stinky.
Smells might be because their sense of
smell is so much more potent.
Let's just start that room.
Or Jimmy Duranti.
As Wolf powers,
wolf smell
senses.
Smell was it explained to me in a real
weird way like the differences between a
person who dog,
but this way is a good way.
If you ever want to like pictured in
your head.
You know how when a skunk sprays in the
air,
it's only a certain amount of parts per
million and you could smell it.
You can be nowhere near it.
Well,
for a dog,
everything's like that.
So like a skunk can spray something and
he could spray something in a block
somewhere and it can be.
You'll be a block away like,
oh,
fucking skunk.
And you smell it for a dog.
Could smell person like that.
Just always.
Everything could just smell things.
It's just a matter of picking these
things out.
So just trying to like,
uh,
like you hear a sound to your right and
you know,
instinctively your ears telling you it's
in that direction.
What were the dog?
It's similar to that.
Especially like a bloodhound or
something like that.
Do you know they have those long ass
ears to make the smell come to their
face.
Know when dogs are like bloodhounds,
they have these crazy long ass ears that
so that the smells waft up into their
face when dogs,
dogs,
like intelligent dogs doing anything.
I'm impressed when they find drugs or
any of that shit or fucking in the cars
as my favorite on cops when they brought
the canine unit and he's like,
that's cool.
We don't have to search your car.
You went the dog smell around the car.
The dog starts like
they opened the gas thing and there's
always some crystal meth pipe or
something in there.
They tried different ways of hiding it
too.
That just never worked.
Like you gotta you gotta put it in
coffee.
A good luck with that.
Try getting that passed for those
fucking dogs.
They could smell it.
You know?
It's terrifying.
They were bringing weed on those cruise
ships.
You bring pens?
No,
I haven't.
I don't have a pen.
Oh No,
no.
Getting off some symptoms.
He's randomly have the dogs.
This is a good one.
Pens?
Yeah.
That's an excellent one.
I'm a big fan.
Thank you.
It's all you buddy.
You're leaving today,
right?
Yup.
Yeah.
New York's got to get its shit together
when it comes to weed.
Carmen,
I hope it's coming.
Anything think if you're carrying an
answer under.
It's just a ticket.
She shouldn't even be.
That shouldn't be.
Leave me alone.
Stupid.
Do you believe in smoking on the streets
and everything?
No,
I don't think you should be able to do
anything on the streets.
It's going to affect anybody else's
health.
Should be treated like alcohol.
Yeah.
Well the problem with smoking is you can
hotbox people you know,
so like if you decided to smoke pot in a
nightclub filled with people,
you can get people around you high.
That's sure that's happened on this
podcast.
One hundred percent.
We've gotten people high that were just
sitting there and they've got a contact
high 100 percent.
So interesting.
That was bullshit.
Recently.
Say that,
but it's not.
It's not.
Have you ever done that place?
Yeah,
I'll have to
talk about it.
It's the only place where if you do a
set where I love it and people smoke so
much weed,
they're like the green out,
so you'll be performing a show in that.
Some guy gets up and he goes,
I gotta go and then he has to go in a
hallway while a nice lady.
Patches like rubs his head while he
leaves,
like lay on the ground right there.
Triply there when triply didn't smoke
weed.
Really?
Yeah.
And uh,
he was just crisp,
defied by the time he went up on stage,
there's no air in the room.
It's all smoke and breathing and pot
smoke.
There was no ventilation.
Dave Smith who was just here A.
Yeah,
it did it.
Did he tell you he did it not too long
ago?
No,
I didn't like the weekend before he came
out here.
He did it and uh,
he was not smoking weed for about six
months.
He stopped and then he's right back.
Can't go.
They're not.
Well,
they changed the coolest.
Yeah.
I'm not sure because money couldn't
guess,
uh,
probably sells weed,
but it's a cool little spot.
It's a cool little spot,
but if you don't smoke weed you cannot
go because you can't stay in there for a
length of time because you realize it's
a different temperature in that room
than the room right next to it.
Don't smoke.
It's just pure people had a bong at
every table.
But it's such a fun crowd though.
Two great kids,
they don't get stoned,
like removed,
like they get,
like they actually sink in the watch
company.
They,
it's definitely like very pro.
So it was very few people in there that
it's like their first time there.
I did it with the iron cheek.
Really?
Yeah,
that's fucking hilarious.
Brought the iron sheik on stage and then
he'd love it.
Oh,
he had a great time.
He poor guy.
He's got real bad hips.
His hips are fucked up I think is nice
too.
He's got some serious wear and tear on
his body from all that wrestling because
he was like a real legit wrestler at one
point in time and like the uh,
what was his bodyguard for the Shaw?
Yeah,
for the shop around.
Yeah.
He's a bad motherfucker.
But uh,
yeah,
he was there.
I guess he smokes a lot of weed.
Was he fun to talk to at all or is he
like,
is he taking him like 20 minutes and
you're like,
all right,
it's plenty.
I had a good time talking to him because
first of all,
I remember him from when I was a kid.
He's always been like this famous
wrestler and he's just a,
he's just there.
He is right there.
It's great
us under version function,
but I want to ask Joe,
what is the top left corner quarter or
that the toughest sport in the Olympics?
His freestyle wrestling served.
I'm certain
he knows what he talks kids.
He's a guy man.
He likes to pull his dick out.
Of course.
Why not?
He's seven years old.
He doesn't give a shit.
Don't get along.
It looks like you already know.
I didn't.
That's a great one too.
What is it called?
Just called chic on Netflix.
That's great.
Yeah,
totally.
and it's,
it's him and his wife not getting along.
It's just him and his just as life in
general,
like not working out,
just kind of sad.
It's kind of sad to kind of prop them up
and send them out to do stuff and like
you always kind of make a living.
He just goes and now his new thing is
just to kind of like freak out on
people,
but he's still like mad and Hulk Hogan
like really?
Because it never broke Keith and he
doesn't know that it's Kayfabe like he's
never bright.
He still is to pissed off as he goes.
Hulk Hogan promised me a rematch at the
Madison Square Garden and you're like,
she didn't know what
he promised me at the greatest arena
where the squirt gun and a rematch for
the title.
He never gave it.
Like,
this is meg.
Oh,
he's always on.
I guess like he was ducking him.
I guess he's just always on.
I mean that's his business.
Got bigger fish to fry.
What happened to his daughter?
I know I'm jumping all over the place.
Uh,
his daughter.
What about her?
She wasn't going.
She was in the public eye for awhile and
then I realize how stupid it will still
be in the public eye.
She's like,
fuck this.
She was making music and shit.
I like when people realize how gross it
is to have people attack you and they're
like,
oh,
back away from this.
You know,
I can remember when a real housewives.
Kelsey grammer's.
Yeah.
Ex wife was she tried to be the current.
Yup.
And they did the fucking attack,
the assault.
She was like,
Hey,
uh,
we're good.
I'm out.
Bailed.
Like he just disappeared from the public
eye.
Like entirely.
I slipped away because she wasn't
desperate enough.
It's what it is like when you,
when you need to.
That's when you have the desperation of
wanting fame.
She,
they want fame already have the money.
Right?
Like wanting fame and needing the money
is such a different thing.
That's why the bad girls club show is
the greatest thing on TV.
Oh,
put a up a trailer for it.
If you're listening,
this is going to be good.
They just get.
They get like we talked about this eight
pieces of garbage and then they just
fucking make them drink and stuff.
I'm going a goddamn house for three for
three months and it's,
it's they have to go to the hospital for
the fights.
One of Europe's this year showed up in
the first day she was there.
The other girl just said she was these
fat pitches or try to ruin my birthday
and picked up like a rocks glass and
bounced it off.
The girls.
Hey,
like splitter,
eyeopener and the other thing is like
they have 15 girls per season because
eight of them get kicked off and they
have to bring in replacements.
Christ season 14,
season 15.
See if you can find the season.
Tina's this year.
This the one I just watched that's not
just grow it.
Go run this,
run this.
They feed them booze morning til night.
Girls just digging stuff ass.
We're back bitches.
It says Los Angeles,
California ladies.
What happened in this time?
There was a women that came earlier.
The three of us got a little bit more
and
we proceeded to go on about all the
other things will stay here in the house
and they proceeded to destroy all of our
personal belongings in the house.
It looks like a tornado
because
isn't going to give me any way
they do.
They broke up each other's money like
their animals,
so they just can't like the worst
people.
They could find.
Make them fuck with each other.
There are.
These are all girls that in two seconds,
if you would just give them a porn
contract,
they would do it,
but they figure they want to sell more
porns by being a part of the show.
Then you're the girl from the bad girls
club.
Why am,
why am I not hearing about this more
often?
This show is is fantastic.
They are the worst people.
It's garbage and then what they do is
then they,
they,
you know,
they filmed the whole season,
they edit it,
then they air it now while they're
airing it.
These girls now watch the show and they
see that all the girls they thought was
their friend shit talk behind their back
or so they were using them for
something,
all the confessional shit and they're
just build up this more.
As much as they already hate each.
Oh,
now they're more irate than they have
like a three part reunion.
They had to break it into three parts.
When people get arrested,
like during the show,
all real 100 percent real.
They got arrested during the reunion
show.
What kind of a person produces a show
like this genius
guy.
He's been reading my mind.
Yeah,
because man,
it's sure.
Fire attainment,
they're going to fuck up,
right?
They're not going to get along great.
They just.
They cut out the middleman of.
Of all the
real world was a show based on alcohol
that shows where it took off.
Where it got exciting was when it'd be
fueled like no one cared about.
This one's trying to get a job in
animation in this girl's and aspiring
singer.
It's like,
no.
It goes,
what happens when you.
When that fucking member,
the guy put his finger in the guy's aids
peanut butter and then that was a whole
thing like that's what people want to
see.
They've cut out all of that,
like shit of like watching live their
lives and have real emotional
conversations and just get them boozed
up and then they're like,
girls were going go karting today,
and then they go kart drunk and then
they're like,
this bitch thing.
She's a better than me.
She bumped in front of me.
I was supposed to be next in the go kart
and that bruise.
Then they get dressed for the night and
they go out and they fight and fucking
bars and limos.
Then they come home and take off their
shit and put on better fighting clothes
and then continue.
The fight gets kicked out.
Every episode has two fights.
He should be in spokesperson.
Why don't you narrate the show?
What we wanted to do is I want to do a
live show where we get transcript,
companion.
I want to know,
trying to get transcripts of bad girls
club.
We just have dudes reek is if you read
what they say with any kind of rational
tone of something is it will be a be a
fucking nightmare.
Is actually a great idea for a show.
I'm in fucking dude fights they've had
this year particularly.
It goes,
uh,
I'm over there trying to work and this
bitch is like,
you know,
she tried to work next to me.
She was writing my workspace and it's
like,
the bitch can't work like me.
You shouldn't be on the same level.
And then it's like having fights like
his face.
He goes,
bitch,
because you ain't on my level.
That's why I'm up in your face because
you ain't on my torque level.
And then.
And then one girl goes,
they throw a punch and then the
confessionals were all like,
I buy that bitch knows who could work
now
and there's blood.
They throw toasters.
It's insane.
I just hurt my eye from laughing.
I got pulled something in my.
I was laughing so hard.
All right.
I'm in,
but if we can get a transcript,
freezer belly room show.
Yeah.
I'm sit there and read the transcript.
If you guys want to practice,
shut the fuck up.
Okay,
let's do it.
Is this bad?
Makes a little larger from the episode.
The Ugly Duckling.
It was a season.
Ward Tunisia,
Tunisia now hosts all the reunions.
She's a big fat black lady.
Hm.
It's hard to know if you have to.
You have to give them and find the
arguments yet.
That's the thing.
Yeah,
because they're just doing them in
general,
but the whole episode would take anyway,
but just finding like a fight,
like when they start getting into it
like a torque level flight
and then they try to have them be like
emotional moments like with like a life
coach.
But that show will be so much better if
you were narrating it.
Oh,
I love.
Since you're such a fan,
you should reach out to them.
It really should.
Do they have a narrator?
Nope.
What they do now,
just like the Internet of Commercial
Shit,
bad girls club.
If you hire Jay Oakerson to be your
narrator,
I will do everything I can to promote
your show.
I will.
I will help.
I will put it on twitter.
I'll make an instagram post and it'll
never stop out on the podcast.
Let's make it happen.
You got you got you got a gold mine here
and do it.
He could do it in an afternoon.
He'll do the whole season.
There is a
say a,
uh,
every season.
There's always a new batch of people who
were idiots and want to do it.
It's a great idea.
They also,
I think I started to find out now that
behind the scenes that reality stuff,
like they'll pull from other shows,
like the cast offs of something else.
Like somebody tried to,
in fact the girl selling this year,
she tried to be on the real world and
she didn't get the real world.
But then she got a call from another
producer a few days later.
I was like,
Hey,
you want to try to be on this show?
And she was like,
yeah,
sure.
Because they just
be on TV.
Yeah.
Well Shit.
The people that did fear factor that uh,
did the casting for fear factor.
They also did the casting for a lot of
other shows too.
And they would do it that way.
You know,
I don't work for this.
You might work for them.
They find people that are like fun and
they go,
Oh,
this guy's like,
you do become like a player.
Like you become like a,
a role player.
Like,
Oh,
this guy,
he's the coach them to.
They sit down with them and they go,
look,
got to be.
Remember how we talked about it before.
You're going to be like really,
really pissed off at him because he's,
he's the guy that had been disrespecting
you.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Don't let him do that because this is
going to be on TV.
Okay.
And you can get them back,
but you gotta you gotTa really get them
back.
Okay.
Got To really get them back and you're
gonna get a lot of air time and so
they'll,
they'll like coach these people go,
oh yeah,
yeah.
So you're watching like this artifact.
And the reality of reality shows is that
it's all just,
it's almost like a curb.
Your enthusiasm thing with like
untalented people.
The scenarios are painted out.
They kind of know what's going to happen
before they get there and they just play
it out with their awful personalities.
But these pieces of shit hate each
other.
They are dead people.
Every one of them stayed behind.
None of them.
But I think if the show is just a wildly
hilarious,
I'm in,
I made any of that.
Like uh,
like reality stuff like that started
with that,
that show they had years back about all
the talk shows like Maury Povich back to
Jenny Jones and all that shit.
Yeah.
Like same thing,
like they really do a prey on the weak
in a lot of ways.
Like,
Oh yeah,
like these chicks are kind of asking for
it.
But uh,
and I,
and as I said before,
like I kind of liken that to springer
now where there's just like people who
are like,
what do they make up?
The stories are not.
It's like,
hey,
we're going to go fake fistfight on
Jerry Springer,
show over a fucking,
you know,
scrawny Hispanic guy.
And they kind of worked that out and
they give them booze and they incite
them to do it.
But the way they laugh at like these are
they're telling like life falling apart
stories and the way that you could even
get the person who's like,
you know,
your boyfriend's fucking your sister or
you already have a kid with the Guy
Kinda Shit at some point of the show.
The fact that she smiles and giggles at
all,
you're like,
this is not that real to her.
You know what I mean?
Like they're making this up to some
degree because why would she,
you would never laugh.
Like you probably genuinely leave the
show,
but they go to them with booze and they
kind of liked that,
lead them in a direction and do it.
But when they did that years ago,
it wasn't always just like,
you know,
cheating shitter who's the father those
shows would try to do like,
you know,
people have tried to cut off their own,
like Dick's,
but you know,
because they hate their own dick,
you know,
try to get,
he's gripping news type things.
And same thing with them is they would
get them all.
Like they'd get these nervous people
just boost them up like that.
Really is like preying on the weak,
just getting them like,
am I just go get hammered and give it a
shot I guess,
but if somebody doesn't eat the wounded
lay antelopes than the wounds,
antelopes will continue to make their
way into the waterhole.
Sure.
Crocodile will starve.
Jerry Springer's a crocodile and all
those jumps on that show their wounds
antelopes he's a genius in way.
I mean,
so some of that 25 years we looked that
up.
It's still going 25 years.
I'm still brand new up.
Shout out to my friend Pete.
The cop from Pete is one of the,
uh,
security guards on there.
He was on season one,
a fear factor.
Oh really?
Yeah.
He's Andre Arlovski's buddy.
Is he the guy who does the start?
That's always one of the one.
Jerry Springer was just go start the
chance.
I don't think he does that.
He's big handsome.
Applicant fellow.
He's a legit cop.
Yeah,
it lacks.
The last time I saw him,
he's actually recovering from gunshot
wounds.
Really?
Yeah.
He got shot on the job and shot in the
arm.
Jesus.
Yeah.
They had a cast on his arm or a sling on
his arm is pretty fucked up.
Whereas the Acom Chicago in Chicago.
Yeah.
Chicago is a scary spot to be a cop.
They do spring or in Connecticut now.
I wonder if that's why get the fuck out
of Chicago.
Not a bad idea.
Probably cheaper too.
I mean that's probably why espn is
there,
you know?
Okay.
I get now.
Yeah.
Espn has been in Connecticut and it's
real close to a New York wwe
headquarters.
Like a lot of people like rich folks
live in Connecticut and make that trip
to Manhattan.
I know that's what letterman used to do
to what Baba booey does.
Does he?
Yeah.
He lives in Connecticut.
No,
Shit.
That's a long ass drive.
It's more than an hour.
Easy.
I could be an hour.
Yeah,
maybe really bad now if you leave at a
good time,
it can be an hour.
If you go into the stern studio,
you're going to Sirius,
Sirius Xm,
and then you've got to go back to
Connecticut and your whole day.
Yeah.
You're.
You're getting home at like the show's
over 11 by the time they get to see him
walking out.
What time do you think he leaves?
I see him walking out sometimes.
Rarely 3:00 PM or so.
Yeah,
because he's got work to do after the
show's over.
So he's probably catching the first wave
of traffic back to Connecticut Western
wrap up show recently.
And when I came out they were like
sterns gonna walk by.
They were Kinda like,
you know,
I don't like shake his hand or talk to
him at all.
And I was like,
Nah,
that Kinda bummed me out.
That somewhat even like,
have to tell you that.
Wait a minute,
what?
Say That again?
Start and walk.
I did the wrap up show,
which is not,
it's John Haydn and Gary.
Right.
And when I was leaving and going back
out to the lobby there,
external to walk by and they were like,
yeah,
I don't like,
you know,
they're basically give me like a don't
try to like,
you know,
hey,
how are.
Yeah,
I mean I wasn't going to anyway,
but I am a huge fan,
but I was like why would they say that
my guests,
because Howard doesn't want to like to
shake hands,
but maybe like again,
it could be one of those things where
they're protecting somebody who doesn't,
who's not asking to be protected so
much,
but who knows,
you know what I mean?
That's a bummer.
Yeah,
and dice will get there,
but dice I can make happen.
I'd like to make that happen.
I really went back in La a probably be a
month or so.
Okay.
But when you're back,
Holler at me twice in the two of you
guys sit down together and do a podcast
together.
I told her,
eleanor,
I'm like,
try to get them to watch my special on
Friday.
Don't do that.
He would love you though.
He would love it.
I think he was a good guy.
You'd see how inspired is by like his
thing.
Yeah,
for sure is he's a good guy.
He's a fun dude and he's A.
Yeah,
he's,
you know,
like we both agreed.
It's very important.
Very important.
That will be a kick for like for like my
step pops was able to call my step up
after and be like,
yeah,
we just hung out.
Like we really.
He was such a big part of me and his
like friendship,
you know what I mean?
Me and my stepfather being like me thing
was pumps.
Pretty cool.
He would love that.
Yeah.
Next time you're in town,
I'll definitely set that up.
Yeah,
let's do it.
He's at the store all the time.
He takes time off,
standing up and then gets back to it.
But he's doing that showtime show now.
Here show.
It's called dice.
Yeah.
Duh.
I'm like,
what is the truth?
But he did that other show too.
It's eight is an HBO show.
Who's doing what?
Who's making it?
Showtime.
Right.
Showtime and associate comedy store type
show,
but that's not that.
But he was.
He played a part in something.
Something else.
Oh yeah,
he was on vinyl.
That's right.
Hbo,
the Vinyl Show.
Yeah.
It was only on an episode,
but he was fucking great.
He's a good actor,
man.
He's really good in that Woody Allen
movie too.
Jasmine.
I saw that too.
I thought it was fantastic in that we
think about that woody allen thing.
What's a little weird,
right?
Which thing?
Bangs his daughter just in general.
A little weird,
but it's not as daughter.
Right?
That's the at the end,
but it's basically his daughter
allegedly.
Yeah.
I mean that's,
you know,
he looks like a drawing of a guy who
fucks his daughter.
Really?
Here's the caricature of that guy.
Yeah.
I have a woody allen stand up a CD,
whatever you wanna call it album.
It's on my phone and when I play I'm
going to have the Bluetooth linked up to
my car.
It's the first thing,
one of the first things that plays the
Thomson one,
but it's a,
it's,
it's because it's the letter a is the
beginning of the thing and when I plug
in my ipod at ace of spades starts
playing every time.
It's a uh,
it's a weird.
It's a weird album because not knowing
that is kind of kinked up sexually.
Like you see how weird he was,
like,
you know,
like it kind of like snuck under the
radar because he was as nebbishy little
Jewish guy,
but he was like letting everybody know
he was a pervert.
Like from the jump.
Yeah.
I mean his voice,
he has a natural voice of the fake voice
you would do as a guy who's like a
creep.
You know what I mean?
Like he lives with that voice.
Yeah.
It's fucking bizarre.
Can you do an woody allen,
woody Allen and dice clay together now?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I couldn't do in bed together.
Take it.
You fucking Jew.
Oh,
as I.
Anthony Kumi always did a great dice man
because like it's getting like the
detail of the oppression of the Ha.
Just like,
just like,
yeah,
it was just like saying hon for
something.
It's nice.
Yeah.
Anthony Kumina can do a bunch of
different pressures.
He's a very good impressionist.
Yeah,
he's great.
Yeah.
He's that dice used to like when they
did a,
if you ever want to listen to a few
seconds of,
uh,
when he does,
dice gets religious.
It's on youtube.
I've heard that.
Yeah,
it's a fucking with us.
The footprints poem was like,
Jesus,
I come one.
There was only one at my hardest terms.
There's only one set of footprints.
Why did you leave me?
You fucking scumbag.
He goes,
that's what I was carrying you and I
cried.
Goes broke down.
It was.
I was over here.
Now I'm over here now with the Lord.
I'm over here.
Are you guys on [inaudible] network?
No,
not anymore.
You were just left [inaudible] that
work?
Yeah,
we're on gas digital network now.
Why is everybody on the sky explaining
network to me?
What's the benefit of being on network?
Uh,
exposure to Anthony's thing was to.
Anthony's a audience was nice for the
time we were there.
It was great.
Um,
the way we're doing it now.
I really like this may be the,
one of the only things that does make
sense to me.
It's the gas digital thing is all of us
in all of our kinds of other things.
So I do the SDR show sex,
drugs,
rock and roll show I do with Ralph
Sutton.
Um,
that's just where we interviewed porn
stars.
And music people,
he has a connection to all music people
in porn stars.
So we interviewed them,
a legion of skanks nails,
me Louis and Dave Lewis has the real
last podcast he does by herself.
Dave,
that's part of the problem,
which is the political when he does and
it's all in the same,
you know,
it's like all kinds of friends kind of,
you know what I mean?
So it's like if you like one of these,
you'll like all of them.
You know what I mean?
Like we're going to be like,
oh,
but if you like elements of them,
there's something kind of for everyone
in this grouping of like this click of
comics,
I guess I'll see you guys have created
your own network.
They did.
Yeah.
Lewis.
And I'm Ralph Lewis and Ralph's.
That sets gets Gomez in Sutton gas.
That makes sense.
Okay.
So then besides that,
I don't actually know.
I don't know what the,
what the benefits,
unless you're exposing yourself to an
audience,
like I said,
for doing bonfire that show I do on
Sirius Xm on comedy central radio.
That's been amazing in so many ways
because it's very discoverable.
You're not playing to like just this
core audience,
like that's people just in their cars
but on comedy central and we're doing
this talk show times a week.
Like that's,
that's done like huge on the road and
stuff like go on the road,
like people showing up to clubs.
Like that's amazing how that hits.
So is that on serious?
Yeah,
that's such a radio.
it's great.
We're going to be extended the days of
that soon.
So this is weird because they really,
they're paying Howard and they pay and
Jimmy,
but everybody else is like,
well that's the beauty of our situation
is we are not employees of serious.
Yeah.
Comedy central works at a contract with
serious for their network to beyond.
And then we are,
we're employees of Viacom.
Oh,
so they pay you?
Yeah.
Oh that's great then.
Yeah,
that makes sense.
Yup.
And with,
we've done it for almost a year now.
We'll get an alert when your
anniversary.
It's going to be great and it's cool
celebrations,
man in Louis and uh,
and my girlfriend both putting in that
skank fest thing is going to be really
neat.
Like Stan hopes coming in for it and
heard todd glass is company wide.
He makes me laugh.
He's so and yeah.
So I'm excited to get a few people in
its first year we're doing it.
So t how todd glass was the.
Well not talking about.
Yeah.
Was it todd glass that a design help
design?
I think it was that helped design
helium.
Oh yeah.
Well that's right.
I think.
Yeah,
I'm pretty sure we talked about it when
he was here.
Yeah.
Alex.
nice atmosphere.
Like he figured it out.
He nailed it.
Um,
so Friday night,
is it Friday or Saturday?
You comedy central special.
It's Friday night into Saturday.
Midnight.
It's midnight at Saturday technically,
but it's Friday night.
Dave said it's fucking awesome man.
Uh,
Dave Smith.
Yeah,
he was there for.
it was a,
it was a hell of a nightmare.
It was really a,
it was above my inbox,
above and beyond my expectations which
doing at Webster Hall in New York.
I'm going to see too that we had a $600
per show and it was great.
We filled it with all fans.
We just did it.
I got the the band when I went on tour
with corn.
I,
like I said,
I was like wigging out about that.
It shouldn't be what I should have
gotten to in that story was when I got
on the tour going through all this
anxiety,
like the second day,
the support act on that tour as a band
called two cents and it's just these
like this wild dudes from like Malibu
basically and some of them from Malibu
silver from riverside,
but they're just like,
they were at a control for like fun
guys,
but I mean like just there on their
fucking route,
first tour bus tour ever for them.
Like they were all excited but they just
got,
took me in.
They just became like real good friends
and they love.
There was a comedian on the tour and
they watched and laughed and supported
constantly and so when I got this
special I was able to get comedy central
to fly those guys out and they play like
the intro,
we make it like a rock show.
And they did,
they blew Cryo jetson and they were on
stage with you are the big backdrop of,
uh,
of the Legion of skanks logos behind me.
So you're onstage and they were like off
to the side while you're up there?
Yeah.
Oh Nice.
And they're in the dark,
but you can kind of see them like lit up
with it because there's like a glow in
the dark logo over by the djs booths.
It's was,
it was cool to be able to like involve
them like that.
That's cool.
That's very cool.
We made it a big,
big.
It's funny,
I was just huge like rock show,
you know,
Marilyn Manson inspired opening and then
uh,
and then I sit on a stool for our
comedy.
Central's taken some fucking chances,
man.
I like what they're doing.
I like the art show already shows
amazing.
Yeah.
He take some big chances with that.
They're taking a big chance with his
roast battle show very big.
They took a big chance on me.
It was,
it was a work.
It was a real like,
uh,
when I got it,
I was why I got so emotional about it
really was because,
uh,
it shows like it came kind of out of
nowhere because three years ago I
pitched him that idea.
I mean,
David Tell,
doing his comedy underground thing,
broke down some walls over there for
like producing a show.
Their issue was never being showing
dirty stuff.
They would acquire someone special in
plate after midnight,
doesn't matter to them,
but putting the money out to produce a
special that I pitched them.
I was like,
let's produce a special that's dirty
uncensored and just show it late night,
you know,
but like we'll make that like a thing,
make it that it's cool to watch it after
midnight.
And uh,
they just shut the idea down.
But they were like,
they liked me,
you know,
and they kind of like hung in there and
I give them tapes and they'd come back
with a bunch of red notes.
You can't say this,
you can't say that.
I kind of just checked out of it even
being a possibility and then like one
day and all the little pieces,
you know,
I said and,
and,
you know,
make no mistake you letting be,
be,
uh,
exposed to your audience like this or
would Ari's done for me.
So many people.
You know what I mean?
It's countless list of it.
Ron Bennington,
Bennington,
sure.
Exposing his fans.
Like all these little pieces came
together.
I mean like he fought for me to be on
that storytelling show.
I was the only newer comic.
There was no other comics from New York.
They brought out a.
Now they are.
But the first two ones I did,
I was the only New York comic and the
first one they didn't want me.
I think they're realizing that the
Internet has kind of changed the the
level they changed the bar and you,
the television sensors are only getting
in the way of commerce like you're
fucking it up because the people can do
uncensored shit in other places like
Netflix.
Netflix doesn't give a fuck.
They don't care.
They gave me zero notes and now you can
say the.
Now you can say shit balls and pussy on
tbs know what I'm saying?
Like on channels like tbs now shift.
They're all close.
Yeah.
Cable is not governed by the FCC.
It's only governed by what the
advertisers are willing to tolerate it.
So they were always able to change the
own.
That's why I said IFC,
that was their big thing.
Like how can I have you just have like
nudity and cursing on their channels.
Like they were like,
damn,
this lady told me they go any because my
show is Iraq was on ifc and we had
nudity and cursing.
I was like,
how is this okay?
And they go,
any like MTV could do that if they
wanted to.
It was just like they'll lose their core
of what they're trying to get you as an
advertising audience.
Maybe not for them.
You know?
That was the big thing with Dave
Chappelle,
the Dave Chappelle when he was doing the
Dave Chappelle show,
they were trying to get him to change
the language because they would get more
advertisers.
They were,
they were telling him he couldn't say
nigger anymore.
They were trying to like cut down on the
amount of this and the amount of that.
They were just looking at dollar signs.
They were looking at taking this
cultural phenomenon and juicing the
blood out of it.
They could of course,
yeah.
I mean that's what they do mean that
they're not creative.
They're not artists.
People in suits make all the decisions
though somehow until you get to that
point that Louis ck thing is like,
uh,
you know,
or,
or like you said,
what you've done here is really like,
you know,
amazing.
Like you give this for free the show and
you give people like hours and hours of
content a week.
You know what I mean?
But it's all on your thing.
You have an audience bigger than,
I mean a comedy central person said to
me yesterday,
I go,
as I'm doing,
uh,
I'm doing the Joe Rogan experience
tomorrow and promoting the special.
He goes,
oh,
that's going to be better than,
than that midnight at midnight tonight.
That's going to be a TV show.
Like this is hits way bigger audience.
You know what I mean?
And you've done it on your own way.
That's like,
that's fucking great.
We just kept doing it to just keep doing
it.
And the thing that is for me,
it's like,
it's not like it's the easiest thing in
the world to do in the sense that it's
fun,
like just show up and you know,
take care of all the pieces that have to
be put into place as far as like how it
gets uploaded and where it goes and how
it gets distributed through itunes.
It becomes pretty fucking easy.
And when it reaches the numbers that
it's at now where it gets to be like TV
show numbers,
it's it.
And there's no end to that.
There's no like there's no cap to it and
it doesn't cost anything,
so for me it's just,
it's all fun.
Your numbers drop for two months,
a little bit.
There's no one looming over you.
So I'm saying to go,
it's like whoa.
I noticed like,
you know,
in this or not even when your numbers
drop,
but it's like you picking up some here
but you're losing the people in
Wisconsin right now.
Who gives like why would you even give a
shit about that?
I would have never made it the way it
is.
There's no way they would've advised me
to pick more popular people as far as
like guests as far as like a really
famous people instead of like authors
are weird.
Scientists are interesting.
People that I think would be fun to talk
to by doing it on my own.
I'm able to do the whole thing,
like book it,
you know,
decide when.
If we know today,
you know,
like we're going to do it at one.
We both ran late.
We just fucking 1:30 gives.
You could have done it too.
It doesn't matter.
It's not like everything else.
Can be done,
they're watching like pounding a thing
like come on guys and it's not a thing
in the world that can reach millions of
people like this that has three people
involved in it.
You,
me and Jamie
right now.
That's it.
How far away before they're coming in to
regulate it?
Just like the free airwaves.
I think they can.
I think the genie's out of the bottle.
I think it's too late.
I don't think people will tolerate it.
I don't think it's possible at this
point without any sort of a massive blow
back.
The blowback culturally and politically
would be so significant that I think it
would.
It would devastate whatever political
party leaned towards that because the,
the ire of the Internet would be
completely focused on them.
Anybody who tried to censor the Internet
at this point in time,
we really try to step in and say that
podcast like,
you know,
no more,
no more saying nowhere.
You know,
you have to figure out when you can,
can say certain things and how nonprofit
said it's a genie gets out of the
bottle.
It's the sort of the thing with like,
uh,
like what was the time of the process of
like cell phone,
regulatory,
whatever was remember cell phone bills
were like,
if you use them genuinely during the day
with any regularity,
your bill is going to be like 700,
$800 dollars or one point.
The words got to the point where it's
just,
there's no more after 7:00 PM that holy,
she's like a sham.
The whole thing which is a shampoo keep
like gouging people go,
this is going to become the new
communication and,
and they'll figure it out around self,
what they did.
Magic Jack Shit like that,
you know what I mean?
Or a orange Internet calling,
you know,
and all that stuff comes around and it's
like you got to make cell phones just
like a regular bill payment that's like,
you know,
affordable for everybody.
Well one,
you already have Sirius satellite radio
which completely uncensored in your car.
Everybody has that.
I mean,
it's so common.
So many new cars come with that.
So what's the difference between data
and podcast?
Nothing.
Well,
podcast is getting in your cars.
They're gonna,
they're gonna run on four g like I
already have podcast.
Most people do have a podcast app on my
phone and when I download something or
when I subscribed to something,
it automatically downloads to my phone.
So when I'm driving around I just press
play and it goes here and we're in.
The best thing about it is if a phone
call happens,
the car pauses it and then you answered
the phone call,
you talked to somebody and then you hang
up and then the podcast plays where you
left it off.
It's not like radio,
it's not like satellite radio.
It's better than all those things with
the on demand now it's pretty good.
It helps.
They are,
there should be on the Internet.
Why does it have to go up to the sky and
come back down the fuck you ain't go.
No,
it doesn't.
Ultimately.
And the thing is like they might,
but they might,
uh,
like serious may jump into that world of
they are like,
a lot of the channels are bringing
podcasts too serious now.
It's a good thing,
which is a good thing.
That's a very good thing.
It's all good.
It's all good in a way,
but you err on,
on open channel.
Right.
But it's an,
it's an antiquated way of broadcasting
things.
It's stupid.
It doesn't make any sense anymore.
It's just like that.
The time is done.
Like that smoke signals you're saying
when the godfathers gone,
that's where I think when sterns done,
um,
all this stuff will really take on.
I don't think he's going anywhere five
years.
He was four and a half more years.
He'll stay.
They're
going to,
they're going to pay him so much fucking
money.
The deal actually though,
it's 12 year deal.
It's five.
It might be a little off on this,
but I'm pretty sure I followed it's five
years on air from about six months ago
or so.
And then they own where they get rights
to play his entire catalog for seven
more years.
Oh,
after that,
I think he's dumb.
He's going to be 67 years old and he's
done this one.
It looks good though.
It was great.
But it means obviously still relevant
show business.
Otherwise you wouldn't have done
America's got talent.
He,
he wants to be relevant.
Right.
Wild.
Why?
Why do you fly back to California all
the time to do that stupid show where
they actually did it in New York?
Did they?
They moved to New York for me.
Just shut the fuck up.
Um,
I just don't.
I just think it's a part of who he is.
I mean,
maybe he take some time off,
but I could see it would be fun if he
started fucking podcast.
Everyone said to me so much money.
He's trying to stand behind that
argument he had with Ari so bad.
It was so silly.
It was,
it was the first chicken is armor I ever
saw.
Well really,
like,
just not even blindly,
uh,
just to.
Because always my friend is just like,
it was the first thing he was just kind
of wrong about like,
you can make a living off this,
but he's way wrong.
I make more money from this than a lot
of other things I do.
Yeah.
You can make more money doing podcasts
then you definitely can look at working
on a local radio station,
which is what he was.
Sure.
Yeah.
It's like,
and doing overnight shifts and the thing
is that is still the shitty process in
many ways for some people,
but if they're doing that,
but there's a difference between being a
radio announcer,
an entertaining podcast,
you know,
there's not a lot of Howard stern's,
it's like the difference between,
you know,
if you want to be an mc at a strip club.
No,
no,
I don't want to be an MC to strip club.
I work as an MC district go because I
need some time on stage.
Right.
Then,
then you become a standup,
like what you want to do,
standup,
blah.
You got to learn how to bring up those
strippers and get to really know how.
No,
I don't have to learn how to be funny.
That's it.
So yeah,
I'm just trying to work out a muscle
here,
buddy.
It's like this isn't.
His argument was weird.
Like you have to learn how to do a break
for a commercial stuff in music or any
of that.
By the way.
Not only that,
like,
wow you to work your way up through
broadcasting and some local job like
nobody wants to do that.
You want to work for somebody,
why would you do that?
And this idea that like podcasts are for
losers.
I get he like,
he's probably in a negotiation with
serious at the time we saying all this
stuff and it's probably part of him
wants to like,
look,
the guy had ultimate power for so long.
He had the ability to,
the ability to make or break careers by
shitting on you with no recourse.
And Ari who was one of the first guys
that owned him,
he owned them.
That video that he did and he did it
politely.
Shit all over him on my show.
Mr Stern.
And then he owned him with that video
where,
because you know how it was trying to
say he's a nobody and then he points to
always get a photo of him with a
billboard on sunset boulevard.
He's got to hit comedy central TV show.
His second comedy central special was
airing that we,
uh,
I mean it was,
it was bad timing.
I said he really picked the wrong mark,
but the thing is,
because Howard is a,
one of the things and he's he showed
that I think are in many ways in
America's got talent and he shows it
with like how he has with guests.
He has come in and when he talks about
on the errors and he's got like,
I don't disagree with all of it,
but like he's got some pretty horrible
opinions on standup comedy.
I mean it's just like he was,
he would not be my gauge for who to
watch or who to know who to listen to.
His little disconnected.
So he does it.
It's dumb that he doesn't know who he
is.
Girl that's comics in the world.
He's one of the top 100 standup comics
in the world.
That's just a fact.
And if you,
you know,
you don't agree with that,
it's because you're not talking to
comics.
That's what I mean.
He's not like,
he knows like,
but he's not being logical.
It's just trying to crush him.
He's trying to crush crush art because
already called him.
An old man,
told him to suck clinics.
Eastwood's old man Dick,
because he hated the Chris Kyle movie.
It's fucking funny,
man.
Like art.
He's a,
he's a gangster but,
but already set them up.
He set him up.
He knew stern was gonna attack him,
stern attacked him and already had a
video response that which is measured
and polite.
Showed,
showed it.
Howard had to get on Google.
He's like,
I don't know what you're using.
Probably Netflix navigator,
a lot of you old folks into the
Internet.
Let me show you how to find my name and
see.
There you go.
Red.
She fear.
Oh look at all this stuff about me.
Look at all this stuff.
And he owned a man.
You know,
it's funny that people in his studio
knew that,
but I've talked to people that worked
there that were like,
eh,
that was like a rough horse,
you know?
They were like,
they were like,
that was because they said like I was
saying,
I was like,
did you guys just want to like,
run in there and be like,
Howard,
just like,
we just let this one go because he's got
comics that work for them essentially,
and they know what it is and like you
said,
but in that thing he's the boss,
you know,
you got to let him do his thing and
he just didn't know the a thing anymore.
He's so used to crushing people too.
He's so used to his whole career.
He's had this ultimate power where he
could just shit all over you like you
did with mad cow with a lot of these
other guys and he just crushed them all.
Crushed them all.
But the playing field's different now,
you know,
wildly.
It's different.
I mean he,
if he comes on my podcast and shits on
Stern,
$2,
million people are gonna hear and see
that.
Yeah,
that's a lot.
And if it then it gets a viral video on
youtube and then it gets on twitter and
facebook.
People start spreading it around back
and forth.
Those things will hit hundreds of
thousands of views like that and you,
you don't have the ultimate like,
like field advantage anymore.
Like everybody can be a broadcaster now.
I mean,
what,
what did you doing?
You're showing something broadly,
right?
In the loosest sense of the definition
of the word.
Well anybody can get on youtube and be a
broadcaster in that sense.
Anybody can get on a podcast and it
didn't use to be like that.
And he used to be.
When Howard did it,
he would do it for.
I mean,
look,
he wielded his power correctly.
He knew how to handle it and he was
dealing with a lot of competitive people
that we're trying to take his spot and
you know,
he would go after them and crush them
with is,
you know,
20 plus million at one time.
People listening to him every morning.
So if you had some rinky dink as radio
show with 100,000 people listening and
you're,
you know,
in Philadelphia where the war,
he could smash you.
It wasn't a damn thing you could do
about it and no one heard you shit on
him and no one could exchange it back
and forth.
There was no youtube.
There was no way for your voice to get
viral.
You only had the operation.
Why that one guy said,
Julia heroed,
everyone that,
uh,
he's a great guy.
Tom Bernard in Minneapolis.
Like,
that's the only town where like,
he came into the challenge.
Tom Bernard's morning show in like last,
like star was there and going like very
quickly on thing under a year.
I wonder what happened.
They just said if everyone's,
everyone's stuck by that Tom Bernard
show,
he still is a radio guy there.
Tom Bernard kidding?
Older guys.
He has like a scarface mansion in that
town.
He really.
Oh yeah man.
He's like,
how do I not know this?
Kind of surprised.
Yeah,
that was a big thing for a while,
right?
Like local radio djs would be like huge
stars locally.
He,
yeah.
His family is that.
They're like,
they're,
well they're doing well.
And then occasionally someone like Bob
and Tom,
they spread their empire out like all
throughout a bunch of states.
And I'm so happy that shows falling
apart.
Seems worse.
People are they bad?
I don't even know Bob.
He wasn't there when I was there,
but Tom,
they're just talking about a bunch of
people who are just disconnected and
hate each other.
Everybody in the studio hates each
other.
Really?
They treated me like a fucking jerk off
here.
They treated me bad too.
I wanted to go.
I wanted to say shit.
I wanted to kind of come out to them and
say some stuff.
But I felt bad because I know it's like
for that club,
that crackers club in Indianapolis,
that's like her promotion man,
that's the big deal to her.
And I like her.
I like ruth and a lot.
I didn't want to get her and a thing,
you know,
with them at all.
But I mean that was biting my tongue for
sure.
I was like,
why are you guys,
the guy just asked what it was like the
Harry Shearer on Wayne's world,
you know,
like,
so uh,
what do you.
So you do you live in New York,
Huh?
And they just start doing something else
and leans back to be like,
uh Huh.
Uh Huh.
Okay.
I'm just looking at his computer is
doing something else.
Like we're looking to cds or something.
I was like,
and I pointed it out at one point and
he's like,
what are you talking about?
Then this chick,
the sports guys like seems like just
disillusion.
They're just angry at you for some
reason for being in there at all and
they all should on the girl.
And then when it goes to commercial,
like the blue angels man,
they split off and formed
and then the fucking chick sits in there
and talks about how shitty everybody
treats her and then they all come back
in and just started over again.
And they were mad at me because I said I
didn't want to do bits will.
That's what happened with me.
I said I'll,
I'll tell you things about myself,
but I'm not doing bits.
Yeah man,
it's,
I guess they just get tired of it after
awhile.
I guess.
So man,
it's got the easiest fucking job ever.
That's what I said four.
It was with the,
with the radio show,
man.
I'm like me and you know,
even with the Legion of skanks,
but all of them like,
you know,
they're all things you choose.
Like I chose to do this thing with Dan
soder on the,
on comedy central.
I chose to do legion of skanks with
those guys.
I wouldn't say we choose it,
so it's like,
yeah,
it's like a thing.
You look forward to doing it.
It's not only that they had a super
successful radio show that brought them
a lot of money,
but bob and Tom,
when I was there were very nice.
They were very nice to me and the people
on there were very nice,
but one of the producers met me in the
fucking dressing room.
He came into me and he goes,
okay,
what are the subjects you're going to
talk about and what questions do you
want them to ask you?
I went,
what?
And he's like,
yeah,
you have to have something prepared.
Like you got shitty with me.
I was like,
dude,
I don't give a fuck.
Whatever you guys want to talk about,
we'll talk about.
I got.
I'm like,
you're talking to the wrong guy.
Like marnee successful.
Like I don't have to do this.
Like I'm doing this for fun.
Like I'm in town.
I wanted to meet Bob and Tom on the show
at the crackers places almost sold out
already.
This is all just for fun,
like don't get shitty with me.
Like it was in town for a UFC and uh,
it was,
it was weird.
It was,
it was like I realized what it's like to
deal with these people that they like
put the clamp on you like get out there
and perform.
You got to get out there and dance.
Like these are the subjects,
but then you have great,
like the precedent.
Steve and Philadelphia.
Oh yeah.
Those guys are great because they're
great.
Yeah.
They don't have the bus.
You're the producer from palm and Tom.
He walked out of the room.
It didn't tick a box walked when I said
I didn't have anything to turned around.
Walked away like I was a piece of shit.
I was like,
you guys,
this is like the worst way to set up
like any sort of a fun interview.
But when I got an Obama,
Tom are great.
Yeah,
the other guy was great to the other guy
that was with them or the Gal or whoever
the fuck it was.
Kitty,
kitty layers.
It was fun.
They were fun.
We just had a nice conversation.
But no,
uh,
that's good.
I thought by that point I got there like
Bob wasn't coming in anymore.
Tom Seemed pissed.
I was like,
it was falling apart.
Fucking guys don't get along after
awhile too.
That's part of the problem,
you know?
Sometimes like a fucking.
Tom's getting all those gundam
attention.
It was the market Brian thing.
Those guys seem to get along.
Do they ever just fall apart?
They just
don't remember.
They were La guys,
Howard attack them too.
Didn't hold a mock funeral for them.
Yeah,
and that John Debella and Philadelphia,
that was a great one and I got to awful.
He,
ah,
he won't let me on the show anymore
because I said I won't give them bits.
Same thing really.
I'm like,
why do you have an opportunity and don't
want to just have a genuine fucking
conversation with somebody.
Why do you want to send me up?
Like,
what are you,
Byron Allen,
people want to hear shark attacks.
What's the deal with that?
Huh?
And then he turns and starts reading car
magazines,
the mustache wax.
And that's how it used to be though.
Before the Internet,
people used to go on these radio shows
and they expected you to do standup bits
and a lot of guys would just
automatically start plugging their bits.
I remember like one of the first times
Marin was on opiod anthony.
He was like doing
bits,
like that's what people used to do.
I remember listening to that going,
Oh yeah,
that's how people do it and go on these
shows and they do bits.
That's no fun.
It's weird.
By the way.
I see the same exact thing I said to you
in that you said to them in that room
where I was like,
just whatever they're talking about,
we're talking about.
They're talking about news.
I was jumping into the news talk.
We're talking about local sports was
just,
we'll figure it out man.
Which just go,
that's a worst way ever to here.
Stand up to in like a fake Byron Allen
style conversation.
Yeah.
We were just like,
you know,
for people in the room,
laughing at it,
sort of and knowing what's coming and
they and they uh,
like to,
to really rub salt in the wound when I
was on the show,
every time they went or came back from a
commercial,
they would just play someone like doing
a bit in studio.
It was like just road hack horseshit and
then they would all,
you'd hear them in the audio laughing
from the time it was live and laughing
now who can edit in the studio with the
same kind of like,
you know,
just referenced.
Just slapping the table and say,
did this to fuck with you?
You think?
I don't know if that was to.
Maybe it's what they do,
but I mean like it's pretty awful when
they're just playing people's.
I mean real like,
you know.
Yeah.
My kids don't listen to me,
you know,
they're all like a whatever,
like the hook line and you know,
whatever.
Like the get her done is of that comic.
Like they all say the.
Were they good or does everyone in the
room says it?
Well,
I think wrec radio is,
it's like every,
everything else,
there's people that are really good at
it.
Like Preston,
Steve,
they're actually fun to fund shell and
then there's people that just,
for whatever reason,
that combination they put together as
far as the team just was toxic.
It didn't work.
If you were at Stanford and sons in
Kansas City that's not,
no one wants you to do like seven radio
shows and it's always like they want you
to do bits and you're like,
we have this argument every fucking time
I come here,
man.
Go Talk.
Yeah.
Well,
pressure to give to you.
To have to do,
I think,
I think they realized they think it's
gonna make you more comfortable.
It makes me so uncomfortable with the
concept of even trying to do that.
I don't think that's what it is at all.
I think they're lazy.
I think they don't want to have to make
something entertaining with you.
They'd just rather you plug in and just
start doing your bets.
Just give us content.
I mean like you saying.
So you're from New York,
Huh?
Yeah,
I mean that kind of thing.
That's like someone that's lazy,
that's not someone who's trying to do
the best possible show they can do and
too jaded to realize they're being like
mega rude to somebody just came in and
you're like,
hey fucker,
it's five in the morning for me too.
Well they know that no one can see them.
Yeah.
So because no one could see them,
they can just totally disengage and let
you just go ahead and dance monkey
because that's,
that's kind of interesting thing too
about a podcast that was so many of them
being video.
Like you're also held accountable for
paying attention.
Oh fuck yeah,
and you could see like weird faces that
people make,
you know,
like if someone says something I was,
I don't think he did it,
you know,
you could get away with a lot more.
There's a lot more things where it's
like,
Hey,
that joke you guys made that black dude
in the back didn't seem too impressed by
that was I went home.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm,
I'm a big fan of podcasts.
I just think it's the best art form ever
for standup.
It's a great thing that that's happened
for staying in particularly in that.
And those are the ones that rise.
I mean there's obviously other ones too
that rise to the top,
but like to Howard's point,
Howard Stern's point,
it's like of course like every shithead
15 year old can just do it.
But like the reality is it's gonna.
It's gonna be like,
you know,
professional well done,
like entertaining but,
but you don't have to be famous and it
can be like,
look at those girls that make that
podcast guys we fucked.
They are always in the top 10.
Yup.
They're always in the top 10 and no one
knew who they were before that.
I mean,
or at least weren't.
They weren't white.
They were still like,
like,
uh,
I mean like in the business and like
lower level comics,
just like their time in.
They sold out the main room at the
comedy store.
I don't know what I'm saying.
It's from their podcast.
So it's pretty impressive.
It's very impressive.
The I,
the idea that that would be for losers.
That's crazy.
I mean they've made it,
like I said it,
it jumped their level on,
that's what I'm saying on their standup.
They're just the years and stand up
through the years and to sell out a
room.
Don't you think there was a guy like
Howard,
he's so famous,
so rich and so successful.
It's probably got to be like so hard to
just hang with people so hard to just go
somewhere and hang.
Well,
he's just accepted like old,
you know,
whatever the quote unquote old Hollywood
to him is now.
So,
you know,
it's like,
it's like Hampton's hangouts with like
Jimmy Kimmel and Seinfeld.
Do you know what I mean?
Like,
it's like that's his world now,
which if you're going to have a group of
buddies to fucking awesome group of
buddies.
Sure.
No,
no,
without a doubt.
I think as people he hangs out with his,
like he does like,
you know,
uh,
are a fun group,
but he's gone that route.
It used to be like,
I'm with you people,
you know,
we're,
we're fucking raging against the Johnny
Carson's and the whatever else,
you know.
Yeah.
And uh,
or just like,
you know,
the upper echelons celebrities were.
Now it's like,
I mean,
he interviews like that drives already
lang,
that's I think is because stern
interviews people they actively worked
to like shit on years ago.
Mm.
You know what I mean?
The Rosie O'Donnell's,
the Kathy Lee Gifford,
these people who it's like,
he's like friendly with now because you
know,
well,
he's changed to way more liberal and way
more openminded and way more relaxed and
way more politically correct.
Sure.
You did mature and there's no need for
him to be extravagant to get attention
or to be outrageous.
No,
he doesn't really have like,
there's,
there's rarely nudity on that show
anymore and it used to be a lot of times
like stripper involvement and,
and when that Howard TV first kind of
came out,
the uncensored one,
there was a lot of like filthy shit on
the show and then it just kinda all went
away.
The bummer for me it was opie and
Anthony.
That was a bummer.
That was a real bummer.
But they split ways that really bothered
me.
Or did they find out physically didn't
like each other for years before that?
Yeah.
But I thought they'd worked it out.
I thought they had like a little riff
but worked it out.
But when the show went on without him,
like I'm happy because I love Jimmy.
Sure,
you know,
and love hanging with them,
but it just always opie and Anthony and
Jimmy,
you know,
it's like that.
That trio was what were the magic was,
you know,
they had,
they had a really good show and I had
some fucking fun times on that show over
the years when we did the baby bird was
me for a rec.
Fear and uh,
who else?
Well,
an opiod,
anthony and Jimmy and some dude threw up
in some dude's mouth.
They did a,
a fucking eggnog eating contest and I'm
pat from when he drank,
he won.
He wins every year when they're not only
diabetes.
So this guy had diabetes and he's
drinking eggnog and I'm not just talking
about drinking some Eggnog,
drank quarts of Eggnog.
And then we were trying to figure out a
way to make it more disgusting way threw
up.
And there's this kid named Pat Duffy who
was an intern and he'll do anything.
He ate dog shit.
He brushed his teeth with dog shit.
He's a,
he,
he ate throw up and cheerios and he
said,
how about if he leans his head over the
garbage can and pat throws up in his
mouth and he says,
okay,
I'm in.
Who named it?
The baby bird.
I don't remember who named it the baby
bird.
I want to say it was red.
It might've been.
I might've been burned put.
So there's Pat.
Enormous man.
Huge.
Remember diabetes drinking sugar,
sugary milk and drinking like a record
number of it.
So he's up to like,
I dunno like 70 cops of this stuff and
then he throws up,
but no,
not keep watching because it keeps
going.
The number,
the amount of throw up is insane because
it becomes cartoonish because it keeps
coming.
Look at that.
Hey guys never break and he's got his
arms crossed.
He's filming it on a flip phone and the
right hand corner.
We'll get it.
Keeps going.
Look,
he just keeps going.
Jesus.
This
is one of the funniest fucking videos
I've ever seen in my life.
It keeps going.
It's insane.
The sheer volume that this sheer volume
look.
I mean there's garbage bags all over the
ground.
Look at it again.
It didn't make any sense.
It's like the sheer volume was almost
impossible.
It seemed like it was photo shopped,
but we were there seeing that live.
I was going to say it has to be like a
really.
It was favorite ops and the memories
always just going to be that I get.
I didn't even have too much of a part in
it.
Look at his face.
That's covered.
Covered.
It's insane.
I didn't have a big part in it,
but it's always kind of cool that it's
such a memorable moment.
Is the patrice laughing at Norton trying
to talk a Bobo's bone or up and down and
he does it and it was patrice.
It's like a famous clip and patrice just
cackling at this happening.
It just happened to be there for the
loan or up and down.
He's got him excited.
He would just,
yeah,
he would just talk sexual shit to him
and,
and he'd sit there with his pants down.
He would get a boner and then no one
will just start talking to him about
something else and then it went up and
down like two or three times.
Jimmy's a national treasure really is,
he's,
he's an interesting guy because he's
like one of the first,
like really open freaks out in the
public guy.
Like an open freak,
you know,
like someone will bring up a tranny,
like wow,
that must've been like,
get excited.
You know,
like he'll,
he'll start talking about sucking a
guy's dank or you know,
being with a tranny and it's just,
he's so open about what he did.
Was He shows though too,
is that like if you own shit,
even if it's like this,
but even if you own it any way,
if you go this is what I'm really into
or if you just like Kinda go like the
distance to be funny.
Yeah.
The world really does like forgive and
forget that even forgives,
not necessary.
Always put like,
and forgets right away.
Like I've never fro the thing me and
Lewis to,
to promote skanks one time they were
doing Kumi network was doing the,
what do you call that kind of
advertising for the other shows like
just the bottom corner of the screen.
It'll be like,
you know,
you want to kind of make fun of that.
So with all the podcasts we're doing
like a little like thing that happened
in the corner,
bottom corner of the screen and we
surprised dave because Dave's the most
like,
you know,
homophobic the wrong word,
but he's the most like least likely to
joke around gay,
like doing stuff at me and Louis just
said like it'll wig Dave Ellis just make
out when we were just taking like we're
just taking a picture together,
like a family photo and then me and you
just start over him just start going at
it hard and sure as shit man,
we did it.
We went for it.
Tongues and everything.
Yeah,
it was gross.
It was hardcore,
Neither of us enjoyed it but we just did
it for the law.
You know what I mean?
We got to laugh but I've never been
like,
no one's ever.
There's never been any backlash for that
in any way because we just kinda like,
yeah.
It's like,
well how could you get back loss
backlash is for people that are trying
to hide that kind of behavior.
It's not for people who are just open
about it.
When they get busted on is like pretend
to be one thing like Jerry Falwell
busted,
but say there was no one that had like a
like,
I'm not going to be a fan of yours after
that kind of shit.
Like I guess a fan,
you'd probably just never heard of them
because there's so many.
Yeah,
I mean more people just kinda like.
It's fucking hilarious.
You'll lose one.
You gain 10.
Like it was a fuck.
This is it right here.
Yeah.
We'll end with this.
But you guys keep going.
Grab my tits.
They got too weird.
I,
I
grabbed your Dick.
Alright,
that's a wrap.
All Right,
ladies and gentlemen,
this Friday night at midnight,
the great big Jay Oakerson standup
comedy special.
What's it called?
Live at?
Webster Hall.
Will have at Webster Hall.
Folks,
please,
please watch it.
Please,
please support support big J.
and you could fall big.
Jay Oakerson big Jay Oakerson on
twitter.
Same on instagram.
On instagram with epic jokers in.
Yep.
And then just skanks bonfire SDR show
and next month he'll be back.
And we'll have been here with dice next
time I can be 100.
That'd be a dream.
Come true.
Alright Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you.
See you next week.
Bye Bye.