Hello friends.
What the fuck's going on?
This episode of the Joe Rogan
experience podcast is brought to you by
Squarespace. If you need a website and
you want to go make one on your own,
good fucking luck to you.
That shits difficult son.
You're going to have to get a program
going to have to learn it. Ooh,
maybe you're smarter than me.
Most likely you're smarter than me,
but for me that Shit's terrifying.
But Squarespace makes
even a dummy like me,
capable of producing a fine website,
a real professional website with all
sorts of different styles to choose from
and you could set up an online store
really easily. Like within minutes,
Brian has done at least 20 websites
while we've done these commercials.
It's that easy.
He just slaps when these bitches together
throws up a template and then boom,
there's a website.
It used to be really difficult.
We used to have to hire somebody is to
deal with some weird motherfucker just
probably is jerking off all day
and not working on your website.
He's probably like,
it takes a long time and we watch
just beaten off furiously all day.
That's all this asshole
does and you need him.
You need him to fix things and
when you need people to fix things,
guess what they don't like doing it.
So those days are done my friend,
go to squarespace.com use the code Joe
and the number eight and you'll save 10%
off your first purchase. A new accounts
including monthly and annual plans.
That's squarespace.com and the code is
Joe eight were also brought to you by
stamps.com stamps.com is a great way
for people who have a small business to
send shit through the mail without
African to go to the post office and get
everything laid out and the
way stamps.com is set up.
You could do it all on your
computer or the printer.
It's all you need and you can get
official US postage for any envelope,
any package and e class of mail and you
just do it all yourself. You weigh it,
they give you a free scale.
If you use the code word Jre,
there's this a bonus they give you
no risk trial, free digital scale,
$55 of free postage and you can try it.
It's really easy way or packages. It
prints everything up. You put it out,
post office takes it away.
It can't get any simpler and you don't
have to go to the post office itself and
annoying someone you know,
you know,
nobody wants that fucking job of weighing
your bullshit. All right? Wait yourself,
no matter what you're selling.
Weight yourself, send it out.
Get your freak on and use the code,
J r e and a save yourself some money.
That's $110 special
bonus offer@stamps.com.
Use the code word jre and you click
on the upper right hand corner.
There's like an old timey microphone.
Click on that and it'll take you inside
and show you all the secrets that is
stamped.com. All right, we're also brought
to you by [inaudible] Dot com that's o.
N. N. I. T. People have been
asking me if the, uh, new, uh,
guerrilla kettle bells are still in stock.
I don't think they are. I'm not sure,
but I know they were almost sold out,
but I think that you can get them on
back order, but they're fucking bad ass.
We can't print them quick enough.
They're very exciting to own if you,
especially if you're a primate
obsessed idiot, like myself,
I'm a very happy when I worked out
with angry monkey and a angry gorilla
kettlebells, it's the shit and
the gorilla one's the new one.
It just came out 72 pounds stop right
now, isn't it? A stock? Yeah. Beautiful.
Good, excellent. Um, they're difficult
to keep around their, their, their fun.
And somebody actually said to me like,
what a move towards was no practical pitch
life is not practical. Okay. It's not,
it's definitely not practical to pay
extra to have a gorilla's face molded
perfectly and do a Kettlebell. Duh. I
want one and I don't even want to use it.
Yeah. I just want to have one. It's
just a fun aspect of life people. Okay.
Everything doesn't have to be practical.
And when it is,
does have to be practical, then it's that.
Okay. And that's okay too. Both are okay.
It's okay to have a big fucking angry
grill of face on your weightlifting
equipment.
You don't have to be all pragmatic.
You have to be one of those fucking weird
dudes and only works out in great gym
shorts either. You know, you could wear
a pink shirt every now and then, bro.
It's not going to kill you.
Okay, go ahead on it.com.
Check out all the strength
and conditioning and fitness
equipment that we have,
including workout videos.
But I'll say this and I always say this,
learn from someone who knows
what they're doing. Please.
Before you embark on any sort
of weight training, uh, program,
get a trainer and scrape
up the money and videotape.
If you can have the guy explain to you
how to do things and then pay attention
to form.
So most important thing,
the worst thing that can ever happen is
you take on some crazy exercise routine
and you fucking hurt yourself.
That shit sucks.
It sucks being injured and a lot of
injuries you can avoid with due diligence.
So please do that. Um, as far as a,
all the supplements that we sell it on
at.com, if you use a code name, Rogan,
you will save 10% off any of
them. Uh, Soko get your freak on.
Use a code name. Rogan. Abby
Martins here. Why waste any time?
Let's get, let's get
busy. Let's rock and roll.
I want what seems cliche balls for my
door. Exactly. It's an awesome doorstop.
Cuban music.
I'm trying.
Good job. Logan experience.
What are you doing?
I don't know.
Was that an accident? That was
an accident. Oops. Sorry folks.
You know what the fuck's
happening? Yeah, it's confusing.
It's confusing to us to be Martin, thank
you for coming and you for inviting me,
man.
I did not know Abby Martin as an artist
and she gave me is fucking bad ass dope
picture that she has created.
It's very sexy. It is. Um,
it's very pornographic.
Can I say pornographic?
If I was like one of those
radical ministered type dudes,
I would say it's pornographic. Of course
there's some. Uh, thank you. So awesome.
I didn't know that you are an artist.
Yeah.
You're a person who main
towns indeed as as are you?
Hmm hmm to shea.
Are you in the porn who isn't?
I mean like, do you watch
it in a minute? Who isn't?
I'm sure there's a lot of people.
That's true.
I think a lot of people say
that they don't watch it,
but they're lying. Really. I,
I do watch porn.
I think there's, um, there's an idea that,
that people have with porn that
those people were being exploited.
That's the weird thing saying like,
you really shouldn't have videos
of you fucking on online like that,
that like doing that for a living,
the only people that are
doing it are being exploited.
But that gets down to a
really weird personal freedom
issue because there's some
people that actually want to do that.
So who's to say,
and it's a weird one because if people
like watching it and people want to do it,
like what's wrong with it? Like
what exactly is wrong? What's,
what is what is really wrong?
If people want to have sex but nobody
wants other people to watch what's real,
what does that really about?
Yeah, I mean, people
do want to do it. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Well, it's, it's all,
it's weird when you tell someone
what they can and can't do.
It's weird because then it gets to
like, hmm, why can't you make a porn?
Why can't you like, what is
wrong with watching people?
Fuck, is there a, is it a,
is it dangerous? Like what's going
on and people getting harmed? Why?
How come everyone's watching it?
How come billions and billions
of people are watching it,
but we're still pretending that somehow
or another, it's like a negative forced,
it seems like, it seems like it's
like an integrated part of our world,
right? I think there's this
misconception about women, you know,
being forced to do what they're doing
and they're not enjoying themselves,
but really, uh, I don't think that's true.
And also I think a lot of porn watchers
are women a lot more than we think.
Wow. That's a strong statement. I agree
with her. Yeah. I totally agree. Well,
you both freaks should
be together. I think, uh,
I think it's probably
the majority of our men,
but I think more women probably watched
today than I've ever before. Right.
It's a strange thing.
You know,
the idea behind it is very strange that
it's such a taboo subject for people,
people that have, uh, that,
you know, we're living in a
sexually repressed society.
Oh, for sure. Yeah. And we're uniquely,
so it's uniquely so because of
all of our access to information,
we were still like sort of riding on
the ripples of the puritans at first
settled here.
Like the ripples of their way of
thinking as sort of a still to this day
influenced like a lot of the tone
and the country. It's very strange.
Yeah.
The entire entertainment industry just
sells sex because they know that it's
kind of this mystique for us because we
had been so sexually repressed for so
long. I mean, compared to other
countries, I guess Europe,
it's so fucking different.
I mean,
I was watching Braveheart on TV and they
blurt out people's acids when they're
moving the camera,
but then they show people's heads
being like beat up against the rock.
So it's like,
why are we able to see someone's brain
being smashed in but we can't see an ass.
Yeah. It's very weird.
It's weird how, you know,
you could have just incredible
violence in a movie and that's fine.
But it's the sex, we draw the line,
we draw a really distinct wine.
Do you remember if there was
a movie a while back called,
I think it was called Brown bunny.
It was Vincent Gallo and him and Chloe.
So you know,
that girl actually had
a sex scene in the film.
He can't play it because it's,
don't even try to play it Brian.
Cause it's actually sex. They,
they uh, they, she actually
gave him oral sex. Yeah.
And it was like,
and people got mad at him.
They were like furious that
they put that in the film.
Like I remember reading this like really
angry review by this guy and he was
actually angry at Gallo for doing
this and making him watch this scene,
this lewd act. But it's, it's a
fucking weird thing where we have,
where it's like, as a society,
like that is the line.
You do that behind closed doors.
You can,
you make out in a movie, you can
fake fuck, but no real fucking,
the weirdest thing to me is the softcore
porn. Yeah. That's fucking great.
How weird would it be this
to be a soft core porn actor?
I had a friend who did that did,
I had a friend that did that and uh,
him and his girl were like taken
it bed and you know, they're,
they're doing the scene together and
they're doing it for awhile. And uh,
in the middle of it she goes,
you can fuck me if you really want to.
And he goes, Nah, that's okay.
So he's just the guy to get paid way more.
If it was,
I don't know what his
motivation was, suspect didn't
want it's cocked to be seen,
but the, um, you know, the idea
behind it. So it's a very weird thing.
We were just like watching people
have sex. Yeah. But it's taboo. Right.
Billion dollar business. Right. But
it didn't. Not really. It's like,
it seems like the business
has been unfairly ignored
as far as like the economic
impact of the industry or on
the Internet on the industry.
Because if you look at the economic
impact of like on the music industry it's
really substantial illegal downloads. Like
really it was, it became a huge issue.
Right. But with pornography,
like no one talks about it.
No one cares who pays for porn. Exactly.
There's still websites where you know,
people would make money and there's,
there's so many people out there.
All the guy has to do is get fixated
on one girl and she, you know,
she just sticks still those inside of
her all week and she's making bank.
But the reality is it's like the,
the actual like buying of the DVDs,
just like a big thing for them and all
that went away and now they get like
paper view from like hotels and stuff.
But I'm sure that must be diminished by
the Internet as well since there's so
many other options. I don't know. It's,
it's illegitimate and it's
like treat it as illegitimate.
It's weird because it's,
it's unclear.
It's clearly a gigantic economic force,
like the need to beat off,
like it's gigantic, but yet it's
ignored as far as like, you know,
like if banks can fail, you
know, we have to prop them up.
If General Motors is going under, we
have to save them. We're saving jobs.
But if porn starts to go
on there, everybody's like,
man, but it was so inflated.
It was so inflated to begin with.
Really the porn industry,
people were getting paid ridiculous
amounts of money for just, you know,
like 10 minutes sex scenes.
What's wrong with that?
I don't think that's a bad
thing. I think, um, it's,
it's what the market allowed. I mean
though they were very valuable then,
but the digital aspect of their creations,
I sort of ones and Zeros,
it could be replicated at, you
know, for as long as they want.
That's where things get weird because
once you have that, it's like, oh,
well I don't have to make a copy of it.
So it's not like an actual DVD.
Like you could just download it
and you can get it in seconds.
That must have just crippled the business
cause you used to have to go buy a
physical DVD and if you wanted
porn that's how you got your porn.
Those like for the longest time there
was a store that I was to go to in Santa
Monica. It was this um, video
store. It was like half porn.
It was like they had a couple of fucking
like Braveheart or some shit. Like yeah,
here's Matt back. Stupid.
The most of it was porn.
This is like in the early nineties and
did you just be a bunch of dudes walking
around? They're shifty,
not breathing too heavy,
trying to get out of there
as quick as they could.
And then the rest of it was like a fucking
ghost town because nobody wants to go
to the one video store. That's mostly
best is when they have the rooms there.
It's like, do you really want to
support and starting to jerk off?
For some people they
have nowhere else to go.
Also for some people they get their
freak on and doing something that's
forbidden in some weird CD way.
Like there's something about going to
a peep booth. It just excites people.
My friend and my, I had a friend who used
to smoke crack and go to a Pete booth.
That was his thing. He would
uh, he lived in New York,
he was a pool hustler and one of his fun
things to do would be a smoke crack and
go to peep booths.
So what does it peak like?
We just get like a glimpse of someone
dance. It's either one of two things,
I guess.
Some of them are like videos.
You can go and get to watch videos and
they would like watch videos and beat off.
And then the other ones
are like actual people.
Like people would be be like
behind glass and you know,
you would talk to them like you,
you walk in and they're sitting down
behind like a plexiglass thing and then
they do things for you.
Me and Eddie F went to that one place
in San Francisco and that's where I,
it was my first time where I touched
the walls and it was wet and, oh,
Jesus son. Yeah. Oh
yeah. It's dark in there.
You see the walls? Yeah. They got beads
and shit that you have to walk through.
It's fucking weird.
The whole idea is weird that you're
allowed to masturbate there though.
I start telling you
that. Right? They don't,
they can't really say
that that's what happens.
It's like one of those things where
they know you're going to beat off,
but they can't say, hey,
come on in and beat off.
Because then it becomes like a
public health issue. I think.
Like people just shooting fluids
all over the place. Yeah. It's like,
and not only that,
they don't just don't want to let you
know that you can do that. Just so just,
just to keep whatever,
you know,
like to keep people from
taking it to the next level.
Because if you tell people that they
can do it, then people, you know,
they'll like, well how come I
can't sell it? You know, they get,
you know what I mean? Like nobody's
like happy with the status quo.
They always want to continue to push it.
So if you tell people they
can beat off in there,
they're just probably going to be about
fucking each other and they're probably
going to go crazy.
They're going to do,
they want to get to want to have sex
there and then we tell them that's okay,
then they're going to want to kill people
that decline them. Porn at
least has raised the quality
of the prostitute though.
So we should just, you know,
think about that for a second.
Well that's another weird thing.
An article where a girl who was a,
uh,
it was a really very smart article about
a girl who used to be a porn star and
then became a prostitute.
And she was saying that it's just,
there's not much difference between
being on the set and being in a brothel.
You know, that it's just like,
there's no cameras where, you know,
just you're just having sex and sometimes
you don't want to have sex with that
person. You just do it because
that's your job. And I was like, wow,
it's weird that we like, that's a,
that's a real issue. Like you, you like,
you tell someone that someone's a
prostitute and that person's like,
oh my goodness,
you go there. There's that website
that lacks illegal. I mean, yeah, that,
that luxury companion website. Have you
ever heard of that? No. What's that?
Hi Claudi prostitute website. But the
sad thing is, is if you go through it,
it's all porn stars. Like you're all
like, man, I actually have sex with her.
That's crazy. Well that's a sweet deal
if you're a fan. Yeah. It's not like,
you know,
you could for $10,000 or $20,000 can
go play basketball with Michael Jordan.
And I was like, Bitch, I'm busy. But if
you're a fan of one of those gals finger,
the task had to be really weird to be
a dude is like super obsessed for the
girl. Wow. What a crazy chance.
It's one thing to meet strangers,
but to meet strangers who are sexually
obsessed with you and get to have sex
with you for money. Like that's a
strange energy exchange right there.
That's some high level shit
should do that too. Like my room
late John, why are we doing?
And we're like the shy ones like oh no
men. Yeah, well it's, it's
looked down upon in bolts.
As soon as is involved it's like
money and sex for some reason did not.
Anytime it's connected, whether it's
a Gigolo or whether it's a girl,
prostitutes like terrible.
It's awful.
Like you're connecting money and sex
money and everything else was cool.
You know,
money
dictation, sex to sell
everything. Yeah. Did you hear,
did you guys hear about that dude who
killed a prostitute and use the self
defense thing and he got off because
she stole money from him and she didn't,
she didn't actually fuck him.
So then he was able to get off on self
defense in some weird fucked up lawn.
It was like one of those stand your
ground things except I was like,
you stole my money and didn't
deliver the goods so I can kill you.
Oh my God. Wait a minute. What's David?
I want to say Texas, but I don't,
what's the story? How long ago was this
story? Just say, dude kills prostitute.
Oh my God. Gets articles are going to
get probably more more hits on Google.
Then baseball bat in the ass.
Guy Kills Prostitute
or baseball bat in the end gets off. I
went to, I went to look once just as,
because I didn't believe it was true.
Someone told me that there was a video
of a young girl with a baseball bat in
their rump and I went for the Google.
But when,
when you go for the Google search,
the numbers are insane. I'm going to,
I'm going to do it. We'll see what the, a
recent one is. Baseball Bat and ass data.
Drm on our friend Dana. She's a sweetie.
Um, let's see how many hits.
Okay, you ready for this? Yeah.
5 million.
900,000 results.
Oh Geez. Wow. Okay, whoa. Knocking.
Choose images because the first photo
that comes up is the worst Croesus image
I've seen. Oh Dude. Jesus. What
the fuck is that? What is that?
Someone being rude, being rude.
I don't know. Let's say it's not,
let's hope it's not.
Okay.
Yikes. Yeah. Whoops. And then it's
like Todd's a rigid stuck in this Abby,
you fall or something immediately looking
at bedtime back in the ass because of
her painting when we started talking
about porn. Oh yeah, yeah, that's right.
It's your fault when you still look.
That was a playboy playboy from the,
like the 70s and sixties. Women
look pretty good today. No,
I just like everybody's good
natural boots. Yeah. Um,
more voluptuous.
I think they're going to have within our
lifetimes a different work around for
that and it'll be a biological
work around, they'll,
they'll have something where you
can actually grow a breast, your,
your breasts or grow larger. I really
think that's going to happen. Yeah.
I think there's going to be all sorts of
weird genetic changes over the next few
decades. The stuff that
they're working on right now.
[inaudible] I talked to Ray Kurzweil,
he told me that they're
working on artificial blood
cells that allow you to hold
your breath under water for four hours.
Okay,
sweet. So you could just hop in a
water, hop in a tank of water, ankle.
And because of these artificial blood
cells are so efficient that you would have
enough oxygen. We, you'd hold your
breath for four hours. That's like,
he thinks within our lifetime.
That's awesome. That's a
mind blowing fucking, yeah.
Yeah. So I think like boobs, it's
going to be an easy one. Yeah.
That's going to be easy. They're just
going to give you the boob bug. You know,
it's like a,
like a version of the flu.
You get sick and your tit scroll like
monsters. That's what's going to happen.
They're probably going to be no
ugly people in a hundred years.
Everyone's going to be super engineered,
genetic looking doctor Manhattan men,
and uh, every woman's going to be like
the perfect sexpot. They're gonna,
they're gonna have that down. There's
going to be no like, why would you do,
why would you have bad teeth when
you could just brush? You know,
it's going to be like that simple, right?
Like, did you go to the Jane Place?
What do you want to like trust, random
chance. And what your body's like,
are you fucking crazy?
You want to trust random chance.
I'm one of the most important things
is far as like social currency.
We all agree that like beautiful
people have like this amazing power.
They have an amazing power
to get people's, they have
like you meet at like a big tall, handsome
man with a perfect face and you just,
you just go, wow, he's here. Right?
You know, it's, it's totally metro.
It's a complete natural thing for human
beings to do, but it's fucking weird.
It's a lottery. And how much would that
fuck up with a social order though,
if everyone knows can throw it into the
toilet, it's going to be a goddamn mess.
We're going to not,
it's like how we bill are lazy because
we don't have to go chase quail to eat.
He just go to fucking Jack in the box and
get a chicken sandwich is fucking easy.
You'd take it takes three minutes
and it's already cooked. You know,
you give him some paper
and you're done with it,
but I think that it's going to
be much along the same line.
It's like we're lazy in that it
doesn't take much to get us fed.
So most people just sort
of skate by in life.
There's no like real desperation of
fear of not feeding in this country.
At least, you know, for
some people it's a struggle,
but one day it's going to get to the
point where that's the way it is with
everything it's going to be.
That's the way it is with your looks,
you're going to be able to just
look like whatever you want.
There's going to be people that
don't even look like people.
People are definitely going to
want to look like dinosaurs. Well,
people that are like
furries and shit like that.
If they could like genetically altered
humans to be like a dinosaur type person
and change your body and then
you have to eat goats and shit,
kill 'em with your face, people
would sign up. Yeah, no doubt. Right.
I'd probably be a huge counterculture
of does dinosaur Tucker's. Yes,
but I always thought it would be so
interesting like a thousand years from now
if the,
you know,
if we died off and then people in the
future came back and dissected our
skeletons and found remnants of like
silicon and they're like, what the fuck?
Where people just like inserting silicon
packets and their body and an APP
implants, you know that that exists
now. I can't imagine I have one of those
just getting like a shield just underneath
your skin cause you're like, ah,
I don't want to fucking try to do crunch.
Well I think it's a surgery.
Um, I might be wrong,
but I think what the APP thing is,
is they sort of like suture it in to
create permanent six pack indentations.
So it's like, just like I'm talking
shit, I've watched a special on it,
but it was barely paying attention
because I was like, do some crunches.
You Lazy Bitch. Should I change the
channel? I was like, that's so ridiculous.
Fake Abs, right? Dudes get fake
calves have implants. Yeah. Yeah.
If you have skinny calves,
I guess.
I think I look at a man, I'm like
30 doesn't have big enough calves.
Well what happens?
I think with uh,
the bodybuilder type gentlemen is the
same thing that happens to anorexics.
I think it's been pretty much proven is
that they have a distorted opinion of
how they look. If some of
those big bodybuilder dudes,
they don't, they don't like,
they won't expose their body. They cover
it up. They have like blankets and shit.
They were everywhere and they were like
four or five sweaters. Like it's weird,
like they don't show their body,
they feel small.
They were a lot of layers sometimes.
And some of these guys are fucking
mountains, like human mountains,
but they're wearing like two sweatshirts
and a tee shirt over that. And you know,
it's almost like they want to like,
yeah, it's gay. They get crazy.
Some of them can get, and it's not all
of them obviously, but you can get crazy.
And so they look at their calves and look,
fuck deuce.
We should have a little cough. And then
just stuff, some shoe horns in there,
pop them bitches out. I mean, I don't know
who the first guy was. It went for it.
It was like,
I'm fucking tired of my fucking bullshit.
Like MTV special on it like 10 years ago,
this little like fucking squarely kid on
the beach. And then after it he's like,
everyone's looking at my
calves. It's like, yeah,
cause they look fucking huge
compared to the rest of your body.
Why is so have you seen this is donating.
People are getting donuts putting
their their head. Oh, I've seen that.
It's céline what it is.
Is it a weight? Yeah.
That's why they do it.
It's um, they pump of,
they actually inject saline into their
forehead and they like put like a little
indentation with her finger sticks.
People are so strange.
Some woman who was this beautiful
model and Korea and then she got,
she doesn't like her face with a
bunch of olive oil and ships couldn't,
they would not give her any more plastic
surgery. Now she looks insane. Yeah.
It was cooking oil. She was awful.
Injecting cooking oil interface.
Poor girl.
I know.
Yeah. The, the human mind
is so fucking complex.
It's so strange because it's like,
it seems like most of your life
is almost like a balancing act.
It's a balancing act of happiness
and friendships and laughter and
accomplishments and not losing
your mind along the way.
But for a lot of folks,
somewhere in that dance is just too much
and they just go towards lose your mind
at full steam ahead and then you're
sticking needles and cooking oil in their
face or we've all seen the,
the one actress that it will not stop
fucking with her face until they become
like almost like hideous
or, or, or pitiful.
You know when you look at them
you have pity like, oh no,
what did she do this thing to her face.
It's a very strange,
strange aspect of,
of the human beings had every now and
then you'd take what looks like a totally
normal person. He's like
keeping it together for a
long time. And then one day,
yeah I'll have to crazy town. Fuck
again. Tick Kiva together anymore.
I give up, I'm just fucking running. And
it's so fucking obvious too when they,
they overdo the plastic surgery
cause everyone just start,
it looks exactly like it's fucking,
well it's, it's, you know what it is.
You get delusional and you
think it's going to fix.
I had hair transplants
and I had my first one,
I think when I was like 26 I had three
of them. Why, why is still young?
Just cause, cause like my hair was
falling out. I was fucking freaking out.
I was freaking out when my hair was
falling out because I was on TV too and I
was making a living like as an actor at
the time on news radio. And I was like,
oh my God, my fucking hair is
falling out. I had new one,
it was falling out for a while.
I saved it though with the Minoxidil.
Minoxidil was hanging in there.
But after a while it was like,
it was still falling out. And I was like,
God, I got to do something about it.
I should have never done anything.
I should have shaved my
head from the beginning.
And so when ever kids ask me online like
dude's ask me, Oh fuck fucker, frequent,
oh Moyer and lose my hair, shave
it, bitch. Just deal with that.
Just just accept the fact you
don't have any hair looked bad.
It didn't look good Mike.
I never looked at my heroine.
It was always like, like, oh I guess
I got hair up there now, whatever.
But you know the way they do
it as like a single thing,
it's not like the old way of doing it,
but they take it big strip of hair.
So I have this like big
scar in the back of my head,
like a smile for the rest of my life.
But I'd rather have that like first
of all it's a good public service
announcement. Like if you thinking
about doing this, just look at my head,
don't do it. Just shave your head. And
then the other thing is that it, it's,
it's almost like what you're
doing is it's a screw ball thing.
Like it seems like it might work a little,
but then as you start doing it,
go why Wayne but isn't their options?
Is there another route that,
and the other option is just let it be
what the fuck it is and stop freaking out.
That's the other option.
There's always the best option rather
than getting knocked unconscious and they
take a chunk of meat out of the back
of your head and drill fucking holes in
there and implant those. It's
nuts. Oh yeah. Jason, what's his
name's Jason. Alex. Jason
Alexander, I think. Yeah,
he wanted to go back in
time just like yours.
So it kind of looked like
he was about to go bald.
See why would just make it more realistic.
Wow. Yeah, he got 'em. He got like
a super cool hairpiece I guess.
Yeah, it's kind of weird because like
it would chick wears a wig. It's like,
you know, no biggie. You know, like,
like when Madonna would
wear wigs or when lady Gaga,
I would wear some crazy wigs. Like nobody
tripped. But if a dude's wearing a wig,
well is that really a little too
far? Too Far? That's beautiful.
It's real. I would love it if
he did that. If he gave up on
dying his hair, like if imagine if
he was all white like that for real.
So he gives up on dying his hair and
then he just has a crazy white hair piece
goes for it. And like, I would actually
really sorcerer. Totally respect that.
Like a sorcerer. Michael
Bolt. Yeah. Hey whatever man.
That's what the dude wants to look like.
But for me,
I can tell you that it was a big mistake
on my part and it was one that I made
and getting hair transplants out of
insecurity because I was young and I was,
you know, thinking like, oh,
I'm not going to have a career.
I'm going to be a bald loser. You
know, like that's what I was thinking.
That's a society drills into us.
And if you,
and if you want to have a solution
to something, you go research it.
And at the time it's
very little internet too,
so it wasn't as easy to research
things. But you know, you talk,
do you find like a doctor who does it
and you talk to them and they show you
photos and you're like, oh, this is going
to work. Oh boy, I'm going to fix my hair.
And then the next thing you know,
what am I doing this stupid fuck.
And I guarantee you probably most women
that one of doing something wrong,
whether it's a lip thing or a nose
thing where they're like, oh Christ.
And they look at it in the mirror and
they're like, what the fuck did I just do?
And then you could try to fix it.
Like I've heard of girls that have had
girls Gore all where that came from
corals than I've had too many nose jobs
and they have to get like cartilage
removed from, from the rib, and
then they recreate the nose. Yeah.
I talked to this guy that told me about
this operation that they had to do that
is,
she was in her 20s to,
she'd had too many nose jobs already and
she'd ruined her nose and her nose like
Jackson, dude. I mean, I know he's
a, yeah. Yeah. This girl had like,
well her nose apparently like started to
like go in after the bone and like it's
kind of sunk in because there wasn't any
cartilage there to support the rest of
the nose.
Ooh,
Ooh. Yeah. It's weird man. It's weird.
Some people just have bigger noses
and they just got to deal with that.
It's our righty. It's
going to be okay. You know,
I saw Michael Jackson impersonator on
Hollywood and vine last night with like a
little kid in a candy shop.
I was like,
this is a ridiculous
moment in time whose kid is
I also got robbed. You
got wrong. What happened?
I got like bum rushed by but like a crowd
and then they just must have lifted my
wallet right out of my purse.
It was crazy.
So they just ran into you and bumped
into your bag and you didn't notice it?
Yeah,
and I was like,
how the fuck am I going to fly?
Apparently you don't need an ID to fly.
You just need to go. There were like,
we need to put you through
like 20 security tests.
They'll come to the airport two hours
early. I was like, God dammit. Yeah, yeah.
Have you ever had that happen before
where you get like roughly frisky?
No, but I have, uh,
gotten yelled at by a TSA agent because
I didn't want to go through the body
scanner and he was like, what do
you, his celebrity? He's like,
only celebrities don't want to go
through the body scanner. And I was like,
why are you, I was like, this is crazy
that you're talking to me like this. Like,
what the fuck? This is nuts. It's
an option, isn't it? Yeah. Yeah.
He was just like totally demeaning.
Mean I can in front of everyone and nuts.
Why would celebrities not
want to go through the new
ones? Like, it's like, yeah.
Why would you want to get molested?
I mean,
well, it's, I've never
had it happen to me.
Everyone has always been pleasant
with me. But, uh, Graham Hancock, uh,
who's been on the podcast several times,
he's a good friend.
He went through one and he said this dude
like just was aggressively sexual with
him, like grabbing his, his body. Like
it felt like he was being molested.
Like,
I shouldn't say aggressively sexual,
but he grabbed his cock and the
whole thing. I mean, like he said,
it felt like he was getting raped, like
obviously not as extreme, but you know,
it's,
it's like a form of a violation.
And he was really shocked
by it and he wrote about it.
He was shocked enough that
he didn't just let it go.
He sat down and wrote some stuff.
Yeah.
Well there's this report that came out
that said that there's so many more cases
of malfeasance and misconduct and the
Tsa than any other government. I mean,
this is like 20 times more. And so there
was this investigation done to find out,
well, why is there so much fucking
like crimes happening? Like robbery,
um, sexual abuse and stuff. And it was,
and basically this representative
figured out that they don't really do
background checks. Oh my God. And they're
just kind of skipping through this huge,
uh, you know, you think that you
would, so basically they're hiring, uh,
pedophiles and child molesters.
What they found out. Yeah.
No. Well, yes. Well not nice people
too. Sure. We should say that.
I met a lot of really nice
people to Tsa and people.
You fucking government chill, relax.
No, I'm just saying I'm just trying to,
in the interest of fairness,
I know some of them are just folks that
needed a job and that's just the reality
of the situation. Graham Hancock
got molested. He'd do a little bit,
what are you going on?
It's a thing where I think that it,
it can be pretty well argued that there
needs to be some form of security,
but it's also a thing that is much like
many other public service jobs is that
it should be really respected and it
should be something you're paid well for.
It should be a difficult job to acquire.
And I think it's a matter of priorities
and if we shifted those priorities that
we could make a sizable change in
the way the whole thing is run.
If you made it so that people
were, first of all, it's made,
it made it so that those, those jobs are
a little bit more difficult to come by.
And that the people that do do a Dubai
get background checks and it's a really
good job to get with excellent benefits
so they don't feel left out of fucked or
disenfranchised. It's, it's
something that's worth,
and then so also worth adhering to a
certain code of conduct because it's a
really good job, you know, I think when
you have a John, but it's, you know,
yeah, get a frown. Just getting
paid like fucking minimum wage.
I think we're a little more polished.
I think it's a use useless agency.
Well, how do you think
that you should do security
did before nine 11 how did that day was
totally created in the wake of nine 11
it's a total,
the new government agencies like the
Department of Homeland Security and just,
I mean, think about it, the
hijackers brought on what knives,
like you can still bring those in.
This guy,
Jonathan Corbet basically expose the
fact that you can just create an insulin
pocket and bringing to whatever the fuck
you want through these body scanners.
So they really have like a
huge security breach. So,
but when you go back to why the body
scans were implemented like an in sown
pocket that's like silver or
something. Oh, so it has to
be a sign. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And you can carry anything
through. Oh Wow. Yeah. But I mean,
the reason that the body scanners
were implemented in the first place,
he says Michael, Michael Chertoff was, uh,
tied up with rape rapist scan, which is
also the name of the body scanner. Right.
Rapiscan rapid rapid scan,
but I call him, right.
[inaudible]
well it wasn't, I got a patent,
so Rapiscan I've got a patent,
I'm not changing the fucking
name because it adamant,
some crazy multimillionaire
guy who just was nuts. So yeah,
sky was, I was running the DHS and he, uh,
he was tied up with the lobbying firm
and profiting off these body scanners.
And so they just put them in all the
airports and they don't even really work.
Even Israel,
the Israeli government was like,
we're not going to use those because
they don't work like they're not going to
stop terrorism. So they're
totally pointless. Uh,
it's just like a money making scam.
Wow. Yeah. Well, but here's
the question. Before nine 11,
they did something right that you
went to reddit radar detectors.
You went through just the regular
metal detectors. Right. And they still,
they x rayed your luggage. No, I
don't know. I think they did. Yeah.
I feel like they did. Didn't they seemed
like they did, but yeah, they did.
Um,
between then and now it's
just gotten more complicated.
Is that what the idea is?
Well, they just, you know,
they want to dehumanize us as much as
possible to make flying the worst fucking
thing in the world is,
and now I get to take off your shoes.
The liquid thing is completely absurd.
That was based on something that
was totally, it wasn't fake,
but it was like these mentally unstable
people who we're trying to mix liquid
explosives that it wasn't even going
to work. It was like totally pointless.
They weren't even able to do it.
So then they just punish everyone by
making everyone put little liquids in bags
and it's just ridic.
Maybe they found like proof of
concept after that that like yeah,
somebody could go on,
someone could ship who bottle full with
c four that looks like conditioner.
You can't bring snow gloves on.
Snow Globes.
I just saw that in a little shake.
Like a paperweight. I didn't.
I was there a snowglobe terrorist that I
miss. Like someone trying to listen to.
Someone was coming at me
and they were trying to get
crazy. I could fuck you up with a
snow globe. So imagine a pitcher,
a really good baseball pitcher and a
snow globe. Oh my God, you're a dead man.
It's going to kill you with that thing.
It can be used as a weapon,
but now the TSA is actually taking
it so fucking farm. And they,
I just saw this video where this
woman comes back from her trip,
she gets her car and there's a little
note in her car that says Tsa inspected
your car while you were
gone. She was like, what?
Apparently it's a local jurisdiction,
a thing they can the, the
local, uh, it's not a TSA thing.
It's a local security for the
parking lot. And the TSA, yeah,
in various districts I think has very
different ways of approaching these types
of situations.
But if they choose to,
for some reason I think
it was like a valet car.
She valued her car and for whatever
reason they chose to see search it.
But I don't think what they're
saying is this not a TSA policy?
I think that was the, the um,
um, the, the response to it,
but it wasn't TSA policy that it
was a local thing and someone did.
So it's not something they plan on doing,
but it could have been something they
were like testing the waters and then
people freak
cow and then they're like,
[inaudible] we have a sign up.
And she's like,
that sign wasn't here before.
It's like we're going to really
inspect your car. Yeah. Oh Wow. Well,
I want to know who to believe their, that
gets weird. I wish I knew, but still,
even if there is a sign, if you're not
told, hey, we're going to search your car.
I mean, it'd be real specific
about, can't just have a sign. Oh,
I might look through your shit.
You're like,
are you didn't read everything in this
entire office before you gave the Valet
Dude your keys. I'll might
steal your change. Sorry.
I will have to sign. Just so, I
mean, it's, it's grown so much.
It's such a waste of money.
I just think, I mean, what,
what have we done really with
the Tsa? Well, the, the argument
I would say, um, I don't disagree
with you, but argument, I would say
if I was, you know, doing
the counterpoint was like,
think of how many lives we've saved.
Think how many terrorist
attacks were stopped.
Thinking how many people did not try
things because they thought they would
never get through the infinite matrix.
That is the TSA line of integrity
in you're right then you're right,
it is hypothetical's but a
certain point in time, you know,
is it hypothetical that if you didn't
have vitamin C you would get scurvy?
See where I'm going with this? I'm
not going anywhere folks, blacks,
I don't believe a word I'm saying. Um,
I hear you. I know what you're saying,
but I think that there should probably
be some form of security just with the
reality of the world that we live in.
I don't fucking trust people that much.
I don't trust people to, I just feel
like if there was no security at all,
I would have to like have a
lot more faith in our society.
Go back to what it was before. It was
totally fine. What is it before though?
Do you know the specifics?
I don't know if it was like,
it wasn't a private contractor. I
mean, I think it was government agents,
but it was just very,
uh,
it wasn't like a huge multibillion
dollar wasteful agency that is just like,
is it this one of those things where,
and I'm obviously not a politician,
nor do I really even understand politics,
but is it one of those things where when
jobs get created and a business gets
created,
it behooves them to enhance that business
and spread that business and make that
business larger. Whether that business
is Chick-Filet or their businesses,
the TSA, once it's an actual business,
so it's not a government agency. Oh,
it's a business.
It's a private business.
That's where things are always going
to get weird because as soon as you can
profit and like it's not just
the state profits. No, no,
no individuals profit
and they have motivation.
And then they also can have things
called lobbyists and they could spend a
shitload of money to try to get laws
pushed by that make their business more
profitable and make more what? That's
crazy. That's where it gets crazy.
You can't differentiate anymore
between the corporatist and the actual
government employees. So
it's hard to tell. It's like,
it sounds like you're calling for
socialism now. You fucks without me.
That's what I'm hearing. I'm hearing a
bunch of fucking anticapitalist nonsense.
Why? If it wasn't for
capitalism, which is so true.
If it wasn't for capitals and
we wouldn't have shit, you know,
communism doesn't work.
You can't get people to work
unless you give them a reward.
If you want cool shit,
you want a Samsung phone,
you want to be able to watch TV on
a big screen, it's flat. You get it.
Someone's going to make that,
okay, you're not going to do it,
and the capitalism is the
only way that shit gets done.
If the whole world is
communists and socialists,
that stuff doesn't probably get made. Why
are, those are only two options though.
My question because I think there's
a lot of flaws and capitalism.
You're so right.
You know what we need,
I think is some sort of moralism.
Capitalism in a,
not just not capitalism, not
communism, but moralism, ethical ism,
and it's something where it's just
like, John, can we figure this out?
It seems like this cannot be worked out.
Like we don't have to like live
like one person has to die,
so that all may live like it's
2000 and fucking 13 or any people
kills me.
Like I get this,
I see the potential that we have and
we're just fucking squandering it. Yeah.
It's like what the fuck?
We know that we can have clean energy,
we know that we can have this,
we know that we can live compatibly
and harmoniously like with the earth,
but we're just fucking raping,
pillaging shit. I mean I think,
I think it's a flaw in
capitalism to see what happens.
Monopolies form and then it
buys out governments. And
you said a flaw though,
or is it almost like a built in
mechanism designed to encourage movement?
It's all, it's almost like the, the
way that things really get done,
but you need some incredibly
greedy fucks if this is the trend
that's designed within capitalism
than isn't that fucked?
Yes, it's definitely
fucked. But the question is,
is it this way because this is the
most efficient way to move this thing
forward.
This is the most efficient way to
continue to produce new technological
innovations, to continue to push
our ability to access information,
whether it's like willingly given up
through the internet or whether they're
watching your cell phones like that.
All of it is kind of connected.
Well, it's interesting because we hear
a lot, you know, um, you need reward,
you need value,
you need people competing
and that otherwise you won't
have innovation and you
won't have these new technologies.
But I look at it, you know,
we had innovations 20 years
ago that cars can run on water,
but the car industry bought out
and pat this patent and this,
you see this across the board.
So we actually see an, uh,
technology is being stifled because of
the capitalist model that we live in,
this vulture capitalism where they're
monopolizing all these industries and
preventing technology from a rising.
So that water car thing is
totally true. No. Yeah. Yeah.
I had heard in the electric car, remember
who killed the electric car. Yes,
I heard about the water thing
on Opie and Anthony. Uh,
they were talking about how the guy who
created it died of a heart attack and he
was, he had a meeting with two men
and he ran the restaurant screaming.
They poisoned me and then
die of a heart attack. Yes.
Yeah. See if you guys can see
if you can find that story.
Cause a stoping Anthony
were talking about it.
It sounded like a fucking scene in a
movie. Like the guy he like yelled,
they poisoned me and ran out and
had a heart attack or a stroke.
I can't remember my memory's
shit. Uh, but it's um,
my memory is actually
excellent for our human,
but there's just too much to
remember. Yeah, that's true.
I don't know.
We can reinvent the wheel here.
I think that we can advance humanity in
our collective consciousness to a point
where we can like figure out a different
way instead of reverting back to these
old paradigms of like
communism or capitalism and
the way that we know, I mean,
can't we recreate something?
We, we know what exists.
We have the ability to intercommunicate
within the entire planet.
The technology's growing exponentially.
I just think that we can do
better than what we've seen.
I think you're totally right.
I think we need to learn as human beings,
we need to learn how to manage
our humanity and there's
a lot of things that we're going to
have to take into consideration when you
start talking about that kind of stuff.
And one of them is that people have a
desire for competition. They just do.
They always have and that has
to be quelled in some form.
Whether you should take up a game that
you enjoy or get involved in sports or in
court.
Martial arts are a good example or some
form of discipline that allows you to
like blow off energy and blow off this
competitive design that you have inside
of you that sort of as allowed human
beings to get to this point in the first
place. I mean we didn't survive for tens
of thousands of years because we weren't
intent on survival at all costs. And one
of that, one of the costs is competition.
It's a part of what what's made us a human
being. It's a part of why we're here.
And I think that when people
get involved in anything,
whether it's a corporate
thing or whether it's uh, uh,
competition and uh,
a game or a team,
there's this desire to do better
than those you're competing against.
Like if you talk to people
that are business people
and they'll talk about their
competitors were fucking kicking it
right down their throat, they're,
they're like very aggressive about shit.
When you get guys alone they start talking
about how well they're doing against
the competition.
Yeah.
They closed down through their stores
and like they start getting like real
excited about conquering shit and it's,
it's, it's that mimicked that this,
this genetic thing. I think that's
like almost been incorporated into our,
our DNA because it's been so responsible
for getting people to this point.
Like you have to crack eggs
in order to make an Omelet.
There had to be a bunch of crazy shit to
get us to rise from apes with sticks to
driving a car and to do it all so fast it,
there had to be a lot of
chaos involved in doing that.
But we should be able
to recognize that now
and go, Whoa, Whoa, Whoa,
Whoa, Whoa, Whoa, whoa,
okay, everybody catch your breath. It
took us a long fucking time to get here,
but let's look at why we got here. This
is what, this was what motivated us.
You see all this.
We just wanted to breed,
want to make sure we have children and
make sure that we stopped the barbarian
hordes from coming over
from the next town over.
If we can just all agreed to not be
fuckheads. None of that's going to happen.
We can all talk now.
Okay.
This isn't like you speak German and I
don't understand Dutch and he's Chinese.
No, no, no, no, no, no. Everybody
pretty knows what the fuck.
Pretty much knows what the
fuck everybody else is saying,
so everybody just chill. That's all
she can. We agree to chill. Okay,
let's choose your own thing. Let's
figure out this fucking resource thing.
There's a natural resource thing that
it seems like as all of ours. Okay.
Why don't other people get to keep that
and how come the people that get to keep
that keep wanting to go to war
and controls you? Let's, you know,
I know it sounds a little radical,
but maybe you guys are kind of being
consumed by controlling all the oil,
isn't it? The Earth's yeah. You suck in
and out of holes in the ground. Like what?
It's fucking fascinating that we're just
wasting all of this magical resource
that's takes billions of years to compound
in the earth that were just blowing
it. Fucking killed. It
makes for awesome cars
does, but we don't save it. Yeah.
It's a stupid thing I've
said before that I think
they're going to do is eventually
come up with some sort of a,
a bacteria that eats carbon dioxide in
the air and they're going to release it
like a moth,
like a colony of Moss in the air.
It's going to chew through all the
pollution, but then it's gonna meet tails.
Yeah, but that's going to mutate
to bring up cam. Charles, please,
please don't bring up chem trails.
Kim Cherrelle believers. I love Ya.
I feel Ya. I used to, I probably
could have been one of you. Okay.
But I read a couple of articles
along the way. Just don't,
I'm not a fucking Geo engineer and I'm
not a new world order person either.
Right.
The illuminati stop.
Well I just haven't met one.
I haven't seen one pilot who's,
I mean if they were spraying chemicals
on us and the government was doing this
around the world every day,
don't you think that some pilot would
have come out and said like, I don't know,
Yo, you know, who knows, why would
he sprays on family, you know,
and like it's very nonspecific
way to poison the world
already getting enough poison. I
don't, but it has been done. Did the,
the thing about
yeah.
Dropping stuff from plains has been done
and in fact there was a recent article
that was uh,
it was just published about a,
these tests that they did I want to say,
oh shoot, I should look it up. But um,
it was uh, there were spraying
radioactive waste from, from playing.
Yeah,
the monitor crazy shit.
Engineering experiments and
then the cloud seeding and said,
there is like geoengineering
happening and it works, but it's not
to the extent of what people look,
it's always they like,
I know I was just about to say, yeah,
they gave the the Tuskegee experiment,
they gave those guys syphilis or allowed
them to have syphilis and not treat
them. This is all like that. They thing
is a real problem because it's not,
they're not all part of the same group.
It's people that are cunts.
That's what it is,
is assholes that have done something
wrong and w w if they're in a position of
government, it's always
they, it's like they have
done that. Yeah. If someone just asked
me last night, they said, do you know,
do you believe in the new world order
or the Illuminati and stuff? And I said,
well,
I think that it's giving them too much
credit and it's also taking away people's
agency to be like,
there's this unknowable group controlling
everything behind the shadows.
It's like, no, we know that these
mother fuckers are, you can, they're,
they're hidden in plain sight.
It's the board of directors of all the
most powerful corporations in the world.
I mean,
these are the people who are,
yeah. Hunting Shit. This is a fact.
Okay. Then in the 1950s and this is, uh,
this is often Yahoo news.
This is,
this is widely reported throughout
the Internet, which means everything,
the Internet,
I don't know what's true. I don't
know. It's true. I'm not a researcher.
Yeah, yeah. We've got one there. Oh,
wow. Bam. We're like, Fuck Jeanie's here.
James does genie's this woman says that,
um,
she lost her baby when her father died.
Uh,
she was a baby rather when her father
died and explicit inexplicably in 1955 and
she watched four siblings die of cancer
and she survived cervical cancer.
Upon learning,
the army conducted chemical tests in her
impoverish St Louis and neighborhood in
the height of the Cold War.
She wonders if her own governments
to Blaine in the mid 1950s and again,
a decade later,
the army used mode motorized blowers,
a top low income housing and high rise
at schools and from the backs of station
wagons to send a potentially dangerous
compound into the already hazy air in
predominantly black areas of St Louis.
Local officials will trope.
We're told at the time that the government
was testing a smokescreen that could
shield Saint Louis from aerial observation
in case the Russians attack. Wow.
But in 1994 the government said that
the tests were a part of a biological
weapons program and Saint Louis was
chosen because it bore some resemblance to
Russian cities at the u s might attack.
Holy Shit.
The materials being sprayed with zinc,
cadmium sulfide,
a fine fluorescent powder.
Oh my God,
that's horrible.
That's so scary.
There's just no accountability for any
of this shit that's, that's happened.
I'm sure these people got like a very
little payout that they've just watched
all their family die. It's so scary.
It's terrible. And then here's the,
here's the thing for the [inaudible]
folks, this is real. This is real.
And when you're looking at a lot of things
that may or may not be what you think
they are, it's really important
to find out what is real. Right?
It's really important.
And if you're not sure if something is
just a jet engine creating an artificial
cloud because it's passing through
condensation or if it's the government
spraying you,
if you call one or the other,
it becomes a problem for
all of the information.
Absolutely dilutes the real argument,
which is the fact that
there's the challenge or even
just the jet fuel of just
planes in general.
The jet fuel thing is crazy and that's
something that we figured out on the
shows that 93,000 flights
a day fly worldwide,
93,000 saying it's incredible.
And there was a study done after
nine 11 which is really fascinating.
And this is kind of funny
because it was in CNN,
this is long before the chem trail thing,
either a,
it's a CNN article from 2002 uh,
and it was talking about
how the temperature shifted
because of the fact that
there was no contrails in the sky and
that these contractors and it referred to
them as the artificial
clouds created by jet planes,
that these contrail had
been cooling the earth.
The difference was a couple of degrees.
I don't know how the fuck they can
tell whether or not they're a couple of
degrees.
Variance is just natural cause things
vary all the time as far as temperature.
But in this article they were trying to
attribute it to the fact that there was
no controls in the sky, which
is fascinating. That's crazy.
I think to me there's no causal
connection to the heavy metals,
corrosive metals found in the,
in the water than it is the spraying.
I mean we have no connection at all and
that's like the only evidence people can
keep showing me is they're just like,
look at you Berrien and aluminum is found
in this and the water. And I'm like,
dude,
we're
fucking polluting the whole earth. I mean
water's cyclical. Like I don't, yeah,
it's,
well it's weird.
It's w what we worry about is
weird because the chem trails,
if the government really
was spraying something,
that is something we should worry
about, but stop. What are the effects?
I don't feel anything. If they are
really doing this on a regular basis.
If they just cooling the water,
what is exactly going on now let's stop
and look at the shit that we're not
paying attention to. We're pumping
like raw sewage into the ocean.
Like people going like just
shitting into the ocean. There's,
there's like boats that
are burning diesel fuel.
This other Schultz with giant nets that
are killing every fucking fish within
it's, you know, whatever stretched.
They've got these goddamn killer net
set up for just salted fish out of it,
throwing plastic in there.
There's a gigantic garbage chat.
There's one in the Great Lakes do.
There's one in every Monday at fucking
talking to this woman talking about
plastic. And she was saying 20 years ago,
this research team went out fucking
hundreds of miles away from the great
Pacific garbage patch and the fish
that they were fishing full of plastic
particles and all of a sudden this guy
went down to the bottom of the ocean
where they were and it was covered in
plastic bags. And this was 20 years ago.
Can you imagine how it is now?
I mean this,
this is the shit that we should be
considering. Exactly. It's, it's,
so this Saint Louis Story for the
chem trail folks, here's one in your,
in your corner. This is
real. Okay. This is real.
So you are right to distrust any people
that could be in a position of power
that could possibly profit from doing
something that could harm people.
You're absolutely right to be
paranoid about that. Um, that's,
that's not what I say when, when, you
know, when I talk about these things,
I just think it's really important to
be aware of exactly what's happening.
It's the same thing with fluoride.
I think Florida is horrible and
it shouldn't be in drinking water.
But the thing is,
it's been kind of hijacked into this
conspiracy theory that says like it's this
mass mind control thing and trying to
give everyone brain damage and Hitler used
it on, on the Jews. It's that,
first of all that's not true.
There's no evidence to back
that up. But also it's like, no,
it's just a phosphate mineral byproducts
that were just pouring in the water
supplies. Like that's what
we should be concerned about.
That there's a waste product being
sold to municipalities and just fucking
toxifying our water.
But isn't the idea that people
who use fluoride fluoride,
what does it fluoridated? Florida doesn't
sound right. Fluoridated sounds wrong.
Um, fluoridated water have better
teeth like that is actual health.
The Ada did an extensive study,
uh,
about a decade ago that showed that it
was just better hygiene overall that just
showed that people just had better
hygiene overall. And it really,
there's no difference between fluoridated
and non fluoridated areas. Whoa. Really,
really just topically applying
fluoride. Yes, that is, you know,
that helps with tooth
decay but ingesting it,
we're already getting it when we shower,
when we cook,
like why are we drinking it too?
It just doesn't back at the history,
the idea was that the,
the water having fluoride in it would
help with tooth decay as well
as does it do anything else?
No kill anything offering.
It's not even Florida, it's a,
it's a this thing called a hexa florists
allistic acid and it's just a fucking
fertilizer byproduct
that they've just like,
it's just this old school collusion
between the fertilizer industry and the
water industry is just based on
like a huge propaganda campaign.
It's saying that fluoride is good for
your teeth and we just kind of still
believe it. It's bizarre. There's so
many other countries in the world.
I do not do that at all.
Wow.
Well if you ever had like real springwater
like right from a, like a Colorado,
well I just had distilled water for the
first time. It tastes like fucking snow.
You've got to be careful.
What is the deal?
It doesn't have any minerals
in it cause it leaches them.
Yeah,
there's a process
process. I don't know. I shouldn't
say it takes out all the minerals,
but I think it takes up most of them.
Magnetize what my friend Aubrey actually
had a problem because he was drinking
it on a regular basis. Uh, you know,
he wasn't aware of the consequences of
not having enough minerals and he started
getting like his heart was beating
too fast. He was kind of freaking out.
Like he had an electrolyte imbalance
and it was because he was drinking
distilled water all the time.
Like you have to have like,
people think that like salt is bad
for you. It's salt is essential. Look,
if you eat a pound of it, you're
dead. Okay. But salt is in it.
It's a huge part of what it is
to be a human being. You need it.
That's why they used to go to war for
that shit. They used to have salt wars.
Like when people kill
people for all their salts.
My friend swears in distilled water.
He,
he drinks it every day and he
should be careful. Well was great.
The idea is if you take it with
like some milk Himalayan salt, uh,
something that has a lot of
minerals in it or to some,
if as long as he supplements with
minerals, maybe he'll be okay.
But Aubrey, I mean he went to a
doctor and the doctor told them like,
you have an imbalance here,
so what are you doing?
Why are you drinking that water and irons
humidifier.
Humidifier fire is a funny word.
Yeah, that's a, you gotta be careful.
But yeah, the floor, I think it just,
it's just one of those things that no
one will even address. They're like, oh,
what do you think fluoride is
bad too? You're like, well no,
you just should really,
you're right. Even it's good.
Don't want to be mass medicated against.
And I will like,
why do we need this in our
water? Right. And it's also,
I'm sure it probably does some
weird shit to your skin too.
Hot Water with fluoride in it.
You get an excess of Florida gives
you fluorosis which eats away.
They namel over your teeth. So you
see the yellow fucking like, yeah.
Cause it's the opposite.
Yeah, it actually,
and it's so thing about what that's doing
to your bones if you get an excess of
fluoride. Oh Wow. I never thought of
that. So, okay. Is this hippie bullshit?
Nah Dude,
that's really funny though.
The way you said that. No Dude.
That's exactly what someone who's
telling hippie bullshit. Nah Bro.
Come on. Cause Jerry Yo dude, I read
that shit. I'm going back website.
I swear I saw on the Internet
is legit fuck's on that floor.
I dated in a water.
That'd be Martin and talk bad
knowledge about that on our tea.
Lots of research dogs, government. Is it,
is it one of those things where like
someone just started getting paid for
bringing fluoride and then the
fluoride is just a part of life now?
Yeah. The aluminum industry needed to get
rid of their byproducts. They were on,
they launched this propaganda campaign.
There's like in the fifties and it was
just this old school thing that was,
we didn't really understand that we can
just have better hygiene by brushing our
teeth now was like, yeah,
people did have fucked up teeth.
How do they purify water? Like when,
like if, if the use, what do they use?
They use chlorine or something like
that. What chemicals? These surefire,
it's from the phosphate mining. So
they, they take it and they just like,
they capture the water that's escaping
in these giant scrubbers and then they
just sell it. Like, I don't fucking
know what they did. A purified,
I hope to God that they're
doing something to purify it.
No, I mean what, I'm sorry. I should
rephrase. What I meant was when,
if you like,
say if you get water out of the Faucet,
when you go to this foster right
now and get a glass of water,
they're doing something in that
water. Right. What do they do?
Cause a purification. Chlorine
fluorine. Uh, well we should ask,
right?
We should like Google this real dark.
As crazy as I just had this interesting,
uh,
thing with Nestle where they
send us this lawsuit threat.
Like they're basically threatening
to sue us because I criticized their
monopolization over the water supply
and how they're trying to prioritize
water. Yeah, I've read that.
I didn't even want to like actually read
the quote because somebody sent it to
me in Twitter and I looked at it.
I was like,
I don't even want to read that because
it's like someone going to be bummed out
by those duties.
There's the, see the ex CEO Peter
Brabeck. He's still like a, I don't know,
he's still highly influential
at the company, but he came
out and said, you know,
it's a food stuff, like any other,
it should be applied to market price.
We should not like basically just
privatized all the water in the world.
And he was like, if he's like, if
you think water's a human right,
you're an extremist.
I was like,
that's fucking great.
And every single day,
yeah, this is probably Nestle. No, this
isn't necessarily, but it seriously,
every single bottled water I've seen
as Nestle and a, it's terrifying.
It's terrifying what they're doing right
during these routes. Yeah,
correct. That's ridiculous.
What a crazy way of looking at
the world. So yeah, that's like,
so he wants to treat water oil,
essentially. He wants to fucking,
what's the next air? Monopolize
it. What we're trying to do.
That wasn't someone trying to
actually sell cans of air because wow,
they do it in a hotel in Seattle.
Well that's actually a oxygen. Yeah.
It's like a pick me up.
Like people think that like
you ever go to the oxygen bar.
They have like those picked me up bars.
He used to have those. I went to one once,
didn't do Jack Shit.
I sat there on Tuesday.
Windows feels like I just paid 20 bucks.
It just
gives you heightened awareness.
I think just that they came a carrot.
I think just thinking that you're doing
something that gives you a heightened
awareness heightens your awareness cause
you're like cognizant of it. Like yeah,
I'm going to really,
really focus.
You talk about so much as the placebo
effect because this is something that's
fucking nuts.
The fact that we can heal things with
their body and people just dismiss it.
They're like, oh, that's just
the placebo effect. You're like,
that's so fucking crazy. That's way
crazier than like having medicine that
cultivating this so much. But also
it really begs the question, what is,
what is the state of our body based on?
Is it based on confidence and
feeling and thoughts and the the,
the kind of like ideas that you called
debate or is it actually based on
genetics and disease?
Like how much is which way when all
of a sudden someone can cure something
because they think that the,
I don't know how many instances
where that actually takes place.
The placebo effect might be Greg
greatly exaggerated. I don't know.
I don't know how much has
actually been done placebo style,
but I know that it's big enough that
it's occurred enough times where it's,
it's documentable. Like people can like
refer to it as an actual situation.
There's a placebo effect that actually
does happen. So what's going on there?
I don't know.
I think that it needs to be cultivated
way more studied way more like I,
it's just funny that it's kind of this
weird thing in science. You're like, oh,
it's just the placebo. It's like, have
you thought about what that means though?
Because that's fucking nuts.
It's also,
it makes you wonder what exactly
is really shaping this world.
Like how much of what's shaping this
world is thoughts and how much of it is
circumstance and how much of
it is just random occurrences.
How much are you steering this thing
with your thoughts when you find out that
you can fix something that you didn't
think you could fix because someone told
you they gave you a pill that fixes it
and then all of a sudden you fix it. Well,
think about what stress does to
you. Can you totally. It's crazy.
It's bill that for you. Yeah. And also
it makes you make shitty decisions.
You do do rash things. You,
you yell at people that you
shouldn't, you're like, ah,
it builds up. Yeah, it's
terrible. It's terrible. Terrible.
It's awful.
But it's the way I saw this documentary
about water and there was like this
Japanese scientist who,
you know,
put different feelings in different
bottles of water, a glass of water,
and then I don't, I mean it's
been debunked. Yeah. Apparently.
I don't know. We'd have to
get a debunker arm. Right.
But then the debunker would get all sorts
of hate mail and it would never come,
want to come back again. That's what
happens when you debunk things, man.
She does nick, Mick West, the guy who was
the debunker on our show, he runs metal,
bunk.com so he debunked everything.
Anything that's,
he finds out what's bullshit about
something and debunks it and he's,
he's right a staggering amount of times.
And this guy's just,
his timeline is just, hey, hey,
on Twitter, people hate when
you debunk their, should
they so invested and JFK
so invested in everything,
whether it's Lee Harvey
Oswald acted alone,
or whether it's fucking conspiracy
from the Grassy Knoll, whatever it is,
anti conspiracy,
or does it really take it
like where you're like,
I will look at everything and really kind
of sort through it? Or is he just like,
I'm gonna debunk kind of the main points?
Yeah,
he's a debunker.
He likes calling people and
conspiracy to Zitter bullshit.
Even if he's wrong. I mean, I don't
know if that's right all the time,
but it's pretty obvious. His trend is
to debunk things. But along the way,
I got to say,
I've,
one of the things that I've learned
about this television show is the
psychological effect of wanting
to believe in something. And the,
the similar attributes that I find in
almost everyone who believes in something
that can't be proven. There's very, very,
very similar attributes
as a very similar mindset.
But yeah, I agree. Um, but when I look
at something like, you know, nine 11,
I know what isn't logical and it's what
they've told us this happened. Yeah.
So it's like, I don't know what happened,
but I know what didn't happen. So
that's another,
that's one that always comes up whenever
someone believes in something that's
odd. There's always the, what about
tower seven discussion, you know? Yeah.
There you go. That's the discussion.
That's the skin people in 2013.
They're almost like Jesus Christ is 12
years of fucking tower seven can't do it
anymore, buddy. I can't. Okay. I
gotta tap out no more tower seven doc.
We can't fix that thing. It's gone.
It's gone. Let's concentrate on bigfoot.
No, it's um, yeah, there's a, um,
there's a reality to the world,
right? There's a reality.
And then there's a trying to decipher
reality from looking at the past,
whether the passage is five minutes ago,
whether the past is two hours ago.
When you're dealing with
something monumental like nine 11,
you're going to have a lot of noise.
There's going to be so much information,
good and real and bad and distorted and
crazy and sane and logical and cryptic.
There's going to be a
lot of shit going on.
So you look at any catastrophic situation
like towers falling and people dying
and you're going to
have a lot of craziness,
so you're going to have a lot of shit
that doesn't jive and you got to have a
lot of shit that also
leans towards a conspiracy.
Then it's also the possibility conspiracy.
And that's what people
don't like to think.
They don't like to think
that it's not an either or.
And that whom you don't know.
You don't think unless you were there.
Can't be sure.
Why is conspiracy about,
it's been a,
it's been turned into a pejorative
where it just shuts down and you know,
it's amazing. Really? Yeah, it is. That
was actually deliberate effort by the CIA.
What's really it? Yeah.
They're so bad ass.
I wish I could score the CIA because
they're so bad ass in so many ways that
they could figure out how to fucking
engineer human consciousness so they could
just make conspiracy thing sync.
Dopey. Oh, you got a conspiracy theory.
You know what? Like the Gulf of Tonkin.
What? Like the Northwoods document.
Just rattle off a bunch of
real shit. That's really
like, what about Enron? Right.
That's a good spirits.
They conspired. People got
together and happens all the time.
It's part of what makes people fucking
group into little huts at the get
together. They have a little
tribes. They go, well,
this one was one was just
one of the fucker's got gold.
They're right over there.
They sleep at night. Let's go get
them. They happen all the time. Yeah.
I love the CIA. Just for the
record, for the record, I don't,
I like them individually as human beings.
I hope they're nice,
but as a group, I'm not willing
to trust them unless I meet him.
That's all I'm saying.
Yeah.
I remember when they were also at
the center MK Ultra Shit. Yeah.
So let me ask you this,
and this is the fucking elephant in the
room when it comes to a journalism cause
you're, you, you're a journalist, you're
looking official journalist, right? Legit.
And you are also not afraid to
talk your mind, whatever it is.
You speak your mind about
various controversial subjects.
And then you see this Michael
Hastings thing. Do you go, oh boy,
I don't know the story.
Tell me the story.
Okay. So Michael Hastings,
uh, amazing journalist,
one of the last real investigative
journalists that we have that, I mean,
he'd go on the court from media
and just fucking destroyed.
Like he just completely make everyone look
like idiots. But he's very aggressive,
very aggressive.
But he was just like,
you could tell he's just exasperated
with the mentality that he was surrounded
by it. Whenever we be like all
these Obama apologists and stuff,
when he would go and argue and he was
embedded in Afghanistan for a while and
actually did a report in the rolling
stone about Stanley McChrystal,
which was the commanding general general,
the Afghanistan war that totally exposed
as us, um, ended up getting him fired.
And when you get a general who's
commanding a war fired, um,
you need to look out and like, you need to
fucking watch your back. And so, I mean,
he got death threats at the time,
months later,
his car driving like a hundred miles an
hour down a fucking residential street
in La and it just explodes. Why the
fuck would you be driving that fast?
Nothing about it makes sense.
He had just written a letter to his
friends and family hours before he died
saying, I have to go off the radar.
The FBI's investigating me. Watch out.
They're going to come talk to you.
Um,
it doesn't mean that it was
the government who killed him.
It doesn't mean that it's,
there's some giant conspiracy.
My view is that you get a commanding,
general fired and he knows fucking people.
He knows security contractors,
private firms that can fucking take
you out if you embarrass someone.
I mean this should happen.
This is a hit.
I don't know what happened to that guy,
but it sure looks like it.
I mean if you wanted to look at a movie
scene, it's like a perfect movie scene.
It is in a James Bond film of a political
assassination. Yep. And it really is,
the door's locked. The steering wheel
start to turning towards the tree like ah,
your cars because salary is going shut up,
bitch.
Why would I explain that on the air?
I think all the old cars,
everybody get an old really old
dodge darts can be hacked too.
And that's what the, yeah, that's nuts.
Well that's what I read afterwards.
We'll do some guy who worked for
Clinton and for Herbert Walker.
Bush was describing how it's absolutely
possible. I don't know if it was him,
was him, Richard Clark, which
I thought was strange in itself that
this guy would come out and be like,
it looks like a car hacking to me. You're
like, you're fucking government insider.
It was just strange.
I didn't know why he,
I think the people in the
old guard probably don't
exactly like how shit is just
so loosey Goosey with the murders these
days. You know, they're like, hey,
we didn't use to fucking
kill report is like,
this guy's going to
security cameras everywhere.
Like Bernstein's still a lot. But
basically they, one of them died recently.
I don't know a little bit of Bernstein,
but I mean, if you're asking if I'm
afraid. No, absolutely not. I mean,
if you can't live in,
I'm scared and I know you like being
in the room with you for three hours.
I can close. Oh, how scary is
that? It's fucking terrifying.
I wrote something down today as
a joke, but it was about, um,
this fucking meat that they're
creating now. Ah, Shit. No, no, no, no.
That's, that's exciting. No, there
was a, uh, a meat that they're there.
They've made synthetic meat and
uh, you know, and I was just,
yes,
yes.
And I was just figured
out how to clone county.
They took some cow meat and
without actually, you know,
increasing the amount of cows in the room,
they increased the meat.
They just put it in some
sort of a test tube,
costs hundreds of thousands of dollars,
but they made like a cheeseburger.
Why did this, this weird meat, and
I wrote it, today's fake meats,
tomorrow's fake person,
solar powered program by the state
reading minds and writing tickets for bad
thoughts like this.
Really possible, right?
Like one day we could easily be in a
world where we have robot people just
wandered around enforcing
the rules of a corrupt elite,
a bunch of old dudes with fucking
just wires coming out of their body,
like barely hanging on, just
evil, keeping them in in the game,
waiting for life extension technology,
just hanging in there
with robots running around
like actual thought crime.
It's not even funny with the NSA,
just surveillance of everyone.
Blanket data mining.
And then this retroactive prosecution,
the ability to retroactive.
They prosecute you. If you fucking say
something today, 10 years from now,
they can dredge that up and be
like you said this 10 years ago,
wrongfully accused you of something
and pull up all this evidence over the
course of your digital life
and use it against you.
And that's another really scary aspect.
It's not even just the chilling effect
that quells descent and makes people not
want to speak out as much. It's
that too. And that's scary.
Yeah, that's very scary. It's very,
it's all very scary. It's, it's we're,
we're,
we're in such strange times because if
someone feels like they have the right to
just look at everything you're doing
all the time, like where are we,
what are we dealing?
Like we're not even America anymore.
Sun America when everyone can
just have their email looked at.
And did you read the shit that David
Seaman put on is a page today that about
how they're using it.
The DEA is using it now.
They're using the information
to catch drug dealers.
They using the information to catch
people selling weed. I mean, they're not,
it's not just a security concern thing.
This is information that's being
distributed to other people.
They're bypassing normal like protocol
for catching criminals and just fucking,
well, what's really
crazy. Yes, you're right.
But what's really crazy is that
he said that this is what's good.
It was really weird,
is that the NSA is giving your phone
records to the DEA and they're telling the
DEA is talking about how to cover it up
and to conduct a fake investigation to
acquire that information to back engineer
your discovery and then going back and
acquiring enough evidence,
post knowledge of the crime to,
you know,
like that they're actually going to
create a fake investigation. Well,
he'd so that they hide the fact that
they got this information from the NSA.
Right? Right. Like, Oh man, that
seems like a lot of work. Well,
it doesn't just seem like a lot of
work. It seems like you're lying, right?
Like you should. Yeah, there should be
some laws in this world, but there you,
there also should be some nobility to
the people that are enforcing those laws
and one of them is you shouldn't be
allowed to lie ever. Okay. Lines not good.
Stop doing that. So if you're not lying,
how much of this actually happens?
Well, none, because people go, wait a
minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
The DEA gets the fucking records too,
right? Okay. Where do you draw the line?
What if someone's giving a friend a
bottle of Xanax because their prescription
Randall able to be hacked.
So where the line really
isn't drawn anywhere.
When you have foreign
governments or entities that
could hack into this shit and
then use it. I mean, who knows, right?
It's just, it's going to be out there.
Everything's going to be out there.
They're just slowly trying to stop it.
They're still lying. They're like, oh no,
it's just the metadata.
It's just the metadata. And
you're like, no dude, because
the the storage center in Utah or
whatever that you're storing this,
like the metadata would only account
for like a fucking eighth of that
information that's stored in there
and you already building other ones.
So what the hell else is the rest of it.
Obviously it's everything just
recorded and stored. Obviously.
It's amazing that anybody would
think that's a good idea. Right?
It's really amazing that anyone would say,
yeah,
this is what people are gonna go for this.
This is a good,
none of them are not going to feel
like they're imprisoned at all. No,
it's not a prison stays. Just willing to
make sure that everybody listens. Yeah.
Can't have that. That kind
of power. Crazy fucks camp
the FBI is doing with
the entrapment cases.
I mean all of these like
thwarted terrorist attacks
in the last decade are all
mostly manufactured by the FBI.
Brilliant. Amazing. Oh,
there's that one that was really hilarious
in Dallas where they got this guy who
was like challenged. He's
like, yeah, not a bright guy.
They talked him into it. Gave
him the bomb. Yeah. Okay.
And told him how to detonate and he
tries to detonate and they come in and
arrest him for bomb them wasn't even real.
You guys are playing,
make believe like you're playing.
Make believe in just Jack and morons,
which I guess it's better that
they take them off the street.
Then some real kind of dude and the
hundreds of thousands of taxpayer dollars,
like coercing some mentally
unstable to fucking
try to get to find those people. You
got to do that. Then for the Tsa,
I liked that. I like what you're
doing and you find an idiot's gone
years and they get paid like
a hundred gcs informants.
There's actually this one case of
this guy in a mosque, I think I said,
this isn't the last podcast. He actually
scares people so much in this mosque.
All these Muslims who were like,
they actually called the FBI and reported
him cause he was trying to radicalize
them so much. It was like he
was the terrorist and they
were like, what the fuck?
This guy is here trying to rile us up
there and then they're like, oh yeah,
he's working with us.
Jesus fucking Christ. Crazy
problem, reaction solution.
One of the worst cases of a undercover
cops was without a doubt in my opinion
that the people in Florida
where they were uh,
operation d minus whether you're sending
undercover cops to go in and pose as
high school students and try to,
Oh my God, cause some weed. So sad. And
some kid actually like fell in love with,
he was like, she was like 4.0 yeah, she's
hot. She's 25. She was a, she's petite.
She could pass for bag. So rude. And
would they, the craziest thing was a,
what's that? A podcast. This American
life. All right, well they have,
they did a piece on it and they actually
interviewed her and they spoke to her
and she was like,
you know,
hey these people that you
know shouldn't be doing that.
They got to watch what they're
doing. Like you, you found a boy,
you found a boy and you were nice to him.
And he tricked him and the boy
tried to give her the weed for free.
Tried to get her weed cause she,
cause she asked him and he gave
it to even really like, oh,
he didn't smoke weed at
all. He tested negative when
they, when they arrested him.
But they, uh, when they asked her,
um, like where they were rather, uh,
when she asked him rather to get it,
he tried to give it to her for free and
she insisted on giving him money so that
she could make the arrest.
Wow. That's so rude.
So mean. Meanwhile, here's my meanwhile
there's real crime going on in,
this is my point and I want to say
this very clearly. Okay. Um, I'm not,
I'm not a male apologist.
I believe that on both
sides people should be kind.
And I think there's a competition
between men and women that has rather
unnecessary,
whether it's feminist,
some masculinist and a
lot of it is unnecessary.
But in this situation it's very strange
because if the roles had been reversed,
the outrage would have been exponentially
greater if a man was pretending to be
a high school student. And he
was a super slick, 25 year old,
been around the block, been driving
for years. He's got a fast car.
Maybe he's got a bunch of poetry
books that he reads and she's just,
he's so different.
He still maturity.
So that would be so rude if you found
that some 25 year old pimp cat is banging
17 year olds and arresting
them for getting them weed.
Could you imagine how much people would
be upset and they would assume that the
guy fucked her.
I assume he fucked her,
you know the girl was fawning him and
next thing you know she's getting them
weed for free and he's arresting
her. It's so funny. It wouldn't,
you would never stand for it. No one
would stand for it. But as long as it's,
it's one of those weird
things where it's like,
as long as it's a boy getting fucked over,
even if there was a woman who
conned him and lured him in,
you are grossly
teachers,
fucking young girls students either.
You hear like a lot about women teachers
like having affairs with like their
high school students and stuff.
I'd never really heard the
story of the opposite happened.
My name is happened to my high
school. Really? Yeah. Yeah.
I don't want to say anymore.
Who was a good dude and I knew the girl.
Yeah. Yeah. Um, what did you
hear about that in Trotman case,
this is fucking sad. This guy just liked
to gamble. He was an optometrist, like,
you know, just had his own
career, had like mildly gambled,
like 20 to a hundred dollars
beds with his friends.
And this FBI agent overheard him
at a bar one night talking about,
I'm waging a bet and he,
so we'd be friended him and then for
the next like six months or a year,
just became closer to them.
It goes on and they kept trying to up
the stakes and basically at the end of
this time frame, he convinced the
guy to bet him $2,000 in one day,
which in Virginia,
that's like running a gambling operation.
So he comes in and raids his house with
a swat team and the guy gets executed on
accident.
There's like some trigger happy cop
who just fucking shoots and kills him.
I'm like, so, so you basically turn this
person into a criminal. Not even that.
I think that's a criminal
to spend $2,000 in a bat,
do whatever the fuck you want,
but like that big shaped this person
and then he just, it's just so sad.
Well,
this has happened so many times before.
There was a famous rolling stone
article about a young man that was a,
he was talked into selling this guy some
marijuana and then he sold them some
marijuana and they put together some
sort of coke deal and the FBI agent
completely encouraged him, set it all
up, or the DEA agent, the undercover guy,
set it all up,
connected to two guys together and got
this poor guy who didn't want to do
anything,
just slowly worked him and coerced him
into the situation where you thought he
was gonna make a lot of money to do
this real quick and know. Meanwhile,
there was no drug deal to be made.
It was all fake.
This guy just completely concocted the
whole thing. It's fucking DEA asshole.
So then this DEA asshole winds
up being a complete criminal,
gets kicked off the force.
Okay. It doesn't get prosecuted.
Just gets it just removed and done.
But you know who knows what he did?
He was doing drugs.
They'd know he tested positive for drugs.
So he was in it yourself?
Yeah, you have to.
If you want to be a part of that world,
you got to do coke with them. Right.
And so this poor fuck is in
jail for the rest of his life.
His kid is just stuck and this was a long
time ago, the article in rolling stone,
I don't know if he ever got out,
I don't know what the story was,
but the kid was doing
essentially the life in jail.
You leave that there was a
major league cocaine dealer.
They put together a major
league cocaine deal. Not really,
but they did as far as like he knew
and big. That's good enough. Sorry.
Getting the box.
When
you're like getting so close to these
people, do you ever think like, wow,
this is really fucked
up when I'm doing like,
I don't understand how these
people can live with themselves.
The ones who are in trapping these people
for months and months and months in
like befriending them and
getting really close to them,
then they realize that they are shaping
these people and to become who they want
them to be.
It's a fucked up thing.
It is certainly that. It
is certainly that. It's um,
it's,
it's a lack of humanity.
It's the same thing as a corporation
that can pollute a river and kill a bunch
of fishermen because it's easier to do
that than it is to take shit and put it
in these toxic drums and ship it somewhere
else. We all know that's happened too.
I was like,
what allows people to do the w would you
look at a broad spectrum of what people
capable of like what allows the worst,
what allows the most extreme
aspects of our personalities?
We could have an empathy pill.
Like I have a gene that's called yeah.
But all the time. Yeah, well that's
what we need to engineer all the time.
Just a really mild dose of Ie.
We just want to hug everybody.
We will be so much nicer.
But it's, it's one,
it's really interesting because if
you stop and think about the idea of
engineering consciousness through pills,
I mean that's what everybody's worried
about when it comes to antidepressants
and Prozac and things that people
give kids for add. And you know,
people were really concerned about this
concept of engineering consciousness and
what are the repercussions of doing
this and giving people things.
But what if they get it right? One of
these fucking nail it and it just becomes,
everybody becomes cool as shit.
Like they just like they give you a pill
and then all day you're on like a mild
x to see super friendly mode,
you know?
And it gives you like a 20 30% Iq
boast boost fast tracks evolution.
Why not? It's not possible. It
seems like it would be right.
It would be weird because what
if something went horribly wrong,
wrong and well for the first few
generations until we get it right
or all fucking getting pigs,
it's pretty, pretty insane.
This generation is pretty crazy.
Well, no one more so than those
people in Saint Louis. That's a,
that is a really hard
thing to fucking read.
It's a really hard thing to read to think
that that actually did happen. Yeah.
It's just so weird.
It's so weird that people can do things
that they can do and then other people
are just cool as shit and normal
or like dropping white phosphorous
in fucking Iraq that, that's against.
What does that, what does white
phosphorous, this and Cindy Arie,
that's supposed to light up
the air when you like drop it.
When you look at bombing and
Baghdad, when we invaded, um,
you see like these like plumes of,
of like light coming down
and it basically just,
it's such a high concentrated incendiary
that it will just cut through skin.
Like it'll just slice through your flesh.
And so they've been using that.
It's against.
I mean it's totally illegal to use during
warfare and Israel does it and so does
this country still? Yeah, those
depleted uranium. That's awful too.
That will never go away.
D you is there forever.
It's that areas like toxic. Yeah.
For like how long? Millions of years.
Oh
yeah.
Shelf of D'you is like
knowing what is the idea
about depleted uranium?
Was that that it penetrates
armor better than anything else.
This radioactive coding on the,
on the shell of something like the shell
casing and I don't know what the fuck
why you would ever use that if it's
like so horrifyingly toxic for the
environment,
why do we need that?
Like don't we have enough the way like
high grade weaponry enough that we don't
need to be using.
Do you know what the fuck do you
think those things are just like,
let's see if we could do this.
I think we could just shoot right through
that thing with the DEU and they're
like, God, go for it. Just like
people watching the nuclear explosion,
it was like glasses on.
They're like, oh sweet.
I think just no concept of anything
in the future, past 10 years.
Like what is this going to do?
The idea that anybody has the
ability to make that call, hey,
we're going to shoot these bullets and
they should work a lot better than our
regular bullets.
They poisoned the ground for a million.
It's fucking million years. Listen, when
I'm getting around, don't worry about it.
It's a million. It's a hundred.
We're going to give a shit bomb.
We got a lot of this stuff.
We have a lot of this stuff.
We might as well make bullets out of it.
What is depleted uranium?
What does it look like? I
don't fucking know. Let's look
that up. Depleted uranium.
Okay,
let's see what the fuck it looks like
bedded. Uh, do you have
to ps depleted uranium?
I bet it looks like, uh,
a bit. It looks evil.
Why is there a navy photo
with no face? No, it's not.
I see a, I see a photo of
it. Look at that. You and I
need to, that's what it is.
You try to find that photo.
That's what depleted uranium looks like.
And apparently it's just
fucking awesome at killing shit.
Just they figured out how
to make something that's way
better than regular metal.
Okay.
Um,
so what it says is the,
its uranium with a lower content of the
fissile fiss Ile Fussell you to 35 that
the natural uranium and natural uranium
is 99.27% you to 38 and 0.72% that you
don't give a fuck about this.
What am I saying this to
people before I reading this?
Because a lot of times when
I go to Wikipedia folks,
I've never read about this before,
so I'm hoping that they'll sort of
boil it down for me within the first
paragraph. No such luck today. Kids.
Just a bunch of numbers that I
don't understand. But um, yeah,
so that depleted uranium shit ain't good.
Did you see a wolverine?
It was like,
there's a reason why I'm saying this
right outside the movie wolverine.
How did she said no?
Yes. With Hugh Jackman.
Who else would be
willing when Walgreen for the past decade,
Jesus Christ,
I think he's the only Walgreen ever.
It's never been an wolverine. Um,
there's a scene in it from Nagasaki cause
we'll ruins 150 years old or whatever.
However he was when they
made them, I forget. But uh,
the idea is that he's a mortal and a in
Nagasaki, like he gets involved in the,
uh, the bomb. But you
stop and think about that,
like let a stir range ability that
human beings had even in 1947 to throw
something out of a plane,
fly over,
you throw something and
just wipe out everything.
Just wipe out the whole Shebang.
Just flatten that motherfucker.
Kill hundreds of thousands
of people just like that.
But we needed to use it to end the war.
Save lives.
See Jacqueline working out looking sexy
piece. I'll do it. I'm getting ready.
It's hard to believe that he likes
musicals to he's a perfect man. No,
I think nuclear nuclear technology
is, is bat shit crazy. I mean it,
it can be used for good,
but the thing is we don't have the
capacity to harness it properly.
Like look at nuclear energy.
We can't store the waste and the waste
doesn't go away for millions of years to
say, what the fuck are we gonna put
this? Like yes, in theory it's great,
but there's this whole other component
that we're just kind of ignoring and then
look what happened in Fukushima
when something goes wrong.
I didn't realize until Fukushima,
what nuclear energy actually was.
I didn't realize it was just like water
boiling and like these giant open air.
Yeah. So on the same page. So
confused. This is what we're doing.
This as a free ticket.
You've got a son that makes
and you can't shut it off. Oh
good move
lines here in the u s well listen,
listen. Well you don't know. Okay.
I've see where you would come with,
this is an uneducated person, but I'm
going to explain to you we need that.
First of all,
it's a major reason why coal
is down on the use is many,
many percent. Now there's a, we have
the situation eradicate. There's,
we're basically no worries. There's
a, Fukushima was a very old design.
We have various fail safes and backup
generators and we don't pitch shit right
next to the ocean.
Like those crazy Japanese
we do.
We have like 23 sister reactors all built
by GE here in the exact same manner.
Some built by fault lines.
There's one on the way to San Diego.
You pass by it. You know what that is?
Shutting that down,
but they said it's going to take like
13 how'd you get shut out your process.
Would you got the toxic water?
Just dump it in the ocean,
right when all the plastic bags. What do
you mean shut down? What does that mean?
I thought you couldn't shut him down.
It seems like um,
isn't there like a bunch of spots in
Nevada where they just like dug holes?
I'll just put it here.
Do they have signs over?
Those are like in a million different
languages go no fucking 10 here.
Right? Don't dig for the next
million years. This spot sucks. Okay.
2012 thanks. When are we doing?
Yeah, that's a weird thing.
The fact that they have these areas where
they dig a hole and they just put all
their garbage. They're like, listen, I
know this is all talk. So again, soon,
whatever, whatever, dig a
little hole here. Drop it
off. Is this your land? Okay.
Can we just dig holes here? Can we just
pay you like a couple of g suite? Listen,
you guys can have prostitution
and gambling. Yeah.
Oh you mean what they've done
to it in your reservations?
And that's pretty much what they did.
They're just like everyone just gone was
toxic areas with like no ability to like
farm or do anything and will just
fucking give you gambling here.
Aren't you happy here or gamble? Here's
a free here's of alcohol, cigarettes.
If you think about it that way,
that's a weird way of looking at it.
But I guess a lot of, uh, native
Americans would agree with you on that.
They've don't live in the best spots.
They don't give like the best spots
away for, for reservations. You know,
they're like, can we have
Hawaii? No, no, nope.
Okay. Know, like how many,
like really good spots where
the Indians were. We like,
no,
not this one bitch.
And there's a lot of really good spots
and Indians had where can't we build?
Okay, go there. I, yeah,
I'm wanting to know. I've,
I've read a bunch of different versions
of why they were called Indians.
Some that makes sense that some
that don't, but there's no denying
that, uh, that name. The
uh, the idea that I've,
I've read two different versions of the
idea that they thought that they were
actually in India.
I've read that that was the case and then
also read that it was based on a word.
I'm trying to remember what it was.
Something meaning free man,
India or something.
I like that.
The indigo choke Chubby.
It's not a band. Indigo girls. How are
they? Are they good children? Is like,
we can't play them, but we have fan.
Brian. I've too much a penis for that.
What are you trying to say? That you
can't be a man who was well endowed,
who enjoys some chick music? No, I think
they're more attracted to the culture.
They're more attracted
to that culture share.
What the fuck are you saying?
That's like shit.
Indigo girls are like share men are more
attracted to men or women or lesbian.
Lesbian is. Okay. Did you guys hear
about this? A this a boa constrictor.
The got out of a,
a pet store and climbed through
the walls and into this kid's room.
Killed a five year old and a seven year
old. Oh my God. Yeah. I was in Canada.
Apparently climbed over the wall
of someone to just house. No,
it was in like they had like a
reptile place downstairs. Oh,
in this fucking thing got out or fine.
Yeah.
All these idiots that actually have
exotic pets as pets here in this country.
Did you know that there's more tigers
in captivity in the u s and there was in
the wild in the world. Really? Yes.
We only Louis through did you
knew who but I don't believe that.
Now Louis through this,
this awesome that works for the
BBC does these crazy families.
He lives with the Westboro
Baptist church for like a month.
He'll go live with like all these assholes
who have tigers in cages in baboons
and like giant snakes and he'll just like
do this documentary about him and they
don't know that he's actually mocking
them because he's like British and so they
don't really understand his humor and
he's like being really sarcastic all the
time.
It's great.
Well he's also like super
embedded he'll, yeah, exactly.
Like he does.
He's not like arguing with them as
much as he's just encouraged them to
communicate who they are, you know, which
is like, you know the hard way to do it.
You're embedded with the Westboro
Baptist church. I'm like, you know,
I've got to kill all these choirs.
They have like a really
great sign making factory.
He was like in there and he's like,
he's like Nelson Mandela Fag. He's like,
I don't, I don't understand. I just
like the most random assignment.
And then had his face on his sign because
he goes back to the Westboro Baptist
Church and then they made a sign with
him and just said like Louis Theroux,
fag lover or something. He was like,
why did you make a sign about me?
Our human struggles.
Just so bizarre.
What a bizarre thing to struggle about
what the Westboro Baptist church is one
of the weirdest like branches of humanity
because it's almost like we expect
them to do something stupid
whenever anything happens
now and it becomes like an
oddity,
like a little side show at these things
and if we yeah,
and it's like impossible to not pay
attention to them cause there's so fucking
outlandish, like the fact that they
will just go and fly to picket funeral.
It's the part of the idea of struggle,
you know,
it's a part of the idea struggle that
the battle between like advancement and
thinking and this the,
the monkeys,
there's the fucking screaming apes that
is still around throwing shit at each
other,
holding up abortion signs does it,
but it's just a part of that
fucking struggle. If you
seen that, a photo of the,
uh, the mountain goat and the cougar
that felt their death. Oh my God,
I want to see it. Hold that shit up.
It's a series of photos. It's a battle.
It over.
It shows a battle because the,
the mountain lion actually has
the hair in his mouth of the,
of the goat.
They're both dead.
They're laying out on a stretch of highway
in Colorado where the road was closed.
They went to war on a cliff and they
both fell to the death. And it's, it's,
it's a wild fucking series of photographs.
Look at this.
Oh yeah.
Well see that thing to the left,
that's one of the horns
from the mountain goat.
Like it lost its horn in the process.
And there's a series of photos, Brian,
if you scroll down, it shows, that's
where the horn came out. See, look,
that's where the horn like literally
broke off shit. Yeah. Okay.
And that's the mountain lion. No,
look in his mouth. You see the tough,
tougher look at that.
He got that thing in his mouth and they
both went for a ride and landed boom on
the ground. Look at this.
Go. It's like, Oh shit.
Boom.
Yeah.
Fuck yeah, no need to look at it. But
they show you the, uh, already look at it.
If you just no need to look at that after
you've looked at that. But if you, uh,
uh, props to Javier Vargas, he's
the guy who sent me that on Twitter,
try to give out Twitter props.
Yo. Um, but he, um, the, the,
the website takes you to like a whole
series of photos. It's pretty, it's just,
it's not beautiful, but it is
beautiful. Like I don't, I don't,
I'm not happy that either one of those
animals died. I'm not an asshole,
but they died in a beautiful, yeah,
it's fascinating. It's fascinating.
It's like any weird strange work of art.
There's something bizarre about
you're capturing this image.
Nobody influenced them.
It's not like they were forced to do
it in the coliseum for our amusement.
This is just something that played out
in the wild and they fell off a cliff and
it's like, it's, it would
have happened whether people
existed or not. Most likely.
It's just a fascinating,
fascinating thing to see that this
is how life exists when you take away
language and you'd take away cities,
you can takeaway advancement.
It's just this wild group of things
that are trying to eat each other and
survive and keep moving
and spread numbers.
How amazing is it that we live in a time
where we can see all of the shit like
the, the planet Earth series where you
can just see what the fuck bacteria looked
like in caves in like New Mexico
or some shit like glow worms,
spinning silk or like the
goats on that mountain side.
And that's what reminds me of that.
Those goats that survived and like the,
it's like a sheer face of a mountain
and they're hunting and they're fucking
running around. Like, how are they not,
how are they even existing up there?
Yeah, it was amazing. I went, uh,
I was in Montana and I watched these
mountain goats climb up the side of these
bluffs and they're standing in
these like ledges. It's like a, uh,
like a chunk like that wide.
And they got one hook here and one of
fair and it's not like, they're like,
oh shit. They're like, oh, how do I
get up here? And then just keep going.
They're not like on a ledge.
Yeah.
They're just on a sheer fucking face and
then that'll gangster was that mountain
line to go, I'm going to take my chances.
Yeah. It's like, yeah, allege manage.
I think I grabbed that bitch by the
neck and just lock onto, I'm right there
guy filming it.
So they waited like weeks,
like six weeks to finally
catch them hunting or whatever.
And it was like this epic chase on
this mountain side and I was like,
how are they not just collapsing
and falling to their death?
The Cot.
A mount mine hunting.
No, it was a, it wasn't a mountain
lion. It was one of those goats.
They were getting chased by
something by a mountain liners. Okay.
Oh, so they filmed that.
Yeah. Oh, it was insane. Yeah.
Mount mines are really hard to film.
That's one of the reasons why
when people hunt mountain mines,
it's a very,
the hunting of mountain lions is very
controversial and on one hand I see the
point of the people that don't want
them hunted. Like they're this majestic,
cool creatures and it's amazing
everything. But on the other point,
like you've got to realize like if you
don't keep their numbers to a manageable
level,
like the last thing you want is mountain
lions like wild lions lion this year.
Yeah. You don't want him
like squirrels. You know,
you don't want like pigeons just
running around gravity slow.
People like we'll a real problem.
Like you need to figure out how many we
need to keep and there's only one way to
do that.
You've got to kill him because nothing
else tells them they don't have any
enemies. The only, they die of old
age and when they fall from cliffs,
when they're holding on to goats, other
than that, they're going to be fine.
Did you hear about the pack of wild pit
bulls that killed that jogger? What?
A fucked up way to die. Yeah.
That's not fun. Horrible way to die.
That it seems like she was with two
other people and they like the owner was
just like watching it happen.
The pit bull just like destroyed
this woman and then the,
they were able to get help, but the girl
died. I think that's terrible. Yeah.
Horrible.
Yeah. And I'm also fucking no joke,
right? It's, we around them all the time.
We get used to the fact that we for
the most part have them under control,
but just dogs. I have two dogs
and one of them was a smaller dog.
One of them is pretty big.
It's like 140 pounds.
And I was thinking if
he just decided like,
I just want to see what it tastes like.
You know,
if a dog really wanted to do that,
we were pretty sure they're not going to,
what do they really want it to?
It's not a lot stop.
Yeah. It's, you know, they are,
they are creature that that's
their instinctual something
snaps and they fucking
go for,
well,
it's going to be weird,
really weird if people do create
this synthetic sort of, uh,
artificial, uh, meat.
If they really do create that and it
starts being something that's sold on a
regular basis, what are we going to do?
Like, are we going to keep grazing cows?
Is going to be a way to justify the fact
that you're, you're killing an animal.
Oh,
we'll get to the point where we just
won't let cows mate that often just keep a
few of them around so they don't go
extinct and just eat these fake burgers.
I think people will always
want to eat the real animal.
Really.
Some will shoot them or if
they just want authentic.
Yeah.
It'd be like a diamond.
Like chicks don't like
server cubic Zirconias I just
don't know how it was like
this. Is this the real deal?
Was this forged in the bowels
of the earth? I know. Uh,
yeah. If it tastes better,
what if it tastes better?
What if like regular meat tastes like
shit? Yeah, I'm down to, yeah, why not?
As long as, well, I'll let people
try it for about a decade or so.
Before I jump in.
You want to be real careful?
Yeah. Talk about being
Guinea pigs. Gmos. Did
you see this thing on?
Um, there was a, um, uh,
an article, it's on my Twitter
where the scientists put Mona Lisa,
a tiny Mona Lisa, the,
they drew it on a surface,
one third, the width of a
human hair. It's incredible.
This incredibly precise instrument at
the Georgia Institute of Technology.
They have printed Mona Lisa odd,
an Ab straight surface,
30 microns in width,
which is one third of the width of a human
hair. Can you pull it up? Yeah. Yeah.
It's actually pretty good.
It's amazing what date is what
date it's on science space.
robots.com and it should be there today.
If you just read right,
look for scientists,
paint Mona Lisa on surface.
Just that and I'm sure it will pull
up the uh, the article. But yeah,
that's it. That's a Mona Lisa they
made, they made that on something.
One third the size of a human hair.
It's pretty fucking good to like,
it's hard, man. I don't know. Wrap
your head around that. It's hard.
What the fuck? They just froze the
light. Yeah, they did that too,
right? For how long? How
long did you freeze line a
minute. Does that make sense?
No. What does that mean?
What happens there?
And you freeze light and then you go
to the speed of light. What happens is,
so for sure for pop out here,
how your spaceship and come down here
to fix the world. What the fuck man.
Crazy three d pen that they can draw
like in the air now and make like a dude.
I don't know. Look like an image. Yeah. Oh
my God. Yeah. How much do you know about,
there's pens that apparently
record what you're right.
So if you write something down,
so there's a pen,
like if I gave you this piece of
paper and I had you write things down,
what you wrote down would
actually show up in a computer.
That technology has been around
for awhile but is it why?
How does that work or does it have
to sync up with the USB? Yeah,
you like sync it up to your computer
and it's like rights into a document for
them. But if it, if, if you
could do it with the sync
up, you could probably do it.
Wifi, right? That they have it.
Cause I saw the first one
actually when I worked at gateway,
they used to have them so some CIA dudes
could probably be able to hook it up
for Wifi. Oh yeah. Or
Yeah. Seems like it. Right.
That's amazing because somebody told
me about this guy, um, that uh, we,
we actually wound up having this guy
on a r a t v show and he's a psychic.
His name is Ben a check. And I can't tell
you what he does in the show, but he,
he'll tell you that it's all bullshit.
He's like, he's, he's a mentalist.
I shouldn't say as a
psychic what he does it,
he debunks a lot of what people think
is psychic, but it's just trickster.
He Shit, he just, he's a master
and all this trickster he shit.
And I was trying to figure out
how the fuck he did what he did.
Cause it was really kind of trippy.
And one of the things that
I think might be possible,
I've been just running through
this through my head is uh,
one of those pens that as you write
things down it without like you could seal
it in an envelope and he has
access to the information
that is possible today. Right?
Yeah. Yeah. Without a doubt. Right.
It has to be about,
they could probably do the same thing
with like a keystroke thing too. Oh,
they aren't there it is. Two
gigabyte Wifi. Smart pen. Boom.
[inaudible] 79. Wow. It's
only $179. That's incredible.
What does that dude's name from um,
the uh,
double o seven movies
that got all the gadgets.
Their Watson,
the guy that's sherlocking who was the
got it.
Right.
You guys know that was one guy. What's
his name? The dude who was like,
this is the new, yeah, the dude. Was it Q?
I don't know his name too.
Okay. Spell the shit in it. Yeah, I would
see two. Please look at the three d pen.
I want to see if I,
if I actually saw it.
Yes. His name was Q was a fictional
character in the James Bond films and
novelizations Q standing
for quartermaster.
Huh? Yeah. There was a bunch
of these dudes that played Q.
Yeah. Wait, you're talking about no way.
What does that look like? Go down
and see the image, how it works.
So this is the pen that
you write something.
You can write something like an air and
it would it actually just draw like a
three d.
Okay,
so he's filling in this.
Thanks like icing. Wait. Okay.
It says doodler and then this is
going to just show up in the air.
Is that what this, is this the
wrong video? There you go. Oh Wow.
That is crazy
how simple it is.
Wait a minute.
That's like a pen that makes like, it's
like silly puddy comes out of it. Kind of.
Yeah.
It's like that plastic stuff.
We used to take those little straws
and blow the little air bubbles. Okay.
That's stupid.
That guy's an idiot.
Not really buddy. Relax dude.
Don't get uptight. Yeah,
he's making a strange time. It's
actually pretty cool. It's cool.
But like in a bit dazzle kind of way.
True. They just created this substance
that water doesn't stick to it.
So you can like put it on your shoe.
Yeah, on it. That's crazy.
We showed a video though.
This guy just ran through a mud puddle.
It's fucking nuts.
You scientists and it's all
[inaudible] so fucking quick.
Every day there's some new thing.
If only we had the most smart minds in
the world working toward technologies
that are good instead of like weapons.
And I mean thinking of wasting.
Sure. Yeah, you're right
where you are. Right. But we
do as well. It's almost like,
do you ever think about the possibility,
and this might be total hippy bullshit,
but is there a possibility that we need
a bunch of dickheads in the world in
order to motivate the good people to
act and that sorta like the struggle is
imperative in the human condition, the
Yin and the Yang, that it's almost like a,
there has to be assholes in order for
people to push society further in order
for us to really recognize her.
Yeah, I think you're right. I think
there's always going to be a balance of,
of good and bad,
but I don't think that we need to let
the assholes get to the extent where
they're actually like fucking up
the planet for the rest of us,
which is where we're at right now.
So if we curve the asshole's
back to a manageable level.
Yeah.
Or The assholes fucking things up.
This motivates the really smart,
nice people to develop
some of crazy technology
that eats plastic and eats plastic and,
and it creates flowers that grow in your
mind and enlightened that doesn't make
sense. Stick needs to eat mushrooms. Well,
they'd said that fungus is actually the
best way of dealing with a plastic that
they've confound found funguses that they
can mutate and get them to eat plastic.
Really? Yeah. There's, there's
no, there's, there's been some,
some headway in that. That's one
of the ideas coming up with, yeah,
it's still scary.
It's still scary when you see this,
the very studies about how large the
patch is and how much of an area it covers
and how much actual material is out
there. It's spooky. It's not an island.
That's kind of a misnomer.
It's actually clean pool. Yeah.
I've called it an island before plastic.
It's um,
cause I was trying to like figure out,
I guess that's not the best way to
say it because it really is floating.
So it's not really an island,
but it's, it's a giant area,
man. It's big. It's big.
It's like Texas sized. Right.
Bigger, bigger than Texas. Jeez.
If you've ever driven through Texas,
just imagine all that fucked drive all
the way through Texas and all that.
It's just fucked in the
middle of the ocean.
I don't know if they're gonna be
able to fix that and our lifetime,
it's going to be really interesting if
it gets all the way to Santa Monica,
if it just gets all the way to the
fucking shores and it washes up on the
boardwalk and everybody's
like, Hey, what the hell it is,
we'll send it to the future or something.
That's what it will happen.
We'll create time travel and then we'll
send to all our trash to like 50,000
years from now and then we could,
we can't even send that
stuff though at this point.
You're dealing with so much volume,
you couldn't really send that.
Like if we wanted to like scoop it up
and put it in rockets and shoot it,
you know that what fucking cost.
It'll be so quick cause
you can't clean it up.
So it's so many micro particles of plastic
and all these fish have formed their
habitats within the plastic trash swirl.
So it's like they have to write,
they had no choice.
It's like animals that were taught in
the Congo when the Congo or grew out of
the grasslands, the uh,
the rain forest trapped.
All these animals like antelopes
and the like, rhinos and shit,
they all got trapped in this rain forest.
It just erupted.
I didn't know where and
changed their habitat.
These poor fish are dealing
with that, right? The, yeah.
If we did scoop it up and
just launch it in this space,
that would be when the aliens would land.
They would be like the angry neighbors.
They'd be like, bitch, what the fuck are
you doing? I said, we've been watching.
You guys know is way
too fucking far right.
You're okay with nuclear power but you're
throwing fucking bags of trash over
the fence.
Stop it dicks.
Fucking we are.
We are the shitty neighbor of space.
Is that what we are praying and last
day, second worse than us, right?
It's probably going to be,
you're right.
What if they're like more advanced and
more douchey and we just end up in the
seaworld of space. They just
suck us up and make us do tricks.
Maybe that's what we're
doing here and what I
realize it, number one, Stephen Hawkins
came out and he was like, by the way,
aliens are most definitely out there and
there we should not be looking for them
because they're most likely wanting
to like take over the planet.
Everyone was like, what the fuck?
We're like Stephen Hawkins is that, no.
You know what's hilarious?
Every one of our scenarios in a film
of the aliens coming starts off bad but
ends us with us kicking ass. Right. Okay.
But what was the last time we went and
scooped up some chimps and shit went
wrong.
You know what was the last time we
went on a monkey search expedition just
starts scooping them up with nets and,
and it went terribly wrong.
We lost control of the planet
and get the fuck Outta here.
Like once they start kicking our ass,
like if they can come here from
other planets, we got a real problem.
The thing is are they real or just a war
of the worlds again and it was fucking
terrified. Tom Cruise one.
Yeah, it's fucking terrifying.
Whole Metaphor about what we're doing to
the planet anyway and just suck it all
up and just spraying our shit back
at us. Like it's, you could argue
I've always done that, but we've never
done it to this level. Like they,
there was horrible,
horrible pollution in ancient times.
If people would get sick because they
didn't have proper sewage systems and
they'd be, people would be
throwing the shit out the window.
And there's a lot of like human waste,
like whether it's waste byproducts
from their body or waste from the,
the food that they have that created
rats and the rats carry diseases,
not created rats.
We encourage them to be in the area.
There has always been
that sort of a situation.
There's always been like this bag better
now. Yeah. Right, right. You're right.
You're right.
It's like what we were talking about her,
we know that we don't shit where we,
but for some reason we sound like we
know that. Not Do that. You say that,
but we do it anyway. Right. People that
we show with the people crazy. Right.
It's a, the battle. It's the
constant struggle. The in the Yang,
the good and the bad,
the sense and the nonsense.
I'll just fucking Duke in and out to try
to get to the end point. That's what,
or was it Orson Welles? Yeah. H
G well said. He said that, uh,
that history is a race between
education and catastrophe.
I've used that quote way too many
times to not know exactly who said it.
So if you're going to use paternity,
doesn't know it.
No real legitimately didn't remember.
Relax.
There's all these conspiracies
floating around through the Internet.
Better to paradise fade away
or you definitely fuck you.
Trying to say that was called
a conversation stopper.
What's fair kind of porn,
which I go to porn like amateur or
that's wrong. That's what you like.
You looked at amateur shit like solo
male masturbation. Backyard black.
I like Rebecca Linaris. Oh, you have
like a specific girl he liked watching.
Okay. The whole world just pulled the
pants off right now. Then like he's Abby.
Please keep talking. The best is
porn on vine. That's the best because
my favorites a,
there's a girl named Siri ruiner pulled.
Oh No, no, it didn't. It doesn't
matter.
Yeah,
there's tons of porn and it's the
best because most girls are just like,
they get right to it. Like I'm right.
Open it up and stick my finger in it. Oh,
now it's going to loop. I'm, I open it up.
It's sticking your finger. Perfect boobs.
Amazing on vine. Huh? Check out
Siri Aaa. A lot of free time
was spent with his pants off.
I've never masturbated mine.
Duncan Trussell has created this
thing called some in the NSA. Oh yeah.
He told me about it and created a website
where you click a button and in one
button it Google search. Just all
like the terrible shit. Everything.
Don't do it. Don't do it from here. Don't
do it kind of here, but whatever you do,
don't do it from here.
And they Google,
they Google the Google searches,
like pressure cookers, backpack.
I was hired right idea and it's all
in one button. I just saw this really,
really awesome,
a parody about the NSA that said,
here's how we're going to beat the NSA.
Just talk like a terrorist all the time.
Like it's shut like this mom calling
her kid and her kid was just like,
all right, I'm going to go blow up
the school. And the way code names
should all start. That's actually
funny. Was it a comedian?
The, yeah. That's great.
That's really funny. He just overload. Oh,
that's hilarious. Somebody, whatever
you do don't. Well, just this luck.
We're lucky that already didn't figure
that out on its own or would a road that
shit to the fucking rocks. What a warped
reality that Snowden just got granted.
A silent by Russia. Yeah, right.
Well, you know what happened?
Do you know the whole story behind it
that the United States that somehow or
another criticized Russia for a silencing
political dissent and they were like,
what? Bitch? What did you just say?
Do you know who's at our airport?
And they were like, oh, okay, listen.
Yeah, yeah. Ed. Hey, what's up vitamin?
Yeah, come stay at my house,
dog. Come, come hang out
bitch.
Are you crazy?
Did you really say that you criticizing
us for silencing political dissent to
you fucking know that's so silly.
We have the biggest story of all time
when it comes to like a lack of privacy.
This is the biggest story of all time.
It's the fucking,
somebody pulled the curtain
back and we saw the wizard.
We saw the wizard like it's,
that is the biggest story of all time
when it comes to privacy. This guy said,
hey, by the way, I used to work there.
I didn't even graduate from high
school and this access to Dan,
he didn't even graduate from high
school. Right? And he was like, well,
but I can read your email. So what's up?
What happened? And I was just a dude.
And by the way,
we're also tapping into China's hospitals.
It erode that shit like civilians,
the structure in China.
It's like what the hell?
Well, what's fascinating is
yes, why? Well, I don't know,
maybe they have an answer,
but an even more fascinating that they
chose to do this and to try to discredit
this guy by going out by the, with the
fact that he was a high school dropout,
right?
Like this is a shady character,
a high school dropout and drop out work
for you and have access to everybody's,
what the hell are you doing?
What are you doing?
And it makes you realize like,
oh these crazy fucks.
They thought no one was
going to check them.
going to pay attention.
They were just going to keep doing
what they've always been doing.
And they can just keep pushing it and
they just didn't realize that they were
doing it like completely out in the middle
of a field in the open. They're like,
oh, oh, oh, oh, oh shit. And I
left with the media is all like,
oh well come back here and face the music.
You're not a hero until you
come back here. It's like, why?
So we can sit and be fucking tortured.
Like Bradley Manning was for years before
he's even given a kangaroo court and
yeah. And you're not saying that,
that sounds like an exaggeration.
Like oh that's really tortured.
No, he, well he was, yeah.
And this is one of the claimant's torture
and naked solitary confinement when it
was cold. Like they kept him
by himself for years. Right?
Like how long did the
key claim solitary years.
But I think it was like three years
before I got a trial. But yeah, he was,
he was stripped down naked,
forced to be stripped down naked
every night and totally dehumanized.
No outside contact at all. Very Sad.
It's the whole thing is so strange.
It's like if we really wore this really
kind and and noble country that we will
want to think that we were,
we would have this person and we would
use this example as an example of how to
treat someone who disagrees
with you but breaks the law,
how to treat them
humanely, how to, you know,
how to bring this up
in discourse with the,
the rest of the people of this country,
but instead of like doing
something horrific and cruel
to them and doing it out
in the open and doing it
where everybody's aware of it.
It's like you showing your intentions.
Your intentions aren't to govern the
world and govern the world and make people
live in a better place.
You're,
your intentions are to enforce your
law with an iron fist. My question is,
where's the Apache helicopter pilot?
Who did blow up those AP journalists?
I'm Betty. He's living
large. Hanging out. Oh look.
See now the guy who like did the war
crime in the video that Bradley manning
exposed. Just like what a, what a
fucked up two tier justice system. Well,
I don't think that guys live in
large and I think that guy's paying
psychologically whether or
not he has to go to jail.
I meant more like on the bigger scale,
Donald Rumsfeld, the real torture,
like actual criminals who
implemented all, you know. Yeah.
Could you imagine getting
high with Donald Rumsfeld,
Donald Rumsfeld to do bong hits?
Just get,
I'm super paranoid and freaking out and
then just start talking about the Iraq
war theory to Larry King
now worked for our t.
He interviewed Donald Rumsfeld for
like an hour and I was like, damn,
Larry King works for our team now what?
That's, that's weird. That's fascinating.
It's really fascinating.
Larry King,
why is he worked for our teams that just
like you wanted to keep working and he
just decided after CNN just go back at it.
I mean,
I didn't know he was
still doing doing news.
I thought he'd kind of retired
him was doing like very nice guy.
So He's been a very nice guy to me. I've
met him twice. It's really nice. You know,
I think he,
well he hosted the third party debates
at Aarti and then Aarti like just offered
him a job. I guess. It's really strange.
Well, he's iconic, you know, he's
one of those guys that people,
even if you don't necessarily want
to hear who is being interviewed,
people listen a certain amount will
listen because Larry King's interviewing
them like,
but he doesn't like king.
Yeah. He doesn't have any opinion.
All of a sudden he just asks. Yeah.
That's how he can get access to these
people like Donald Rumsfeld. So it's like,
do you want that
Gary? Yeah. Yeah. He's
enormous access threat. Yeah.
Kind of have to be that guy. If you
want to talk to the president, right.
If you're lucky, you
know, you have to like,
you have to have a long history
of not getting crazy, you know?
Have you ever been crazy at all?
Like probably Geraldo
Rivera doesn't even get to,
it doesn't get to interview Obama.
Mm.
You might do something goofy
just to get attention. Yeah.
You have to have like a certain level,
like a Matt Lauer.
Matt Lauer is not fucking around.
He's taking this seriously. God,
Katie Couric,
she's not doing anything crazy.
She's going to ask you questions
and be very respectful.
You can't be some wild.
Okay.
Came out in the wake of Michael Hastings
death and he was like, you know,
I'm really sorry for, for uh, the
loss of everyone for Michael Hastings.
But he did get one of the best generals
of Afghanistan were fired and really
like fucked up the war. It's
like, yeah, that's, that's
great taste dude. Like yeas,
after he dies,
it's just like tweeting.
Well he was showing his ass.
Yeah,
that's what he's doing is showing
his ass to the new world order. Look,
kiss my ass. I'm on. Come on. Love
you. I liked that shirtless photo.
Yeah, he's an interesting cat. You know,
that's why I brought him up
because I was aware of that tweet.
He said are fighting one of
our best fighting generals.
Like what are you saying?
What does that even mean?
Doesn't mean anything.
We were losing the war mean first of all
has nothing to do with this guy dying.
Right. So this guy, did he make things
up? Like hiring someone, what happened?
It was just, okay, what he,
you did those like generals who are
doing a bad job. I mean, I don't know.
It becomes a weird thing. It's
like what you know, does it arm,
does it aid the enemy? That's like the
big question. Does it aid the end of,
that's the big question.
I know Barry Crimmins is political comic
from Boston old school guys been around
a long time and he said Bradley Manning
was acquitted of aiding the enemy
because we're not the enemy.
And you're like, Oh snap.
And I mean that's essentially what I mean.
He definitely violated a bunch of rules
and they're most likely going to jail
them.
But
no problem is he's still facing over
a hundred years in prison with all the
charges, the 19 charges and there's
like six charges of SB and I was still,
but the SBA,
the fact that Obama's actually gone
to the level that he has to prosecute
whistleblowers and criminalize
whistleblowers is so
fucking crazy to me because
he's dredging up this world war one
piece of legislation that was used for
foreign spies and using it just
like Willy Nilly. He's like, oh,
espionage act like why? I mean, what did,
what did Edward Snowden to do other than
tell us about an unjust law. Like yes,
he broke the law,
but he's exposing something that's illegal
and unconstitutional. Like the
government's breaking the law. Right?
So it's all relative. Yeah.
It down to that wartime thing.
Especially at wartime.
He never supposed to do anything that
weakens your government. You know,
that was the, what Geraldo was
trying to express. You know,
I don't think he realized how
people are going to take it,
especially after guy dies. You
know the guy was a reporter. Okay.
It's not like he made things up.
Okay.
The guy was a reporter and you can't say
can't help but remember that you can't
say that. That's stupid. It doesn't,
but yeah, in the same
tweet. I mean motherfucker,
the guy's life isn't even where the
tweet without reminding people of Geraldo
expose the coordinates like during the
Iraq war. Did he? Yeah. You remember that?
He like gave a coordinates here. He's
the one who fucking, how did he do that?
He was like fucking reporting from some,
from some foxhole.
Did he see rock and they were like,
you just fucking like talk about aiding
the enemy. He actually did aid the enemy.
He rock.
Oh my God.
I have to time to look this up in Amaze
Geraldo and then I think that's when he
got kicked off like war covering.
Oh Geraldo exposing war coordinates.
Oh my God.
Well he's also the one that interviewed
the soldiers that were guarding the
poppy fields. Do you know
that? Have you ever seen that?
I have not seen him interviewing him.
Was He asking them what? It's wonderful.
This is what's wonderful
about it is because he's not
like, what the fuck at all?
He's like, well, this is just
something that we have to do here.
Why do we never see them pull it up there
and why you would have to maintain the
Bobby field? It's important because
we need heroin, right? We need,
we need a late tax for
our [inaudible] know.
If for these people to give
us information, we have to
let them do what they do.
It's rather unfortunate.
Even though the Taliban had eradicated
opium crop before we invaded,
and now 90% of the world's heroin
comes from Afghanistan. Yeah.
It has nothing to do
with it. Is this it? Yes.
Fox News live from Africa.
Here we are tolerating it.
We are tolerating the cultivation of the
OPM because we know that if we were to
destroy it now,
the population would turn against the
marines and it would be a real security
risk. Let me introduce, we tend to put
all Brian Krebs therapy, third battalion,
sixth marines, a really a
wonderful group of marines here.
I know you care deeply about
this. Uh, this contradiction.
The fact that here you have one of
the best fighting force in the world,
ever rounded is one of the
strangest interviews ever.
You watching this opium is being grown.
I know how to adjust your gut.
How do you deal with it?
What are you doing? Well,
frankly,
he says part of the culture.
So while it might grind in
my gut and it's what they do,
we provide them security,
we're providing them resources,
and then we're providing them alternatives
and the alternatives or different
crops to grow. You're getting the seed
and the fertilizer. You can do it. Uh,
they can, they can rotate any of
their crops now that they want it.
They want to get rid of their wheat
and grow cotton for the winter.
They can that and we're gonna help them
do it. So whatever we,
whatever crops, cotton, heroin,
whatever, we're going to help them out.
They don't want to ruin their culture.
We don't want to disrupt their culture.
We're bombing the shit out of them,
destroying everything else.
But we don't want to fuck with the opium.
There's Geraldo manscaping wearing towels.
Oh yeah.
I can't.
It hurts my feelings ordinance.
Oh Man. Yeah. This is the
drug war is so ridiculous.
When you look at something like that,
it'll take care [inaudible]
2003 10 years ago,
Fox News channel correspondent,
Geraldo Rivera as being expelled
from my rack for broadcasting.
Details about future US troop movements
in the country. Hey, per fucked up.
You made a mistake. Handsome, faster
though. Still even at this age,
still rocking that, that Harry
Reems mustache. Yup. Hey,
you made a mistake. I'm sure he didn't
mean to do it. Whatever, whatever.
Just out there. Heroin Cop, and if
we're talking about aiding the enemy,
it is a pretty funny thing.
He fucked up.
He didn't mean he didn't mean I don't
think he willingly did it right.
Is it the idea? Is it Bradley manning
willingly did it? Well, Bradley Manning,
what he did was start the dialogue and
that's what Julian Assange's did too.
He started the dialog and these guys are
all obviously vilified and turned into
monsters because they started the dialog.
But look at that.
Oh Shit, Geraldo. It's just
really, really, really fucked up.
Here's what really fucked up the tower
was way too low dog for anybody that's
way too low for Justin Bieber.
Those like there's no age
when you're allowed to do
that. That's not old for Joe.
That's,
that's too low for Justin Bieber.
It's tool for John Meyer and it's too
old for her role, so it covers all bases.
It covers like young teens or 20s
it covers thirties enhance of.
He had John Myers Goddamn Stud.
He's a walking God, but you can't,
I don't want to see your
fucking phones. Right, right.
That's the call them the kids these days.
They call them the fuck bones,
the upper musculature of the hips. I
don't need to see that. Those fuck bones.
Yeah, he fucked up. He's crazy.
He's crazy for showing us so much.
If the guy just had a nice pair of
boxer shorts on. Did Bush paint that?
You heard about Bush painting,
right? Yeah. He paints a
lot of Cox, right bathtub.
He paints himself in the bathtub.
Oh,
he does his painting while he's in
the bathtub. He painted himself.
That's the paintings that
he painted was his sad face.
Looking in a mirror and then like his
naked body in the bathtub? No. Which Bush?
Bush jr. Oh God. Yeah. Do you imagine the
nightmares floating around that? So I'm,
that guy is mine. He probably
didn't even want to do that job.
Just kicking it. Painting. Yeah.
But hanging around a bunch
of dudes with machine guns,
just looking left and right.
Everywhere you go.
Did you ever see that video
of George Herbert Walker?
He went into a restaurant and
this guy just starts screaming,
you're a war crime at all.
Awesome war crime at o.
And it's,
it's really freaky because, uh, you
know, no one knows how to deal with it.
This guy's obviously
willing to get arrested.
There's all these secret service
guys and you know, he's this old man,
this old rickety man and he's walking,
at least I hope these people are hounded
for the rest of their lives and tried
to be put under citizen's arrest and
they can't travel because they're wanted
for war crimes and other countries.
They've already been declared like
under a international courts to be a war
criminal.
I hope that they fucking live in suffer
every time they go out in public.
Fuck these people.
Oh, I hope they take mushrooms and
apologize. Yeah, that would be great.
Is this all bushes drawings?
[inaudible] you find the one in the
bathtub because these ones were actually
hacked. Someone hacked into his
email account or something and found,
so he's only released
the ones that are dogs,
but he does find the bush in the bathtub.
Dude.
It's fucking weird. Did you read, uh,
with Jimmy Carter said recently that
we're no longer a functional democracy.
Jimmy Carter is amazing. He's,
whew. That's a weird one, Huh?
Look at that Bush painting
a bunch of dollars.
That's what he does are
there is there is open,
that's him.
There was one of his face in the mirror.
Go up and click on the left hand side one.
Yeah. Can even large at one. Oh my God.
Look at his face in the mirror.
You can't click on it.
You can't zoom in. That's as
much as you can see. Oh Man.
Well quite perplex looking
back at him like very weird,
surreal lists like inside.
Wow. Weird. It's, you know,
here's the thing about art. Okay,
there's one thing if you suck at it,
but it's another thing if
you're old and you suck at it,
right as it comes through,
really weird.
It's like if you're not a thing,
if your Bush,
if you're a fucking eight year old
and you just learning how to paint,
that's one thing. But there's
something strange and I don't know why.
How about someone who's really old?
That paints that sucks, dude, move on.
You're not good.
And you think it's the drawing is one
of those things that you either have a
talent for. You don't like. Singing
is clearly that way. Singing to me,
like I have zero singing talent,
so I know that I can't do it,
but I've see people saying that don't
have any lessons at all and they just have
a voice that just can carry a note. Do
you think that's the way withdrawing too?
No, I think, I think
art is different because there's so
many different mediums and I think that
we've been conditioned as a society to
not approach art and think that, oh,
we're not artistic and stuff because
really imagination and art are what drives
like creativity and,
and reinvention.
And so like every great and Venner has
been an artist in a sense because he's
imagining something that didn't exist.
So if we are stifled and we don't,
you know,
by the powers that be or whatever,
and art and music are the first things
cut from public education and really it's
fucking up society because people,
when they don't express themselves
artistically in any sort of fashion,
then that's inhibiting their
own like personal growth
and Catharsis. Yeah. I think
what we were talking about earlier about
men needing some sort of competition
and sometimes women as well, I think
people need a focus that it's, it,
it really helps us to figure things out
because we don't have to figure out how
to do it.
You look at this,
the photo so weird.
It's so weird even in low resolution
cause we don't have to uh,
figure out a way to
hunt or fish or defend against enemies.
We have this,
we have this like need to like make
progress and make things happen and figure
things out. And creating is
one great way to do it. Yeah.
It's like yeah I was sitting
down doing something,
figuring out how to write a
story of figuring out how to,
do you think that's why so many people
have anxiety now because and as we've
evolved as humans,
we needed like huge adrenaline rushes
to go hunt or to do things like that and
fight and,
and getting these altercations and now
we just have this kind of mundane lives
where you go to work and sitting in front
of computer and we're so we have like
this mild just adrenaline
like anxiety all.
I totally think that's part of it.
I think the,
the people that I know that have the
least amount of that or people that engage
in a lot of martial arts, like my,
most of my friends that do Jujitsu,
I liked the calmest,
easiest going people to be around because
they're just constantly doing that.
It's a,
it becomes a part of their every day life.
This sort of like physical struggle so
that they don't need it and they don't
look for it in other ways and
their body doesn't look for it.
That that sort of like constant buzz of
anxiety could easily be attributed to
not blowing it out of your system,
not exercising your system,
sort of like a sexual thing all the time.
Sitting, sitting is terrible for you.
Horrible. Kelly start one of the guys
that I've had on my podcast, he's a,
I'm a strength and conditioning specialist
specialist and he's got a phd in
something Super Smart and uh,
he was explaining,
he a doctor and he's explaining
how the sitting is the new smoking.
Like what's terrible for your body
and your spine, your back. Like,
people are like slumped over and you know,
like terrible posture and push all these
pressure, this pressure on your discs.
They've either found that girls in north,
not girls,
people in North Korea are getting,
um,
disc issues because of phones because
they're looking down all the time.
And so they're getting bulging discs in
the back of their neck because of their
fucking, their, their posture, their
constant posture. Here's something crazy.
Weed is legal in North Korea.
Wow. Yeah, I heard that.
I heard that.
I blocked it out.
Such a weird thing that
doesn't drive with [inaudible]
I think we know about. Yeah. But
if you smell good, they eat you.
They serve you to their
political prisoners.
Maybe that's why they act the way
they are because they're just super,
everyone's just super stone. Completely
high. Everyone's out to get him
fucking tooth is Riley.
Yeah. Can I grab it? Yeah.
Did you ever seen that? Um,
vice special on a North Korea when
they went to North Korea? Tons. Rodman.
That was so weird. It was so weird.
One of the strangest happened.
He's like,
I just wanted to say behalf of my country.
You're like, why is Dennis Rodman's did
you want me out of the country? Got sure.
Go for it. Well, interesting. It was
cool. If you had to choose 10 people,
he definitely be there. 10 people to
represent the U S I mean, I thought it was
cool that he, he, yeah, it was,
it was fascinating that the,
like the Harlem Globe trotters would go
there and be like, I was just bizarre.
Well, he's a big basketball
fan and the new, the young,
the young guy who's running things
is, he's fairly young. Let's see.
He's like the 15 I think he's older than
that, but uh, I think he's fairly young.
How old is it, Kim Jong now he can't see.
That's the thing. I can't tell the age.
Oh,
are you being raised?
No, that's a compliment. Kim.
Jon Did it too. Oh my God.
He's 29 years old. He Shit. That's
so crazy. It looks a lot younger.
Wow. That's still extremely young. He's
29 years old. Weapon runs the country,
got nukes.
That's kind of,
that might be one of the craziest things
I've ever read that a 29 year old would
be able to run a country
with nuclear bombs,
a military dictatorship
with nuclear bombs. He's,
the supreme leader says what it says here,
Kim Jong Un is a supreme leader,
son of Kim Jong Il and the
grandson of Kim, he sung, Whoa,
where are we live in strange times.
Yeah. But then you know, I've,
I've actually got my horizons had been
brought in about North Korea a lot
because I've realized that there's a lot
of disinformation about why the country
is the way it is and it has a
lot to do with the Korean War,
which is something we very,
we know very little about and why there's
a demilitarized zone and why really
has a lot to do with,
with a u s policy kind of forcing them
into this fortress like mentality that
they feel like they have to act like
they're going to use nuclear bombs on,
otherwise we're going
to fucking take 'em out.
So it's almost like a self preservation.
I mean, I'm not justifying it.
I'm just saying,
you know,
it's kind of these last remaining
independent states in the world who aren't
completely overtaken by hegemony,
need to either act like they have nuclear
bombs and they're gonna use them or
they're going to get fucking
taken out. Look at Libya, Iraq,
serious in the, you know,
the cross hairs. Now
what do you think, I mean, you're,
you're a person who pays
way more attention to the
political atmosphere than I
am. What do you think's going to
happen in the next 10, 20 years?
If you had to guess, how do you
think this is all gonna play out?
I think that arrogant empires always
fall and we definitely are living in one.
Um, and we need, unless we scale back,
unless something happens within the u
s to try to maintain and preserve this
country from collapsing, I
think we're going to see, uh,
some fucked up shit go on
in the Middle East. We're,
we're driving such instability
in the Middle East. If you
look back at US policy,
you know,
we look at the Middle East is like this
clash of civilizations and we're kind of
trained to say,
oh these people are barbaric,
they're so behind where
the western world is.
But really ignoring the fact that
the US had been propping up military
dictatorships and Mubarak
and sponsoring his, you know,
militarism for the last 50 years and it
also in Afghanistan were the ones who
radicalized Islam there
and propped up in Lawton.
And I mean where would those countries
be if it weren't for us kind of
suppressing that growth and
evolution in those cultures.
And it's really turned them more Islamic
and more like radical and that in that,
right. So I think that
we've really cultivated this
schism in the region that's,
that's created a lot of this
instability and like look at a rock.
It's a fucking civil war. Why?
Because we fucked up the country,
we fucked that shit up for 10 years and
we just bounce and we're like, whatever,
your rocks just fucked.
And then it's on the border of Syria
in Syria is doing the same thing.
I mean it's a mess and it's, it's
a shame. I hope that it doesn't.
I see it going into a full on civil
war there in Iraq and Syria and it just
depends on what the u s going to do
because the u s paves the way in terms of
road policy. So I don't think Obama
wants to get involved in Syria.
I think he's trying to do
everything you can and not,
but I think there's a lot of pressure
from a lot of people to get in there. Oh,
but that's going to be
fucking deal. More wars, more whores,
dude in fucking God. More wars.
You know, we had Dan Carlin
on from hardcore history.
You ever listen to that podcast? I
have heard about it. Fucking amazing.
One of his most bad ass
podcast is about the goals.
And he told a story about how the Mongols
invaded Iraq and the 12 hundreds and
essentially it never covered the killed.
Everybody killed everybody through all
their work into the ocean or into the
river.
The river was black with ink and red
with blood and like they just slaughtered
the town.
And they said that this was in the 12
hundreds and he was talking about how
scholars have argued that.
And today,
like even in 2013 never really recovered,
sort of recovered a little bit,
but it was always like,
it was at one point in time,
it was one of the highest levels of,
of,
of culture and intellect in the world.
Like the,
the Islamic world had many scientists,
many scholars,
many poets and all these different,
really an intelligent and well respected
people as far as the intellectuals of
the day. They killed all of
them. They killed all of them.
They threw all their work into the river.
They,
the literally wiped out the town and all
that they learned and all of they had
accumulated all of that. The
Mongols just destroyed it all. Yeah.
And then we came along,
you know, 2000 whatever.
And one more time just
to the ground again.
I mean, he ran one point, yeah. 3000 year
old Persian empire. Um, and we, and it's,
it's facing extinction.
I mean we can weave,
we can decide whether or not we're going
to completely fuck up that, that region,
the world. But yeah, I mean a rock and
then the looting of all these ancient, um,
libraries and museums there. I
mean, all these ancient artifacts.
And then look at Lebanon,
another birthplace of civilization.
We just like Israel just bomb the shit
out of it and just fucking destroyed it.
I mean, it's just unbelievable. We
should be protecting these sites,
but I guess we're a little bit
too short sided to give a shit.
Well, it's, it's just s I
think it's a really strange time as far
as our ability to influence events and
to change the world and our ability to
physically impact the world and are sort
of our,
or our ability to have evolved to the
point where we know that that's not a good
idea.
It's almost like our,
our ability to create movement and to
create events is far greater than our
ability to recognize the
impact of these events.
What do you think this is all about?
Do you think that it's,
it's just an a sheen that's kind of
operating almost on its own in terms of
perpetual warfare in the
military industrial complex,
not being able to be scaled down and just
like the enormous growth and you know,
need to just attain more and more
power. And what, where, what is that?
Well,
it seems like that kind of a thing is
a trend for human beings that when they
get into a position of power, they try to
keep pushing it. They don't scale back.
They don't,
they don't never see her.
They never get comfortable with their
salary. They always want advances.
They always are.
They always want bonuses.
They always want more money and they
want every year they want to raise and we
want to continue to move
forward and forward.
And we see that happen
where people cut corners or,
and people in positions
with extreme power,
they can manipulate the actual laws
themselves in order to allow them to do
things that maybe most people wouldn't
agree to. But it's sort of the same,
in my opinion,
at least the same sort of process or
the same sort of pattern that exists
throughout the human race.
When people get into a position of power,
they tend to push it. That's
just what we do. When we,
when a guy becomes the sheriff and a
town and he's got corrupt tendencies,
he starts to control the
town. And when, you know,
yeah, it's just like t
when the technology exists,
it will be abused by
people almost until the
pinning of the big mind.
And I think if there's anything
that's going to save people,
it's the opening of the big mind and what
I believed the opening of the big mind
is that we're going to eventually come
to a point in the very near future,
2030 whatever years. I don't want to
gas, but what we share consciousness,
not just be able to email each other,
but literally I can get inside the Abbey.
Martin said, I can understand.
You can get inside of my head.
You can get inside of his head and
then you're gonna kill yourself.
Once you get into his head,
you're going to go, this is,
I didn't even know these
people like this out there.
Fucking shitty videos plungers
and all sorts of shit.
He didn't even think it fit in your
ass and it's just the the point. Yeah,
things that I think that if there's any
trend that seems to me to be inevitable,
this is two and one is the things are
gonna progress. They're going to always,
there's going to be a faster laptop next
year if the cars are going to get more
gas mileage and go zero to 60 quicker
and your phone's going to be lighter and
stronger and it just keeps coming up that
he's to have a problem with that plan.
Obsolescence,
obsolescence though that we have this
system that knows 20 years down the road,
the model that they're going to release
in 20 years and then releasing these
antiquated models year after year so you
can just buy the newest version of them.
I don't know how much
of that is real because I think that in
an environment is competitive as the one
we experienced today.
I think eventually the cream rises to
the top and the competition is so strong.
Like let's put the smartphone market
for an example to develop a smart for
phone, get it approved by
the FTC, then release it.
I'm not sure who's holding back shit.
I don't know if they really are.
I don't know if it's a simple matter of
you have to get things approved or this
is just what they can
do on a mass level now.
And if you'd like say if like it's like
Samsung Galaxy s four or some shit like
that.
One of the newest android phones.
I pretty sure that's about as
good as they can do right now.
I don't think they're really
holding anything back,
but they also know that six months from
now that's going to be dog shit because
this is going to be an help me. It'll
be one phone that you press a button.
It makes a Princess Leia Hologram, you
know, I mean that's going to happen.
There's this dude from a, there's a place
in, um, I think it's Marina del Ray.
It's called just cause it's a
and an emotion capture thing.
Just do named Ruben who took us and
showed us how to use this motion capture
shit. And one of the things that they
showed was that they can take you,
you put on a suit and then they put,
instead of you being Abby Martin,
you're a giant dinosaur or your a
spaceman or your a wolverine, you know,
they can just make you whatever you
want inside this game. Yeah, yeah.
Without a doubt. So there's gonna
be a phone within our lifetime.
They're going to bring up press a button
and you're going to be able to appear
in a Princess Leia outfit and you're
going to, you're going to be able to say,
help me Obi one my only hope, you mean
you could literally be a three d hologram.
We are definitely going to have
virtual reality with reality. But wait,
when you're talking to
is planned obsolescence.
Well it's good.
I get the sharing of consciousness thing
cause I don't understand how that would
work as how can you really,
I don't either conscious or we're fucked.
I don't think it's isolated consciousness.
I think it's accessing,
I think it's the ability to access
information and the ability to access
thoughts. I think one of the first steps,
and this is completely hypothetical,
folks, people that are screaming on
science forums, this is not possible.
You fucking idiot. You're right.
We're just talking shit here. Okay,
relax.
But I think one of the things that's
probably going to happen is it gonna be
able to record memories.
They're going to be able to put a hard
drive in your mind somewhere in your
system that can record your memories more
accurately than your own memory, Ken.
And that will act as our new memory.
It's so sort of how,
like you can't really
remember that many phones,
phone numbers anymore because they're
all stored in your cell phone.
I know like four or five numbers
and that's it. Once those are done,
they're out of my system.
But I think that we're eventually
going to be able to get a, uh,
a version of your memory that's going
to be an artificial recording that's in
like an HD. That's
absolutely perfect. Wait,
no, then that's, that's incredible.
But they already are doing
studies where they can,
they have like analogs and cataloging
dream sequences and almost like
deciphering different shapes of
people of what people are dreaming.
It's really rough right now,
but the technology's there and it's
definitely developing. So that's,
that's to fucking
revolutionize shit right there.
Those are dreams to be able
to be recorded. Hitting me.
There was a woman, um, I think, I'm
trying to figure convicted on her memory.
There was a woman, um, it was in
another country. Okay. Women's center.
There was a woman who was accused of a
crime and they called her into court and
tried this test on her fucking FTM.
I forget what it's called.
They, um, they figured
out how to register or,
or to access her memories.
And in those memories they determined
that she had a personal knowledge of the
crime and that they couldn't prove that
she had actually committed the crime.
They couldn't prove
whether she was a witness,
but she said she wasn't
even anywhere near.
And they proved that she had a
personal knowledge of the crime. Now.
Bob Murray Basin had
nothing to do with like,
yes, like lie detector technology
or no, no. Straight up.
Yeah. It's somehow or another
they're accessing memory. Let me see.
I'm trying to Google the correct
things. Yeah. Somebody uh,
showed it to me the other than that it
was, it's really crazy. This, um, I don't,
I don't have the store in front of me.
Next podcast.
I'll find it folks and I'll
get it to you and shit fucks
you do 300 podcasts. I don't even know
where this is. You fucking asshole.
How about your fucking research ship?
Before you talk about it,
somebody showed it to me.
I'm assuming it's real. You.
I'm sure you, you smart cats.
We'll send it to me on Twitter.
Did you hear about the cops and
Detroit robbing people? Real cops?
There were real crops. What are
we in fucking Gotham city? Well,
Detroit Kinda is Detroit's way
scarier than Gotham city. Detroit is.
We were just there really with the film.
The TV show does log island thought Zug
Island is where they make a lot of cars.
It's, it's mostly like a steel factory
in plant. And uh, when we were there,
we saw houses that were like 50 bucks,
cause we,
we saw found one on one and it
was 39. Yeah, $39 for a house.
No regular is there 500. There's a lot of
$500 houses there. You just get it out.
But you wouldn't want to live there.
Like they would have to pay you to live
there. It smells horrible. Like it,
like a sulfury burning chemical. He smell
and it's just in the air all the time.
And people were s they were fishing
in this polluted river. And uh,
my friend was like, why are they
efficient in that river? It's like,
because they need to eat.
Like it's really that
crazy 47% illiteracy rate,
the highest rate I believe
of abandoned houses,
like the growth of abandoned houses in
the nation. Pretty sure I read that too.
I might've made that up though.
But yeah, we can't, and I'm not an,
let me preempt this by saying I'm
not advocating bailing out cities,
but it is just funny that the
government's like, oh, we can't help you.
We're going to fucking
take all the pensions,
but at the same time we're just going to
bail out giant corporations and fuck it,
maintain 900 bases around the world
and spend trillions of dollars fucking
maintaining this empire basis.
But it's a,
but we're just going to
neglect all the cities and yes,
there was a lot of corruption in Detroit.
Yes.
There's a lot of externalities that
I'm not taking into consideration.
It's just an interesting dichotomy of
who the fuck does this government really
care about?
And again, it brings us full circle
to porn. Nobody bailed out at all.
Nobody comes for a circle to
my neighborhood was a porn guy,
lost his fucking house.
Bullshit, man. Nobody cared.
You're trying to try and get
them moved to Detroit. Yeah.
All the people who lost out in
the porn industry in Detroit,
free taxes and those people,
fuck you for cheap.
They're willing to eat radioactive
fish though. Fuck you on the cheap.
Okay.
That's a good move. This is the end of
the show. Clearly we ran out of gas.
I'm going to pee. You guys talk amongst
yourselves and then we'll wrap this up.
I'll come back and we'll
clean it up tight. Oh yeah.
Dry wants to see it.
Show up on snap went off.
So what are these little lamps do?
There's Salt Himalayan salt lamps.
Supposedly they have some kind
of energy that comes off of him,
but I don't buy it,
I think was just a hippie closeted hippie.
So they're actually made of salt.
Yeah, they're made out of salt.
Crazy. Um, so your artwork, you do,
do you also have like a,
like a gallery or do you have a any online
where you can buy posters over your,
over your stuff.org?
I'd be mark and check out
the gallery there and a,
I just brought something that I thought
you guys would like here. But yeah,
I do a lot of like abstract
art and political art as
well. Oh, that's cool. Yeah.
Did you go to school for art or no? No,
I think art school is kind of bullshit.
Yeah, it's kind of conforms.
You knew what they,
whatever they think artists or whatever.
So our,
it just started off as mostly
a go into the collage section
right there.
Okay.
It started off as just mostly an
outlet because political activism was
dominating my life,
but then it,
okay.
It ended up being something that I was
able to bridge the two together and it
just, it keeps me sane. I don't get to
do it as much as I would like to. But,
and what is, is this, what is
this medium you're using as ink?
That is all paint pen and cutouts of
paper. I do nothing on the computer,
so that's all just hand drawn ink and,
and collage has really cool paint pen.
Thank you.
Now do you ever do a live gallery or do
you ever have, have you ever done that?
Like a,
like a showing of your year?
Oh yeah,
absolutely.
I did a lot of art shows in the past and
I did my first political installation.
That's a line of riot cops I took a
photo of. And then just drew over it.
What did I miss? I miss a
lot of shit, dude. Your style
did I miss out?
We're looking@herartworkatabbymartin.org
I love when a,
I don't know something about somebody.
It turns out they're bad acid
shit. Yeah, that's pretty sweet.
Like finding that you have to
look at here. Bad ass artist.
What's the video? Cool. Use it. Yes. Okay,
so this is a little compilation promo
that I made of what I think are the best
clips of the entire first
season of breaking this set,
which is the show I have on rt America.
So this is kind of just a little two
minute a preview of what the fuck the
show's about. Okay. Check it out.
Hmm.
Media candidates, corporate talk.
Cracy how rude. You can't wait for this
to be over word New York Times.
Welcome to the,
this administration has no
credibility club. Remind me again,
why does that people are worshiping kings
and Queens in the year 2013 five novel
idea.
I'm blaming the whistleblower for trying
to evade death by way of the espionage
act.
You actually talk about what the NSA
revelations are in a counselor's republic
democracy. This is not informed
consent by those who are governed.
This is manufacturer consent and I would
actually argue it's core is consent in
secret. Guys, this is not about
safety. It's not about terrorism.
This is about shilling descent
and controlling society. Live,
live, die, die, die. Is he dead already?
You can't conduct these kinds
of wars around the world,
killing innocent people in the pursuit
of a few bad guys and pretend that it's
not going to come back to, to hurt
you. Did you find the logic flawed?
Now looking back,
do you regret your vote to invade,
not occupy a country to find one man?
See,
we ought to be critical of
highly concentrated forms
of power wherever we find
it, because that kind of power was
usually subject of chronic abuse. Hello,
I'm Stephanie from Nestle.
We sold a video.
You post on youtube criticizing
this Nestle over water.
So He's all response.
Walmart's also been described
as an economic deathstar
destroying everything in
its path. Ligon behind nothing
more than homogenous wasteland.
So the harmless activist is now the
criminal yet actual criminal banksters run
free. Well, I'm glad this government
has its priorities straight.
So do you shackled down your mind and
subscribe to old school paradigms or do
you liberate yourself by
acknowledging reality? Sure,
the world would lose its innocence,
but wouldn't you rather know the truth?
Powerful. Abby Martin, you're all
angry and shit. I'm all pissed.
You like causing a revolution
or something. I'm just pissed.
And you don't see people
who are like, yeah, don't,
but Archie allows you to be pissed, but
I should say that you're very pleasant.
You know by saying you're angry,
you're kind of angry when
you're doing these clips.
If someone didn't know you and they
saw that, they would think like, wow,
this is like really intense check. But
you're very pleasant. You're very normal.
That's funny. It is funny that you
say that because everyone I've met,
they're like, wow, you look, do you seem
like you're really intense? And I'm like,
oh, just yeah, I'm pissed off
when I'm talking about the shit.
But I could also be a normal person who
can have conversations about different
things.
Yeah.
Ultimately it all boils down to you
can't deny what's going on and so many
people are and if it's not for people
like you that come up and go, hey,
quite honestly what the fuck is
happening if that doesn't happen.
It's a real controversial thing and I
applaud you and this is going to sound
condescending, but it's, I
have to say it this way anyway.
I applaud you for doing it even more
because you're a woman because I know that
a lot of men don't want to hear
women talk about important issues.
There's a weird thing like
especially old school, he type men.
Like if you're like how many dudes
in their 50s one to listen to some,
how will the you like 29 or
something like that. Yeah,
29 year old chick fucking smart mouth
talking shit about our military or
whatever.
You know,
like they don't want to hear that shit
like old dudes don't want to hear that at
all. So it takes a lot of balls
or whatever you have ovaries.
It takes a lot of ovaries. It
takes a lot of courage to, uh,
to be able to do that.
It's a tricky situation when you start
talking about shit that other people
should have taken care of.
It's like,
cause you're not just saying to old
dude's like, hey dickhead, you know,
like you paying attention
to what's going on.
Like this is what the government is
doing to you. You're also saying, hey,
how did you let this happen?
You were the ones that were in truck.
What are you doing that accident?
You were like,
you were the ones who
are in charge of this.
Like you guys allowed this to happen.
Like,
and anybody that's upset at the
way the situation is right now,
who had anything to do with it,
look at yourself, look at yourself.
Don't get mad at Edward Snowden.
Yeah. And I think, you know, people
have told me that I'm, you know,
why don't you provide more solutions or
you're like me fearmongering and stuff.
I'm like,
look,
we all need to get this information first
before we can even get to what we can
do about it.
Like,
we don't fucking know any of this shit
because we've been conditioned to not
knowing it. The media is
controlled by six corporations,
six corporations that work in concert
with the establishment to push their
narrative.
Six corporations that have about 120
people sit on the boards of directors of
that also sit on the board of directors
of defense contractors, Monsanto. I mean,
this is what's controlling.
That's the corporatocracy.
The media is allowed to lie.
It's about entertainment.
It's not about providing information.
So it's,
it's a shame that I have to work for
Russian government to provide the truth
about my own country.
And it's a shame that there's no outlet
here that will allow me to do that.
It's amazing that this is like
when we think about Russia,
when you think about Putin,
you think about like, oh,
don't piss that fucking guy off.
Like the, those people are crazy.
Like those people are gangster as fuck.
But uh,
we don't think about that when it comes
to this country. Right? But meanwhile,
you look at what the fuck is
going on. I'm like, look at this.
The Edward Snowden thing
is a classic situation.
They're offering political asylum to
guy that exposed a worldwide spying
program. Who else? A spine
because the UK spine,
their spine to China spine.
Everyone's spine. What's going on?
I got Kathleen and fucking
like Brazilians. It's like,
why the fuck are we spine on?
Brazilians never know that ass [inaudible]
they they find out about you husker.
He has he ever eat a full go to
Sean. I read it. One of those places.
That's how I supposed
to say if your culture,
by the way you don't say Chao Fogo de
Chao, you don't say that. You say Sean,
but it's true. Acting like, oh,
it's a thumb in the eye at the
middle finger of the u s well,
actually the u s set the double standard
years ago when we denied repeated
extradition requests of
actual criminals from Russia,
Russia has fucking asses to extradite
multiple criminals and we said, no. Yeah,
Ecuador. Venezuela. Yeah, but we
didn't want to write. That's a,
why are we acting shocked when
other countries don't do it?
Why are we acting so shocked
when Russia is like, no,
we're not going to extradite this guy.
Isn't it funny that we keep saying we?
Yeah,
I need to stop doing.
I tried it too, but it's so easy to do.
So easy to go. We're the ones who write.
That's what pisses people off though.
I know. They're like, don't call it. We'd
say, well, okay, it's somebody. Yeah,
this should, yeah, it should be a better
account of what the fuck we stands for.
Yeah. It's like I'm sick of just
saying like the US government. This,
that's the real problem with
like conspiracy theory type talk.
The government is trying to,
how much of the government,
because the government itself, it's
the IRS, the CIA, the FBI and the NSA.
A lot of them which don't even like
each other. Even though we have,
it's not us necessarily doing it.
We are sponsoring it with our tax dollars,
so it really is. We in
a general sense. Sure.
In a very general surgery general,
we think of like responsibility for the
actual action itself and then we say,
we did this and Afghanistan,
we did this and that. Right.
I didn't fucking slaughter
any Afghanis or it's,
it gets real tricky when you get
into the weeds. Strange Times.
That'd be Martin to think about that
like your historically to be a reporter.
This is one of the weirdest times ever.
It's one of the weirdest times ever
to to be witnessing sort of a society
boiling. I guess though the, the,
their statement holds true that every
time was the weirdest time for that time.
Right, right. But this is
the weirdest time ever.
Yeah. I, I think about that a lot.
I think because of the advancement of
technology and the fact that we are so
interconnected and know about all the
horrible shit going on at any given time,
does it just seem like it's so much poor
fucked up now because we have access to
all of that. We get like an AP newser
when everything horrible happened.
It's like, I don't know. Or is there
really more like horrible shit going on?
I don't know. Well, we definitely
have more if you hear that.
It's not me paying for corn, a little
coffee. I think we definitely have. Yeah,
more access.
There's no question about that.
And so we're going to hear more stories
about things that have happened, but I,
I wish I knew how much of it's,
it's how much of it is actually how much
of it is affecting the actual things
that we,
we
do, I don't know about. Well,
that's the problem is all we
hear on the corporate media shit,
that doesn't affect us. Jodi
Arias, case, Zimmerman. I mean,
in the grand scheme of things,
you can argue that yes,
the stand your ground laws
definitely affect people.
But did it warrant that much coverage
for weeks and weeks and weeks and every
detail of the case. Now,
here's a perfect example today.
Think about all the shit that's
going on in the world today. I mean,
there's giant chunks.
Manhattan size or falling off
a fucking Greenland, that huge
chunks of ice, right?
We all know about that.
We all know about this
Bradley manning thing.
Edward Snowden thing.
We all know about what the
fuck is going on with Iran.
What's happening with North Korea.
We all know about that.
But the front page of CNN,
I'm fighting for my life.
It's a ride because he's
suspended for a year.
You know what?
He only has $270 million.
What will he do if he is forced to take
a heat a whole year off for using roads?
Fucking bad for him to stop what you're
saying or what are you a communist?
This is front page news for a reason.
Cause this is the most important
story in America. A rod suspended,
but in lineup during appeal.
So he's allowed to go into
law so we can go, this is,
how is this going to play out? It's
going to kind of watch it. Grand drama
as fuck. You know what terrified
me is I vice is so awesome.
I love that you've been
interviewing as Shane Smith.
Yeah, he's, he's awesome dude.
This oh wow. Great column and taking
rides to um, whew. Wow. No. But the Fenix,
the Venice one where he was like,
Venice is underwater. Holy Shit.
Like underwater for a hundred
days out of the year. It's just,
that's how much the
oceans rising right now.
So it's like the people who
are much is accessible. Um,
they've just built bridges all over,
so people just walk on these
platforms all over the city. Wow.
A hundred days of the year, it's
totally flooded. So it is, is it rising?
Like how much of a difference is it from
before it's been progressively rising
and Shane Smith is just like,
look,
these people who are arguing
about is global warming,
manmade is climate change
payment. It doesn't fucking
matter. It's happening now.
We don't need to have the argument
about fucking who did it. Yeah. Yeah.
Shit's fucked up and bullshit.
What do we do about it?
That's a quote somewhere in the
bottom of a message board now.
That'd be more him chips fucked up.
That's going to be in a bottle.
The cork bottle. A real good
point. There was an article
Miami, they were talking about Miami and
within the decade we'll be underwater.
They're like,
you can't stop it.
Also because Miami apparently is
on like I very porous limestone.
It's not hard ground cause it's like,
it's not just at sea level.
It's like a giant sponge. Great. So they
were saying that like it's gonna be,
it's gonna be crazy. Like it's all
just going to be a marsh. Like you're,
you're not gonna be able to get here.
Mondo. I think the problem with the whole
argument is people like Al Gore who are
actually profiting off the solutions,
the carbon credit thing.
I think it's bullshit.
Um,
you can't trade pollution and somehow
think that's going to be fucking in the
answer. So I think, and then
when you see things like, uh,
the meat industry not getting penalized
for the fact that they are creating the
majority of carbon output. So this
is a meat industry that's doing that.
The methane coming from far farther.
So,
so the methane from cow farts are the
biggest problem the world's ever known.
I think it's a large percentage of,
of carbon emissions.
But the fact that we're not even talking
about that, it's like the, you know,
the burdens put on the consumer
where we're like calculate
your carbon footprint.
I think people like what the fuck?
Yeah. We need to put cups
over the back of cows. Bucks,
tape those bitches down and capture
all that methane. Just capture it.
You know what?
Put them in the Dome like that Stephen
King Book put all the cows inside of the
dome. Is that one of those cows? It
has a, um, is that we'll get the balls.
Jesus Christ the size,
that fucking bull. Um,
they could capture it.
Why can't they capture it and you can,
they figure out a way to like dome
them cows in and suck all the mess.
You could put a man in orbit
in the space station floating
above the planet and he could
fucking Twitter from up there.
You tell me you can't dome up
a few cows and suck them farts.
Turn them in the resources.
Isn't that possible?
It seems like he's pretty positive.
It should be, right? Yeah.
If we can figure out to do satellites,
we should be able to figure out a suck
methane out of the air, out of cows,
asses the future gloomy or Rosie?
Abby Martin.
I think it depends on your
perspective. I hate
people who are like, oh,
I don't look at positive or negative news
because I was pushing of your grandma.
I now look at news cause it
makes me sad. I don't have, oh,
I'm just really positive. I just like
don't, oh no, that's just too negative.
It's like, well this is fucking reality.
So you're going to intake reality
and figure out how you're going to relay
your own message of what reality is
like.
That's fucking truth.
So if you're going to reject
a whole portion of the
world because you don't want
to fucking be negative, then I didn't
really answer your question. I think
either way it does. It's your, you're just
sort of hedging your bets. Yeah. Yeah.
It can go either way. Right. Do you think,
do you have a responsibility being in a
position where people are listening to
you to talk about certain things?
Uh, I think, yeah,
I mean I think I have the resources and
natural does it mean I had compassion
for the law.
I started off as an anti war activist and
then it just went from there realizing
all this shit was censored.
Why is it sensored?
And I'm getting into media and so I've
been passionate about this stuff for,
since I was 17, you know, out
in the streets doing activism.
You were in the streets at 17.
What are you doing out there
fucking trying to lobby against
is not blowing you rock up
when you were 17. Yeah. Wow.
How many people listened?
They're like, bitch, come
on. You're fucking 17.
How many people listen to 17 year
olds? Yeah. So unfortunate and aspect.
Well,
what's crazy is that there was millions
of people in the street saying the same
thing,
but we were at Norton.
Um, when you see like a occupy
Wall Street and shit like that,
do you think that that has positive
effect? Absolutely. I think so. Yeah.
I think that it really got the,
uh,
the debate into the 99% versus the 1%
kind of realizing that we all have so many
problems and when people
demonized occupy and saying,
oh you guys can't get a consolidated
message, what the fuck is this all about?
It's like, well there's fucking 99
problems and a bitch ain't one. But no,
I mean there seriously so
many problems facing I was,
it all stems the same system so I don't
blame the Movement for not galvanizing
behind one message.
The problem with occupies,
it was so inclusive that would be like
homeless people would be doing open mics
and shit.
Mike check. So like it's like,
dude, you can't mark chart number.
Everyone's like Mike
check and you're like,
I need a sip.
Well there was a cultural aspect to
the whole occupy thing that got little
strange and that was that Mike check
thing that people would do that like in
courthouses, Mike checking in, people will
like yell it out. It was very military.
I think there needs to be some sort of
leadership, you know? But then again,
I think that there needs to be, if we
had like a true democracy would be, uh,
and I think if we had people
actually having democratic input,
but the thing is we don't have that.
We have like what one delegate that can
go and fucking the electoral college is
bullshit. We don't even have like
direct representation. So it's just,
it was a good concept and I think
it's the start of it, you know,
it was cracked down brutally
by militarized riot police
all across the country
on a federal level.
I saw it firsthand.
I was in Oakland living there and
there's a fucking police state dude.
I was like,
why are you guys expelling so many
resources to shut down at a little camp of
like a hundred people? It was like fucking
a thousand police full riot riot gear.
I like treating it like a riot.
Like I don't understand if you have,
if you're dressed as a paramilitary troop,
um,
I don't understand why you need to be,
uh, using these crowd control methods if,
if there's no right. It's like,
I don't know. It's just bizarre.
Fart in the new generation. It's part
of what it always is going to be.
There's always going to be a resisting
of change and try and fight back.
The angry hoards.
I mean this is very similar to
dress like a troop. You're going
to act like a fucking soldier.
You know what?
I have described it as like an enemy.
I've described operation or occupy Wall
Street as being sort of like white blood
cells like there,
they're going around the infected area.
They don't know what the fuck
they're going to do, what they're,
they're making it inflamed.
They're causing attention.
Like when you get an infection on your
knee and you look down at your knees
swollen, that's sort of like white
blood cells and occupy Wall Street.
He looked down and this,
these areas where these people camped
out and screaming and yelling and doing
mic checks all day and like that's
inflammation. You've got an,
you got an inflammation spot,
you've got a sore,
you got a dirty little store right there.
It's, it's for there for a
reason. So future. Rosie,
can we say Rosie? Yeah. Possibly. Possibly
Rosie get worse before it gets better.
But I have faith in humanity and I think
that we can pull things around and I
wouldn't be doing what I'm
doing if I didn't believe that.
Do you like working for our tea?
I do.
I have an amazing amount
of editorial control over.
What do you say that you
like working for Russia?
It's a pretty fucked up world, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah. It just, it's just twisted.
It's like I never thought that I'd just
right and right is left to tell the
truth. That's crazy
powerful. Poff Abby Martin,
so he could follow Abby Martin on
Twitter. It's just Abby Martin, right?
Harvey Martin. And um, is
there a website for your show?
Oh, just look at breaking the set on
youtube and I also have media roots is my
immediate organization on the side. Abby
Martin. Dot Org. Anything else to say?
Like five people before you bolt?
Yeah, just fucking the truth is,
is enlightening.
Don't reject it.
Embrace it and express yourself.
And if you're passionate about something,
it's a responsibility to express
that in whatever medium you choose.
But don't reject the truth and don't
turn it off because we got to fucking
progress.
In other words,
get it together.
Bitches with much love for all who
spread the love and you shall receive.
We will see you guys
later this week with um,
Greg Fitzsimmons will be stopping by
and I got some other shit going on too.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna try to bring in
one of these dudes that are angry at me,
the chem shell dudes and have them sit
down no unedited for several hours and
let them express themselves cause they're
so pissed at me. Can we bring the big,
big flick I into at the
same time? Why not, right?
We will see you freak soon.
So until then,
go shop with stamps.com do you don't shop.
You send shit stamps.com.
Use the code word jre Savior's house.
I'm cash and squarespace.com use the code
Joe and the number eight eight stands
for August freaks. That's
right. You're slowly dying.
W also brought to you by on it. That's
o.N , n. I. T. Use the code name, Rogan.
Save yourself 10% off of any and all
supplements. And I say you're dying,
but that might not be true. In fact,
this Wednesday we explore that option.
We're talking to Ray Kurzweil.
It's all about transhumanism on Joe Rogan.
Questions, everything. 10:00 PM on Scifi.
All right. Thank you for all the love and,
uh,
even for criticisms cause it makes me
consider whether or not you're correct or
if you just to come to find out
everything through life. Keep it together.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Bye Bye.
[inaudible]
oh.