Is looking to go to war.
Everybody else was looking to kill them.
Everybody else is looking at take it.
Most people in this world just want to
get by.
They want to be healthy.
They want to have children and have
those children be happy and want to get
through the day.
They want to get through the fucking
day.
There are led by people who are
profiting off of the drama.
That's the real thing.
This is why this podcast is so important
and not to be melodramatic is to go back
to the success of this podcast and the
success of vice and all this stuff is
that it's because all of the other shit
out there is bullshit.
This is the whole thing is what happens
in mainstream media and the news cycle
is crap and what's happening here and
the reason why you have so many people
listening to you and supporting you.
And the reason why vice is growing so
rapidly is because we're just regular
dudes were regular guys just like,
you know,
we like,
we like mma fighting me,
like having a few drinks with you and
yeah.
And you go out there in the world and
you say,
hold on a second,
where's the fucking rationality?
Yeah,
why did these fuckers have nuclear
weapons?
Why the fuck is this happening?
Why is the fucking world sinking?
And we're not doing something about it.
I don't understand.
I'm not like,
I'm not a Jesus on the cross.
I'm not,
I'm not trying to be that guy.
I'm just going out in the world and
going,
holy fuck someone.
I say it's the end of the world is
because I went to cashmere,
I went to the Indian side of cashmere.
The Indians said if we have another
Mumbai attack,
we will attack Pakistan.
Then I went to Pakistan.
I was like,
why are you still sending these?
You're training the ISI in the military.
Why are you still sending these guys in
India?
They've said that if you still,
if you send them in again,
they're going to attack you and they're
like,
yes,
because we're going to win and you're
like,
nobody's going to fucking win.
You're going to new kitchen,
you're all going to die.
And the thing is,
as I keep saying there,
and it's the same thing in China,
it's the same thing.
Even the funny shit that we do is like,
it's the absurdity of the modern
condition that's the world has become
insane and I'm saying where all the
adults say,
but where's the rationality?
Where's just two regular guys?
And by the way,
we're just sitting here in a,
in a,
in with a beautiful oak table,
having a few drinks and so many people
are resonating with it.
So we're just two dudes talking.
Yeah,
but the thing is there's so many people,
you know,
resonate,
resonate.
Why?
Because everyone just coming out of the
pond going.
Hold on a second,
hold on a second.
What the fuck's going on?
What?
We're all rational people.
We're all smart people.
We all have the Internet.
We use fucking.
See,
all this shit's going on,
what the fuck's going on?
And I think that the answers are
terrifying because you know what?
Nobody has an answer.
Oh well it's just this,
this,
and this.
It's not really going to happen because
it's that and it's just this guy doing
that.
Brian Cowen for Fox News.
But the thing is,
is it's not true.
Like the regional thing,
the New York Times
says,
D,
refuted that.
Uh,
yeah,
but it's not true.
Like there is no rationality.
The answer is more terrifying than the
question is why aren't they fucking.
Why do they have nukes?
Because we gave them because we're crazy
because we're crazy because we so rushed
now had money.
They needed to nukes.
We hadn't needed money.
Boom.
Chucka boom.
Correct.
You know what to stay scary real.
The real scary story is Canada had this
thing that can do reactor,
the failsafe react to the most safe
reactor on her fucking beautiful
reactor.
The titanic and reactors and Canada is
like,
oh,
we're the largest donator of 48.
I'm Canadian by the way,
and we're the largest foreign foreign
donate as a foreign aid and then we gave
the reactors to Pakistan and we said,
now whatever you do,
don't do anything bad with it.
And they said,
oh,
of course not.
And you're sitting there going,
what the fuck?
What the fuck were you fucking thinking?
Canada giving them fucking reactors.
What the fuck were you thinking?
That's so silly.
The reactive thing is a real freak out
to me and I talk about my act like I
don't know if I'm allowed to swear.
By the way,
what are you talking about here?
What's the matter?
Oh,
you want a cigarette?
Will say that shit.
I didn't know.
I didn't know what you were saying.
I didn't know that was a bad thing that
somebody would not want you to indulge.
Let's be real here.
I don't know.
Come.
Come on.
Shane Smith.
You know I love you like a brother
telling me what's going on.
Who doesn't want you to indulge?
You got an issue,
Mrs.
Mrs Shane Smith is perhaps doesn't want
hubby had cancer or bullets is
cigarettes,
is the last thing she should worry
about.
These dudes go to the Congo and his
underwear.
He shocked with the Congo.
You should worry.
Have you gone?
Did you go to the Kinda?
Yeah.
See,
that's where I dropped it.
I've been to Goma and it's a right now.
It's,
it's,
it's going fucking crazy.
The only way I would go to the Congo,
it was if someone absolutely showed me,
we're going to find the apes.
I could see one of those eight giant.
We're,
we're still working,
bro.
It's something you don't have.
That's not like a sasquatch.
Did I ever tell you about the David?
Show him the dinosaurs.
Yes.
I watched that episode.
He went.
They believe there's a Brontosaurus in
the Congo.
He lit.
There's alligators.
Yeah.
Okay.
We need to wrap our heads around the
idea that alligator is fucking survive.
You know,
I'm reading this Chris Ryan book sex at
dawn.
Fascinating,
fascinating book.
And he talks about the name you Katon
with the name came from.
Is the one of the,
uh,
American or one of the Christopher
Columbus settlers.
You don't have to worry about where you
grew up in comedy clubs and pool halls.
Let that shit go.
Don't worry about it.
He,
uh,
he asked them what is the name of your
land?
And the guy said something like,
well,
you know,
in,
whatever the Mayan tongue is.
And so they said Yucatan.
Okay.
You could tie that was like as close to
it.
Turns out one reviewed
what the actual original word was
because I guess they wrote it down
somewhere.
It means in mine.
I don't understand you.
So when people go down to Cancun and
they go get their freak on from spring
break,
they're there in the,
I don't understand you peninsula for
Ryan.
That's when they went to India.
Then said what?
Where are we in there?
Like Mumbai.
Bombay.
Perfect,
perfect.
Love it.
Where are you?
Beijing.
Peking.
Love it.
Well,
like Greece,
they don't call themselves grease,
right?
Don't they have another name?
Yeah,
Hollis.
There's a couple different countries
like that.
Japan is Nepal.
That's another place where we just shot
grease whole
Lee.
Fuck yeah.
Greece is completely insolvent.
Is that the case?
Well it is.
And,
and you know,
so we just shot the riots in Greece,
France,
Spain,
Italy,
and actually the rise of the neo Nazis
in Germany.
Oh Jesus.
But they're back.
They're back.
Don't call it a comeback.
There's chicken fucking Nazis again in
Germany.
Really?
Germans.
Folks,
come on,
you got the Internet,
you've got four g and mother fuckers
actually.
What's,
what?
Faster Internet than us.
Do they bribe the nos?
Yeah,
no,
no.
This year.
Oh,
we online at all a wipe.
I found out that you probably have dsl
and which is like the worst internet in
the world.
Right?
And uh,
so I put it down to like mobile
bandwidth style.
So like it's such a low a right myself.
But is it working?
Barely.
You're a technological genius.
Well,
he's a bad motherfucker and without him
I'd be lost.
And he has,
he has,
he has a great tee shirts and I won't
want to.
Is a great taste in women.
It's bad motherfucker that Brian Redman.
Um,
yeah.
So do you mean look man,
I love you,
but every time we get together we start
talking to them and gloom.
I fucking Shit my pants and I want to
believe that there is a way out of this.
I want to believe I know is human.
There is,
and I've got to say this,
I've got to say this because it's up to
guys like you guys like me and guys like
everyone listening to this podcast
to say we have the power to.
That's a lot of responsibility.
We have to get high and watch the
hobbit.
However you want to get high.
The hobbit.
However,
I'm going to say this publicly and
online.
I'm Joe Rogan,
who's a famous dude who does UFC and TV
shows and comics,
comic genius and all the stuff.
He does a podcast,
you know,
pays for a fucking studio,
pays for oak tables,
pays for state of the art equipment and
all this stuff to do a podcast to tell
the fucking truth.
And by the way,
that's fucking admirable.
everybody out there who has a camera who
has an iphone who has a fucking youtube
connection,
everyone can do it and everyone should
do it because it's time to start fucking
changing shit because you know what shit
is fucked up.
They are doing.
And that's the beautiful.
That's beautiful.
There's a bunch of people that we've
introduced via this podcast,
like Danieli Bolelli and the guys from
London real who came down to cast and
they,
those guys are really popular now
though.
Their podcasts are popular and it's,
it's instead of you going through this
traditional system of not being about
the value of your contribution,
but rather being about like who's hot
and who's not,
who's it and who's fucking date and who
and all the nonsense that we get roped
up in as primates,
as social primates,
and to instead say the fuck them.
But I would like to say to everyone
who's listening to this Joe Rogan Red
van over there,
just fucking the technological genius.
You guys are doing something that is
purely democratic,
that is incredibly fucking important,
incredibly useful.
It's the reason why every time I come to
La to do this,
because you guys are giving guys like me
and everybody else a fucking platform to
say,
hey,
by the way,
I don't want to be all doom and gloom
what I want to say,
but hold on.
What I want to do is say this shit is
happening.
It's real and people should know about
it and we can do shit about it,
and by the way,
it's not just us.
Here in America.
People in India can do shit about it.
People in Pakistan can do shit about it
and by the way,
youth are fucking pissed off.
They're upset.
The politicians have failed them.
The rich are getting richer,
the poor getting poorer and what we're
trying to do is bring back journalism in
the sense that journalism is saying this
shit is fucked up and we collectively
have to solve it.
Otherwise you have kids.
I have kids,
our kids are gonna be fucked.
Yeah.
I run through these various scenarios in
my head about the future of humanity and
the only thing that gives me hope is the
access to ideas and information that are
available today.
Just for me,
what I know about me with a phone,
I can pretty much answer almost any
question I have about anything in the
world and within a couple of hours of
sitting there and reading shit,
all you need is a goddamn.
You're a guy that doesn't have to do
this.
You don't have to take your time out.
You don't have to pay all this money to
set this up.
How much money?
Well,
okay.
It's fairly reasonable and it's hard and
it's money and it's time of your day and
you're setting up this shit by the way.
More people should be doing it and more
people should be doing shit because
thinking about it that way.
I mean,
the way I think about it is,
first of all,
we were doing it at my house and then we
were doing it.
Brian's place that he set up,
that's quite studios in the ice house.
And uh,
I found out about it,
I was like,
why am I doing my shit in my house?
Like,
let's,
let's take this to the next level.
It's.
So I was inspired by like Brian Putting
together this crazy studio that's using
it for,
you know,
how long have been there,
Brian?
Yeah,
it was a year anniversary month.
Bob Fisher.
You beautiful motherfucker.
You the guy who owns that place is just
such a sweetie.
They're all sweeties.
They're the wages are sweeties,
but everybody's nice.
But look at what you built
out of it.
Now I've got to say everybody out there
should take this as an example because
everybody can do shit.
Yeah.
And by the way,
you're doing shit.
You don't have to do shit.
You're doing shit.
See,
that's where it gets.
That's where I want to sort of
straightened.
I don't think that I.
it's not like I don't have to.
There's no,
there's no motivation to do this other
than joy other than fun other than the
fact that I have.
I love talking to guys like you.
Like how,
how else would I organize a three hour
conversation with you?
And I,
the only way to make it enticing is I
have to fucking broadcast online to get
to meet someone like you.
Like tomorrow we're doing that.
Uh,
John McAfee,
the guy,
the virus guy who is,
you know,
in believes on the run.
We're doing that guy.
I couldn't get to talk to that guy in
real life.
Why would he talk to me?
But you tell more truth here,
right?
Your podcasts,
then Msnbc and Fox put together.
And I've got to say that's the future of
journalism,
that it's,
it's,
it's people,
regular people like you and me who
actually give a shit and who have
actually learned stuff.
And because you go around the world
and UC Shit,
I go around the world and should we see
this stuff?
And we go,
hey,
this is ridiculous.
Yeah,
change is incredibly difficult,
incredibly difficult for people to
change.
It's incredibly difficult for systems of
government or systems monitoring systems
to change.
Change is incredibly hard and resisted
tooth and claw and the people that are
involved in Msnbc and CNN and all these
people that perpetrate all this nonsense
journals and I don't fault them,
I don't because as a guy who's been,
well,
this is my position as a guy who's been
in the system of television before.
I've been on two different TV shows that
was on a sitcom for five years,
and then I was on fear factor for six
years.
I kind of see.
I've got a pretty good view of the whole
system of creating things in the
network.
It's insurmountable.
It either has to collapse or be absorbed
by the Internet.
Those are the only options,
but it as it stands,
is bureaucratic.
There's too many people involved,
too much decision making.
It's not,
it's too different.
It's too expensive and difficult to put
together a fucking Sitcom.
If
you look at your audience and you look
at what you're doing and,
and other people like you are doing,
you have millions and millions of
followers.
And I would say this,
I would say,
look,
you have as many.
And by the way,
more,
um,
you have an audience that's actually
willing to do shit and willing to
participate and then they,
you know,
they tweet and the,
and the facebook and then get on the
socials.
And I would say this is like,
if you look at Fox,
which is an aging at 67,
68,
those people are dying and you're going
to die out.
This is the future.
And what you're doing is you're saying,
I'm going to put my flag in the sand and
I'm going to say,
you know what?
I'm going to have you been in TV.
You've been successful.
You're still on TV,
you're still successful.
You're killing it.
And,
but yet still,
you'll take your time out of your day to
come here and say,
we're going to try.
We're going to do some funny stuff.
We're gonna do some regular stuff.
We're gonna do this and that.
But we're going to try to fucking at
least say,
hey,
this is what's going on with mcafee.
This is what's going on in Pakistan.
This is going on.
Whenever you have me on,
you have other people on.
And I got to say,
look,
that is the future of journalism because
that is the only way today that we're
going to get to the truth.
And I,
look,
I,
I agree with everything you just said.
And the reason why do it is because
people like you are out there.
The reason why I'm so committed to doing
a podcast like this and the reason why
Brian and are committed to keeping them
free is we,
we,
we benefit from it just as much as
everyone else does.
We benefit from it from our own
conversations.
I mean,
Brian and I were just talking about
simulation theory today,
you know,
it's,
and it's because it's brought up by so
many brilliant people in the podcast
that,
you know,
we,
we've had these like freaky discussions
about it.
It's a,
this podcast has been an incredible
fucking thing.
Like I can't ever take.
Not only can I,
I don't feel like I can take any
responsibility for it.
I can't take any accolades for it
because all it is,
is,
it's,
it's really,
um,
just,
uh,
I feel like completely like a conduit.
And I feel like if I can tune into guys
like you or had less trout on last year,
last week,
survivor man,
you know,
and I've had Alex Grey,
the brilliant visionary artists.
If I can get a forum where these people
can talk through the Internet and reach
all these other people like I who else
has that opportunity.
And also you had it,
you would do it if anybody else had
that.
They would do it.
If you're thinking in your right mind
and you had a million people that were
paying attention or whatever the fuck it
is now and you knew some shit,
you'd want to tell people some shit.
But I'm allowed to say it's admirable.
And listen,
that's not nearly as admirable.
We're chilling here in the fucking
valley.
Brian and I are in the air condition
studio.
You're out there and Mumbai to out there
and I'd like to say is life is good,
right?
In our life has been good and we got to
kind of get out of jail free card.
When I got out of college,
I used to say I'm never going to live in
a house as nice as my parents or,
or drive a car is nice to my parents and
gen x generation sort of got to get out
of jail free card,
but Gen y is going to have to pay the
bill and you know,
and,
and so saying,
I think it's our responsibility to say
we know the fucking problems.
We know what's going on.
We know that this is a fucking problem
and we have to go out there and say,
look,
this is a problem.
I don't know the solutions.
Again,
I'm not Jesus on the cross,
but at least people.
And this is why.
This is what gives me hope is that
people fundamentally I believe are good.
And I also believe people are
fundamentally smart and people
fundamentally want to do the right
thing.
Well,
I think people fundamentally want to be
good because love fields better than
hate.
Like if I have a little tiny dispute
in my life,
I don't know about you,
but the way I feel about,
especially if like amongst my circle of
friends or amongst people I do business
with or work with,
if there's any sort of a tiny dispute,
there's a ripple in my force and I don't
like it.
I don't like that feeling and I want to
resolve it is lovingly and as kindly and
as apologetically as I can.
I always feel like that and some people
never get to a position where they
really feel at peace with their place in
the world and how they interact with
other people.
They can't.
Whether it's because they're too in debt
or they're in a fucking terrible
neighborhood or they grew up with a
crazy mother.
Whatever it is.
You took a bad career path,
stuck in a fucking abusive job position.
Whatever the fuck it is that locks you
into your reality,
your existence.
It's very difficult for people that are
in a torturous position to look at
possibilities and options and to look at
the possibility and options that this
might not be the correct way to live
life and that in reality,
my narrow minded view has sent me on
this insurmountable path of ultimate
failure and there's no way to accumulate
enough shit in this life if you're a
temporary being,
there is no way.
So if that is a focus of your existence
to accumulate,
that doesn't mean you shouldn't enjoy
some shit.
Doesn't mean you shouldn't like get a
fucking Samsung Galaxy s three and go
Ooh,
because all that shit's bad ass too.
The,
the,
the reality of like something like when
you,
when you hear people talk about,
I was having a conversation with someone
and they started talking about the law
of attraction.
Oh,
it's the law of attraction.
You bring it into your life.
It's the law of attraction,
like
maybe,
but maybe babies die and drive bys too.
Like what's real?
What's realistic is let's look at this
whole thing,
the reality that we exist in.
Let's look at this whole thing.
It'd be honest about it and say we woke
up in the middle of a dream,
the,
the American,
the whoever the fuck you are with the
Japanese man who 50 years old who wakes
up and his alarm clock goes off today
and looked at this world.
This world woke up in motion,
and the people,
there's too many of them.
First of all,
there's too many of them to ever
communicate that no one can.
No one understands what I fucking
anybody saying.
There's too many different languages.
There's no universal acknowledgement of
our plight and we are headed to doom.
Ultimately.
There's no way if we continue along a
certain path that it doesn't completely
exploded in our face,
whether it's overpopulation or whether
it's pollution or nuclear disaster.
There's a certain amount of stops along
the way until the whole thing ends.
Well,
I think I agree with you and I think
that our generation,
yours and mine has come out of the pond
and we've had a good life and I love.
I love this country because I came down
here and build your country better.
I know I do.
My Shit hits the fan.
I'm moving to Canada for fucking sure.
I don't even care if it's Montreal.
I'll deal with that snow.
I'll take it.
Toronto.
I'll get a snowblower in the warm coat,
but the thing is is you sit there and
you say,
we came out of the pond.
We realized that shit is happening.
Yes,
we want to live a good life.
I want shit to get better.
Precisely because I've had such a good
life and I'm not a doom and gloom guy.
I'm a party guy liked to drink.
I like to travel.
I like to eat.
I like to do stuff.
I like to learn or to go to all these
different places.
The reason why I'm like,
Hey,
hold on.
These guys want to nuke each other or
hold on the world to sinking or hey,
hold on.
This shit's happening.
This is going to fuck everybody up is
because I like my life is because I like
guys like us because I like where we've
gotten to date.
The problem with it is is that you sit
there and you say,
okay,
I don't want the next generation to not
have that,
to not be able to go outside,
swimming the river,
go fishing and do all that stuff and and
bright.
Now we're at,
we're at literally just sort of breaking
point.
We're at that inflection point of,
of we are,
we can fix it,
we can solve it.
We're smart,
we're good.
People want to do it,
and if you follow this,
I'm sure you do.
The people who follow you and,
and,
and if you look at what they say on
twitter and you look at what they say on
facebook,
people are fucking angry and they're
down and they're happy.
He want to do something.
They're not ready.
They're not represented.
And the thing is,
is what's happening,
especially globally,
let alone in this country,
but what's happening globally is that
the people with the power or
disenfranchised because the systems that
are in place are set up as such,
that they can't be represented.
So what this is,
is this is true grassroots democracy.
And by the way,
I hope to God it continues and gets
bigger and bigger,
and I was making a joke earlier,
this is the first podcast from here,
and I'm like,
I'm going to look back 20 years from now
and say this was the first podcast that
changed the world because this is the
root of journalism,
which is the root of democracy.
Well,
I think that the people that are in the
position of power that are doing these
horrible things,
we really need to figure out how to heal
those motherfuckers.
I think we have to figure out how to get
them the fuck out.
You got to get them the fuck out,
but you also get them the fuck out.
We got to discourage that type of
behavior in the future.
I mean,
if you want to be a real hippie and a
total idealist,
you would say that there's gotta be a
way that almost everybody can change and
that these people that are in this
position,
these positions of power that are
looking at things like war and economic
attacks on countries embargoes or all
these different various things that
people do that really can cause
unbelievable irreparable harm to
communities and families and like,
wow,
we need to figure out a way to get those
people to look at things differently and
say,
your motivation is off.
Your motivation is based on many shitty
primate shit.
It's based on some ancient primate shit
while you were running away from Jaguars
and you had to be the most vicious
motherfucker to survive and that stuff
manifests itself today.
Millions of years later in the male
dominance mentality and that mentality
is not best suited for attacks against
your fellow man and it can be conquered.
It can be conquered.
It can be understood.
It can be understood in your mindset.
You will be happier person if you do not
behave in that manner and you won't be
any happier if you get more money.
There's a certain amount of money where
it doesn't matter.
Well,
I have.
I've got to say also that if you look at
it and say I want real people.
I want people like me who have had a
drink too many,
who've done a few drugs who've done
that,
who've had a real life.
If you have,
you know,
guys like,
you know Romney who's like squeaky clean
and whatever.
I'm like,
I don't want a robot representing me.
Yes,
because I'm not a robot.
I'm flawed and fucked up and I've been
through crazy.
Well see,
but the whole thing is,
is I want someone who's human.
Well,
he's,
I want someone who's been through shit
and who spoke fucking dope when he was
fucking nine years old and someone who's
emerged.
I want someone who knows what the fuck
is going on.
Romney could be saved with mushrooms,
mushrooms,
and tie hookers and just get Romney on a
fucking island and just give him some
mushrooms and let them understand that
this is,
this is a fucking dream,
man.
This is one frame and an infinite movie
that goes on forever and the only
control that you have whatsoever is to
enjoy it,
to increase harmony,
to spread the love to use as you were
talking about,
you know,
talking to she emails or talking to
Taliban or talking to this or that.
The thing is is if you just talk to
these motherfuckers,
everybody has a point.
Everyone has a point of view.
Everyone has appointed and if you
actually say,
look,
you know,
by the way,
for example,
when I was in Pakistan,
they were like,
we are Super Mad that you let the
innocence of Muslims come out like
America,
you know,
sponsored that,
whatever.
And you're like that video you're
talking about and you said you
understand that there's millions upon
millions of videos uploaded every day,
every fucking day on Youtube.
There's no government regulation.
There's no,
you know,
Obama's not sitting there going,
ha ha,
we really got them now and they could
not believe that they were just like,
no,
you guys have done this thing and that's
why we're shooting.
There were people killed and there's
been no violence because of this.
And now there's a whole,
uh,
you know,
because a lot of the people that are
literate that your mom say,
well,
America is doing this and this is part
of their policy whenever,
and you're like,
this was just a bunch of fruitcakes who
did the fucking thing and all of a
sudden now people are dying and there's,
you know,
home militias being mobilized because of
this and that point.
You're like,
if people just actually fucking,
which I do,
I say,
look,
I'm going to tell you I lived there.
I do this.
I have two of the most popular channels
on Youtube.
People just upload shit.
It just fucking happens.
It's not like government policy.
It's not propaganda.
It's not this,
it's not that they don't fucking get it.
And if you just actually just said,
look dude,
here's the way it is.
Here's the reality of the situation,
which no buddy does.
That's the whole fucked up thing is
nobody sits there and says,
this is actually what happens.
This is the truth.
Well,
you're not saying you're incorrect.
It's not,
it's you,
you do it.
Your motherfucker.
Y'All fucking channel does it.
What are you talking about?
It's,
there's guys like you,
there's this,
there's the congressmen that are coming
up like Daniel Seaman,
the congressional representative,
or a candidate rather who is completely
honest and well read.
And the young,
there's a,
there's a whole group of people that are
coming up now.
There's a bunch of people that are
broadcasting,
whether it's the young Turks or whether
it's,
uh,
you know,
any,
a number,
you know,
and Alex Jones to a large extent,
a lot of what Alex Jones says,
although absolutely ridiculed in the 19
nineties,
shows to be true in 2012.
I've been Alex's friend for a long
fucking time and a lot of people think
he's crazy and he's fucking crazy.
That's why they think he's crazy.
But he's crazy in a beautiful way.
And he's right a lot of the time.
And that's sort of,
that's sort of understood now and
there's enough information now that
people have their head collectively
cocked sideways.
I think the whole United States is like,
wait a minute,
there's something I tweeted yesterday
that someone tweeted me and I've read
tweeted it was 33 different conspiracy
theories that turned out to be correct.
And when you go and look at them and you
go,
oh,
okay,
this is just.
This is sort of how it's always been.
So what we have to do is figuring out
how to get these people that are
thinking this way and this crazy
position of power where they,
whatever group,
however many agree to do something
totally a moral and for profit.
I guess that's really the only real
reason.
Whenever it comes down to it,
we have to figure out how to reach
people like that and to let them know
that this is a false pattern.
Your mind is locked in some nonsensical
thinking that is based on the predatory
instincts of animals that had to survive
from fucking cougars and Jaguars and
bears and shit.
There was a ruthlessness that's designed
into the DNA to make sure that the
animal procreates and that can be
overcome and that we have to understand
that the only,
the only way to true happiness is to
look at each other collectively as if
it's us living another life and you look
at every person you meet because if it's
you living with,
but also just to,
to,
to.
I agree with you 100 percent because it
sounds like hippie.
No,
no,
but,
but you look at you and you say,
look,
here's a guy,
you know,
ufc came up,
taekwondo,
Chevy's,
you're fighting guy.
You know all this stuff.
Obviously we're two guys here sitting
here.
We're not hippies.
But what we're coming to is,
is saying,
look,
we came up,
we came up hard,
we fought,
we did all this stuff and now we're
realizing this shit.
And we're saying,
hey,
you know,
we've seen this.
We've learned from.
This is why to go back to it is I don't
want politicians representing me who
don't understand this.
Yeah.
Which is I came up hard.
I came up from the streets.
I learned this shit,
I learned that the hard way by going to
these places and what I've realized is
exactly what you said,
which is unless we've overcome our base
desire,
which is I hate you,
I'm going to fucking bomb you.
We're all dead.
We're all dead because now it's not a
knife.
It's not a gun.
It's not an RPG.
It's not a tank.
It's a new kid or fucking warhead.
And when we start fucking trying to
fucking be alpha male with a nuclear
warhead like Achy Yukon,
then we're fucking.
Where's that guy is?
He's still alive.
He's in Pakistan Christ.
And he's the reason why there's the
proliferation of nuclear fucking.
Does he have technology?
20 bitches around him just dancing in
their underwear at all times.
Do you think so,
but no.
Be a fucking man with it.
At least if you've got to be at concord,
be a fucking old school cafe.
He has a bunch of Isi guys around him at
all times because those guys,
those guys.
So the ISI is the CIA of Pakistan and
they started the Taliban and they are
the guys who are basically running
Pakistan and they are the guys who were
becoming increasingly radicalized and
they're the guys who were saying,
we are going to bomb India,
needed to get those people on mushrooms.
What we need to do is just say,
you're not allowed.
You're not allowed to blow up the world.
You cannot do it.
And by the way,
if we had politicians who were doing the
right thing,
you would go to India,
go to Pakistan and say you're not
allowed.
Which means that we have to say Russia
is not allowed.
We're not allowed.
Nobody's allowed.
Because again,
to go back to it,
if you're playing roulette and double
zero means the end of the fucking world,
you shouldn't be playing fucking relax.
And so take that double zero off the
fucking
board police.
If you're playing Russian roulette,
you have five chances to not get shot in
the head when you're playing world
dominance.
It's like how many opportunities you
have to start a nuclear war.
Exactly.
It's really not a question,
not a question of,
of when,
if it's a question of when.
Yeah,
there's not a whole lot of chambers.
It's the whole thing is fucking
ridiculous because it's people locked up
in this idea that somehow or another
conquering makes things better and then
somehow under the controlling the
resources makes things better.
And this,
this all these observations now from
people that are,
uh,
paying attention to what's going on in
Afghanistan about minerals,
minerals,
and how long they've known that
Afghanistan is.
It's an incredible deposit and mineral
minerals from Congo.
Yeah.
What's happening?
What's happening now in the Congo is 100
percent due to Colton.
They wouldn't be fighting.
They wouldn't have all the money,
they wouldn't have tram Colton,
Colton.
Colton is a,
is a rarer thing wrong that makes all
your iphone,
your Samsung,
your ipad.
They all need Colton,
uh,
to actually work.
And the majority of Colton actually is
in Congo.
And so what's happened now is this
continual warfare,
um,
you know,
and it's,
I believe now the sixth bloodiest war in
the history of humanity is all happening
because of ipads,
iphones,
samsungs,
all these things.
We're buying them.
This is the whole thing were
disconnected.
I mean,
I grew up thinking,
well,
whatever happens in Africa,
in Africa,
and that's their problem,
not my problem.
Then you realize,
oh,
that fucking war is happening because I
have an iphone five.
I mean,
that's the reality of the situation.
It's sort of analogous to the human
experience.
If you really,
boy,
that sounds gay,
hippie and gay at the same time.
So we're really having a love fest to
pick up a confused dude
in the new,
in the new
studio,
the human.
If you look at the human experience and
you look at where we're at right now at
the highest levels and let's perceive at
the highest levels are innovation and
technology.
And that the fact that we can broadcast
this with minimal cost,
even though it's kind of sucking right
now,
powerful att and t the.
Why'd you get DSL?
I don't know,
man.
I had a fucking.
Who did this manager handle this shit.
Oh,
does this business manager?
Uh,
I dunno.
I never met him.
Listen to it.
You need a young kid do that shit.
I got shit I need to deal with.
This is not one of them.
You've thrown me off.
Where was I?
Minerals.
Everything Metro's earlier.
Whatever.
What's the.
Is it important that I finished my
sentence?
I have nothing to say.
Ladies and gentlemen of grandstanding.
Clearly I'm trying to somehow or another
project project better ideas through
whiskey.
Three whiskey and marijuana allegedly
allegedly don't think it's necessarily a
bad thing.
Folks.
Sounded like Colin Quinn there.
You've got to irrigate.
Yeah,
irrigate the mine.
Yeah.
That's important.
People don't drink.
I've never been drunk.
I don't really like you.
Nor do I trust you.
Okay.
I'm going to be honest.
I trust drunks.
I even trust dry drunks.
I trust her.
Just saying that because I'm here.
Nope.
No,
I'm just being honest.
I,
uh,
I appreciate sober people.
Don't get me wrong,
but if you have not a least experienced
whiskey with all the people raving about
it,
would you not dive in the water so at
least once?
How stubborn are you?
You've never had a drop of alcohol.
Who are you partying with?
Man,
that's ridiculous.
If your friends have kept you from a
drop of alcohol,
they're assholes.
It's usually people that have had too
many drops of alcohol.
It seems like everyone I know is in a
hour.
Well,
you know what?
The issue is slightly biological and
that's something that I'm willing to
admit 100 percent because I have friends
that I trust dearly,
like Fitzsimmons.
Greg Fitzsimmons is greg and I have been
friends since we were in our early
twenties.
I think we met when I was 21 and Greg
was probably the same age greg has
always had.
He's.
He's a legit alcoholic and it's in the
sense of he could have a drink today and
he could be fine,
but there will be a pole,
a biological pool that's reinforced by
his relatives.
It's reinforced by generations and I
have many friends that have this issue
and I do not discount it.
My friend Tate Fletcher,
he's a brilliant guy and tate has a
problem with substances.
He cannot,
you know,
he's like,
I go,
could you even like take a look,
a baby hit of a joint?
He goes,
maybe or I could wake up in an alleyway
naked and not know what the fuck
happened and I'm not willing to make
that jump.
I'm not willing to take that chance.
There's biological weirdness.
People fucking get.
They die from peanuts.
Okay.
A person can be allergic to peanuts and
die.
I would never discount that,
but I think that generally speaking,
there's a mentality of non chance taking
boring bullshit that comes with the.
I've never had a drink.
People.
There's a few examples that are
contrary,
like Penn Jillette has never had a drop
of alcohol and the only time he's ever
had any sort of medication.
There's been injured after surgery,
like a,
some sort of a painkiller,
but he's a brilliant guy and I love
talking to him.
He's one of the rare examples.
Most people that have never even been
fucked up,
you never.
You never tried to get laid when it was
preposterous.
You've never tried to pick up a girl
with.
There's no way medically you can get an
erection if you've never been 21 years
old and thrown up in the backseat of a
cab.
Who are you?
Who are you and who do you party with?
But I also think that it's,
again,
to go back to the people we're talking
to is it's a way to sort of distance
yourself from all the norms and to say,
I'm going to question what the fuck's
going on.
I think and maybe some conspiracy
theories are not true and maybe some
aren't true,
but at least we have to question them.
Oh,
for sure.
There's a lot that aren't true,
but for sure there's not,
but we have to question them.
Yes.
And that's the whole thing.
We have to question shit.
That's our.
That's what we are as humans.
We have to fucking shit.
And we also have to say,
how do we get better?
It's a funny thing to say,
but I'm not endorsing alcohol
consumption,
but there's a certain humility that
comes from being an drunk.
Will you step back and kind of,
you know,
you just realize like,
look,
this is all fun.
You know,
like Tony Bourdain,
you know Anthony Bourdain,
I've had the pleasure of having on the
podcast.
He said,
Guy,
just like you,
a regular dude,
you talk to them,
but there's a certain like having a
drink with you,
having a drink with him,
having a drink with anyone who's just a
real guy.
Anyone who's where,
where there's a moment that comes when
you've had a couple of drinks.
When you look at each other.
Yeah,
we're fucked up.
Who knows?
It's crazy,
but he's a perfect example of a dude.
Yeah.
I had a cooking show on the travel
channel.
Well before that,
he's a chef.
He was a chef.
Wrote a book,
but the book,
it's told truth,
but what the hell happens in
restaurants.
Exactly.
But he had it.
He had a cooking show on the travel
channel,
nothing in nothing,
and he turned it into a political
statement and he turned it into trying
to tell the truth and he turned it into
we're going to eat some food,
but what the fuck is really going on
with real people?
Yes,
and I think again,
there's a lot.
There's a whole movement.
There's you,
there's him,
there's me,
there's,
but there's like $100,
million.
There's millions of this now because of
technology and I think that you know him
and I believe he built the travel
channel on his.
What about Bert Kreischer?
How do you feel about Bert?
Bert?
Bert Dot com.
Just to finish with,
with Anthony Bourdain.
I would say that that guy,
that guy went out into the world and,
and talked about shit that you should
talk about on a channel that would never
talk about that shit otherwise.
And a channel by the way.
That's very conservative on by script.
Yeah.
Which is the server scripts.
Scripts.
Yeah.
So travel channels on prescriptions,
pps.
It's a very Christian fundamentalist and
he takes a lot of heat and he gets a lot
of shit and they tell them not to do
stuff and he says,
fuck you,
I'm going to do it anyway because he
wants to fucking tell the truth and I
got to give it up to him.
He has a lot of fun
in their defense and their defense.
I do understand that the travel channel
has started to try to reevaluate their
position and maybe reach out because I
heard they're interested in Arusha fear
because some of their executive saw him
kill at the dcm product and so they
just.
But bordain ordain me like,
look,
he opened the door.
Oh No.
DRIPS is super,
super conservative.
Super Christian.
Their poster child is a dude who goes
out in the world and says,
you will eat some food.
We'll cook some shit,
but I'm going to tell you the fucking
truth about what's going on.
What he did.
He.
He said,
I'm going to show you some cool shit.
I'm going to show you some cool music.
I'm going to show you should cool bands
and I'm going to talk about and people
are going to talk about what's really
going on
and people are going to go,
by the way,
watch the travel channel.
Okay.
I Bert Kreischer,
I love him to death.
I would totally watch any show that
he's on,
but I never watch the travel channel
before.
Anthony Bourdain was never.
I never even thought about watching it.
I don't know how I even tuned into his
show.
I suspected I was just channel surfing.
Yeah,
I was just flipping through channels and
all the sudden there's this guy's
talking about Vietnam and how much he
loves Vietnam.
And I remember going,
who is this crazy fuck my barrier and
camels and he's loving it.
And,
but most importantly,
he approaches the whole thing with this,
this really palpable feeling of humility
and honesty and you know,
pie drunkenness on occasion and it's,
uh,
it's,
it's not just admirable.
It's enticing,
it's attractive.
It pulls me,
you know,
it's like your shows all of your shows,
man.
I found out about vice because of the,
uh,
the Heinemann x a episode.
The guy who lives in the Arctic,
where does he live in northeast Alaska
or something like that.
He lives in the most remote part of the,
of the world.
He's the,
he lives.
He's the most remote human being in the
world.
There's um,
uh,
I have a message board on my website and
the message board is before twitter,
it's been around since like 1998.
My,
my friend Andrew started the message
board and it's been this incredible like
magnet for fucking Weirdos and a lot of
cool people.
But what's,
what's been really fascinating that
twitter is sort of surpassed it in a way
just because of the sheer access.
But what my message board became was
just this strange area where cool shit
would be drawn to.
So they would post these things,
these threads about shit you would never
find out on your own.
Just the average person is not connected
to community.
You're never gonna find it.
What do you,
why would you even look at [inaudible]
Dot com?
Why would you,
what would you be googling that would
connect you to a series?
Someone put up this,
uh,
this link to this video and I watched
this guy that's got frozen caribou
hanging from a fucking tree and he saw
them and cooking them and your guys that
were there,
which is blown away by the experience of
hanging out with this dude lives in a
100 foot square shack in the fucking
most hostile environment,
known demand and to see that he was not
only was he not a loon but that he was,
there was no narration.
The narration was just sort of
describing how they got there and what
was going on,
but it was never.
It was never any judgment on people or
the scenario and w w what I found really
fascinating about it,
I was like,
you got to know a guy with all the.
And Hind mole has lived here for 65
years.
He used content wondering the frozen
countryside,
hoping to spot a Caribou.
Is He happy?
Only high mode truly knows you didn't do
that.
You,
you,
you instead inserted intelligent people
into a alternative sort of a situation.
This sounds like a Bologna.
No Bro.
Fucking watch this one live is,
it's because we practice it.
A type of journalism called immersion
isn't where we go.
We immerse ourselves in the actual story
and we just pressed record.
You guys changed this podcast?
No,
I want you to know that for sure.
One hundred percent that,
that episode and the subsequent episodes
that I watched all the devil you guys
changed because I was like,
this guy is a fucking.
You're in,
you're there,
you're actually there.
You know you're really going to write.
When I was making fun of kissing
someone's Dick,
but I will say talking about twitter is
after I do this podcast,
you get so much response from people who
give a shit and people who are saying
this shit like the truth and it blew my
mind and this and that,
and you realize like,
you know,
we're guys just,
talking about shit and whatever and
they're going,
this is.
I learned more on that podcast and Fox
and MSNBC and CNN and everybody all put
together and that's the tragedy.
It's,
it's great.
For us,
it's the tragedy because we're just
regular dudes going,
okay,
this is what the fuck is happening.
Don't think it's a tragedy,
man.
I think it's the the,
the normal chain of progression and I
think it's a natural.
It's a natural system and I think that
you don't get to be you unless you've
seen burt reynolds get a crazy facelift,
right?
You don't get to be you until you've
seen all the most preposterous shit that
people have done.
You don't get to be you until you read
all the crazy accounts of nonsensical
violence on the Internet,
either the crazy revolutions in Arab
spring and all over the world and all
the things you physically experienced by
actually being in these places where
there are chaotic events that are just
uncontrollable by the population
out of,
but it doesn't mean anything unless
people watch.
It doesn't mean anything unless there's
an audience.
It doesn't.
The you're compelled like you,
you,
you can't even take credit for what
you're doing because you're compelled.
You're compelled by the natural order of
the universe.
The natural order of the universe is to
move in and in a progressive direction
and the more understanding and more
comprehensive and lightened direction.
That's all of our ideas.
The idea is not to maintain the science
of the 17 hundreds.
The idea is to figure out how to,
you know,
how to get on Mars and create an
atmosphere so we can have a new plan in
case someone gets hit by an asteroid.
The ideas that are consistently move
forward and I think we're just caught in
the struggle of that happening and my
real hope for,
for the world.
Like I,
I,
you know,
all that shit about a gi.
The people that believe that you can
manifest reality.
They know the secret and the idea that
you know your own mind and the more you
focus on things,
maybe maybe,
maybe it's just the fact that you're not
paying attention to what you could do
positively.
And that's what impacts the world.
And positively.
What we've got to figure out how to do
is to change the mindset of all the
people and the people that are in
positions of power instead of fighting
them and attacking them and try to
understand the fact that the human
animal is incorrect,
doubly frustrated.
We don't know what's going on.
We have these fucking bodies that are
exactly the same as pre internet pre
movies,
Prix cars and planes and it's all
happened so quickly all around us that
we haven't had the chance to really as
as a,
as a super organism,
taken all of the knowledge and
distribute it in a way that w,
w,
w where we we govern over the
consciousness of the population in a
fair and ethical way.
That keeps everybody happy,
but I think ultimately that that is a
possible scenario for sure.
It has to be.
Has to be.
If we don't believe that,
then we're really fucked.
I don't think,
because I was saying doom and gloom.
I don't think this is doom and gloom.
I think this is positive because as long
as we know what the fuck is going on,
we can work towards doing something
about it.
The problem is is we didn't know what
the fuck was going on because nobody
fucking told.
That's a perfect way of describing it.
That's a perfectly describing it.
The real problem is that we were living
in some crazy movie.
We since the 19 fifties,
we have been locked into some sort of
crazy version of the world that is in
many ways based on fiction and the real
issue is whether the war of the worlds,
even when the war of the worlds.
You've got to Piss.
No,
you got to go.
no.
What are you doing in your head?
I'm going to go and get a drink of it.
I didn't want you to say that.
The war of the worlds freaked fucking
people out.
If you don't know what it is,
Orson Welles in like,
who knows when the fuck it was.
Alex wants to get out of here,
but it's not happening.
Bitch.
Take a seat.
Don't worry about your previous
commitments.
They're not as interesting.
The war,
the war of the worlds was the first time
where human beings were able to be
tricked into thinking by Orson Welles
that there was an attack by alien beings
like people freaked out and it's really
difficult to discern how much of it as
bullshit,
how I,
how much of it actually happened because
they say there were suicides.
Who knows what the actual statistics,
where you know,
we're talking about the 19 thirties or
whatever the fuck it was,
but the reality which is that human
beings were not prepared for
the information that was coming at them.
They were in prepared.
That wasn't an,
that wasn't a regular part of their life
where they had grown accustomed to
having this fakery planted on them.
It's not like today with the onion,
you know,
like every now and then I'll retweet an
article and it turns out to be like some
new fake onion,
like some,
a bunch of dudes who like think that the
onion is cool.
So they create their own bullshit news
story.
Those motherfuckers and your retweet
them.
But that's to be expected that the,
the,
the people that existed before the
internet or before,
those are the people that sort of set
this scenario.
They set the momentum of our culture and
they did not have access this shit.
We have now.
The idea that we're so hung up on the
brilliant wisdom of some people that
lived in the 17 hundreds and created the
declaration of independence,
which by the way,
it was written on fucking hemp.
The first drafts that the fact that
we're committed to the ideology,
these people that lived,
they didn't have
car cars or 2000 years ago.
That's when religion started.
And ever since then,
everything else is a cult.
But 2000 years ago,
that's when we knew what the fuck was
going on.
Well,
I've got to juggle my act about Romney,
that it's a cult when you know who wrote
it,
because we can.
It's not like we have to go back to some
fucking shit they found in Qumran that
was written on animal skins.
You know,
this is like we know the guy,
he was,
his name is Joseph Smith and he was only
14.
I mean this is not that confusing like
you're a fucking cult man,
but he found the book of Latter Day
saints in his backyard.
But you know,
what's beautiful about the Mormon
culture is that what I've learned from
my personal experiences is that there
are certain people in this life and
although I don't
feel it's justified to lie to people,
there's certain people who do get by
better if they follow like at least a
scaffolding of morality.
Sure.
Some sort of something that lets them
believe that at the very top there's a
Cherry and that cherries God and he's
right up there on top of the whipped
cream and you just got to get.
I think that's the problem is that if
you look at this,
we were talking about global warming
earlier and you say,
okay,
yeah,
Shit's fucked up.
The world is thinking we're not going to
believe in that because of God.
And you're like,
yeah,
but you're going to die and your kids
are going to die and it's going to be
bad if we don't just say,
this is the thing that is bad that's
happening in a sense.
No,
because it's gotten whatever and they
want.
And I think it's this yearning to have.
There's a rational being who has a plan
for all of us.
Well,
the fact of the matter is is we are
creating our reality and we are not a
rational entity.
Humanity isn't rational.
Humanity is irrational and complex and
fucked up and weird.
But at some point somebody has got to
come up and say,
yeah,
rational and where we given.
But there are certain things that we do
which are self destructive.
And by the way,
they have to stop.
For example,
if you have the ability to destroy the
fucking world,
which is my world,
you're destroying my world,
right?
And you're halfway across the world over
there.
If that's even a possibility that no is
the answer,
no,
I'm not going to let that happen.
So that's why I keep preaching on this
stuff.
Because when I went there and I said,
Bill Clinton said it's the end of the
world by the way.
And I went,
yeah.
And so when he left the presidency,
he said,
that is the reason why cargo was more
between India and Pakistan was the
glimpse of the end of the world.
And then he got his dick sucked by young
and old.
So
that's why it takes blows house of
interns.
So why not at least enjoy that sweet
release,
eat,
drink,
and be merry phase,
eat,
drink,
and be merry.
The problem with that is,
is when we went back,
we realized,
oh,
it's fucking way worse than when he said
it was the end of the world.
So hold on,
hold on.
The whole thing is,
is though,
is we can stop it.
We can say fuck it.
Fuck it.
We can't just,
we just have to say there is,
there can be no,
uh,
you know,
intercontinental ballistic or nuclear
warheads.
There can be no,
because what you're saying,
just so everybody understands what
you're saying then is as long as that
technology is there,
it will go to Iran.
It will go to Pakistan,
it will go to Congo,
it will go to Libya,
it will go because the technology is
there.
Right?
And what happens when Kadafi now could
fee is gone,
but what happens when Kadafi has
warheads?
What happens when a que con has
What happens when,
when Iran has words,
when Israel attacks Iran,
because it can have a nuclear around
what's going to happen,
what will happen when they attacked
around?
Everybody knows.
Everybody knows what will happen when
they attack rent and it's going to be a
fucking catastrophe.
However,
it's nothing zero compared to what's
happening in India,
Pakistan,
Israel and Palestine is like,
you know like I guess when you're like
20,
21 and you have that one couple that
just won't fucking break up and they
keep fighting and they keep asking you
for advice.
What do you think I should tell her,
bro?
What do you think?
There's tiller and I'm like,
I think you should fucking run.
I know there's people now.
Well yeah,
there's a lot of them that use that as a
distraction,
right?
Don't they don't.
They aren't all conflicts ultimately
some form of distraction because if,
if the Israelis looked at the
Palestinians that are suffering and
these poor people that are trying to
make
this sort of
home for themselves in this Gaza region
is very dangerous and hostile region.
What if they treated them all as
Israelis?
What if they treated them all as just
fellow humans would if instead of
lumping them into groups based on
ideology and who believes what old crazy
shit,
what if they just looked at him as
things that could be cousins that I mean
that would instantly changed the whole
thing.
The idea that we need to exist in a
conflict scenario.
Is that the problem?
That's the real issue.
I don't agree with that.
I have a neighbor,
I don't even know this motherfucker and
he wanted me to chop down my trees,
but he's still nice.
I say hi to him when I drive by.
I had a convert.
The only conversation I've ever had with
this guy was a conflict,
but I don't hate the dude.
You know?
I want them to be happy.
Just don't be crazy.
Let me alone your mother fucker.
I'll give you a hug.
Come here,
give me a what are you nuts,
you know,
come on,
let's go have a drink.
You know,
that's what we should treat.
The whole world can approach other human
beings like that.
It's just we have to get past this
ingrained scenario that we have in our
head,
which is that war is a part of nature
and nature is unsurmountable.
It's,
it is what it is.
You got to accept,
man,
they're gonna want to be philanders and
you know there's going to be conquest
and swords and fucking rocket.
Yeah,
but if you go,
if you go to Mexico and you see what's
happening there,
now it's the rule of the thug.
If you go to Pakistan as the rule of the
thought,
if you go to Congo,
it's the fuck.
Why?
Because conflict breeds lowest common
denominator.
It breeds I have a gun and I'm willing
to shoot it.
Right?
And whoever that,
those aren't high thinking people.
Those aren't people thinking we're going
to save the world.
Those aren't people thinking,
you know,
the world is thinking.
Those aren't people thinking we could,
you know,
destroy the environment by,
by having a new kid or standup.
What they're thinking is,
I'm going to gain power because I have a
bunch of guys,
you know,
young guys,
you generally young men with guns.
If you look at what's happening in
Europe right now,
this is what's terrifying is you go to
Spain and you say Spain,
you know,
old country educated country,
country.
Fifty percent of young people are
unemployed,
so you've taken away their future.
We were just shooting.
Their 6 million people came out and
fucking shut the whole country.
Then that's people who are pissed off,
really pissed off.
While you were filming there,
what happened?
Riots,
what,
what would they have?
Well,
there about us anti-austerity.
So it's,
it's young people saying we're fucked,
but I mean there's riots in Paris and
how sturdy means.
What does that mean?
So,
you know,
Spain is fucked economically,
economically.
What's happening there?
This is what's really terrifying is that
in,
in so prolonged economic crisis.
So the recession.
Now,
the last time this happened was the
depression.
Now what happened?
Because of the depression was the rise
of radical political solutions.
I eat communism or fascism.
So now what's happened is you have the
rise of the Communist Party in,
in,
in Greece,
and to counteract that,
you have the golden dawn,
which are full on fascists,
who now are,
are,
you know,
14 percent of the government.
Did you say the Golden Dawn?
Golden Dawn are?
Yeah.
That's what I heard.
The Golden Dawn.
They have.
They do this.
Say the golden dawn will pretend because
it's ridiculous.
Whatever.
Golden Dawn.
Yeah.
Okay.
They do the.
They do the Nazi salute.
They had the swastika
saying,
imagine if they had a big fucking thing.
Other shirt was a big golden day.
Frothy dogs.
Would it be,
would it be hard or would that be
offensive for a military would have to
be like,
well,
they have the support of the military
and the police and everywhere we went
was anti immigration,
anti EU,
anti this.
After that,
and what's happening in Europe.
This is what's terrifying is because you
have an economic crisis,
you have the rise of communist and
fascist.
So for example,
in France you have a very far left
government and the second party is from
national fascist and you sit there and
you say,
okay,
the exact same political situation
exactly.
That started World War Two is happening
today in Europe,
not fucking Africa,
not Pakistan,
not India,
Europe,
and it's happening in Germany.
It's happening in Scandinavia,
it's happening in Spain and happening in
Italy.
It's happening in Greece,
it's happening in all these countries
and you sit there and everyone just
watching as exactly the same fucking
thing that started World War II to the
t,
to the fucking teeth,
riots in the streets,
ultra right?
Ultra left wing parties fighting each
other,
radical parties getting more and more
power.
And you're just saying,
what the fuck do we have to do to.
We have to relive it again.
It's exactly the same thing that started
world,
a natural cycle of humanity.
I mean,
if you look at societies,
you can look at cultures and you look at
this rise and fall.
When you go to the Acropolis and you see
the ancient Greek ruins and you wonder
how the fuck why?
Why are these regular houses like really
close to this incredible structure?
What happened is this,
is this inevitable?
Do are we in this constant state of
developing consciousness and one of the
big wrestling matches of trying to sort
of innovate and accomplish higher levels
of,
of society and culture is that you,
you have to meet some sort of opposition
and if you don't meet opposition,
you won't have the motivation to really
accelerate things as fast as the
technology around you is accelerating
and completely get out of hand like it
is right now.
It is right now with with dictators and
crazy fucks controlling nuclear weapons
almost.
It's almost like those things have to be
in place in order to motivate the
highest levels of thinking.
You know the,
the,
the cliche is those who don't understand
history are doomed to repeat it.
What's interesting is when you go talk
to young people in Europe and you say,
understand that this is exactly the same
thing that happened at the start of
world war two.
They were like,
don't you know,
they don't know what you're talking
about and they don't understand history.
The other thing is they don't understand
war and if you ever go look at war,
and this is where I was talking about
with the rack is war isn't the manly,
you know,
I got my shoulder nicked by a,
by a bullet or you know,
I come back with a purple heart or is a
catheter bag.
War is I don't walk again,
war is I'm irradiated.
War is I'm fucked up in the brain for
the rest of my life.
And those who don't understand war are
doomed to repeat it.
And by the way,
you know,
hawks and people who say,
let's go to war,
go to war,
go see a war zone.
It's fucking tragic.
It's tragic from start to fucking finish
its babies with no fucking fathers.
It's every man fucking killed.
It's rape.
It's,
you know,
in some cases in Africa cannibalism,
it's,
it's literally the lowest form of what
we are as humanity and people who say,
let's go to fucking war,
let's go to war.
Let's go to.
You should fucking realize that before
you go to war,
young dudes,
you know that we know are going to come
back and their dick isn't going to work
again.
The fucking shit.
Right.
Again.
All this stuff and you go,
okay,
that's what these people are proposing
in Europe,
in India,
in Pakistan,
in Africa,
in Southeast Asia,
in some cases in South America and in
some cases here,
that's what people are proposing.
You're like,
what the fuck?
I would just like to take anyone who
wants to say,
let's go to war.
I'd like to take them to a war zone
because if you take people to a war
zone,
first you puke,
then you cry and then you freaked the
fuck up.
People,
do you think in positions of power
actually go to war zones?
None.
Wow.
And the what are some must.
I mean
you see photos you don't,
but you don't see what it really does.
So you don't see the reason why.
The reason why I do what I do is because
I've been to war zones and I've seen
shit that makes your stomach turn and
you'll never sleep right again,
because when you see what war really
fucking doesn't talk to marines and
talked to rangers and talked to guys who
come back from war,
talk to them before they go and then
talk to them when they come back.
It's a completely different fucking
conversation I have
and it's very similar to people that I
know that had been to jail.
There's A.
I have a friend.
We were friends when I was a teenager
and he was always crazy and he just
vanished.
We didn't know what happened because I
just knew him from the martial arts gym
that I trained at,
but he came back three years later with
all these crazy scars all over his body.
He had been a prison and he was a
completely different human being.
It was like before he was as lovable
troublemaker and three years later the
lovable troublemaker was gone.
There was a psycho.
There was a guy who had.
He would fight for survival.
He was a wild animal.
You won't come back normal.
You won't come back.
No,
I know.
I've met friends that have gone to war
to.
I've,
I've had quite a few friends that were
in the military and went over and came
back including a buddy of mine who went
over as a mercenary.
Yeah.
You know,
and it's a,
it's a weird conversation when you're
alone,
you know,
sitting down on the curb somewhere.
Go on.
So.
So would you have to do.
What was it like what would you,
you know,
how much they pay you?
Do you want to do it again?
You're done.
I'm done.
Are you sure?
Like what the fuck?
There's,
there's realities in this world that I
think most people in their day to day
existence do not consider as a part of
the equation.
And those realities are real problem.
The real problem for our culture because
not only are they disgusting but they're
unknown.
They're avoidable there.
Most of them are avoidable.
We have a distorted perception of what
can be done with the resources that we
have in place.
And I think that the sort of perception
is based on greed.
Yeah,
when you see war and the aftermath of
war,
which is again to describe it,
I'm not even going to do it justice,
but it milky eyes from chemical weapons.
People with their limbs hacked off a
systematically,
um,
you know,
women who have been raped,
uh,
you know,
50,
70,
one,
hundred times,
you know,
incredibly scarred people.
And by the way,
if you go over,
especially if you go over from our
culture,
spend three years in that culture and
look,
it's chronicle after World War Two,
after Vietnam,
after Afghanistan,
after Iraq,
and you go to these things,
you will never be normal again.
You will never other mentally or
physically you will never be normal
again.
So why do we still fucking rattle our
sabers?
Why do we still say we're gonna fight?
Why do we still say we're going to fuck
each other up?
And the thing is,
is if you look at it and you say,
okay,
why the fuck did we go to Iraq?
Why the fuck were we there?
All these fucking guys,
all these marines,
all these army guys who come back fucked
up.
Why did you come back?
Why did you come back so fucked up and
you're never going to be normal again.
Why?
Why was it al Qaeda?
Was it nine slash 11?
No.
Jesus Christ.
Shane Smith.
You motherfucking Downer.
I was going to go home tonight and maybe
watch a little boardwalk empire.
Reminisce about how fucked up people
were in the past.
Have.
That's your network
by the way.
We're doing a new show and the other
thing is I will say this next year we're
launching a news channel in 18
countries.
18 languages.
Twenty four hours news around the world.
Why?
Because news is so fucked that we're
going to do at news on her own.
Fuck it.
Fuck you.
Fuck everybody.
We're going to do it on our own way.
A lot of fucks buddy
is out there.
I don't know if that's good Karma,
Brian.
It's not.
Brian says it's got to be careful with
what you project
and by the way,
I'm gonna have to go now because we're
launching news channel
and we're going to go do the deal right
now and I wanted to come here before we
did that because this is what I enjoy
doing.
Shane Smith,
you sir are a bad motherfucker.
Thank you very much.
It's been an honor once again to have
you on the show.
You,
uh,
you,
honestly,
you've changed this show for that first.
Like just say this is the first fucking
podcast from the new,
the new studio,
which I fucking love.
This is it.
I love this day.
One of Internet sucks of fat Dick Joe
Rogan.
We will fix it though,
folks in.
If it's possible we will fix it.
God Damn it.
We will get a satellite for the roof.
Okay.
That's even worse.
I think we're going to make this shit
happen.
Shane Smith.
You bad motherfucker.
Follow him on twitter.
It's Shane Smith 30.
Why?
Because Shane Smith anonymous is a
greedy bitch.
Doesn't want to give up his fucking
name.
Listen,
Shane Smith,
all I want you to do is go and watch a
few videos of the real Shane Smith in
the fucking Congo and you sir will give
up your twitter name.
Okay.
There is more important things than you.
Can't you be snuggled bunny 69 or some
shit son.
Uh,
go to [inaudible] dot com and be
informed in an honest and real fashion.
You fucks.
And one day soon there will be a show
produced by advice that will be on h be
mother fucking.
Oh,
and what is that?
What's it called?
It's called Vice.
That's why you need to know why fuck
around and get creative and call it snow
flowers through an extra dimension.
It would have been better for planet on
Vance.
I would've had some better things to say
there,
but I ran into a wall shit time to pull
myself out with August first.
Brian Red Band,
August first or August.
Why do I always say August and December?
It might be a little drunk.
August and December to me,
for whatever reason,
they blend together.
If you were,
um,
if it's in August and you're listening
to this and in the future and it's the
apocalypse and you go with the Moody
Theater in Austin doesn't even exist
anymore.
I'm sorry,
I just went brain stumbled over my
words.
December first.
It will be Dunkin motherfucking
trussell,
Brian motherfucking red band and me and
will be at the Moody Theater in Austin,
Texas,
which is if you're listening live,
which I don't think anybody is at this
point,
uh,
it will be this Saturday night,
a December first.
Come get your freak on with us.
And Tay Hos a thank you to [inaudible]
dot com for sponsoring this podcast.
Thanks for providing the best
supplements available at the best prices
available and the,
the ethics behind it to give 100 percent
money back guarantee on the first 30
pills.
He,
nobody's trying to rip you off.
Just trying to sell you the best
vitamins,
the best nutrients.
Use them in accordance with a healthy
lifestyle.
Uh,
Shane Smith drinks whiskey and allegedly
smoke cigarettes.
It's,
trust me bitches.
It doesn't matter.
Okay.
You could have all the Kale in the
world.
Your Shit will end,
it will end,
but what's what I'm trying to do is have
the,
the part that's not ending as fun as
possible,
and what I found is that little Kale
shakes actually help makes you feel
better.
It increases your mood.
A little exercise,
a little vitamins,
some kettlebells.
See those shit by feet and that's,
that's manly as fuck.
Those are called kettle bells.
Those are 60 pounds.
Don't worry about it.
I got those.
It shows us.
This show is also sponsored by death
squad dot TV.
My little buddy brian red bands,
uh,
by the t shirts podcast network,
which by the way includes one of the
best podcasts on itunes right now,
which is Kevin Perreira is pointless.
He is fucking brilliant.
He's awesome.
He's a beautiful human being.
He's got awesome bone structure.
He's a sexy bitch,
pouty lips and he's got it all going on
and he loved the fucking shit out of
that dude.
And he is hooked up to the desk squad
network and you can get his podcast on
itunes along with Ian Edwards is a.
what's the proper posture?
Is preposterous session another fucking
beautiful human being.
You know,
one of the coolest things about having
this podcast,
as I said before,
is that I get to have these beautiful
conversations with people like you or
people like any number of you.
Fuck fuckheads had been on my show.
Oh,
you crazy bitches.
Including John McAfee,
who will be on tomorrow.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
A fascinating conversation list with a
brilliant technological genius.
I just said fascinating
conversationalist.
I think it might be time to pull the
fucking plug.
Brian,
why are you letting me ramble?
Ting.com.
T I n g data.
If you go to.
I don't know what it is.
Taking dogs.
Joe Something.
Whatever.
I said it earlier.
I'm,
I'm supposed to say it twice.
Listen,
there's no structure to any of these
commercials,
but one thing that you can guarantee,
ladies and gentlemen,
we will never,
ever,
ever have something that we promote on
the show that we do not believe in.
We're not trying to rip you off.
We're just trying to keep this pitch
rolling.
Okay?
All right.
Ah,
Salaam Alaikum Dirty Fox.
So Morrow,
John McAfee,
Wednesday somebody.
I can't really remember.
Oh,
that's right.
the motherfucker Dr Russell's in the
house and we'll see you fucked at the
Moody Theater Saturday night.
Paula.