Byron bowers,
Ladies and gentlemen.
Hey,
what's going on?
What's up brother?
Man,
thank you for having me.
My pleasure.
What's the latest and the greatest with
Byron?
You've been traveling all over the
place,
man.
Check your instagram out.
Oh Man.
I just got back from the Dominican
Republic a few days ago and uh,
it was a very interesting experience.
Yeah.
Like anytime you go somewhere tropical
you like,
man,
this place is beautiful.
And then by the third day he'd be like,
man,
this is,
this is horrible politics.
The way they treat people.
Oh.
So you see the balance of,
you know,
everything.
Especially as a,
you know,
uh,
being from where I'm from and being
black and what's going on,
I'm always in exotic places when cops
are killing black people.
So it pulls you out of the situation and
it lets you see how fucked up things or
for like the Haitian people.
But yeah,
I mean at pretty much every third world
country deals with all kinds of fucked
up shit.
Yeah,
like way worse than we have it here.
It puts things into perspective.
Like,
I often think like if,
if United States wasn't established just
a few hundred years ago,
if that didn't happen,
like what would the world be like?
Like what would most of the world be
like?
A lot of these countries that you visit
where you deal with insane police
corruption.
Like I've,
I've had friends that have been pulled
over in Mexico and you know,
the,
the cops basically just straight up tell
you like,
do you want to get out of this?
Give me some fucking money.
I think I had a situation like that
coming through Tsa,
but I didn't realize until they let me
go.
But they held me for a long time where,
uh,
in Dominican Republic because I had on a
button up shirt that's denim,
like the one I'm wearing now.
And they was like,
take your jacket off and I'm precheck.
So when he would come precheck it's like
a white privilege.
And I'm like,
I'm not taking off my shoes.
This is not a jacket.
This is a shirt.
So in the Dominican Republic,
yeah,
doing this and I'm flying out on glasses
and stuff.
And they was like,
oh,
okay,
oh it's a shirt,
huh?
Come through.
And then as soon as I came through there
was like this your bag.
And he started trying to take my cologne
like,
yeah,
that's flammable.
You can't take that on a plane or my
umbrella,
you can't take umbrellas on the plane.
That's a weapon.
Sorry.
And they just held me there and we just
made eye contact with each other.
I'm like,
show me on the chart.
That's all I kept saying.
And then after awhile they was like,
you know what,
you can take it,
you know?
So after a while they just gave up.
Yeah,
they gave up because I was like,
okay,
if I check the bag can I take
everything?
And he was like,
yeah,
so what I did,
I unloaded all my bags and start
rearranging things so I could put it so
I can check it,
can make it back to America.
But once they saw me doing that and they
saw how neat I was,
like every time they touched somebody
had to put it back a certain way.
They like it.
It's just going to be a waste of time,
but even us.
Yeah,
but don't they have rules?
We have rules as far as like how many
ounces of liquid and stuff like that you
could take on a plane.
They do,
but it made it over there.
So that's why I was trying to get them
to explain to me like why exactly it
probably made it over there because the
people that work at Tsa over here
fucking barely paying attention.
Well you take it everywhere.
I take it everywhere.
But how big is your Cologne?
First of all?
Clones.
Stinky man when we were in that I love.
I love it.
I know you disagree with Cologne.
You know what I mean?
Just a great political point.
Disagree with Cologne.
You more Alpha though.
You know what I mean?
You can choke them out with your muscles
and I could choke them with the smell.
I'm
not exactly sure where to go with that.
But.
So how big is the Cologne?
So you're like three point something
ounces.
Okay.
So I think you could bring on like four
ounces of liquid.
Yeah.
Isn't that how it works?
Yep.
Toiletry bag.
Yeah.
It was a total tree back.
Now mind you,
I just,
I kept,
I went from Montreal to some from
Montreal,
from New York and Montreal here to
Dominican Republic.
So this same luggage has been like
everywhere.
So what were you doing down in Dominican
Republic?
Oh,
I met up with some friends of mine from
college,
some African homeboys and I hopped in on
their trip because they visit the Dr Lot
and I wanted to see what it was like and
I snuck it a lot.
Like I came back sore.
But yeah,
I did a lot of time in the water
morning,
evening and like late afternoon.
What's beautiful for that?
Yeah,
that's one of the cool things about this
tropical climates,
the uh,
the oceans down,
they're amazing.
The ocean.
It's amazing.
Some of the reefs wasn't as you know,
not like when I was in Jamaica or when
I,
like in Hawaii where everything just
comes alive and it looks at the city,
but it definitely.
You do feel like you landed on another
planet to me and you're flying like I'm
cruising over,
you know the terrain.
You mean when you're swimming?
When I swim?
Yeah.
Anytime I snorkeled like it's that it's
that other world experience to me.
Yeah man.
I'm a big fan of the water,
but the sharks fuck it up for me.
Yeah.
I'm just not going to get neat.
But yeah,
that's the thing about it.
Sometimes I keep looking around like
especially if it's not a lot of things
in the water,
but I saw squared that was the most
beautiful thing I saw from this trip was
just like 40 baby squid all lined up in
a row
that looked like they'd just been born,
you know,
Popo and they were just there and I
didn't even know they was squid.
I thought it was like fish with interest
in his fans because it looked like,
you know,
like a lady just doing her dress like
that.
When I got close I could.
I realized that I was at a tentacle part
a and I was just locked eyes with him
and I was like,
oh,
this is the most beautiful thing.
You know,
Duncan trussell.
Yeah.
Dunkin has this new virtual reality
thing.
It's a virtual,
it's an htv
vive.
And uh,
you put it on and you,
you actually feel like you're
underwater.
They have this program because I think
it's called deep blue or something like
that.
Something blue,
um,
but you put it on and one of the uh,
reality programs that you put on is an
ocean one and you're standing at the
bottom of this like ocean area and these
fish swim by and it's,
it's not a hundred percent realistic
because the graphics on totally there
yet,
but it's like 85 percent realistic.
And as amazing a whale pulls up to you
and you get to look at the whale,
like you look in his eyes.
But like,
I dunno if you've ever used any kind of
virtual reality.
I'm pretty new to it too,
but you get a full 360 degrees so you
can look down,
you can look up,
you can look everywhere.
So this whale,
as it's in front of you,
you could choose different spots on the
whale that you look at it,
you can look at its eyes,
you can look at its tail.
It's fucking fascinating.
And it lets you know that,
you know,
within a hundred years from now,
probably not even,
probably more like 20 the 20 years from
now.
Oh,
this is it.
Is this the program?
So this is it right here.
So you,
you stand there and you're looking
around like that dude's just looking
around with these goggles on and this is
what you're seeing.
I mean,
you're seeing it feels like the actual
ocean.
Yeah.
That's,
uh,
that's basically what it,
that's basically what it looks and feels
like a,
that's beautiful right there.
It's crazy that that's what is it like
79 percent of the earth or some point
that is.
Yeah,
we looked it up the other day.
It was over 70 percent of the earth is
water and 95 percent of that is ocean
water.
That's amazing because almost like how
they say our bodies are made up of the
same.
Not Quite.
I think a bodies like 60 percent.
They used to say it was like 90 percent
water,
so finding out what it is.
I think the human body is actually only
60 percent water,
something like that.
Maybe.
But I've,
I've,
I've experienced virtual reality,
the one where you could just travel
everywhere around the world.
60th five average human bodies between
50 and 65 percent water averaging around
57 to 60 percent average percentage of
water and infants as much higher
typically around 75 to 78 percent water.
Huh?
That makes sense.
Dropping into 65 by one year of age.
A little water balloons.
It's probably why the scan gets crazy.
Like the older we get,
the water's drop it in,
drop it in there.
Then like I said,
the percentage goes down.
The older you get.
Oh Man,
he probably just drinking too much.
He'll get wrinkles and stuff.
That's actually Collagen.
That's,
um,
that's the wrinkle thing is the last set
of your skin gives out your body stops
producing college incorrectly,
but you can mitigate some of that
moisture and you know,
some people use creams and shit like
that,
but at the end of the day,
time,
time when
certain ways.
I definitely use creams.
I use cranes.
Do you clone?
Yeah.
All the things that stink things.
Well I can't use,
I can't use dyes and perfumes and
lotions.
How come it,
it makes my skin,
it dries my skin out and make it break
out perfumes and lotions.
But you can work alone.
Yeah.
I wear Cologne,
Cologne last,
a certain amount of hours and it lands
on your skin.
So,
you know,
look at you.
You clump correctional Atlanta.
Scared.
So dedicated.
Have you always worn Cologne?
No.
Well once I got into it,
my mom,
like I was raised by my mom,
like sense of smell is just so strong,
you know,
so it was always frigates around and to
me that's the first like that.
That can alter your mindset or your
mood.
Like when you smell something good.
Yeah.
It's an anchor.
It'll,
it can cause like a,
like a mental trigger.
Yeah.
It brings you back to that place like
certain smells,
like smell of apple pie.
If your mom cooked up a pie or something
like that,
you could smell it immediately.
Transport you back to that good place or
bad place or bad place.
Like yeah,
like I like,
like sexy smells,
so I like to be reminded of something
that's pleasant life a woman,
smells,
you know,
so I don't wear like hardcore masculine.
But I liked the smell like a rose,
like you like to smell like a rose.
I like to smell like something fresh
like that,
you know?
I'm learning a lot about like,
yeah,
it takes me two hours to pick out my
fragrance,
you know what I mean?
But hold on,
it takes you two hours to pick out your
fragrance.
It's just in a day or like when you go
to a fragrance store.
When I went,
when I went to the fragrance store.
So you're that dude,
you're just wandering around.
They're touching this one?
Yeah,
smelling it.
And if I don't get like a small,
like erection,
like that little erection.
Yeah.
Like if it don't turn me on in a sense
it's not the one.
Huh?
But you know,
it just like,
you know,
like when you feel the energy of a lady
or you know,
whatever you're attracted to the sound
of a motor when it goes by,
you know what I mean?
Well I'm with you on that.
Yeah.
They've said that on with engines that
actually like when you hear an engine
revving,
it actually raises men's testosterone.
But why?
I wonder why it's uh,
it's like,
I don't know that anybody ever driven a
car with pipes,
which is rare in California that have
custom pipes.
But you think it's rare?
Yeah.
It'll be like for as far as like loud
and those fucking things are everywhere
really.
Yeah.
They cracked down on them here.
It's not like in Georgia.
I'm from Georgia where you can,
you can get a Honda and put in open
exhaust.
I have a quarter inch and take the stuff
off us.
He that stupid.
If you've got a Honda.
Yeah.
You shouldn't do that.
If you're a four cylinder,
that's awful.
I did that before,
but my friend had a Cobra Mustang,
68 a and you can hear that car coming
down
the street,
but when you hear in a real car with a
real motor is almost like a,
like a tiger growl in the song.
It's just an energy that want to
release.
When you press the gas,
you know,
so that it makes you,
it just does something to you.
What's little explosions?
I mean it's controlled explosions
essentially and that's what it
engineers,
right?
It's just the steel explosion container
and all these pistons are in there and
they're all firing.
I don't know.
As much as I know about cars.
I really should know more about like how
engines work.
Like I really don't know that much.
I kind of know there's some,
I ain't gotta have cam shafts and you've
got to have some cylinders and there's a
spark plugs and night,
some shit and some fire explosions going
off.
I don't really know know,
you know more about me when it comes to
cars.
I know the simple like few air spark
gets it going.
That's it,
yeah.
Yeah.
The simplicity of it.
But you are in the cars to your
conversations.
I definitely liked them,
but I can't get into it.
We'll displacement and offsets and the
correct suspension and steering.
You don't know about all that stuff?
No,
no.
I just know what I like body shapes and
what it feels like.
But don't you enjoy like what it feels
like when you drive them?
Like you have a nice car when you drive
that thing,
like you know,
like it has like a certain feel to the
way like when you turn corners and stuff
like that.
Certain responsiveness to it.
Yeah,
that's true.
I definitely know that but there's not,
I can't dial it in.
I can't put that in a computer and be
like,
hmm,
you know,
like I need my suspension adjusted.
Should I go with this call?
Oversell a colo visit.
But that's the beautiful thing about the
Internet.
You know,
you have a bmw so you can go to a BMW
forum and then you can say,
you know,
what is the deal with this year?
A three series.
Like what's the best suspension set up
for handling and some some people like
comfort,
some people like handling.
That's the real trade off is because if
you really want the car to sit flat
around corners that it has to have a
little more stiffness,
still feel everything a little bit more
and I feel that and I liked that.
Like I had enough for for 83,
which to me the best,
but it was the best car or home.
Those portions are sweet man.
Those are underrated cars to be able to
fill a cart.
The field role do this,
like you're on a boat was amazing.
A lot of cars don't give you that
feeling.
The boat feeling like you know the
street is uneven when you drive it now
instead of just the flattest most paved
street,
you know,
you could feel the wave in it.
Oh,
because you must have pretty stiff
suspension.
Yeah.
That car came like that though.
Well those older cars were way more
responsive.
They were way lighter too.
Like if you go to like the really older
porsches like the old nine slash 11.
So the long hood models,
I think it was like 65 or 64,
I think it was two 73.
Those models,
they're really light,
like that's a 2000 pound car a lot of
times.
So you feel everything when you bumping
around those things?
Yeah,
it feels more like a go cart,
you know.
And that was ignorant with my,
like I had to buy tires for it and they
was like,
uh,
it's 83 and I'm like,
it's 150 horses.
I'd take it to the tire place.
And he was like,
yeah,
you need these $150 tires.
And I'm like,
no,
fuck that.
This car,
the only got 150 horses.
Let's put some van tires on it,
you know.
And I bought two brand new van tires.
What's a van like times that were going
on a van.
Why would you do that?
Because it to me it's just a tire.
Oh that's ridiculous.
Slot slid on the freeway or bunch of
times just stopping and wasn't used to
not having abs.
Automatic breaks.
And every time it stumped the brakes,
you know the car was slide on the
freeway,
but I would stop in enough distance to
where a slot and not hit the car.
So you had antilock brakes?
No,
I didn't.
I didn't have it.
What kind of car was this not for,
for those?
Didn't have any brakes?
No,
not 83.
They didn't come to like 86.
And you put van tires on Jesus Christ.
Dude,
that's a sacrilege.
That's terrible.
It was.
It was what you learned lessons,
you know,
anytime you work on your car is cool,
but you learn your lessons.
You learned about Torque,
torque,
applying torque to old cars and plastic
pieces.
Breaking.
Yeah.
And all types of stuff that,
you know,
antifreeze tastes like.
You know what?
Any furniture,
we drink it in the fridge for you if you
don't drink it,
but you have to rework working on a leak
or changing something in drips and it
gets in your mouth and Oh,
I get it.
It is sweet.
It's like koolaid almost doesn't really
taste that good.
I would have no idea.
It looks disgusting and antifreeze looks
nasty.
Looks like,
like,
like nuclear waste or something.
Yeah.
So yeah.
You learn your lessons with cars by.
You still carrying those old ones.
Yeah,
they're different,
you know,
you can actually work on them.
You can open up the hood,
there's stuff you can change and swap
out.
You can go to pep boys or whatever by a
part.
New Cars,
man.
You open up the hood.
It's just like a computer.
It's like opening up the back of a imac
or.
Yeah,
that's true.
He have no idea what the fuck's going on
there.
And everything's connected to some sort
of a,
you know,
a computer management system.
So,
you know,
three,
three and the bemer it's three.
Three what?
Three computers.
Really?
Yeah.
They ignition switch when you put the
key in,
talks to this module,
reads the key code and it talks back and
allows the car to crank,
but all they have to go through the main
computer also.
Wow.
And I know that because I know Colin and
I studied engineering for two,
my senior year and I had to,
um,
I had to snatch a remote start system,
faulty remote start system out of the
basement when I got it.
So I had to go under the Dash.
Rewire everything.
You did all that?
Yeah.
Wow.
Why'd you do that?
To take it out,
but you did,
you know what you were doing?
What,
what made you decide to embark on that?
That seems like something I would want
to take to a dealer.
Well,
I learned how to do install car stereos.
Oh my friend,
when I was younger,
he used to steal a car.
Radios.
He taught me three basic things to start
a radio is like the cars,
you know,
power ground,
you could turn the radio on and the
remote wire was,
makes it switched on and off.
Would you really don't need a remote
wire at the test or radio just like you
got jumped,
started answering.
But you know,
you know,
you start to learn a pattern of things
just like the universe had patterns when
you learn a combustion and stuff like
that.
Just the pattern is was important to me.
That makes sense.
No,
the universe has a pattern and then the
universe,
because now I'm the bigger pattern
scale,
you know,
but the media,
yeah,
the university has a pattern of the way
it runs to me.
You know what I mean?
When it comes to seasons and things like
that.
The revolution of earth around the sun,
you know.
But
Stereo's also had that pattern.
That's an interesting comparison.
Well they definitely have like whenever
you're dealing with electronics,
you have to have power in the ground and
then there's a bunch of other stuff that
goes on.
I've installed some stairs when I was
younger,
you know,
but,
but they were easy back then.
It wasn't that hard,
you know,
there wasn't that,
it wasn't that complicated.
You get to everything pretty easily.
Give up the dash pretty easily.
Pull out the existing stereo and you
just have to figure out where the power
is and where the wires connect.
You tie everything up.
It wasn't that hard,
but I would never fuck with a new car.
Like,
you know,
like a new lexus or something like that.
Try to take stereo out of one of those
things was more tough.
But if I break it down to you like this
coding and stuff is all if an statements
right.
If end if,
ands.
So if this go there,
go here,
right?
Ones and zeroes,
right.
If there's one poem here because zero
boom here and it's just a bunch of that
going on,
right.
Computing at one time.
That's the pattern,
right.
You know,
has it as a simple.
Yeah.
Well it's more complicated than that.
Right?
Well it's not going on.
What does a bunch of those all in one
was.
It's amazing how well these cars work
when you really think about it because
like I'm like I have a lexus and I have
a key that is actually in my wallet.
It's a credit card and that's my key.
So I don't ever take a key,
I just get in my car and it always knows
it's me.
I come near it.
The light goes on near the side.
Mirrors the side.
Mirrors have like an underside light.
The light goes on,
the handle illuminates let you know you
there,
it opens for you,
you get in,
you just press start and go.
It's crazy how often it works.
We get never fucks up.
Yeah.
And that's cool.
It is cool.
But it's just when you think about how
many different things fail in terms of
electronics,
you know how many different people's
iphones start fucking up most cars,
especially when it comes to like your
card,
a German engineering or Japanese
engineering,
something like that.
They're so fucking reliable.
I mean the,
the amount of times that they actually
do fuck up is people complain about it
but it's pretty small.
And while I was in school and I learned
a study in [inaudible] 95 when it came
to the Lexus and the Honda,
the car,
we're pretty much perfect [inaudible].
So they had to add features.
So now have you noticed where everything
is about the features and less about,
you know,
and there's a cycle of cars having more
power and cost saving gas cars having
power.
That's just a pattern.
It's just gonna happen.
Um,
but yeah,
it's all about the features now.
Even with phones,
it's all about the features.
Yeah.
Well for sure.
I mean with new cars tube is like you
have to have apps and all sorts of
different things that your car can do.
But those older cars,
the one of the interesting thing is how
long some of them lasts.
Like I have a friend who has Alexa,
so it was a million miles on it.
It's a million miles because the gs
$300,
the fourth member.
But model it is the older,
bigger ones.
The big one.
Yeah.
That's,
that's the one that's supposed to be an
asset car asset car.
Yeah.
Like,
it's gonna appreciate really because
yeah,
you know,
the foreign cars are just now starting
to appreciate versus the old American
cars.
Well you mean foreign,
like Japanese cars.
German cars are always kind of
appreciated,
right?
Like porsches.
But yeah.
Porsche's and stuff like that,
but as far as like the little light.
Yeah.
Japanese cars and like the Lexus.
Well,
you know what's really appreciating now
it's kind of interesting is those old
Nissan skylines.
Yeah.
The ones that became the gtrs.
When you look at a gtr now,
it's very different looking,
very spaceship looking,
but the older ones are kind of like more
retro and kind of cool looking.
But the oldest ones now are starting to
become really valuable.
Yeah.
Like the early nineties and late
eighties.
Yeah.
It's just hard to find one.
It's not molested because a lot of
people took,
um,
and they did shit to the fenders and
they fucked with this.
He fucked with that.
I just told her ticket about that the
other day we was talking about cars and
I was like,
yeah,
it's hard to find something that you
could find one.
It's not been molested.
She was like,
what in the heck?
Explain to her what molested was and
what retard tranny is.
Retard.
Yeah.
For a car.
We don't turn over.
It's like when they don't move forward
with something is holding it back.
Yeah,
you called it a retard retard,
like have you tried to turn the car and
it won't turn over retarded.
Slow like it won't turn and then mostly
using like the Europe,
Europeans use it
most of the time.
Do they really use it like a standard
term?
Yeah,
like some of the blogs and stuff.
It's like,
you know,
it's amazing.
Do you read blogs?
I'm cars.
Yeah,
like when I,
because I work on my car myself.
So yeah,
anytime you are trying to diagnose a
problem,
it's more reading then going actually
going out to figure out what it is.
That's interesting.
You read all that kind of stuff but you
don't read up about like suspensions or
different tire offsets or anything like
that or no?
How come?
I don't know.
I think uh,
I don't,
I really never really have what they
call a super car up or modified it too
much,
you know,
so everything I get,
I used to just ride basically with it
and I can have fun with that because I'm
not a high horsepower guy.
I just need it to be quick and like turn
and handled well and I just live
dangerously within that.
You know,
you live dangerously
well.
Those cars,
like,
you know,
you have a BMW three series.
Like those cars,
they're handled.
They handled great anyway.
Like my friend Eddie bought one of those
a few years back and he had before that,
like an old shitty bronco and when he
got that a bmw three series,
he was like,
oh my God man.
He goes,
I like driving now.
I never knew that driving was actually
fun.
Yeah.
Like I would go,
he would go,
he was a,
I would take Mulholland just for fun,
like just decided I'm gonna take it this
way if no longer just because I'm bored,
you know?
I took,
I was in Topanga like last month with
the car.
The road is a road as a ward now.
Pure warped.
My role is a warped from what?
From just breaking and like his driving
Topanga.
How many times did you do it that day?
I was filming something like a
documentary and I went hard that day,
but it was already working for.
I went that day.
You were filming a documentary in your
car?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Um,
somebody was doing a documentary on
creating comedians create content and I
was showing them like what,
how,
how I get inspired and what gets me in
the mood and the car is one of those
things,
you know,
because when you talk about,
you're talking about engineering,
so kind of you know,
and putting it in comedy set.
Yeah.
And I'm just a balance between
the left and right brain,
the logic side and the creative side and
the balance between the two because my
style is basically that balance,
you know?
Oh,
you don't know.
Well,
I'm,
I'm trying to get.
So you get this by driving,
is that what you're saying?
Yeah,
I've been driving is something that's,
that's beautiful.
I took him to a junk yard also cause the
death of a car and the rebirth of parts
when you need it,
you know,
the life and death,
the Yang Yang of that.
And I took him to paint a cane because I
did la,
I did acid in Topanga.
And it's a good place to.
Acid.
Yeah.
So at one part we kind of an original
though,
a lot of acid going onto panga.
So when you,
when you out there,
you got nature right?
And then when you turned onto the
street,
you have all these sports cars,
you know,
which is beautiful.
You got a manmade creation.
They also has life to it.
Are you looking at just trying to follow
you?
I get it.
I get what you're saying.
So we found and I took traction control
off and it was four of us in that little
car and we just slid around a corner a
corner and uh,
those guys were scared,
you know?
Yeah.
You're sliding.
Yeah,
it was a residential street.
They should be kind of nervous.
It was a little nervous and I was a
little nervous,
but that will made it fun.
You know,
we did that together.
He has tricky though because that's kind
of a lot of people drive into Topanga.
Yeah.
And that's what adds to the,
the edginess of it,
just like my set,
you know,
is that line you can call that edginess
or irresponsible on public roads,
you could call it that.
Yeah.
What I don't,
you know,
once you get into that,
that's like trying to figure out the
offset of attire,
you know what I mean?
What do you mean?
Those little details,
little details of what's fucking
dangerous.
There's no,
that's not a little detail when you
slide in sideways on a residential road.
No.
One thing that's a little detail.
Yeah.
That,
that,
that could be the difference between,
you know,
a man that was close in like somebody to
call nine one one,
you know,
uh,
yeah.
That's irresponsible,
right?
Isn't it?
No,
it's fine.
No worries.
Just edgy to scuttle sliding around.
Losing control of your car on public
roads.
No big deal.
It's like when you,
we will be at high school at parties and
like a,
a gun would come out.
Oh Jesus,
you thought the Party was fine.
But when that pistol came out,
that's when real excitement happens
in school.
Dudes are pulling guns out in your
parties.
Yeah,
right apart.
A party wasn't good and lets the cops
showed up.
Jesus Christ.
So you have the cops didn't show it was
all right.
And so when guns were getting pulled
out,
what were they getting pulled out for?
Oh,
people probably was arguing about
something.
Some.
How many times did you see this?
A.
Not a lot of times this will happen.
It just what happened regularly,
like,
you know,
at the night clothes and you started
going to nightclubs.
Yeah.
These things will happen,
you know?
Yeah.
What do you think about all this shit
lately?
That it seems like every couple of days
there's some sort of a mass shooting.
Well,
the,
the problem with being a black guy from
those areas in your thirties,
that's just what happens,
you know what I mean?
So,
um,
but in your twenties at any man really
took me in the twenties is more fight.
It's like that military,
like we're not going to take this,
Yada Yada Yada.
But you know,
and I could imagine like I'd be imagined
sometimes I look at it a funny way like
this,
my grandmother,
this is nothing,
you know what I mean?
Because they were like hanging people
and throw them over the bridge and the
county where she's from and shoot them
shot guns for fun.
So this is like,
you know,
to me in her mind she's like,
oh they need an excuse now
who is doing this?
What do you mean?
Like they were throwing people,
hanging over bridges,
shooting them for fun.
Yeah,
because I'm from the south,
so things are a little,
you know,
little old school sometimes it's not
that long ago when certain things
happen,
you know,
like Jim Crow and like these things
aren't that old,
but you still hear the stories.
You're,
you're,
you're brought up a,
I don't know,
I don't want to say racist,
but you brought up to like these people
are their enemy or be careful when
you're on that side of town or like they
say you might not come back home when
you leave the house.
So when you're talking about is white
people doing fucked up shit to black
people like that.
This was something that was so common
that it was just talked about all the
time.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And you still have nice people,
you know?
Um,
it's an honesty in it that I don't see
anywhere else because when I got out
here people act like racism didn't exist
and it affected comedy like three years
ago.
You know,
who the fuck was acting like racism
doesn't exist.
What would be like,
oh,
it's not,
come on and it's not that bad at or who
was in that?
People would say that it's not that bad.
Like we don't.
When people love to say there's no
racism because Obama's black.
Hilarious.
That's one of my favorite ones.
Yeah.
Like people.
And I was like,
well I'm still shellshocked but my
situation is different because I was
treated unfair within my own community.
Then I left my community,
you know,
like I had the whole light skin dark.
My sister,
light skinned,
fair skinned.
I'm dark skin,
you know?
So you were treated poorly within your
own kid because your skins too dark
because of that one thing and you know,
single mother being looked upon
differently and we are in the Bible belt
so there's a lot of like not having nice
clothes and bullying Brian and then I
got sent to a white school when I was
bad at my first year.
You know what I mean?
So to me it was like this whole,
this whole world is crazy,
you know?
Yeah.
That's the weird thing,
isn't it,
that the racism inside the black
community between light skinned and dark
skinned people.
Well it isn't until you go to Brazil and
you see,
um,
where they all Brazilian and see the
racism Brazilians or you know,
you started hanging out with other
cultures and start seeing the
separation with the other coaches in
saying that what I call a pattern of
human behavior.
Well there's definitely a pattern and
human behavior and trying to find groups
that they belong to and then an
alienating,
isolating themselves from the other
groups.
Yeah,
that's a,
that's an unfortunate thing that people
do and they do it.
The feminist thing to me to separate man
from woman.
Uh,
and then you got the,
you know,
the gays and then you got what's going
on in between the black people in the
cops know.
I mean we just two groups that are
opposing each other more so now than
ever.
So you think feminism is separating men
from women?
That's what they're doing.
I think it's a,
it's a slight shifting of,
uh,
especially with the guys,
you know what I mean?
Oh,
male feminists,
male feminists and male feminists or
barely real.
It's weird.
It's a weird situation.
You know,
he just parked his joint.
Keep up with you.
Male,
male feminists.
So seriously,
barely real.
They're barely real.
There's a very tiny percentage of men
that are actually male feminists.
The smallest percentage are actually
adhere to those ideologies.
The vast majority are doing what's
called virtue signaling.
Michael Shermer has got the best
expression.
I wonder if that's his expression.
I see it everywhere.
I see it more often now than ever
before.
I think since he's been on this podcast,
but um,
what they're doing is just trying to
make everybody think that they're
amazing.
They're there,
so virtuous there,
so ethical and so moral and so open
minded and fair and they're thinking
that they've,
you know,
they identify as a feminist,
but most of it is guys that just can't
get any pussy.
Well,
I thought I was the truth.
I thought I was a true feminist,
but I was talking to this young lady
about how beautiful women are and I was
like,
they like,
I like to be in place with beautiful
women.
They like cars once good,
you sure.
And she was like,
you objectify women.
And I was like,
well,
I guess I take the five women then,
you know,
you see that thing Jamie and a thing I
tweeted the other day from Cosmo
Cosmopolitan magazine side-by-side
cover.
It was a retweet from the amazing
atheist.
We'd a side by side cover.
One of them was white men who objectify
women are the effing worst.
And then,
and the very next cover it showed CV.
It's identifying men's bulges during the
Olympics.
Yup.
It's hilarious.
That's hypocrites.
Yeah.
But I always had confirmed,
confirmed men who objectify women are
effing horrible.
Thirty six summer Olympic bulges that
deserve gold and then it's just guys abs
with their,
you know,
speedos,
looking at their cocks.
It's hilarious.
People are fucking hilarious.
I agree.
And I feel like,
you know,
when I talk I try to be as truthful as
possible,
but I only learned through my ignorance.
You know what I mean?
You only learn.
Well I learned,
we learned through my ignorance,
but you learned a lot from shit that you
didn't know I'm messing up.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Or Yeah.
Or not knowing.
Yeah,
I mean I think there's a,
I think feminism and all these things,
this is like a giant scale,
right?
And then there's,
there's feminism that totally makes
sense to me.
I think there's a lot of women that,
um,
they did get treated unfairly.
They work with assholes who just want to
fuck them or want to treat him like shit
because they're a woman or they have
power over them and they know they can
pull some stuff on them that they can't
pull on men.
I think that's 100 percent real and I
think there's a lot of women that are
awesome.
They're,
they're,
they're cool,
they're creative,
they're funny,
they're powerful and you know,
to call it feminism or whatever it is.
They're just awesome humans.
It happened to be women,
you know,
so I think like the,
in some ways the idea of feminism is to
recognize those women for what they are
just awesome human beings and to sort of
shield them and protect them against a
lot of sexism,
a lot of misogyny and a lot of shit that
gets directed and their direction.
And I know it's real.
I've seen it.
It's 100 percent real.
Yeah,
that's true.
It's a lot of sexism,
just like anybody that would say to you
that there's no racism that is fucking
papaschase.
Of course there's racism is racism
amongst black people,
against other black people.
Yeah.
I experienced that.
This,
I think there's just ignorance,
just foolish people and I think in a lot
of ways it's not even the people's
fault.
A lot of what we are is a measurement of
who our parents were,
who their parents were,
the neighborhoods that we lived in,
the people that were exposed to and the
think process,
the thought process that surrounds these
areas.
It's super difficult to escape.
You know,
it's just really hard for people to
think outside of the box.
It's easier now because you might live
in a bad neighborhood with a bunch of
silly people that don't think very well,
but you have access to the Internet now.
So now you can start to take it into
their ideas and consider those ideas and
say,
well,
maybe these fucking people around me are
asshole.
Well,
the problem with the Internet is,
and I got friends and family that don't
have the thought of going to the
Internet.
You know,
that's the problem with the Internet,
not the Internet.
But when you know that situation,
you know.
Um,
yeah.
So if I have a conversation with
somebody and I was like,
why don't you just google it?
And they was like,
what I'm asking you.
Yeah.
You're,
you're hanging around with Chili people.
Well this is just real people.
I'm related to,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
There's nothing you can do about that.
No,
but it's like you got to leave them
behind.
It's tough though.
It's tough.
It's tough,
man.
I mean,
I would have left,
but I realized once I left home,
the smarter,
the only person that's educated or the
person who thought outside the box is
gone.
You were the only person that was
thinking outside the box for the most
part.
Yeah.
Well,
what do they think about you being like
this sort of subversive comedian?
You know,
you're this like minded,
free speaking.
It says wild shit onstage.
You know,
they don't get it.
Uh,
the funding.
No,
to be honest,
I'm here to tell them they're wrong.
Nah,
they don't.
You can just tell by the look in their
face when they see it.
Um,
isn't that what they,
it's not worldstar hip hop.
Is that what they're expecting?
Yeah,
that's what they found.
Like,
look at this dude gets slapped,
know.
Yeah.
So it's just a different.
I've,
I've socially,
economically,
mentally crossed over,
uh,
but it happened so long ago that you
felt like you can't relate sometimes
when you're talking to them.
Well in a sense,
but the thing,
you know,
there's things you find interesting,
uh,
they might not find interesting and it's
always a thing in the black community
when they was like,
how a desegregation in the black
community because it took the doctors
and lawyers out of the community but
don't think,
I don't want to hang around them.
Niggas ain't trying to sit around
motherfuckers that drink alcohol all
day,
you know what I mean?
And they tend to talk about how to
invest in what percentage the bank
returns versus,
you know,
uh,
our,
you know,
ira or something like that was like,
he tried to like.
So I see.
I understand why these things happen
now.
Why people move out.
Yeah.
You know,
um,
but that's the journey that I'm on.
And then I try to go back and his
spleen,
those things,
you know,
there's amazing aspects to all sorts of
different ethnicities,
different parts of the world,
different groups of humans.
There's like amazing aspects of their
culture that they,
they have that it's gonna,
it's gonna be weird if all that stuff
gets lost.
But I think ultimately what human beings
eventually you're going to have to
figure out is the only things that
matter or like,
I mean it's really like basically
straight Martin Luther King Jr.
Yeah,
judge a man by the content of his
character or a woman who are you.
But we can identifY each other so easily
by what we look like or where we're
from.
It's so easy.
So,
so many people are like so proud of
being from a certain part of the world
and in some place I think in some ways I
think it's kinda cool.
Like armenians talk some shit about
Armenia and armenians.
They'll smack the fuck outta of play,
man.
They're fucking loyal to that and they
don't even live there anymore.
Man.
That's like being someone who's really
into being american and living in south
America.
You know,
you talk shit.
If you talk to shift to an ex pat like
that lives in south America,
you know,
if you're like,
man,
America is shit.
America's fucked up.
It's ruined the world.
He's like,
yeah,
that's why I'm here.
I'm here,
bitch,
get the fuck out.
I got the fuck out because they didn't
want to deal with anymore that you
can't.
Like there's something cool about that.
These people that come over and they are
unapologetically like one of the things
I like about armenians,
I don't mean to.
I'm not picking on them,
I'm complimenting them.
They're unapologetically masculine.
Those dudes will were fucking wife
beaters.
Tank tops with a gold chains hanging
down.
It's hilarious.
They're like rockets.
So old school.
I like it.
A lot of ways to test out or they look
like they looked through.
You sometimes.
See I don't want to lose that because I
think there's something cool about what
that,
that community represents.
I don't want to lose that.
I don't think you,
you lose it.
I hope not.
I mean,
I'm from a situation,
like I got african friends and when we
met they had to sneak me in their home.
Um,
because I'm not african really?
Because you're from America.
Yeah.
What part of africa?
They from Nigeria.
Okay.
It's funny like saying,
saying someone's african,
it's like you don't fucking big africa
is so many different countries in it.
I was a,
I think it was umeboshi.
I was watching some documentary about
Namibia last night.
I think it's a mirrored bia.
No,
maybe not.
Maybe Namibia.
Namibia.
Extremely under-populated.
It's enormous.
It's like bigger than Texas by like one
quarter,
which is Texas fucking huge.
So this country is bigger than Texas by
more than one quarter and I think it
only has like 2 million people in it.
And uh,
they were,
they were showing the little,
this one village that they visited,
how little rain father was.
They had one inch of rain in three
years.
It's crazy,
man.
When you look into how these people
live,
like I like watching documentaries that
highlight human beings that just easily
could be you or me easily if just this
happened.
And that happened.
And her mother gave birth in this weird
part of the world and they're just
people,
man,
they're waving.
These kids are real playful.
They're waving to everybody.
they,
they're waving to the camera.
They're so excited that the camera
people are there to film this and
they're out there cooking and it's so
dry,
it's so dry,
you know,
you look at it and be like,
where are they getting their water?
Where's the fucking water?
There's no water.
This is crazy.
They had a on this documentary,
they had a problem,
was a show.
It's actually called uncharted.
So this guy named jim shockey and he
travels all over the world and he's a
professional hunter.
And he visits these communities.
a lot of times he's helping people.
He had to,
they had to take out some crocodiles
that it'd become addicted to eating
people or customers accustomed to eating
people.
And this one,
they had to stop a hyena that was
killing all their livestock is hyena
would come in and just mangled their
livestock.
And uh,
they had to get up in the middle of the
night and then drive there super early
in the morning before the sun came up to
observe this hyena because he would only
be there for like a few moments.
The early,
early morning.
Then we'd Bolt.
But it looks like a werewolf like this
werewolf.
It's tearing apart this cow and I'm
watching this and I'm like,
man,
these people are living in these little
houses near this.
This fucking thing is out there.
Just mangling their cows.
They have no water.
It's dry as fuck.
It's so fascinating.
Men.
Anyway,
dot is a country in africa.
Yeah,
of course.
there's other countries that are
tropical.
There's other crunch.
it means africa's,
it is insane how big that place is.
I haven't even been.
I was going to go this summer,
but I found out that you have to take
malaria shots and I'm like,
I'm not going to have a malaria
medication to my kids.
Fuck that.
Those shots.
I'm not a fan of.
The malaria ones are supposed to be
particularly abrasive on your body.
And there's,
I don't want to see my kids walking
around poison just because I thought it
would be cool to go see an elephant.
It's natural environment
to live on my own.
I mean,
I think it would be fucking cool to see
for sure.
Yeah.
Africa,
the africans I met with so real,
but they broke down.
The white man will theory to me,
the white man wolf yet.
What's that like?
You're not full blooded.
Not african.
Normal.
Are you white man's will.
You'd like to appear.
Oh,
that's you.
That you would be the white man's wolf.
That's why on the low the community
black people saying,
no,
we're not african americans because they
consider themselves african americans.
Yeah.
I had a buddy of mine.
I went to africa to another black guy
was telling me the same thing.
He's like,
dude,
he goes,
don't don't ever call yourself an
african american.
He goes,
because you go over there.
He goeS,
they don't like it.
He goes,
they don't like you.
They don't want to see you.
And they're jealous and they get angry
at you and they want to fuck you up.
And I go,
really?
He goes,
don't ever think you're going back to
africa?
No,
but it's weird because you see people
holding up the fist and all this other
stuff,
but we're so far removed.
I can send us a group of people that,
you know,
the things have happened in our past.
So we're afraid of that,
but we don't know how future looks
either.
Well,
it seems cool to have this idea that
there's africa and it's like,
like fucking narnia or like it's like a,
it's like the,
the blue people that lived in,
um,
the fucking avatar avatar.
What was that planet?
The planet they lived on.
That's what about the name of those
trees with beautiful matt?
It's like I read it reminded me of other
tanium.
Pandora.
Dora.
Yeah.
Pandora or I'm pandora and dora.
Yeah,
that's hilarious.
Um,
but I remember like the way people would
think of a native american life,
like a,
it's really similar.
Yeah,
I think they'd had this idealic
existence.
It was beautiful.
They lived in harmony with nature.
They only killed what they needed.
And there's no war.
Like I've had a bizarre conversation
with hippies about north America,
but native americans,
and not that I'm anti native american,
I'm by far the opposite.
I think it is insanely cool that this
place was populated just a few hundred
years ago by people that were
essentially living the way people live
tens of thousands of years ago.
And they were successful at it.
They were,
they didn't even horses,
man.
They didn't have horses until european
settlers.
There's a lot of people don't realize
what's even more fucking weird about
that is that horses actually evolved in
north America.
Horses started in north America and made
their way to africa on land masses and
became zebras the course of millions of
years.
This is a,
one of the weirdest things about plains
indians and horses is that they didn't
really have them,
but they,
there's some belief.
this is all from this guy dan flores,
who's a,
um,
I guess you would call it an
environmental historian.
I think that's what he's called.
Um,
but I'm reading one of his books on
coyotes.
But when he was talking about north
America that they almost,
they had like,
almost like a myth about,
uh,
about horses.
Like it's possible that at one point in
time they had domesticated horses
somewhere in north America,
killed tens of thousands of years ago.
But this is all like pre ice age,
ice age,
hits,
ice age thaws out like a lot.
A lot of shit has gone down here.
But those people,
they did not live in avatar.
Existence Is my point.
Like native americans,
we would go to war with each other.
They fucking kill each other.
They do horrible things.
The ones in the great lakes area,
they did a lot of cannibalism.
Yep.
The nez perce,
I think they,
the name of the indian they were talking
about,
they were like,
kill their enemies and shIt.
They would find trappers and kill them
and eat them.
You know,
like it was not this beautiful world,
but dave's doing the same thing.
But I thinK it's just a matter of
resources.
Right.
That's how I look at a light or.
Yeah,
that's also the same reason why racism
exists.
It's like people get in this us versus
them thing.
We want these people,
whoever these people are,
they want,
you know what?
Everybody has to be on this team and
fuck everybody else because that's the
only way they feel like they can
survive.
That's the oLd way,
you know,
but what's interesting to me,
I think is that in this day and age,
thAt old way is just melting in front of
our eyes because people understand each
other.
I mean white people,
that black lives movement hashtagged on
their fucking twitter page.
A fuck load man.
How many people today are racist and
compare it to a hundred years ago it was
probably radically lower.
Is lower.
It's amazing.
Like how white women want to fuck black
dudes because of this thing.
Sure.
So in a way,
it's not all for nothing.
You know what it's like to.
It's like your first liner,
your first responder,
like the nine slash 11 firemen.
They got mad pussy after nine slash 11.
Those guys were superstars.
Girls would just fuck firemen for real,
especially if a girl worked in a
building that was close to where the
towers went down.
Like those guys were goddamn heroes
there.
All their hero genes fired up.
That's it.
I wonder if that's what makes men want
to do it in the first place.
They know that women are going to think
through heroes.
Fuck them.
I think so.
I think guys like want to be the alpha,
you know,
in a certain.
I found my plAce to be an alpha,
you know what I mean?
So if I was a black guy,
I would probably play up racism big time
just for white pussy.
However you could play it up
its chicks that,
that told me yet now you just want to
make out with black dude,
they feel nothing they could do.
so they just want to make out what black
this guy and they could do.
They feel they feel so whatever about
what's happening.
Oh they want to just make out,
just to make,
make it.
Could you somehow.
And I was like,
you know,
well,
there's a few videos that have come out
this year to just every where
everybody's got to go.
Okay,
we'll now give me an excuse now explain
it now.
There's a few that are like the one that
the guy got shot in his car,
reaching for his wallet with his wife
and kid in the car with you telling me
these things don't exist.
Because everybody was like,
ah,
that's how they said it went down.
But you know,
the guy probably said something or he
went and reached for something or maybe
he had a record.
Maybe they knew this guy was a
dangerous.
Nope.
Nope,
nope,
nope.
Just to dude complying,
reaching for his wallet and gets
unloaded on by some fucking psycho,
some stressed out ptsd.
Who knows what the fuck is going on in
that guy's head.
Who knows?
You know,
one of The things I thought was
interesting,
they had this video online recently that
I saw it was,
um,
they took this guy who was an active,
he was a big time detractor of the
police who's talking about how horrible
the police are.
And they invited him to go through like
one of their police training safety
courses.
And what they do is they,
you're supposed to determine when to
shoot or when you,
when you can get shot,
when,
when someone can be a threat,
when you have to shoot them.
It was fucking amazing.
It's amazing to watch because this guy
in just a few of these scenarios started
freaking out.
like he got shot in a couple of them.
When they shoot you,
they shoot at the ground in front of you
with a blank.
Like,
like.
So you had to realize that this is how
quick a cop can get shot by a psycho.
And so there's different times where he
got pulled over,
he pulled someone over or where he was
handling this one guy in a parking lot
and the guy went behind the car real
quick and they came out and shot him
like within a second,
you know,
it was like,
sir,
can I see some identification,
sir?
Yeah man.
Hey man,
I'm just working,
dude.
I'm skipping my stuff here.
And he goes in the back and pulls out a
gun and shoots him.
He's like,
this happened.
This is an actual scenario.
Yeah.
This has happened and it's probably
happened 100 times.
A bunch of times.
Yeah.
So they have to.
They're always fucking like this man.
They're always arguing.
And you know how people are.
Some people like,
oh my god,
we're almost out of gas.
Oh my god,
we're almost,
we're almost doing this.
What are we going to do?
What we do there?
And you're like,
will you shut the fuck up if we get out
of gas,
will walk to a goddamn gas dash station.
It'll take us 20 minutes.
We'll get some gas will come back.
Don't cry.
Jesus christ.
Yeah,
I know somebody to talk to a cop and
they said that when they started working
and then 11 years later.
Oh yeah.
Going into those areas where these
things always happen and after years and
yeah,
it just,
it just wears on you for sure.
And I know from the air just me growing
up in situations,
you know what I mean?
I wouldn't want to go back.
I barely go back there,
you know,
so.
But they do give you nerves.
Your nerves heightened,
it naturally kicks in 100 percent,
you know,
and like,
yeah.
And soMe people can't handle those
nerves.
You learned how To breathe quietly.
You don't know,
like somebody,
you could walk down the street and
somebody could pull a pistol out on
those things though.
I've been driving down the street with
my ex lady and she was talking and I was
like,
get down because I saw a guy draw on a
corner and shoot across the street at
another guy that's the gun went up.
We drove under the,
the,
the fire.
Right.
But it was long.
It was long.
Oh my god.
And then they went up,
we went under,
oh,
we got the second shot off and I drove
and I was like,
man,
that was crazy.
Like I'm that guy,
like lady,
like get up,
we made that was crazy.
And she's like,
you didn't call the police.
And I'm like,
for what is he like to tell what
happened?
And I was like,
I don't want to be.
And that's how crazy it is,
the way you don't even want to be
involved because you've got to go to the
cops.
And I ended up calling the police and
I'm just like,
he described a victim.
I was like,
white t shirt,
blue jeans,
that's all I said.
And that he was like,
was he black?
And that was just a long pause.
It was a long poles like sarah is he
black.
And I was like,
man,
you know,
that nick was black
man.
It felt weird.
But yeah,
because I realized,
yeah,
like
it's just weird things that happened.
But uh,
it's interesting with goes on because I
met guys who shot at people before and
shot people.
So if you hear anything About my set,
you know,
I know both sides,
you know what I mean?
So it's just interesting attitude,
you know,
the chop people,
how many of them got caught?
One.
Oh my god,
one because he ended up shooting my best
friend's sister and her baby in a
passion crime.
Oh jesus.
And his last words to me was,
he was weird.
I was leaving the house one night,
we was in the projectS,
you know,
he played,
play cards and shit,
like I don't really want in thAt like
that.
Um,
but I remember
and he was on the steps and he looked,
he looked up at me and he's like a mad.
He was like,
you're smart,
you got a chance to get out of here.
And it was one of those weird moments,
You know,
uh,
and he was like,
man,
just keep doing you.
No matter how weird or whatever,
people say,
y'all just keep doing you type.
He's like,
I love you.
And I use love like that.
So I was just like,
all right,
you know,
and then I left.
And then that was my last tIme seeing
him.
You know,
how long after that did they do the
crime?
Probably like a week or two
because I was out of town and I got back
and they were just.
Yeah,
there's war zones.
That's what more zone.
I mean,
when you're in an area that has a lot of
shootings,
so much so that you drive under a car.
You don't even want to call the cops,
you know,
if you saw something like that in
beverly hills,
if you were an average person who's like
a successful accountant,
he was a nice home in beverly hills and
you're driving to your house and someone
shoots over your car,
fucking for sure you're calling the
police,
right?
Because it's rare.
Doesn't happen.
They're very often.
That is if you think,
how many people died during war time?
Every year.
Um,
how many find this out,
jamie?
How many?
Uh,
I wonder if this is possible to know.
I was going to say,
how many shootings occur in Iraq and
Afghanistan?
How many military involved exchanges of
firearms?
And then compare it to how many people
get killed in America every day from
gunfire and you know,
everybody's like,
well,
this is just a gun,
a gun,
right?
Tissue.
No,
just not just looking at what's
happening,
like looking at where they're like super
dangerous spots and the,
and the in the mindset and the lack of
the so called lack of resources people
think they have.
Yeah.
Um,
I all.
When you say lack of resources,
you mean no hope for the future.
Oh,
it just fear based.
So I got to eat.
You know what I mean?
Like the power company don't care that,
you know,
you all love each other and you're
trying to go to better your life.
Exactly.
And Sometimes your lady,
your girl don't even want to heAr that
either.
I think that is a big part of what keeps
these communities exactly the same way.
You know,
there's a dude named eddie wong,
he's a chef and an author and he's done
a bunch of cool shit and he's funny
dudes.
Got a show on vice and he brought up
this idea of universal basic income and
he's like,
you know,
just giving people enough money every
year so they live,
you know,
like you don't have to worry about your
bills,
you don't have to.
Everything's paid for.
yeah.
Everything after that you have to work
for.
And I remember thinking time is fucking
ridiculous.
You can't get.
People think people are going to get
fucking lazy.
They're just not,
that is not,
that's not gonna work.
But now the more I think about it,
the more I think of that might be like
the best way to curb crime,
the curb need to curb people doing
things at a total desperation to,
uh,
to curb A certain amount of despair that
some people feel.
And then from there it might be like a
jumpstart for people pursuing other
ideas that might successfully contribute
to the economy.
and I'm,
I don't know enough about the economy to
really comment is I'm just reading a
bunch of different things a bunch of
people have said about it.
And I'm like,
well,
so it might actually make sense in terms
of law enforcement,
in terms of unemployment,
like all sorts of different things you
would have to factor in like where the
money would come from.
and I was like,
wow,
it's kind of counterintuitive.
But once you look into what you like,
look if how many of these people that
are super desperate and don't have money
for bills,
there's no jobs.
How many of those people would relax a
lot if they got x amount of dollars a
year,
whatever it is,
they would survive.
I know like with myself,
I'm like,
I'm around people that make money now
and they like,
money's not important,
but I'm like,
you made it to the mountaintop already.
You know what I mean?
You made a certain income,
but when you're surviving you don't have
time to feel things.
You don't have time to be philosophical,
to fail.
Yeah.
I feel like I'm sad.
You know what I mean?
Like,
or these things.
Like I even look at my mom definitely
now because she had at one point lost
her children and she had to get them
back and she raised us in survival mode
so she never thought or reading a self
help book or learn how to money manage
all those things,
you know what I mean?
And me and my sister had a place now
where we could do those things,
you know,
we can talk about,
how we feel or even look back and see
where we went wrong.
And tHat's just a luxury that,
you know,
I see what you're saying.
My mother,
who was a father,
a mother,
a woman who becomes a guy and take
though roles on it,
does something to her emotionally,
you know what I mean?
Uh,
you know,
so,
um,
when the kids is gone now she might have
a chance to grow and see what things
went wrong.
If she doesn't feel it's too late.
Yeah.
But in survival mode,
I try to tell people that who tried to
talk about these issues but never have
been in this situation before and feel
the need to go out and see why people
get out and don't look back or they try
to help people and people concentrating
on other things.
The reason why.
Yeah.
That.
Yeah,
the survIval mode is very primal.
You know,
the law,
the law don't matter and survival model
or a.
Yeah,
you can take things.
You could run up in this door and take
things because you just that hungry.
You know what I mean?
So yeah.
I've seen and been a part of all these
things.
You like clothes,
you want luxury stuff to the point that
you would take it,
you know,
go to the mall and take a polo shirt.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
You know,
so yeah.
Yeah.
Survival mode is a place that most have
no idea,
right?
Most people would just guessing me
included,
just guessing.
Well,
as people that is in a situation even
worse than mine and I'm.
Yeah.
You see what it,
it,
it does the people.
And after a while they kind of like it.
They might make six figures,
but they still go to the projects
because it's exciting.
It's exciting.
One and two.
They can't communicate with people
who've been making 100,000 they whole
life.
I grew up in that situation.
Well,
you know,
that's a big thing with people that go
to war.
People that have been to war,
they for some reason,
even though it was awful and saw friends
die.
It was the best time of their life.
Yeah.
It's like there's something about living
knowing that any moment you could be
dead that makes the live moments,
the moments where you're not that more
special and then you come back here and
everything's sort of muted.
Yeah.
Just tone down.
You know?
I think that's why a lot of rich people,
they start,
if they don't have any meaning in their
life,
they don't have a thing that they're
really into.
They just start buying shit.
They just start collecting houses and
boats and they're just trying to figure
out there's got to be something exciting
to do here.
There's got to be something.
Yeah.
You know.
Well,
once I started making like $30,000 a
year doing a standup,
it changed me because I came,
I wasn't invited to la.
I slept on the floor for a year.
You know what I mean?
I did the whole car thing and built
everything up from there.
He lived in out of the car.
You were doing that for like a couple of
weeks,
you know,
but everybody's got a cool story that
makes it,
that might make it that I know a lot of
people like rhonda rousey.
She had a cool living out of that was a
very interesting interview.
A lot of emotional,
a lot of people that live in out of your
car,
you be to meet x.
That's kinda normal for la.
But I figured,
I think I made it cop.
Pardon me,
think I made him.
I graduate from college because I was a
fresh graduate from college and I was
like,
I got to unlearn everything I was
taught.
now
how so?
Because it's institutionalized thinking
to me there's no difference between the
university.
Yeah.
There's no difference between college
and prison sometimes to meet what bay
way different.
You can quit college.
Well,
yeah you can't.
you can't.
That's true.
But you know,
both get money for how many occupants
they have and right.
I Look at those stats and they teach.
You assert it's a society within both,
you know.
Then even the military,
because I went to Afghanistan for 13
days,
I think colleges are incredibly
important,
but I think that like all things when
the world around them evolved quicker
than they do,
it creates issues and I think a lot of
what you're seeing,
I've,
I've talked to some kids who go to
school that are taking these classes
from ridiculous left wing professors who
are basically communists.
You know,
there,
there's a lot of them.
IT's not just a few and this left wing
thinking is like super uber prevalent on
campus to the point where it's like
distorting kid's versions and views of
the world and it's trickled down.
It's the students is to faculty.
There's a lot going on.
It's ultimately a lot of it is like the
people at the very top of it all.
It's really kind of fascinating because
those people are shaping people's minds
and they're involved in a lot of ways
from what comes out of that in a
cultural sense,
but there's a lot of backlash because
that too is a lot of people that are
going to those schools and now we're
reading online accounts of what these
professors do and how these.
A lot of these professors have zero
experience in the world itself.
They just live in academia.
They,
they get the degree can go from getting
a degree to teaching and they teach and
they just don't enter the world,
so they live in this world of these sort
of esoteric ideas or these philosophies
that they would like to be real but
might not necessarily be real.
They teach kids.
I was kind of fortunate in that because
like I test,
I took some weird tests in elementary
school that sent me to these schools,
a upper middle class high school and
they just figure it out.
You're smart.
Yeah,
but It alienated me from my community,
my,
like my.
We got bused to a school,
so everybody in my apartment complex got
on the bus and went to school And then
we got separated to where it was like
five black people in this class and when
we would go to lunch we have to walk on
different sides of the hall and
everybody in my neighborhood just coming
through the whole stuff.
So things started to happen then,
but how could they not see that coming?
That almost seems like one of those
government experiments,
lIke a psychological tuskegee
experiment,
you know what I mean in a,
in a sense.
But what happened was by the time,
like my professors were like rich
millionaires because they taught the
subject that they did well in.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Uh,
I would say like a comedy comedian,
I mean a comedy class,
except that that teacher made it right.
You know what I mean?
So they write books and they write their
own books.
They got millions,
you know,
they're doing this because they want to,
they retired already.
I think my stat teacher retired at 30,
you know what I mean?
30.
Yeah.
He wrote his own book and I didn't like
that goddamn because I couldn't steal
this book.
You couldn't steal It went up because he
wrote his own book.
So he gave.
We had to buy it from him and,
and he download the uh,
downloaded somehow.
Oh,
that's interesting.
But sold you his aunt.
He had to sell his books.
Every time a class he taught.
Ooh,
that's tricky.
So I went to college my freshman year
and then have books because in high
school they provided books,
books.
So I made a,
I made money to buy a book and they got
booked buyback programs,
but they give you 25 percent with a
book's worth and I just couldn't get
into that.
So I had this still books and I would
sell the books at 50 percent.
You steal them and sell them.
And what would you steal a physical copy
of the book?
Where would you get them from the
bookstore to snag them from the
bookstore?
Yeah,
because the thIng that the alarm they
had where they alarm and it's fun
because the engineering books school,
but it never was hooked up properly.
So.
And I was standing up just to put it in
my waistband and walk out.
This is all very alleged.
Id never really happened.
Never really happened.
You know what I mean?
This is just fiction.
If I was the right cast,
if I was to write a book though is how
it will be done.
Right.
But I didn't do it like a massive.
I didn't do massive because I know what
grand theft is.
Right.
You know what I mean?
So it's only a few people that I
supplied and it's easy.
You buy,
you getting it for 50 percent and then
you can have that money back at the end
of the semester.
Yeah.
That's a good deal.
That's a pretty good deal when,
when except for stealing,
stealing,
stealing part.
But
I allegedly might've gotten college
books that way to a lot of super common.
Well Today kids can just download most
things,
right?
Yeah,
that's true.
It must be really hard for them to sell
their books now because kids can just go
to like a bit torrent because especially
if there's like a college course that's
an a major university and most likely
someone's gonna upload it to a torrent.
Right?
We assume,
but we wasn't tourists.
I went to school when napster drops,
so we was a group.
Oh shit.
That's pushed all that for.
I remember now.
I remember the crazy argument about
napster.
I remember I had to sit back and go.
I remember very clearly when that
metallica guy got involved,
lars ulrich got involved and he was
saying that this is stealing and and it
was going crazy and freaking out.
I remember literally sitting back
because I was listening to it on sirius
satellite radio.
I Think it wasn't something I was
listening to something on my car.
What year was that?
Like what year was napster?
O two.
Was there even sirius satellite radio.
My imagine this might have been the
radio actual radio.
Xm was right around that same time.
I think it might've been whoever was out
here,
it might have been howard stern.
it was listening to something and they
were talking about it and I remember
thinking just stepping back and going,
whoa,
this is a new thing.
Like people have figured out how to get
stuff for free online that normally it'd
be like 20 bucks or 10 bucks,
where the fuck it is.
And I remember thinking,
whoa,
this is a new door that just opened up.
I remember,
I remember like sitting back in my
chair,
I was in my car,
I remember the fucking parking lot.
I was going to buy dog food and I was
listening to this and I remember I sat
back and I went,
oh man,
this was a moment.
Yeah,
it was a real moment in our culture.
Well before then,
look,
our dorms didn't even have the internet,
right?
You didn't have an internet.
You sTill had to go to the computer lab.
So check this out,
check this out.
This was the hustle.
We met two white guys.
One guy broke his foot when he was young
and his dad gave him my old computer and
he started working a little car game and
from there he learned programming.
Right.
He said we can get him access to a
computer lab.
He could supply our rooms with internet
because they was wired,
but it wasn't hooked up.
Oh,
so he can get the numbers and if and
statements and make the thing
communicate with one another.
So a few of us in the dorms had
internet.
whoa.
And this hack the door,
it's like an episode of mash and this
the problem with learning how to learn
how to hustle and survival mode.
You learn how to get stuff for free,
but you don't learn how to monetIze it
all the time.
But what we did was we,
we started selling like cds and stuff
like that.
You know what I mean?
So you download stuff and then sell,
sell,
sell because nobody had laptops.
I'm nothing like that.
Oh wow.
Yeah.
A friend of mine called the crazy
stories.
We're going to look back on this.
This is like,
those people were in the camera first
got invented.
Yeah.
We started around for four hours and he
painted us.
You know whaT I mean?
This is literally what that's like.
This is what happens man.
And thanks to I think a year or two
earlier,
I was in the crack game a little bit.
You were in the crack game a little bit.
Like 600 would be a meme.
I was in the crack game a little bit.
What this thing was new.
ThiS thing was a new hustle because more
people love music.
Yeah.
When did the crack game open up?
That was 80.
The eighties something.
That was when everything became a.
They blamed everything on crack.
Yeah,
it was.
They literally blamed everything on
crack.
The epidemic.
like all white people are terrified to
crack.
They thought that for sure.
For sure.
Do you want to match that brand?
Now you're lookIng at it.
Oh wow.
So like the top off of it.
Put in your drink,
you'll get smArter.
It um,
it affected me in the nineties,
mid nineties.
How so?
With my father and my aunt
to see,
see a deterioration,
deterioration of people
and families,
like full on
somebody you look up to.
Just,
you know,
it was a,
it was a way for people to get coke way
easier.
Right?
Yeah.
That's basically what it is at the same
high for it or the amount of for
cheaper,
you know what I mean?
Five,
$10,
but it has a different effect.
It must have some sort of a different
effect because people said that the
crack thing,
like after you do it,
it's like really good in the beginning
and then it's not so good after awhile.
But at the same with coke,
I think you still chasing that happened.
Did you ever know say yet though?
Leaving the possibility.
Open bowers ready to party,
you know,
everything I've done,
I do it for experiment with it and to
understand addiction and learn like
comedy makes me so happy that I don't
have to lean on anything for any
emotional thing.
So when I do it it's just to see what
it's like.
Right.
So like when I did shrooms,
you know,
that was,
I was there documenting the experience
and then I will go back into it and then
I can go out being self aware mentally.
Almost like from an engineering
perspective,
we trYing to back engineer what's going
on during these drugs to try to figure
it out.
Let me write this stuff down.
Then I'll go back and look at it and try
to figure out how I got there.
Well,
even when I got into business,
it was like,
let's see what makes you so powerful.
I remember having it in my hand like,
let'S see what makes you so powerful.
You were sayIng that to the crack
itself.
What did it say?
oh sure.
You basically,
when it ended,
what was the low?
For me,
when I stopped selling the low,
it was a low for me because I didn't
know that the person who sells it is
addicted just as much as the user
because you're addicted to selling it.
The power,
the money.
When you walk in a building and people
know who you are and people you can use
the control you have over people.
I'm like,
this will wipe
power.
Feels like
that's.
It was a guy who ran into a store,
got some clothes and brought it back
because he dIdn't have any money.
That's a powerful thing,
you know?
Right.
Yeah.
People are sucking your dick,
you know,
stuff like that.
Wait a minute.
How's it equate to guide getting some
clothes and bring them back?
What?
How,
what the power.
Yeah,
because they don't.
There's nothing they would normally do.
You can make somebody do that.
You know what I mean?
So I look at it like if I was,
and I can think like a one percent
because I got a business education in
business.
So they give you a republican mindset.
So if I was in control of over society,
right?
And I had a group of poor people and I
control the resources and this happened
on the street with drugs to this drug,
they will get robbed.
If I control the resources,
I can allow it to go out or I can not
allow to go out.
I can control the price point and if you
can't afford it,
you know what I mean?
Then it's like,
okay,
let's see what else you could do
to get this thing that you want.
So you were getting addicted to the
power of controlling these people,
having these people dependent upon you
that you would show up,
you be important,
you'd be making money doing something
that's kind of dangerous.
There's like a bunch of different things
going on,
but I think I did it enough to see it,
but I didn't do it long enough to get
out.
I think probably like six months or a
semester to.
How'd you get out of it?
I had the
one point I had,
I got propositioned to take control over
this town and it was at a point
consciously why?
Like I was at a private college.
I lived the triple life.
I had basketball scholarship,
I had classes that I was failing.
It was a religious college,
I had white friends and then I would go
to the black community and hustle at
night.
There's a lot of stuff to do.
You know what I mean?
And I'm like,
at one point I was shot at,
I was hanging with my white friends and
they didn't know what the fuck was going
on.
He got shot at with your white friends
because they wanted to buy weed,
but guess what?
They had to go get weed in this other
place.
You know what I mean?
Uh,
yeah.
so,
and that,
that person allegedly,
his uncle worked for me.
this is the first allegedly of all this
is a legit,
you know what I mean?
So,
uh,
I remember it was a pharmaceutical
company in that town that made a lot of
money and I remember standing outside
face to face with it and I was like,
this is a setup,
we will never win this.
All the money Is right here in this
pharmaceutical company is illegal,
you know,
and I met a guy who was addicted to
crack and he owns a pharmaceutical
company and cvs bought them out for like
one point five,
one point $8,000,000 and you know,
all that money went,
you know,
um,
and uh,
and these and these things made me be
like.
And then the fact I was getting angry
because I'm feeling realized how unfair
life is because now mean black people
who grandparents went to college,
you know what I mean?
And during that time they will do like
brown paper bag test to see if he was
allowed to go to school within the black
community.
They will put a brown paper bag up to
you and if you were lighter than that,
you know,
you could go to school and stuff.
But yeah,
who did this?
This was like certain hbsu bsu,
black universities and stuff like that.
I know they would do that just to get
into a fraternity,
you know?
Really?
Yeah.
You could research this stuff.
A brown paper bag is so white.
I know you're telling me,
look at me.
Wow.
Uh,
so the anger started to come and then
you In the streets hustling.
And I don't think I had the mentality.
It got to one part.
I knew that if I crossed the line,
lIke if I woulda hurt,
harm somebody in a very bad way,
there's no coming back from that.
I don't think I was ready to make that
decision.
But I do know the guys,
when I left,
he went on to build that part of town
and finished.
It was just two of us at the time.
But it became a a crew of six and each
made 13,
five a week.
Take home mom.
By the time they hit five,
six or seven years.
But by the time I linked back up wIth
him,
he was the only one left alive,
alive or not in jail.
And no religion saved them reAlly.
So he pulled it out because religion,
the rest of them are gone.
Yeah.
But I just saw the way my mind works.
I just saw stuff early.
You know,
you just put the pieces together early.
Right?
Well that's,
that's a skill I just killed a lot of
people who have to learn.
And you learn about watching either you
do your own fuck ups or you watch a lot
of people fuck up around you.
Yeah.
Like if you talked to the children
of alcoholics,
they rarely drink.
Not,
I shouldn't say rarely.
When I should say is I run into a lot of
people who were the children of
alcoholics who realize like fuck that
noise.
And they realized growing up with
unreliable parents fucked up and this
and those people like proof positive.
You don't have to actually go through
the mistake to learn yourself,
but once I learned I didn't hate drug
dealers no more,
but until then I did because one,
not my dad I out and they,
I heard he climbed the flagpole for,
for fun because he didn't have no money.
But before then this was the guy that
raised me who,
who managed to.
We live in a small bedroom apartment,
two bedroom apartment to him,
a five bedroom house and cars and boats
because he was just that smart and good
and I seen it all disappeared,
you know what I mean,
what I call it,
like Carol King falling or something
like that.
So I just wanted to see like the other
parts of that and I will be in the crack
crack house asking people's parents
about their kids how to make kids feel
about this and they,
you know.
No,
no,
no.
YoU know,
I talk about that right now.
Like I'm like,
so even during that time,
still like gathering information and
just,
you know,
well,
what's most insidious about crack is
that affects poor neighborhoods in
general and black neighborhoods in
particular.
Like
that was one of the weIrder drugs
because there was cracking poor white
neighborhoods.
Like there was an area called lowell in
Massachusetts that had a big problem,
I think it was crack or was it heroin?
But there's a lot of it was crack
neighborhoods for sure.
Like I know I know poor white people
that smoke crack,
but it seems way more prevalent in black
communities And it,
I always wonder like,
what is,
um,
what's the need that's being met when,
when a,
when a drug provides a certain type of
sensation,
like what is the need that's being met
that is uniquely attracted to certain
neighborhoods.
I don't know that I really don't know.
I know it was cheap for certain.
It wasn't cheap where we was doing it,
that that's what made it so profitable.
But do you think that it's because of
all these pressures that you were
talking about,
like you're,
you're talking about this despair.
He talking about how it just feels like
you can't get out,
you're stuck in this bad place with all
this danger and violence and just the
constant fucking pressure of that.
Yeah,
I think so.
I think I look at what my dad,
the type of people they are personality
wise,
very friendly and then being in a bible
belt where you're taught to behave a
certain way but they are real like horny
people and they like the fuck.
It's true.
You know what I mean?
They do.
So I'm just Being confined,
you know,
growing up with two parents.
I here,
my friend be like they have to have
pressures.
I didn't have,
I didn't have a curfew and nothing,
you know,
but I was just a good kid.
I was still,
they call me a square when I was younger
I didn't partake anything but I will be
out.
I'd be like,
it'll be like right there and I see it,
but just instinctively I knew better but
I see people came up a certain way with
certain values.
Even my friends,
they had to live with that for awhile.
Well,
I had the freedom to be like,
nAh,
I'm going to do this.
So you had the forethought or the
foresight to see where this could all be
a problem and then you got proven.
Correct.
So You got,
you got to see all these other people
fuck up doing all these things.
Yeah.
Well I noticed like,
oh my god,
my grandmother and granddaddy snuff
cigarette people snuff.
That stuff.
So weird though.
My grandmas,
they slam that shit for people don't
even know whAt it's like.
Snuff is like a powder form of tobacco.
Um,
almost like chewing tobacco is what the
dude's dead,
but you don't.
It's an snuff is what the women,
there's a powder form and they still put
a mouth and they got a spit cup and they
will always be like,
oh,
you know,
as a kid,
go grab my spit cup and you watch a lady
just spitting up this beautiful aspect.
They get a paper towel and put it at the
bottom.
So don't make a noise.
You remember?
That was like a big deal.
And the wild west,
they have spittoons yeah.
Remember that I saw movies.
That's the capital,
the capital in sacramento,
and they got those spit things.
I used to work with this dude.
He was a stuntman unfair factor.
It's name is peri perry is crazy.
He used to swallow was tobacco juice.
Oh,
that's a good aNswer because he said he
said he,
he was working on the movie sets so
often that um,
he couldn't spit.
It couldn't like carry around as cop and
spit.
So he started to swallow and this juice
and they got used to it the most.
I drank.
I drank,
And their tObacco tobacco.
Before you drank tobacco,
not drink alcohol and tobacco,
because I used to do focus groups.
Might have Algeria and friends they put
me on.
So that gIve you 50,
75,
100,
$200 to drink and taste it and give you
opinion on it.
Right?
But if you [inaudible] my name is byron
bowels,
which can be byron powers,
which could be Brian Bowers,
Brian Powers.
I could do full focus focus groups in
one day.
So you just change the name a little
bit.
Change name,
put on a different shirt.
Income for like,
this is the hustles that we had to in
college to me,
colleges with four people learn white
collar crimes and stuff.
Right?
So I had to do tobacco and they never
would do it.
Some people and I will do it and then
they will be at a tobacco me like it'd
be like me and the red and the white
guys,
they all like,
yeah man,
this one tastes a little more like stuck
at the citrus flavor pops more than
this,
you know?
And I'm in there
just lit.
I'm like,
oh man,
they're just choosing my hanging out my
mouth.
I can't even spit.
Right.
What is the feeling of doing chewing
tobacco when you don't do it?
Was duty in that group?
Uh,
I think it's like I'm the equivalent to
like,
it.
You just get like a weird buzz feeling.
Like you just really like your eyes are
red and they say it's really good to
write on the nicotine is one of the best
things to write on.
It's like,
it's like a more.
It's like an alertness alert.
Like if I eat chocolate,
drink coffee,
like my heart exploded,
I just started doing this,
you know what I mean?
So it's like an alert version of that.
But you still like happy and stuff at
the same time,
like as if you're on alcohol,
it's like you buzzed in A way.
So it's better,
better than,
than coffee.
Uh,
it's more of a,
a drunk feeling in coffee,
huh?
To me from chewing tobacco.
This is what kind of,
this is just like the loose leaf stuff
or stuff that you will know when you
watch them do it and then you.
And then you got,
you don't even know how to spit and you
like.
yeah.
And I saw this one fucking dude,
uh,
who was doing public service
announcements,
who's going to colleges and high schools
rather,
and grammar schools.
And he was missing most of his lower
jaw.
He got jaw cancer from doing chewing
tobacco.
I think he was a baseball player.
He used to be this strapping handsome
gentleman.
And then as time went on the cancer,
eight,
his jaw,
his things,
to me,
it's things to me,
it's like a stronger a spearmint mint
stealing.
And if you don't know how to do it
right,
it gets all in your well.
How many people actually get cancer from
that stuff?
I don't know,
man.
It seems like there's a lot of people
that do that stuff,
right?
They don't got no electronic version
now.
They got.
No,
no,
no.
Well,
I mean I apparently,
according to people that smoke
cigarettes,
e-cigarettes just don't give you the
same rush.
They don't believe that they don't give
you thAt kick like a at the end of the
day to me.
But it's still smoke going inside your
lungs.
Yes.
it's still smoke on of lungs,
but it's not those e-cigarettes or
vapor.
it's actually a liquid tobacco.
It vaporizes the liquid tobacco in some
sort of particles have to be in the air,
but it's a.
It's attached to vapor to different
experience than the coal.
I mean,
the hot smoke from fire that was caused
that burn with hydrogen or something
that you've ever raised in the air.
Hydrogen turns into air.
You burn it,
you know,
or is it turned the water?
Some water,
oxygen or water?
Some hydrogen burning.
Burning hydrogen turned the oxygen or
does it turn the water?
The water comes out of jamie and google
five things at the time.
We need to goddamn assessment.
Um,
but yeah.
Yeah,
put cigarettes,
man.
they do give you a weird rush.
I don't smoke cigarettes,
but I've had hits of people cigarettes
before.
Just to see what it feels like.
Like a tony hinchcliffe kamia pull off a
cigarette the other night right before I
went on stage.
it gives you like a rush.
It gives you,
like your,
your mind fires up.
And he's like,
dude,
be careful.
You can get addicted.
These thIngs.
I'm like,
I am not getting addicted to your
fucking cigarette and relax.
I'm just going to take one puff of a
cigarette.
That's how I feel about stuff.
Like certain things.
When I told my mom did acid
and I tell people in the south,
I do ask them,
hey,
thank you know what happened to your
father?
Why would you go down the same path?
They think it's the same
trend.
See things different.
I understand what he went through,
but.
And also I came back as moses also,
so that didn't help.
ExcUse me,
but I came back like,
we mean it came back.
I met god.
Oh,
after you do,
these are the instructions.
EverythIng's,
everything's gonna.
Be okay.
I seen life,
I seen death.
I time traveled.
Hm?
Yeah.
That sounds pretty a trippy.
It's like god dammit,
byron,
you went nutty all not around what those
white people.
But that adds on to the fact they
already think I went and for graduating
and saying I'm going to do stand up.
So they were right.
Then.
It's like you're confirming,
but they're confirming that they were
right.
Oh,
well yeah.
In a sense they already like nuts.
This guy is already.
He's out there.
I don't know what he's doing to an
asset.
crazy.
He's,
he's telling.
He's telling jokes.
I got introduced like,
yeah,
this is my nephew who graduate from
college.
He say he gonna go tell jokes.
Like it's a joke.
Yeah.
I got introduced to his dad and tell him
how much Kevin Hart makes.
I said,
tell.
Tell those people how much capital.
This was before kevin.
It was before kevin.
Tell him how much jamie foxx made.
Tell him how much.
I mean,
fill in the blank.
Go to martin lawrence,
work your way up the million different
fucking comedians like jet graduated
from college is a less likely scenario
than if you're actually funny.
Making a lot of money doing standard.
Yeah.
You know,
like I,
it's now.
Now you're at the point be like this is
all you do.
And I'm like,
yeah.
And they like,
oh,
they realize Now that you're.
I was in Dominican Republic and I was
like,
what you do?
I was like,
I talked to people for a living and he
was like,
that's all.
I was like,
yeah,
well you gotta write some shit down.
You got to fIgure out what's funny about
what you're about to say.
it's a little more complicated than
that,
but yeah,
at the end of the day,
that's all it is.
I call it communication.
That's all.
Yeah.
You know,
at this level a level that it's
interesting now because I'm in a weird
space with far as stand up weird space
to me how so far as to show business.
So that's a show business.
How so?
Because there's a place in show business
where art meets the business part.
You know what I [inaudible]
and that's when it gets interesting.
That's when the fight begins of like,
you know,
uh,
do uh,
what platforms can I,
can this be allowed on or okay,
you're going to put me on the show at
five people.
I waNt to do a show.
It's just myself,
you know,
and those things.
Or you got agents now you ask them to
book you and then you don't hear from
them for five months,
you know.
So that was the weird part of just
learning that part of show business.
navigating the waters of sharks.
Yeah.
It's funny,
daniel tosh and I were at the improv.
NaMedrop watch me,
we're at the improv the other night and
there was this one dude who was a
manager is kind of shifty character and
daniel came over and he was like,
that guy gives me the creeps and I tell
him,
I go,
you don't know.
That guy said to me once,
he said to me,
you're the one that got away.
And he said,
dude,
he said the same fucking thing to me.
And then tosh even tweeted it to me
with a bunch of passes.
At the eNd of it,
it's,
there's gonna be those guys.
But if you find someone that's good,
you know,
you develop a good relationship with a
good agent and a good manager.
It's like everything else,
man.
You can come to hollywood and meet a
bunch of crazy actors or you can meet a
bunch of artists.
You know,
you can meet a bunch of people that are
completely out of their fucking mind
full of shit.
DoiNg math,
doing adderall day,
promising you the world never delivering
shit.
Or you can meet some of the people that
you.
And I know from the comedy store,
like you're in a family,
like you're part of the comedy store
family.
That's true.
You go down there and there's so many of
us.
I mean,
I hate to keep bringing it up,
but this goddamn love fest at that
place,
you know,
it's a very interesting.
It's bEautiful,
right?
People's like,
oh,
that's weird.
Energy is bad anymore.
Like,
it's a,
it's a frat and you know,
and this is a thing,
it's a different place for sure than
it's ever been before.
But there's,
there's no bad energy at the comedy
store.
That's a goddamn hug fest.
Well,
I,
I felt a little something when I first
went there.
That's probably what brought me to the
store honestly.
Um,
because I started in the urban rooms and
they didn't want to book me because it
was too far.
It was too experimental,
my style.
So I was like gonna try to get into
comedy store.
And I was like,
I broke in the club before I know how
tough it is or whatever.
And he's like,
hey,
you can't go there.
They don't,
they don't let black comics and they
racist and I was like,
they racist.
I was like,
man,
I've been dealing with racism.
Like that's easy.
That's a mental thing and that's what I
did.
What do you think the comedy store was?
Racist.
That's what I heard.
Who said that?
Like a lot of black comments were saying
that when I got here,
I bet they weren't that funny.
Well,
it's different,
you know,
it's a different style.
First off and a racism is mental.
Like,
you know,
to me hollywood is racist.
You go in a room and be like too light,
too dark,
too tall,
too short,
too fat,
but then it's sexist.
It's
just.
Then it's,
it's a sizes,
just like they don't like fat people.
There's a lot of things at hollywood is,
but it's because they're trying to fill
apart.
I have an idea in their head and what
it's going to be and not live.
You let that get to you.
I had went through so much mentally
they.
I was like,
that ain't going to stop.
That's nothing.
But yeah.
But still they were racist.
They were still in higher you like it's
not the comedy store is,
is they get a lot of pressure to be more
this more diverse,
more.
I know I've seen it.
I've talked to them about it.
Yeah.
Well they tried to do is just book the
funniest people.
That's what they always try to do.
Just before the guy was booking it was
fucking crazy,
but his idea,
he probably thought he was doing the
right thing.
He did.
Well,
that's how I made it through that.
You know what I mean?
Yeah,
yeah.
You know,
so everything else was easy.
I sat there and listened to the talks
and you let it,
you can let it affect you or you can or
you can be like,
fuck it.
Well people don't know that.
That stopped like,
well,
like two years ago that guy stopped
working there and from then on it's
become a completely different
environment.
It's insane now.
It's so much better and I'm glad I'm a
part of it.
Like as far as making the cut because
the talent as far what people got going
on,
I still feel like a regular comic
compared to what the people that I'm on
stage with now and that says something
about me I've failed confidence wise,
but also letting me know like,
you know,
I gotta get,
whatever else I need to get done done.
You know what I mean?
Like I should be like,
amongst the big book,
I feel like it'd be a monster,
big monster,
big boy.
Monks amongst.
I get it because after a while you do
rooms and you're the funniest person in
the room and that can make you cocky.
But then one night somebody don't show
up or somebody don't want to follow joe
rogan and you have to follow joe rogan
and then you learn what season is on a
different level and you can't cheat your
way to being seasoned in anything.
You know,
you gotta put your time in your timing.
Yeah.
And that's one of the things that comedy
store's always been very good at giving
guys opportunities because of the fact
that also there's a bunch of people on
it at night.
It might be,
you know,
people on an average lineup was like 13
or 14,
12,
so 12 people doing 15 minute sets and
the show goes on all day.
So you're going to get some
opportunities if you're a young guy or
young girl to go on,
like right after chris delea or right
after,
you know,
a joey diaz or ron white,
you get a chance to see these people
take these tough spots after they just
watched he go on after ron white,
you're going on after someone.
These people love.
They love that guy.
Come to see him.
They're excited when he's there.
They're
all googly eyed.
The.
That was their time.
There's a bunch.
If ron white's at the comedy store,
there's a good chance that a bunch of
people in the audience came there
specifically to see him.
So if you go on right after him,
you have to introduce them to the world
of byron bowers.
You know,
it takes a little time,
you gotta like ease them in,
you've got to relax them that now you
know,
ron's gone.
I know that he was only here for 15
minutes but he's gone and now I'm going
to come up and it's,
it's a very,
very unique environment in that sense
because it gives us a chance to also see
how other people do that and then also
see,
I mean,
you're going to get the chance to see 12
different people styles if you sit there
the whole night.
Yeah,
that's true.
So much difference in their style and so
funny.
So much.
I mean big difference between you who's
really funny and a guy like michael
costa who's already really funny,
our,
uh,
as well all really funny.
But when you look at the two of you guys
together,
what you both have in common is that you
both have like all this really cool
potential and you might see that 10
times.
Yeah.
So,
you know,
and it's weird because tommy told me
this,
he was like,
look,
we started you in the belly.
We're going to put you in a.
Later he broke the whole thing down for
me.
He's like,
your stuff is regional,
right?
He's like,
well,
I'm gonna put you up in front of these
international people at 2:00 in the
morning.
And I was like,
what?
And what happened was I started learning
how to communicate with.
I thought it was funny,
tell jokes and then he said,
by the time we put you in the main room
with these guys to do theaters,
you will learn how to perform it in
front of a group of people between
220,000 by the time you mastered these
rooms.
So he to me,
regardless,
I listened to what people say he told to
them,
but he didn't have those conversations
with me.
He just made it.
It just prolonged what I thought I was
ready for.
But by the time I got to the main room
and I'm used to doing these intimate or
all tea rooms and I'm performing behind
like you are louis.
And I'm seeing like,
oh,
this is a broader audience and I got to
perform.
I got to walk the stage.
I got to.
I can't do it like I've been doing it in
the or,
right.
I gotta I gotta up the ante and it made
me grow as a comic and I tell people now
like,
yo,
you performing the main room at
midnight,
you're going to be just as strong as
somebody who does it at 8:00 by the time
it's all over.
And when you go to another club and you
get an 8:00 spot,
boom,
you're gonna kill it.
Yeah.
So you run them with weights on.
Yeah,
for sure.
I just take cso for this hbo,
uh,
I was at just for laughs and I did that
gallery show they have there and they
had to do a warm up show and my wall was
so strong I had to close the typing.
You know,
I had to close the taping because they,
cause I,
they had me like up at a time.
You got to close the shit that y'all had
to close the taping and I didn't want to
close the taping.
But in their mind they like,
now you're strong enough to do this,
you know what I mean?
Um,
and my first time with the montreal,
I went up first doing them audition
montreal comedy festival.
Yeah.
The first time I did the,
uh,
the call back that got me to montreal.
I went up first and I didn't want to go
first,
but the set was so strong.
It affected the next three comedians
after me because people were just
staring at him.
And when you do content,
like you just said,
but did it affect them or did they just
not be that good?
Well,
there's a,
that's a lot of what it is,
right?
It's like when someone sees you kill
what the.
One of the big things that happened to,
one of the beautiful things about the
comedy store,
about what you're talking about going on
after I was telling people that are
killing is you learn how to relax.
There's a lot of what happens is when a
guy has to go on after someone that's
really strong is that they panic and
when they panic,
they can't even be themselves,
which is not as funny as that guy.
Yeah,
that's true.
I used to feel that was a big thing that
happened to me.
I would always go after.
There's a ton of guys that are going to
have to.
One of the ones who would always bomb
afterwards,
martin lawrence,
he was just too good back then in two
famous and too popular and you know,
he would do it 45 minutes and then I
would do whatever like 15 minutes after
him and I always bombed,
but I always.
That was the spot that I got and I
realized like a bunch of things I would
see here.
My own jokes come out and knew they were
not good.
Like I didn't think they were good.
So I realized like okay,
I've got to change pretty much
everything about my approach because
what I'm doing is I got comfortable.
I found like a little area that I could
sort of a right and performing and these
are,
these are the jokes that I've sort of
got and try to work with and I didn't
try to expand enough.
And when you get stuck into a situation
where you have to kind of duke it out
for survival,
it makes you reassess.
That's true.
Why is all this bad?
Like what's,
what's going wrong?
Like what am I.
People don't like doing that because if
you do,
everybody wants to think they're a
finished product.
Right?
That's like,
no,
that's the comfort zone,
right?
Everybody wants to stay inside their
comfort zone.
This is it.
I'm good.
I'm pretty happy with the way things are
like,
okay.
But if you do that,
like it's gonna take too long.
Like if you really want to get,
you want to be like a martin lawrence,
like you're not going to do it by being
comfortable.
So it's not going to happen.
That's true.
That's why I came up to you that night.
I had a following and was like,
yo,
that was some heavy weights right there.
You know what I mean?
Off loans.
Just content like.
Yeah,
just the content and life experiences
and sandstone learning like okay,
if I tell these stories about my dad,
schizophrenia and stuff,
they don't even have to be the funniest.
They just so interesting.
They hold.
Wait,
yeah.
That if a funny guy to come up and talk
about relationships,
people still going to be like,
man,
that last year was crazy,
but when I start doing that,
people wouldn't just come up to me
saying,
you find it more.
They were just like,
man,
that's that.
I know what that's like because my aunt
was paranoia,
schizophrenia,
and to me that's the universe saying hi,
now you're onto something,
but that only comes through.
Failed to me.
Like you've improved through failure.
Like the light bulb was invented through
failure,
you know what I mean?
Not through getting it right the first
time to 10,000 times,
but that thing to get perfect.
You know?
So I think also we were thinking a big
part of what you just said,
that it's important as you were talking
about the way it feels when you're
listening to it,
that it's not like your standard
relationship stuff,
that it's something that's in some ways
more,
more enticing.
Right.
It's an interesting subject like
schizophrenia,
like there's something,
there's weight to it,
right?
Yeah.
It's honest.
Like my,
my black lives matter stuff is honest
and is not going to get me liked by
people,
but it's how I feel,
you know what I mean?
And it's,
it's,
it's to even,
to me it's a little messed up how I feel
about the situation,
but it's honest at the moment how I feel
about this.
How do you feel about it?
We'll talk about it.
Well I can,
but to me,
not that it's the worst part of me about
the video is that he got shot in front
of a toyota camry and I'm like,
that's how shallow I am.
If it was me,
I would've found a bands or something to
crawl near just because I know it's
gonna look good because I'm about to go
viral,
right?
And I want to look good before I get
turned into a hashtag because that's
what the police are doing is turning
niggers in the hashtags.
And I turned to somebody look white.
I was like,
you know,
the average lifespan for a young black
man,
25,
but hashtags live forever.
So it's the thing about fear,
death and shallowness.
And like,
that's the complexity of my bits,
but I have to admit,
and that's a true how I really felt,
you know,
when even when he hit the car and I was
like,
oh,
that the car was bouncing.
I was like,
look at the suspension on that.
But that's what makes it funny.
The people,
you know what I mean,
that's what makes it fun of the people.
But I have to learn to,
you know,
as artists we learned and you do this,
you learn to let go of those things.
But the more work I don't get,
the more honest I would come because you
don't,
you stop trying to fit in and you don't
care if they're trying to book a nice
black guy no more.
You get paid,
you take another jacket off,
you take another shirt off to you just
dealt with no shirt on.
Like,
look,
I'm in my thirties.
I got wrinkles right here now.
But I never got laid more in my life.
You know,
like he's just honest,
like,
uh,
and it's something relieving.
It's something whatever from a kid who
was quiet growing up and held everything
in such a release into being able to put
this stuff out.
Yeah.
That's probably something a lot of
people don't understand.
Right?
A lot of people don't understand that
like that.
Where you're coming from is not just
where you are now,
but it's where you started out.
Yeah.
And you,
you,
you're taking particular joy in your
freedom.
It's particularly unusual the way you're
expressing yourself.
Yeah,
and it's.
And as,
as being volunteers,
that vulnerability that people talk
about,
but
as you grow,
as I grow as a person,
my comedy has grown.
Yeah.
That's got to happen.
It doesn't,
it doesn't have.
I read something in the day on jen
kirkman and there was talking about.
She was talking about the comedy is one
of those things you actually do get
better at when you get older and it's
one of those things,
a rare thing for women to,
that they're still at like a 40 year old
woman,
doesn't have a lot of opportunity as an
actress,
you know,
kind of play some mom rolls and stuff
like that.
But as far as like to lead something but
a 40 year old comic,
like a lot of them are just kinda
getting started.
True.
Look at sarah silverman.
She's better now than ever.
She's like,
what is she like 46 or something like
that.
Like everything like attractive and sexy
with a woman.
Like it just,
it just grows on,
its not,
it's not the way you look,
the way you carry yourself and the way
you move when you talk to.
You're trying to say your fan out the
bat signal before.
But I look at it like I'm talking about
like all women now.
You know,
you told her that before.
Yeah.
I told him this was attractive looking
woman.
You know what I mean?
Like I've been in the green room with
her.
Respected the boundaries,
you know what I mean?
Not stare there.
I see little bits but she's very nice
person too.
She's nice outside and it don't get all
like yeah no shit.
But for sure she's real friendly too.
She's a.
And by the way,
I'm talking about all women with that
ladies,
like if you have self esteem problems
like we all do and don't think,
oh,
because your hair doesn't look a certain
way.
It's all there,
but it,
it kind of comes when you stopped giving
a fuck,
you know,
mean sexiness
in some ways.
Yeah.
Because people that are like super
nervous about everything,
every aspect about them to get a
draining exhausting because you know
that there's a lot going on.
There was too much chaos,
doesn't allow you to be comfortable when
someone's comfortable in their own skin
and they don't give a fuck.
Like it's like,
ah,
I kind of like being around you.
He relaxed me.
He will let me know that it's okay to
not give a fuck.
That's what the benefit of the true.
Not give a fuck people through not give
a fuck.
People make you appreciate things
better.
Women say I look sexy now.
And I was like,
what?
Who are they?
Why are they learning?
I don't know why they line is something
that some energy they feel and I don't
believe him because I'm still that kid
with the look.
You're a talented guy.
That's what it is.
What they.
My mom still that kid with the scar on
his face.
Yeah.
And the crooked teeth,
you know?
Well you're,
you're handsome black gentlemen and
you're funny.
Smell good though.
Just smile.
That's what I hear.
But you know,
I mean talent is a big thing too,
right?
You see a lot of talented people in all,
all sorts of different businesses.
Even even like businessmen,
like a businessman as well,
that she just after him for his money,
maybe you know,
maybe that guy has that really beautiful
wife because they're just after him for
his money or maybe they're attracted to
his talent for being successful.
Like there's a little bit of that too.
It's not just the money.
Yeah.
Like I don't think women would be as
attracted to a guy who just won the
lottery and got $500,
million dollars as they would to some
guy who's some media mogul who started
his own business,
built it up into an empire and now has
$500,000,000.
That's true.
Those guys are different.
Like they have that wizard air about
them.
Like this guy,
you know,
like a certain type of like elan musk
how much pussy elan musk must have to
beat away from him.
How many girls are just
bombing on him?
Just constantly because he's a super
genius.
Multibillionaire was several successful
businesses.
He invented fucking pay pal.
He's built his own cars that run on
electricity.
He's making a fucking rocket ship to go
to the moon is making a hyperloop that's
going to go to san francisco in 30
seconds or whatever the fuck and I'll
still questioning it.
I looked at his stock today.
I still question.
She's not a part of me like this is
going to be like the naked general
electric.
That's what I'm telling people in my
mind.
The thing that thing he's going to do
with energy,
you know,
he's doing that with everything.
He's a super winter.
There's,
there's certain guys that are just super
winters and he seems to come without any
of the baggage the most super winters
come with.
You know,
there's a lot of baggage that most,
most of these like crazy entrepreneur
type characters are also genius has come
with.
He doesn't seem to.
He's like remarkably stable for someone
who's that fucking smart and successful.
He's like a god damn alien.
That guy.
It was weird because I had tickets talk
about the silicone valley guys and made
money now.
And it's like,
it's like they said,
yeah,
they nurse,
but now they got money and power.
So they act like that when you see them
out.
They 10 women,
you know what I mean?
Kissing all on the neck and acting like
the guys we used to beat them up the
job,
you know what I mean?
They get bullied.
But if you look at the warren buffetts
and the,
the uh,
bill gates and the guys was just like,
yeah,
this is my lady right here.
Spent all my time working on algorithms,
but it's a new day now.
You know,
warren buffet still lives in the same
fucking house in omaha.
Yeah.
Me and hannah was a in that
neighborhood.
Did you see his house?
Nope,
but we airbnb the property and they
stared at us.
When you airbnb property in that
community and you have to have a cookout
at 5:00 in the morning,
you don't get some stairs and the next
day he had a cookout at 5:00 in the
morning show after party.
And then was it like when you making a
lot of noise or something?
I don't think so.
Just the average is that,
you know,
people make after they leave the club.
That's pretty loud,
you know,
stumbling around 5:00 in the morning.
Shit.
Would it be annoying as fuck if you live
next door to that house and you know,
try and get some sleep?
I think so.
Probably.
Yeah.
The house across the street had three
volvos in the driveway.
I was like,
oh,
that's a lot of safety.
Yeah.
That's a lot of white people.
That's too much.
It must be furious at you for waking up,
so I don't know.
We woke him up,
but the grill was outside and so they
can smell it.
Yeah,
and they had chilean sea bass and we
came with an appetite,
you know,
but don't you think that that was
probably pretty loud.
Like how loud were you guys?
I don't think it was that lab.
I fell asleep.
Oh,
but it was.
We did turn people away though.
You know,
how many people were there?
I don't think it probably be like five
or seven,
but more came,
but that's chaos.
Five or seven.
Seven people that are awake at 5:00 in
the morning.
Those people were probably lit up loud
as fuck.
Barbecuing doesn't bother you.
I slept well.
I didn't bother me,
but at the same time I don't.
If I look at it from my neighborhood and
my neighborhoods I lived in and they
bring that bouncy castle over and they
play the myriad.
I see the 5:00 in the morning,
which happens.
Doesn't be like,
oh,
okay.
I get it.
I don't hate on him though.
Right.
But that's,
that's the neighborhood that you chose
to live in.
Yeah,
right.
That's what they do.
Like you're saying,
you live in a mexican neighborhood here.
Actually people asked for fucking
parties.
They got roosters in my niche kind of
deal that get up at 5:00 AM.
Three am in the morning.
Dude,
my gardener had the son of one of my
dogs,
my gardeners friend of mine and he's
cool as fuck.
Doesn't speak very much english,
but he's.
He's cool as fuck.
He's got like 100 fucking roosters.
100 of them in his yard.
His yard is like a chicken fighting
ring.
Chicken fighting is different man.
It's funny,
like you tell people that you know
somebody that fights dogs and they look
at you like what a monster of a person.
Because dogs are really complex and they
love you.
They have give you unconditional love
and for you to violate that and making
them fight each other is fucked up.
I get it.
I agree with it.
One hundred percent.
I'm not saying that,
but you tell people that,
you know,
somebody fights chickens and they go
like,
they don't even get grossed out.
I mean there's some super vegans
probably get really pissed off or animal
rights activist,
but the average person doesn't give a
fuck about a chicken and if those
chickens are fucking each other up with
spurs on,
they put like razor blades on their back
feet and they cut each other up.
I noticed that I saw a tape before vic
went down,
have a recruitment training tape and
that was my first time seeing the
animals electrocuted and how they breed
them and stuff like that.
This was a real tight good that was
going around the hood because people was
fighting these animals and I know people
that executed dog that I'm closely
friends with.
You know what I mean?
And it's very,
you know,
interesting situation.
But once again,
you're talking about people who was
like,
oh,
we was treated worse than that.
You know,
it's still that innately that's in you.
But it's shocking when people come out
against dogs like that and
that's why you have certain communities
like,
oh,
what will we get shot by the cops or you
know,
and all this other stuff.
Well there's certain communities were
dog fighting is super normal to.
That's what I'm saying.
Like is this normal?
It wasn't a but I don't mean normal in
that it's like less offensive than how
the adult human beings are treated in
that neighborhood.
I mean,
it's a part of the culture.
Yeah,
that's what I mean.
Yeah.
In the south,
right?
Yeah.
I know dude who had like 30 dogs used to
keep 30 dogs in his yard.
He's a professional pool player.
He had a big ass yard down in,
I think it was Kentucky and he,
he,
he was part of what he gambled on.
He had dogs that they train and they
would fight them,
you know,
and
the person that I am right now looks at
that and goes,
well that,
that's a fucking terrible thing to do.
Like why would you do that?
Like that?
That should be absolutely illegal.
But him,
whatever his life was like him growing
up in wherever he grew up,
that was a normal thing.
So I,
I absolutely judge them.
I absolutely judge anybody there
does that.
But it is.
We don't understand.
Yeah,
it's weird.
Like,
and to me,
I think understanding comes from me
personally.
Like if we could really assess ourselves
and look at our demons and accept all
dana's right,
how bad that we could possibly do some
real fucked up things.
Then it will make us judges other less
and then the conversation can be had
they try to understand.
But yeah,
it's certain things that you see that
you accept depending on where you are
are,
you know what I mean?
More than a lot of ways than what you're
saying is like those,
those principles of life and those
things that you're talking about,
these different patterns that you see in
electronics where the universe,
you kind of see that in life.
You see that in comedy to exactly what
you were talking about in comedy.
Like having gone through things,
making mistakes,
making things like really obvious and
then realizing,
whoa,
I got to look at this for what it really
is versus people who look at things
through a distorted perception like most
of the people that you know that have
distorted perceptions of their own
abilities or distorted perceptions of
their own life or where they fit in in
the world.
Those are the people that don't progress
because they're not looking at
themselves.
They're not.
They're not taking these assessments of
themselves accurately so they're not
moving forward.
They stay where they're at because they
think that where they're at with
whatever they're trying to do is good
enough or it's perfect or it's better
than it really is.
That's true,
but yeah.
What I learned from my last,
my acid trip that the one you saw me
today after that,
yeah,
the in art and in our genes because I
saw idea or conception with.
I told you it moves everything for
my art,
moves everything forward and the jane,
like you have a child or you have an
idea that moves the culture or the human
species and everything continues to
evolve and move forward.
Without those things we would.
We continue to make the same mistakes
over there,
stuck with certain things,
you know?
Yeah.
We're fueled by these things that we
create,
whether their innovation or whether
they're a piece of art,
a movie,
you know,
we were fueled buddies things and
sometimes in a negative way.
I mean,
how many people have you met that act
like a movie?
Like they think they say things like
they're in a movie.
Oh yeah.
A bunch of people.
I know a dude who got in a fight with
another dude and as they were scrapping,
like as we're about to fight,
he goes,
tonight,
we dine in hell.
He yelled that at him and the dude told
me,
I'm like,
are you fucking serious?
He's like,
yeah,
it really,
really said that to me.
That's a layer.
And the guy was like,
why did you fucking say tonight we dine
in hell.
And so they get in a fight.
And the other guy,
the guy who didn't say that turned out
to be a really good wrestler.
So the whole thing was a disaster for
the other guy.
Well the guy did the guy who said that
dying in hell that night.
Well not.
I mean it's just he thought he was in a
fucking movie or something.
I mean he was drunk too.
There's a lot going on.
Right?
But it's just that movies create these
scenarios in people's minds that they
almost want to reinvent in the real
world.
If a similar situation presents itself,
you know,
you really think you could say something
fucking stupid.
I mean,
I was,
I said some things before that sounds.
You know what I mean?
And especially in the throes of passion,
in the throes of passion.
But by even poetic,
you know what I mean?
That should be.
That should be the title of your first
netflix special,
the throes of passion.
But byron bowers and you just sitting
there with your legs crossed with like
some nice slippers on in front of a
fire.
That's what I call it now.
Reading a book.
That's what I called it.
Now I won't even say fucking no more.
I call it because I feel I'd do
something a little more creative,
a little more different.
I don't call it create just a lot more
involved.
It's a little more.
There's a little more passionate about.
So you're trying to separate yourself,
like your branding,
your style.
Fucking oh,
I wouldn't do that.
That'll be interesting.
That's a lot of fucking right there.
Well you think about how many different
kinds of music there is.
There's only one pint of vodka and you
know like it.
Music is a style of expressing what's
going on inside your mind,
your imagination,
sodas.
So was fucking a lot of ways we should
have like different classifications for
fucking men.
We kind of did.
We have basic bitch fucking,
which is like missionary little kisses.
Fucking grill.
Fucking.
Yeah.
That's very important.
You need to couch,
you've got stuff in the corner of the
couch.
That's what gorilla fucking is about.
You gotta grab a hold of things,
going to be all subtraction.
You might want to keep your shoes on.
You got some traction.
I got this nike rope,
a leather and not weird and
I put it out on these young lady and I
put it around her neck like a,
like a puppy,
like elise.
And she was like,
what are you doing?
And I was like,
it's the exact right thing to ask.
And I was like a normal.
I was like,
I'll show you,
I'll show you.
Get up and try to move when she got to
try to move like that.
But yeah,
she liked it and it turned on.
And then to the fact that she wanted her
around her neck and I put it around her
neck and the more,
you know,
poor white girl,
right.
I don't want to say,
but it's gotta be,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
A jewish probably,
you know what I mean?
So I'm super liberal.
Jews and blacks now.
So as I'm pulling it,
she got more turned on,
but then she died because he started
licking my thing and I got because I'm a
skinny dude,
somebody my was shaking like this and in
my mind I was like,
this ain't me,
you know,
I just let the rope go.
Follow your instincts,
your instincts with the knock killer.
That's good.
She wasn't gonna die and I don't think
I'm strong.
I think you could definitely kill
someone with a belt around her neck.
That was a length of rope,
but it's kind of like the same thing,
isn't it?
Well,
the rope belt,
what kind of leather?
Very good.
Very good leather,
you know?
Very little.
But it seems like you definitely kill
somebody with a rope.
It hurt.
It would hurt if you,
if you hit them with the leather,
you know,
but then you can kill them if you can
like pull hard enough.
You could kill somebody with any kind of
like thin wire.
I think I could probably kill someone
with a boot lace.
That's probably true.
That's probably a true.
Be careful about that.
If I got a good grip on it,
you know to to.
It's not hard.
The,
the human nac is real vulnerable.
No.
The weird part about that is having a
condom on,
you know,
like what part of this is safe.
Like
that's hilarious.
She's got ligature marks or nac but std
or she didn't get aids but she still
did.
Yeah.
Rough sex is fucking strange,
man.
You gotta be real careful with that
because if you do weird shit and beat
each other up and the girl goes to the
cops,
you're fucked.
Yeah.
Especially if they're not the same race
and that's when black people will be
like I told you,
I told you I was reading about this
thing in toronto.
There was just this judge in toronto,
that sentence,
this man,
he was convicted of rape and he had
consensual sex in his opinion with this
woman and this woman had sent them these
text messages saying,
you know,
come on over,
let's have some savage sex and this and
that.
And then afterwards,
and he broke up with her.
She decided or after they had a bunch of
these experiences.
I forget how it works,
either way,
she lied to the judge and to the court
about sending those texts and then
because she had deleted them,
but then they somehow or another
recovered them and they found that she
lied about that and she lied about a few
other things too,
but the judge started quoting all this
feminist theory and quoting different
feminist writers and a wound up getting
this guy convicted,
which is beyond a reasonable doubt.
Like as soon as someone says,
I did not send him a text asking him for
sex and then you find out they did in
fact send a text asking them for sex and
it deleted.
Well then you've got reasonable doubt
like instantaneously you have doubt
because you have to go,
okay,
what about the rest of this stuff you're
telling me isn't true?
Now I'm not saying that he didn't force
her to give him a blow job or that he
did.
I don't know.
I wasn't there.
He doesn't.
The judge doesn't know either,
but in my opinion,
you instantaneously have to have
reasonable doubt when you find out that
someone's willing to lie about certain
aspects of what happened.
Yeah.
So,
uh,
I was,
I was watching this and I was listening
to this,
uh,
this woman,
from what does that,
what's that conservative website,
the blaze or something like that.
Is that what it is that Glenn Beck
things and it is at the blaze.
She did this breakdown of it and I was
like,
god,
it's so,
so dangerous when you get involved.
Crazy people.
You're sticking your dick and crazy
people like you don't,
you don't really know what's going to
happen.
Like you,
you're there choking that girl with a
rope and she's looking your arm like,
where's this going to escalate to,
you know,
you can things only a volvo and these
kids
only place to go or she doesn't know
that you've been snipped and uh,
you don't tell her that,
uh,
you,
you can't get pregnant.
So you keep pumping loads of nowhere and
you've got to keep ramping up the sex.
And so now she's wearing a helmet.
And you're fucking driving it through a
wall.
Oh,
that'll be interesting to doing that to
make her happy.
But you really don't like it at all.
Both of you are confused.
She thinks it makes you happy,
but you think it makes her happy and
you're just giving her cte and
throwing her head through wallboard.
I mean,
someone has for sure putting a helmet on
and some on fuck them from behind and
slammed her head through a wall.
That's 100 percent right.
That's definitely happened.
I think so.
What are you looking up,
jamie?
I was looking at this case,
but I stumbled across something I
haven't seen before.
Did you know canadian lawyers have to
wear an outfit like this?
Thank god.
So you know the ridiculous.
I looked up canadian lawyers and they're
all good.
The lord.
All the lawyers have to dress like that.
That's hilarious.
Oh my goodness.
Look at this fucking outfit they have
on.
They might as well be working at like
one of those,
a reenactment restaurants,
medieval times.
That's why none of them are smart.
They got wigs too.
They are barrister.
Wow.
Male barristers make more than doubled
their female.
Um,
what does it say there?
It's dot,
dot,
dot.
What does it say?
Do the female had to wait weeks to just
wrong crushing question.
Bullshit.
Oh,
their female colleagues.
Male barristers with their ridiculous
wigs that his.
God damn hilarious.
Wow.
That's,
that's an Australia though that you just
pulled up
still.
There's parts of the world makes you
wonder,
like what would happen if the United
States had been formed?
There's parts of the world that are
still wearing wigs when they're doing
their law stuff.
She's hot as fuck outfits.
Portrait of a woman in canadian law.
She don't have to wear a wig,
but the outfit looks better on her.
You want her to visit you in jail?
No.
She tells you.
I'm sorry I didn't mean to convict you
and I'm going to work to get you out.
And she don't have no oatmeal's.
He better not come with a different
outfit in jail.
You have to bring an oatmeal.
Yes.
Let me see the light.
She carries them.
Quaker state.
What's it called?
Wait.
Quaker state is.
Oh
yeah.
Yeah.
There's some.
That's a funny one,
right?
Like what the fuck does pilgrims have to
do with oats?
Did they grow the oats?
Is that what the deal is?
Because he's a quaker.
It's not a pilgrim,
right?
Quaker oats,
that's like a.
That's like saying I'm going to buy
mormon granola.
Right.
You imagine how many people would buy
scientology flakes.
Oh,
that'll be dope.
Right?
I mean,
that's exactly what it is.
Are clear.
How about catholic?
Crisp.
That's my morning cereal.
I enjoy catholic.
Chris.
Everybody got the same bowl?
How can.
What does quaker oats.
It's religious cereal.
What?
What it.
What the fuck does a quaker?
I have to do anything.
They didn't give a fuck about quakers.
Quakers were so innocuous that they were
willing to use them as props was like
the way they sell klondike bars with
polar bears.
They use the quaker.
It just says that was the first.
That was the right it.
The layers.
Don't you think that's what they did?
That do make sense.
Totally.
I bet quakers had fucking zero interest
in quaker oats.
I bet they don't get paid.
I bet they get fucked over on the
commissions.
I bet the quaker oats company keeps all
the money.
Pepsi owns it now.
There you go.
Those quakers are out there going,
what the fuck?
This is ours.
This is our outfit.
But you look at that outfit and you go
that some wholesome oats.
I bet that oats doesn't even swear he
doesn't drink.
That oats makes its own butter.
That oats lives and the either niceness
falchuk way in a field and they plow
with the fucking like a regular
mechanical plow and they do everything
old school.
Right?
My grandmother was
telling about the cotton gin class time
I went to see.
She liked it.
She on her way out.
You telling me about this?
We were in the back of the comedy store.
Yeah.
It was interesting.
And then so she wasn't alive when the
cotton gin was korean mother,
her mother.
These are the stories she heard.
My grandmother was alive.
I was like,
what drugs did y'all do when you were
young?
And she said,
aspirin just came out,
jesus.
So that's what.
That was the.
That was the thing.
You know what?
I mean,
we mean people took aspirin for
recreation or she was just like,
that was just the,
that was just the thing outside of like,
you know,
home grown because they was farmers.
My grandmother was like,
that.
Remind me of the movie,
the help,
the help.
I don't know that movie.
It's like,
it's about the,
uh,
that black lady who raised the white
family type thing to help.
Is that a recent movie?
Really?
Um,
who was in it?
Who was in will be goldberg,
white family raised her preppy goldberg.
Hilarity ensues.
Emma stone was in it.
Here's a picture.
What fucking movie is this?
It helped.
I have no idea what this was.
My grandmother.
So those two black women raised those
two white women.
But in a sense,
in like the relationship that happened,
like I went to one of my grandmother's
birthday part,
I think she was like 80 and it was a
white family there.
And I was like,
who are these people?
And their,
my family.
That's the family that's your
grandmother helped used to nanny for and
they remained close because of,
you know,
uh,
she helped raise these young ladies,
you know what I mean?
Man,
they fly,
my mom,
my grandmother out to philly to spend
time with them and stuff like that.
Uh,
and it's,
uh,
it's an interesting,
you know,
situation.
So,
uh,
just to hear these stories and you know,
my grandmother telling me about when the
cotton gin and she broke it down like,
yeah,
we'll tape the cotton and take the seeds
out and let it go.
And people are amazed by this.
They just watching it like,
whoa.
Like that was the thing that people
looked at,
like how people look at computers.
Like,
oh man,
what are we going to do now?
The napster revelation.
Yeah.
Like,
whoa,
what are we gonna do for her?
This thing is here to put us out of
work.
And you know how people would do a day's
work and got to,
like she said,
once slavery in it and people had to get
paid how somebody,
I don't know if it was a father or
somebody dealing with a job and they
gave him a dime,
you know?
Wow.
So now you're not getting lodging or
food or nothing like that and you got to
earn a wage and you get like a dime,
like doing like some heavy,
you know,
things.
And who this is blowing my mind amongst
everything else that's going on
in the world,
you know,
you know what's crazy,
that person living that life and making
a dime and living in a modern semi
modern to us,
you know,
modern in
its context,
society is doing so much better than
someone who was born 200 years before
that.
Yeah.
And so much better than someone,
you know,
any anytime prior to that.
So check this out.
My grandmother's 90.
So the women on her side.
Okay.
Family along longer.
My mother,
my grandmother,
his mother died at 107.
So between them two,
you got over,
you know,
you got like over 200 years.
That's incredible.
So,
uh,
it's just an interesting
timeframe,
you know,
when you,
when we look back at people that lived
like a couple of hundred years ago,
we think to ourselves like,
fuck that,
you know,
especially if you were a slave or if
like,
if he would,
if you were a free person living in
America in 18,
10,
let's just go to 18,
just a regular person like you.
And I don't want to do that.
You don't want to go back to that
fucking life.
Like,
good lord,
good luck getting fresh milk.
Good luck finding vegetables.
Uh,
in most cities,
like good luck getting everything
delivered to you.
They didn't even have cars yet.
Ah
man,
this is a good thing.
I,
since I lived,
I was born in athens.
My first six years in athens is a small
town with uga is even athens before.
So everything I ate vegetable wise was
grown,
you know,
in that area,
in the yard,
in the backyard.
That's amazing there.
The grapes on the vine,
the tomatoes came out the ground,
the chickens,
you know,
my grandfather haul chicken.
So the chicken,
the a's came out of the backyard.
He shot there,
we fished on saturdays for cut the fish,
here's off,
get the skin off and they're from in the
yard.
He took the grapes from the vines and
made wine and if he caught an abundance
of fish,
he will keep enough for her family and
all the neighbors traded food.
So my first six years is like,
when you know,
when you,
eight or 10,
they put a pellet gun in your hand,
you work your way up to a hunting
rifles.
Um,
so that's what I left when I moved to
the city.
That's interesting.
So I was a country,
so vegetables and everything tasted
good,
you know,
you get the corn off the stalk and then
grandma and corn was yellow.
It was like a lighter color.
It was like a whitish color.
She make cream corn from scratch.
Um,
the preserves,
it was jelly was made.
Uh,
the rabbits squirrel,
the pks fell out of the tree.
You can third,
you hungry.
You just go outside at any time and grab
food,
grab two peanuts,
squeezing with your hand.
You got a snack,
you know,
and that's,
that was the first,
like six years,
like food was there things you put them,
you get a bucket,
you opened them.
He used to run your thumb,
thumb through them,
which I didn't like none of that,
but that's what,
that's what it was.
Well there's something beautiful about
that right?
At this point.
Yeah.
At this point,
because they overcharge them for that
stuff now,
but for
them it is not easy,
but it looked.
They made it look easy.
Well,
it's large scale.
Everybody could do it like that.
You'd have to have small populations of
people with good pieces of land.
Like you know,
I'm sure your grandfather had to have
some.
My grandfather had a similar situation
in New Jersey.
He had a pretty good sized backyard.
It was all garden.
He had his area where he would drive to
his driveway and then everything to the
right of the driveway was all sticks in
the ground and tomato plants and my
grandfather grew everything and they
turned their tomatoes into tomato sauce
and my grandmother made homemade tomato
sauce and like all of his vegetables,
he would grow.
Everything that he would eat all year
would be like in that garden.
That's a.
That was a normal thing for the
immigrants,
you know,
for people who grew,
who came here from other parts of the
world where you know,
you had to have a supply of food,
which is true.
I mean,
it only makes sense.
We figured out a way to truck things in.
People have,
you know,
once we start tracking things in,
nobody grows anything anymore.
I heard a story about people like my
uncle and his friend I have in money and
they put $300 together and bought a goat
and ate off that goat.
You know?
Smart.
Yeah.
They faded a little bit and then they
ate off of it for like a month.
Yeah.
If you,
if you kill a goat in your yard though,
when people find out about it,
this is my friend used to say his name,
but my gardener guy that I was talking
about earlier,
he had,
well his name's jose.
It's not like you don't know.
You don't know which jose it is.
I don't want to give away his identity.
Probably jose conseco,
but this,
uh,
he uh,
he got a goat and uh,
him and his,
uh,
his friends killed it in the yard and
butchered it.
And then they had a cookout and the
neighbor complained apparently,
and he didn't understand.
He was like,
what do you like?
What's bothering you about this?
Like,
what is he didn't like?
He literally didn't understand.
He's like,
it's safe.
It's healthy.
Like this is an animal.
I know,
I know where that the meat coming from,
you know,
he's trying to explain this to me in his
broken english.
He's like,
I know where this animals meat comes
from.
Like why would anybody have a problem
with that?
If you buy meat yourself,
I don't know,
like he didn't understand,
you know,
he came from Mexico.
He did just did not understand why
someone would have a problem with him
killing a goat and a yard.
Like course I killed the goat in the
yard.
What do you want me to kill a kid?
It didn't make sense to him.
They're like,
you can't kill a goat in the yard.
He's like,
where the fuck do you kill your goat?
And like,
you don't kill your kid.
Strange like,
well what do you get your meat?
You go to the store.
He's like,
well,
you don't know where that fucking meat
even came for his idea.
That was alien.
It's the logic is man of how things
happen.
I'm too weird.
And you're like,
yeah,
if you talk to older people,
you understand struggle.
You know what people actually went
through and on a good part,
like my grandma taught me about the
first dryers.
Yeah.
And my grandma like,
no,
don't use it once a month.
Once a month.
Yeah,
don't because they,
you know this better.
The of lennon in the sun.
It still better to dry your clothes in
the sun because the sun kills bacteria.
Really?
That's why you will.
If you look at how to tie them and they
say,
how do you take care of denim and keeps
it from fading,
they'd be like it and hanging in the sun
because the sun kills the bacteria that
gets rid of the smell.
But when I'm in jeans fade because of,
because of the now you want to clean
your genes because it might get smells
and the like.
When you break it in jeans,
you really don't watch him like that.
You know you were.
I'm just like everyday type stuff and
the dye in the denim fades and it at the
cotton shrinks and all that bullshit.
So hang them in the sun,
you know,
to keep it from shrinking.
That keep them from shrinking.
And it was heat though.
That was just the water.
And then the evaporation from the
extreme heat,
extreme dryer,
that's what makes them shrink.
Right?
But if you hang it in the sun,
you're still.
The sun still kills some of the bacteria
and stuff and it makes sense.
But if you ever drive,
if you ever like,
we don't do it here,
but I did something.
I had to stay in the country home and
you watch like a sheet or a shirt and
you hang out in the sun and with the air
hit it and it just the freshness of the
smell,
you know,
and what was smart about this place,
they put the lemon trees near the
hanging place.
So now you're close to the city.
A lemon smell to it.
Right?
Because the wind that comes through.
That make sense?
Yeah,
it does actually make sense.
But if you're in a city and it's
polluted,
that's different.
That's different.
Yeah.
You're
clothes might smell funky.
Like that's the weirdest thing to me is
when people are around people who smoke
cigarettes,
how strong the smell is in there.
Close.
Strong.
Like I never realized it until I would
come home from back when you could smoke
in clubs.
It was a big thing.
Comedy clubs,
man.
I mean everybody smoked.
It was just constantly.
We'd go to a bar,
everybody smoked,
you would go to comedy clubs.
Everybody smoked and I remember not
realizing when I smelled like and then
taking a shower and then picking up my
clothes and be like,
what the fuck?
Like they stunk.
It's smells bad.
That is a weird thing,
man,
that people have something that gives
him cancer.
It makes everyone around them stink.
Like not even me.
I wasn't even smoking,
but being around those people made me
stink and people like,
who cares?
I need my smokes.
I used to smell like gasoline when I had
the nine,
four it because they had a hairline
crack in the gas tank,
so if you fill it all the way up to the
funerals that get in the car.
My barracuda,
I used to have to drive with him
window open,
fucking terrible smoke and fumes and
shit.
We're getting that car.
Worst smell.
I remember the gasoline smell.
I remember that car and I met in that
stu about that car and you really broke
it down kinda with and they're like,
oh,
this is a real old school car.
Like the problems that people I know
have an old schools.
They car was built to look great.
That was a problem with the suspension,
the setup and everything was very low.
She was very low to the ground because
it was so low to the ground and bottom
out on things.
Yeah,
it wasn't,
it didn't handle very well because it
wasn't designed for that.
It was just designed to be like a really
low car,
like it was tubbed.
So the back,
the back area where the backseat is,
was all cut out and then the frame was
welded and bent up so that the wheel
tuck deep back wheel.
Well,
it looks great.
I seen him as stupid as fuck.
I watched the being made.
Uh,
and um,
you know,
I learned with my friends who got old
school cars.
Once you've started,
you just can't modify.
One thing was certain cars,
you know,
especially when it comes to suspension
and wheels and not doing the brakes.
Well,
you know what they do now,
it's really interesting.
They do these different companies have
suspensions and frames that they build
for these old cars.
Yeah.
That's one of the problems with those
old cars.
You're like the suspension and the
frames are just,
it's so whack,
which don't have fully independent
suspension there.
The way it's all set up is so old
school,
so they have some upgrades and that can
definitely enhance the way these cars
perform,
but now they do say certain companies
like art morrison,
they take a suspension and they build a
frame and it's like say if you're going
to build like a 1969 mustang,
they would build a frame and suspension
for the [inaudible] 69 mustang,
and then you take the old body and you
bolted down to this modern frame
suspension.
You have a car that performs infinitely
credits and the original car,
it's going to be waste,
stiffer,
it's way better designed,
and then they have all these suspension
improvements.
Now they've figured out a way to make
suspensions that adjust the way on
modern car does.
So it just constantly like thousands of
times a second.
So if you're driving a car,
like if you say like you get a brand new
bmw seven series,
yeah,
those things are smooth as a baby's ass.
Just whooo.
So comfortable with that.
And one of the reasons why they're so
comfortable is there,
the suspension is constantly adjusting.
It's constantly adjusting to whether
it's bumpy outside are smooth and every
bump that it hits it calibrates what it
needs to do to adjust for this impact.
And you get this incredibly stabilized,
right?
I'm doing a shitty job of explain.
There's a lot of people right now,
there's car experts like you don't know
who to go.
Cars that make sense.
I know enough to kind of butchered that,
but this,
uh,
they know now they know how to do that
with old school cars so they can take
that 1969 mustang and put a similar type
of computerized suspension arrangement
in it where it's constantly adjusting to
the,
um,
the terrain.
They're also figuring out how to do
antilock brakes on old cars.
They haven't figured out that totally
yet.
That's a little bit of a struggle.
My,
a friend of mine,
he,
he bills and sell cars,
but he knows exactly which ones he
liked.
Like the 71 chevelle.
Oh yeah.
He had the 68 colbert,
which I drove,
and that was two cars and scary.
I drove the 68 cobra mustang.
He put 10,000 into the motor and it was
like over 500 horses and if it,
if it rained a little bit,
yeah.
Uh,
for me it had a kenny bail blower on it.
Oh god.
And that was my first experience with a
supercharger and how hype they are
[inaudible].
It's like you could lose control of that
car.
Easy.
And a viper or jews.
Yeah.
I drove a viper before I drove one of
those ones and a rented one.
I have valet.
I got lucky and just an idol.
That call goes.
It just goes.
Oh yeah.
Well you've seen the new ones.
Yeah,
they have a poll is up.
They have this new viper viper ar
something I think it's called.
I think that's what it's called,
attack that attack mode.
This thing is fucking insane.
It's basically a race car that you could
buy,
but what they're doing with these vipers
is that bringing them to these race
cars,
these race tracks,
and it just breaks every record,
every race,
every race track.
They take it on this thing break,
right?
Breaks records,
and it looks ridiculous.
Even the curves straight away.
Oh fuck you.
At curves.
It's got giant tires on it.
The tires are super wide and it's got
more than 600 horsepower.
What is it called?
Jimmy acr.
Acr.
That's it.
Easier.
You've got to look at this thing.
The deep bevels in the hood.
Look at that face.
Get the fuck outta here.
You kidding me?
It's supposed to be just a fucking
preposterous automobile and you could
buy that at a store.
I mean,
it has ground effects that come right
out of a race car,
but this thing is insane.
When people,
uh,
review it when the review and that's
like you independent canyon going
sideways when that far it was just a
little bit,
you know,
if you're going to love it,
it's just,
that's just long enough.
Yes.
Less than a second is long enough for
fun.
Yeah.
To,
you know,
it's a great road.
Keep placing more.
That shit.
Don't shut it off.
You know,
it's a great road to go to.
There's a road off of um,
the to chris.
Chris.
Yeah.
The,
I know what you're talking about.
I don't know the name of it.
It's a road off the two,
but it's like if you take the 2:10 and
uh,
you head towards pasadena and you go up
into the mountains.
Yeah.
You know,
there's this crazy abandoned roads where
you might not have anybody out there
except maybe like a dude on a motorcycle
and everything's like turning and
twisty.
They do a lot of testing out there.
If you go out,
they'll use like mules,
like a car that uh,
they cover,
like they would take this car and then
they would cover it over with like
graphics,
even some plastic or something.
So you couldn't tell what it looked
like.
I've seen that before.
It's kind of dope.
Look at that thing.
Jesus christ.
Yeah.
They trying to get me to go up to
somebody trying to get me to go up to
the chris highway up there off the two
of them are fun.
You should go up there,
go up there with your card because you
don't even have to drive fast.
I have a good time up there,
but I don't drive on any of them.
If there's a car in front of me,
I might slow up and wait for it to go
by,
but I'm doing like 40,
40,
which is a lot.
That's down.
That's downloadable for what'd you post
to do with a car like this?
You wouldn't be doing that.
You'd be going a lot faster.
That's the problem with these cars as
opposed to like an old car.
Like say if you got like an old bmw.
You know what?
I really like those.
I love those.
They're cool man.
Yeah man.
And their little boxy and.
But when you drive those things,
apparently you feel everything.
They're so small.
I'll see this.
See if you could pull up the smoking
tire two.
Oh,
oh two.
Um,
he uh,
some dude had a souped up one and then
not even souped up like you put a giant
engine and it was just like a really
well done version of that engine,
but he's driving around in it.
I met matt before he comes.
Matt farah?
Yeah.
He couldn't come to the club is a big
comedy fan.
He's a good dude.
He's,
he's a real good dude and he fucking
loves cars.
So this is a give you some volume on
this.
This is a course.
He's.
What I really like about him too is he's
like a regular dude.
Like he's not trying to pretend to be
some super professional presenter.
He's just a guy who knows a fuck load
about cars and really loves them.
And look at this thing,
man.
What year is that,
jamie?
They build them up properly from what I
can see.
No,
no,
no.
That's the name of the car.
Jamie
[inaudible]
doesn't say what year I was running
into.
They've swapped the interior for this
luxe package,
which is only available in europe.
Let's scoot ahead so you can hear what
it feels like when he's driving.
This thing,
yeah,
here we go.
An interesting because on the one hand
it was sorta bmw's corporate engine at
the time,
but it actually the way up to and they
would use these seasoned m 10 blocks to
build their crazy turbo formula one
engines and there's a really neat
documentary about the history of
pedals.
See he's a.
That's what I'm saying.
This is a serious geek when it comes to
cars or really knows his shit though.
You know what I like when he's in the
car with a person who built the car much
time and money you put in.
I'm going to put all this time and his
money and his energy in it and he was
like,
that's you're not going to find another
car like this.
He was like,
we bought to drive it.
Then he'll take off like the brakes,
a little squishy and the suspension
little off,
but it's got a nice little pull to it.
Like he just started with this like just
disappeared off the title.
He is honest.
Honest jamie.
Sixty six to 77 dope little car man.
Well,
little fucking beer can though.
You know who I had a chance to pleasure
to meet and I used to have to try to.
I used to drive around downtown and by
nine and see if I can find it at night.
Magnus magnus.
Yeah.
I had the pleasure of meeting.
Somebody was trying to get rid of a nine
to eight and we went over there and he
showed us around.
Oh yeah.
No,
he's a real friendly guy here.
His place is amazing.
There's so many old porsches.
I think he's got like one,
two,
three,
four,
five,
six.
He's probably got at least 10 of them no
more.
I counted like 17 or 17 main room
and um,
he got some more like the 9,009 s nine,
nine,
14.
Oh,
it's kind a bunch of turbos to quite a
few turbos now.
He really got into a turbo phase where
he's buying those nine,
three zero turbos.
Yeah.
He's an interesting character man,
because his love of his crash.
You fucked.
Oh boom.
Did.
Yeah,
that was really dumb.
You got a little silly.
He plowed into the back or the side of
his car into the back of a giant.
It looks like a car carrier,
just that's why you're not supposed to
drive like that.
Byron.
It's not supposed to go sideways on
public roads.
It wasn't that I just,
I just my my ass with a little bit.
I called it.
His cars are all like pretty reasonably
horse powered up to magnus has cars,
like he doesn't have anything like
really crazy,
but a shark worst gave him one of their
cars to drive around for a little and a
shark works made 800 horsepower gt two
and magnus a painted it like a different
paint scheme.
You know,
he's a crazy paint schemes.
I got a picture with that one.
Oh,
the guy that was sitting outside?
Yeah.
I'm their scared the fuck out of me.
I drove that car of real scared the fuck
out of me.
It's one of the few cars where I drove
it once.
I was like,
eh,
I'm good.
Like this is too much,
but I see I see yours and I'm like,
I'm good on that.
I just want to stop,
you know,
I liked naturally aspirated because a
way of pools in the certain time.
It just was like taking like a nice
little breather in.
There.
It is right there.
Yeah.
I saw that.
The car,
that car is so fast,
it just doesn't even make any sense.
Downhill
with the gravity.
See he's um,
he's taken it around some corners here
is actually this exact same road where I
took it.
Oh,
I was there at this time.
I was there with them when they were
doing this.
But this car is too fast.
It's too fast.
I mean it's not maybe too fast for a
race car driver,
but too fast for a guy like me because
it just,
you don't like one of the cool things
about like that 2002.
As you get to ring the engine out,
there's a lot of range where you can
drive your rev it up and that's where
you get your power and you,
you can go plenty fast than it.
The handling of those cars.
A lot of times it's connected to the
lightness and the whole.
All the feel of the car is coming from
the fact that it's not,
there's not a lot there.
This car is a totally different
experience.
This car is like all about managing the
pedal because if you stomp on the pedal,
that fucking thing is going spinning.
It's way too powerful,
but you know,
it's one of those things where they keep
coming up with new and improved cars
every year.
Every year cars get faster and faster
and faster.
Especially performance cars.
They've broken the three second barrier.
A lot of cars you could buy today goes
zero to 60 in less than three seconds
to.
There's a gang of them.
I want to drive with gotti.
Fuck.
Was I going to sit in one?
Do not drive it with just sitting there.
That might as well be a spaceship.
The,
uh,
those neurons.
Yeah,
those are ridiculous.
The um,
yeah.
My homeboy he built,
he built this 69 shelby.
The 68 got damaged so the insurance had
to cut them a check and he spent that
money and built a 69,
69 that I haven't drove and he don't
drive it as much because it's worth a
lot of money.
Look at that 1000,
200 horsepower.
That's a lot.
That's ridiculous.
That's a ridiculous car.
I saw one of those the other day in
beverly hills.
Some was,
it wasn't the,
uh,
the,
the yellow,
the yellow and black one.
I'm.
No.
What color was it?
I don't remember what color.
I want to say it was white,
but it had arab license plates on it,
which is really interesting.
They're getting these cars and these
super rich dudes from Saudi Arabia,
they bring them over for saudi summer.
See,
that's what's going on right now.
Where we are is hot as fuck.
Where they live.
It's crazy way on where they live is
like 150 fucking degrees or something
nutty.
And so they come over here when they've
got crazy oil money,
they come over here and they bring that.
They bring these cars with their plates
that are registered to those other
places and they drive them around and
they get away with it because they're
super rich like is nothing dude.
Did you see that shit that happened
where these guys were racing in beverly
hills?
There were racing with a ferrari and a
gt three,
a porsche gt three and they were fucking
racing on a residential street in
beverly hills just
flying through fucking red lights and
the neighbors saw them do it.
So the neighbors all we're fucking
furious.
They're all standing outside on their
street,
holding up their cameras
and filming these guys right here it is
right here.
This guy has got them oats of ferrari.
It looks like.
I don't know which version,
but then the,
the gt three.
I mean these guys are a full lying down
residential roads.
You got two things run at the same time,
buddy.
You got two windows running.
But I'm so while while these guys are
doing this,
the neighbors are aware of it.
So they start
filming because it probably do.
See you look at it,
see everybody.
And then.
So this car fucking started smoking
guys,
engine started smoking and he pulled it
into his driveway.
But look at everybody standing out here
with their fucking cameras.
They'll realize like,
oh my god,
this guy's a piece of shit.
No one cop insight.
That's crazy to me.
But it's so funny.
Everybody's like,
world's school of course going to blow
up.
Everybody's assuming that car's gonna
explode.
So they're filming it.
So this guy was driving his car so fast
and so hard that it caught on fire.
So I'll never buy a fucking ferrari by
the way,
are people should not be designing
things.
I saw I a,
a solid nine.
18 that with the dubai plates on it.
They had the nerve to put the silver
metallic paint on it.
So not only bought expensive car,
they put the real.
What made the car look chrome?
Oh,
I've seen that.
Justin bieber had one of those chrome
fisker.
How do I know that?
Why?
Because I'm friends with jamie.
Jamie tells me these things.
The cops in shout out to the cops in the
beverly hills because they nice.
You know,
I was coming through the apart,
fell off my,
my,
my pores that holds the alternator and
the,
and the serpentine belt together.
So the car was just lose power.
Right.
So I'm running through beverly hills.
I was going to the summit a,
the is a place on mulholland drive.
I was standing there and I'm,
I'm in beverly hills with no lights on,
just driving up the street and the cops
pull us over and I turn off the car,
can't turn off the car.
Well,
not because it's not going to come back
home.
I turn it off.
They was like,
what?
Let me explain to you what's going on,
is a piece of mail.
Tried to explain to them the mechanics.
They was like,
nah.
I was like,
I get out the car and you can do
whatever you need to do with this car
because I'll here,
it's going to be here.
And uh,
I had my,
my african homeboy who I just want to
try with me all right.
And he's like,
hey officer,
what's going on?
He's not going to show you how powerful
this thing is that I do.
And he's like,
look,
I'll work for the artists a lot of guff
from visiting from Washington dc.
I worked for the national government.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
He's like,
I got the irs notice saying that they
should have shot them onsite so
everybody's afraid of the irs,
the terrify,
pull the bags out,
yada yada,
yada.
And then he was like,
okay,
you're free to go.
And then I was in somebody's shrubs and
uh,
you know,
there was a cop right there.
He was like,
sorry,
you don't have to be so close and like
in the bushes.
And I remember looking at him,
but sometimes it's fun having your face
in the bush.
And I smiled and he was just like,
he's like,
just step away.
They
get my jokes,
you know what I mean?
Well,
there's tents been a.
So the pulling people over no lights
that say they can't shut their car off.
They don't know what kind of crazy shit
you're doing.
Yeah,
that's true.
I mean,
you pull up to a dude,
there's two dudes.
One of them's from the,
from africa who works for the irs.
The other one's a comedian with some
weird jokes.
Their cars running,
they can't,
they can't shut the car off.
Something to talk about it.
Right.
But a lot of shit could be going on
here.
Like whenever you deal with someone who
won't,
they don't have their lifetime.
That's weird.
Like,
okay,
why is this guy not as full time?
And then you deal with another thing.
You won't show this car off.
What,
what?
What's going on?
Like there's a bunch of shit that
supposed to happen.
One,
you're supposed to have your lifetime to
get pulled over.
Shut your car off.
You show your id.
Everything is supposed to go according
to plan.
So you're throwing in all these new
poles.
So the improv game,
we're doing no lights.
Okay.
Why don't you have lights?
I can't.
Doesn't work.
Altair got an issue.
Alright.
Shut your car off.
I can't shut the car off.
Stays here.
I'm gonna.
Tell you it's is true stuff.
When I moved in,
I had a honda prelude.
I put a time of building it.
Fourth generation drove here.
I used to get pulled over all the time.
Black on black.
I,
I lived in inglewood and I realized like
all the time I get my car search put in
the back of police cars and I talked to
a cop and he told me about proximity and
how criminals operate and when they wake
up they get descriptions in the morning
and if you fit that description they
going to profile you and that's when I
realized like,
oh,
I'm living in the wrong neighborhood
driving the wrong vehicle.
So when I got denied for four,
I get what I call corporate old white
man colors that champagne or that boring
gray and I just drive and now I have
really no problems.
You know what I mean?
That's what I,
that's the thing.
It's like how my mind works sometimes to
figure out that pattern and be like,
okay,
this is what it's getting pulled over
and stuff.
Then I need to,
you know,
I don't know if it's the survival in
your way,
but it's like I have to shift and some
people real.
I'd be like,
I don't feel like I should shift like
that,
but I'm like,
you know,
the cops,
the cops will be like,
slow down.
I've messed up in the.
I was doing 60 on franklin one time just
enjoying my life
because white women jogging and
everything and the street.
I'm like,
this ain't bad,
you know,
life is great.
I tell jokes and the cops were just
like,
sir,
you slow down.
And I remember putting my hand out the
window,
like no problem officer.
Then that was it and I was like,
this is amazing right here.
But I also experienced another white
privilege thing when I had an.
I had an accident in the nine,
four,
four and it was a latino people and the
guy got out of the car.
The cops showed up and I was sitting on
the car,
the old white guy,
sir,
is this your car?
And I was like,
yes sir.
He was like,
okay,
everything is gonna be okay.
And then he went.
He lit into the mess and people to where
I got uncomfortable for a while.
I almost said something to yelling at
the mexican people assuming this ain't
regulation and where the paperwork for
this and asking them all the time,
let me see your id.
When did you get this?
And and me coming from Georgia,
not using.
I'm used to seeing black people treat
it,
but no other culture,
so to.
I almost stepped in but something was
like hold on,
don't.
And I swim sitting on the car like damn,
feeling guilty.
Like this was white,
white guilt feels like,
but I'm still on the other side.
Right.
So I'm just letting it ride.
Like,
you know,
that's funny,
but like I said before,
it's like when you in that place where
you see different stuff,
it's shapes you.
Somehow it gets that understanding.
I think with a lot of cops,
something can happen to where they pull
over so many people that are illegal
immigrants.
They start getting upset and start
getting upset of that and they treat it
like disproportionately.
You know?
I've seen a lot of fucking people that
are driving illegally in los angeles
truth.
I got rear ended by a dude.
That's right.
I remember that there was no driver's
license,
but I know a lot of white people who
were driving illegally.
They don't worry about it.
Nothing happens.
But you do.
If you get pulled over though,
if they find that if a cop finds out,
you're driving illegally,
you're in trouble.
Yeah,
for sure.
Everybody,
no matter who you are,
they'll tell your car,
but the odds are you're getting pulled
over.
It's kind of slim.
Um,
um,
yes.
The odds are greater if you are black or
if you're mexican of getting pulled
over.
I would say that probably,
definitely true.
Cut the me getting out the car like this
and was like,
no,
not you.
And you're like,
oh,
I was just stretching,
you know.
Yeah.
But you know this,
it's what it is to me.
You know what I mean?
I wouldn't want to be a fucking cop.
Oh no,
no.
I think me honestly,
I think that their job is to nurture to
nerveracking for the regular person.
And I think so too.
And they don't make enough money to go
through the mental part of it.
Exactly.
To affect their relationships and their
family.
Life.
Suicides.
Yeah.
The cops commit suicide.
Lots of cops feel despair.
It's a crazy job.
This is a crazy job,
you know?
Yeah.
Like,
yeah,
they got to go.
Like I said,
I got to go.
They got a reputation.
Cops have almost a reputation now of a,
of a black man to act like they,
like people look at them like prejudice
against.
Yeah.
And it's like,
oh,
to me it's like,
oh shit,
truths.
Ironic.
Um,
and they have to go in those situations.
They have to go to the hood with that
reputation.
Yup.
And that's outfit on.
And that's a scary thing.
You know what I mean?
If your outfit is being represented by
people that do and fucked up things like
those videos that we were talking about
earlier,
that's your outfit,
that's the team you're on.
So you have to go and you know that
these people are gonna see you and
looking at you and know that you
represent that team,
that they've been watching all these
videos.
And I'm from a place where the cops
looked like said the cops,
they treated you fucked up like,
oh,
they were dirty.
So it's a different ballgame.
You know what I mean?
Yeah.
Um,
but that's what it is.
It's so much that isn't understood
outside of the videos that are being.
Do you think there's a way on stage that
you can relay a lot of this stuff that
you're talking about?
Say I feel like,
um,
if you could figure out a way to make
humor out of the difference between your
background growing up and what you're
experiencing now and you just,
you're on your own unique perspective.
Yeah,
I'm talking,
I'm slowly talking about it.
Yeah,
you can ask.
Touch.
When I worked with tosh,
my opening jail,
I walk on stage and be like,
not all black lives matter.
Some niggas should die and that's a
shot.
Just 30 seconds.
I will get applause break in 30 seconds
at the,
at the tense time or that.
And by that I'm telling them,
I explained the story of the protests
when traffic is being held up and I'm
driving with my gas light on.
Yeah,
and I'm like,
this don't if this,
my car dies,
I'm a hostage in a situation I don't
want to be in.
And then feeling sorry for that black
guy who's stuck in traffic and don't
know why.
And every white person looking at him
and he liked this ain't got nothing to
do with me.
I'm just on my way to owners counties.
I can fuck this white girl.
That was the bit,
but all of it's based on truth.
But you know what I mean,
on truth,
I felt like when those black lives
matter protesters were shutting down
highways,
I'm like fucking white people.
It was white people that are trying too
hard to be dealt with.
Black lives matters.
So they took it to the highway and shut
down the highway.
So I knew this one dude is like a super,
super lefty guy and he uh,
he was a part of the black lives matter
shutting down highways and I was like,
what are you doing man out in berkeley?
But super,
super liberal,
crazy people.
It is a hierarchy of black people just
like a of white people.
And me and jim martin neighbors,
we say some shit like real niggas don't
give a fuck about black issues.
It's just true because their survival
mode,
you know what I mean?
You know,
so things like,
you know,
education and shit like that don't
really matter who leaving to me.
I didn't talk about politics going on.
So I really don't care about politics.
That's how I feel about it.
Like I still got to grind either way.
Do you care at all?
Like when you,
when you're looking at hillary clinton
and Donald Trump,
like what's your thought?
You just don't think about things.
I think,
and I said this before,
before everything got crazy.
Trump got crazy.
Uh,
I understand sometimes where he's coming
from through educational purposes.
I understand republican mindset,
you know what I mean?
Because that was taught to export
businesses and stuff like that.
You know,
all that makes sense to me.
But I don't think.
I think this part is for ratings.
I see it as a show and I think,
I think trump is like a,
uh,
a character.
Uh,
definitely they want everybody to vote
for hillary.
I think they're gonna lead people that
way,
like you leave water to go down a
certain ravine and then hillary is gonna
make a because their personality and the
best,
like it ain't like a barack obama people
be like,
oh,
like this lady.
But I think once you get in,
she'd been to kind of personnel is
terrible.
Well,
you know,
I think she's going to make some
adjustments on the low that's going to
really fuck up people.
She does things that make me super
nervous to sing.
Have you ever see the video of her?
Was she was talking about uh,
uh,
gaddafi.
She,
she's,
she was laughing about how uh,
she,
I think she says we came,
we saw he died and it was like off
camera and like she,
I don't think she realized that she was
being filmed or this is just not her
behaving like I'm gonna play it for you.
This came,
we saw he died.
Yes,
we came,
we saw he died.
What
is basically she's also looking off at
someone else,
like for their approval when looking at
the woman she's talking to necessarily.
It's just,
that's so weird thing to joke about,
the enormity,
the magnitude of assassinating a foreign
leader,
whether he's a dictator,
dictator or not,
like there's a lot going on there you
are overthrowing the ruler of a
government even though it was a terrible
reader and you are now opening up that
government and those people that were
being suppressed by that car,
you were opening them up to the turmoil
of establishing a new leader.
That's true.
And that's where it is right now.
So when you see someone who is running
for president and they are joking around
about a scenario that has taken place
that they were a part of,
she was a part of.
And that scenario is now directly
connected to horrific tragedies and this
chaos that,
that is an isis stronghold.
Now,
Libya is nicest store.
So I,
uh,
that,
that sits in that living situation isn't
the.
Yeah.
Okay.
This goes on Libya.
Yeah.
Well,
it's none.
None of those things are good.
You know,
whenever you have a brutal dictator like
Iraq,
saddam hussein,
it's not good when the world is
entertaining.
Brutal dictators is a brutal dictator
that's in charge of these people.
They're,
they're,
you know,
it's not,
it's not fair is dangerous and we have
to interact with this person in some
way.
I love a country where there's a curfew
and I'm thinking that's going to happen
here,
but I just love a country
where the public has a curfew for women
at a certain time and they will.
If a chick was out by myself,
they just put a straight into van.
Yeah.
And if the republicans and if a dude was
out and his lights wasn't right or he's
on a motorbike,
the cop got on the bike with him and
rolling with it.
The jail,
he had to take the copper jail.
Whoa.
Uh,
so yeah,
it's certain things like,
you know,
that it's like,
wow,
that I,
that I see like it happened here.
And as far as that video,
to me that's how people power act.
When I say like real,
like rich and successful,
powerful people like and poor people.
I always tell people they don't give a
fuck the people in the middle of all the
ones that's timid and like,
we should do this for animals in that,
but those people and poor people like
you listened to that jokes.
They don't give a fuck.
Just like guys I met,
we talked about man,
I shot three times,
man,
I shot the first time they go through,
he started hobbling.
I was like,
oh shit.
And the gun jammed.
I got nervous.
Like these are the stories.
So I had the ability to sit with both
and just the,
the,
and it ain't,
it ain't my comedy is based off this
too.
So I got to be like one of these people
to talking to some of these murders,
someone with a gun.
It's laughing and joking around about
it.
It's got to be fucked up,
but it's like this guy didn't die but he
did get hit,
you know,
but you hear it's like somebody telling
his story and they tell him how bad it
was because you know,
they live,
they live it and it was over something
simple.
Like I told you next time I see you that
this was going to go down,
you know what I mean?
And it just went down,
you know,
over something simple.
But I always say like the people like
that at the top when people at the
bottom don't give a fuck and that's.
And if you look at the politics and now
you got trump and you got to support it.
The redneck shit that people say they
don't like those top and bottom people
that pattern wise.
Um,
but I think yeah,
hillary get in,
I think they're trying to lose everybody
the whole way and then she's gone on the
low side,
some document that's really gonna fuck
people up down the line.
Those are my predictions.
Why do you think she's going to do that?
You know how you find that outfit?
Why?
You know,
how you found out later on?
Like,
oh man,
that document,
that president signed three years ago.
Fuck people up,
right?
Oh yeah.
You know what I mean?
It was a lot of the us.
Yeah.
So I think it's going to be something
like that.
Well,
she's gotten away with so much already.
That's what I'm saying.
She's gotten away with so much already.
The idea that she's gonna stop once you
get to the office is ridiculous because
she broke so many fucking laws where
their email server,
all the lies that she told about bengazi
all throughout her career.
There's like,
there's many websites document all the
time.
They've caught her lying about like
pretty important issues.
The idea that she's going to stop doing
that once she becomes president.
It's crazy.
She's gotten away with it.
She lies when she talks about getting
caught in lies like what?
You talked about the fbi.
I'm having this long interview with her
about her email server.
There's a direct video
that shows like the direct comparison
between what she said and what he said,
what she said and when he said it's
horrible.
It's horrible to watch.
Like how is this person even qualified
to run for office?
Forget about the fact that everybody
wants a woman to be the the new
president.
I get it.
Yeah.
That'd be fun for everybody.
Yeah,
let's,
let's do this.
The one,
six months to that new car smell gone,
but this is,
she's not the one.
This is not the one you don't want.
I mean,
the only thing good is that she's a
longterm politician,
so she understands the business.
The only thing bad is that she's a
longterm politician.
She knows the business.
So the both things.
She knows the business sucks and people
don't understand it as a business.
You know what I mean?
They are mostly caught up in it.
Exactly.
But I definitely think,
I think people like we all should,
we could find a better way to do things
better.
I'm hoping and not put power and like
church and government and these things.
It's just hard.
It's got such a stranglehold.
Yeah.
The idea that you have to register as
either a democrat or republican to vote
in the primaries,
the primaries decide which candidate is
going to represent these parties.
It's a show rate.
It's never been more obvious.
So that's a charade.
And I fully never learned learned it
because I look at the bigger picture and
the pattern.
So,
you know,
um,
well byron,
we're going to come back
four years and we'll see if you're right
about hillary clinton if she fucked up
because you don't remember just a little
while ago,
everybody was saying that,
that,
uh,
hillary clinton,
that the fbi was going to drop some
bombshell and that more information was
going to come out about the horrible
things that she's involved with and
she's done and then she's going to
probably be indicted and then she's
gonna wind up pulling out and she's not
going to be running for president.
That was like the big rumors just a few
months ago now.
Trump has gotten so fucked up.
He's done so much stupid shit and said
so much stupid shit.
Then now,
like the harvard republican club for the
first time in over a hundred years is
coming out against the nominee.
The,
there's like a bunch of different
prominent politicians that have come out
against him.
Like you don't remember that.
Usually by the time someone gets to a
point where they're running for
president,
the republican nominee with mitt romney
or anyone else,
like they're kind of embraced,
you know,
like,
okay,
we've got the nominee,
everything's in order,
let's move forward.
That's not happening now.
Even even with the election just a
couple of months away,
people were freaking out and they got to
go.
We can't have this guy,
this guy can't be our guy.
Well,
what happened in dr.
They got a lady,
you know,
I'm in charge and it was some sneaky
stuff like that,
but when she got here,
she started doing the curfews and she
took the haitians and kicked them out.
You know,
she gave him to be fair.
She was like,
you got this amount of money,
you can stay a haitian church.
Yeah.
So it got in.
God was showing me scars that allowed
them to stay into in the dr.
So yeah,
it got real for me over there because I
finally talk to
these dudes that used to be kids asked
for money and now they adults asking for
money,
what's going on?
And they started breaking it down like,
yeah,
let's see.
A group of people just like kicked out
of a country like that.
And he's like,
man,
maybe we,
maybe we should be glad we're lost tribe
that could easily be,
you know,
it could always be worse for sure.
Yeah.
And they look up to us and he was like,
you know,
it was like,
regardless of what's happening,
and I know this guy,
I know black people getting killed by
the cops,
but you still got a chance to be
something.
And I couldn't even say nothing like me
while North Korea looks up to them.
North Korea,
you know,
at least they don't have to deal with
dear leader.
They don't have to cry for hours and
hours when his dad died,
if they don't cry correctly,
they get put in jail for six months and
forced to work in labor camps.
They have labor camps in North Korea
where people are literally starving to
death when they sick dogs on them and
the dogs eat them.
I mean,
this is game of thrones type shit and
it's going on right now.
This guy who he grew up in a slave camp,
he was a child of someone who was
convicted of some sort of a crime and
forced to work in these slave camps,
grew up in this camp,
did not know the rest of the world,
did not know that there was a whole
world out there and somehow or another
escaped,
but he talked about,
turned his own family in like they had,
um,
they have everybody narcan on.
Everybody turned his whole family and in
his description of the different levels
of torture and treatment,
like different levels of slavery,
what you're capable of doing when you're
almost dead,
what you're capable of doing.
Like they have it like classified,
like what jobs you get dependent upon
how close you are to death.
Fucking terrible man.
It's crazy.
Like,
you know,
you hear these stories,
you meet people that like one six
degrees away from that.
Yeah.
You know,
what's crazy is that it's 2016 and where
we're living here in los angeles,
this super progressive at the front line
of culture,
we feel like,
well,
hey,
everything's looking up.
Everything's getting great.
No,
I'm hearing no Korea.
You fucked up the world,
fucked you,
and you got you gotta.
This is where you.
You came out into the world.
That's your spot or Namibia.
What we're talking about before an inter
rainfall in three years you're like,
fuck thirsty,
fuck
you got all that koolaid and only the
interwar to come in.
If they even get koolaid to get going.
Now is that my mind processed,
starving.
That's a.
There's not a lot of food there.
All that peanut butter they're eating
and they can't
shoot animals and shit.
That's all I can do.
Byron bowers,
ladies and gentlemen.
Hey man.
Glad we did this experience.
It was cool.
And check out byron,
if you're ever in los angeles or if
you're ever anywhere he's performing.
He's fucking hilarious.
What's?
You got a website?
Byron bottles live.com.
A twitter facebook at byron bowers.
Snap byron bottles live instagram,
instagram,
byron bowers.
Love instagram.
All right,
beautiful.
Thank you.
Thanks brother.
It's been fun.
Yay.
Have a good whatever.