I need fear tactics.
This video will not get demonetized
watch.
We're getting demonetized.
What's happening?
Are we going,
Oh God,
this is so stressful.
What do you need?
The scare tactics because it takes me so
much.
So many threats,
uh,
in so much pain to change my habits.
But you're so self examined.
A Tory.
That's not the right word.
It's called neurotic.
But,
but that's not very nice synonym for it.
Thanks.
Were not getting anything done.
I would agree with you.
Oh,
interesting.
It's not paralyzing.
I do.
I,
I come from such a dysfunctional nine in
the word.
I feel like that's lost its value.
I come from a very sick family and I'm
very determined to not be sick,
so I'm trying hard to.
You get a lot of shit done.
See,
I don't,
I don't agree with this.
Like the,
the idea of paralyzing.
It may hinder in some way,
shape or form or caused obstacles when
you maneuver around those obstacles.
So I don't,
I don't agree with you.
It's tricky.
I mean,
how do you.
I definitely would say it would identify
as self analytical,
but like do you think that's part of
being a good comedian is being able to
analyze yourself and your neuroses and
you know for sure if you can't see
yourself,
it's going to be super hard to really
get other people to relate to you
because if there's some obvious blind
spots that they see that you're not
addressing,
it's my nightmare to not be self aware
and have everybody knows something about
me that I don't know.
I am in constant paranoia.
I mean,
and we know people that don't know
themselves and who they can't see
themselves and it seems real.
It terrifies me.
That's what bothers us about those
people.
It's not necessarily those people with
that knowing what it is is we're
terrified of seeing that in ourselves
100 percent because the antithesis of a
comedian as somebody who can't see the
truth and can't look in the mirror and
like that's my nightmare.
Well,
I think we all know and I think anybody
knows,
is trying to do anything.
Whatever you try and do when you're
trying to start a business or write a
book or what you just did.
Oh,
okay.
Bye.
Whatever you're doing,
whatever you're doing,
it's going to be.
It's going to test you.
Right.
And it's going to be difficult.
There's no,
no one is going to like get through it.
You know it all in one incredibly smooth
linear process.
It's going to be like weird shit that
happens on the way.
And when,
when you see someone who's not doing it
correctly in your eyes or not doing it
to the best of their abilities or
fucking off or being delusional,
it scares the shit out of him because
you're like,
God damn it.
That could be me.
I could lose a year of everything I've
been concentrating on to like deny.
I lived in denial I think for a long
time.
And um,
I was sort of like sleepwalking through
life and kind of like unconscious I
think for like a lot of my teens and
early twenties due to like some fucked
up shit that I saw and lived.
And it was all survival mechanisms,
but I just always want to make sure that
I've disarmed those and [inaudible] and
I'm not like just being a puppet of my
fear.
Right.
But I think like to give you more credit
than you give yourself,
I think that that self examine the
Tories,
self-reflecting aspect of it,
which seems to you to like this be as
constant self criticism is just almost
like a watcher.
I go watch her over your thoughts to
make sure have you keep this fucking
thing together.
You crazy bitch.
Come on.
Here we go.
But along the way I look all the things
you've accomplished.
So I don't think you've been.
I mean you haven't been impeded by it as
much as you've been aware of it.
Yeah,
that's the idea.
And I definitely think I need to start
there.
We live in this world of constant
feedback and I guess my thing is like,
I give myself enough feedback.
I don't also need your feedback with the
likes and the at replies and the trolls
and the reddits and the whatever.
So I think that that magnified it a
little bit.
And I had to do like a little bit of a
social media internet cleansing where I
didn't sort of constantly let go down
the wormhole of like people trashing
negative,
just good,
just as a matter of resources.
And if you 24 hours seems like a lot of
time until you start dissecting it into
the things you actually enjoy doing.
And how much time do you actually really
have with eating and sleeping and
traveling and commuting,
crying,
furious.
Punching the wall furiously.
Masturbating and crying.
And the tub.
What do you,
uh,
you know,
how much time do you really have law?
You've got to be careful with your time.
Yeah.
No,
I agree.
I'm pretty hardcore about protecting my
time.
I used to not be before,
before I got a handle on like my
codependence,
anyone who wanted to go on a fucking
hike.
I was at runyon every morning.
Everybody was getting coffee and I just,
I don't do that shit anymore.
That's like one of the biggest problems
with conspiracy theories.
One of the biggest problems with people
that get involved in conspiracy
theories.
They go,
you remember what the fuck is his name
that come in?
Who was,
um,
Kevin Costner.
Kevin goes to JFK movie.
Yeah.
Oliver Stone.
I wrote my seniors honors thesis on the
postmodern implications of JFK.
Did you really?
What do you think about jails cleared?
I don't have a ton of thoughts on like
I'm not an authority on it.
The movie is unbelievable.
I believe at the time it had the most
cuts of any movie and I was obsessed
with postmodernism at the time,
like Jean Baudrillard,
so I was like obsessed with him using
like archive footage and reenact of
footage and new footage and outfit and
just the way that he told the story was
brilliant.
I Dunno,
I think you mean jfk assassination was
actually thinking subject.
I'm,
I just in the last couple days got
annoyed at JFK as the president and he
was the most telegenic president and the
first televised president basically.
Right.
He kind of.
Well,
I definitely had been on tv that good
bunch of guys had been on tv,
but TV was a different thing in 1963
then it wasn't 53.
He was the first like star handsome.
He was the first president who was after
him.
Presidents had to start being handsome
and charismatic,
and I was just in some arguments this
week where people were like,
well,
Hillary just wasn't charismatic and I'm
like,
who fucking cares?
Like since when is that the number one
box that a president has to check?
Not qualified or like we can't match
the.
Yes we do.
We want cult leaders.
Well,
yeah,
we want someone that comes out of
nowhere that also doesn't want to fuck
all the time.
Correct.
We want someone that can figure it all
out and it has all of these key
attributes of a leader,
but we don't want that leader conquer
mindset.
Correct.
We want to have our cake and eat it too.
But,
but JFK was the first,
like handsome precedent for presidents
had to look healthy.
I don't want my president look healthy.
I want to be tired and anemic.
I don't want them to have been at
Martha's vineyard getting a Tan.
Can you imagine a time where we have a
president that everyone likes no means I
kind of amazing.
Yeah.
But that's just our tribalism,
right?
We're not really designed to live in
tribes over like 60 people.
Right.
This is all just madness.
Total madness.
We're not designed for it.
We're bad.
It's like.
But is it possible that someone can
achieve some sort of.
I mean even if you achieve some Martin
Luther King Jr state,
you know,
where you were,
that level of speaker in,
although you were a black guy,
you were so obviously super intelligent
and so spiritual that even racist had to
go make it.
A lot of good kids.
He's got a sexy guy.
His fucking way of speaking was so it
was like a song.
It was a,
it was like he had this,
it was almost like a,
sorry to denigrate Marlin by saying,
but he had the cadence of like a
comedian who was like in the rhythm,
like he was hypnotic in the way that he
spoke.
Oh yeah.
Do not judge a man by the color of his
skin,
but by the content of his character.
Like why?
Like how,
like where did that come from?
Preachers,
right?
Is that like Jensen?
You know,
it's like musical.
That was why kinison was so good.
Kinison was amazing.
Preacher.
He was one of those hell fire tent
preachers.
These,
there's video or at least audio,
maybe video as well of him doing a tent
revival and it's fucking incredible to
see that.
It's just all about the rhythm and the
Jesus,
but it's also just the electricity,
which is like,
you know,
people are always like,
how do I do comedy and how do we just
stand up?
Do I write jokes?
It's like,
yeah,
you can write jokes,
you can do this,
you can do 10,000
hours,
you can get whatever.
But like,
do you,
can you deliver electricity on demand?
I don't know how to teach you that.
You can't teach someone that know and
hit.
That's the thing about a guy like
Kennison too.
It's like what he was doing,
like,
you know,
he was talking about the power of the
Lord and the power of God and the power
of Jesus and say his name.
He stopped around on stage and you know,
and then that God,
God is alive.
And the thing is,
he was doing it so good that he was
right.
He was doing it so good that the people
who are watching got a feeling from it.
Like,
oh my God,
and maybe you and I are too skeptical.
Maybe.
Maybe we're fools because we can't just
give into it.
Maybe we're fools that we can't just sit
there and watch some guy go off.
Maybe we were fools that we don't just
speak in tongues.
Just let it all go.
I know it's.
I mean,
I'm too much of a fucking contract.
I'm just a science freak.
I'm like,
but what about I love the Lord.
But like are there some metrics to go
with that?
Something's happening.
Why are they getting so happy?
Obviously they're getting,
he's exciting.
He's inspiring them.
He's giving them some sort of almost
like mental placebo effect.
Yeah.
I really do feel like there.
I mean,
you really do get dopamine from someone
being a leader and taking charge.
So like just entertain the thought that
that's what God is a god is those
moments,
you know,
when they.
They're more and more extreme as we get
more and more evolved,
but those moments where people sort of
figured out and get together and lock on
whatever that energy is,
but sometimes they on and they decided
to kill Jews.
Yeah,
but they don't get together and look,
I have a good idea and it's a bad idea
and they all start locking on.
They don't do it on a post.
You can use it for evil or you can use
it for good.
I feel like.
Well definitely the whole biological
instinct of humans can go south.
They can get Western with people real
quick,
which is why people should be really
terrified of anybody who assumes any
sort of position of power.
Even the state itself.
Right?
That's what freaks me out of all these
people that want Marxism and socialism.
It's like you are.
You want to.
How much money do you want to give the
taxes?
Like you want people to pay 90 percent
taxes.
Do you understand that?
That means someone is getting that
money.
Do you understand that entity getting
that money?
The government is going to want more of
it.
They grow,
they just keep growing.
The only trick about that is like you're
so smart and you're like,
you the word understand it has no place
in people trying to feel safe.
Like we're just these visceral animals
who are just like,
am I safe?
Am I safe?
It was maybe like our brains are only
designed to keep us alive.
They're not designed to make us think
logically and you're not safe,
you know,
one safe,
you're safe right now.
We are a trash bag full of blood,
live texting and driving.
We are about to die every 20 minutes.
Make some good trash bags,
hefty law in there and shit.
We are,
uh,
I mean I can't,
but everyday I'm like,
how did I make it through?
How did I survive this day?
Why aren't I doing everything should
kill us.
I mean,
I think it was in that book Sapiens,
just the idea that like,
you know,
so much of our anxiety comes in the fact
that we all know that we're only
subconsciously at the top of the food
chain.
Like we should not be at the top of the
food chain.
It's only because we developed weapons,
like we know that at any point like we
deserve.
We deserve our life expectancy to be
like 16,
but I think developing the weapons is
also what led to us getting like this
here,
but we're so vulnerable,
but I'll think all this vulnerable stuff
came along with the advent of
inventions.
Yeah.
I think that when we.
Obviously I'm an idiot but don't listen
to me,
but I would think that when we didn't
have anything other than the other and
what will the animals had our instincts
clause and okay,
well we can't sleep outside overnight.
How long you're actually that whole
month person I know who could probably
live outside a site.
Anybody can do it,
but it's not good for Elon.
I mean we are not anymore,
right?
We're so infantilized at this point.
I think we're getting closer and closer
to those fucking gray aliens that you
see in the movies.
That's what we're going to be a giant
head,
little skinny arms and that's what those
things are where they have vintage
glasses on instead of black eyes.
It was a fucking great commercial.
I don't know what it's for,
but it's a hipster and Danny trio and
and Danny Trejo is a bartender and some
hipster is asking for like this custom
craft beer that's like leather but not
shoes like a belt and he's like going
through all this like hit woody earthy
like he's going through all different.
It's really funny.
Did a trio staring at him with his no
nonsense face dude.
The tattooed up Mexican towns.
I'm aware of that.
I know Danny Trejo.
It's fucking hilarious commercial.
I can finally talk about this,
but it took me getting my ear bitten off
by a dog to realize how fucking
vulnerable we are.
Oh yeah.
It happened.
I didn't eat.
I didn't see it come.
It just keep.
My ear was gone and it seems as a rescue
dog that you have a dog that I.
That was at the Carson shelter and was
about to be euthanized.
I just got.
I try to grab any dogs that's going to
be euthanized.
He came in.
He had been taken from his mother too
young.
He wasn't neutered,
didn't have spacial intelligence yet it
wasn't his fault.
He didn't attack me.
He was.
Their mouth is their hands and when
they're taken from their mother too
young,
they don't learn manners basically.
So I also made the mistake of not
establishing myself as the alpha.
I was just felt so sorry for him and I
pitied him instead of doing the right
thing,
like all my dogs,
I established myself as the alpha.
They're not allowed to lick me.
They're not allowed to jump on me and I
let him do that.
Then I pushed him off me and it's just,
you don't allow your dog to look your
jump on you sometimes,
but I have to end it before they end it,
but I genuinely.
I generally don't.
Wow.
That's deep.
It's not.
It's not ideal.
It's deep because every now and then you
do need them to really respect you when
a car is coming,
when they get out and it is a dominant
thing to lick you and to jump on you.
That's weird.
Why?
Because I never thought of that like
that.
But I do have these moments with my
puppy of a puppy.
I guess he's 10 months old now,
maybe 11 neuter,
not yet know.
And he's just a super sweetheart.
Super Sweet.
Golden,
right?
Yeah.
Just like humans and sometimes he
doesn't want to kiss me,
like sometimes shies away from kissing
me and then once he kisses me realize
that it's okay.
Then he kisses me a bunch and uh,
he's always,
he did climb on top of me except in a
submissive position and climbs on top of
me and lifts his arms up in the air so I
can rub his belly.
This is very good news.
So,
um,
when you make eye contact with him,
does he look away a little bit?
That's good.
That's what you want.
You want it.
So whenever I have to ascertain whether
a dog is dominant or not,
I look them in the eyes and if they
don't look away,
I have a dominant dog and that's a
problem.
So you have to do all these things.
You've got to like put them on their
back.
You gotta like hold them down until they
exhale.
That's a problem.
You don't,
you dogs.
Um,
when they don't have an Alpha,
they're designed to have a leader.
They love discipline and when they
don't,
it's just,
it's chaos and most people are not in
control of their animals.
Yeah,
that's interesting.
We do a lot of things like we make them
sit before he comes in the house and
it's going to stay with the door wide
open.
They love that.
Put his food out.
He has to stay,
walk through a dog.
You never walk around a dog.
Like if your dogs in front of you,
you walk right through them,
just bumped him.
You just get them out of the way because
that's,
you're in my house instead of I'm going
to walk around you.
That's interesting to other dogs.
A massive.
And uh,
I have a,
he's a sweetie too.
My kids ride them like you can ride him
like he's just like such a big teddy
bear.
I have a great day.
And pitbull who's like kind of looks
like Johnny cash is his name and he's
what's called a regency massive.
And the regency massive is half
Neapolitan.
Massive and half pit bull with a bread
for.
Oh,
if it has pitfalls.
And the guy who bread it was one of,
he had had dogs if you brought on fear
factor too,
and they used them as attack dogs and it
was fucking hilarious because we used to
have people that they would get these
Belgian malinois on.
People does dogs or police dogs.
Those dogs look at you.
So different than any,
the dogs they have like a look of like
just give me the green light dance and
they grab and they shake.
Oh,
I know someone who they grabbed face
shook his face.
Oh God.
Yeah.
Smaller.
There were a smaller dog,
like a 60,
70 pound dog.
Like I'll just have taught ball of wire.
But these regency mastiffs are 140 in
their tanks.
Did Gypsy that stupid movie,
the Hulk with Eric with uh,
what's his name?
Band bands.
Didn't have.
Ignore it.
And do one also.
Yes,
his was better.
But the ban of one Nick Nolte D was.
I can't believe we're talking about this
too,
but I forgot to bring up this one
crucial part.
Nick Nolte DC was Eric Ban his dad and
he injected these dogs with this hope
serum.
So these pitbulls became hulk pit bulls
do attack the hawk.
It was so stupid.
But the dog thing to model the hulk pit
bull was curly.
Curly was my dogs dad tank of a dog.
That's the sweetest dog you've ever
seen.
That's like the image that they drew for
the renderings the actual dog looked
like in the movie.
It was like a giant hooked out pit bull
rescue that to us.
That's it right there.
I would let that dog in my bed.
I love them.
I live right.
I think that there is something about
it.
So interesting that you have a couple of
kinds of breeds because I feel like
people usually see themselves in a breed
and that's their thing,
you know,
and if yours is massive,
but what made you do a meathead?
He looked awesome.
Yeah.
That's literally.
He was awesome and he was super sweet
like he's this
dog.
Curly was the sweetest dog,
you know that the most.
The dogs that were bred to fight dogs
and they were also selected for the ones
that were the kindness to the owners
because the dog fighters didn't tolerate
dogs that were violent towards people.
A bunch of pit bulls.
I know the whole deal behind them.
The tragic irony is that they're trained
to be weapons,
but they're trained to be very
emotionally attached to people's.
They're so attached to you.
Those things give you is so intense and
so unconditional,
so intense.
It's weird.
They're like,
there's so much more vibrant than a lot
of other dogs and the way they love you,
it's like so different.
And the ones that are rescued I think
also know on some level.
Yeah,
I had this one.
She wouldn't even let any other dogs
near me,
like I had to give her all the love of
the other dogs came near her.
Everybody got snapped at and backed off.
I had to get all the love to her first.
I had a friend,
I mean,
and they also gravitate towards
vulnerable,
so when I'm sick they get more
protective of me.
When I had the injury,
like when my ear was ripped off,
they were all like when someone come in
and they'd be like extra flexing on like
the gardeners and stuff like they,
they're really empathic.
It's pretty.
I've learned so much from training dogs,
especially ones with low impulse
control.
They don't have a lot of impulse control
so you have to teach them impulse
control because they're designed not
only to fight but also to chase rats and
there's a root.
So to bring it all back.
Johnny cash,
my two dogs,
brutus as much smaller.
Brutus is an English bulldog.
She inu mix and so many flaps and so
when they're both going to enter into
the house to eat,
Johnny always knocks brutus or either
way like pitch,
step aside,
bitch,
like it's,
they have such a clear run how it works,
pecking order.
I told you about when I went to that.
Um,
no,
I don't think I did the wolf sanctuary.
She did like how,
you know,
you just,
you have to leave them alone and let
them have their pecking order.
There's the Alpha,
the Beta and the mega.
You got to just leave them alone.
Like people like don't leave them alone.
Let them work it out.
You can't interject into nature just
because you're uncomfortable with your
own mortality.
Exactly.
I mean,
I tell people to leave the dog park all
the fucking time.
People are so stupid with their dogs and
they project their shit onto their dogs
and they're codependent with their dogs
and uh,
you know,
the way to get pimples or to unlock,
to get dogs.
Yeah.
So I'm just sticking my finger in
buttholes at the dog park constantly to
get dogs to stop fighting because people
don't want to control their dogs.
Most people that have those kind of
dogs,
they don't realize that it's.
This is not like getting a lab.
You're getting a dangerous animal.
Loves to fight.
Loves it.
They fight the lock on each other and
wagtails.
Yeah.
And you have to be able to ascertain the
difference between when things get real,
like the hair on their back and went and
playful and you're.
And then the dog feels your fear and
then they started to get protective.
That's.
People don't understand like all the
time when I'm walking my dogs and
someone's like and they start pulling
their dog away and I'm like,
what you're doing is you're feeling fear
now your dog's going to get aggressive.
So you're manifesting this dog fights
with your fucking bullshit fear.
Like get your shit together.
So frustrating.
Well,
that's where the argument comes in.
Do we really want those kinds of pets?
I mean,
do we really want people to have
dangerous doners pets?
Yeah,
but it's a super responsibility.
And I agree that many people could do it
correctly,
but it is a super responsibility to have
a warrior animal.
I agree.
And I mean,
I,
I do think that for a lot of these
animals that are just so unbelievably
fast and you know,
designed to do damage that,
I mean the same way we get driver's
license for cars,
you're operating something that can
injure people like you should.
I don't think people should have big
dogs but big teeth without taking some
kind of test prep.
I have a friend who runs greyhounds,
they have greyhounds and they have these
dogs that they there are so fast and
he's like,
these things are so ferocious that they
won't even play with other dogs.
Like if they find him another dog or a
coyote or a poodle or they'll kill it.
Yeah.
They just immediately kill it.
And that's a bummer.
It is a bummer.
And I had a buddy who rescued racing
greyhounds stimulus before pimples,
actually.
Great.
Hence,
well the ones that were there,
I mean they weren't pets at all.
They were just existing to race.
They were existing is gambling dogs.
Yeah.
And that's a really common thing.
I know,
I hate it.
So he would rescue these dogs.
He rescued one of them and he couldn't
keep it because it anytime it saw a cat
or a small gods having a cheetah.
Yeah,
we're just having this thing.
So I mean if you raise it from a puppy
you can usually,
you know.
No really.
I don't know a ton about greyhounds,
but I don't know.
You can raise the lions from cubs and
they,
they seem on instagram.
They're biting them and hanging out with
them.
But oddly enough,
and this is going to sound weird,
lions seem to be calmer than a lot of
other animals that we.
It's male lions for sure.
Right.
Male lions are only awake two hours a
day and they don't do anything as long
as you feed the female on,
you're nice to them all the time.
I think you can connect with these guys
on Instagram,
black Jaguar,
white tiger,
you know the guy and they're snuggling
with fucking panther or something.
I heard something that they have their
scent on them.
They put their urine on them like they
declaw them.
I don't recall,
but even that's not going to help you if
the thing decides to bite you.
It's a wrap.
There's no way you're going to survive.
It's over.
Well,
member Tippi hedren.
She the hitchcock actress.
Well,
you pulled it like the Tippi Hedren
Shambala.
She,
Melanie Griffith,
grew up with 18 tigers and lions in the
home in La,
in La.
Right outside.
And they did a documentary about it and
everyone on the crew got attacked.
They got their scalp ripped off.
Melanie Griffith had some injury and
then tippy came out later and was like,
they are not pads,
do not have them in their house.
It's dangerous.
Is a bad idea.
But she had 19 of them in Encino.
Like,
what the fuck is going on?
I wish I was alive in the seven days.
People just didn't know how to live yet,
but.
Or did they?
I don't know.
But if you raise them from infancy,
if they're domesticated,
it's just a little different.
Right?
I'm sure.
I'm sure it's different,
but there's still the potential for
something going sideways,
but it's also tricky because it's like,
and this is like the work I do with
horses and dogs,
it's like if you get scared and they
feel it and if you run food runs right,
it's you fuck yourself.
It's really like you decide if they
attack you or not based on your energy.
They're like baby,
first generation,
like Viking animals.
You know what I mean?
It's like if you could get them and
raise a bear and then have the bear's
cubs and the bears,
cubs cubs maybe.
Have you seen any generation's
epigenetic imprinting of.
They've always been domesticated.
Have you seen that guy that swims at the
polar bear?
The fuck is he doing?
It's going to keep that thing in
Benadryl or what's happening?
Why is it in a swimming pool?
And the best part of that video is the
gate is like chicken wire.
I'm like,
there's a neighbor who's just like in
his house who has not left in two years.
Your neighbor has a polar bear wrapped
up and chicken wire and what is,
what's,
what is that?
Well,
this is some gay bear stuff with him.
This bear.
I'm a hundred percent sure of it.
Like,
look at that fence.
Look at that neighbor.
That neighbor is like,
fuck this shit insane.
Where is that?
It looks like Cincinnati.
Well there was a guy in Ohio that had
his own zoo and then he shot himself
before he shot himself.
He let all the animals out.
When was this years I'm making that TV
show on NBC or so.
Yeah.
So yeah,
it's real show.
He committed suicide.
Client is running down the freeway and
crazy shit.
So it didn't just happen.
Wasn't there like a tiger lose recently?
There have been other ones,
but this one we just committed suicide.
Yeah,
he whacked himself.
He just like,
I don't want to do this anymore.
And he led all animals.
Fuck,
sick lions is just too weird.
I just don't want to do this anymore.
And you just ended it.
But he let all the animals go first.
So funny.
Yeah.
So the cops.
Who is this?
Oh,
this is the guy at the front,
like where is this one?
One Call Jaguar deputies with this bad
luck.
It's amazing.
It's amazing that they had to shoot all
the animals.
Well,
they couldn't let them go and once they,
they were in a certain area that had
isolated before they spread out.
It's really couldn't find them.
I know they killed them all.
Nightmare.
It's a nightmare.
When I see a human die,
I'm just like,
oh bummer.
When I see animals,
I'm like,
that's freaking nightmare.
Um,
okay.
So you're new when your,
when your new dog gets neutered.
It's gonna be a game changer.
Yeah.
I'm sure it's energy.
Yeah,
right now.
But he's sweet.
He's,
he's a different kind of.
Dogs are just like lifeguards.
I mean there's weed is dogs.
They're just so nice stories about they
smell a fire and they get the kid and
they opened the door and they take it to
a shelter and they put it on a plane and
travel arrangements.
Really,
they help you get into college.
They're on a kayak.
I mean they're just such incredible dog.
He's,
he gets a little silly sometimes because
he's young,
like sometimes will test you with things
and won't listen when you tell them to
do things.
Animals tests you.
I want to go like,
are you the leader?
Are you the leader?
That's what they're doing.
I think that's kind of what audiences do
as well.
You know,
we were talking earlier about self
analysis and I am trying to stop with
that shit but it's just hard to turn
that off because it's like we get on
stage and were like,
do you like me now?
Do you like me now?
What about now we do that for an hour
every night,
you know,
and then I get off stage and I'm doing
it to myself.
Do I liked me now?
Do I like me now?
Like it's just a hard thing to fucking
shut off,
you know,
like how do you negotiate on stage?
Like getting feedback and using that
validation and then as soon as it's
over,
not needing it at all,
will you have like people that love you
and a family and shit,
you're answering for yourself and people
care about you?
I think the.
I think doing things that are more
difficult than that is a good way to
even that out.
That is an unbelievably salient point.
Yeah.
I think if you're all,
if that's the most difficult thing in
your day,
it becomes a.
it's got extra weight that it doesn't
need to have on it.
That's fascinating.
Yeah.
Is there something more difficult than
standard of care?
Is Everything is more difficult.
Standup is easy when it's going.
Great.
Joey.
Joey Diaz said that stand up is the
easiest,
hardest thing you'll ever do.
Perfect.
Way To describe it.
Of course.
Joey said it.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Do you.
Of course,
you know this,
but I read something recently about how
the reason people hate are so scared of
public speaking,
evolutionarily speaking,
if you were in that position,
public speaking,
you speaking to hundreds of people,
that meant that you were exiled from the
tribe and you were defending yourself.
Whoa
Shit.
So if you were ever like trying to get
people to like you,
it was saying,
please don't kill me.
I didn't eat all the meat.
I didn't steal that thing.
Please spare me.
Oh my God,
that makes so much sense.
So much sense.
So when we're up there on stage,
the reason you feel that fear is because
it used to be you were begging for
forgiveness and not to get speared to
death or stoned to death or whatever.
It makes a lot of sense.
That's crazy because we always
associated with being a leader who,
speaking to the tribe,
nope,
no,
please don't kill me.
Please don't kill me.
Holy Shit.
Yeah,
that's what it was.
And tribal times at the same thing about
like there was that article in the
Atlantic about how um,
loneliness is now is bad for you as
smoking because it used to be,
if you were living alone in an
apartment,
in a pod that meant you were exiled from
the tribe and had no protection from it.
So your brain stops producing serotonin.
Endorphins,
you basically just get depressed because
it's like you feel so unsafe and you
feel so much anxiety designed to live
together because that meant protections
before we had like alarm systems and
locks and shit.
Right.
Wow.
That totally makes sense as well.
And it seems like the,
the more people get advanced socially,
like the more we understand each other
socially,
we more and more will understand like
that there's all these causes and
effects that go on inside of human
relationships,
on both sides that make things go well
or go bad.
And hopefully over generation after
generation of US studying this and
paying attention to the way that we
behave and talk to each other.
Because I think people talk to each
other far differently today.
We definitely do in media,
right,
and it didn't make the 19 thirties or
forties or fifties.
It's like there's a very crude,
rudimentary form of communication that I
think it's richer and weirder and more
aware now today and I think it's going
to continue to get better and better and
if it does,
maybe one day we'll get into a more
relaxed society place.
Like if we can ensure that more people
are nice and friendly and helping it and
honest and helpful and less people are
dangerous and fucked up.
But instead of doing that,
what we do is the opposite.
Will I put a bigger walls,
lock things down more,
separate ourselves,
ourselves further,
you know,
secure our position.
I think as a society,
and this is total hippy talk,
right?
But we have to figure out a way to make
less people live.
Sucky lives soon as you make less people
live,
suck lives.
Everything becomes way less dangerous.
Right?
But like I was in Guatemala once and I
remember looking around and going,
what a sucky life,
what a sucky life.
And then I drive past people.
They're sitting around laughing with no
teeth in hammocks in a shack,
and I'm like,
why are they happier than me?
And um,
from what I gather it's because they're
together.
So it's like,
so much of our communication is
nonverbal.
They say like 80 percent of our
communication is nonverbal and I'm on
here texting,
texting,
texting.
You're seeing the verbal but you're not
seeing the nonverbal of like,
you're safe.
I'm connected to you.
Or getting oxytocin for making eye
contact and hugging.
Like we're communicating more and more
and more,
but actually reaching each other less
and less and less on a chemical or
neurochemical level.
Right?
Yeah.
And you've got to figure the people that
are living in a village or some third
world country or they're living closer
to the land of less electronic
stimulation,
less they're who they are as a person
and where they're living their life is,
is fitting into the world that they live
in.
Right.
It's like those grooves I've already
been cut.
There's smooth and deep and everything
just slides into place.
Everybody's been doing it this way for a
long ass time.
Yeah.
When do you start factoring in all the
crazy shit that we're after dealing with
just with traffic and the sheer number
of humans clogged into this
intersection,
just trying to move forward and
everybody being frustrated and honking
and cutting each other off.
And that is
brain doesn't know what a car is.
It makes sense.
Like our primordial brain,
it's just a lion running across,
uh,
the fucking horror,
you know,
it's just like things coming at you
quickly.
So we're kind of in fight or flight mode
all the time.
And the phone is the sun,
right?
Our brain basically think it's just
producing cortisol.
It's like we're constantly looking into
the sun all day and then we see just
things coming at us in our periphery
constantly and it's depleting and it's
putting us in fight or flight mode,
which sets shuts down our frontal lobe.
Right.
Which is like our feeling and decision
making sound though.
What is it?
I remember reading this,
but I don't remember what the answer is.
What is it about the disassociative
aspect of driving in a car that makes
people aggressive to other people like
verbally and giving them the finger and
get and the anonymity?
No,
no,
I remember what it is.
What it is is they had concluded that
you're in a heightened state of not
necessarily fear but reaction time when
you were in a car because you realize
that you are going 65 miles an hour and
everything is happening fast.
You have to be paying attention to
everything.
And so in this heightened state,
you're almost in like a heightened
altercation position.
Like you're ready for anything,
right?
What do we got?
What do we got it you.
You're ready to go?
This fucking Dick had just cut me off
like it's everything so ramped up.
But let me ask you a question because
I've been in cars with people who are
just like,
oh sorry.
And I've been in cars with people a
little fuck you.
And to me it's like I feel like kind of
every guy turns it into a sport.
You can do that if you let it get away.
You're competing and who's going faster
and that sort of thing like does that
happen to you?
You can do that.
If someone's a total dick and you start
falling into that,
it's always best to think twice.
It's always best just relax and just
avoid because it's not worth.
There's no upside on that sort of like
involvement.
There's no upside on that.
K,
there's nothing been like,
fuck you.
And been like,
that was a good idea.
There's nothing out of that.
There's no upside.
But the downside is gigantic.
Actual violence.
Like you could get shot,
you could get stabbed,
you get beat up,
someone could run you over,
you could get into some terrible
position where you hurt someone and you
have to pay for their medical bills and
their legal bills.
It could be devastating to you.
Is there something like,
and you could feel terrible about the
fact that he did it cause you did it in
the heat of passion when you weren't
even thinking straight.
Stupid guys do dumb shit all the time.
Changes their life.
I was in a,
uh,
is it called Artesia?
That's a place in California,
California.
I watched a guy like two guys tailgating
each other,
chasing some guy,
fucking got out of his car with a
baseball bat and like came in and they
got in a fight and I was like,
I'm going to leave.
There's a great video of that.
Some guy gets out of his car,
pulls a bat out of his car and smashes
other guy's car and the other guy gets
out of the car,
grabs them,
gets them in a rear naked choke,
puts them to sleep,
pushes them to the side of the road,
gets in his car and drives off.
It's amazing.
There's no,
but I'm just saying is that I got into
this and I know I was texting you about
that calcium storico thing.
That thing in Florida,
you've got obsessed with that shit.
I'm I want to make a documentary.
I've been trying for years,
but I'm obsessed with our need for
violence and if we didn't have violent
sports and competitive sports where we
all just constantly be having baseball
bats in each other's windshield's all
the time.
Like we have an inherent need to be
violent.
Right?
And do we need to just sort of control
the reason I'm obsessed with Callisto
Storico,
which if you don't know it's.
We've talked about it I think on the job
before,
which is like it's bare knuckle boxing
football essentially,
but the month that they do it in
Florence,
there's virtually no crime because they
purge,
people purge and they get it out and not
healthy ways,
but at least in controlled ways,
you know,
like are we designed to just be like
taking baseball bats to each other's
windshields?
I think what it represents is a very
valid release for primal instincts.
Yes.
And I've been studying it most of my
life.
I mean,
most of my life I've been paying
attention to martial arts,
studying martial arts.
I would have to be.
I'm usually in the woods if I go a whole
day and I don't see someone fight,
right?
Like I see it every day constantly,
always.
I watch more Thai fights every day.
I'll watch a wrestling match or watch a
Jujitsu match.
I'm constantly watching these things and
what I get out of all of it is what
these people were doing.
Everybody's doing is,
first of all,
they're engaging in something incredibly
difficult and when you engage with
something incredibly difficult,
it's a great way for strong willed
people to find themselves.
They find themselves around this,
that,
but it's you're,
you're finding validation through
incredibly difficult acts like,
I think I'm special.
How do I prove I'm special?
I prove I'm special.
Like choking out other trained killers.
I'm going to get to a place where I can
choke out all the experts like I'm not
just choking out regular people.
I want to be able to choke out the
experts and those guys who do that,
they find themselves in the most
exceptional minds and the most
exceptional bodies.
They all,
it converges together.
You cannot have one without the other,
but it's so recent that were not choking
each other out in the streets all the
time.
I mean like 100 years or something.
I mean,
I was reading our that our eyes evolved
to be sunken end because we were getting
punched in the face so much as a
species.
That's why our eyes are sunken in.
I swear to fucking God are our fists
evolved to do this
so that we could use,
keeps going with all the.
I poked me supervisor get thicker.
I would give up like a little bit of
vision to have like poke proof eyes.
The eyes are made of glass.
Yeah,
there was so weak.
I mean,
we're pathetic,
but so it's so recent that we're not
just constantly fighting each other and
choking each other out in a socially
acceptable way.
But here's my thing.
What I've noticed and everybody has.
Look,
everybody's a work in progress.
You know,
I mean,
you want to judge someone by an argument
that you got with someone 10 years ago.
I think that's kind of ridiculous,
but we're all capable of weird,
uh,
aggressive behavior and mistakes.
But the people that I know that are
involved in martial arts are uniformly
some of the nicest,
most peaceful,
friendly.
They didn't
think they would be if they didn't get.
No,
I don't know.
I don't,
I would hope not.
That's what I know.
But it gives them something.
It gives them a feeling of security and
it gives them an understanding of ego
because you lose a lot like the thing.
Most guys don't lose a lot of fights
because they don't get in a lot of
fights.
You talk to an average person.
I might've been in my whole life like
street fights,
like three or four ever,
ever really.
All my fights I had were in competition.
So your thing is you learn how to avoid
fights.
Definitely.
Well,
that drives you to need to do it.
It wasn't my choice like I was avoiding
fights because I was scared of getting
my ass kicked and then I got into
martial arts completely because I was
scared to fight people and I moved
around a lot and I didn't really know
what I was doing,
but my point being that this,
this desire,
once you understand,
you really know how to fight,
all that shit goes away and you're
friendly and you don't have the need to
overcompensate or prove anything because
you proved it to yourself that you can
do it.
There's a little bit.
As soon as I actually felt like I was
funny as a comedian talking into your
net value,
that smoking thing,
I remember there was like 10 comics.
They used to do that.
Like the nineties,
they'll Hashtag your banker.
Um,
I forgot what I was talking about.
I forgot what we're talking about too.
No,
I was saying like,
as soon as I felt like I was actually
funny as a comedian onstage,
I stopped trying to be funny in my real
life.
I didn't need to be right.
That makes,
I think it's probably pretty similar.
I think it's probably pretty similar for
guys.
I think also they get it out of their
system and also they don't have this.
A lot of male and male to male
interaction happens just out of fear.
Like guys want the other guy to back
down because they're fucking terrified
that they don't,
they don't want to fight,
but when people are not afraid of it,
it's not like a terrifying thing to
them.
There's more relaxation and less things
happen.
Can I ask you a really weird question?
Sure.
It's illegal.
It's illegal to fight people.
Just in the street in California,
it is not in Washington state.
Washington state has something called a
mutual combat law.
Will cops will actually stand by and
watch people beat the shit out of each
other if they agree to and as long as
they know there's no such thing as like
assault.
It is wild west Shit.
They literally.
Trenton state Seattle in Seattle.
What if it's man versus woman who I
don't think you can do that.
Really?
No,
I don't think you could do that.
I don't think so.
And what if you're you?
You can't do that because you're allowed
to see a candle that's not real.
Although isn't there a thing registering
yourself as web and of that's real.
Fighters had to go to town hall
registered my hands.
I'm a human weapon.
My hands.
I've heard that.
Why have I heard that?
Real?
Because people used to always say that
you can't.
If you're you,
you're not allowed to fight the human on
the street.
You go to jail.
But if I hit someone,
I'll get like an assault charge.
First of all,
everybody hits someone for no
reason.
It's going to go to jail unless it's
self defense,
but if you're vandelay Silva and someone
doesn't know it's vandelay Silva and
they go and pick a fight with him and he
beats the fuck out of them.
He's not gonna get in trouble or some
sort of proof that these guys were
starting a fight with them.
He's defending himself.
So if I attack Ronda Rousey at whole
foods,
she flips you in your breaks my neck
with her finger.
She can she.
That was self defense 100 percent.
Yeah.
You know,
it's not our fault that she killed me.
Well,
not only that,
she doesn't know.
You might be some crazy black belt in
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu who's insane once a
strangle or been lifting,
but there are.
I mean there's danger in interaction
with new people.
If you can get sued,
well,
you could always encounter someone that
knows how to fight.
When you,
when you're,
when someone touches you or they're
arguing with you are there in your face,
you have no idea what they're capable
of.
They might be.
Even if you're a martial artist that
they might be better than you are.
You don't know.
No one ever knows what you're saying.
This is this crazy idea that somehow or
another you have to have your shit
together to be a fighter.
I've known a lot of fucking crazy people
that were insane that we're really good
at fighting really.
Part of it though,
you have to be lacking.
Not spect approach to or St Pierre isn't
George St Pierre is super present and
kind and a fun guy to talk to.
A sweetheart just ultra,
ultra competitive.
Right?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
He's like adrenaline addiction shit,
or when.
My point is he's not a mean person,
but there are mean crazy people that are
also really good at fighting.
The idea that only good people are good
at fighting is a ridiculous know that
you have to be always careful.
These hands and feet are registered as
deadly weapons in Guam,
Guam,
Guam.
You can do that at the bottom.
There's a law about the,
like if you went to Guam and he
registered karate or judo expert,
who thereafter is charged with having
used his art in a physical assault on
some other person shall upon conviction.
There have be deemed guilty of
aggravated assault upon conviction
though that's a component that should
be.
I agree with.
You have to have been arrested already.
Well,
I agree with that.
What I take,
this is how I interpret that,
that if someone like say a Brendan
Schaub decided to pick on some guy who
didn't know how to fight knowing that
this guy didn't know how to fight and
Brendan would never do that.
He's the nicest guy ever,
but beat the shit out of this person.
They should be charged with like an
extra level of assault because it's not
just a salt.
It's almost like assault with a weapon.
She told me that people come up to him
and he'll be like,
uh,
you know,
I used to fight and he's just like,
don't say that.
They instigate and sometimes you just
have to leave DFP ever.
I have people do that where you just
have to like leave because sometimes
people are delusional,
but I've seen it happened even to Chuck
Liddell.
I've seen people come up to him when he
was in his prime.
People are crazy.
There's always a certain ones
that people who come up to.
I mean as a comic people come up to me
and like,
what's up?
I'm like,
you don't want to do this,
don't do this,
don't do that.
To like,
hey hooker.
And I'm like,
don't try to be funny.
I'm going to go well for you practicing
that at home.
Then when I see her tonight I'm going to
look at yours.
The things people say to me are so like,
what do you think by reactions and be
like,
you think I'm going to like crack up
laughing and be like,
here's my phone number.
Like what did you just drop your needs?
How did you think that was going to go?
I don't think they think.
I think people also like maybe they have
an idea of what?
Of what will be funny and I think about
a total of 15 seconds before they say
it's shocking and my favorite has been
something that bores you with like a 15
minutes,
the longest vagina monologue of all
time.
Something just like terrible and awful.
They just talk about like traffic and
then they're like,
you can have that one.
Can I.
Did you ever notice like,
oh no material
or like you're talking to someone super
boring and they're like,
are you going to put me in your act
like,
no,
you're fucking bombing.
Say something funny and I'll think about
it.
No,
the worst.
Every guy says that on dates.
They're like,
we're gonna.
Put it in your act.
Wow.
Really?
Is that a part of the issue?
The Guy I'm dating has never seen me to
stand up.
That's what I'm going to do.
How long you been dating him?
Eight months.
Keep them that way.
I think that's kind of a light.
Never goes well.
I don't think guys love seeing girls and
like an Alpha stance yelling about
Dick's.
They've sucked in the past.
I like to separate church and state like
that.
Or do you think that that's delusional?
That I can.
I don't think it's delusional at all.
You've done it for eight months,
eight months.
Why can't you do it for eight years?
Which is as long as I ever want to be in
anything.
Yeah.
But it seems like it's totally possible.
Why?
I mean,
if that's what makes you comfortable and
it doesn't give a shit.
I think comedy's for strangers.
I don't think it's for people.
You know?
My friends were like,
can I come see your show?
And I'm like,
that's not what it's for.
It's for complete strangers.
It's not for people,
you know,
you just nailed it.
Oh yeah.
Like if you're doing standup and someone
who you know really good is in the front
row,
like what are the front row is all your
family?
I can't say that.
It's like I'm doing these shows in La
and I'm like,
why am I doing la shows?
Because it's gonna be all people.
I know.
Everyone's like,
can I come on?
Like,
you can't.
Actually,
I'm like doing a complete,
like you got to tune into everybody
else,
but it's just like,
you're right,
you're not even thinking about.
Those are the people they may or may not
be an impediment in,
but they're not going to enhance it.
They're not going to be a part of the
normal crowd.
For me,
I'm always thinking in the back of my
head,
oh no,
I can't say that I'm going to hurt their
feelings.
It's like you can't say anything because
you can't just be like,
oh,
because my fucking crazy family.
And then they're like,
where are we creating?
I'm set in.
Everyone's.
Everyone's such a fucking narcissist.
Like it's like the worst when you're
dating someone or whatever it is and
you're like going on and on about like
in this stupid guy,
and they're like,
what's that about me?
I'm like,
no,
I made that up.
It's not about anyone.
It's my friend told me this,
like everyone just has to like turn your
act into a war shock tests and
everything's about them and I just
can't.
Okay.
I mean there's this unspoken shit that's
going on in your act.
It's me,
no,
you're fucking,
you know,
this is so ridiculous.
I don't have a problem with you doing
calm.
Really.
You work out or shit on stage.
It's like,
well,
it's interesting because bill bird
number talks about his wife on stage or
he never talks about.
He says that she doesn't like when he
talks about him or when he talks about
her,
like she drew a boundary about it,
which I think yeah,
makes sense.
And I think what you're saying makes
sense to that.
It's the actual act of doing it.
You're doing it for people who don't
know you.
You're trying to do a thing.
I,
if I was a stripper,
I wouldn't want you to come to me.
It's so emotionally revealing and it's
about vulnerability.
It's about like I'm going to talk to you
for an hour and then never see you
again.
They're completely makes sense.
It is a one night stand.
But what about songs?
I feel like songs the same way too.
Like if you know someone really well,
like God damn like,
do you really want someone to sing a
song for you?
I went to a wedding where it was two
brides who was lesbian wedding and one
of them sung to the other person and I
had to get up and walk away.
So uncomfortable looking in her eyes,
singing to her.
I was crouched over.
I literally was.
I was sweating.
I,
I mean I look like fucking the joker.
My Mega was.
I was so uncomfortable.
I think singing to me.
I would rather blow you making eye
contact the entire time.
Then have you seen to me,
I will put a gun in my mouth before I
let someone sing a song to me.
Awful.
Disgusting.
I don't know why it.
So what is it?
What about the human condition?
How can we,
from a primordial perspective,
I just am trying to do.
I can't.
Why is it so embarrassing?
Maybe if you're a good singer,
this was a good singer too.
That actually made it worse.
Yeah,
but even if you're a good sandwiches,
you and this one person,
you're alone in your kitchen and they
start looking you in the icing and
you're like,
yeah,
hey,
cut the shit.
And active aggression really is a very
awkward thing to do.
Oh yeah.
You have to listen now because making
eye contact.
It's just makes me a guitar and you're
so comfortable.
You could look someone in the eye and
say,
no,
you've got to go around.
It's wrap.
Can't do it.
Like something really intense.
Right?
Like,
what would it be 10 songs would sing
too.
I'm like a Sam Smith Banger or like,
um,
maybe some Elliot Smith.
Were you thinking about sticking the
knife in your heart?
It's just,
it's just,
um,
what is it?
Because we are designed music releases
endorphins,
right when we listened to music.
But it's great in a small gathering
together.
I think we don't love on top of each
other.
It's just our Kelly was wearing glasses.
He's wearing glasses.
It's different.
I could do it in sunglass sunglasses.
He is
Super Yogi.
I don't fuck with any of that shit.
No,
I'm just not into that.
Interesting.
I did once I did it once on a radio
station.
I say kiss song.
How did that go?
It was great.
Really like fucking,
you know,
they,
they had this thing that they did on the
Alice.
It was a radio station in San Francisco.
Yeah.
Alice was the Sarah.
No name where the hosts of the show.
Those kinds of.
Yeah,
they have like a,
another thing now.
Are they doing a podcast or something?
Probably.
I mean,
yeah.
What do you.
What do you show more r Kelly.
She's like playing with his Dick while
he's on stage saying,
oh,
the girl behind him playing with his
Dick while he was onstage singing the
fan.
Understand someone just playing with you
before you're saying a dick.
That's so this girl is reaching up,
grabbing his dick while he's saying hand
him his balls.
Setting.
Beautiful.
Speaking real.
What are those small stokey while he's
doing this in front of 50,000
people.
Oh God,
look insane.
Wait,
is that enjoyable?
Having someone just tell your dick from
behind.
I'd have to have it happen.
Especially in front of all those people.
That would be uncomfortable.
Depends on how you do it.
Some people are really good at playing
golf.
Other people.
This is fucking.
They hit that meant to me,
what is what's going on here?
Same thing.
I guess the.
He hands him a towel and wipe him off,
but he's got clothes on.
I'll give you some volume on this.
I need to hear this.
What mental illness does he have?
All of them
get the good ones.
The bad ones,
they cancel each other out.
He's doing great.
He's just hitting the frequency.
Getting out of this.
He's amazing.
I don't like this.
The Christmas tree is kind of sinister.
Come on.
This is beautiful.
You got to just let it go.
Let it go.
This is know about video.
This is beautiful.
This isn't just the one time sweat off.
You just take off your coat.
She's got her hand on his Dick and this
is making me sexist against women.
Look at your mother.
Must be very proud.
Listen,
she's doing a good job.
Everybody's happy.
I see a lot of love in the room and I
see one hater.
Oh,
look at this right here.
She's grabbing.
Oh she.
She heard his dick.
Why would you.
What did he do?
She do.
Just grab,
grabbing.
Crushed his balls.
She tried to snatch it and take it home
with her.
I feel like
this took a turn.
So many amazing.
It's amazing.
That grabbed enjoyable.
Not like that.
It's she highfive and bitch.
I'm still confused about that Dick.
She's like,
get over here.
I'm gonna.
Get it again.
Women are letting me down.
Not all women.
You can't be on team woman.
That's crazy.
I agree.
I agree,
but I get a little bit where I'm like,
it's not.
You are not on the same team.
You're a human being who happens to be
female.
People get ridiculous.
I can't say women.
That's great,
but I'm just like,
I need everyone to class it up.
Everyone needs to just elevate our Kelly
dropping his dick in front of some
woman.
He's disgusting.
I mean probably drunk.
When was that?
Was that recent exciting videos from
December?
He's garbage real recent.
He does that.
I think probably every show.
First of all,
how dare you say he's garbage?
He has.
He has provided some of the best
unintentional comedy in the history of
the world.
That's the job.
I don't like it when musicians take our
job.
No,
no,
no.
She'll talk.
No.
What is that?
A song where he talks for like the
entire song.
Beautiful Mama and the Joe Rogan
experience.
Please don't make eye contact with me.
Even if we get pulled off youtube.
I don't give a fuck.
We can pull up youtube basically every
video.
Anyway,
so we're gonna get demonetized.
It's hard out there for a pimp.
But you,
you gotta listen to this.
Gonna make me.
I'm going to play it.
Play it,
play it.
We're gonna play and we're going to
comment over it and then we get called.
We lose a step so we'll,
we'll re upload it and then this is
going to have to go out live.
All you Internet folks.
Just take chunks of this and save this
part.
This ain't going to climax.
Don't make eye contact with anybody.
Don't look at me.
The profanity represents just how real
shit gets when you argued with your girl
and Shit to my.
I gotta get me a drink.
He'd go give me a drink.
Me a shot.
Take me a shot.
He's jumping off here,
so I'm just going to do it.
I'm doing this for the fans that I know
around the globe.
We'll talk.
Oh,
oh,
wait a minute.
Calm down to the club with who is the
happiest I've ever seen your job.
Listen to this man.
Is that a landline to sit up here and
argue with you about who's to blame Tom
Seeker only thing I'm trying to.
I'm trying to establish smoke free and
say she saw me at a club with some other
beachy CFP.
Was this you say that with other guys?
Does she stay?
There were other guys there with the
other guys.
Well,
tell me this.
Well wait a minute,
let me finish one.
I've got the Martin Luther King Jealous.
No Man.
Some old bullshit when I'm just trying
to have a good time smiling.
Nobody.
No damn money.
Always running off at the mouth.
Telling your girl your motherfucking
business.
They don't sleep with us.
We'll talk about bullshit.
That shit.
Anyway,
put
this girl.
This isn't a healthy relationship.
Fuck me.
Fuck you.
What was the best lyrics come back.
This is a game changer.
Game Changer.
That's out there,
and that's not real.
I mean,
that's real.
That's real.
That's a real song.
That's a real sore.
That's a non ironic real song.
That shit I changed my mind.
He's an artist,
an artist,
a visionary.
He's a performance artist.
Leave your 20 year old at his house.
These goddamn visionary,
um,
that requires an amount of bravery that
I'll never understand.
No one will yelling one side of a
conversation because.
And humiliating.
I mean,
that's what a real fight would sound
like.
And he'd say those other guys,
the other guys they use of silence.
And that song is brilliant.
It's art,
Art.
That is art.
I'm,
I'm feeling so many different emotions
simultaneously that I've never felt
before.
It's repulsive.
Repulsive art.
It's like a,
almost like a disgusting punk rock scene
will.
It also made me examine a lot of my own
beliefs.
Like I'm,
I really like,
I have a lot to think about.
You need to know that that's real.
That's a,
there's a dude out there running shit
like that.
I just said,
oh,
have you heard this?
Really do tell.
There's been all these stories that are
Kelly us,
they're accusing him of having some sort
of a sex cult.
Oh,
I think I did hear about them from their
families that you tried to join you.
I tried to join.
You have to do it.
What's the requirements?
Um,
uh,
a heroin addiction,
a lack of a frontal lobe,
no college education,
um,
love of r Kelly holder of the towel,
the towel,
and you can be literate,
right?
But once you hold a towel and a woman
said she was under the spell of a master
manipulator are killer.
After watching that video,
I feel like I would actually like to
join this call to question if you say
that you were under the spell of a
master manipulator.
But can I ask you a question?
Why do you need to start a sex cult?
Why can't you just get a girlfriend?
I don't know.
I don't need to sleep with a lot of
people.
Can't you just,
you're already a musician.
Don't you get to do that anyway?
You'd have to talk to our.
I do not want to speak for the man
because.
Yeah,
because I,
I,
you know anyone who I don't really fuck
you.
Fuck you.
It's,
it's,
it's infinity infinity.
You can't argue with that.
We'll talk is banging your head against
a brick wall.
You cannot win a fight with that guy
because he just repeats your insults
back to you.
Yeah.
I don't know if he's really running a
sex cult so,
but if he is,
why does anybody ever run into any
popstar running a sex cult?
It's not what being a pop star is.
What does it say here?
This is kitty.
You gave me your number.
He said,
always refer to me as daddy.
Oh no,
that's not good.
Whatever we say baby during sex,
which is me,
but it does make sense that if that was
your kid though,
you'd be freaking the fuck out your kids
in art.
Kelly's.
They strike me as someone who fights
with a women.
I'm not into it.
I don't like fighting.
I don't think it's fun.
It's not necessarily.
Most of the time that's the point.
It's not necessary.
I no longer have the need to have those
chaotic arguments and people disagree
all the time.
I've had a pretty heated arguments with
some of my best friends and sometimes
over ridiculous shit.
Right.
You know,
I think it's the same with
relationships.
Like she'd never say something in a
relationship.
Like people say things in relationships.
I feel that they would never say to your
best friend like that.
It's very rare.
That's interesting that you would like
say something to your best friend.
Like,
like a hurtful thing without her.
I mean at least me.
I think it.
I don't want to.
I don't want to hurt my best friends
from when I had good friends there
acting a fool and it's like I have to
say this uncomfortable thing and protect
you from yourself because what you're
doing is stupid or dangerous and I feel
like most men agree with that.
But most men that I've talked to about
fights with their wives,
a lot of guys have told me that shit can
get really ugly and you start like going
after the things that you know we're
going to hurt the other person's
feelings.
It's like woo.
I was like,
do you do that with your friends?
And they were like,
no,
don't do that with my friends.
I mean that's the whole point.
But a friend is like,
I used to have weird,
acrimonious things with friends.
I'm like,
this doesn't make any sense.
Like,
if I'm not fucking you,
I'm not fighting with you.
Friends should be safe place should it,
unless you know,
like,
I mean I see a lot of friends of mine.
I'm going down in a blaze of glory on
instagram with their crazy.
Have you ever lived?
I've lost some friends to insert like
oak trees are falling every day with
the,
just losing their minds with their
documenting every last thing.
And I've done a couple of interventions
where I'm like,
hey,
you're starting to look crazy.
And it never goes well.
Trying to help.
Trying to just hold a mirror up.
You're starting to look bad shit.
You gotta take your kids off.
You can't be filming them and saying
their name and saying where they live.
It's just dangerous.
You know?
I run someone to tell me,
you would tell me if I was going crazy.
Right?
Well,
there's definitely a lot of people that
get addicted to the idea of posting
things that are getting the feedback,
feedback.
There's some sort of a weird serotonin
thing that comes from.
Oh,
for sure.
Yeah,
definitely.
I mean it's like rats with the fucking
whatever the skinner box and that.
Just like Pavlovian response.
I was at instagram the other day.
They said the average instagram user
goes to instagram 35 times a day.
Oh Jesus.
30 five times a day.
That's more than once an hour.
It's nice to know that my average.
Do you think you go that often?
No,
I'm probably close to five times in a
row and then not for like a couple hours
I follow a bunch of,
like really cool.
Um,
nature ones.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Me Too.
I know.
And like travel things and like now I
follow doctors and surgeries and zip
popping and that kind of shit.
Oh,
do you follow Dr Pimple Popper?
Yes,
of course.
She's amazing.
Yes.
Obsessed.
I like when they take a tool and like
push down and it comes out.
Why is that so satisfying?
Because as humans we're designed to
groom each other because before
antibacterial soap and fucking purell
and stuff like we were,
we get endorphins from popping zits and
grooming each other.
Wow.
Yeah.
Does your wife ever tried to like
puppets and stuff on you?
Well,
yeah.
You don't.
Yeah.
Well your skin is like kind of amazing.
But like ingrown hairs and stuff.
Does she ever want to like get stuff?
Oh my God.
My boyfriend.
I'm constantly like in his,
he hates it.
He hates it,
but he lets me do it because he knows
how and I tweeze eyebrows.
So what is it?
It's like a monkey thing.
You think like grooming and everything?
Yeah.
So when we're watching Dr Pimple popper,
lance the zits and pus endorphins,
it's like little
mini orgasms.
She's unapologetic with it to doctor.
She actually loves it.
I love.
I go on planes and go in and I squeeze
my and then stuff comes out of every
pore.
I love it so much.
It's the greatest.
Go on planes and squeeze one off and it
hits the Mirror.
No,
I don't have the ones that like are
projectile.
I wish I did glad I had those in high
school or something in every one of your
fucking little pores and if you just
like squeeze your skin,
it'll come out all at the same time.
It's Lauren.
I love it.
And look for it.
Yeah.
In the high school used to get those
volcanoes.
It's that like you'd be walking around.
It was like this white bubble.
I used to have to get cortisone shots
for that.
I used to get them.
Yeah,
like when I got my period they would
like.
You'd feel them and they'd like Hertz
and you like can't even sleep on that
and then you'd have to wait four weeks
for them to surface.
So I would get a quarter
in Brighton.
The time when you're most vulnerable and
confused as a teenager.
Yeah.
Your body starts to fall apart.
The little basis for having acne as a
teenager.
It's a hormonal thing,
sort of a reaction and the.
There's a bunch of different ways to
mitigate it and a lot of them are.
These medications are really heavy.
They drive it.
I took,
oh,
I took acutane.
Oh,
I took acutane twice because I mean or
something.
I mean you met me.
What do you think the layman on the
accutane?
No,
but there was this.
When you take it,
you have to take birth control
simultaneously because you have to
because it causes birth defects and
fetuses.
So I'm like,
if this causes birth defects,
maybe I shouldn't be putting it in my
bloodstream and the side effects are so
gnarly.
I'm suicidal.
You have to sign this form saying this
could.
Oh,
sorry.
Drove you to suicide.
Like anal bleeding is one of them.
Hey waiting.
You're giving that to a 14 year old.
My skin started flaking off in like
croissant,
like pastry sheets and my lips were like
bleeding.
It was a nightmare.
Your eyes start itching and drawing out
like this isn't ready for the market.
Don't release this product yet.
It's not a thing now.
Was it possibly like you took too much
of it.
You're on it for six months and that's
just.
It varies.
Yeah.
Dries your skin out or like a hair
starts falling out,
but my skin cleared up.
God,
that's awful.
Behavioral effects as well.
Or Am I,
I mean,
yeah,
they said it's a,
it's a,
here's my thing,
it says increases your risk of suicide.
Oh Christ.
But when you're a teenager having bad
skin,
it's like a chicken or an egg thing,
you know,
because all you want to do is fit in.
So I'm always like,
was it the accutane or was it the bad
scan?
I don't know.
That's what they're arguing.
I guess.
Would you ever let your kids go on
accutane?
No.
I mean,
I wonder what,
what natural alternatives there are?
Like I wonder if anything has to do with
the amount of probiotics you'd take.
I wonder if anything it has to do.
Any of it can be mitigated with oil
glands.
Really.
It's genetic.
There's not a ton you can do about it.
But is that the case?
Does the genes express themselves
exactly the same way?
Dependent upon environmental stress?
Uh,
the amount of nutrition and you take in.
I mean,
we're a coil plants.
I,
no.
Can you shrink
or grow oil glands based on Diet?
I don't know,
but it's not uniform.
Right?
So there's only a few in certain places
like why,
why do they want it's variable.
I have oil glands and large pores.
Right.
But it's not all your pores get
infected.
Right.
So some of them do like why are they
getting infected?
How much of that could be dietary,
how much of that can be changed?
Like what if you cut out dairy,
who knows?
There's probably a lot of things that
are causing issues from what I gathered
and this could just be all of the
dermatologists trying to prescribe me
more stuff,
but a lot of it is genetic diet.
I know that.
I wonder if it can be mitigated with
diet or wonder if maybe poor diet
exacerbates it.
Like,
I don't know,
probably it's just,
I'm just guessing,
but I just wonder if medication can do
something for you to.
Maybe there's another way to do it,
to handle it in some sort of a more all
encompassing way.
Deep systemic ones like that is just
like,
well that is.
So those are the worst.
But I think it's probably a hormonal
thing.
Like can you control your hormones with
diet?
I doubt it,
I mean,
I'm sure it enhances,
it enhances your body's ability to
produce hormones if you eat the right
foods,
but uh,
I wonder like as a child,
you're,
you're in such a state of flux and it
might actually be,
I wonder if there's some biological
basis for like the Darwinism of having
really bad skin and overcoming it,
you know,
like what is the point of that in terms
of your pecking order in the tribe of
like having some kind of stigma and
overcoming it and if you're a bit more
of a bad ass,
like,
um,
that's interesting article.
I don't Miss Scientific American or
something that,
that people who had acne,
our over performers in life because they
had to overcompensate and overcome
adversity.
The adversity overcome,
right?
Like the more resilient you are.
And um,
yeah,
it was just like something about you
completely partners.
Isn't that funny how something will come
up and it seems completely
contradictory.
Yeah.
Then you stop and look at it and you go,
oh,
okay.
They had to try harder.
So they got stronger.
But then again,
who's tracing the people who had acne,
who weren't successful,
no one's following them and they don't
know about.
You know what I mean?
But is there a disproportion amount of
people with acne that's succeed?
Apparently it was some study about like
a ton of people who say,
I was a Dork in high school.
I had acne,
I was a loser,
and then they're like ceos of companies
or performance or entertaining like Bill
Murray,
you become funny.
You sort of have to develop some kind of
personality to fit in because you're so
stigmatized.
That line of thinking is a real similar.
It's similarly criticized to the line of
thinking that they use in like the movie
the secret.
Remember that?
I was just talking about the secret.
Yeah.
The problem with that thing is not that
the law of attraction isn't real.
Not if that.
If you don't focus on something and put
your energy towards something,
you're more likely to achieve it.
Then if you don't focus on those things.
Right.
But the problem is you're only looking
at winters,
right?
You're only looking at people who
focused on following the losers.
There's so many of those.
If you just go over 300 million people,
it's easy to find a few thousand super
winters like those people.
You find them and you say,
what made you so successful and they
will tell you,
you know,
I use the power of the law of attraction
and I wrote things and I had a vision
board and I went towards.
But you also like took all the necessary
steps to make that happen.
You also were very disciplined and work
hard,
but some people don't and you also
thought it through correctly,
right?
There's a puzzle in front of you.
You solved it.
All of a sudden I'm the CEO of Exxon.
Obviously I started apple.
Like you have to figure that fucking
thing out.
Just because you made it there doesn't
mean you have like a valid roadmap that
anyone can use and just think positive
and think about the future and make a,
you know,
some sort of vision map.
But it's definitely going to work out.
No,
you have to do all the right things to.
And it's not going to be easy.
Yeah,
most people are going
quit,
but they kind of person who goes to buy
the secret,
it makes a vision board is probably the
same person who's going to do all the
right things hopefully.
Right.
But there's a lot of people that will
try a new thing like that and they sort
of start them out and then they bail on
them.
And I used to do that for a long time.
Fuck,
I did that for a long time.
I would get like those anthony robins
books.
Do you remember Zig Ziglar?
Did he ever listen to that guy?
He was like one of those.
That was a rich one though,
right?
It's like dreaming and become rich or
some shit.
We know how to influence people.
I don't remember.
Zig Ziglar.
He was like something positive thinking
bullshit.
I know it sounds like a English pop
star,
but you mean you would start?
Wait.
So you would start these inspirational
start these programs.
Stop fucking bail on it.
I just,
for whatever reason,
I never completely discipline myself
with any,
any sort of self help program.
I would start them out and then I'd bail
on him.
Yeah,
but it's like everybody has a different.
Like,
I mean,
do you feel like your training is kind
of that now?
Yeah,
but I think even then like it was just a
matter of me just developing as a person
and being able to understand the process
of disciplining myself better because I
was,
I was never very disciplined when I was
younger.
I would just get obsessed with things
and I would do them because that's all I
wanted to do all the time.
Like it never felt like discipline
because it felt like this was something
I wanted to do.
Well,
productivity incorporation makes
dopamine,
right?
So I had to learn after the fact how to
be disciplined.
Discipline is doing a bunch of stuff.
I don't want it.
You strike me as.
I mean one of the most disciplined.
I mean you're certainly one of the most
people I know.
I know.
More disciplined people than me.
Really?
Yeah,
for sure.
Wow.
My friend Cameron Hanes,
I talk about them too much on the
podcast.
People thinking we're gay for you.
Polar bear.
Well,
he's the guy who taught me at a bow hunt
and he runs ultra marathons.
He runs any works fulltime job and as a
family he runs a marathon a day.
You could follow him on instagram.
Yup.
Follow minutes.
Pull up his instagram story.
He lives in Eugene,
Oregon and he runs the Mount Pisgah is
the the mountain.
That's crazy.
He's a fucking savage and I think
there's something to be said though,
like I'm pretty disciplined,
but I think my next step is to be like,
you know what?
Let things be sloppy.
Wake up and don't know where you're
going to fucking do because I am just so
attached to a rigid control.
Well here's the thing though,
as a comic that fuck off instinct is a
good one.
It's good to have because
fuck off is where the ideas come from.
Like I only feel like I can do that
onstage.
This is crazy.
Fucker.
He runs goddamn marathon a day and I'm
not kidding.
Nope,
definitely unhealthy.
He doesn't care.
He's training for something called the
Moab to 40,
where it's 238 miles of running and you
run them through the.
Yup.
Is that takes more than three days?
Yeah,
it takes more than three days.
He did two.
Oh,
five already.
Does he run in sneakers?
Yeah.
Under armour runs in these things called
fat tires.
They've got like a good amount of
cushioning to them because the amount of
pounding,
you're kind of constantly do it.
He likes it that way.
It's just like he's talking to you.
You're talking to extreme volume of
running.
I mean it's just insane or just.
That can't be great.
It's fine running on pavement and he's
running on sometimes runs on pavements.
Sometimes he runs on the road.
I mean he'll run early in the morning
near his house,
you know,
but like this is the lab two.
Oh,
five to 2:30.
Two 40.
We'll have 240.
I've heard it called the 2:40.
I think they changed it to the to 40.
They were calling it the $200.
You get paid what is the question?
But look at the fucking scenery and look
what happens if you slip,
you're looking down,
you're not enjoying this.
Look if you fell like goodbye,
see you.
No one,
no one is surviving.
CanNot help you,
sir.
No,
there will be no trump care that gets
you out of that crevice in between those
rocks.
So this is,
and this is for four days,
more than three days.
I mean they,
they stop and eat.
Yeah,
you stopped.
They get like a snack,
a but the strongest after ours,
they keep running.
They don't go to sleep.
How many runners?
I don't know.
It's interesting.
I think he said a hundred.
Entered the 200.
The big $200.
And he said 45 completed it.
I think those are the numbers.
I don't remember.
40th five.
Complete.
And what is the main element of someone
that completes this?
Is it mental or physical?
It's mental.
It's mental tenacity.
Because first of all,
the physical is involved.
Like you certainly have to be physically
tough to do this,
but the physical toughness is most of
the time dictated by your mental
toughness.
Like the navy seals that make it are
never the biggest or the strongest.
Australia,
it's always like,
you know David Goggins,
that ultra marathon runner,
navy seal character who's like a famous,
a ultra marathon athlete.
He always says that people quit at 40
percent and that yeah,
most people quit at 40 percent.
Forty percent of the kids probably the
place where you get to go.
Like,
I didn't fail.
I stopped when.
No,
you get to go to.
I can't do this anymore.
I gotta stop.
And that's 40 percent of what you're
actually capable of.
So where does mental toughness?
I mean it comes from adversity at a
young age,
right?
And overcome Ken,
but there's no recipe for it,
right?
You could decide that you don't like
being a pussy at 18.
I just started doing Jujitsu and become
like one of the hardest trainers in the
real.
You escalate who you are and who you
become and become some world champions.
Jujitsu burst.
It's been done a bunch of times,
but a bunch of different guys.
A lot of like worlds Jujitsu Champs,
that kind of Nerdy,
Geeky book type characters.
Really amazing.
Yeah.
Crazy.
And they,
they become these like
when you are studying,
I mean it is like you.
It's so precise and it's like the same.
It's geometry and math kind.
The nerd,
right?
There's definitely an equation,
There's definitely some sort of an
interactive equation going on,
but it's also incredibly physical so you
get away with all the physical anxiety
and all the bullshit that most people
carry around with them.
You talk to people like after training
or after class,
everybody like so chilled out,
so relaxed because they just went to war
for an hour and a half.
Everybody's like so chill and afterwards
I like the funnest guys to hang out
with.
Go to dinner and laugh and joke around
and what happens if those people don't
do it for a month?
They get itchy every time you get
injured.
A lot of guys get injured again because
they'll get a surgery and then go into
quick.
Super common
because they need that.
You just want to do it.
You miss it so bad.
Can you go without doing standup before
you start,
like doing bits for your wife?
I never do that.
She'd never tolerated.
But um,
I could probably go.
I mean,
I've gone a month.
Yeah.
But I didn't do that for as long as
you've gone since you started?
Yeah.
Wow.
Um,
that was a long time ago.
I just did it because I was,
I moved in,
I settled into new place and I was uh,
doing a lot of stuff for the UFC when I
was traveling a lot and I was like,
you know what,
I'm just going to just do nothing for
them
doing ufc stuff.
I get so fascinated by the,
like our need for visibility and like
how much do I need and whereas this shit
coming from and do I exist if I'm not on
like I need to work on that thing.
Do we exist when we're not fucking
documented?
And um,
because I sort of took some time off of
being on TV and stuff and then I started
being like,
do I still exist?
Does anyone,
you know?
And because I wasn't seeing a lot as a
kid,
but it's like doing ufc where you're,
you're being heard,
you're being seen,
you're valuable.
People love you,
you know?
Is that the same reward centers in your
brain is performing stands?
No.
No,
it's totally different.
It's,
um,
I'm a representative when I'm doing the
UFC has almost nothing to do with me.
The only thing that has to do with me,
it is true.
It was true.
The officiant auto stuff.
Honestly.
All I'm the one without their,
the fight without that,
what I do is useless.
Right.
So all I'm doing is trying to use my
vocabulary and my creativity in my
understanding what they're doing to best
represent it.
Right.
To honor their hard work.
And so that's what I feel like that is.
So that's so not like I've,
I tried to keep myself
in.
Right,
right.
I mean opinions on tactics and stuff
like that.
It's not like you're a creative point of
view.
Sure.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
I mean it's just my perspective on
performances and the character and the
different interactions between these
different
people's.
Your human for understanding the science
and stuff,
but you're not infusing your incendiary.
It's just a very different feeling than
being stand up.
Like when I go do standup,
it's like I'm going to go and I'm going
to do my act.
Like,
Hey,
here we go,
what's up?
How's it?
And it's about me interacting with
people.
Whereas like doing the USC is really
just about being a representative.
I'm a scientist.
I mean you're kind of a more of like an
yeah,
an analysts,
right?
I'm just,
I'm trying to.
I've seen so many of these things.
I'm like,
what?
What does this represent?
Oh,
I know this code.
This code means left high kicks coming,
you know he's moving this,
he's lifting his leg.
I see where it's coming and because
scaleio is dropping his hands out.
There it is and you call it and it's,
it's representation.
So it's very different than doing
athletes will start or have they already
started getting elective surgeries when
they don't have injuries.
There's only a few that I've ever heard
of that think that that's willing to do
that.
And Brody Stevens actually told me that
was wrong.
One of them was a Tommy John Surgery
where it apparently makes you able to
pitch.
A lot of those guys I think are getting
it,
but I thought it was.
You get it when you need it when your
shoulders.
Fuck
right.
I had read the people were getting an
elective.
Brody said that was bullshit.
So
person three get one knee.
He did one knee and then he did the
other one just as rg three.
That guy from.
Am I saying that right?
Quarterback,
quarterback of the Redskins game?
Yeah.
Didn't he get an elective knee surgery?
Just because they can improve your knee?
Yeah.
When it's not sure.
I have not heard this at all.
That he got one knee done because he had
to.
The running quarterback guy.
I know nothing about sports running
quarterback guy that runs with the guy.
He was on the redskins.
Right.
I've never heard of someone doing that.
I don't know.
I'm just curious if you think that
that's going to start to be a.
it's an off season.
I'm just going to get a new risk because
they can make better ones than genetics
can.
We've talked about that with legs,
like what if they get to the point where
someone breaks a leg and it gets
gangrene and have to move the leg,
but they were replaced with the bionic
leg and it's like the $6,000,000
man.
What if they get you a leg that you can
feel and it works way better than
regular legs?
What would you rather do?
Would you rather be in a wheelchair?
Would you rather be on crutches or would
you rather have a leg that works way
better than a regular leg?
What would you definitely take the
fucking leg?
The bucks way better,
right?
So then if you feel it and it feels like
a regular leg,
what's to stop you from just deciding to
just do the other leg to get your arms
done?
What?
Let me get my neck done on it.
Why not ahead with fuck?
Carry around like that.
For Real,
you just carry somebody around with you.
Send a text message or phone explodes.
I mean,
I feel like we might be moving towards
this.
We now have this,
like where everyone's trying to be a
super human super.
Everyone thinks they're a fucking
athlete.
Well,
I met a guy who didn't have an arm.
He lost his arm.
I forget what the accident was,
but he had a carbon fiber arm with an
articulating hand and it could move from
his thinking.
Well,
I don't think so.
I think he's moving it somehow or
another with his nerves in his forearm.
I think somehow or another that's how
he's moving it.
But I'm not,
I'm not entirely sure.
The idea is that they've had,
um,
people that were there,
they put a,
these sort of electrodes or something to
their head and they can have them
articulate fingers like people that are
paralyzed these mechanical fingers.
But I've,
I've done this thing,
I went to this lab where they do these
tests and we put this helmet on me.
And by thinking about things you can
make a drone fly around by thinking
about like when you're,
when you get,
achieve a certain frequency,
it communicates wirelessly with this
drone,
through this thing that they put on your
head with all these electrodes.
We can actually,
I mean you were just talking about it
with a Kennison.
We can kind of do that.
I mean he was doing that with words,
but I mean this is the shit that I do
with horses is that you can kind of
communicate with them,
with your lines if you're really having
a 50 slash 50 consensual relationship
with them because they're prey animals.
And you can literally just think if your
intention is pure enough.
I mean this sounds like bullshit,
the secret,
whatever.
But if you think about what you want
from them and you're really present and
connected to them,
they will do it.
Wow.
Unbelievable.
And it's like really into horse riding
because they're prey animals,
their prey animals.
So the way that they've evolved,
if anyone cares that there's this book
called Zen Mind Zen horse and talks
about the evolution of the prey animal.
And basically how they can feel fear,
they can feel intention,
they can feel where you want to go and
if you're training to be the lead mayor
of the herd that they look to you and if
you basically anticipate something from
them,
they will fulfill that anticipation.
It's wild.
So it's like we don't use bits,
we don't use saddles and I don't use any
sort of leads and I'll be on him and
I'll lead a little bit with my knees,
but if I just visualize where I want to
go,
he'll just go there.
But if I'm disconnected and,
and just came in from traffic and I'm
just like bullshit,
like thinking about my shit.
He's just like not connected to me and
we'll do anything.
It's hard to achieve.
You have to get to that flow.
Meditative state.
I haven't smoked weed and hung out with
my horse before.
That's an interesting idea.
I've played music and stuff like that,
but maybe I should try that to trough my
amygdala.
Yeah,
just try a little.
Don't get crazy.
Just try a little bit.
That's actually a really good idea
because when you bring anxiety around a
prey animal,
they feel it and they just feel fear and
fear is,
you know what,
there have just been designed to avoid
any sort of companion animal feels the
same thing like dogs love.
No,
I think dogs knowing your high totally,
totally,
totally.
Because they get high with you and her
small.
They not.
Well,
I've had that happen before dog,
that she got a panic attack.
Oh No.
She fucking hit underneath the table.
I wish he was high as fuck as we hop
boxed or me and joey ideas.
Oh Geez.
My office we were doing in my office
with my dog,
Lucy.
Um,
there's this guy that the dog that bit
my year off,
I couldn't find him a home know.
Basically if a dog,
a self soothes that way and it was taken
from his mother too young.
It's always going to sort of be a
liability and I wasn't going to put them
down obviously.
So I sent him.
There's this guy named Stephen Baldwin
and he takes dogs who've been people
knowledge.
Alec Baldwin's brother.
Not like Alec Baldwin.
Oh,
there's a state.
Well he stephan s,
t e F,
f e n,
but Stephen Baldwin might also have a
dog ranch.
In which case on Stephen Ball.
I like to go there immediately.
There's a Stephen Baldwin.
Yeah,
there is senior moment.
Actor Stephen Baldwin,
right?
Your guys.
Stephen.
Stephen,
yeah.
I said Steven,
I hope got.
Probably fucked it up.
That's amazing.
And I've learned a lot today is to
Stephen Baldwins.
There's two others.
Two hogs were handled on.
Fuck me.
Fuck you one hour.
Kelly.
Mark Ruffalo forgot.
Here's the best,
newest hawks.
The best hopes and amazing actor.
He's pretty amazing because he uses hemp
treats for his dogs.
Good move.
Can you chill them out?
Chilling a little bit.
I think that's smart.
Need to pop one?
No,
I put A.
I've been trimming elk steaks and I have
these little scraps,
little scraps,
and give them to the doj the greatest
training aid in the history of
[inaudible].
Just give it to him.
Not Cooked,
right?
Yeah.
Raw.
You can give them one piece of less than
three days.
You have to feed him for three days.
Three days,
yeah.
I have a friend who just gives the dog
like a slab of raw meat every three days
and they don't feed them the second
thing or animals way too much.
Dogs do not need to eat twice a day.
We give him this fucking giant bowl.
All of our dogs are overweight and
overfed.
We're giving them.
We're giving them way more food that
they need and it's terrible on their
joints and just terrible for them.
So I only feed my dogs as training
rewards.
Wow.
Yeah.
They don't use training.
They don't get just a big bowl of food.
They get marrow bones,
they get meat,
they get eggs sometimes,
but they only get feeding throughout the
just running shit.
And your house.
You totally out for the fuck of how many
dogs do you have at your house?
I have three.
Yeah.
So you gotta kind of be running shit
because they're alone right now.
Just plot.
They're in.
Crates are almost always.
Dogs are den animals.
They want to be in credits.
People are always like,
it's mean to put them in crates.
No,
it's not.
They love it.
It's mean to just let them roam around
all the time because then they get
territorial and they think that they
have to control things.
My dogs are guests in my home.
That's the whole deal.
Yeah.
They don't get on the couch.
They don't get to do anything.
That sounds like you're a slave master
kind of sound like a species is to me,
kind of.
I mean I have had my ear ripped off so
I've made some mistakes,
but with my dogs,
dogs really do well.
When you dominate them,
what kind of food do you feed them?
I feed them this place called the way in
this kitchen.
It's just keenwah and Turkey.
Keenwah and beef and chicken and they
come in these frozen things.
Is it a good thing to give them grain?
Does it help them in some way?
I don't know.
They seem to do really well on it.
When I give them store bought food,
I sometimes do that.
Buffalo,
what's it called?
Buffalo wild buffalo or something,
but they start eating grass and I see in
there they puke and I see in there
because they eat grass.
Just sort of restore equilibrium because
they're too acidic.
So they'll start eating grass with that
if that's where they do that.
Yeah.
So some sort of an instinct to restore.
Exactly.
They're not getting enough of certain
minerals and vitamins.
They're not there.
It means they're malnourished and
they're getting it elsewhere.
That's when they start eating dirt.
When they start
eating shit,
they're malnourished.
So,
um,
I give them this stuff and they don't do
that.
Hmm.
So you got this from watching them just
eat grass around the backyard like after
you played them?
Yeah.
The dogs puke up grass.
Are you seeing their poop?
That they have grass in it.
That means that they're having to go
other places for nourishment.
So have you ever tried to feed them?
I know there's a lot of companies that
sell,
like sort of a raw diet for dogs.
That's why I'm asking you this.
They have like these tubes of raw food
that I have,
that's,
I usually only do it for like training.
Um,
but that's what they're designed to eat.
I mean,
they're designed to rob their walls,
you know,
they're just designed to eat raw meat.
This dark,
like,
like I said,
he's the sweetest dog of all time,
but he can barely keep it together when
I have barely.
It's crazy like credit you get jumped up
because also the meat that we eat is
full of antibiotics and chemicals has
been frozen 50,000
times.
There's no fucking blood in it.
You're bringing home this fresh real
meat with no garbage in it,
so he's like,
you're awakening his prime.
His reactions are incredible and his
reactions are way.
They're just,
it's way more extreme.
Be Super Interested in juxtaposing,
like store bought meat and then your elk
meat and seeing what he goes.
I think dude,
either one of them for sure,
but I mean meat is meat.
I think to the dog.
I don't mean.
I bet if you gave him time and allowed
him to discern and hunger was not an
option.
Yeah.
If had already lean towards the elk
towards the bloody stuff,
it's certainly more than that.
Toward then dog food.
If you put the elk down next to a bowl
of dog food,
he would totally ignore the dog.
If you let the dog loose in to ride one
bowl of elk in one bowl of dog food,
they would go to the elk 100 percent of
the time.
The ingredients in dog food,
it's like sugar or sucrose or high
fructose corn syrup.
I mean it's just like trash.
I buy this stuff that has no grain in it
and it's all.
A lot of it is wild game.
A lot of his like lamb and beef and
people talk about their dogs sitting
cancer at five.
Feeding your dog.
Well,
it's also could be like a genetic thing,
right?
Couldn't it be fucked up breed.
But I feel like if I think dogs are
supposed to eat meat,
I would.
I would think that like if you could
figure out a way like I've been thinking
about that lately,
like actually hunting for my dog,
like getting a,
like some food and putting aside just
for the dogs do that.
I always do,
whenever I make eggs,
I'll make some for the dogs.
Yeah,
just grind it up,
like make a and just see if they behave
different.
If they feel there.
Yeah,
sometimes I'll just feed them meat and
then eggs and then a couple days later
I'll just give a.
sometimes I'll just give the marrow
bones for the day.
What's the thinking of is like,
that's like some of the only mass
produced factory farm food that I still
buy.
I mean it's.
Yeah,
it's got to be factory farmed.
I mean they're getting it the cheapest
way they get it.
Right.
If you're buying some sort of dried
chicken
feeding your kids lucky charms,
you know?
Yeah.
Just because the dog's meet.
And then they sleep more,
you know,
it's just probably fart more.
Yeah.
Does he fired a lot?
Sometimes it's not a lot,
but when he.
Does that seem like actually having them
eat meat and see if he farts less
because their bodies are working so hard
to break it down and they have to
methane gas.
There could really be what it is that
when your dogs are fighting,
that means something's up.
It's like when you're fighting a lot.
So it's like one of my wanting to eat.
Yeah.
What's going on?
Why is my body working so hard to break
this down?
Why isn't this digestible?
Do you follow any kind of crazy diet?
You know,
I had eating disorders,
shocker plot twist.
I mean obviously.
Um,
so I have to be careful with that shit.
How'd you get over him?
You know,
a lot of things.
Um,
I like want to do a 12 step program for
codependence,
you know,
which,
and I did this like inner child work.
It all sounds like very hippie and like
ridiculous.
But I had to start re parenting myself
because I grew up around eating
disorders.
I saw a lot of it.
There wasn't a lot of eating in my
house,
there was a lot of eating on the go,
there was nothing in my fridge,
like it just never occurred to me to
take care of myself nutritionally.
But eating disorders are a lot about
control for the most part.
I'm sure you know that.
So it was like my life felt out of
control when I was a teenager and that
was the one thing I could control is
what I aid getting thin also got me
attention.
It got people to like worry about me and
font over me and that I wanted attention
and I think that coupled with like
intense therapy with it and then doing a
job where I get
my sort of
quota of attention in healthy ways that
box is checked.
I no longer need to get attention and
unhealthy ways.
Does that make sense?
So it was basically an attention thing
and also just a bad programming saying
bad conditioning had both of those
things sort of.
Yes.
And I had an adversarial relationship
with my body and with food and um,
it was a very antisocial behavior as
well.
Liked I was able to isolate,
like I in school was not very social.
I have a socially awkward,
I was really scared of people and having
like fucked up eating.
Like you're eating in your car,
you're high,
you know,
you can't really go to dinner with
people.
It's kind of a way that I put a wall up
between myself and other people as well.
Why does a more common a female thing
like from your perspective,
like when you think about like people
having like that,
that phrase,
having an adversarial relationship with
your body.
You don't really hear guys say that
because we have an expiration date and
you guys kind of don't maybe.
And then we also have this sort of,
um,
what is it?
Golden rule,
symmetrical need to look fertile to you
guys where it's like tiny ways,
tiny legs,
big hips,
big boom,
you know,
like I think there's just a lot more
pressure on our bodies because our
bodies are why you guys decided to
protect us and procreate with us or not,
you know?
And then there were of course the social
construction of what's beautiful,
like,
you know,
eating disorders.
I read this amazing book,
I can't remember the name of it,
but how they're eating disorders in
Italy only started when American
television went over there.
And it's like tearing the fabric of
their families because food is how they
show love and connect with each other
and mothers,
you know,
make,
it starts with breastfeeding and then
it's feeding you pasta.
And this and girls stopped eating pasta
and dairy because they started getting
eating disorders and it was like tearing
apart the fabric of Italian families.
Wow.
Amazing
to think about.
But I definitely grew up around a lot of
it.
I saw women,
you know,
I think that we all have such a fucked
up relationship with,
you know,
our children because we tell our kids to
do certain things,
but we don't do those things.
So I heard adults say it like I need to
lose weight,
I need to lose five pounds.
Adults who were not fat.
And so I internalized sort of,
oh,
that's the body that I need minus,
you know,
like I just saw a lot of fucked up shit.
Um,
and women that had adverse ational
really adversarial relation with the
body.
So I just like,
I didn't know any better,
but it seems like a lot of women have
it.
Like from the jump,
right?
I mean,
it's not something that I don't even
know if you're really aware of your
expiration date when you're 16 and 17,
are you think you're not thinking about
your longevity,
right?
You think about your current state.
Yeah.
Women are objectified.
It's such a young age.
You know,
my brother is so good.
He's got these daughters and they're
gorgeous and he always tells people
don't tell them.
They're pretty.
Tell them they're smart at such a young
age.
You're told like,
you're so beautiful.
You're so pretty.
Did it.
Ah.
And whereas boys,
they're like,
you're so cool.
You're so awesome.
You're so good at football or whatever.
So I think from such an early age,
I thought my appearance was the only
thing that I had to offer the world and
I just got really obsessed and
fastidious about like what it looked
like and I just thought I had to be
really skinny at a young age.
How do you talk to kids like that in
that regards?
Very important.
Like instead of saying,
you're so good at that,
you're supposed to say,
see how working hard has paid off this
way.
Yeah,
I suppose to say,
look,
all the times you've gone to class now
you can do this.
This is amazing.
You've progressed.
Also heard.
It's really good because I had struggled
with intense perfectionism in eating
disorders are a big part of that because
I didn't know I was allowed to have
flaws as a kid because my parents I
think always tried to put on a front
that everything was fine when it wasn't.
Whereas what they say you're supposed to
do with kids as fuck up and then course
correct,
and then they get to see resilience.
So you go,
hey,
I was late to pick you up from school
today.
I totally miscalculated the time.
I'm really sorry.
Instead of being like,
oh,
there was a line at the bank and things.
Or just,
you know,
like you don't lie to kids.
You weren't supposed to pretend things
are fine or you're not supposed to
pretend you're perfect to be this hero
to them.
Or if like you're fighting with your
spouse,
you go like,
hey,
we kind of got in an argument and I was
wrong and now we're fine.
You don't say like,
no,
everything's fine.
We were just watching a movie.
It was the sound from the TV,
you know,
you don't lie to them.
Right,
right,
right.
And I never had any of that.
I just got the message very young and
like I had to be perfect and then.
And that's the way of traffic.
See that's very rare that boys get the
thin message.
Just what I'm trying to get to it.
It's like it's odd that it hits
just the opposite.
You have to be muscular and strong.
I mean,
I recently just learned that men like
have body image stuff.
I just had no idea,
but it just manifests in different ways.
Right.
It's like you guys have to be like cut.
You have to be big.
You have to be,
you know,
have a big Dick.
Like you guys have all that Shit Shit.
Yeah.
Some men do have the,
the fat,
like where
it really bothers him.
Really books their heads,
they're eating salads all over the
place.
There's a lot anorexic,
no question about it.
I mean it just.
Especially when you're trying to course
correct,
you know,
like you've got,
you decide,
okay,
I'm going the other way.
I'm going to fucking like,
you look at yourself in the mirror,
you get disgusted,
you know,
like I'm not eating.
I see a lot of guys and I'm curious your
take on this because you're such a big
part of this world of like these guys
who are like,
I'm Paleo,
don't eat anything,
and I'm like,
this is still fucking rigid and fucked
up and I see guys with their cricket
protein.
I dated a guy who just ate dry protein.
I'm like,
this is a fucking eating disorder.
You know,
like when is it healthy?
When does it go into disorder than
dysfunctional.
It's unnecessary based on the results
that you get from it,
right?
It's like,
okay,
if you just eat healthy foods and you
take like say.
I mean depending upon how much training
you're doing,
you might want to take a protein
supplement.
Occasionally you get to take something
that's easily digestible,
concentrate on macronutrients,
concentrating on getting most of it from
your food,
but making sure you balance things out
with supplements.
Once you do all that,
like why are you eating dry protein
dude,
just eat some food,
get a nice piece of salmon and the salad
and it's going to be way better for you
than what you're eating.
If it's irrational.
I used to have such an irrational fear
of fat,
like I would go to a restaurant order
steamed vegetables.
If there was oil on it,
I would like pat it down.
Like it was like insanity.
It was.
But,
but eating disorders are not logical
completely.
They become more like a mirage.
Like I used to only eat like dried
fruit,
which is so fucking bad for you and
fattening.
It's pure sugar,
you know?
It's not logical.
So good.
Yes,
but then it would like go to the gym for
four hours.
It's like I wasn't even good at having
an eating disorder.
I like,
you're not even eat.
I was eating 4,000
calories a day.
It's like,
what?
You're not even good at being anorexic,
so it's like I just,
it becomes so irrational and you just
get so a logical and you just have so
many blind spots about,
but don't you think you just know a
whole lot more about nutrition now too
because like when this is going on,
like say say,
say back to like 20 years ago,
how many people really knew how to eat
correctly.
Everybody was eating whole grain bread
and they thought that was the way to go.
Everything there wasn't this like high
fructose corn syrup and fucking
everything and like antibiotics and
garbage and everything.
We didn't notice there was that,
but we didn't understand like what your
body actually needed.
We were trying to go low fat with
everything like everybody was trying to
go with low fat yogurt.
Low fat milk has sugar in it.
It's disgusting.
Put sugar in it because otherwise,
yeah.
There's also this rat king's rat kings.
Kings are now saying,
I saw a photo of a bunch of dead ones
all tangled together by the tail and
they just starve to death.
Well,
is that what a rat king is?
A rat king is when
they're.
They all get tangled together.
Retails get tangled and then they shared
in an all congeals and they just turned
into a mass of rats and then they starve
to death and die.
Oh,
Jesus.
No.
How do they get all tangled up?
Like,
I don't know.
It doesn't make a lot of sense.
All.
I mean they are
pretty.
But Sinewy.
I've never seen this before.
Jamie King?
Yeah,
there it is right there.
So that's one way.
Tails on your it out or they get stuck
together,
aren't they?
Like kind of slimy.
Guess if I had a gas that they spend too
much time in a very small area,
I would imagine.
Scroll King.
Those squirrels got accidentally
intertwined.
No,
no.
That's heartbreaking.
What are they going to do?
Don't get eaten by coyotes.
Fox Goes,
hold on,
but that bother you.
This predation bother you.
Like you love animals,
but I do love animals.
Here's what I'll say.
Your deal,
because you do it from an angle of like
conservation is I think is amazing.
Well,
I sort of do it for,
from an angle of conservation,
well,
but you have more food,
mostly foods number one,
but conservation is a consequence of
trying to seek out food that way because
the money that's spent goes directly to
try to preserve the habitat where these
animals live and to keep things public
to keep all this land like we have
millions of acres of land
public.
Yeah.
I know that we need predators in order
to look for things to make sense like
that.
Why,
you know,
wolves being reintroduced into
yellowstone basically everyone,
you know,
like you call out a couple and more
people more get to live,
right.
Not People.
Um,
but I'm sort of obsessed with that.
And also,
I mean just understanding that like kind
of such a big key to,
you know,
whatever as this sounds ridiculous,
but I don't know why I have shame about
like giving a shit about the
environment.
Um,
I don't know when being into the
environment became like,
I mean that's quite lame,
but it's like I think it's 240,000
gallons of water for one cow and we only
eat 40 percent of cows,
normally,
50 percent of its body,
percent of his body if we are so
wasteful and the way that you do it,
which is like you're eating every part
of the body and don't you eat it for
like months at a time and stuff.
I think what you're doing for the
environment is amazing.
Well,
I think that's a consequence of just
being selfish and selfish.
Not in a bad way,
but so,
I mean the honest word is selfish
because my feelings about meat where I
really enjoyed eating meat and I,
I was thinking like,
well let me look at it from a health
perspective.
And boy,
if you look at it objectively,
there's a lot of shit that vegans try to
point out.
But if you look at it objectively,
there's almost nothing that shows that
eating meat with vegetables is bad for
you.
Well,
they do these different speeds.
Is that true?
What does,
what actually matters to me?
What?
This mic.
I'm sorry.
Why am I doing this?
What's wrong with me?
I'm rusty on my podcast.
I know because I'm actually trying to
talk to you.
I keep forgetting we're on a job.
It just gets weird,
but is it.
I mean because our teeth are sharp.
This is proof.
We're designed to be predators.
I were more
omnivores.
We're not predators because if we're a
predator,
if we were capable of did this like the
argument against us being predators by
like really like argumentative vegans
who they give these speeches about.
If we were really predators,
we would have fangs.
We'd be able to eat things raw.
You know,
we are just opportunists.
We are heatedness and we don't need to
live like this and they argued that
because our intestines are longer,
but here the arguments not good.
Here's why it's not good.
We evolve to kill animals and cook them
and then chew them up and eat them.
We've been doing that for thousands of
years.
That's why we looked this way and we
don't look like chimps,
chimps,
they,
they cannibalize chimps.
Eat monkeys or chimps.
Eat a lot of monkeys.
Jesus,
a lot of monkeys,
one of their favorite.
They eat them alive.
They tear them apart.
Is must much video of chimps,
particularly in the Congo,
grabbing monkeys out of trees and eating
them along.
Just tearing them apart with their hands
champs.
What?
Rip.
That guy's face off.
Yes.
Chimps are the closest to us.
Of course.
They're super humid.
Yeah,
they're so.
They're so close to what we are there,
like one step left or right of the
evolutionary chain.
Something like 90 to 99 percent of our
DNA.
Insanely strong,
insanely strong.
Like we can't even rationalize.
Smaller than gorillas,
way smaller,
but as strong as a 500 pound man,
like a 150 pound chimpanzees like
literally like bigger than a game of
thrones guy just rip you apart like you
don't.
You'll never be able to understand the
amount of power they can generate with
their limbs.
My concern is more where does it meet
Greg?
Right?
But the way that we eat meat is actually
killing us in the longterm and
destroying our planet.
So much that we're just going to fucking
go extinct if we don't just do it in the
kind of way that you do it.
Yeah.
There's some chimps,
right?
They're tearing apart a monkey.
See the little hands.
Holy Fuck.
Why does that look like a gorilla to me?
Now that's a chimp.
That's a straight up chimp.
That's a big ass fucking tearing that
monkey apart.
I had no idea that they meet.
Their favorite thing was the thing they
love more than anything.
It's just hard to get a monkey when they
get a monkey.
They don't give a fuck about a banana.
So what's it resumed?
Chimps and gorillas?
Gorillas are vegetarians.
We're 100 percent vegetarian.
Yeah.
Yep.
Huge.
The biggest primates we know of,
they have these giant fangs and that's
just for war,
you know,
that's just one gorilla takes care of
like,
you know,
a gang of bitches and grill has tiny
little Dick Taylor because penis sizes
and testicle size is directly
proportionate to the amount of
promiscuous females in the area.
So with chimps,
chimps have giant balls because all
chimp women are hoes and these bitches.
Just slinging that pussy from branch to
branch.
It's not white.
Dick's human decks evolve to have that
little hook at the end of scoop out the
competitors seem.
That's why the bigger head is more
successful because it's like a plunger
and there pulls it out to circumcision.
Fuck that up.
I wonder.
I bet it does.
I'm sure.
I'm sure it would.
Yeah.
You're going to hear all about this
tonight at the icehouse circumcision.
I used to have a whole series of bits
about it.
Really?
Yeah.
It's.
It's insane.
It's one of the last insane rituals that
we almost universally,
right people lose penises every year.
There are many kids every year that lose
their penis due to infection where they
never get a dick their entire life
because somebody wanted to go through a
ritualistic Dick.
Skin cutting and a bait beside the
religious argument for it and also the
sanitation argument no longer makes
sense.
We had purell.
Now we can disinfect.
It's such a stupid argument.
It's like in the argument is that
there's a direct connection to the
amount of people who are uncircumcised
who also have HIV in Africa.
The way it was explained to me like,
yeah,
but the people that are uncircumcised
also probably weren't taking care of
themselves,
weren't in a good family environment
where they went through ritualistic
things,
who knows what they were exposed to,
what can I intervene intravenous drugs?
What kind of lack of food and
nourishment?
What kind of diseases do they encounter?
The crush their immune system.
You know,
what part of Africa they.
Yeah.
What,
what is the prevalence?
Have they actually been tested positive
for HIV or as we were dealing with a t
cell count issue,
like what has this been establish that
these people have aids?
Like what?
What's causing it?
Well,
there's also all this,
um,
these metrics coming out now that it's
emotionally traumatizing,
which makes it,
that men can't express their feelings.
Eighty percent of the men that are
circumcised have a harder time
expressing their feelings.
It was like something I read.
And uh,
yeah,
because the only woman that you have
ever met gives you a stranger when
you're five days old and cuts your Dick
off in front of people.
And when you start crying,
they just start clapping and taking
pictures.
Of course you're going to not distrust
one.
Literally heard this come out of a
lady's mouth.
I did it to my son because I don't want
it to look gross for him.
Oh my God.
She's like,
I don't want to a little gross called
child services.
So you're allowed to do it.
That's what's crazy of circumcision.
It is insane that it has even legal.
Imagine if it didn't exist and then
someone came along off women's vaginas.
There would be riots in the story.
I mean,
I've heard some really crazy fucking
arguments from people that are super
ultra progressive that start going down
the rabbit hole with Islam where they
don't want to criticize anything.
Someone called it egalitarianism.
Gender Surgery.
That the,
the genital mutilation was some sort of
egalitarian gender surgery as like men
and women.
Yeah,
women.
But women,
women,
which is to cut off your clit.
It's not the same thing.
A lot of porn stars do that first set of
Grayson,
Slavia Prostate,
you know,
like in porn will cut their clinicals.
The enemy.
Yes.
Do you ever see a vagina cut their
currency?
Vagina?
You want me to draw it?
You're a few.
See vaginas that don't have the chicken
gizzard?
No,
that's the Labia plasty.
And they do it for aesthetic reasons
because they have the,
they've got that like,
you know,
the mud flaps,
but yeah,
they've got the kind of of Oyster vibe
going but this,
the tourists get cut
there as well,
which is like you guys are watching porn
with these girls that don't,
that are generally mutilated and aren't
even having orgasms.
And you're being lied to.
Yeah.
So if the vagina doesn't have this on
it,
you know them.
They went to one of those,
a strip mall plastic surgeons and got
that thing shaved off nights.
It's like you.
I've seen porn where I'm like,
where's her Lavia?
What is going on?
They're just cutting them right off to
numb the outside edge of your pussy and
resetting the attractive.
Yeah.
No.
And,
and that is what's causing so many
problems because you're seeing that fake
vagina and then you see a real one and
you're like,
oh,
this is ugly.
It's like,
no,
this is just what a vagina looks like.
It's like the new voluntary female
circumcision.
Sorry,
Toro Hood reduction is.
We do need to change the name of that.
Look under the hood and everybody.
I'd really rather not a Hoodie,
a Hoodie.
That's at least a little more daring
relatively.
Oh my God.
Was it worth it?
Look at this.
Reviews costs pictures.
I have friends who have gotten the
vaginal rejuvenation surgery and they
said it was more painful than childbirth
and what they do is they ask you do you
want to go back to 16,
18 or 21.
They ask you what age you want to go
back to 12 girls at different amounts of
sex at those ages.
So it's like I want her 21,
not my 21.
Fuck kind of question is.
I know it's disproportionate to the
amount of people that get circumcisions
versus the amount of people to get
Libya.
That rejection is somewhat consent.
I mean you're choosing to do it.
I mean,
you probably aren't all there if you're
a porn star anyway,
but like I just think doing it when
you're five days old isn't particularly
fair.
It's so unfair.
It's so crazy that it's the norm.
It's more common than norm.
I think something like 75 percent of
American men,
it's so unnecessary and it doesn't do
any good.
It's not,
and it gives some numbness to do you
know guys who are uncircumcised that say
it feels way better when you're
uncircumcised?
Yeah,
exactly.
How do you.
I'm just talking shit but might be
worse,
but it's a thin layer of mucous develops
over the head of the Deq where it's like
protected by the skin.
It stays moist in there and supposedly
more sensitive.
Whereas after you've had your four skin
remove this,
dried out so numb,
but also cut some nerve endings,
which is actually,
you know what?
Maybe you guys do need less nerve
endings.
I actually think if all men weren't
circumcised,
nothing would ever get done.
That's probably jerking off all day if
you can.
If everybody gets sucked around Dick
circumcised.
That's the reason why everybody comes
like just short.
Maybe that's why our country has such a
prolific GDP because the men are
circumcised and it does suck.
If sex felt any better,
we'd have a real problem on our end.
Maybe if you go to a and it's like super
advanced,
you know,
that the dick size is directly
proportional to the face to how far the
face can get down on most men.
They're on deck.
I'm just curious.
Oh yeah,
there's a dude.
There's a dude online that uh,
someone sent me a video of this guy
literally fucking his own face.
It was so disturbing.
He was doing a shoulder press.
Yeah.
He was doing a shoulder press,
whereas like his neck was flat on the
ground.
Okay.
And then his body was like super
flexible and it was up like his back was
this and he was bent over,
so down that he was literally deep
throating his own deck.
And then he,
he just,
his own mouth pulled out,
like kept jizzing on its own phase and
then stuck it back in his mouth again.
Yeah.
And I saw it and I can't unsay it.
Somebody sent it to me.
It was an animated Gif and I was like,
you motherfucker can't believe.
How about that one that Nick Swardson
sent us the other day with the fist.
You didn't remember that one guy that
fucking asshole nick.
And he said stuff.
Nick sends me.
It's just I've become desensitized to
it.
It's a guy carrying a guys.
If I imagine if you had a backpack in
front of you,
you have a couple of chains going with
the three of us go a girl with a gun?
No,
it's one where a guy literally,
it's like his arm is soaped up.
There's all white foam all over his arm
and he's got a guy and he is like
literally elbow deep inside of this
guy's ass and he's picking them up and
putting them down.
And the sledding fist.
It could be anything.
I don't.
No bear spray.
Hold up Mr.
Mace I fuck with Mace is a fucking lube.
I'm looking through our chain and it's,
it's pretty horrific.
Yeah.
There's a lot of horrific shit and that
shit.
Oh,
I see.
Wait,
is this the thing with the guys goes?
He said,
yeah,
that's it.
Oh,
click on it.
Oh God,
I don't know this.
This might be more upsetting than r
Kelly.
Real tall weight.
It's not playing so it's still know what
is this?
No,
that's not the one.
Sorry.
That's the one where dudes fucking to do
that,
but that's still the one with all of us
together is a isn't there a way you can
do it?
There's a way you can go to just the
things that had been texted and just he
gets drunk and it'll just hurt your
feelings.
Animated gift like,
Hey,
one quick adrenaline and I'm learning a
lot on this text chain.
You can learn a lot.
Humbling.
Quite frankly.
I'm like,
am I supposed to be doing this?
Am I supposed to be doing this?
Is this what the kids are doing?
I can't.
I can't keep up with this stuff.
No one can keep up with anything
anymore.
Establish what.
Who is that a real thing?
You're willing to take it to a level,
sort of like ultra marathon running,
you know,
like why are you running 200,
five miles?
You just taking it at durance and mental
strength to a level that very few people
can to fisting
is not only why I let you fuck my ass,
but I'll let you ball up your chickens
pause and the whole design.
That's a pathological.
I'm saying why do people get their face
pierced?
Why?
Why do people have robot?
I want to be stigmatized and I want to
be a part of a tribe,
but like getting fisted in private.
It's not about acceptance or maladaptive
behavior.
That's like,
it's about taking things to the next
level.
Like a lot of things people do sexually
is to try to freak out the other
partner,
to let them know that they're on another
level.
Like I'm on some super freak level it
put in my ass baby.
Like I'm at the point where I'm like,
you know,
it'd be really kinky missionary.
Like the craziest thing you can do these
days.
Yeah,
let's get crazy.
Let's kiss during sex and I'll be on the
bottom,
but some people know,
right?
Some people want to do freak shit and
then if someone's going to want to do
freaky shit,
there's always gonna be someone who
wants to take it to the next level and
show,
you know,
I'm a super freak.
I'm not a regular fee.
He could fill me motherfucker.
But then the next thing you know,
do you think that this is all the people
who don't get to do what you get to do
and fight people and do comedy.
Like people that don't get to get those
extreme needs met,
they might not have ever found a path
for them to sort of express themselves
through and then they're,
they're spiraling out of control with
like poor programming and shitty
relationships with their family and
friends that are fucked up.
And all that leads to someone fist up to
your sign up for an open mic at the
comedy store or something else.
You know?
I mean,
the thing is like everybody's
personality would lend itself to a
different kind of pursuit and it's one
of the real problems.
Like some sort of a cookie cutter
existence,
like the idea that you in any way,
shape or form would be most happy in a
cubicle is patently insane.
It's insane.
Insane.
Literally.
Oh look,
you're good to put your star wars toys
up in the typical nerd guy.
Is fisting new because we're all in
cubicles or has it always been around?
Even when we were fighting each other in
the streets?
Well,
you got to think during the Roman
Empire,
somebody fisted somebody right?
Constantly.
For sure.
They were going so deep.
They were crazy.
They were.
They were literally trying to be as
hedonistic as possible.
I was just.
I was just at the Coliseum and amazing
and I don't know that much about it,
but it was funny.
I was like,
this is fucking barbaric,
and the tour guide was like a.
nothing is as barbaric as nfl.
Like these.
She was like,
these were like criminals.
These are people who were going to die
anyway.
They only did these spites once every
couple months if the emperor wasn't into
it.
They didn't do it at all.
They were like,
you guys routinely have people killing
each other on television and you guys
chair?
Yeah,
sort of.
They brought in lions,
animals.
They were but allied animals extinct.
Yeah.
They made species of animals extinct
because they used them in the coliseum
so much.
I
didn't know that.
Oh yeah.
Good.
That up.
I read that just a few days ago that
they were talking about what they were
doing was actually reenacting wars that
were.
Because they didn't have newspapers.
They were like doing reenactments and
stuff and people will get injured,
but a lot of them,
when they told you they put water in
there and had boat fights,
you're like,
what?
What?
How?
Why were you guys more advanced than we
are today?
They had seaworld,
seaworld.
They had like a show,
like they have actually seaworld show,
like a water world show at universal.
Oh really?
I didn't know that.
Yeah,
it's fucking pretty bad at it.
It's like this choreographed waterworld
scenarios.
People,
people shooting at each other and shit.
What is this?
Who fighting killed off whole species?
Yeah,
the sheer quantity and slaughter in the
coliseum.
Saw the number of lines Jaguars and
tigers plummet across the globe
according to some Roman hunting,
absolutely devastated the wildlife of
North Africa and the entire
Mediterranean region,
wiping some species of animals off the
map.
Entirely thousand
animals,
particularly irritable
set of games in which 9,000
animals are slaughtered.
The hippo disappeared from the River
Nile at North Africa.
They were fighting elephants that will
use an elephants and lions and and some
of the lines escaped and Tigers had
leaped to the front.
Rows were the richest people lived or
the richest people have their seats and
killed the richest people and so they
had to develop these fence systems all
around and they had to raise the whole
thing.
This guy was like explaining how they
had to protect the rich people sat in
the front row.
I think that's fucking amazing.
Those lions are awesome.
Could you.
I hear they're going to start putting
nets up at baseball games.
Going to be from baseball.
Baby got hit by a ball,
got a baby,
baby,
baby nets and all the baby to a baseball
game.
Is the baby dead?
I don't know.
I didn't ask,
I didn't want it now,
but there's going to be no,
it happened in hockey after a girl got
hit by a puck and where I'm from,
but hockey pucks slow down,
but baseball's like don't as quickly or
something.
It killed her.
She died.
The girl in Columbus died.
That's why they have nets up all over.
Like every entrepreneur.
The pucks aren't flying into the crowd.
It used to get hit by a puck.
No,
used to be a thing to catch a puck when
it came into the crowd,
like a foul ball and baseball because
they would flip over and whatnot.
But they started flying because people
got better and hidden faster.
Slap shots.
So they had.
Now there's like a net up almost.
You almost can't.
A hockey arena at least nhl.
Where did it hit her in like a like I
think it here in the head.
Yeah.
I'm sure she wasn't sitting very super
close,
but I mean most good seats now.
So they're all good seats,
et cetera.
Hit it.
I'll get in trouble.
I mean I guess get a pat on this.
Is your mom yelling you?
Well that one guy got mom,
I killed that lady in the audience.
Do you do you get paid more money
because you're so good at hitting and I
got an assault charge that for hitting
the guy with the stick,
but that was like player on player.
That's different.
Illegal or within
sexual assault.
Under ticket it says like you're
assuming all the risk of potential debt,
whatever can happen to you at the event
eating puck,
but yeah,
so now,
but now I'm.
All baseball fields are going to have
nuts.
Some of the worst idea in the world.
People died from it,
but the nerfing of the world continues
to say you can't bring children and
babies.
Baseball just different because it's
like American mass time.
Yeah.
I think you should wear gloves and don't
bring a baby.
That's my take on it and if the ball's
coming,
you got to be paying attention all the
time.
Don't leave your kid alone.
You've got to be there with the fucking
glove tonight.
Mayor should be able to show that you
can catch a 90 mile an hour.
I mean,
do you think that,
is that going to like kill baseball to
have to look through nets?
Well,
what's happened to all sports is their
nerf and things up.
Right?
And that's the big thing that Donald
Trump got criticized for the most was
when he said that the,
uh,
not just the thing about the players
kneeling,
what?
That they're killing the game with all
these safety regulations.
Like,
wait a minute,
man,
regulations.
These people are,
they're changing the rules at 35,
all of a sudden they are getting fucked
up and do something.
All the things that are supposedly
making them safer,
the helmets are actually becoming
weapons and the things that they're
entering each other.
But the people that believe that.
And I,
I tend to believe that a rugby is a
superior sport.
I was no helmet,
no helmets,
no helmet.
See,
I'm not a fan of either one.
Not that I don't.
If I wanted to walk,
if I had to choose to watch one,
since I don't give a fuck who wins the
superbowl?
I don't,
I don't watch it.
Right?
But about choose to watch somebody said,
hey,
you wanna go to a rugby game or football
game.
Like I want to go see a rugby game.
Yeah.
They don't have any helmets or pads on
like that's real,
but they're not hitting each other the
way that they do and can't.
You would die.
You would.
You'd break your body,
you'd break your teammates.
Everybody would get fucked up.
They hit each other a lot.
Don't get me wrong.
It's a rough game,
but it's a smarter and it's more
realistic game.
It's like putting on this stupid outfit.
No offense guys,
but all that shit.
You're doing all those.
If you're such a bad ass,
why do y'all pads on?
Like what is this?
The only reason why you're able to run
at each other full clip is because of
past crazy.
Take that stupid shit off and you'll get
a more honest representation of what's
possible when people collide with each
other and you'll have way less scaled
ahead of just brute force.
Exactly.
Do you think there will ever be a day
where there's no nfl?
I mean,
no nfl.
Yeah.
Um,
I would hope that the NFL would just go
to a more rugby based system.
Obviously.
Look,
I'm an idiot.
Don't listen to me.
If you're an nfl fan you love,
you don't understand the game relatively
trivial days.
I don't know shit about nfl,
but I know that wearing helmets,
like if it's the same thing to me about
like striking with boxing gloves,
I think to be bare knuckle I think we'd
be safer.
I think you'd have.
Fighters would have less brain trauma.
You wouldn't even strike less,
wouldn't be able to just openly start
wailing on someone.
You just shatter your hands.
It's not that easy.
So you're more um,
but you know,
calculated and much more calculated you.
There's much more emphasis on accuracy.
You couldn't just hit somebody as hard
as you want to.
Like the thing about having pants
gloves,
it's like if you're going to punch a
door,
right,
like a real wood solid wood door and you
just knock on that door full blast,
man,
you're going to get fucking hurt.
But you can kind of punch a door like
this.
So you could do that.
And it doesn't really hurt,
but you can hit some on a bunch of times
like that and it doesn't hurt you if you
have bare knuckle.
But if you have pads,
if you have pads on your knuckles
pitching and hitting and hitting and
hitting lamb that table,
and it doesn't hurt at all.
You're literally not capable of punching
full blast with knuckles all the time.
Especially if you hit like an elbow or
you hit a forehead.
Guys shatter their hands on people's
foreheads.
Your Ford is a dome that's good for
headbutting like this area.
It's so hard to break that and you're
not going to break it with a hand.
But if you hit someone right here,
it's pretty devastating.
This is a more softer.
It's more flat.
You can get a good impact on it.
But if you catch this bridge like a lot
of times people break their hand
catching this bridge.
So what happens is the curve of the head
runs into the middle of your hand
because you're just trying to tee off,
right?
And if you're in a fight and you're just
trying to swing as hard as you can,
if you hit forehead and the curve,
that forehead hits the middle of those
fingers,
like we're the.
It's the weakest area.
It's almost like bends in between the
joints.
They snap and they also snapped back
here.
The snap on the top of the hand,
particularly the last two knuckles.
These aren't really connected to the
rest of your,
your arm,
these two knuckles or what you're
supposed to concentrate on because
there's sort of reinforced by the risk.
But they break too.
Your whole hand brakes.
Fans are super fragile.
Making me wonder,
like the same way,
like Michael Phelps was just born to
swam,
right?
His Wingspan,
his heart,
you know,
all that shit.
Are there people whose faces are just
born to fight?
Oh,
for sure.
Wow.
Faces were born for sure.
They can take more impact,
wider faces,
bigger heads,
thicker next for sure.
They can absorb better.
Everybody can get knocked out because of
the human body is just so flawed.
Especially if you have like some crazy
Alistair overeem type character kick you
in the head,
anyone can get knocked out,
but it's less likely to get knocked out
if you're shaped a certain way and your
hands,
the shape of your hands makes a giant
difference as well.
It's like how much impact you can
deliver.
Like if you have someone like us,
like George Foreman had enormous hands,
like there's a guy named Francis and
Ghana was like one of the top UFC
heavyweights.
Every time I shake his hands I just go
with Jesus.
He's got these fucking hammers,
like these giant hammers and he just
knocks people just dead.
He's,
it's a huge advantage.
Structural advantage.
It's like the difference between having
a ball peen hammer,
a little tiny hammer nails and having a
sledge hammer is literally as a
difference.
You know?
It's just the having that extra weight
on the end as a.
especially if there's a lot of,
you know,
a lot of body mass behind it as well.
Just a massive.
You want there to be no gloves,
so look at his hands,
the sizes motherfucker saying yeah,
they're enormous.
Seemed Fair.
There were enormous.
Yeah.
That's Brian stand by the way.
Who was the UFC or the WC 205 pound
champion.
Okay.
He,
uh,
was a UFC fighter,
a top UFC fighter at 185 pounds.
He's a big boy.
He lives.
His arms get dwarfed by in Ghana whose
hands it looks like a stump.
So that,
that is an undeniable physical advantage
if you can land that punch more dumbed
head.
Yeah,
there's a lot of shit going on.
But my point is that if fights had no
pads,
we would get a more accurate
representation of what the body can
really do.
Instead we're making fighters get more
damaged because you're letting people
tee off.
I don't think you should be able to tape
your risks either.
I think that's unfair to because you
can't.
Gives it,
make it stiffer so it doesn't buckle as
much when you impact something because
when you hit something of your handles
like that,
you can really fuck your wrist up.
And when you really get torn tendons,
all competition,
they'll put like cement and their gloves
and they have.
Yeah.
Margarito did that.
Yeah,
he,
um,
he was fighting,
a bunch of different guys and busting
them up really bad.
And then before his fight with sugar,
Shane Mosley,
they caught him in the locker room with
plaster in the wraps of the gloves.
Somebody caught them and then they
started putting two and two together and
realizing like when he beat up Miguel
Cotto,
when he beat up all these different
fighters,
it was an unusual beating.
Like he was hitting them and it was just
having an,
an,
an inordinate,
inordinate effect on them.
Like hitting people way harder than
anybody else was.
No one could figure out why.
Once they took that way worse because
Lance Armstrong was doing that when
everybody else was also doing that.
No one else was putting too much and
people are gonna start getting
suspicious.
Well,
they weren't,
he wasn't necessarily beating everybody,
but he was beating a lot of guys.
And the way he was beating him,
he was fucking them up.
And then when he got the sugar Shane,
they caught him with the plaster.
They took it out.
Rewrap his hands and Sugar Shane beat
the fuck out of him.
And sugar.
Shane knew about it.
Everybody knew about it.
They were talking about it on the,
uh,
on the broadcast and that they were
almost not letting him fight and they
let him fight with new,
newly wrapped hands and sugar.
Shane just lit him up like a Christmas
tree.
Fucked him up.
And then manny Pacquiao fucked him up to
everybody fucked up.
Why do you get to.
I mean,
he should've been.
He should've been probably retired from
boxing.
They should've said there's no way you
could ever fight again were just like,
we want to see you get killed a couple
of times.
Yeah.
I mean he was never the same guy and he
actually wound up fighting.
He had a really badly torn retina to the
point where I think they put an
artificial retina from one of the
beatings that he took.
I think two sugar.
Shane.
It might've been the pack.
Yeah,
it might've been the packout beat him.
Beat him bad.
There's a couple of guys beat the fuck
out of him,
but it's just that guy was putting
plaster and his gloves.
Gloves are the way to go.
I mean if you want to do it for boxing,
I get it.
Boxing is a completely different sport
and there's an art to catching punches
on the gloves and.
But my thing about mma in particular is
why is it okay to elbow someone in the
face,
but it's not okay to have gloves that
are like bare knuckle.
That's crazy.
You could literally smash someone's
reading this and this.
Yeah,
you could smash someone's head with an
elbow like right in their eye socket and
that's totally legal.
You could smash their nose to a pulp
that's totally legal,
but some are like a shin.
You can hit someone so hard with your
Shin.
It's a razor blade.
Ultimately it's a baseball bat.
Kick someone in the head with a shin.
It's crazy.
There's no padding out of the all,
but you have to have in your fists.
That's crazy.
Is that it's old.
We left.
It's when the UFC first came about,
it was beer and alcohol and then in,
in some sort of a,
you know,
sort of concerted effort to turn into a
legitimate sport and be accepted by
athletic commissions.
It's pretty new,
very new in terms of big time sports.
It was started in 1993,
so it's just 20 something years old,
24 years old.
So they wanted to make it look like in
the beginning of the first fights that I
saw in [inaudible] 97 when I first
started working for the UFC,
there was a lot of bare knuckle
fighters.
Guys fought with shoes on.
They were bare knuckle.
You were allowed to grab people's
crotches still.
You rather grab their clothes are
Kelly's.
Yeah.
Not that a little different.
You were,
you're allowed to do a lot of shit.
You could pull hair for a long time.
They finally got rid of that.
They got rid of grabbing clothes,
but you didn't have to have knuckle
padding on your knuckles back then.
And the people that were super
successful realize you could hit people
way harder if you have patty on your
knuckles.
So Vito Belfort was one of the first
night he was 19 years old and you enter
into the UFC,
UFC 12,
Dothan,
Alabama in 1997 and just beat the fuck
out of everybody with gloves on.
What would it take for them to do a rule
that said no gloves anymore?
They just have to listen to me and
listened to a lot of other martial arts
fans.
Some people wouldn't want because they
think you would get cut more,
which I think you would.
You would get more superficial tissue
damage.
But I think ultimately you'd get less
brain damage I think because you can get
him less.
Yeah,
I think you'd get hit less.
And especially if you practice
correctly,
I think you could,
uh,
I mean you would still run the risk of
getting elbowed indeed and kicked and
it's not safe by any stretch of the
imagination.
Do you think it has to get to a point
where because I'm so young,
we're fighters or 60 and they're blowing
their brains out and doing what nfl
players are doing?
Anybody would.
I don't think people would have to know
or hear about a concussion crisis and
mma that much,
but it's real.
I mean any sort of combat sport you're
going to have it.
No,
I mean I know it's there but it's not
like in the zeitgeists really at the
moment it isn't yet,
but it certainly could be and it
probably certainly will be when some of
the veterans get into their sixties and
seventies and we start to see them.
Like,
do you ever see Joe Frazier before he
died?
He was on my throat.
He was on Opie and Anthony Show and he
was so bad.
His,
his snoring and his inability was on
Howard.
It was like floyd mayweather.
I don't think he's showing any signs.
Stuttering.
Maybe just.
Yeah,
maybe it's just 5:00
AM.
Five am nervous.
Maybe try and get it together or talking
to Howard and you know,
probably has zero come left and his body
was it all night long,
right?
For sure.
For too much comment.
His mouth.
What does this.
They have a Ct.
He tests,
they think of boston university.
THey found a biomarker.
they think that can let people know now
ahead of time before it doesn't interest
you get your bell rung three times and
they sort of know that already because
it's not.
It varies upon the person.
Some people are way more durable for
some reason.
They don't know why and it could be also
connected what we were talking about
before,
the actual shape of the head,
the thickness of the muscles of the
neck,
the ability to keep the head from
snapping back too much.
How many times it actually happens,
how good you are.
Avoiding things and roll.
Like some people get hit and then they
learn how to roll with stuff and it
takes a tremendous amount of impact off.
So you think what mma fighters are in
their sixties and seventies and it's not
looking good.
They might consider.
I don't think they're going to consider
it Because I think to the general public
gloves mean safer gloves mean sport.
Fans of mgma want faith.
They Um,
or if you got.
If I would say,
if you're talking about public opinion,
you're going to have a lot of the people
that aren't really fans that are also
going to weigh in.
Right?
So if you have public opinion,
should they take the gloves off mma?
There's gonna be a lot of people out
there arguing passionately that I had no
idea what they're talking about.
Gloves me and more dangerous and They
will say no way.
It's already barbaric enough.
It's really what we should concentrate
on and putting more pads and more safety
procedures and stopping fights quicker
and looking out for the safety of these
athletes.
but I think much like how pads and
football probably caused more injuries
to players rugby.
I think the same thing should be said
about mma.
I think mathematics or logic of like
helmets and pads cause injuries.
IT really does because think they
present them the.
That's the only thing that it does any
different.
It doesn't like if I had to choose
between fighting someone with them and
make gloves and fighting some bare
knuckle with a good hand wraps and I'll
be like,
yeah,
write me up.
Write me up,
you could just tee off on somebody.
It's a totally different experience.
If your hands are fragile,
a lot of times guys will hit each other
with the palms of the hands instead
because you don't want to break your
hands.
Get on top of someone.
You could smash their face with a palm
of the hardest part of your hand when
you hit things hard with a poem and it
doesn't hurt at all.
Yeah,
it's a different kind of a bone.
It's a thick bone and it's used to
touching and pushing against the hardest
part of your body,
your elbows,
maybe your knee and your elbow,
but the real hard.
I mean you break your elbow.
People break shit all the time.
They break chunks off the bottoms of
their elbows from fighting to get.
Yeah.
I've had friends that have to get
surgery where they have like floating
bone chunks from elbow and people in the
head.
You can chip off little pieces of your
elbow.
That's not great.
Get kicked their pain.
When you get
hit,
when you're fighting,
you feel less pain than you probably
would in regular life because your
adrenaline's through the roof and you're
in this heightened situation,
But you could definitely tell some,
some shots,
huRt guys,
shots the legs.
A lot of times when you get that second
or third leg kick in the same spot on
the legs from a really good lead kicker,
there's like a jolt that goes through
your whole body.
It's like,
um,
the difference between like a leg kick
and anything else.
as you're different,
you're dealing with a giant piece of
muscle and there's a lot of nerve
endings in there.
The outside edge of it is kind of
tender,
especially if you're not a person who's
used to getting kicked there.
And if someone like a,
you know,
like a maurice smith or an anesto nesto
who's like a world champion,
kickboxer slams a shin into there.
It is extraordinarily painful
because I remember that girl that got
her arm bitten off by a shark.
Bethany a,
someone she said that when she heard the
sound of she heard it,
the crunch,
but she felt no pain.
In fact,
she said it felt like blissful orgasmic
because so much dope men goes to the
area so that you don't give up.
Oh my god.
So I just curious if in like fight or
flight mode fighting if you're even
feeling this stuff.
Yeah,
you feel it.
You feel some stuff more than others.
Just like kicking in.
As soon as the fight's over you're like,
oh fuck,
I'm so much pain after a fight.
You,
you're in severe pain for sure.
Just after your whole body's bruised up.
It's been a long time since I've felt
that,
but I definitely remember after fights.
What's the most painful place to be hit
the head for sure.
The body too though,
you know your body can hurt for days
afterwards if you get hit with like a
left hook to the liver,
like a really hard left hook to the body
is tearing the achilles heel.
Really the most painful injury there has
done a really bad one though,
but I think injured discs are pretty
goddamn bad.
Injured disc sleeve,
a lot of people with a atrophied arms
and pushes on nerves and jen
nerves,
impingements impinges on the signal.
So working your muscles literally
atrophy and shrink up and if you don't
act on it really quickly,
it's a really common thing with men,
um,
that,
uh,
either lift a lot of weights or do it
incorrectly and fuck their back.
But are we all sleepIng wrong and
sitting wrong and just doing everything
wrong.
There's definitely sitting wrong.
Yeah.
I feel like I'm in the sybian right now.
This thing's awesome.
Well,
yeah.
This is this.
I'm always supposed to be sitting
because we're sending ron wrong,
straight up,
sleeping run.
Just sleep.
But do you sleep on your side?
Do you put a pillow between your knees?
Sometimes?
Yeah.
Are we all Supposed to do that?
We're also shooting,
right?
Uh,
I should write.
Got a squatty potty.
Got one of those phases in your
backyard?
Yeah.
I have one of those two and people come
into my house and they think they're
like,
does a handicap person live here?
I'm like,
just calm down.
We're all shitting wrong.
It's easier to shoot that way.
Squatty potties.
Primarily women.
We don't empty our bladders completely
when we use regular toilets and that's
why we have to pee all the time because
we have to use squatty potties when we p
also.
Yeah,
we don't empty our entire bladders
toilets are not designed for our
uteruses.
Basically uti as a plural,
as uti.
I don't know,
but yeah,
that's why women always have to be.
But you can piece it in.
Yup.
No problem.
Right?
No.
Yeah.
It just goes all over the place.
But because they got a mess.
Right?
But in the shower,
right?
I don't do that.
It's just being in the shower only.
What seems like it'd be a real clean way
to do it.
It's a great way to stay single forever.
Am I going to be like,
hey,
would you be down with a woman peeing in
the shower if you were in there with
her?
I don't give a fuck dated.
A lot of guys will be in the shower.
I pee in the shower all the time.
Is it just like I have to pee and I'm in
the shower.
What?
I give a fuck.
I've had guys pee while I'm in the
shower with that.
It's like you're peeing on my foot
bottom.
WhaT's on my body is grosser than what's
coming out of my dick.
She really true.
Is that why are we so grossed out by p
two?
Is that socially constructed?
Like why is this so disgusting?
It's gross.
A nine year old pulls it out.
I know I've seen you out,
but this is weird.
What is that?
Conditioning?
It's probably conditioning.
Yeah.
It doesn't seem like there's a
renovation.
Scratching your ear if you're scratching
your eye.
If you reach it,
what do you pick up?
Food.
But this is gross,
but I don't even have any boogers in
here.
It's a good question.
I don't know.
Tell me.
I really wish I knew.
I guess it's like a shame thing from the
time you were little,
you got a booger in your nose.
That's true.
That's true,
mike.
He eats his bugger.
This is my face.
All my fits like I have a blood hold on
my face.
Like why is this is gross crumps,
but why is it so satisfying when you
pick out a giant,
a giant winter burger and you're like,
whoa,
look at this goddamn thing.
I started getting my nose waxed hall
inside of my.
This is what happened in the second of
the pocket and they just started meeting
things.
I should never tell anyone that it's
always have.
It's on the job.
No,
because you have little hairs and
they're just like unattractive.
So I started waxing them.
That's a good move.
It hurts.
I stick a little,
but why you guys having those hairs?
Fine.
Girls having good success gets itchy.
Boogers get stuck in it.
I cleaned it out just like a blow my
nose because then you get.
Yeah,
the boogers get all but we're supposed
to have knows harris needs more.
I just sneezed.
If you're running,
do you ever run?
I do.
Okay.
When you run to emotional rocket,
do you put a finger on one nostril like
that?
Golf club?
Not only when I'm running,
why would numb running because it's a
good thing to do in the middle of
running outside.
Yes.
Yeah.
I'm trying to start running inside
barefoot.
Like those socks you sent me a
ridiculous because here's the thing
about those socks and I feel it with
those five fingers known.
I don't even know.
Yeah,
I've heard of him.
the steel socks.
Dyneema.
Dyneema is the same stuff they used
to make bows drinks.
Oh really?
Use it.
Yeah,
because it's incredibly strong.
I mean you think about it a bow you're
pulling back like at a really heavy book
and go like 80 pounds of pressure to
pull it back.
And so you have all this force on those
very thin wire that's like a shoestring
thinner even in fact that's how strong
dyneema is.
So they make these shoes out of dyneema
and you can run on things.
Well,
I'm getting a date.
That's it.
I'm trying to be barefoot outside.
Thirty minutes a day.
It's a good move.
Is this a dyneema?
No.
Well,
today I kept.
I did kick boxing,
which I always do barefoot,
so I got my a lot of barefoot moving in
and I also do it on a fairly soft
surface,
which is great because your feet really
get to dig in your toes.
Electrons from the earth.
That's it.
It's deep dyneema.
Jamie.
Yeah.
I got these myself too.
It felt like just putting on a garden
gloves on your feet,
but can you walk on.
I walked outside of my little parking
lot and I was like,
nah,
it's phillip felt better barefoot like
glass was going to go right through my
foot.
I wouldn't.
I wouldn't have done.
I wouldn't have run anywhere,
but I won't go through it.
I wasn't going to test it.
They felt they didn't feel like,
come on bro.
This is supposed to be like sneakers
there.
I didn't.
I didn't buy the advertising,
but well here's 80 bucks.
Boasts strings cut all the time.
Accidentally this bow strings or they're
not.
It's not an invulnerable.
In fact,
when I was in Hawaii,
I accidentally cut one of my bow strings
with the broadhead from the arrow.
Just touched it and I didn't even know
what happened.
It's not good.
So that stuff for fishing line,
some sort of a synthetic line.
I don't know how exactly they make it.
I think it's got to be different,
but there's a bunch of different kinds
of fishing line too.
They have braided fishing line.
that's like the most common stuff that
they use today.
Yeah.
Fish were mostly.
No,
mostly salt,
water fly fishing boat fishing in the
ocean.
It's great to catch fish and then you
bring it like if you stay in a
restaurant or a hotel on mercury,
mercury,
we can definitely get some mercury in
your body if you eat a lot of salmon or
if you love tuna rather.
They're supposed to,
but they just say don't eat it all the
time every day,
you know,
but with the amount of heavy metals that
are in the ocean,
you're definitely going to get some.
I don't know how much of it they're
actually testing though,
like have you ever been?
I'd get my blood tested.
I've never shown it.
I did at one point in time I was eating
a lot of sardines and it tested positive
for arsenic and the doctors,
I don't know,
it was a very tiny amount.
The doctor was like,
hmm,
what do like go through your diet?
And I,
as soon as I hit sardines,
he goes,
how often you eat?
I go,
I eat like two cans a day.
Just like what?
And he's like,
yeah,
that's it.
I think he was,
yeah,
they live in very polluted areas often
and they're at the bottom.
They collect some of
the heavy metals that comes from our
polluted.
How often?
Not every day,
not two cans a day,
but I eat it can last night.
What is it?
Why do you have to do in canned?
Because you don't.
If you could eat them fresh for sure.
Yeah.
They're just a good source of healthy
fats and there can.
Cause they can't have an olive oil.
Yeah.
But it's a good,
a high fat thing to eat for me.
Well,
um,
yeah,
they're not that bad.
I like this.
We were talking about this earlier,
this whole thing of everything has to
taste good.
Like doesn't cave shake that clicks.
There's this thing where it's like
everything has to taste good.
I'm like,
no,
they don't.
Everything that tastes good is fucking
terrible for you.
Sometimes things that taste good or
great for you,
like a juicy steak.
Well tHat's true.
That's a good thing.
There's things that are good for you
that tastes good.
Beets.
Beets tastes delicious.
I'm a big fan of beets.
Love beets.
They're super good for you.
Yeah,
so like there's lot of stuff that tastes
good.
That's good for.
I'm trying to figure out what to eat.
I just don't know what to eat.
I'm going to start eating whatever you
posted on it.
Don't get it.
Don't get another eating disorder.
No,
I'm now my eating disorder is I only eat
shed that you post.
I bought all this cave shakes.
I'm only eating those cave shakes now.
Why have meat for you?
I go elk for you.
Had to say thank you kelly.
Fuck you.
I got me for you.
Don't you take a shit on my.
Wait.
Are you a good singer?
No.
Are you sure?
Definitely.
One hundred percent.
I don't know.
I think that your job is actually pretty
amazing.
Our kelly,
if I wanted to go on tours are nobody's.
They can do things with their voice.
Like I can only make noises.
It's a muscle ultimately,
isn't it?
I think is a sound that you're capable
of making,
right?
There's like impressions.
I can do impressions of some people and
I know when I could do them.
Are they in your same register?
Yeah.
Good.
Sam kinison oppression.
yeah.
Maybe I can do that.
If I could listen to them in particular
can do it.
Then you could just got to get into it.
I cAn do a Mike Tyson.
I can do a few of them,
but then there's other ones that I hear
and I go,
I can't do that one.
Apparently people are good at
impressions are good at singing.
It's the same part of your brain,
right?
Like you hear something and can
replicate it.
It's about hearing not about replicating
or something.
Well,
it's singing is a weird thing,
right?
Because it's mariah carey style singing
and then there's amy winehouse saying.
Right.
And I liked both of them.
You know,
like it's a very big say I did not see
this coming.
I say the difference like mariah carey,
I wouldn't say she's known for
songwriting,
whereas amy wants different artists,
but like that fantasy song.
Great song.
The one with busta rhymes on it.
Sweet.
Yeah.
That one,
believe you just said that.
Me and mariah,
back leg babies.
I listened to that.
That's like my go to song.
Is it old?
Dirty bastard?
Oh god.
I'm so racist.
Sorry.
ShouLd not have smoke weed today.
Conflating black rappers with deep
voices.
Oopsies.
I'm not even joking.
That's like my go to song and put me in
a good mood.
Good song.
It's a great song.
Which is also weird.
She's got a beautiful voice.
They can.
Hero makes me cry every time.
But I also looked like liz fares voice,
which is all like talking through songs
and I do love me some.
Oh shit.
Oh yeah.
Mariah carey.
She's like lost it.
Right.
Listen,
we all lose.
Can you put out on the podcast how
famous you get if you get that famous,
good luck.
Do you remember her in that field of
corn with those?
She booty shorts on.
I mean that was the first song,
right?
That was our first big hit pigtails.
It was like jesus louisa's and she was
dating some record executive right now.
Jimmy ivy.
Who was it?
You just know everything.
Don't you know who is Jennifer Lopez?
First husband before puff daddy.
I don't think they were married before.
Antonio.
Antonio banderas did ben.
What's his name?
Ben affleck.
Did he dodged the bullet or he didn't
get married?
They didn't get married.
They did some.
They did some music videos together.
Marc anthony was very true,
but I don't know about before she was
married to some guy who's a sued.
Where you going to try everybody dodging
her.
He ain't gone crazy.
lopez leg.
Remember when ben affleck was in a music
video with her?
Chris died.
That's her story.
That I hope is true.
It
someone told me that they were told by a
construction guy that Jennifer Lopez
called them and told them to take then
affleck's basketball court that he has
and move it to her house and they were
like,
what?
And she was like,
I want to surprise him.
I want to move.
I want to move his basketball court.
She did.
She wanted them to literally build a
basketball court in her.
Like I'm sure palatial estate that is
his.
He has an indoor basketball court.
She wanted them to recreate it at her
place,
take it board by board and move it to
her place.
Now if that is true,
and it may not be,
it might just be bullshit that somebody
told me,
but I loved it.
I loved it.
I'm like,
oh that girl,
like how hard does she squeeze?
I mean,
do you know what I'm saying?
what kind of for roche,
everything.
Everything emotionally,
sexually,
how hard does she pull it in?
How much control does she clamped down
that she thought it would be a good move
to move his entire basketball court?
I
like it when women throw money around
and give gifts,
women's stealing your basketball court
and putting it into your house.
That's a crazy person's move.
Make him happy.
That make you happy when someone steals
your basketball court because you get to
now play basketball at my house.
Isn't that the whole point?
He's like,
I wouldn't do it.
Boyfriend has a tennis court.
I don't like where it is.
I needed to be closer to me.
I'm not going to drive down to your and
bullshit and we are together forever.
I'm convinced.
Are you okay then let me make this
fucking call her joys.
I think it sounds like an awesome
solution.
frustrating problem.
I'm not going to drive over to ogden and
sunset.
If you come to me,
you come to calabasas,
right?
I understand what you're saying.
Well,
it's like,
well,
you're fighting about it.
He's like,
I want to go play basketball.
And she's like,
but I need you here.
And he's like,
well my basketball courts over there.
And she was like,
now what?
I respect that now.
What the fuck?
You fuck you,
your basketball courts right now.
I'm going to go play baSketball,
my boys.
oh,
that's interesting.
The basketball courts here now.
What's your excuse now?
Where you going?
That's like,
that's like a.
Let me smell your deck mode.
Right?
They put like a,
like a little balcony where she could
like watch over the basketball at all
times.
Like some princess in a castle
and I would like,
I would like put all these like shaming
devices in like every time you miss a
basket,
the whole court reverberates with a fart
noise
has to just to emasculate him as much as
possible.
But if she just sat there just cross out
like reading a book.
Like this is where I like to read.
I like to read to the sound of you guys
playing basketball.
No one can talk any crazy shit,
dude.
Dude.
Dude,
listen to me.
Do guys like expensive?
Gets donk,
donk,
get married.
It just don't do it.
how am I going to not do it bro?
She moved the basketball court.
I mean what the fuck did didn't get
married?
No.
so it either didn't work or it didn't
happen.
Imagine this story is true by the way,
right?
I don't even know the story's true.
Let's assume it's not true,
but let's just for fiction,
let's create this true story that she
did move the basketball court and here
poor ben is was few actor buddies that
are hanging out with him.
Like,
dude,
you can't do this.
You can't do this.
Here's what it is.
My nightmare is the guy I'm with going
out on a boys' night.
I'm going to go play basketball with my
boys.
Digney meaning if the basketball courts
here,
I know what you're doing.
I'm in control of your shit.
You're not secretly going to jumbos
clown room.
I can control the.
You treat the boy the same way you pre
treat a dog.
Like when you look in his eyes.
I just looked at them.
I just give them raw meat and marrow
bones and they're not allowed on the
couch.
Like I fuck them looking at me.
Now.
I'm very beta in my relationships,
but something I do wonder is apparently
giving his masculine.
And I'm always curious if guys like
expensive gifts or if they don't.
I don't have an opinion.
We're dating.
I'm getting you a watch or you were
rich.
so I wouldn't know.
I'm not because I buy guys watches.
I would say that's very sweet.
That's the nice thing about.
damn,
I gotta buy this pitch something now.
Yeah,
I would think that.
Yeah.
I don't want to feel like I don't want
to feel like keeping
right.
But if I get you a,
I don't know,
fucking another salt lamp or whatever.
That's not a strong.
So salt lamp.
if I get you something fancy or pay for
a trip or something,
do you like it or do you feel like
gross?
I think ideally this is,
it sounds like shit,
but I'm being honest.
I think ideally,
especially in the situation where it's
someone like you has a lot of money.
I don't have any guy looks really give
it all to dogs and sick relatives,
you know,
hurting.
Um,
it's,
you don't have an issue with money,
right?
It's like the person that you're dating,
if they're successful,
likely they don't have an issue with
money either.
So if people don'T have an issue with
money,
money should just be like fun coupons.
She'll be like,
what can we do something that doesn't
have any money?
Then it becomes weird and it could,
it depends on what kind of relationship
you have with the person.
But It also,
it's like what,
uh,
like,
what's the purpose of this?
It's like a control thing or is it just
like,
let's go have fun thing?
Yeah.
So like if ben affleck was dating
Jennifer Lopez,
they're both fucking kajillion.
Doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter.
here's a car,
here's the whatever.
Yeah.
Like if ben orders the private jet,
jennifer doesn't go like,
fuck you bitch.
I'm paying for this.
She doesn't even know.
I don't even know.
I don't care.
But it's like,
yeah,
it's fun.
Coupons.
They feel like money is the last
frontier of weird.
It can be.
It's anonymous.
It's just so symbolic.
I feel like now I've had financial
arrangements with friends before they go
south and it just gets real weird.
If you were dating now,
let's say we're some alternative string
theory universe where you were dating,
would you pay for everything if you're
starting from scratch?
If I was starting from scratch with a
new person,
for sure.
if the person didn't have money and one
of the reasons why I like paying,
it's because I like to tip a lot,
but what if you date someone who has
money,
then I'm going to give a fuck.
then you split it.
Yeah,
like my friends,
like if I go out,
my friend stayed with a woman is
different.
Well it depends.
I would be more than happy to pay
because I don't give a fuck,
but if they for some reason wanted to
pay,
I wouldn't give a fuck about that
either.
But like okay,
as long as it didn't feel weird.
But like I've met guys where the guide
doesn't make any money and the woman
makes a ton of money and the woman pays
for everything and that relationship
always gets squirrely.
Ever.
World.
I'm your mother,
but it doesn't correlate the other way.
it can work.
Like if the guy has a ton of money and
the woman does it definitely can work
and I don't know why.
I mean I don't,
I'm not saying it's impossible.
It's alpha though.
It's just not likely.
It's not likely that that's going to
work for whatever reason.
I never know if paying makes things
weird or if it's,
you know,
like beyonce and jay z.
Do you think they give a fuck about who
pays for something
that sells bell?
I am the happiest person on the planet.
That would be hilarious.
Sammut.
Now I got the shampoo.
If you could just put this into carts,
but I think you're obligated at that
level of fame to tip ridiculously.
Yeah.
I just heard somewhere that 20 percent
is actually not a good tip.
Really?
Yeah.
I think that's a good tip.
Someone,
a friend of mine who has a daughter
who's a waitress,
said the waitress is like,
that's now not so what is it now?
Twenty five.
I don't know.
I guess so give me all your money.
Fuck yeah.
Like what is that?
It's just like such a nightmare.
I feel like I'm always standard standard
20th expecting used to be 15.
right.
You start working at a restaurant.
One oF the last jobs I had was like a
day.
It was a brand new restaurant and the
rule they were coming up with to decide
how much we had to tip out to our
coworkers was basing it off of us
getting 20 percent off of every table.
Wow.
Twenty percent is expected.
Fucked up Man,
because then they're screwing you
because you know there's gonna be a lot
of cheap people.
Yeah.
I've seen some people leave some fucking
horrendous tips.
It really bothers.
Honestly.
That is my number one pet peeve.
It makes me sick.
It's just so selfish.
Unless you're super broke and like
you're barely pay and then honestly you
probably shouldn't be just don't be
going out to restaurants,
but yeah.
But how do you,
how are people supposed to know this
stuff?
Because I thought it was 15 percent go
out.
That's another service started getting
mad and like we shouldn't be going out
to eat if you can't afford a 20 percent
tip and then add 20 percent to the whole
bill.
This is a place that I go to a sushi
place to put the tip on the bill.
Always kinda liked that hotels.
It's always a gratuity included,
which is like how shitty is your
clientele that you have to include
gratuity because you don't trust them?
Well,
it's not necessarily that.
It's just like you take it out of the
equation.
It's nice to not have to think about it
and be like,
just like that's the worst part.
At the end of the day when you're like,
what's the,
what's the percentage?
It's weird that those people who are
working don't get paid.
RIght?
They only get paid through tips.
Like people say they rely on your tips
as a way to do.
Only make tips that's fucked up.
I had no idea.
why don't you pay them?
like why are they.
Why don't they get some kind of lump sum
can fire them,
but you don't have to pay them or you
pay them.
Very little.
Good insurance?
No.
Where did you work in Ohio,
which is a right to work state.
What kind of restaurant?
Uh,
all kinds I worked at a chain.
Opens up health insurance.
No,
no,
no.
Just tips is also pre obamacare.
So I don't know how actually works now,
but like you,
I wouldn't have been able to afford it.
I can tell you that.
How much money a night in tips for a
guy.
It's also different between guys and
girls there too.
Is that like the one profession where
guys get fucking.
It's a woman's game was discussing the
other night and we kind of came to the
conclusion that might be not for sure,
but it might be that um,
let's say a guy's taking care of the
bill,
he might feel shittier or it might be
more okay being shittier to a guy than a
girl that's taken care of them for
whatever reason.
Might be lots of things could play into
that.
But that's kind of where we arrived to
where we're all sitting and really
servers to two of the girls talking.
Well,
a lot of men have weird competition
issues with other men.
Let's got him some guys bringing your
food.
You're like,
fuck that guy.
You can shitty.
Yeah,
just shitty of that way and like you
don't want to be mean to a girl.
You don't want to make her cry if that
might not happen,
but you just don't.
You think it could and you just make all
your decisions based off of that.
Yeah.
That is so nuts.
I never thought about like being a male
waiter,
you're going to make less money than a
woman probably.
Unless you're really good at it.
It's a sexist professional,
but you're a really good restaurant.
You like a really good male waiter who
knows exactly what kind of fucking dijon
salt,
the preparation
then it's.
You have to be almost way above and
beyond the job knowing way deep being
anticipating everything.
100 bucks.
Maybe it was a good decent night,
but like out here,
you'd be expecting to make three or $400
a night or you wouldn't probably
survive.
Right?
But a lot of us out here,
you want to work at a place that serves
alcohol though,
right?
For for cash.
That's the only way to make money.
But I would think that if you were,
if you were like a waiter,
like,
like it's always fascinating.
Most fasting when you go to a nice
restaurant and the waiters obviously
from Italy.
Oh,
interesting.
I'm coughing.
Jesus christ.
Yeah.
I just have phlegm.
But if the weight is from Italy,
like it's more impressive.
Right.
You got a nice title restaurant.
What do they bring those guys over?
How's that work?
Do they have like some sort of a
service?
Restaurants like request the services
because italians take service way more
seriously than we do it.
Everybody who is working as a waiter,
I feel like at least certainly out here
is trying to do something else for a
living.
Right.
But it makes your restaurant more legit.
Like you don't even know who the fuck
cooking.
It could be a straight up white guy in
the back.
It doesn't bother you.
But as long as it's an italian person
explaining what the right,
you know,
an ncaa can of the words,
you're just enchanted.
What's the most fucked up thing you've
ever seen a restaurant like restaurants
or just nightmares,
right?
not fucked up,
but I just remember because I explained
this to the newer restaurant I worked at
that was expect expecting that 20
percent.
The clientele they weRe trying to
attract with like a white tablecloth
kind of thing.
Although it was not in that kind of
place and was not that kind of
restaurant.
And one of my first tables I got that
was expecting that service I like
cleared.
The gentleman's played before his wife
for.
She was mostly being done eating.
I literally got yelled at about that and
explain to why you shouldn't do that.
And my boss,
he got yelled at by the client and then
he left the next day.
He's like,
hey,
just so you know,
don't take people's plates until
everybody's done.
I was like,
it's what?
That iS just a weird thing.
And then
I hear there's no such thing as chilean
sea bass.
That's not a real thing.
They just take white fish and they call
it a bunch of other shit so they can
charge different things.
Definitely chilean sea bass,
like an invention,
like a restaurant invention.
The look up New York times.
They also say,
don't eat sushi in Oklahoma city and
shit like that,
but that's not what she's saying.
She's saying chilean sea bass is not a
real fish.
Apparently restaurants just take random
fish and call it a bunch
of fancy.
Really?
Chilean sea bass has a very interesting
and unique buttery taste to it.
Like don't.
A lot of restaurants just take garbage
fish and put a bunch of salt on it and
it definitely dancing that they found
that people lie about the type of sushi
you're eating.
Oftentimes fake fish on your plate,
right?
But that's chilean sea bass.
He just ordered.
It isn't a bass and it probably didn't
come from Chile.
What does it?
It says,
fuck,
this is crazy.
Chilean sea bass is a fraud.
First off,
it's not really a bass.
It's a cod.
Oh,
that makes sense.
Because you know what it tastes like.
Miso,
cod,
so cotton,
chilean sea bass,
buttery.
Right?
Until the late 19 seventies named
chilean sea bass didn't exist,
the fish went by the unappetizing name
of the patagonian toothfish.
Oh,
okay.
So it is an actual animal.
It's just not a bass.
So that makes sense.
Why it's uniform and its flavor,
but it's on a bass.
The cock.
That's better.
Tastes better than bass.
That's why it's interesting because bass
doesn't taste good.
Most bass is a bass or not like the
tastiest fish.
Really fishy.
The large money fast are kind of boring.
Tuna used to be cat food.
It used to be trash fish.
That's hilarious.
Until the 19 seventies,
bluefin tuna was considered a trash fish
suitable for cat food.
Today,
it's one of the most prized fish in the
world.
That's hilarious.
As the bluefin sushi craze spread across
Japan from Japan,
the United States over fishing triggered
a 95 percent decline in the fish
population.
Holy fuck.
Crazy.
Ninety five percent since 19 seventies
going extinct,
isn't it?
Oh,
That's not good.
Ninety five percent.
I'm not a doctor,
but like go outside or sick up attend
event.
Uh,
when seafood buyers found the fish
adaptable in terms of taste and texture,
they rebranded as chilean sea bass and
peddled it as a gourmet fair.
Is that legal to just lie about.
Look at what they're saying today.
Much of the fish sold as chilean sea
bass comes from the an arctic waters,
not the chilean coast.
Whoa.
Is that,
isn't that like false advertising or
like blasphemy or isn't there some law
against just lying about food?
Look,
it's the same thing though.
Look long,
considered worthless.
The patagonian toothfish can live up to
50 years and grow to seven feet long.
But when seafood buyers found the fish
adaptable in terms of taste and texture,
they rebranded it as chilean sea bass
and peddled it as gore.
Mayfair scam.
So disappointed.
Real talk.
Real talk a lot.
Don't you think?
got enough bullshit on my mind.
You got to press your head.
My favorite is pitch.
I wish you would burn my mother fucking
clothes.
We all wish someone would burn your
aren't kelly there?
Just stick.
I love it.
Like it's more like,
don't you know how many sexual
harassment lawsuIts I have?
All my kelly have on his mind.
Does he have a lot on his plate?
I don't think he's remarkably calm.
Yeah.
Of this
old is r kelly.
He's 80.
He seems to be like gliding through five
for 78 years.
He's,
he seems to be gliding through any forms
of controversy.
Like relatively.
Oh,
godly toms.
It's 50 slash 50 this year.
50.
How much one is he worth?
Let's say?
Yes,
way more.
Hundred million.
Just write his own songs or whatever the
thought.
Take somebody else's writing that shit.
One hundred and $50 million.
That's a low number that he's got
probably $150 million stored in his
fucking basement somewhere.
Yeah,
they concerts.
He's constantly live shows.
You're right.
It sells out giant places.
Every time you sell out a giant places.
Website is towards hundreds of
thousands.
Constantly tourinG tours.
He tours a lot when he's not fucking.
Oh,
look at that.
Go to events.
That's a beautiful photograph.
Ontario.
California is a rodeo arena bitch arena.
You know,
why do an ontario?
I do the fucking improv.
The citizens on citizens bank arena.
That's like a 20,000
seat soccer bucks.
50 bucks the after party tour.
So no one's mad.
No one's mad about,
oh,
127 bucks.
We'll talk.
Fuck you.
Hey girl gunpoint.
You know what?
Nevermind,
I'll stop.
That was a cogent point.
He's um,
he's still raking it in.
He does those every now and then rick's
in the cash,
goes back to a sex slave slangs until he
falls asleep.
So do you have to pay to be in the sex
cult,
john?
Everybody pays her integrity and
everybody.
Petrel health,
everybody pays.
Go listen to it emotionally.
You have to take notes.
Fifty years old,
$150 million.
Sold over 100 million albums.
woo.
It's amazing.
He's only got 150 million left.
What?
He's got a dollar an album.
That's crazy.
You've got to get a new manager.
Actually.
Pretty good.
I saved that.
A dollar album's pretty good.
B,
we just think that guy that plus concert
sales,
like he maybe he's got a lot more money.
Man,
you know those fucking people don't know
that celebrity network,
they're just making guesses.
So I was going to say,
what is that based on?
I've gone to mind and it's not true.
I don't think how much.
I literally have no idea.
Fifty nine and kelly,
I need you to support her.
X r kelly.
Kelly's ex wife.
He agreed to a $50 million dollar
settlement with his ex wife were they
married more than 10 years.
So it must have been because in you get
home after choreograph and blah,
blah,
blah.
When she auditioned to be one of his
backup dancers in 1994,
they married in [inaudible] 96.
They had three children.
Can't afford a divorce in 2009.
Since then,
he has gone on a dick slinging epic
proportion.
The senior,
uh,
explain the grounds of their divorce in
his 2012 auto biography.
Solar coaster.
The dIary of me
live that book then diary my diary.
Diary of me egomania coaster.
It's been a solar coaster.
It's been a solo coast towns,
but I'm hearing that you can just say my
direct solar coaster.
Why would he want it looks so awesome.
Look at all those microphones point that
I'm flying.
That looks like the cover of the rosetta
stone.
Looks like maybe the greatest book of
all time and 199 consumer reviews and
four and a half fucking stars.
That's what I'm seeing.
I'm seeing success.
I'll talk.
do you know that matthew mcconaughey,
his mother has a book.
It's called.
I amaze myself.
Cool.
I didn't want to pick anybody's mom.
realize I've ever seen you.
She talks about paid out millions and
out of court,
sexual misconduct settlements.
We'll talk.
Fuck you.
You think I got enough?
Boom.
Were you all?
Hey,
I mean,
he's finding people that like to live
his way.
Like you could start a cult.
You kind of have a golf.
Actually,
I think pretty much anybody can start a
call.
I know some shitty comedian that's
basically started a cult
gotta go.
Yeah.
I'll write it down.
It's more common than you would think.
I think like people have.
Yeah.
That one.
I think there's.
I think there's a lot of people that
want to be led.
like,
just how some people are born tall.
I mean I joke about this,
like what I was trying to explain to my
kids something and I was like,
you know,
some people are big ears and some people
have literally years old,
some people have brains that are made
out of dog shit and then you find people
that are dumber than them that let them
have sex with them.
yeah.
And then they make kids and those kids
are fucked and don't let anybody tell
you any different.
And if you have a really low watt brain
and you run into some charismatic figure
that you feel,
didn't we just see this happen in
november?
Yeah.
There's a lot of that.
When that's.
I mean that's what a lot of what
happened,
right?
A lot of people who would
finally,
finally let them know,
my president.
You fucking let your president until you
pj real talk.
Yeah,
you can.
There's a lot of monkeys out there.
Yeah,
they're really dumb people.
I just want to be told what to do by
someone who's confident and alpha.
It's 100 percent absolutely evident to
almost anybody that I know that's
honest,
that there are people out there that are
far smarter than them,
right when I have him on my podcast all
the time I talked to astrophysicists and
it and people breaking down the,
the,
the actual fiber of reality and he tried
to talk to them and have them explain
things to you and you're like,
well,
bundonally clear that I'm not nearly as
smart as them,
but I talked to a lot of people and I,
you tell like somewhere in the
conversation like this is all you got to
work with you.
We've all met people.
Then it's not even their fault.
It's just like this is what they have to
work with it,
but nobody wants to entertain that idea.
So we all want to pretend that we're on
the same starting line,
but what if we're not at the same
starting line with dick size and width
height and with a physical strength and
with all the other attributes that
people possess,
why the fuck would we be on the same
with mine?
It's not.
It's not real.
If all of us had the same mind power,
we'd be extinct by now.
You've all just destroyed each other for
sure.
There's a general sort of range that
most of us fall into and you can for
sure improve upon that with really good
schooling and and study and discipline
and supportive family and all the.
All the good things that we all aware
of,
but there's always going to be these
fucking people that are way smarter.
There's going to be this elon musk's
talk to them,
john carmax,
you're going to talk to them.
They were barely the same thing.
The same thing.
Yeah,
super computer.
So if that's the case,
if you're going to meet people like
that,
and I think you have,
and I know I have for sure there's
people that no matter what you say,
you're not going to help them and if
that person,
that dumb person runs into an art kelly,
and it's like we're doing right now,
is communicating with saturn through
love saturday.
This is of course sad and see they don't
want to go there because if you go
there,
it will be all about the bliss.
One day we're going to get there,
we're going to get you through earth.
Then you get your through my bedroom and
they're gonna.
He's gonna fuck you.
To the center of saturn.
I have a hundred and $50.
Million dollars.
Yeah,
like when he's banging you just sorta,
sorta like when kinison was yelling
about jesus and really sort of wanting
to believe in you,
feel it in your body and I'll feed you
dinner if you come to my house.
I mean,
I think it's really susceptible
vulnerable people.
I want those cycling scientology preys
on.
How about those?
Uh,
the comment people to kill themselves
because they thought there was a ufo
behind the comment.
Right?
Those were real people kill themselves
during the eclipse.
Oops.
So I think there was a bunch of people.
I mean that's just like the new
darwinism.
It's like the people who acquiesce to
call it.
It's like,
that's just monitor data.
I hope it's not your kids,
but you know,
if I hope all their parents are dead
already and luck someone gets killed
himself during the eclipse,
they were going to go somehow.
Yeah.
It's like walking into a wall or falling
off a building or something.
It's not a good choice.
It's not the way to go,
but I think for sure like those people
are always going to exist.
Right?
Those people like the heaven's gate cult
or who have so little to lose a need to
believe something that exists bigger
than themselves or their brain doesn't
work good.
You know,
there's certain people you know,
hey,
brain,
right?
Just doesn't work that good no matter
what.
No matter what you do,
you're like,
oh,
by the way,
this is spelt wrong.
Get it even knows that.
So you're just operating on another
level.
But there's some people,
right?
Yeah.
The,
you know,
for a fact like they can be.
There's certain,
especially like open ended pursuits,
like standup comedy.
It attracts those people,
right?
You need those perpetual open miker who
are convinced that some labs.
No,
the guy who,
because you like,
we're not going to be heat.
Is that what you know?
But that is one of my favorite
documentaries on the plate or whatever
it is.
Movies on the planet a.
It's heartbreaking but amazing.
Uh,
it's,
it's unreal,
it's almost as good as that r kelly
video you showed me in terms of the
emotions that evokes.
But dId you ever see the guy at the
comedy store who are adult house on his
head?
no,
I think you missed that.
He was on the porch of the comedy store,
whatever,
the front patio for like a good year.
You were gone.
Dollhouse giant doll house.
Well,
that's a way to get people look at you
and jesus guy and jesus guys got gotta
look weird in because he's dressed up as
jesus.
like if the same guy dressed up as
mohammed people like,
get the fuck out of here.
I mean,
what happens when,
when you're that guy who dresses up as
jesus on sunset,
he's probably listening right now
crying.
What does that,
what does that life look like?
What's your life look like?
So tweet me.
Google his network.
Either a trust fund kid and you're a
billionaire.
Oh my god.
It's just probably not the smartest way
to live.
But the message that he's given when he
walks around like that is of one who was
a disciple of jesus.
So you see him,
he looks like jesus,
he's dressed like jesus and you think,
ah,
guys,
probably find out if he's jesus.
What
right is that?
What if I,
I've.
This isn't really my beliefs is done.
But if jesus were to come back,
where are we going to go?
Huh?
He would have to show,
first of all,
it's going to be in Israel.
Take pictures and things.
She was the crazy homeless guy.
Those people that are convinced that
jesus,
when he returns is going to return to
Israel.
So we have to secure the safety of
Those really super evangelical
christians.
yeah.
Piece that advice piece.
While these people go over to Israel,
all these southerners,
all these southerners that a real,
real familiar with the lord's word,
and they go over there and they're
literally talking about like where jesus
is going to return and it's going to be
over here.
Sure.
I was going to speak.
Speak up on high.
They voted.
I think about.
This is the.
This is the area that's dictated in the
bible more where he will return,
where your talk was,
that crazy thing called where they go
over to Israel and they end up taking
off all their clothes and jerusalem
syndrome.
Jerusalem syndrome is like a mark.
Marin actually wrote a book called
jerusalem syndrome.
Yeah.
But it's.
Yeah,
it's people that.
It's a relatively common thing that
happens.
They go to Israel and they,
they think that they're like a messiah
and they freak out.
They think that they're hearing the word
of god.
Right?
Isn't that,
am I reading this wrong?
Like a lot of people do this.
Yeah.
Like a couple of year.
And then they literally have a name for
it called the jerusalem syndrome.
Here we go.
What does it say?
Or jeremiah says,
a group of,
uh,
a group of mental phenomena involving
the presence of either religiosity
themed,
obsessive ideas,
delusions or other psychosis like
experiences that are triggered by a
visit to the city of jerusalem.
Yeah.
Wow.
It's not a demo to a single religion or
denomination is affected jews.
ChrIstians and muslims have many
different backgrounds,
but when they go to jerusalem,
that's what's really crazy.
Tourism wobble,
poison,
imagined.
Jerusalem really is a holy place.
I'll go there and only some people can
hear the calling.
What if we're wrong?
We could be wrong.
We're arrogant left.
When you're telling us about this,
said that I feel like it.
They said that most of them were
southerners from the us.
Of course they're the dumbest people,
but do you know about art?
Used to listen to you.
Do you know about the hookworm?
I can epidemic in the south,
yes,
and that's part of the reason that they
were slow is because people in the south
all head hookworm will explain that.
This is recent.
Will you look this up please?
I listened to,
I think it was on how stuff works or
something.
How?
Because of the heat and the way the
south is so humid that hookworm was so
prevalent.
They were founding hookworm and all of
their feces and it eats away your brain
and something like 70 percent of all
southerners had hookworm until like the
forties.
Jesus,
will you look that up and corroborate
that so that I'm not just lying.
There is scientific explanation for
southerners being slower.
Sorry,
southerners.
I love you.
Wow.
But some of them are super smartly.
Jimmy carter.
Well,
of course,
but like this is the,
you know,
and who was it?
Was it roosevelt who tried to.
No,
it was
rocks.
Weren't lazy,
just infected with hookworms.
A story of the postbellum south as told
by parasites.
Holy shit.
Yeah.
It makes your teeth fall out and it eats
away.
Your brain got stereotypes are almost
always the conclusion of lazy science.
They're just empirical generalizations
that are stripped are the variances and
encoded as fact into the collective
consciousness of the general population
to the,
to bubba bubba,
blah,
blah.
However,
sometimes the stereotype reveals a
hidden truth that provides an origin to
the myth.
The trope of the lazy southerner dates
back to america's postbellum period
following the end of the civil war.
No one really knows where it came from,
but the image of lethargic,
filthy drawing farmer has pervaded art,
literature and popular culture until up
until this very moment.
So one argument recently published by
rachel,
newer for pbs,
nova techs present some compelling
evidence for the theory that a hookworm
epidemic was responsible for the rural
stereotype
shed laziness through the exhaustion
mental fogginess attends to inflict upon
its victims.
Historical evidence shows that the
parasite ravaged the american south
route,
the early 20th century as a result of
poor sanitation and lack of public
health programs among the poor.
Crazy by 19 oh,
five,
the parasitologists,
that's a job.
I'm a joke.
Topologist charles says,
as we 40 percent or more,
not 60 percent,
I was wrong,
of the southern population,
was infected with hookworms.
The parasIte thrives and fecal matter
and the combination of shoddy waste
disposal.
In the rarity of shoes,
shoes,
no shoes allowed hookworm larvae to
enter people's bodies through the
webbing between their toes.
How fun.
Once they penetrate the skin,
they travel through their hosts,
lungs into their intestines where they
survive on a diet of blood,
they suck out from the intestinal wall.
A female hookworm can lay up to 10,000
eggs in a single day,
which gives you an idea of how rampant a
localized infestation can become in a
very short time.
The laziness that is synonymous with
hookworm a hookworm infections is
synonym of iron deficiency anemia.
Due To blood loss,
holy shit.
Getting bled out.
Forty percent of people were anemic and
had blood loss.
the poor malnourished victims,
the paris,
I can cause stunted growth.
That's right.
Children with hookworms,
we're plagued with attention deficit
disorders.
lower iq and the infected often had
strange food cravings for dirt clay
paper and chalk.
How nuts is that?
Southern states where the nexus of
hookworm friendly climate is the
parasite loved the sandy soil that makes
the real with the region.
So for at all,
in 1910,
seven point $5 million southerners had
hookworms.
Oh my god.
that's insane.
Insane.
Yes.
the rockefeller is who donated money to
try to combat it,
but that's the illuminati.
Isn't he like a.
Maybe this is all a scam.
Started
50 years for the worm to be eradicated
from the south.
In 1960,
it was eradicated.
Oh my god,
because of the sanItation issues,
look at that.
Almost entirely freed from hookworms by
1985.
Yeah,
that was 1:20
years ago.
So recently.
It's completely insane.
Is that nuts?
Well,
then add that to the fact that half the
people in the country have
toxoplasmosis.
What's that?
That's from cat parasites will know
about that.
No,
this is a crazy one.
Most people,
if you're around for real,
If you're around like farm animals,
if you're around cats,
comedians,
comedians were all fairly.
If you,
you're around,
um,
any sort of feral cats,
it's a parasite that it only can
sexually reproduce inside of cats gut.
So check this out.
They,
they,
these rats get it and it rewires the
rats to make them sexually attracted to
the smell of cat urine.
And the roads there.
Fear of cats.
So these rats literally get enlarge and
some of them,
their ball swell up and their dicks get
hard and they,
they go to find the rats and so,
or they go to find the cat's rather when
they go to find the cats,
they get killed.
The bacteria gets inside the cat.
And that doesn't seem to have any effect
on the cat,
but the cat shit has an effect on women
in particular were they tell women like
see how that rat is not scared,
not scared at all the cat.
And sometimes they chase cats and like
jump adam and shit.
It's nuts.
See look.
So this is going to kill the rat though.
But the cat,
the rats not afraid it's running and
then stopping like it doesn't,
it knows it's being chased but it's not
like I have to get the fuck out of fear.
So it's not just,
it's fear.
It literally makes them sometimes
sexually attracted to the smell of cat
urine.
So then this parasite is toxoplasmosis
gets inside the cat's gut,
the cat's shit it out.
And that's why they tell pregnant women
to never touch litter boxes.
It's extremely important because it can
be deadly to children and cause all
sorts of birth defects.
But a crazy amount of people have it
like maybe as many as 50 percent of some
countries that people have 50 million
people in America.
Abbott.
I think that was the latest number.
See if that's the case number of people
in America,
but it manifests itself.
Well,
it makes men reckless.
We had this guy dr robert sapolsky on
the podcast.
Yes.
And robertson polsky's is fascinating.
Um,
scientists,
scientist and researcher,
and he spent a tremendous amount of time
studying toxoplasmosis and one of the
things that he talked about how they
found a disproportionate number of
motorcycle accidents.
Whoa.
Where the person who died had toxo.
So they would do these tests.
One of these doctors told him when we
would get a guy who died from motorcycle
crash,
we test them for toxo and it was a
disproportionate number and they think
toxo was making people reckless.
And there's also a connection in some
strange way to soccer teams that are
successful.
They find a disproportionate number of
soccer teams that are successful.
The players test positive for toxins.
They're reckless in some way or they're
fearless and it may in fact even raise
testosterone and some males and it,
it made.
No,
no,
no.
It can't be cured.
So you can test yourself for it.
Yeah,
it's a part of,
you know,
literally on the front of every
magazine.
Well,
um,
people like paul ski have only been
studying it,
only been aware of it for the last
couple of decades.
It's,
and you know,
as people who've grown up and talked
about all the various factors for why
people behave,
the way they behave is just recently
coming into the realm of understanding.
It's not a,
it's not a real like,
well established fact for many,
many,
many years.
But so paul skis done a lot of
incredible work on it and you can read
his lecture or listened to his lectures,
rather read them.
In fact,
some of the shit that he probably,
I probably have it.
Yeah,
I've got a lot of feral cats.
I've had a lot of wildcats.
Yeah.
I lived with a wildcat flick seven years
and I had a couple of,
when I was growing up that were wild.
There was always living outside,
you know,
and who knows what the fuck they were
getting outside when I was a kid.
My counts were always outside.
No,
my cat needs to bring home squirrels.
I just seen him walk across the street
with a squirrel.
He be killed a squirrel.
He had it in his mouth and squirrels
almost his size and he's literally
walking across the street with
squirrels,
body in between his legs.
He's dragging the squirrel across the
street to show me that he killed the
squirrel.
So he was probably out there killing
rats kinds of things.
Smart.
Uh,
there's a great documentary on netflix
about rats called rats.
What does It say here?
Morbid attraction to leopard urine in
toxo plasma infested chimpanzees.
Yeah.
Seeing that the chimpanzees that are
infected by toxo fuck with fuck with
leopard.
So they can get killed because the toxo
wants to grow inside the cat's gut.
Sexually,
sexually reproducing the crypt.
It is.
That's where it's actually reproduces
inside the gut of cats.
It's the only way it's viable.
They stopped being afraid so they can
basically,
they commit suicide,
not just be something afraid.
They're attracted to it.
It's drawn with them like they're like
reckless.
People are attracted to danger.
A light.
That's my fucking mind blowing.
The parasites have some sort of innate
intelligence that explained people who
are just have a higher tolerance for
danger and attraction to danger.
Yes,
probably probably addiction for sure.
There's got to be some kind of
relationship.
We know so little.
Like when we learn,
we learn shit now it's like I remember I
get really bad migraines and I was in
cedars getting morphine and I was just
like,
when was this?
Oh,
I get gnarly migraines.
Oh you go to cedars and they shoot you
up with morphine.
Says I got a headache.
I noW,
yes.
Which by the way I was on the,
the watchlist because drug addicts go in
there and they say like,
I have a migraine helped me.
So I was on a list.
They were like,
don't give it to her.
And they were like,
it's this whole thing if you go into
frequently.
And uh,
I used to get really gnarly migraines
and now I have like a whole system.
You know,
Michael Jackson,
dr.
I do see available.
I feel like he's on craigslist.
Oh,
that guy's in jail.
Told Michael Jackson,
you can't just kill the king of pop.
No,
you can't get away with that.
Is he in jail for life or a c and r?
Kelly's called now.
I think he's in jail for a wee bit
though.
like a hot man.
That shit is [inaudible] or what was,
it was a profile when I froze my eggs.
They gave me that and I was like,
I got it.
He got out on parole.
He's not allowed to practice though.
Sure.
It's talking to me tonight.
It's got a podcast.
It's going to put me under to sleep and
shit.
But I remember asking him.
I was high at least Michael Jackson died
doing what he loved sleeping.
um,
I,
uh,
one time was just like,
what causes migraines?
Like,
no,
they're like,
we don't know.
And I was like,
what do you mean you don't know?
And they're like,
there's just a lot we don't know about
neurology.
I'm like,
what are you talking like?
And then I remember another doctor was
like,
yeah,
that's why we call it a practice.
We're doing the best we can with what we
know.
So we don't call it space it out.
Like how often can you go in there and
walk yourself to the moon?
I haven't had to do that for like a
couple of years,
but when you go in they're like eee.
I think now it's a little bit better.
I don't go back to cedars because they
were shitty about my ear surgery.
Uh,
what?
I have a tattoo here when we're attached
to my ear,
they were,
it just did not go particularly well.
The doctor was very dismissive to me.
So funny.
Is this an only an la thing?
They were like,
you're need a plastic surgeon.
Do you have one that you prefer?
Oh god.
I was like,
excuse first of all.
Thank you.
Second of all.
What the fuck?
Like I just have a plastic.
Is that only in la question?
Yeah,
I would imagine.
Have you ever gotten plan to get plastic
surgery on a,
a injury?
No.
Oh really?
Have,
you know,
you have to get a plastic surgeon if
you're,
you're comes off.
I know dudes who have had their ears
fixed where they had the cauliflower
moved.
Oh,
that's hard to do though,
right,
because it's got nerve endings in it.
Well,
it's real tricky.
They have to delay your ear.
Oh,
I'm aware of peel it back and they have
to pull the,
the calcium deposits out of the hard
parts of your ear and had that on my
nose.
Really?
Yeah,
and a lot of calcium deposits in
segment.
Thank you for what you.
I mean I would assume it'd be a little
more.
The inside was pretty fucked up until 10
years ago.
You have a thing in there?
No,
no,
but when I had a deviated septum
operation,
they put these plastic stents in there
and opened everything nice.
And they cut away the turbinates.
They cut away all this tissue.
They showed me all the tissue that was
removed from my nose.
It was fucking crazy tissue.
It was like a.
Yeah,
a lot of scar tissue and a lot of when
you get blood clots,
like,
like the same stuff that happens with a
cauliflower ear,
but that is his blood leaking inbetween
the tissue cells and then it stays in
their pools up and then it calcifies and
when it calcifies it literally becomes
like a rock and you can get that stuff
in your nose too.
And some guys like it,
you get calcification in there and it,
it hardens up and,
and you also get a lot of scar tissue
and it,
it closes up the um,
the,
the nose,
a window you can't breathe out of your
nose happens.
So a lot of guys,
a lot of people that do fighting,
they talk,
like you'll hear them,
they have like a way of talking and
that's why it's because they can't
breathe through their nose.
Super,
super common.
But they can't.
Did you,
but you haven't done your areola?
No,
I never had it in my ears.
So I got a little,
I got little pieces in my ears,
but I always worked your guards.
This is important.
This helps you hear shit like all the
stuff.
The design of the interface is fucking
design of the ear though.
Particularly.
So like just take your ears.
That's what I was telling you.
Yeah.
Take your ear and then talk like this
and then fold your year's over like that
and keep talking.
La,
la,
la.
It dulls the sound.
Now imagine if you have one rocks like
literally randy coture way that the.
It's formed.
Well.
Mine is all fucked up now,
but you
can.
I guess I don't know the case.
Wouldn't you get cauliflower ear
surgery,
but they can't.
An anesthetizing your ear actually hurts
more than just getting the surgery
without anesthesia because they had to
put anesthesia in the laceration.
I guess because the cartilage,
it doesn't spread as well.
So they did the reattachment surgery
without anesthesia.
It was a fucking nightmare.
It was real as fuck.
And he was doing it and he wasn't
listening to me.
You know,
surgeons can be kind of dismissive
anyway because they're like,
god,
they think they're god.
And I was like,
sir,
can you please just give me a heads up
of like when you're going to do that,
just would do it without telling me and
I'm just like freaking out.
And I was like not being heard,
which was actually like triggering me
emotionally.
Like I can deal with physical pain.
I was getting triggered.
I was like,
I need to know.
I mean heard.
He's like totally ignoring me.
Just like doing it.
I mean punching holes into my body,
like without,
I was like,
can I get like an honorary rafter three?
And then the next day my friend called
to be like,
hey,
when can you come get her stitches out?
And the nurse was like,
oh the uh,
the surgeon can't talk on the phone,
he's deaf.
I got a depth surgeon and they just
didn't even tell me.
I feel like you need to give someone a
heads up on that.
You should definitely give her.
How the fuck is he going to know if he
was screaming at him.
LIke,
sir,
can you please like give me a heads up?
And he just was
deaf.
I know a dude who got cauliflower ear
and then somehow or another got a staph
infection inside of his ear and it was
so bad they had to remove his ear and
they had a solder it because the
infection was so prevalent.
It was constantly leaking fluid out of
his ear.
What solder mean?
They had a fucking like do in the wild
west movies where a guy gets shot,
they slap iron to it.
Oh god.
Cauterize.
It caught our eyes.
So the cauterize.
The inside of cold solder.
I'm being dramatic.
I don't know if they do that with a
cleft palate.
Highrise.
The inside cauterize,
the smell cauterizing
and it didn't work.
They had to do it again.
Carla.
Just tricky.
You had to go in there more than once
and cleaned it out.
Put shoot antibiotics in there because
you can't fight with it or wrestle with
it because it'll keep popping and had a
staph infection inside of his ear.
That's good.
Which is super bad.
What does it.
These headphones.
Bone conduction headphones.
Good enough yet.
I don't know.
No,
I haven't.
That's what you're talking about.
The sound name.
You think of that their,
uh,
their headphones you put,
you put them on like headphones,
but they don't go in your ear.
They go on your ear and they vibrate in
your jaw.
The sound literally as vibrant.
There's no sound coming out of them.
It's vibrations,
which is what sound is.
And it vibrates into your head,
not through your ear.
All this shit.
I went to sound audio engineering
school.
He's very smart.
That,
um,
have you heard them?
Yeah,
yeah.
I was at the cs I went to a couple
months ago.
I tested them out there,
but like they're coming out again.
There's a video going around where
people are getting,
like,
amazed by how,
what it sounds like when you're putting
something weird.
It's a very weird feeling because it's
literally vibrating really small pulses
on your skin.
It didn't sound bad.
You would fucking
love it.
What do you smoke some weed.
Go to a sound bath.
There's one in pasadena.
I just didn't want to in joshua tree.
it's like,
will you,
you'll,
you'll probably be better.
It's this guy that does bowls,
but it vibrates your entire body with
sound.
And it's like this hypnotic you,
I mean,
I liked,
got paralyzed,
like I couldn't move my body.
It's so clean this place.
The way that they dome it and the way
that the sound travels like renders you
paralyzed.
It's like this insane out of body
experience.
There's one of these places that's
really famous.
That's in palm springs,
right?
Isn't it?
See that white one.
That's the one I went to.
That's in joshua tree.
There's something about joshua tree.
They say it has the most conductive
sound or there's something about the
electricity in the earth that makes it
particularly powerful.
That's the one that I went to.
I mean I did some other good before.
how it was on a scale of one to snoop
dogg was r kelly.
I was like.
And I was like a six out of 10 in
hiGhness.
So you saw a concert inside?
There's one.
Actually I'm wearing a shirt of.
Oh,
concert.
Oh really?
Really special.
They had a screen up and they projected
three d images on the screen and you
couldn't take your cell phones.
And so it's really hard to find anything
about this.
But yeah,
it was a really cool experience.
It was the sound insane.
It was weird because it was all in,
it was different.
They had to spend some time figuring it
out so it sounded good in there to enjoy
it as a concert.
So if You stand in the middle of the
room,
you hear like waves just because of the
way that there's like a hole in the
ceiling and you just like hear this,
like it's oddly numbing and your skin
starts tingling and you just go into the
hypnotic state.
I came out of it and I was like,
I had no idea if I was here for six
hours or 10 minutes.
It was wild.
he was like,
no concept of time.
It was pretty awesome.
So it's doing something to you.
It's doing something.
W what's someone in pasedena?
That's the one I want to try.
Um,
but I'm super into it,
super into it and I'm like not like a
lay on the ground with strangers type of
person.
So those are the bowls that he rubs.
Soundbath center.
what's the science of it though?
Oh,
there's one in eagle rock,
same science that makes crystals really
dirty feet.
See,
I don't do.
I'm not a crystal.
Are you on the crystal tip or you're
into crystals.
Crystals happening.
That's salt lamps,
but they just look cool.
Oh,
you don't do this because it's like,
no,
I don't think they do anything.
That one doesn't even have a light bulb
in my house and I don't even know why.
I do have those lights that are sunlight
replicates sunlight and make serotonin.
Happy roads.
I have those in my house.
I always wonder if like maybe some of
the positive energy in this room is
because of that salt lamp.
Very good vibe in here.
I'm worried about you getting a new
studio called studio.
This energy.
It's very good,
but you're replicating this size.
That's awesome.
Almost exactly the same.
This amazing tv is a little bigger.
I like that same desk.
This desk has like.
I like how life like intimate as it is.
yes.
All right.
We're done too much.
We've talked for three and a half years.
I know how we always do crazy.
Crazy.
But your book is out.
Tell everybody about your book.
I wrote a book,
buy it.
Go buy that book pitch.
All right.
Thank you.
Catch up.