We're good.
We're live art.
What does that echo thing going on
anymore?
We'd killed that were good.
Nick,
how are you buddy?
Pretty good.
Well thank you.
So you've got this hat on.
Nick.
Curse on that.
I'm saying not last name.
Curtis in Carson.
Yeah,
like Chris and have you.
You train a Hofeld Osan.
Joe's a Russell on providing the cough
and you've got his hat on roofs.
Salons hat on.
It says what does it say again?
Ratzy bowler hats and in Russian I
believe that translates to something
like young warrior or young fighter,
something like that.
That's funny because I ran into a couple
of Russians the other day and asked them
if they knew what it meant and they
didn't even know.
They just need.
The last part was fighter and they
didn't know that the first apartment.
So I don't know.
That guy is a character providing the
crops.
One of my favorite fighters to watch
because he can't be in a boring fight.
He doesn't have it at him.
I mean that guy fights like the most
exciting style of fighting inboxing to
that.
It just comes at you.
You know,
he's just an animal.
Unfortunately.
He takes a little too much punishment
though.
Yeah.
Well he's almost too brave.
You know,
almost two brave in too tough,
but fucking not fight with Matisa.
Oh my God.
That was insane.
That was what everybody was hoping.
Floyd Mayweather.
It would be made with a pack.
Yeah,
that's what everybody was hoping it
would be.
I was like,
you know,
you guys are out of your mind.
You don't know what you're about to
watch.
You guys are spending millions of
dollars.
It's going to be like the biggest gate
ever.
And what you're going to watch is a
floyd mayweather exhibition on movement
and Jabbing and straight rights lead.
Right?
Hands clench.
Get out of the way.
I mean,
that's what you're going to say.
That's,
that's exactly what it was.
But providing a cough.
God,
how do you think the guys feel the,
uh,
tuned into the child's junior fight that
night and miss the Monica?
They were silly.
I watched both.
I mean,
that's the beautiful thing about dvrs
Chavez Jr.
Looks like he's phoning it in.
Yeah.
He just does not.
Look like the same guy like daddy
wouldn't when he was younger and much
more exciting and just looked,
looked like a real promising future
champion.
He just doesn't,
doesn't have the volume anymore.
Doesn't look like he's in shape.
Fighting much heavier,
right?
Yeah.
I'm a tsa and providing a cup fight with
something else.
So you're a strength and conditioning
coach.
And one of the reasons whY I wanted to
call you and here is because I am
absolutely fascinated by the marina
bitches,
right?
The guys who taught you a lot of what
you know.
And um,
I'm also fascinated by just tHe
boundaries of human potential when it
comes to strength and conditioning
because as,
as an analyst,
as a guy who sits there and watch his
fights and I've seen,
I don't even know how many fights would
have probably professionally called
several thousand fights at this point.
I don't even know how many it's been
really.
It's been at least 1500 or something of
the best fights ever.
Right.
And you start seeing things over and
over and over again.
And occasionally there's these outliers
and these outliers are guys who just
have way more gas than anybody else.
Guys who have way more ability to push
deep into the fourth and fifth rounds
and you just wonder,
like how much of what we're seeing in
terms of what a fighter can do inside
the octagon or inside the ring,
how much of it is,
how much endurance they have.
And I maintain that.
It's a significant amount.
AbsoLutely.
I think it's,
I think it's everything.
It might be 90 percent of it or
something like that at least because it
seems like everybody is pretty skillful
once they get to the upper levels of the
ufc when you're dealing with a pedes or
a dose on joe's or all,
all across the board.
When you,
when you hit those high level guys,
they're all very skillful and some are
better at certain aspects of fighting
than other.
But it seems like the ones who can win
and win the way,
the way pedis and dos just went down the
way.
Dos anjos just dominated paddocks,
right?
You have to have a fucking insane gas
tank.
Absolutely.
Um,
I don't know if you've see my instagram
and seeing some of the videos I did.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I'm,
I'm a fascinated by it.
So yeah.
Rafael,
when he first came to me,
this was after the [inaudible] fight.
He'd tried several other strength and
conditioning coaches as we came to me
about two or three workouts in.
He's like,
wow,
this is already amazing.
I feel the difference.
And that's when I began to assess like,
like a longterm plan.
So like when I first get a new athlete,
I don't just look at the immediate
fight,
I look where I want,
I want them to be about a year from now,
six months from now and three or four
fights from that,
whatever.
But I kind of knew like some things that
were holding him back and areas that
weren't trained properly that we needed
to rectify.
What do you see when you,
when you start working out with a guy,
like how do you,
how do you first of all realize it?
you know,
what I'd like to do,
like this is something that the
marinovich has did with bj penn was the
first thing they did was they got a
heart rate monitor on them,
so,
and then they put them through sparring
to find out what areas tax them the most
and then that's what they would kind of
designed the camp towards.
So if wrestling taxes you the most,
so that's the energy system we need to
train the most for you.
So,
you know,
like with bj,
he never had any problem with his
longterm arabic.
It was always as anaerobic energy
systems.
So it was always sprinting.
Exactly.
The big burst,
short burst and long bursts.
So entire amount.
The issue was the recovery from short
burst.
Absolutely.
And uh,
yeah,
exactly.
So if,
if your,
if your anaerobic systems aren't chain
properly,
you won't get that recovery in between
the burst and some guys will go their
entire career without ever correcting
that.
And you're always exactly in this weird
limbo state where you're scared to push
it too hard.
Right?
Exactly.
Now you take a guy like hoffeld dos
anjos that has beaten donald cerrone.
So when he came to you,
who's already world class one of the
best fighters in the division,
I think it was ranked 10th when I
started with
him.
So he's a good fighter.
And that time we began training for the
roost.
Um,
he was scheduled to fight roost on copy
of exactly and we did a pretty much a
full training camp.
We did six weeks of training and then
colby law pulled out I think two weeks
prior to the fight with a hurt finger or
something.
And so,
so then we had a break for about three
weeks in between and then he got the
news that he's gonna fight khabib.
So he did another full training camp and
prior to the cubby fight I actually left
for weeks before the fight.
So we stopped strength and conditioning
for weeks.
So he missed the complete peak to peak
fanny,
a peak training phase of the,
of the conditioning program.
And I think that's one of the reasons
why you lost that.
Partially.
Yeah.
I feel a little bit of a responsibility
for that.
Sure.
But,
uh,
also you have to admit habib number
grumet off is a fucking monster.
He is.
He's a monster.
He's a,
he's a good fighter.
uh,
I think,
and I hate to make excuses,
but I think if people understood like
what referral went through before that
fight,
they would be a little more accepting of
the fact that he might kick khabib's ass
next time they fight.
You know,
a lot of people are already saying
kebabs.
A new champion I did roughly almost had
his fricking eye gouged out.
THe whites of his eyes like this was
during the training camp.
So he had to take another couple of
weeks off in the middle of the training
camp.
The whites of his eyes were literally
hanging down from guys fingernails where
he though they're sparring,
they got poked his finger nails into his
eyes and the whites of the eyes were,
were stripped of it were hanging down
below his eyelid.
Oh god.
Yeah.
And then so what they do to fix that,
I guess they just trimmed it off and
yeah,
I just turned it off.
And then let.
Yeah,
wait a minute.
You could trim the whites of your eye
level.
Apparently.
God,
yeah.
Rafael is a monster.
Like people don't understand is because
the guy had fingernails.
Fingernails.
Exactly.
And there's farming and he went to push
them back or something.
Two fingers went right into his eye and
know,
you know,
obviously he's not going to put that out
there on the internet and show people,
hey,
look at my fucked up.
I or she should not.
Have you seen his ear?
I don't know if you saw the picture of
his ear recent.
Uh,
no.
This is the same thing leading up to the
khabib fight.
Prior to that,
his ear was ripped off in the cage.
So it got stuck in between.
A couple of the links have seen that
picture and his ear was hanging on by a
thread.
It is jesus christ.
So this is all going on during training
camp.
Wow.
One thing after the other.
And then I leave for weeks out.
Not to mention he switched to a vegan
diet.
What's?
Yeah,
for that fight.
Why did he do that?
I have no idea who told,
told him to do that.
No idea.
Do you have any response?
I just ate vegan lunch by the way.
So talking shit.
I eat a lot of vegan food.
I talk a lot of shit about vegans,
but my,
my,
my diet consists mostly of vegan meals
and murdered animals are combined those
two.
That's pretty
interesting.
I just,
I feel like you can't get.
It's very difficult to get everything
you need from just vegetables,
but I feel like you really can't eat
enough vegetables.
I think vegetables are super important
for you.
I think that it's one of the main issues
that people suffer from when it comes to
health anD nutrition.
even a lot of vegan people,
they too much breads and pastas and rice
and things along those lines.
And I think you need a lot of
vegetables.
I think it's super important for it to
change is the way I think and feel.
Have you ever tried to supplement called
dim?
What is it?
Dim?
No,
what is it?
What does this diane doll me thinking?
Hmm.
And it's supposedly like a concentration
all the cruciferous vegetables,
but it helps lower like estrogen levels.
Scott phytoestrogen.
So it helps.
It helps your body metabolize estrogen.
And I tell you what,
it actually works.
It gives you gnarly gas,
but it works.
I don't know if I'm willing to make that
trade off.
I did.
It's worth it.
Take it on an empty stomach.
Back room.
Yeah.
Jesus.
Crazily.
Yeah.
Don't tell certain people that I know
that.
Not blowing Farts on folks.
The other night my fiance and my baby
woke me up.
He was laughing or that,
that poop?
No,
it was very funny.
So,
so who talked a dos anjos into going
vegan?
Uh,
you know,
I don't know to be honest.
I don't remember.
I think he just kinda something he
wanted to try and his own and,
and,
and if you notice in that fight he looks
quite a bit smaller too.
Like his shoulders look smaller and he
looks
loss of muscle mass.
Well,
you know,
there's some health benefits to eating a
lot of vegetables.
I just don't,
I don't think there's enough evidence to
promote veganism.
I just don't think it's worth the.
I think the,
the tradeoff is too significant and I
think your body,
I mean we're omnivores,
it's just the way it is and especially
when you're dealing with high level
athletes that are blowing down a lot of
muscle tissue on a regular basis.
So a lot of recovery that needs to be
done.
If you're just a regular person going
through life without any significant
stress on your body,
you probably can get,
get through,
fine with it.
But I think for high level athletes are
very difficult to find a vegan,
high level athlete,
especially in an explosive combat
sports.
Um,
so you don't have anything to do with
the diet stuff.
If a guy needs my help,
then yeah,
I'll do it.
But a lot of these guys now have
nutritionist,
so that kind of takes a lot of work off
of my back workload off my back.
But
it's funny because fighters have a short
window of time to be the best,
right?
I mean a fighter's career,
like somebodY pointed it out once,
I think it was on mixed martial arts.com
that there's like a nine year period
where a guy can really fight great.
RIght.
And then after that,
excuse me,
the wheels just sorta start to fall off
and just the body can only take so much
finding.
Great.
You think that's a mental Thing though?
Do you think they get too comfortable
and they loSe it?
It's possible thAt I think that's
absolutely.
I think why gsp quit at the right time.
You know what I mean?
He's got all these like gq magazine
things coming up and I don't know how
much money that guy's work now,
but he doesn't need to fight.
Yeah.
Maybe the same thing happened with bj.
Maybe he quit a little too late,
but yeah,
I think once they get too comfortable,
I think then it's,
that's it.
Silver.
It is possible.
I think the mental strain of camps is
absolutely brutal on these guys.
I mean,
you would know as good as anybody,
you know,
I've,
I've been to high level training camps,
I've watched guys go out and I've
watched guys go do their strength and
conditioning routines and it's fucking,
it's an ungodly.
I barely can get through a fucking yoga
class,
you know,
these,
these guys are doing two a days and
strength and conditioning in the
morning,
beating the fuck out of each other at
night and going home and exhausted.
And then one of the things that bj said
about training with the marinda bitches
was,
it was just too much.
Like his performances were legendary,
legendary.
So was,
was it the training really too much read
bj had enough.
that's the question to ask.
That's a good point.
You know what I mean?
By the time the has got a hold of him,
he'd already had a 10 plus year career.
Exactly.
You know?
You look at that diego sanchez fight,
I maintain.
There's very few people ever that fought
at 1:55.
You could fuck with bj when he was in
that mode.
Goddamn he waS a killer.
That.
Exactly.
It's funny because I just talked to
[inaudible] about this the other day.
No,
I,
just to clarify why,
what happened with us and it came down
to what gary explained to me was they'd
reached a point in training where they
were doing their strength training in
the morning.
Then they had the spine was going on in
the afternoons and pj approach them and
you know,
he wasn't like a dick about it or
anything.
It's totally cool.
Like,
hey,
like,
you know,
how would you guys feel if we did the,
uh,
strength training on another day so that
I can do my sparring,
you know what,
I'm fresh for sparring.
And I think marvin gary took that as,
you know,
he wasn't ready for that.
He wasn't at that level yet or they're
ready to back off the air conditioning
training.
They don't do that.
so I mean there's a method behind their
training and it's very rational.
So I think the fact that he was
questioning them at that point was just
like,
enough.
Maybe there's some other stuff goIng on.
I don't know.
But I think the questioning of their
abilities as trainers at that point,
like as if they didn't know what they
were doing was enough to turn them off
and kinda well wish.
I think what the,
the mindset of fighters when it comes to
strength conditioning versus versus
skill work is that it's very important
to stay sharp with the skill work.
It's very difficult to do that if you're
already exhausted from strength and
conditioning.
Right.
So how do you find that balance?
Is it,
is it smarter to do the skill work in
the morning and then the strength and
conditioning later on the evening or
like how,
how do you,
how do you find that balance?
Are we talking about in general here?
Are we talking about general?
What I would perceive for,
for bj either are either we're like if,
if I was closer and closer to my side,
if I was,
is a,
I probably would've done the same thIng
and maybe
tone down the sparring a little bit
already.
Phenomenally skilled.
Maybe the one of the most skilled
fighters we've ever seen in the ufc.
I was a fan of his before.
He was even in the ufc,
I told people this dude when I saw him
at tournament's as a blue belt,
black belt in jujitsu,
by the way.
Uh,
so I've seen these guys from the start.
I said,
this kid's going to be freaking
phenomenal.
You said the same thing about nick diaz
two years ago,
and I was,
when he was a purple belt,
I'd seen him at tournament.
It was a blue belt even.
I'd be like,
this guy,
when he gets you watch,
he's going to be a fighter and he's
going to be phenomenal.
Like tear these guys up.
So pj skill has never been in question
right there that tells you,
hey,
conditioning has always been the issue
with bj.
I've never seen him outclass like skill
wise by anybody,
you know.
It's always been a strength and
conditioning.
That's,
that's costume.
His fights.
What did you think when you saw his last
fight with frankie edgar?
Would he adopted that?
Very strange blown away at how stupid
that was?
Well,
I mean that was just ridiculous.
Like why would you.
You're pretty much.
I just had this conversation with
freddie roach about a month ago.
he told me bj penn was one of the best
boxers he's ever trained.
Really like even out of the boxers in
the gym.
Bj penn was one of the best natural
boxers he's ever trained for folks who
don't know what
we're talking about.
Bj had adopted this very strange style
that I'd never seen before.
Whereas feet were very close together
and he was just moving really ending up,
right?
Like iT's a raf almost completely
straight up instead of like the classic
style of a stand up fighter.
I mean there's various it,
there's variables when it comes to
standup fighting for mma because you,
you have a more squared off stance
because you want to have your hips in
place to take down defense.
But the classic stances shoulders or a
pi hands are right by the face,
you know,
head movement.
Bj did this weird thing where it just,
he looked like,
like almost like a guy playing
pretending to be a fighter.
Like he was doing this weird and he had
said afterwards,
which really bothered me.
He said that he did it to conserve
energy.
That is again,
conserved energy.
There it is again.
I thought he said because his trainers
really felt that he generated more
forced that way.
There's no way.
That's insane,
but I love whatever conditions there.
You don't need to worry about concerns.
Right,
right.
Okay.
So what was the consensus that made them
part ways because the performances that
he put on with them or individuals war
legendary really work some of the best
of.
WhAt was it?
It florian and then they did the diego
sanchez fight and then they left about
five weeks out from the frankie edgar
fight.
Really?
Yeah.
So five weeks at this type of training
needs to be done pretty much up until
the day of the fight.
So they did train him a little bit for
the frankie edgar,
three weeks,
maybe four weeks at the most and what
happened and that's when they had the
dIscussion about changing up the
program,
like a can we do the conditioning on
different days and so they just decided
to walk away.
Yeah.
Wow.
It just felt it wasn't going the way
they want it,
I think.
Yeah,
I think they were.
They respected frankie edgar is that
this guy's going to be trouble.
This guy's coming to fight,
has got a gas tank.
He's,
he's no pushover,
you know,
and who's a motherfucker.
He's a relentless motherfucker which
shows you how god damn good uriah
favorites because they,
you know,
right.
Your rise to fighting one weight class
up,
right.
You know,
usually fights it.
One 35 finding 1:45
and they,
they went five rounds and I mean frankie
won a decision,
but there was no point in that fight
where he was going to finish your Ohio.
No point where you.
I was in significant trouble,
you know,
they were pretty much gone blow for
blow,
but frankie was getting an edge and
basically every round,
I think frankie is one of the best
condition guys and I would love to find
out what he does for his strength and
conditioning because he's never fucking
tired.
He's always able to push that same pace
every round.
And that seems to be what separates the
greats that truly grades from everybody
else underneath them.
No,
it's funny.
It's a lot of people are talking about
the dust angeles pettis fight,
but between me and the yield and the
rest of the world,
in my opinion,
rafael is in better conditioning,
better shape for the benson henderson
fight.
Really?
Yeah,
absolutely.
He wasn't a fight.
He was injured so three weeks out he
injured his knee and aspiring accident.
And so we had to change things up.
We couldn't do any more field work,
we couldn't do any writing or anything
like that.
So we had to kind of modify it.
And that's when you see,
I got them during the sprints on the
airdyne bicycle and only pretty much
something safe,
you know,
and uh,
but I had him at like 12,000
feet elevation,
gradually built them up to that.
so we're at high altitude
to the benson henderson fight was
incredibly impressive because he was the
first guy to ever stopped.
Benson was strikes and benson is just
notoriously durable,
unbelievably tough,
big for the weight class and,
and dos anjos just jumped all over him.
He had destroyed him,
was a big fight.
It was a big like,
like,
whoa,
this guy's on another level right now.
That's why it kind of blew my mind,
like why people pay to keep reminding
you,
but it closer to get sentenced.
I,
it sounds good to us,
but the recording is weird.
I got you.
Sorry.
Don't need to repeat anything.
No,
it's fine.
Okay,
well,
like I said,
I think he was in better shape for the,
for the benson henderson fight,
you know,
I don't know why people couldn't see
this coming,
you know,
like get a good sense.
Just so good.
Pete.
Me look at how he handled that.
Right.
You know,
brendan,
that she is fucking huge and a killer.
I kids big see how big that is in real
life.
He's fucking big.
He's a big.
He's,
he's a good size one.
80 five.
Right.
and as a seventies fucking huge.
And benson handled him.
Yeah.
So I think people just thought,
hey,
this is a great fight.
I mean I didn't,
I didn't necessarily count dosantos out,
but I certainly didn't think he was
gonna stop them the way you just fucking
beat his ass.
Yeah,
I thought it was gonna.
I thought it was gonna be a really good
fight.
That's what I thought.
I mean
hence pharma champion,
been there with some of the best ever.
You know,
I've thought this is gonna be a great
fight.
Yeah,
that's interesting.
I didn't,
I kinda knew like at the end of the
training camp,
the different sites,
the difference we've made in that
training camp in terms of speed and
power and his stamina.
I just knew like I knew where he was
before and I knew where he was after and
I said he's just going to destroy him.
Like I hope I almost wanted it to go
five rounds so he could show like what
it was capable of.
Wow.
Well,
that's pretty crazy that he,
you know,
when we found out after the pettis
fight,
where he won the title and just one by
just dominating the champion and a guy
who dana white had been pretty public
saying he thought was the best pound for
pound fighter in the sport.
and you know,
I didn't,
I didn't agree with that necessarily,
but I'd certainly did take the kid was
spectacular.
I mean,
the way he stopped donald cerrone,
the waist up,
joe lozan,
I mean he was capable of just unleashing
these kicks out of nowhere to put people
away.
He just fucking good way arm barred
benson.
I mean he's just in the way he caught
gilbert to mean called gIlbert and good
team.
He's fucking good.
And you think he
gilbert in that or do you think it was
almost.
I mean,
not saying that fight was rig or
anything,
but gilbert made a terrible mistake.
I mean he's sitting on his knees with
his head up.
He had been tagged.
Yeah,
that's what it was.
Been hurt.
He,
if you watch that fight,
I've watched it several times.
A pet his had caught him several times,
some pretty hard shots when gilbert was
coming in because he knew gilbert
strategy was.
It was no secret.
Gilbert was just gonna stay on the
outside a little bit,
press hIm up against the cage.
Who's this to the clay guido strategy
essentially.
Yeah,
it was.
Which was his first loss.
I mean,
that was pegasys first loss in the
octagon.
You know,
when he first came to the ufc,
he was the wec champion and clay gui to
beat him.
And everybody's like,
well,
welcome to the ufc dude.
Right.
And everybody kind of knew,
okay,
well this guy,
at least at this stage of his career is
vulnerable to something like this.
Yeah.
But gilbert just didn't have the same
tools that dosantos house until sandra
says much faster,
much faster.
He's,
he's a fucking.
He's a dangerous dangerous right now.
Yeah,
he's extremely dangerous.
And his conditioning was off the charts
and then when you tell me that he was
knee was hurt three weeks out and he
couldn't do anything but airdyne
sprints.
That's incredible.
I mean,
that's amazing.
Well,
they're at high altitudes,
so that's pretty,
uh,
how's he doing it at a highlight?
Have the,
I have an altitude simulator.
I have the hypoxic altitude simulator,
not the little velcro masks,
but this is the actual one that thins
the air and,
and changes your blood oxygen levels.
So,
I mean it takes time to build up to
that.
I wouldn't recommend anyone go try it at
12,000
feet right now.
You're going to have like a seizure or
something,
you know what I mean?
Maybe I aneurism,
I don't know.
But it took probably three weeks to get
them to that point where he was able to
sprint on that thing.
So I mean we'd been building up for
awhile and then there's things.
Obviously I can't tell you on the air
because I don't give away too many
people that I tell
you it was rigorous and there was,
there was times when I would watch and
I'd want to pull the plug and be like,
hey,
you know what I mean?
but you gotta listen to your gut.
And uh,
just keep pushing them and know what
they can take.
Is that a factor,
a big factor when you're working with an
athlete that you have to know what this
athlete is capable of and where were you
going to break them that?
Absolutely.
I think that's probably the most
critical factor.
I think you hit it right on the head
because it seems like you're.
You're dancing that line,
man.
He was a thin line man and that's the
way you get a guy better,
right?
You gotta get them right to that fucking
ads and then pull them back.
How have you seen the movie whiplash?
Yes.
That's basically sums it up.
Right?
And then that teacher was so good at
what he did.
He brought out the best.
I've got the wrong move in my head.
You're talking about the movie.
I'm not going to tell you,
don't tell me about it,
but I saw the ads are screaming and
yelling at somebody.
I was confused.
I'm like,
how does that factor in?
That was the thing in a totally
different movie,
but it is,
it's the,
uh,
I was thinking,
fuck,
is he going to make this a.
No,
no,
but that's it.
The intuition and the I,
I believe that I as the most important
in what you see and what your athletes
doing,
you see the speed deteriorate,
then you've gone too far.
You need to know how to get your,
got a peak In every exercise and then
cut it off.
And what's the variability as far as
recovery?
Does everybody,
I mean,
people must recover at different rates.
Absolutely.
Uh,
it also depends on their past like
conditioning too,
you know what I mean?
So like if a guy's never had a certain
type of aerobic or anaerobic training
and of course it's going to take a few
more days to recover,
that's going to take a lot longer to
develop.
That was one of the things that you
arrive,
faber said was one of the reasons why
his team,
the team alpha male has so few injuries.
So like there's some camps that have
amazing records,
uh,
as far as their fighters fighters when
grape,
but they have a giant amount of
injuries.
But his,
his camp team,
alpha male,
occasionally guys get hurt.
LIke tj had to pull out of the head and
brow fight because of a broken rib,
but those are just bones,
just like you can only take so much.
You know,
your bone is like benevidez said it
best.
He's like a rib at the end of the day is
just a rib and it can only take so much
and when it breaks it breaks.
Um,
but those guys are always in shape.
And you're,
I was saying that it's like a lifestyle
thing that they never get out of shape.
they're always training very hard.
They're always in peak condition.
So it's not about getting,
having to get into shape already in
shape.
Well,
I'd also wonder what kind of strength
and strength training they're doing.
And to this day,
I mean,
if they're doing heavy weight lifting
and you're doing that,
you're around,
you're going to get fucked up.
It's just going to happen.
It destroys the muscular equilibrium.
And that's been proven.
So if he,
if you got a good program and it helps
maintain the health of the athletes and
you know that's something.
No,
when you say that heavy weightlifting
destroys the equilibrium of the athlete,
would exactly do you mean by.
so what I mean by that is let's say a.
Let's say you're doing bicep curls for
example,
and you're.
You're doing a heavy weight lifting,
you're doing heavy bicep curls,
you're shortening that bicep,
right?
We know the one that has a muscle gets
bigger,
it gets shorter because of the
cross-bridging.
So when you shorten one muscle,
you lengthen the opposite muscle and
that puts the joint and the tendons and
ligaments are at risk for injury.
Hm.
So if you do like,
say if you're doing something along the
lines of bicep curls,
it must be critical that you do tricep
extensions or dips or something along
those lines.
Absolutely.
But what's more,
what's even more important is to engage
the tendons and ligaments,
the elastic components of,
of the,
of the connective tissue.
So the musculaR attending unit as a
whole,
and now that's on a,
that's a whole nother level.
ThAt's like a.
It requires a certain amount of
essential overload.
Essentially it would be like the
movement coming downward,
like when you do a bench press,
the negative portion of that,
that's the eccentric portion of the lift
has to come down with approximately 40
percent greater force downward.
Then it goes up to maintain muscular
equilibrium.
How do you do that?
Well,
biometrics biometrics are a perfect
example of that.
So like
do you,
you would not just incorporate bench
press,
you would do
like a plow metric.
Manage press.
How's that work?
Uh,
I don't know if you have video or
anything that,
um,
you can,
you can probably see on my instagram.
Uh,
you probably seen bj penn doing it too,
so.
Well,
so plyometric bench press?
Yeah.
As opposed to a traditional bench trust
on what happens with that is I can
describe it when,
if he brings it out.
Okay.
I can describe it now if you like,
you see anything on this room?
Is it a speed of sport?
Yeah.
Instagram,
speed of sport.
And then if you scroll down you might
see one I hope finally here,
here go plyometric ballistic bench
press.
I don't know if I'd use that one to be
honest.
No,
I don't know.
Let's check it out.
Is that somebody else?
It's not me.
No.
Okay.
Let's see.
This guy.
He's throwing it a little too slow on
the way down.
You get typed in speed of sport on
youtube and you can find it too.
Okay,
there we go.
Click.
If you click on that one right there.
Here we go.
You'll see a couple of random bits.
Trina's still see a couple of other
guys.
Whoa.
Serious fucking jumps.
Is that a girl?
Yeah.
Really,
because it's a dude with crazy hair.
I was like,
that's the most bad ass chick of all
time.
If you took a jump like that.
Yeah.
That's like the ronda rousey of box
jumpers,
right?
Yeah.
That looks like a girl.
Yeah,
up until you go.
Wait,
what is she even doing with our
endocrine system?
Exactly.
Like jesus christ.
These are crazy jumps,
man.
Yeah,
these are.
This kid came to me.
This was about five weeks after a grade
two ankle sprain,
so you can see this heels don't even
touch there.
It's just All balls of the feet,
the toes.
So this is similar to what,
like an ice have a,
excuse me,
a plow plow metric,
um,
bench press would look like,
but they,
we're doing with the feet right there.
So these jumps,
I'm like your,
your big obviously on explosive
movements,
plyometrics.
So this thing is,
I've seen this on the ba bj penn
training things.
He said this kid is sitting with his
back,
he's lying on his back rather,
but it's but,
but has a bounce ball under it.
And then there's this padded thing above
him that he keeps kicking up.
and what's the philosophy behind that?
First of all,
you learn how to control your limb
better.
When you're upside down like that and
there's no load.
You get greater control of your limb at
the same time you can,
you can work the full extension of the
foot,
which is crucial in pretty much every
sport.
So he's catching these,
these guys,
these things for arms to now and so
that's.
So that's like a plant metric movement
right there for the upper body right
there.
so it's explosive.
Now,
what's interesting is that these,
other than this particular exercise,
those are machines and a lot of people
right here.
This when joe right there.
Okay,
so this is the bench?
Yeah.
Okay,
so it's.
You catch it with your hands.
There's pads,
so he's throwing it off so he.
He's maximizing this contraction as it
comes off him.
He's not shortening his reach.
He,
he's got to produce a great amount of
force to throw that off his fingers.
That last thing he did was crazy balance
ball thing.
This is nuts.
That's some incredible movement.
He's a kids.
I'm a three time national champion for
taekwondo.
Jesus christ.
Yeah.
That kid is ridiculously flexible.
Look at that fucking leg.
What's that kid's name?
Ryan tucker.
Wow.
Where's he out of torrance.
Torrance,
California.
And he's in national taekwondo champion.
Yeah,
that's.
Taekwondo has its fault,
but god was.
When it comes to leg dexterity,
some of those guys have the most
unbelievable leg dexterity and if you
could teach them all the other skills,
thai wrestling,
all this stuff,
they have such a weird advantage with
their legs.
Right?
Like looking at that guy.
Fucking people can do that.
Not many.
That's not what that kind of range of
motion.
And he's doing it with ankle weights on.
Is that what going?
Yeah.
How many,
how much pounds?
Probably like two and a half pounds.
just very light.
Yeah,
just enough to get a stretch out of the
muscle.
So that's what we're trying to do.
Yeah.
The whole method.
Here's the stretch shortening cycle.
So you want to stretch the muscle before
you shorten it,
so stretch it before you can track that
plan metrics through the same thing.
They put the tendons,
ligaments and muscles stretch and I just
snapped back with greater force.
So that's called the stretch shortening
cycle.
So now the benefit of that is it trains
fast twitch at a speed also that's
relevant to the sport.
So if you're not training at the speed
of sport,
you're training any slower than that.
you're training slow twitch,
you're training,
you're doing a detrimental a exercise
for your sport.
So anytime you're doing like a heavy
lift that slow.
Right?
You think that that's bad for the sport?
Absolutely.
Without a doubt.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
and it's,
well it is,
but it makes sense if you look at the
best athletes are the ones that have the
highest rate of forced development,
the ones that can produce the greatest
amount of force in the least amount of
time.
Okay.
So that means like a guy that can,
you know,
I don't know,
jump and touch his head on the ceiling
versus a guy that,
you know,
in a split second person,
the guy who would take him three or four
seconds to get up there.
So that will be a comparison between a
plyometric band trust.
Like I just showed you on the video
there as compared to like a 225,
250 pound bench press.
So you're a biG fan of doing everything,
just exploded everything.
Absolutely.
That's interesting because there is a
school of thought,
especially along with jujitsu guys,
were they like a super super slow
training where they'll do like a chin up
and each chinup takes like 15,
20 seconds.
You seen that?
Yeah.
Do you think about that?
That's just a pretty much,
that's an isotonic contraction.
I don't see how that even helps jujitsu
at all either.
well,
the idea is that if you get someone's
back and you're working the choke,
you,
you know your arms might gas out,
but this way they won't match up.
I'll tell you right now,
as soon as the whole thing with bj penn
opened my eyes to so many different
things and what I felt when I was
training with him was there was no
strength.
His technique was so precisely time that
he needed absolutely no,
no strength.
Literally.
No,
sorry.
It was more about timing and the speed
at which he moved and so if you're
squeezing the guy,
maybe you need to brush up on your
technique a little bit,
you know what?
Do you know what I mean?
Like when you've trained with john.
Jock I ticket.
Yup.
Okay.
When I started jujitsu,
I started with hixon gracie.
I was there for three years.
I got my blue belt from hixson and then
I went to the machado school in redondo
beach and I went there at a time.
When you show up on saturdays,
john,
he again,
haji,
and they're all on the mat.
There are training with the students.
Plus you have bob bass,
you have rick williams,
you have all these great black belts
underneath them where are training with
all the students deaf and so how can you
beat that role?
I mean,
that's like amazing.
You know what I mean?
So there's like these guys have these
red things on their black lady,
like,
what the heck is this man?
I'm like,
I don't even know.
Like,
what planet is this?
Are these guys good luck.
Yeah,
but you've trained with john jockey.
You feel how he just effortless whatever
you do,
you do it to yourself.
You know what I mean?
It was the same thing with bj penn.
It's like I was a decent black belt.
I was okay when I first got my black
belt and then after training with bj and
those guys,
man,
being in a,
in that training camp,
it completely opened my mind to fuck.
I've been doing everything wrong for the
last 20 years.
How so?
Forcing things.
I was forcing everything,
my workouts,
I was forcing everything.
I was pushing myself to the limit.
I was lifting heavy weights.
Money.
I could squat 425 pounds.
I can bench three.
Oh five.
I weighed 168 pounds so people can talk
to me all they want about weightlifting,
but I tell you right now,
I am far more far stronger than I've
ever been.
Like I might not look it,
but like,
just great.
Don't be hard on yourself.
Thanks man.
Come on.
You don't think I needed a nose job or
anything but,
but uh,
it's just,
it's the way the body moves as a unit as
compared to weightlifting,
which,
which actually fragments muscle groups.
So things along the lines of like bench
presses and curls and absolutely it's in
a sensitivity training is training the
body.
But what about like guys who want to
bulk up,
like I say,
like what meckey shall stone when he
trained evander holyfield to get them up
to heavyweight and he had them do all
this crazy weightlifting stuff.
What do you think about that?
A lot of that's genetics really.
Yeah,
absolutely.
I think,
oh,
that's mexican supplements.
Could be.
It could be very well,
but I think,
I think genetics play a huge role in
that and what's your frame can handle.
There's an optimal size for your frame.
You know what I mean?
My guys I've seen ultimately times guys
would put on more muscle than their body
can handle on their performance
deteriorates.
Sure.
Vanda was a fairly big guy.
Yeah.
And so he can handle it with this frame
plus,
yeah,
you have to look at the genetics of the
athlete too,
but if you take a guy like I'm perfect
example,
maybe like Michael Jordan when Michael
Jordan was playing against the pistons,
right?
Like one of the things that he realized
like,
jesus,
fuck,
I'm getting pushed around and getting my
ass kicked.
I got to bulk up when a guy wants a bulk
up.
There's very few ways to bulk up other
than lifting heavy,
right?
Um,
I would say no,
I would.
First of all,
let me,
let me say this,
I think there's too much of an emphasis
on getting bigger and it might've been
more advisable to train your body.
Maybe there were certain weaknesses in
his hips or his feet or lower back or
obliques that were making him weaker.
I've seen plenty of guys whose whose
bodies are working as a unit,
like with my,
with the type of training that I offer a
that can literally bullied like guys
that are way bigger,
more muscular,
and it all comes down to the efficiency
of the movement.
You know what I mean?
But a guy like,
here's a good example,
a guy like brock lesnar,
you can't get that fucking big and less.
You're throwing some really heavy shit
around.
Yeah.
Or taking mexican style bowl a little
bit.
A little bit of it.
Yeah.
No,
you're absolutely right.
I mean there is,
there is,
but again,
it then again,
haines,
Alaska as who beat him with more or less
the bj penn approach.
Exactly.
Look at cain when cain is thrown a
punch,
you never see like there's no tension.
There's no efficiency.
Yeah.
that's actually a good point because
that's been proven,
that repetitive bouts of absolute
strength training,
which is like your maximum strength
training,
like maximum bench press,
the heavy lifts will deteriorate a
boxer's punching power and accuracy.
Really,
that's been proven by the russians to
erie.
That's fast and it can last for up to
several months still.
Whoa,
whoa,
whoa.
Okay.
So,
so like say if
a guy goes through your conventional
strength program,
a dead lifts bench press,
that can deteriorate his punching power
because it deteriorates the speed.
Strength qualities.
There's different types of strength.
Speed.
Strength is one that emphasizes speed
with.
It would be like maybe like 60 percent
speed,
40 percent strength.
Like if I had to put a ratio on,
the emphasis is primarily on speed.
Every sport is one by a fraction of a
second.
Just About,
you know what I mean?
Like even like a basketball team that's
domInating the entire season,
there's something about every play that
might be 1000th of a second faster than
the other teams that's making them
better.
and then at the end it's cumulative.
You know,
It all adds up and it compounds on top
of each other.
So at the end of the game it's,
it's a mismatch.
Wow.
So even though the pettis fight was
closer than people think it was a
fraction of a second difference between
rafael striking and,
and strike every time,
every time and that compounds and
compounds and how.
that's a funny way to look at it,
but I think you're right.
You know,
when he lAnded that straight left in the
first round crack and you see pedis,
his head snapped back.
I was stunned first of all,
by the speed in which he threw that
shot.
Right.
um,
I'm,
I was very impressed with the speed,
but also that,
you know,
he was able to keep that speed up
through the fourth and fifth rounds.
I mean,
when he nailed them in the first round,
I mean petta said from then on,
he was having a hard time seeing out of
that.
It was getting pretty much fucked from
then on that.
That was super impressive because if you
go back and watch his earlier fights,
like go back and watch them against
Jeremy Stevens were early in his career
where he lost by knockout though the
stevens highlight reel.
Um,
he just was different guy,
different fucking human being.
I mean,
very few guys when you look at their
early ufc career and then look at their
peak performance,
which dos anjos clearly is in his peak.
He just won the title against one of the
best guys ever in that division.
But he's a different human being all
around.
The funny thing is I don't really read
too much on the internet and I that I
had to have this one,
you know,
people sayIng pdds and all this shit.
Uh,
and others I see comments,
there's no strength training program
that can do that.
If he look,
it's been going on for a year,
you know,
we've been building it up.
Uh,
so if you,
if you compare,
like I said,
like his fight with serone,
he's really stiff.
he,
he told me himself by the third round he
was gas.
He goes,
fatIgue.
And so this doesn't like one training
camp,
I mean this has been going on for a year
of really good trading where he and I
are trading like three or four times a
week.
I mean,
you know,
granted that separate the times in
between fights when he,
he's got his downtime.
But I mean,
it,
he's been very consistent with it.
And uh,
you get after about three months of this
as when you see the tendons,
ligaments and everything really start
working as a unit.
And that's when it really,
the power and everything really come
into play.
So,
so safe.
He took a
guy like,
um,
let's just,
what's this?
Pull a guy out of the roster.
Let's go with matt mitrione.
Big heavyweight fast guy moves really
well for a heavyweight.
What would you do with a guy like that?
First thing,
the guy comes to me the first day,
I'm going to do muscle tests on them and
find out what's going on with his body
and find out if there's any types of
weaknesses in his feet.
And the rotational power,
his hips lower back,
especially a big guy,
lower back and lower abdominal cavity.
A flexibility his shoulders.
I can't stress that enough for punching
power.
There is an optimal range of motion
where you produce the greatest amount of
force in all of your joints.
So does that mean that pretty makes is
pretty easy to understand,
right?
Like,
so if my shoulder flection or my
shoulder,
uh,
flexibility is,
is,
is here,
I'm going to lose speed.
If it's,
if it's.
If it's.
Yeah,
exactly.
If it's too short,
you're going to lose speed too long.
You're going to lose speed to islam.
Yeah.
There's two flexible acts really just
too much slack in the muscle.
So.
So how would a guy get to flexible?
Some people are born with that and you
know what I mean,
that's,
that can be a genetic thing or like
swimmers tend to have a lot of
flexibility in the shoulders.
But I mean for that support their
support,
that's okay because they're kind of
dragging that resistance,
that slower resistance.
But for,
for a snap in the muscle,
there's gotta be a little,
just the right amount of tension in
order for that muscle to activate as,
as,
as quickest.
So if it's too long,
imagine like a rubber band.
If it's,
if they're slacking the rubber band,
you can't,
you can't get the snap out of it.
Okay,
I see.
And then is that,
does that make one more prone to
injuries as well?
Absolutely.
Can cause joint instability or
impingement?
All kinds of stuff.
Like I've heard of that with knees.
Absolutely.
And that goes back to the muscular
equilibrium thing I was talking about.
So let's imagine you're doing heavy
front squats every day for like three
times a week,
you know,
80 percent of your one rep max or
whatever,
and you're doing your max is on one
every other week or whatever.
You're developing those quadriceps at
the expense of the hamstrings.
It's not even a running movement,
really just a front squat.
That's just a movement up and down.
That's good for like putting groceries
on a top of a shelf or something like
that.
Okay.
So yeah,
you're going to shorten those quadricep
muscles,
you're gonna,
you're gonna.
Build them and make them bigger and
shorter.
And what happens with the hamstring,
it gets longer and weaker.
So now you've got an imbalance between
the two.
So if someone was going to do front
squats,
they would have to do something to
compensate for that.
Like maybe some sort of a dead lift,
straight leg dead lift or something that
hamstring oriented
again.
Then you're training the hampshire
depends,
you know,
let's put it this way.
It depends on the sport they're going to
do,
but if it's.
If it's a fighter fighter,
I'm not going to have him doing that.
No,
no squats,
no.
No fronts,
but it's not practical for the sport.
One of the most vital elements for
fighting in my opinion and is neglected
his feet.
Like,
like yoU hear mark talk about the Feet.
I talk about the feet all the time.
The strength in the feet and what it
does for the nervous system are Crucial
for athletic performance.
And yet it's like one of the most
neglected areas.
The feet like the neural impulses.
So the sensory and motor nerves are very
highly active in the forefoot.
Okay?
And this can,
this can actually help speed up your
reflexes by type or training the feet on
different planes like balance exercises
and stuff like that will actually speed
up that circuitry between the reaction
between the foot and the spinal cord
through,
uh,
you know,
as you speed up the neural impulses
speed up the neural impulses by
strengthening the feet by,
without like reactive,
uh,
exercises,
balance exercises on like slant boards
and,
and disks and stuff that forced the feet
to stay reactive.
Like is,
for example,
it can actually,
that reaction can kind of relay into the
whole body,
you know,
can can affect the entire body.
Like if you've ever been ice skating or
something and you slip like your hands
are already like,
well,
you know what I mean?
They're already reacting before your
brain even has time to think because
it's processed in the spinal cord.
It doesn't even get processed in the
brain.
Your reaction from your lower limbs can
actually be processed in the lower
portion of your spinal cord and right
back out to your limbs.
So you're like a safety mechanism.
I see.
So you bought as sort of a fail safe
act.
Exactly.
So it's like,
hey,
there's no weight on the feet.
put your fucking hands out dude.
Exactly.
Okay.
Can you put your brain doesn't even know
that's going on too late?
It would.
If it did,
it would.
Exactly.
Okay.
I see.
So by hyper training the feet,
you keep the body in sort of a ready
state for reaction and you know,
it's like manipulating the safety device
to increased sports performance.
The guys at the ana Jim were telling me,
the cub swanson does virtually all of
his workouts on a balance board.
It does either a balance board or
balanced ball,
like everything he does and he's
extremely athletic.
Yes.
Yeah.
So when you're doing these heavy,
heavy lifting it dead ends.
That impulse,
it slows it down and not.
Not to mention you're neglecting the
forefoot.
All these exercises are pretty much done
on the ball on the hill.
I was squatting,
I remember I was taught to press through
the heel,
deadlifting the same thing,
so your,
your,
your training over and over these
movements that are not practical for a
sports movement,
which pretty much every sport is played
on the forefoot.
Yeah,
that's true.
Like you never really in a sport.
You very rarely push off the back of the
foot.
So kind of moving forward when you're
punching the back heels around.
Absolutely.
And so knoWing that it's kind of like,
why are we doing this?
It's improper training.
I mean it really makes sense.
Has been preaching this for years and I,
you know,
and people kind of scoff at it and you
see,
oh no,
I gotta get my heavy back squat and
that's fine,
but maybe this can help you with it,
you know,
start training the feet,
looking at,
looking at what we're talking about here
and the sequence of muscles that you're
going to start firing when you do start
training the feed,
like how is this a better option for
squatting would be a front squat.
And now let's say you take a couple of
45 pound plates and you put them onto
the balls of your feet.
So now you're engaging more of a sports
movie and you're on the balls of your
feet and you're loading up the front
instead of the back,
which is the back squat is technically a
lower back exercise.
It really hits the lumbar and his lower
back.
A lot of front squats going to hit more
quadricep muscles require for jumping,
you know what I mean,
as well as the core and stabilizing the
spine with the abdominals and
everything.
So that's just a thought like maybe you
can do that.
You think like,
start thinking in that process where
you're training from the feet up the
forefoot up,
not just the heels of the forefoot up
and you'll start connecting different
muscles require for sports movements.
Um,
uh,
we were talking before the podcast that
I'm really getting into yoga recently,
last couple of weeks I've been into it,
like in one of the things that is really
shocking to me is how much my feet hurt.
Like all the bouncing on my feet give
out before a lot of other stuff and.
But I do so many things barefoot.
I lift barefoot box all jujitsu,
all that stuff's barefoot.
Right?
But for whatever reason,
like just standing there,
holding your foot up in the air and
stretching out my foot is the one that's
having a hard time dealing with it.
It's kinda.
Yeah.
It's very interesting.
Obviously I've weak feet in some weird
way.
Yeah,
it's a.
It's just.
It never was.
It was never tested before.
The problem with that is when you do
have weakness in the feet,
other things start to compensate.
Like your hips,
your hips start to compensate for the
weaknesses and the feet.
I'd say a lot of guys have flat feet.
They have poor hip abduction and
adduction or tight hamstrings.
Flatfooted guys almost always are a
little hamstring dominant when they're
sprinting.
They're good at like the acceleration
phase,
but the tops the tops be.
is it lacking?
I have flat feet.
Do you?
Do you get tight in the hamstrings?
Not really.
No.
I mean he might be.
The exception to the rule will have very
flexible hamstrings.
Probably the weed weed my hamstrings.
Nah,
I'm just kidding.
No,
I just uh,
grew up doing taekwondo.
I have a lot of.
So for whatever reason I don't,
I don't have tiging back there,
but um,
it,
I definitely a flat fee.
Can we start?
You know,
kelly,
uh,
he wrote that book,
the sub sea.
The crossword guy.
Yeah.
He,
he wrote a book called the supple
leopard.
He,
he doesn't even believe in flat feet.
He said he thinks it's like you said,
it's like you're sort of almost like
learning from people around you to walk
and stand a certain way and it's almost
like a laziness of the posture of your
foot.
To paraphrase him,
I don't know.
I'd have to read it thoroughly and he
thinks that you could retrain someone to
have a hierarchy.
You can't.
ABsolutely real.
Yeah.
Done it really from a guy like me
because I guy like,
like I said,
like the balance balancing type
exercises we have and the foot
strengthening modalities that we use.
Well,
definitely,
man,
I,
I challenge you to try this.
If you try like a calf raise,
like or you can go on like a seated
seated a leg press and don't put any
weight on there,
just do a few of your shoes on.
Okay.
Then take your shoes on and try a few
without your shoes and really
accentuated the movement and the toes to
the tip of the toe and not just to the
pad of the toe,
but to the tip of the toe and see the
difference you feel on your achilles and
your calves.
Okay.
I guarantee you it's going to blow you
away.
A tremendous difference when you just
use that little bit,
that little extra inch of your toes and
you feel it all through the arch of the
foot and you fill it all the way up
through the calf.
it's really police something else.
that's where I always have pain in my
foot.
Yeah.
It's always like a.
I got pain there from skiing.
I get pain there from sometimes hiking
gives me some pain there.
Yeah,
that's fixable.
Interesting.
Okay.
we'll talk about me later in that,
but that a lot of people have issues
with that.
A lot of issues with flat feet.
Um,
do you find that fighters ever have
issues plotting,
like say if you get a guy and like maybe
he's kind of lumbering like we all know
fighters that just,
they just don't move well on their feet.
For example,
roselawn has the flattest feet I've ever
seen an athlete really actually maybe
top three and so,
but surprisingly after this training
camp he had a little bit more strength
than I noticed that less of a drop in
the arches of his foot.
And so that says something about what
we're doing and there were points in the
fight where you can see him bouncing
around on his feet and he looks pretty
quick.
I think even like the 10th or 11th
round,
he was popping around on his feet and
the announcer said,
what is this?
He's bounced around his feet.
It looks quick.
What's he doing now?
Is this some kind of strategy or
whatever?
And uh,
no.
So we made incredible gains in like the
strength of his feet and his cast,
you know,
unfortunately he fights flatfooted.
He comes at you head first and you know,
that's just the style.
But yeah,
he was coming on in the later rounds.
Matina was cracking him early in that
fight.
That was a war to comment of the best
I've ever seen could be,
could very well be.
He did get hurt.
He got hurt one of the rounds and it
slowed him down.
It's hard to not say throws bombs.
Yeah,
he was,
he was really pleaseD with his
conditioning though.
He came out,
he actually came by on the way to the
packet.
I'll fight.
He flew into lax and he stopped by my gm
And he wanted to give me a bonus.
He's like,
I've never felt like that.
Am I in a fight?
Even though I lost like that's the best
I've ever felt.
Like it's awesome.
And I said,
uh,
like,
you know,
I looked as managers and actually like
maybe we should just wait until you win
little accent,
you know,
we'll,
we'll take care of when it.
When on a winning day.
so did you see the,
a urine sample that he gave?
Yeah.
Tasty,
huh?
Yeah.
For folks who don't know,
if you look on providing a coughs,
a instagram page was a photo of his,
his urine sample looked like coca.
Yeah.
It,
we've showed it a bunch of times in this
podcast because it's so fucking crazy.
Yeah.
I've never,
I've heard of that before.
Guys who do like ultra marathons,
my friend cameron hanes,
he's done an ultra marathon.
He said pop like coke,
breaking down muscle and dehydration and
all that and kidneys,
kidney problems,
you know,
who knows.
So to that fight was just that fucking
brutal.
It was insane.
I'll tell you what,
one of the first,
I mean,
first of all,
I have so much respect for both of those
guys.
Like when tesa and rose on honor,
both in my top five,
top 10 fighters with tcs punching power
is freaking ridiculous.
Ridiculous.
I don't remember,
I was in there and I was like,
where am I,
where am I going to sit?
I,
you know,
I was going to be originally going to be
in a corner and then I ended up getting
a seat at ringside and I turned my back
and I'm,
there's a first round,
10 seconds in.
I'm already hearing the punches behind
me.
I'm like,
oh fuck,
I got to run around and get my ass over
there as quick as I can because it's go
another round.
You know,
you're in a good fight and you can hear
those punches landing.
It's just ridiculous like the power that
they generate.
But tisa is a monster.
Puts those,
a monster.
He's the way he keeps coming and coming
and moving and throwing bombs.
But jesus would've fight.
That was.
And the,
and the.
And the cool thing about that was I like
roselawn at,
but the last,
the fights year prior to that,
you know,
he attended,
had a tendency to fade after three or
four rounds and whatever that was,
you know,
focus or conditioning,
I don't know.
But even if his mental focus,
you need to condition that as well.
And so this training camp,
I really dedicated a lot of time to
learning how to push him into the later
rounds and get into bringing it more and
more as a,
as a fiber grass.
Now I'm freddie roach trained sim as
boxing.
Yeah.
And what was like freddy's assessment of
like the difference in his performance
from training with you is what we can
get out of him in the gym.
He looked great.
Everybody was pleased with his barring.
Like this time they said this is the
best he's ever looked in inspiring,
like phenomenal and a renaissance of
kind,
kinda like a robot.
Like whatever he does inspiring,
he's pretty much going to do on the
fight.
And so even in sparring he would come on
a little slow and then pick it up
towards the later rounds of sparring.
And uh,
so I,
I don't think it surprised anybody in
the performance.
Like freddy,
he even said in the beginning,
you know,
it's a 50 slash 50 fight,
like I don't know who's going to win
this.
And uh,
to be honest,
that fight went down exactly how I
thought I would exactly in the dressing
room before we walked out.
I said to the ra,
I pulled the ref aside and I asked him,
you know,
hey,
look what happens if he gets head
butting in like first or second round,
I shit you not.
I asked him that.
Wow.
And I said,
are you going to stop the fight?
He going to have him check it or You
gonna let him keep fighting.
If there's blood,
you know,
I just want to get some things clear
because I kind of had this weird feeling
and uh,
sure enough,
second round and I had a feeling matina
is going to win by decision and I just,
sometimes you just get that weird
feeling,
you know,
there's an aura and a,
you can put all the work and you want.
But you know,
like if it's not your night and it's not
your night and there's just something.
So there now provided
a cough.
What kind of diet does that guy follow?
Because I'd read some crazy shit about
like until he was like,
yeah,
he had,
he'd only eaten raw meat and now he
still eats raw meat.
Really not when he's here.
He has a,
he has a nutritionist here,
but where does he like when he's inside
barrier barrier?
Yeah.
What is it?
They sell it like in his talent.
I guess they sell it in restaurants and
shit.
Like you can go into a restaurant and
just go,
hey,
I'll have a moose heart.
Really?
Yeah.
So they all,
they're all used to eating raw meat.
They're like eskimos.
You know what I mean?
They're really,
they're really ahead of the times.
Well there's something to be said for
those genetics,
I'll tell you that.
Yeah.
Because those are some fucking stout
human beings and that diet has got to be
like incredibly nutrient dense protein.
absolutely.
If you're in as long as you're eating,
you know,
game animals and not predators,
you can pretty much get away with that.
They were eAting bear.
Obviously you couldn't eat it raw,
but eating a caribou or something like
that.
Raw.
you're reading it fine.
I've eaten cariboU before.
Yeah.
No,
I'd be interested to try that.
It's very.
It's reindeer reindeer.
Like santa has reindeer.
There's caribou.
Elk.
Elk is delicious.
I've had a.
I've had raw horse in montreal.
I had a horse tartare.
Yeah.
The ground up this raw horse and served
it with like egg on it and everything.
Like raw egg on it.
It was a manager saying,
yeah,
there's thIs place called joe beef and
montreal.
Is that fresh?
Oh yeah,
yeah,
they do that.
Do they kill the whole,
I don't know.
Fresh.
You'd think that they'd killed the whole
horse and some little would spoil or do
they just like take off limbs at a time
and then like is a good question?
I don't know.
I mean the thing I don't know,
when you buy beef that you buy from the
stores fresh,
they're not freezing your stakes for the
most part.
Some fish is frozen,
but almost all beef you're buying is
been killed fairly recently.
Some of it's dry aged,
but this was,
this horse was,
you know,
I guess I actually,
they killed a horse in America,
but you can't sell it in America in
stores,
but you can kill them in America and
then they export them to,
to Canada.
It's very tricky,
you know,
because people have very strong
attachments towards them as animals,
as pets.
yeah.
But a delicious.
Although weird,
you know,
I don't have any horse horse,
I'm not about to eat a dog provider.
Worse.
Might trip me out.
Yeah.
What's with the cats?
I think I saw a picture of your cats or
something.
You got cats,
girl.
I've always had cats.
I have a 19 year old cat.
I've had her since she was a baby.
Yeah.
is that bad?
no.
So it's just different when you try to.
Seemed like a macho guy.
I'm balanced.
I got to get in touch with the feminine
side.
Touch with my feminine side.
I like little dogs too.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
That's great.
What if I have a little dog in a purse?
I carry it around.
Batman.
Think you're pushing.
Chuck liddell does.
Desi,
chuck odell was a little tiny chihuahua.
He used to take with them everywhere.
Nobody said shit.
exactly.
Iceman
cats,
man.
My daughters love cats.
Yeah,
they're cute.
You got daughters.
Oh,
that's rIght.
Yeah.
You want to soft shoulders,
which was a comedy,
a comedy club in hermosa few years ago.
Oh,
the comedy magic.
Fucking phenomenal guy.
I never saw it before.
I remembered you from the.
Was it the sitcom news radio news radio.
I thought that was pretty funny there.
And then I saw you at the thing.
My buddy got us tickets and I was just
like blown away.
Oh,
thanks for the thing about the daughters
in her hand.
That's true.
Story resonates in my mind.
Really did,
man.
Yeah.
She's lIke,
I want to go to bed.
Mad dogged me.
Does a total true story.
I had to figure out how to react like
this is.
You don't want to freak out about this
because this.
Then she'll know that you can get a
ride.
The other day I made a mistake.
I swore in front of my kid.
He's going to be two on a few weeks and
I said that I was frustrated.
I was tired.
I want to get in the shower and I'm
holding him in one arm and I hit the
dimmer on the light switch.
It doesn't work properly,
so you're always messIng with it to get
it to work.
It's a fucking lights.
It just said,
brad,
I love it and I try to get this thing to
work.
my son goes fucking light.
Okay,
that's great.
Now everything.
No,
it's still going on.
This is like a month and a half ago.
It's still going on.
Fucking uncle rudy.
Fucking garbage car.
You know,
as soon as you give it like a,
a response,
then it's like,
oh,
their eyes light up.
Like you don't have to say anything.
I mean it.
Your eyes just kind of latch on is like,
oh dude,
did you just say that?
So two days ago,
a mommy and me class,
kids are singing twinkle twinkle little
star.
I shit you not fucking lights fucking
lights.
I feel like such a bad dad.
No nonsense.
Don't let those people fuck with your
head.
I'm not cares.
You're a grown adult.
Your fork and knife.
He Said fork and knife and you go,
but don't even lie about it.
Is there anything wrong with saying
those words today?
You and I are together.
Two gRown adults.
So stop.
Everybody stopped.
My wife always says that.
My wife gets mad if I swear on the kids,
you know,
just like stop with the language.
I like pushing bitch.
Fuck you think I make a living and make
a living with this language.
This is called english.
It's called american english.
And occasionally we say,
fuck jesus.
Don't say that's cool.
Kids.
My three year old,
when she was three rather we were
skiing.
I took them skiing from the time they
were really little,
like my kids have been skiing since they
were two.
And um,
uh,
when she was three,
we're packing all the stuff up.
We're getting ready to leave.
We're leaving the trip and we're in the
hotel and uh,
you know,
she's got her little bag is zipped up
and my wife goes,
we forgot to put the helmet in the bag
and the little kid,
she's three,
she goes,
shit,
my
wife looks at me and her eyes,
her eyes light up and I had a fucking
turned my face and run out of the room
because I couldn't stop laughing.
I laughed.
It was funny,
but I didn't want to like,
make sure she finds something that's
funny,
like she loves being funny because I'm a
big laugh.
So when she says funny shit,
I just fucking fall overlap.
So I had to be real careful about that
when she was three,
but it was just something funny,
but she wasn't even doing it to get
attention or anything.
She's just looking her suitcase.
My wife has the helmet.
She realized the helmet's not a
suitcase.
He goes,
shit,
tiny,
tiny first and say shit is fucking like
if we were,
it was just you and I forgot your
senior.
How might you be like,
gosh,
that would be normal.
That was normal to her.
Yeah,
I just,
I don't buy this.
It's something wrong with kids swearing.
It's fucking stupid.
Dumb.
Well there's a certain age when it's
okay.
What's that age 19.
Because then when they start fucking
isn't when they drink.
Like when,
when is it okay to swear like we're
babies with our fucking language and
it's so dumb because it's all just by
television.
It's all like the censorship that we've
imposed upon ourselves with television
is the same censorship that we bring
into the household and you expect from
kids at school.
Like I don't give a fuck about language.
I,
w I appreciate how people treat each
other.
How do you,
how do you talk to me?
Are you nice?
Are you friendly?
If you're friendly and you say,
fuck,
I feel good about talking to you.
You know,
if you're a rude person and you don't
use bad language or you're uncomfortable
or you're,
you're not kind or considerate,
then I,
then I feel gross about talking to you.
But if you're a normal person you say,
fuck what?
What kind of a weirdo cares about that?
But we've imprinted it into our brains
and the same retarded shit.
We pass it down from parent to child and
parent,
the child and the widow.
When does that stop?
When?
When do we stop giving so much power.
These stupid fucking words.
It's dumb.
Just dies.
A parent.
It drives me fucking crazy.
Drives me crazy because I know that it's
not like when people are alone,
when they're comfortable,
when they're together,
when they're out drinking,
when they're at a bar or restaurant,
they swear and it's fun.
It's freeing.
It's liberating.
But you're in an office.
Everybody's dressed like a fucking
penguin.
Some weird stupid outfits.
You know?
It's,
it's dumb.
It doesn't make any sense.
It doesn't mean it's a weird habit that
we're stuck in that people think is
like,
oh,
you've got a lot of class with your
language.
Fuck you.
Shut up.
This is stupid.
So dumb way to express yourself.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
Yeah.
I don't really think that much about.
It drives me nuts.
It drives me nuts,
man.
Because I've had people come on my
podcast and I'm like the podcast,
like someone will say it was a great
podcast except for rogan's language and
my language like he.
He asked great questions.
If you get past the language,
it was a great conversation.
If you say it in like a foreign
language.
Yeah,
right.
Some the word french,
french word for fuck.
It's just silliness.
It's,
it's infant tile.
It's like it's self imposed infantile
behavior and one year the adult,
when you're a grown person,
you're a fully grown adult.
You t,
you pay your own bills,
you feed yourself the whole deal.
You decide when you go to bed,
like the idea that you were imposing
this stupid language restriction.
The only language I care about is
language that expresses like human
interaction.
Yeah.
I.
I care about derogatory language.
I care about offensive,
evil language,
racist language.
That kind of stuff bugs me,
but just saying fuck the.
The type of people that do that.
The good thing about that is if you find
someone who cares about that,
you know you're,
you're around an idiot.
Just avoid that dummy.
I got a little excited,
I got a little carried away with that.
That thought we got off track.
That's why this podcast is.
We should change the name of it too.
Off track.
What do you see in the store on sunset?
Pinches tacos.
You know what that means?
No fucking tacos.
Really?
Yeah.
Good,
good,
good.
I hope somebody protests.
I hope some social justice warriors have
it closed down because it's racist or
something.
I hope white people on it.
I don't know.
Fun.
Google.
Yeah.
I don't know man.
I just think we're.
We're very childish when it comes to
language.
That's not the point.
This podcast,
the point is pocket.
I have just so many questions for you.
I'm sure I'll get back to this because
it's really fascinating.
What do you think when you watch those
countdown shows and you see like guys do
with the battle ropes and there's like a
bunch of very specific things that you
see.
You see like guys pushing sleds,
that's a big one.
The weight sled pushing that fucking
sled.
Um,
you see like all these different ways of
training.
What is like the biggest mistakes that
you see
or what you feel are based mistakes?
Obviously they exercise modalities like,
I don't know how pushing a sled is even
relative to like mma.
I mean if we're talking about mma guys
up against the cage,
what if you get pushing them?
Are you holding him?
Well,
if you're trying to push the guy up
against the cage,
say if you get,
you get in a collar tie,
right,
and you want to push the guy up against
the cage,
you want to work your entire.
You want to work needs to the body that
seems
that would be more about leverage of the
leg,
the leg,
the placement of the leg,
and the leverage and the power of the
foot,
which I take it,
which we go back to.
The strength and the feet.
The feet of the strength of the foot can
not be understated.
They've done studies like on olympic
weight lifters that show that the force,
uh,
excuse me,
the foot actually produces the greatest
amount of force and the olympic weight
lifts.
So real.
Yeah,
it's the actual foot.
If you look at the leverage of the joint
there,
it's just such a short lever.
So the pushing off the ground for clean.
Exactly.
That produces more forced than,
than,
than the quadricep.
Even even the hip.
That's amazing.
Yeah.
So,
um,
are you opposed to cleans and presses
and things along that?
I'll have my guys do them and I'm not
going to say there are terrible.
I think if you start going too heavy
then yeah,
you're overloading your spine and you're
doing a disservice to the rest of your
body.
But like what's too heavy?
I think something that you can't do
quickly and incorporate the stretch,
the stretch shortening cycle.
Like I said,
plyometrics in my opinion are the king
for strength,
for strengthening the body.
So box jumps,
those type of exercises.
Were you doing the descending exact
press and catching it?
Anything where the muscles being put on
stretch and then firing back at a,
at a faster rate.
So you can even do that manually.
Like to exercise for the hips.
You can do that with a hand throwing the
leg down and work it in different
angles.
So imagine strengthening every muscle in
your body plan metrically.
Then you've got like a fast twitch
animal.
It's highly trained.
Can you take a guy who's slow and you
can make them fast solutely there's
through the stretch shortening cycle
again,
which is the neural neural impulses,
uh,
that go through the muscle and the
stretch shortening cycle actually,
like,
let me give you an example of this.
So imagine you go to the doctor and
you're sitting in the doctor's chair and
he comes up and he hits you in the knee,
you know,
he does the patellar tests to kick test.
That's a stretch shortening cycle.
And what,
what he's doing,
he's testing for any kind of
abnormalities like that might be in your
spine or,
or might show up in your nervous system.
It could be some other kind of disease
or whatever.
But what it's doing is it's sending a
neural impulse through the,
through the tendon.
Okay.
All the way up through the,
through the muscle,
into the spine,
and then inhibits the hamstring so it
switches the hamstring off.
Okay.
And that's why your leg jerks without
you even having to try to do anything
right there.
So like,
you know,
you just sit there,
you're not making a kick.
So that's what's going on.
Exactly.
So exactly.
So if you,
if you hit the hand,
if he hit the right in the patellar
tendon,
your leg kicks,
it's actually switching off your
hamstring simultaneously at the same
time.
It's activating the quadricep so you get
a greater,
you get a greater contraction now,
the quadricep without even trying.
That's where the efficiency that you've
been talking about comes in.
So by training the stretch shortening
cycle,
you can,
you can duplicate that throughout the
entire body as long as you're training
every muscle like that.
So do you have like a standard mma
fighter protocol that you follow or does
it vary depending upon what the athlete
brings to you in the first place?
Do or do you try to get them to a place
and then work from there?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Like I said,
we start with muscle testing to
determine weaknesses like the feet and
the hips.
What,
how do you do this muscle?
Manual testing per,
you know,
for example,
all hold your toes and I'll have you try
to push me back and I'll feel like it's
like a manual muscle test like something
a chiropractor might do or our physical
therapists and looking for weaknesses
and then the hips.
You can test the abduction and
adduction.
You can turn the person over and you can
test the rotation of their hip here
which is.
And all these things play into the
mechanics of sporting movement,
so the rotational muscles of the hip.
If you've got,
let's say you're right handed and you've
got weak rotational muscles in the eye
and the left and your left leg,
that's going to affect your left hook,
right?
Same with the right hand,
straight,
right hand.
If you got a weak gluten ham
contraction,
you're going to have a a weakness in
your straight right hand if you're
punching from the hip,
I mean assuming you're punching with
good mechanics,
right?
And so all these factors play into where
we want to get them.
So first you would remediate the weakest
link first.
So 99 times out of 100,
it's the feet.
And the hips with the guys and then like
usually the lower back and the
shoulders.
So you get like,
watch the video that I remember gary I
think is explaining it when he trained
bj penn,
like you know,
first we fixed his feet and then his
hips and it's the same strategy for
remediating weakness.
Like you want to,
you want to strengthen all these weak
links first to get the kinetic chain
working,
you know all the way through.
So.
So if you get a guy and say the guy has
lower back issues is really common with
bj players,
brazilian jujitsu guys that work,
the guard.
Especially a lot of them have lower
eddie bravo.
Right.
He's just serious lower back problems.
What would you do
that.
First of all I'd probably want to turn
them over and fill with his spine.
Feels like and feel for,
for what the vertebraes lined up like
and his hips.
And then I.
And then I do
visual assessment of his lower back and
tests.
He's extremely flexible guy,
right?
In some ways.
Tight hamstrings.
So tight hamstrings.
Yeah.
He's,
he's a guy that's fucked up.
I can probably fix them up.
No problem.
You think so?
Absolutely.
Guaranteed.
Eddie bravo.
Yeah.
Where are you?
Gonna?
Call nick.
Let's go.
Eddie.
I think I trained with him a long time
ago,
man.
He used to wear the head gear and like a
wetsuit thing on.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
This was probably like 15 years ago when
he had really long hair.
He used to tuck in a wetsuit.
Yeah,
it was pretty cool guy.
he's awesome.
He's a character,
but his,
uh,
his flexibility's very unusual.
His leg dexter is very unusual in the
hips.
His ability to,
you know,
like when you called jail break,
like say if you have them inside control
him,
he can pick his foot up without even
grabbing with his hand.
Bring it across like that.
Yeah.
Get a deep butterfly hook and in turn
and face you.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
It's an amazing dexterity that he has
now.
I guarantee I can fix it.
I fixed nfl player's backs and those
guys have the worst backs.
So savvy guy get a guy who's got some
bulging disks,
a bunch of shit going on.
That's kind of sketchy,
like I don't want to be sued for
anything,
you know what I mean,
and like,
but there are some tricks like traction
stretches,
you can do like some manual therapy
stuff that I've learned from a very
like,
uh,
well,
like,
well respected,
um,
neurologist and physiologists,
crazy russian guy scientists and uh,
so we've implemented a lot of that stuff
to,
for the health of the spine.
And uh,
yeah,
there's some stuff you do to relieve the
pressure
there because back and neck,
those are really common with grapplers.
So I know so many wrestlers who have
fused disks,
like tito ortiz,
I think he's got three fused.
He's got one in his neck fuse and I
think he's got to and it's back one of
his lumbar and maybe one thoracic or
something like that.
Yeah,
I had to have the steroid injections in
my neck.
Dji herniated discs,
five gen,
pretty aggro back then.
And so I had the cortisone.
Yeah,
exactly.
What are they,
the,
they put you to sleep for that?
Is that the cortisone?
Yeah,
I dunno.
they put me under for it,
man.
And it was,
it was,
it was.
I couldn't sleep for three weeks before
I had the shots.
I mean I was up in so much pain.
My atrophied,
it looked like a wet noodle.
Yeah.
So you had a pretty good one.
What happened to your neck?
Uh,
I got thrown into a wall and jujitsu and
I just crunched,
but I think it was more like years and
years of building up,
you know,
and then they found there's like a bone
spur in there that like irritates the
nerve and so they have to go in there
and take the bone spur out.
But I probably will one day,
but not yet.
I have so many friends that have atrophy
issues with the neck where their arm
shrinks.
Yeah.
Bas rutten.
He had his neck fused.
He,
he actually had some significant neck
problems for years.
And then he was on thinkers on sons of
anarchy,
one of those shows where he was doing a
stunt and they throw them on his head
and just cried,
man.
Yeah.
And his arm just went foreign and then
it shrunk up.
Boy calls it baby arm.
He's got one arm,
it's still to this day,
hasn't romoland.
Yeah,
he had several operations.
He has disc fused in his neck.
He uh,
he had um,
the,
the nerve opening.
They go in there and they sort of carve
it out,
clear,
clear the opening to relieve the
pressure on the nerve and even that,
like he probably did it all too late in
his arm,
had been atrophied for so many years
that it just,
uh,
it's a long process to rebuild the
neuromag I know about that.
There's out for you.
Yeah,
well I was in a car accident till where
I was actually rear ended.
That guy was going about 100 miles an
hour.
Geez.
Yeah.
So shattered my pelvis,
broke my hip.
I've got a plate in there now.
Like a steel plate.
Whoa.
Yeah.
And so I was in a wheelchair for like
six months,
but the nerve,
like apart from all the muscular,
you know,
rebuilding the muscular,
the muscles and all that,
the nerve pain from the recovery was the
worst.
I mean I still have like right now I can
fill it up my foot.
This is like 10 or 12 years ago and I
just felt like animals were eating my
toes off man.
I remember waking up one night like
screaming in pain,
like fuck did my foot as something
eating my foot and I looked down there
and the toes are kind of moving on their
own and that was the nerve waking back
up.
Wow.
And it was excruciating.
I mean even like I said,
even to this day I still feel it,
you know,
get some issues in my toes with that.
But that's why a lot of guys didn't have
back pains and women as well.
Obviously they,
they get really hooked on pain pills.
It's like it gets to a point where I got
hooked on them,
man.
I'm not gonna lie to the point where I
would take my pain pills and then I
would take a laxative because this shit
makes you constipated.
So like I was taking a lot of those
things,
like on a daily basis,
you're doing that for four or five
months,
man.
You're going to get hooked.
How'd you get off a?
My will.
I think that was it.
Yeah.
I'm weird like that,
like I don't get addicted to things,
but like when I go too deep,
if I feel like something bad's gonna
happen to me,
like emotionally or I can snap out of
it,
but yeah,
that's self preservation man.
I got when I used to think about taking
them,
I get that taste like under my tongue,
like it candy,
you know what I mean?
Yeah.
I mean it was brendan schaub said the
same thing.
A sharp didn't even realize he was
hooked on him.
He was taking them every day for like
three or four months and then his
friends apparently intervened and said,
hey dude,
you're fucking whacked out all day.
You got to get off.
These pills were were the pills?
They went to his house,
cleaned out his bathroom cabinet and
said,
enough,
do we just did that with my buddy like
two weeks ago?
He had a dirt bike accident.
His fucking bone.
Can I tell you a quick story?
Okay.
You know what those things are.
Have you ever seen a razor scooter with
a cage around on either built to crash?
Oh no.
Fuck no.
I think I'm looking at a different
thing.
It's kinda like an atv but a little
bigger and two guys came like a dune
buggy,
like a miniature dune buggy with a cage
around it and guys go up hills.
Like you can see all these fucking guys
in the south.
Love them and yeah.
So you know where I'm going with this
fucking gnarly.
So this guy killing my buddies,
buy a brand new and they're like,
come on out.
It'll be a great weekend,
man.
Let's go fucking writing this weekend.
Whatever.
Long story short these guys ended up in
the hospital,
they flipped the thing and one guy
busted his scalpel open.
He's got a whole like size of a golf
ball,
broke his arm.
My other buddy broke his arm and like
four places just had surgery.
So our third friend who went with him,
he called me.
He's like,
man,
these guys have been in an accident.
The next day he sent someone,
sends me a text of him laying down with
a bone popping out of his fucking go
indian burial ground.
Dude,
what the fuck is this shit?
You know what I mean,
like all these kids got made.
Yeah,
it's a great weekend guys.
Thanks.
But one of them got really hooked on
the,
on the pain meds and he went from being
a super active guy too,
just staying home all day,
being hooked on pain meds and we were
like really worried about him.
Like he was calling us like crying like
dude,
I'm going to do something bad.
I'm going to on.
And we got this thing called bro chat on
facebook.
A bunch.
A group of our old buddies got together
and we started a group chat like
probably like two months ago.
I everyone who has practically been
kicked off facebook for it for one
reason or not sending pictures,
you can imagine the shit.
But man,
we all got together on umbrella chat and
we saved his life to broach.
That saves.
It,
saves it.
It pisses off wives because I swear to
god,
every one of us is on there until like
1130 at night laughing our ass off.
All the girls are putting the babies to
sleep the fucking flow,
man.
You can get a girlfriend or something.
A honey.
I'll give you a blow job if you get off
the phone.
I fucking wow.
Hilarious.
Some bros before blowjobs like,
yes,
not me.
I'm the first one off.
I just go in there to save you,
man.
That's it.
I've had several friends that have had
like serious pill issues.
Uh,
it's,
it's weird how prevalent they are and
how easy it is to get them.
Yeah.
You know,
I had my nose fixed.
I had a deviated septum so they cleared
it all out,
cut the turbinates out.
Stretched open though the openings,
like put splints in there and shit,
and actually kind of widened the
physical look of my nose and kind of
changed a little bit because it was like
a little more sucked in like nasal
breathing.
Anyway.
Point is,
it wasn't fucking painful.
Really mean.
It was when it was over,
it was over and I need that.
I have a deviated septum is one of the
best things I've ever done.
I didn't do it till I was like,
I think it was 39 or something like
that,
but once I did it was like,
yeah,
I get this big.
Rafael just had that done.
Did he?
Yeah.
He because of,
I don't know if that had been going on
for a long time.
Like he had it so bad he couldn't even
breathe that junior.
Joe santos did as well.
Huh?
Interesting.
Well it's just fighting,
you know?
Yeah.
I had my nose broken for the first time
when I was five.
I fell down a flight of stairs and it
was always kind of crooked,
like the bones kind of weird.
And it was inside.
It was always fucked up.
But then years of just getting smashed
in the face,
he just gets awful.
It's a point like,
you remember vandelay would vandelays
knows you slipped from flat to his face.
Yeah,
just smushed down.
No cartilage at all.
Everything just mushed.
And every bumper door,
farc the farc.
Right.
Um,
he,
uh,
he had his fixed and he went deep the
other way.
You've got like an extra big nose so he
could breathe better.
Like they constructed,
it knows out of his rib.
Let's see.
Yeah,
it looks really.
How dare you.
I dare you.
I see you're being sarcastic.
Well,
I mean for practical purposes,
you want to be a fighter,
really smarter,
which shows a lack of vanity.
It does.
And he didn't try to look at all.
He cut out all the scar tissue in his
neck,
that eyebrows,
you know,
because he was getting that.
There's another thing that fighters get,
is that sort of relaxed,
it impedes vision.
Absolutely.
In some guys have it so bad that you can
see there are lids.
Yeah.
Because I guess it's from punishment
from getting hit repetitive scar tissue,
scar tissue and also like the relaxation
of the muscle.
That new nurse probably.
Yeah.
So it starts to fall over the eye and it
actually gets in the way.
It's vandelay,
but that's vandelay before he got fucked
up.
That's vandelay.
That's when he was young.
Probably like 2003.
That's uh,
that's the early days of annually.
That's vandelay when he was the pride
channel and labeled knows number one.
Well,
you got to see vandelay in like,
that's what he looks like now.
I mean his eyes are different,
but that's not what it looked like right
after the surgery.
Like that's his face with cat woman
Right.
He came onto the scales,
uh,
at the,
at the ufc and he was cornering.
Somebody stepped up to the cage.
Like that's him.
You see where the pink tape on his
gloves.
That's him and his,
his best.
That's before his nose was fucked up.
That's when,
that's probably him in 2001 or something
like that.
I mean that was a,
that was vandelay in his prime.
I want to say that looks like it was
right before rampage jackson or
something like that.
Two thousand one,
2002.
His nose was fine.
And then if you see like vandelay versus
chocolate dell,
I have a poster on my wall in my gym at
home,
have a vandelay versus chocolate.
Dell and vandelays knows is just
smashed.
It's just like flattened to his face.
And that was a,
like that one where his arms are up in
the air.
Jamie,
see that picture up there,
like click on that.
Go go large on that.
You could see in that one.
I think that's,
that's it seems like after the
[inaudible] fight that it's tough to
tell there.
But for a lot of tHe fights,
like his nose was just useless.
He couldn't breathe out of it.
So he went the other way and he got this
fucking crazy nose job where they gave
them a bigger nose so he could breathe
out of it.
Yeah.
so you see like knows number three,
like that image right there.
Yeah.
Look,
look how much bigger is this?
But that's smart.
It's like he did that so he could
breathe out of it better.
There's a lot bigger,
like the bone or the cartilage,
you could see it like goes lower.
Like when you're talking to them it went
lower to like sort of like he has a big
accentuated cartlidge there.
That guy has taken some fucking
punishment.
You want to talk about a warrior for
christ.
I mean that guy has been in fucking wars
like down there.
You see all those images.
Look at that one where he's got the
white tank top right there,
to the right of that,
right below.
That it right there.
That's where you could see a tough now,
not even at his worst.
It's not even at its worst.
At its worst was right before we got the
operation.
I think it was just completely that
after the operation right there.
I think that might be photoshop him.
He was jimmy duranti for halloween,
but that's a dated right there.
Right there.
That black one in the black shirt.
Oh man.
Yeah.
His nose pretty smashed there,
but that might be after a fight.
Yeah,
I mean that's not even at the worst.
I mean he's.
That guy has taken some fucking insane
damage in his career and we've watched
his face alter because of that damage.
Out of all the fighters in the ufc and
in pride and in mma in general.
His face as altered the most because of
punishment.
[inaudible] probably second close.
Yeah,
but mandalay's more than anybody because
he's the one that got it fixed.
He's the only.
Only one of those guys that got it
fixed.
Nick diaz had some stuff done to his
eyebrows
till you said he had so much scar tissue
that had.
He actually had his bone shaved down to
because it's the edges of his bones.
I'll cut you.
A couple of guys.
I trained in the Philippines like that.
They're pretty susceptible to cut.
You want to see some boxers,
man.
He's like,
did you see the genetic,
lufkin and chocolate?
Yeah,
totally.
Dude,
you want to go see getting a glove can
this weekend at the forum?
They got me.
I said,
no,
I want to go see chocolate.
Tito.
Tito is a bad dude.
He is.
One of my guys fought him in Japan about
maybe six months ago and I did a hell of
a lot better than the other guy.
Kind of stopped short.
we,
I don't think we would want to.
We probably wouldn't have won that fight
either way.
You know,
chocolate tito's amazing.
But uh,
these lighter weight division is 1:12
division and the [inaudible] eight
division right now are like exciting
divisions and I'm,
I'm just stoked that they got some
coverage in the us,
like on hbo shows.
Like I mean it's,
it's really a stacked.
If you really look into it.
THe lighter weight man,
it's really stacked and there's a lot of
action,
a lot of knockouts,
as long as they have short referees,
like a jockey that'd be sick.
He didn't like.
If you have a 108 pound fighter,
you got to have a little tiny reference.
Right.
You know,
and maybe slower the ropes a little bit
too.
Like you did a good move.
I really thought about that.
The last fight you see better,
but I got a guy who I trained in the
Philippines,
daunting yet says noni,
and yet he's the longest reigning
filipino champion of all time and this
guy is such an exciting fighter.
He moved,
his nickname is aha.
Switch in the gulag means snake.
Oh.
So he moves like a snake in the ring.
Like his head movement.
He,
his speed and timing are just on another
level,
but he's got one punch knockout power
for 100,
eight pound fighter.
It's ridiculous.
The power of this sky generates whatever
happened in novato,
dinair.
He's a.
I'm actually gonna be seeing him in a
few weeks in the Philippines.
He's a,
I worked with him for one flight and I
actually ended up having to leave like
maybe like three or four weeks before
the fight,
you know,
some things,
whatever.
But um,
he kinda,
I think my personal opinion,
I liked the guy as a person.
He's a fucking great guy.
Did like a really cool person.
Seems very cool.
He really is.
But I think what he got that fighter the
year thing I maybe went to head a little
bit and then,
you know,
I'm sure you're probably hearing this.
Oh sorry did.
But I think it went to his head a little
bit and maybe the ego got in the way and
he kind of stopped listening to the
coaches and it was evident in the
walters fight,
you know,
he even said like,
I stopped listening to my dad,
I should have been listening to my dad
on the corner and look what happened.
You know,
and I said this in the training camp,
some people in his entourage.
I said,
you know what?
He's not listening to me.
He's not,
he's coaching his dad like had to train
him like,
you know,
this guy could potentially be one of the
best boxers we've ever seen.
If he just listened and I was at this
rate,
something's going to happen.
He's going,
they're going to get knocked out or he's
going to get hurt and then everybody's
going to snap it and they're going to
say,
hey,
we should have fucking done this or we
should've done that.
You know what I mean?
And now he's doing it.
He's,
he's back and he's dedicated
to late.
How old is he now?
He's 30.
I think he's 31,
but I have a really lightweight.
He's fighting a 1:22
I think now.
Right?
Is that right?
I think so killed.
Did he like the guys in his division?
He'll destroy them.
Yeah,
he started to.
It just seems like that at that age,
at the lower weight classes,
age is like if he was 32 years old and
he was fighting and heavyweight,
I was like,
oh,
he's going to keep going.
Yeah,
I mean those.
It seems like heavyweights mature later.
Do you agree with that?
Uh,
you know,
I don't know to be honest.
Maybe I was wondering about that.
Actually.
One of the things I wanted to ask you
about is it,
is it because like a guy like vladimir
klitschko,
so just this massive person,
I always wondered like,
does it take longer to develop
efficiency of movement and the ability
to move your body better to
understanding your body if you have more
of it to,
to learn.
If you're,
say if you're dealing with a much larger
frame,
much more body mass.
Yeah.
So is it more gravity?
You're dealing with more gravity,
you're dealing with the influence of
that gravity.
It slows you down.
You're obviously slower in a lighter way
person.
Is it more difficult to develop mastery
of skill?
Yeah,
I think that's a good question,
joel.
I think there is some,
maybe some truth to that.
Like the length of the limb requires the
leverage that you get on the muscles.
It's going to be a lot greater.
Like the torque you need to generate out
of the smaller muscles to control the
larger lamb.
Of course,
that's gonna play a big role,
so the length of the limb can determine
how much,
how much force you can produce also,
so it'll play a role on the mechanics.
But I think uh,
yeah,
I think uh,
I think it is maybe a little bit harder
for some of those big guys just strictly
like on the,
on the,
I don't know,
maybe it's the relative strength,
you know,
I don't know.
I really can't answer that.
I always felt like they're just,
they're dealing with more gravity.
Like it seemed to me that like lighter
weight guys,
especially back in the kickboxing days,
I had noticed that the lighter weight
guys seem to learn quicker.
They seem to pick up the skills quicker.
There are obviously always faster
be a higher degree of relative strength
to like your strength to bodyweight
ratio.
So,
or
could have something to do with it
because the other thing is you never see
a guy at heavyweight that can move like
mighty mouse,
right?
Like they just don't exist now.
I mean,
you look at,
if you watch mighty mouse,
demetrius johnson,
the ufc flyweight champion,
the guy who my opinion is best pound for
pound fighter in the world.
I think when it comes to taking the
least amount of punishment,
the ability to make great fighters look
average,
the ability to impose his skillset and
never runs out of gas and is always
technically he's always in the best
position.
He's always doing the right thing.
Like he's really,
really well trained.
I don't,
I've never seen a fucking heavyweight
even remotely move like that.
Like the best heavyweight in the world
is cain velasquez obviously,
and he's to beat purdue.
It's
tough fight.
Very tough fIght because his big
strength is taking guys down,
you know,
take down.
You're in a world of shit.
Yeah.
That guy is no joke off his back.
His fucking guard is head and shoulders
above anybody that cane has ever faced
without a doubt.
Absolutely.
I don't know who he brought in to train
with it,
but they're not good enough.
No.
Who the fuck are you going to bring it?
Unless you bring it in,
you'd have to bring in a vinny
magallanes,
someone who is a go really and only
specifically work the ground aspect of
it because vinny can't hang with volume
on the feet.
Right.
BecAuse hafez,
al has done an amazing job of of taking
those guys and turning them into
kickboxers.
I mean he's.
He's just fucking.
He's a master.
Hockfield codero.
One of the original guys for shoot box,
the original brazilian berzerker camp at
occurred t but Brazil are fucking
animals,
man.
They were just the most feared camp ever
at the time,
you know,
but he's so smart and so skIllful at
taking those like grapplers and turning
them into elite strikers.
You look at dosantos,
you look at verdugo for doom out
kickbox,
travis fucking brown and chris travis
brown's and animal,
you know,
you figure if we're doing is going to be
travis browne was going to take them
down,
submit them,
right?
No,
he kicked his ass standing.
I mean that was crazy.
Watch him double jab travis brown,
you know,
being that was crazy to watch.
When you go back to his fight with
junior dos santos or even before that,
his fights and pride and you see the
rudimentary striking he had back then
and then you look at his abilities now.
Pretty god damn impressive.
Cornell has a great striking coach and a
humble guy too.
Really,
really nice.
He's a great guy.
I love that dude.
But if you.
You look at the best fighters in the
world,
the two best guys,
the two best guys in the heavyweight
division currently the best of all time.
I kinda gotta go with fader.
I just think fade or.
Yeah,
I think he's the best of all time in the
heavyweight division.
I just don't,
I mean maybe became with a beat him.
I would've loved to seen them about the
natural.
Um,
randy is really a light heavyweight and
heavyweight.
He was undersized.
I mean he was a great,
great fighter,
but I think honestly,
pound for pound,
I just don't.
I mean fado easily could have been two.
Oh,
five,
two by the way.
No,
he waSn't a,
it wasn't a like when you see a guy like
that's carrying around all that extra
fat,
what do you think about that?
Like cain carrIes around extra.
Yeah.
Uh,
I think as long,
you know,
again,
that's,
that's uh,
doesn't matter,
obviously not,
but it does it mean,
look,
he's obviously a monster,
but would it be better if he had very
little muslin?
No,
not necessarily.
because that goes back to what we're
saying about the rate of force
development and how,
if you look how explosive fader is
despite not being looking like hercules.
Right,
right.
That goes back to what we're talking
about,
the rate of forced development and how
the nervous system,
you know,
plays the greatest role In how much
force you produce,
so how explosive you are.
He's an interesting case too,
in that he started off his career early
on.
He was into heavy kettle bells,
did a lot of lifting,
and he was a thicker,
bigger guy.
And then as time went on,
he,
he talked about how he didn't lift
weights anymore and he just relied on
skill training.
He just would wrestle.
And sambo and kickboxing and all that
stuff.
I don't remember you asking.
I think I heard a show you're asking,
you know,
you're wondering what the russian guys
are doing.
Like these wrestling guys.
I'm like,
what are they doing for their
conditioning?
The truth is not much.
They're not doing weights.
a lot of them,
they're just wrestling.
I know this because a,
I don't know if you know,
I train aaron peko.
Are you familiar with their agenda?
Yeah.
So he's one of my guys too.
Um,
so I trained him and he goes out there
for months at a time and changes with
the russians and the ukrainian national
teams and he says,
no,
they're just wrestle.
That's it.
No strength and conditioning.
Not really.
Wow.
What do you think?
I'm gonna do some running and stuff like
that.
I think uh,
well they've got great wrestlers.
So I would almost rather have that than
have a detrimental thing.
And they're like heavy weight lifting or
something like that.
So you'd have.
Yeah.
I would rather have them just focusing
all their energy on their skill and
doing some cardiovascular training.
Have you ever seen the workouts that
cain velasquez don't know how you want
to throw up?
Sure.
Okay.
Yeah.
I don't mean a good way to say it out.
Cain velasquez has some weight lifting
routines that he has some guy working
out with them.
I showed it to steve maxwell.
Steve maxwell got angry.
Really?
Yeah.
Let's check it out.
It's like got a video.
Yeah.
Show show I'm kettle bell swings.
He's doing like really heavy kettle bell
swings.
I'm not lying.
Maxwell got angry.
You really get angry.
Steve maxwell the kettlebell and master,
rIght?
Like I been do it for a long time now,
but he's not just kettlebell master.
He says like an overall fitness guru.
He understands the human body.
He's like a real student of all sorts of
different modalities.
Like watch this,
watch this.
He's got this giant kettle bell.
Look at this.
He's like,
kinda.
It's almost like he's doing like tend is
look at.
It's not really a swing because he's
kind of pulling it up more like a,
like almost like a dead lift.
yeah,
I mean it's got got to make them
stronger,
but the lower back thing he's doing is
not swing like he's popping it up.
Right.
Whereas every other kettle bell swing,
you'll see.
I just fell off.
I don't.
I have no idea how it's gonna help in
the new ufc,
ms.to
make them stronger.
I guess it's wrong or it's going to make
them stronger at doing kettlebell.
I bet about it lay some pipe like a
motherfucker,
see if he can find a correct technique.
Double-handed kettlebell swing online,
like maybe maxwell has a video or
someone or mike mauler is very good at
that and he.
He's a.
He's a great instructor as far as like
proper fundamentals,
but there's a bunch of those that he
has.
Like one of them is leg extensions.
I'll show you the cain velasquez leg
extension one.
You'll throw up at that one too because
he's doing like 300 pounds.
Leg extensions needs to happen.
Crazy.
Both shoulders blown out,
shoulders repaired.
See this guy,
this guy's using three pounds.
It's might not be the best guy to look
at it,
but this is how it's supposed to look.
Right.
He's popping his hips forward and the
arm swings.
That's why it's called the kettlebell
swing phase two,
like 10,
15 years ago.
You were early adopter.
Yeah.
I love them.
My favorite thing to work out with,
you know what I like,
uh,
for an athlete I wouldn't have them do.
Um,
to be honest.
Yeah.
But for guys like you and me as we're
getting older and I'm going to be 42,
like I need to keep the muscle along a
little bit.
So yeah,
for general fitness,
I don't think there's anything wrong.
Performance wise.
Like I said,
the movement pattern there.
You're sitting back on your heels,
you're training.
Excuse me.
You're sitting back on your heels,
you're training yourself to,
to.
I felt that affect me.
Like I've been in that position where
I've been training with guys and I'm
like,
fuck,
why is this guy taking me down?
I'm way better than this dude,
but he's beating me to the punch every
time because I was sitting back on my
heels.
I was in that kettlebell posture when
I'm standing there,
I'm standing there with my back then and
my heels are flat on the ground.
Why couldn't I get off my toes?
Because I've trained my body to sit back
on the heels.
That's interesting.
So you,
your Body.
I automatIcally went into that posture.
Exactly.
So you can retrain that though.
That's the good thing.
It takes some time,
but he trained the forefoot.
So you're quick around.
How many times have you heard it in
sports?
Man,
these guys are on their toes now.
They really looked great in there.
You know?
What do you think about like turkish
getups from grappling?
I'm a big fan of those.
I just,
I don't know how that plays into
grappling.
Just being able to lift heavy weight off
of you,
get up off your back,
have that ct scan like,
I don't know.
I think at a high proof,
really proficient level of jujitsu,
you're not going to lift anything off.
You're going to move around it.
You know what I mean?
like maybe the best shoulder stability,
maybe.
Does it help them that way?
It's only going to help wherever,
you know what I don't know.
This problem with my back and this guy
gave me advice.
This guy was a strength and conditioning
coach to do a lot of windmills.
He was like windmills,
you know,
kettlebell wind like dropping down like
that and really good for stabilizing the
spine,
stabilized in the shoulder joint and you
know that.
Anything that is in the thoracic area,
in the cervical area as well?
Yeah.
What do you think about neck exercises?
I love him.
Do you think on like the neck bridging?
I think that the desks are so small and
the nac,
that man I used to do like 45 pound
plates on my chest and do the neck
bridge is on the back of my head.
Real.
It's just stupid.
I've got this exercising machine straps
on your head.
I mean you look like a retard,
like isn't that a good way machine?
Is that or is it a different thing?
Yeah.
Maybe I have a picture or something.
I don't know if I have a picture on my
instagram or not,
but no,
it's.
What's it called?
Do you call it halo?
Oh,
I've seen that.
Have you got a strap under the chin and
a velcro strap on the top and you pump
it up with air and it's like this big
metal thing.
I mean you look,
you look ridiculous wearing it and what
do you do?
And you can exercise in all ranges of
motion.
It has like an elastic band that you'll
attach to a wall so you can put just a
little bit of tension,
tension on it to see if we can find
that.
Jeremy.
If not,
I have a video on my phone.
I don't know if he can show that on
there but probably will.
But it's pretty cool.
If you could email it to him,
he could show it.
Don't give out no battery or though.
No,
you don't have a battery charger.
So I'm sure that's an iphone.
Yeah.
It's.
Or this thing.
Is this it right here?
A similar to that halo?
No,
this one is a little more hardcore than
When I got this.
about like seven or 800 bucks.
Does it have a um,
so it has a rubber band?
yeah,
it's got like a band attachment to that
man,
I think we're saying.
Yeah.
And I'll show you.
Is there a uh,
there's a plug back there somewhere,
but behind you.
That's it right there.
Oh,
okay.
Take this thing out.
Oh,
whoa.
Look at this fucking thing spaceship
looking thing.
yeah.
okay.
So this,
I really rotates around.
He can hit every angle.
Okay.
And that's the pump up a little.
So you put it on.
Oh,
I have seen this.
Okay.
I've seen this very video.
So he has this thing on and it's just a
rubber band.
That's the resistance.
Yeah,
exactly like that.
Or you can use it with like a,
like,
uh,
wait,
so he's moving his head,
in fact running around in a circle.
Yeah.
So you can exercise at all different
angles.
What is the resistance though?
Is the resistance the spinning of his
head?
So is it pulling a.
It's a combination of the two,
so looks like.
So if you see it's pulling right there,
he'll be exercising the side of his
head.
If he faces it,
he'll be exercised in the back of his
neck.
Excuse me,
on the back side of his neck that he
looks like he's got a steel cable,
like he's doing a lat pull.
Yeah,
he's probably got it hooked up to like a
cable machine,
but I have a guy on training right now.
We're actually,
he's actually going to Mexico next week
for a title fight,
but he put on two inches in the last
month published because that good great.
One hundred,
eight pounds with a 16 inch neck.
She has christ.
It's called the iron neck dynamic neck
strengthening rotary cable attachment
gives pointers as he takes a college
football player through the iron neck.
Basic workout.
Huh?
So you have this guy,
he puts this exact thing on that you got
right here.
And then what do you have them do with
this similar stuff to what you just saw
right there,
like rotational exercises other than the
neck.
Uh,
and it's all like circular movements,
all different movements.
And that
doesn't fuck with the discs or anything
because it's a very lightweight.
Well yeah,
if you're going to go on there and put
like 80,
90 pounds,
100 pounds or something.
And what do you think about those
traditional ones that people use those
leather things and I'm not a big fan of
them and I think because it's too,
it's too linear and again,
you don't really get the,
the stretch out of the muscle.
It's just like an isotonic contraction.
So that's just the same weight going up
and down over and over right now,
would you recommend something like that
to somebody who had a neck injury?
They're trying to,
you know what?
I think actually I believe they use them
at the disc institute or the spine,
the,
the place in la,
you know,
marina del rey,
the spine or whatever disk or something
like that.
Yeah,
I think they have it there.
So they use that for rehabilitation?
I believe so,
yeah.
Because there's a lot of um,
different.
Uh,
kelly started again.
I hate to bring him up again,
but he,
he,
uh,
he hates a lot of these machines that
are out there.
I like those machines where you can say
neck flexion,
extension and all that stuff.
You hate those things too.
I don't hate,
but I just don't use them.
Yeah,
I think it's to the pattern of the
movement is to linear,
it's not efficient enough for like
sports and stuff,
right.
So it doesn't mimic how you would use
the neck in real life.
Seemed like a squat or maybe a bench
press,
you know what I mean?
So I think if there would be a way to
strengthen your neck up,
that would be really crucial for
striking sports.
Anything where your head's getting
jolted back more than it should.
And then the endurance of the neck as
like,
you know,
you're in a longer bout,
it's,
you can't resist anymore and pop your
head flies back.
Absolutely kind of doing their thing has
been shown to reduce concussion.
Like the damage from head injuries.
Sure.
So that line,
we use that frequently.
You can do it also with like an exercise
ball,
you can put it against the wall and
roll,
roll your head against it,
you know,
there's a lot of different ways you can
use a towel.
And so,
I mean I've got a lot of different
modalities I use.
Um,
but yeah,
we,
we really focus with roselawn like
durability for this training to really
building the abdominals and the obliques
and lower back and the neck.
And what do you,
what kind of exercises do for the
abdominals?
Yeah,
I like the,
we call it the horse,
but the glute ham machine can do a lot
of abdominal exercises on there.
You can like the russian twist.
I like that exercise.
I like a lot of medicine ball,
rotational medicine ball throws.
So the glute ham machine,
you're like leaning back.
So yeah,
I back on the,
the big pattern.
Exactly.
That one.
Yeah.
Why do you,
why do you like that one particularly?
Uh,
it's,
it's pretty versatile I think for,
for how basic it is,
I think it's pretty versatile as far as
like the amount of exercises and the,
the how specific you get with each
muscle group.
Like if I want to target your obliques,
like I can hit that oblique so easily
just by turning your hip a certain way,
you know what I mean?
And I can find all these little weak
areas in the abdominals and the feet
lock in on sort of a similar way to like
an old school like sit up bench.
Yeah,
exactly.
And when you do house those old school
set up benches of those,
you know,
and I don't think so.
I think you can get some good work done
on those.
Believe it or not,
like yeah,
I'm not,
but they're not as good as the uh,
no,
my preferences is the glue.
I like that better.
That's the glute ham.
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah.
And that's,
that's a guy facing forward.
You haven't faced backwards as well.
Go both ways.
Yeah.
Lower back.
You want to get back in there and,
and um,
and that machine seems like it would
give you some spinal decompression as
well.
It's phenomenal for,
for the lower back.
And,
and is that guy holding a weight in his
chest when he's doing that?
If you look up that those two guys doing
on the right,
they're banging what to do it.
If you're in a bad guy.
Yeah.
What the fuck is that?
That's the same guy.
Two different phases.
Yeah.
I know.
It's kind of banging his buddy.
That's how you do it.
It was pretty interesting.
You know how that was a,
you know how the machine was invented
was the russians took a pommel horse and
they moved it up to the law.
They took a two by four on the wall and
they just put their feet on the wall and
back extensions over it.
No shit.
Yeah.
Pretty cool.
Huh?
That is pretty cool.
Have you seen the reverse hyper?
Uh,
yeah,
I have.
What do you think about that?
Uh,
I think it's good.
I think there's one of those back there.
I love that thing.
Yeah.
I think there's some.
Is that better?
Do you think through the glute ham?
I think the way you do the exercise is
the most important.
That's the key to what's cool about the
reverse.
Hyper is on the descending.
It's,
it's got like an active decompression.
It's like releasing.
Oh,
is that right?
Yeah.
Well you feel.
Like fully on your lower back slightly
and then you lifting up and
strengthening all that.
Yeah.
So now this like for sports performance,
the speed of which you do that would be
a crucial factor.
You want to feel the stretch out of the
tendons and ligaments before it fires
back up and the weight that you would
put on it.
How much weight put on.
Maybe maybe start off with two and a
half pound ankle weights first.
Real.
Yeah.
See it,
you know,
and just build it up.
So you would explode up lower down.
I don't load guys up with weight unless
the quality and the speed of the
movement and the speed will not be
compromised.
So if that's compromised and there's no
sense in moving it up,
for me it's all about getting the guy
faster.
I'm producing more forced.
So.
So do you,
when you have a guy like dos anjos and
you obviously got them in incredible
shape,
do you incorporate any traditional
exercises that people are familiar with?
Like say hill sprints or sand bags or
anything and he'll like,
he'll sprinting is kind of like old
school,
you know,
like I used to do that shit like crazy,
but fuck man,
I pushed myself to the limit.
Like,
oh my heart rate's like 190.
Wow.
I'm really pushing it out.
$100.
But it slows you down.
You just sprinting should be for done,
for speed again.
So running up a hill.
Why would you try to go fast?
You're,
you're running against resistance,
you're making yourself slow.
It's actually been shown that it's
proven.
You can look this up on the strength and
conditioning manuals,
whatever.
That a downhIll ski,
downhill sprinting has been shown to
increase the top speed and sprinters
performance downhill because
decelerating that because because it's
forcing your body to adapt to a higher
speed.
You know what I mean?
So instead you're going up hills,
you're forcing your body to adapt to a
slower speed,
but you feel like you're going to
fucking face plant at any moment.
Right.
I think the biggest misconception with
all the resistance type training is that
somehow you're going to put the weight
down and you're going to move faster,
right?
People believe that,
but why?
Because you can lift the heavier weight
and so your muscles are stronger.
It makes you faster at exactly that.
it doesn't work that one out.
it doesn't work that way.
some sort of a study on power lifters
that they found out the power lifters
that increase their,
their ability to do vertical leaps and
all sorts of other different explosive
exercises just because of power lifting.
there might be some truth to that and
olympic lifting as well.
They found their good sprinters,
but you would say that that
strengthening of the feet,
uh,
I'd say that has a lot to do with it,
but also the strength of the quadriceps
and relation to the,
you know,
the lag in relation to the rest of the
body.
But how do they Move laterally?
How do they move rotationally that's
where they're deficient.
Well,
when you see a really big bulky guy in
the ufc becomes super obvious when they
fight,
a guy who can move moves real good.
They're almost like stuck in mud.
Exactly.
You know,
when you seat,
but for some guys like their style,
but like who's smart?
Paul harris,
you know,
he's a guy where that big beefy fucking
build he always tried to do is grab a
hold of your leg and rip it apart.
So it's like,
it's almost for him it seems to benefit
him to be like really over muscular and
super strong because he's,
he's about that very small movement or
they're very small group of movements
rather.
It's pretty interesting because I'm
actually training another guy from the
ufc.
I just started working with him aBout a
month ago.
Ricardo dementia.
A braille cyborg.
No,
ricardo,
ricardo brain.
He's this guy is another really good
jujitsu guy from Brazil,
but this guy is on the ufc a,
I don't know how many fights he has now.
Maybe this will be the second or third.
I think he's Pretty new.
I think of a cyborg or fighting on the
june.
Sixth garde.
I think there's one,
right?
Uh,
probably the fight night.
Yeah.
He's fighting on that one.
Oh,
there he is.
Yeah.
That's him.
How many fights in the ufc a?
Just want one fight night.
rear naked choke.
He fight what nurse?
Okay.
He's another guy.
I mean you look at this guy and he's
just like freakishly bill.
He was in the Brazil card,
the meo chick versus maldonado car.
Really good jujitsu to the hydro gracie
and all those guys and it's like really?
But he is classic case of a guy who's
lifting.
I mean he's huge but just ripped a.
he's lifting all these heavyweights
slowly.
Hey,
I got them out to their first day
sprinting.
I couldn't believe how slow forgot was
slower.
Molasses.
Blew my freaking mind.
Here's this gigantic muscle bound guy
and the guy couldn't.
It looked like he was jogging.
really?
Yeah.
I take it slow because you thought
you're going to torture him.
Now did go slow to get that time and
then I have them do like a,
like a throw off,
like what I showed you with the
plyometric bench press type movement,
like maybe like 45 pounds,
right?
Guy can barely throw it off six inches.
Really?
Yeah.
Because his muscles are trained to be
short and slow here.
So the body remembers the movement
pattern and the speed,
not just,
you know what I'm saying?
So you're training slow twitch and now
already a month later,
like getting huge gains.
Getting explosive.
Like friday was a breakthrough day,
you know,
a month later.
Yeah.
That's interesting.
So you would take a guy like that.
He's a good example.
Fic fairy,
obviously fricking huge.
Right?
Right.
Yeah.
So what do you do with a girl like that?
Like what's the first thing you do?
First thing I do is get a moving dynamic
movements,
getting him to move a little quicker on
his feet,
learning how more coordination exercises
but keeping him loose and dynamic rather
than anything that's tense and going to
tighten them up.
So like even the shadow boxing a month
ago,
it was just like,
like it looks like slow motion now.
It looks,
it looks pretty good.
Like that's amazing.
You can do such so much progress or make
so much progress happen in such a short
period of time.
Yeah,
it is.
And uh,
yeah,
it's really,
it's,
I'm not gonna say it was easy because
this is one of the harder cases.
Usually it takes about two weeks before
I start seeing a difference.
But uh,
but no,
once you get that breakthrough and you
start seeing them moving differently and
quicker,
man,
it's,
it's on from there it's like okay,
now we can start really progressing and
hitting the nervous system with really
like intense plyometrics and stuff like
that.
How cutting edge is this style of
training?
I mean marinovich did he invent all
tests or marv?
Marv did was,
he took a scientific studies from,
from what the russians had developed
back during the cold war period and he
translated into his,
his exercises.
And so I'd say at least 80 percent of
what I'm doing is stuff that he's come
up with 80 percent.
Yeah,
maybe 75,
80.
Yeah.
But something like that.
And how did you do?
Did you do like an internship with him?
Like how to do that and even if it's not
what he's doing,
it's something along the lines,
you know,
it's something similar.
It's very heavily influenced by what the
russians came up with and their studies
of the nervous system.
And uh,
so mark took these things and translated
in exercises and it's just been
phenomenal.
Like,
you know,
it's just,
it's really,
uh,
he got to try it,
man.
I,
I believe you can work out with me for
two weeks.
I changed your life,
but you're way the fuck down
there.
Where are you?
I'm in woodland hills.
Oh look,
you're here right now.
Burbank.
We're all.
Well,
let's do this.
Okay.
Do it.
I would love to.
Your life.
You're a guy with an open mind.
He'd be blown away at the differences.
Well,
I would love to just from the point of
view,
first of all for a person always,
I'm always trying to work on,
you know,
different things and improve different
things about my performance physically,
but I also as a commentator,
I think it would help.
I figured that's one thing I really
liked joe,
is how you've educated the fat and this
is something I think maybe boxing needs
a little bit more of is like educating
the fans on the different techniques and
strategies of the fighters.
You remember that one fight?
I think it waS who was anderson silva
and the crowd was bullying.
I think it was anderson facility one and
crowds bullying.
You're like,
why are you building?
That was like a great performance,
like fucking strategic performance.
Well I loved floyd mayweather versus
pack.
Yeah.
He didn't know.
Yeah,
I mean I love skill.
Yeah.
I mean very important to me.
I didn't love it.
I respect it.
Like I respect me whether skill.
Like he's a phenomenal boxer.
I just would've liked to see it for 200
million bucks.
Like go for the kill.
Did you know that guy's tired on the
twelfth round?
Put a little something out there for the
fans.
I,
I loved it,
but I didn't love it as much as I love
canelo alvarez.
James kirkland.
that was more or matisa and provide the
cost.
That was more my mean,
that was definitely more crazy and watch
one of my favorite fights of all time in
the ufc.
I mean there's been a few favorite
fights,
but dan henderson versus shogun,
which was just phenomenal.
I just watched that the other day,
man.
Oh my god.
I couldn't be brain damaged just
watching it.
The other one I watched the other day
was the don frye bush versus a takiyama
that exchange,
two of them were in the corner and we're
just color tie haymaker haymaker out of
his eyeball.
Man.
that was insanity.
I love that.
That was crazy.
Some of those pride fights were fucking
absolutely nuts.
But um,
I'm a fan of skill.
Like that's why I said mighty mouse is
like one of my favorite guys to watch.
But vanderbilt is probably my all time
favorite,
although vendor skillful.
What I loved about vandelay,
which juSt you knew you're going to see
some fucking chaos and that guy got in
and started rolling his knuckles.
You're going to see some shit.
I'm so happy that he got that lifetime
ban rescinded and I don't know whether
or not he was on.
I don't know what the fuck he was on,
but I do know that the vast majority of
those guys are doing something to help
them recover in and when you take a guy
and you take away his livelihood
forever,
you see you can never fight again.
That to me is just disgusting.
It's disgusting.
You can't do that to come lead to right.
Or then they send it back or something.
No,
they were going to give him a one year,
so suspended a one year suspension.
They were going to give him nine months
and they tried to shift it to one year.
He had agreed to nine months and then
when they try to shift it to one year,
that's when he started hearing
all these people on the internet that
were saying that the tests that they did
were not proper,
couldn't handle either ms dot handled or
what it wasn't.
The protocol wasn't estaBlished.
So what the ufc did is they kind of
overstepped their ability,
you know,
like if you're going to have someone get
tested,
you really have to have some water type
organization come in and handle it.
People that have been doing that
forever,
the people that handle the testing did
not do the best job so that the results
were in question.
They would not have probably held up in
court and the ufc had a stand down and
so now calmly is involved in some crazy
lawsuit with the ufc and he's a part of
the whole class action lawsuit thing.
But I think he was also kind of on his
way out.
You know what I mean?
I think it's a bit of a money grabbing
certain ways.
But I think,
um,
the,
the bisping fight was,
it was an interesting fight because con
looked great.
It was ripped,
chiseled,
and that's why people are like,
what the fuck is going on with that guy?
What is he up to?
He gets these tests,
the results in question,
but the tests apparently showed very
high growth hormone rates,
like unusually high.
But yeah,
when the tests are in question,
I'm obviously not a doctor or a
scientist.
I don't know what the fuck really
happened.
Guy looked awesome at 40 something for
the first time I ever talked to jack.
Pretty good transformation.
Kind of like a one one mark as when he
fought.
Pack out that.
Yes.
Yeah.
That was an interesting one too.
Same gym or something was packet.
I was guy packing.
I was old guy.
Alex.
There's a lot of that going on.
You know what,
when you hear okay,
we kind of talked about this slightly
but you didn't touch on it.
There was a bunch of like Bobby Green
was accusing hockfield hassan joe's
fighters high level fighter in the ufc
lightweight division.
What's he ranked?
You know,
he's highly ranked.
Is he?
Yeah,
he's,
if he's not 10 or top 15,
I don't know what rank is,
I'll find out,
but he's a very good fighter,
but he,
his,
I think he's exact quotes were pedes got
played by a ped cheat.
That's what he said.
That's interesting.
But it's just speculation right?
Immediately.
Yeah.
The referral trained with,
I don't know,
one I think and I think they train
together,
didn't he told me about a guy running
his mouth and then he came up to raphael
was all humble.
I wanted to train with them and then
they started training.
the guy was complaining,
don't kick me here.
Don't keep me there.
Oh reAlly?
Yeah.
It's,
I think it's the same guy.
Hmm.
But uh,
what do I think about that?
You know,
I think the guy,
if he's not top three and he's saying
that he's probably just trying to make a
name for himself and um,
it's pretty disrespectful to rafael,
but it's kind of complimentary to me.
LIke,
okay,
cool.
It's like stuck anything.
It's that good.
All right.
Come on,
sign up.
See what the body does not look that
much different.
It doesn't look.
If you're a,
you know,
if you're juicing,
you're going to have traps up to your
ears.
You're going to look like a freak people
out.
I always look at lance armstrong,
lance armstrong,
but he's taken epl.
You just take an epo and testosterone
and a bunch of other things as well.
Yeah,
I called cocktail wrote to be honest,
I'm not that educated on this stuff,
but I'll tell you this,
if I've got him at 12,000,
500 feet altitude doing sprints,
I'm not going to have.
I'm going to make damn sure he's clean.
Cause if you're taking any kind of
stuff,
I don't know what the hell that could do
to your body and your blood up or
something like that and you want to keep
you.
Yeah,
absolutely.
Could you imagine that?
And then and then you're taking 12,000
feet,
that's like ridiculous.
Bobby green or whoever you are,
come and go through a workout and See
what he does and then you'll see why
he's the best.
Do you think that this sport has an
issue?
I mean,
it seems to at least a perception that
there's an issue with ped.
Do I think it does.
I'm sure there is.
I'm sure there's an issue.
Why do you think that exists?
Do you think would exist because of
improper training or because guys want
to get an edge.
I think that man,
joe,
if you and I are trying to reach for
that cup of coffee and you take
something and I and I know you took it
and I want the coffee,
I'm going to take it to if I need,
it's going to give me a benefit.
Right.
It's totally understandable if if one
guy,
if you don't have proper training and
you feel slow and you need to take some
shit to to feel stronger,
you're going to do it because you know
the other guys doing it.
You know what I mEan?
Like what did you.
What did you think about the whole
testosterone replacement therapy
debacle?
Which I think is a real debacle.
I think the way they handled it was just
ridiculous.
They gave it to people.
They allowed it for a few years.
You had these staggering perform like
[inaudible] is the poster boy for,
for testosterone replacement.
You know what I think if it's a medical
thing and like you've been to a doctor
and they say,
hey,
did this,
is it?
I think if it's regulated to the point
where it doesn't put you above an
average level of testosterone,
then I don't see what,
how it should be a problem to you.
I mean what benefits you?
It gives you more quicker.
Recovery allows you to train harder.
Right?
But I'm saying as long as it's not above
an average level,
so if you're deficient,
let's say your total testosterone was
100 and the doctors are moderate,
like they're monitoring it thoroughly
and you show up every week and they're
doing a test and they can show like,
hey,
this is his thing and it's 300.
That's it.
Then I don't know if that would be.
I'm not condoning drugs,
but I'm just saying maybe that would be
an acceptable way to let it in.
I agree with you.
In a perfect world,
I think there's too many variables.
If your testosterone is low,
you probably shouldn't be a fighter.
Yes.
And also probably it's inter indicative
of one or two things,
pituitary gland damage or,
or gonad damage or you took steroids and
now you're not producing.
Yeah.
And your body shut down.
And that's,
uh,
that's,
that's what a lot of guys were doing.
They were taking it.
And then when you,
when you add in exogenous,
as I say it,
I guess I'm testosterone.
Your body goes,
all right,
we've got plenty of this and it stops.
It's natural production.
And so then you would do that and then
go get tested.
And then the doctor would say,
oh,
your natural production is way down.
Way down Testosterone.
Yeah.
And that's what a lot of guys were
getting away with it.
You don't need it with a great diet.
Like raphael liked the guy saying that I
don't know who he is,
but you have to understand there's a
reason he's the champion and it starts
with his mind and his discipline and his
dedication to the fighting.
He came here with nothing.
Did like,
uh,
his diet is impeccable.
His training is impeccable.
I mean,
he drives two hours to train with media.
That's dedication,
like do all the pds and what you want.
If you're not willing to make those
sacrifices to beat him,
like the same sacrifice that he makes,
you're not going to beat him.
so when he goes down and train with you,
how many days a week does he do this
for?
Three to four days.
Three to four days,
depending upon how he's.
Sometimes I'll go down there.
Yeah,
exactly.
Or how he feels,
you know,
sparring so really hard.
Or he's got something in the next day,
you know,
that we'll take it off.
but yeah,
I really think it's kind of
disrespectful to him.
Did he put in so much work?
How many?
Five flights in the last year or
something like that,
but six training camps.
When you look at the guyS who's beaten
to eating some table guys.
Exactly.
And towards the end we're not going to
lie.
It started to take its toll.
I'm looking at a partial tear of the
mcl.
He was getting worn down and now he
really needed a break.
So the other thing is the guy walks
around with like one 81 probably about
[inaudible] 91 93.
Yeah.
You've seen him wiTh the weight cuts,
you see how holly macerated,
he is the guys fighting in an aca state.
He's probably fighting about one 72,
maybe [inaudible] 73 when he fight
night.
So imagine you take a guy who's one
night and strip off 20 pounds.
Of course he's going to look ripped and
lean like we all look like that
underneath,
you know.
So these accusations are kind of like,
they're very disrespectful I think.
But people think it because we have the
stamina,
stamina for sure.
He's just,
he's just a monster.
You know,
when,
whenever you see someone who excels at a
very high level,
people go,
hmm,
how's he doing?
I do that too.
Like I questioned some guys too,
like there's some guys in the ufc I
question and it's because their bodies
have changed a lot over time,
you know what I mean at the time.
But uh,
there's some guys you look At it and go,
okay,
what,
like,
what did hector lumbar tested positive?
Nobody went,
what?
No,
that doesn't even make sense.
Right?
Hector lumbered had muscles that weren't
even in books.
You go like medical books and they go,
what the fuck is that?
What does that.
ThAt is not even a human muscle.
What?
I don't even understand what drug he
would need to take to.
How like raphael,
I don't even know what drug he would
need to take to have great stamina.
That's easily trainable.
The problem is all these guys are doing
such improper training that they're
making me look even better.
You know what I mean?
So if you took a guy that had poor
stamina,
like okay,
let's take bj penn.
Bj was on pds when he fought diego
santa.
No.
Why?
Why watch this training and.
Well first of all,
beaches,
one of those guys.
That was only a few guys.
Yeah,
he wouldn't even take an fucking ivy for
the frankie edgar fight and wouldn't
even rehydrate with an iv,
which I think is crazy.
Huh?
But beach is one of those guys where I
don't think he's done anything ever.
I don't either.
I don't think he would either.
Why do people think raphael house?
Because he's brazilian.
You know,
that's one reason.
Not like the most handsome dude in the
world.
Sorry,
raphael,
what are you trying to say?
No,
but you know what I mean.
He's not going to be on the cover of a
wheaties box.
Like,
yeah,
he's from Brazil.
The dude comes here to fight.
I mean,
he's a fighter.
That's how fighters look.
Sorry.
You know?
Yeah.
Well,
I mean he'S obviously done it.
Even if he had done any sort of ped,
there's no fucking ped in a world that
makes you that good.
No,
that's hard work.
Hard work and dedication.
One hundred percent.
Not only that,
but they did blood and urine testing for
the fight.
No.
you know what I mean?
Like I think it was three weeks out from
the fight like.
Right,
right.
And then they did urine testing after
urine.
I mean they can detect some stuff.
From what I understand,
like I'm not a master of mexicans
supplements,
but I know a little bit.
And so,
uh,
yeah.
I don't know,
I just keep bringing the compliments
man.
I like it.
So if you took a guide,
like a guy that was known for not having
the best stamina in the world,
the guy who fades,
um,
how much time would you need to get him
to a point where he had a fight?
Like say he's fighting a title fight,
like it's taking a guy who's a known.
Here's a good example,
tyron woodley was one of the best,
170 pound fires and world carries a lot
of muscle memory.
Right?
He'll get tyron.
He's fucking huge.
I mean,
it's amazing.
That guy makes one 70 and they're guys
yoked as fuck.
And when he gets in the cage,
I don't know how much it weighs,
but it ain't one 70.
Right.
You know,
and he's known for being very fast,
very strong in the first round,
but slows down a little bit in the
second one.
Right.
How much time would you need with a guy
like that?
And what would your advice be to a big
muscular guy like that?
Three weeks?
probably about three weeks.
I think that's it.
Yeah.
I can probably get them gone through
weeks.
Three weeks.
How come you only need that much time?
Uh,
I'm just kind of trying to base that off
of like past experiences.
I'd say about three weeks to get them
ready for about five rounds.
He might struggle a little in the fifth
round,
but you made a full training camp with a
guy.
He'll do like seven or eight rounds.
Heart,
no problem.
Seven,
eight were not humble.
What is a full training camp for you?
Look,
if you.
Ideally roughly eight weeks.
So if you had a guy and you wanted to
get a guy to the best possible shape for
five rounds,
he say he's going to be fighting robbie
lawler for the title.
You've got to go five rounds through
fucking hell.
How long would it take?
It depends who it is and again,
what he's had in the past.
So I'd have to assess them first.
So if you give me a guy who's got good
cardio and he,
his stamina has been in,
his stamina is not known for stamina.
He's not known for selling.
I could have him ready for probably like
four or five weeks.
then once you take a guy like that who's
got a lot of extra muscle,
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry to interrupt,
but again,
he did have to prioritize that in this
training,
so something else might have to be
substituted it because training energy
systems is very taxing.
So let's say we're doing sprints or
we're doing something to train the
energy systems one day.
Then he might have to shorten his
wrestling.
He did.
He'd have to be willing to make a
sacrifice,
shortened his wrestling.
You know what I mean?
yeah.
You've got to find a,
an even trade off where you don't
compromise,
um,
all the aspects of the,
of the,
of what the athlete needs.
So the skills,
the skill work almost takes second
place.
If the guy's conditioning is bad,
you have to look at the athlete as a
whole.
So if the guy sucks at wrestling,
but he's got great stamina,
then you need to devote more time to the
wrestling or striking a fist striking
socks.
and he's good at jujitsu and he's good
at wrestling.
He's got no stamina.
Then you've got to devote your time to
this a little more time to the stamina
and the striking.
They try to build that up,
but again,
with the skill,
there's only so much you can do on a
train in one training camp that's more
like a year long process.
No.
Do you hook you guys up with
nutritionists?
If they don't have one?
Do you have someone that you know,
you don't.
Usually they have their own guys and but
if they asked me then I'll help him,
you know what I mean?
But you know,
I'm not a licensed nutritionist or
anything like that,
but an older they're raphael's use and
george lockhart who's getting kind of
popular and he's pretty happy with him
and I think ricardo's using him to.
A lot of these guys,
they get their meals prepped way in
advance.
They get them in like little tupperware
boxes and they keep them in the fridge
and then heat them up before each meal.
Son some girl or something like that.
They delivered to your house.
Oh really?
Yeah.
There's one son foods or something like
that.
They can deliver and it's all athlete
prepared stuff they can do.
They can.
You can tell him what you want and got
like a menu or something like that.
I think.
I think it's called sun foods or
something because I would think that the
more things you could take out of the
athlete's mind that they have to think
about the more happy sources they have.
Right?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Yeah.
How did one marina ventures when they
developed this sort of style of
training?
Was this met with skepticism?
Still is.
Yeah.
There's going to be a lot of haters on
the comments on youtube.
I don't know.
I'm sure.
Chance squat.
What do you mean you can't do a dead
lift?
You know what I mean?
Like unless you can prove it,
show us that the proof in what you're
saying.
Like we,
we already know the proof is out there.
You just have to to,
to,
to read the fine tax of the nervous
system training.
You know the,
the records that they have on the
nervous system training.
I mean,
I think my theory is that this whole
thing with the weight lifting came about
because they needed like a universal
measurement,
you know what I mean?
Like they needed to be able to put a
number on improvement and so they would
use weights because it's universal so
that can kind of show regardless of
whether or not it's good for sports.
It's just showing an improvement in
strength.
You know what I mean?
That's before they have all the fancy
monitors.
Athletes in the us now are gravitating
farther and farther away from weight
lifting.
A lot of the football guys,
they do it because they have to.
They don't like to do it.
They don't like the way it makes them
feel.
The boxers hate it.
Like I haven't met a boxer yet that has
told me,
yeah,
I want to hit the weights.
They don't like it because it makes them
too stiff and it makes them to slow.
Marquez was lifted in a lot of weights
for their pacquiao fight when they
showed that 24 slash seven or whatever
the fuck hbo corner.
So what it is 24 slash seven.
When they showed his routine,
I mean a lot of it was like weight,
like weight lifting,
dumbbells,
heavy dumbbells.
Yeah.
Pretty crazy.
But he wasn't clean for that.
I mean it's just.
No,
it's just like I showed it looked like a
24 year old beach model man.
You know what I mean,
like 41 mexican,
you know,
like been through wars,
like,
you know what I mean?
It's like you guys shut up.
That was ridiculous.
I mean,
yeah.
And it might be.
That might've been a fight.
We're packed.
Y'all was cleaned for the first time,
you know.
Well there was always a lot of
speculation about him as well.
Right.
And then,
you know,
he found jesus in a very deep and
meaningful way for awhile.
Right.
And his body changed a little bit.
His body changed quite a lot of
divisions.
It will,
the titles,
different ways.
Divisions.
That's pretty crazy.
Yeah.
And kept his knockout power all the way
up to.
That's just about it actually hasn't
knocked anyone out though in the last
what,
five yeaRs or something like that or
like,
I don't have any many.
You got to be thinking about who he's
fighting.
No fighting world class competition.
You guys are very different.
Very difficult to hit me in the last big
k.
I was like,
what?
Ricky hatton.
YEah,
but he fucked up.
Chris algieri.
I mean he knocked him down.
That was pretty badly hurt.
He looked great in that fight.
Chris algieri though.
He's,
he's got it.
Some balance issues and his feet and
this I can tell and it doesn't buy.
Absolutely.
You know,
you can tell by looking at a guy's caps.
So the gas,
the two calf muscles on the side of the
other calf right there.
If they're really underdeveloped,
the guys,
chances are the guys got poor balance
[inaudible] let's do it.
Sort of fast twitch muscles that control
your balance.
So like packouts footwork is fricking
amazing,
right?
You see the size of his cast or
watermelons.
Exactly.
So that plays a crucial role iN lateral
movement and footwork.
So he took a guy.
You look at one more kids,
doesn't have great footwork,
but have you seen his kaz?
They're like noodles.
What about jon jones?
Jon jones is another guy.
He's really skinny cow.
He doesn't have very good footwork.
He's quick,
His upper body is quick and he's got
quick leg kicks,
but he doesn't have the greatest
footwork,
I don't think.
Really?
Yeah,
I don't think so.
Rafael has pretty good footwork now.
He's in and out real quick.
You know what I mean?
You see thAt in the henderson fight?
For sure.
Yeah.
Uh,
who else?
Pianist.
I haven't been following the ufc that
much.
Your work with dos anjos is what got me
excited about talking to you.
have a lot of fighters started
contacting,
you know,
I've been contacted by a lot of guys,
I'm very like,
uh,
I'm,
I'm very choosy about who I trained.
So only so many hours in the day.
not only that,
but there's,
there's Different personalities,
man.
It's,
it's exhausting.
Like guys,
you don't want to listen or they don't
want to have time for that anymore.
I'm done with that.
Like I did that in the beginning.
I did a lot of shit and had to deal with
it.
Now it's like,
if I sense right off the bat,
you're not serious.
I'm just,
we're done.
And that's how the marinovich is
treated.
Bj and the sec.
This camp with frankie,
I think.
Yeah,
but I think,
you know,
miriam is really cared about bj.
Dude,
it's,
it's a funny thing when you're working
with a guy that close you really get
attached to them.
You really care about their wellbeing
and I think they took it aS kind of like
a,
like an insult and kinda like,
almost like a,
like,
um,
almost like a stab in the back when he
questioned their,
their,
their intelligence as far as training
goes,
like,
you know,
their,
their programming,
the way they programmed the training
camp.
So I think that,
I think they were hurt by that,
you know,
to this day.
I mean,
gary and marv,
you know,
if he talked to them,
uh,
they're still saying,
you know,
I just can't figure out why he,
he had it.
He,
he,
he knew how he felt after the training.
And why would you get rid of it?
Why was hard,
you know,
it's also when you're that good and you
have so many.
Yes,
men around you.
That's the problem.
It's very hard.
That's the biggest problem I was staying
in Hawaii,
man.
All the hawaiians is gonna.
Hate me now,
but stay in Hawaii.
The reason why I stayed in Hawaii
because Hawaii is fucking awesome.
Fucking great.
Don't get me wrong.
I wouldn't just do the same training
partners over and over.
That's just monotony kills athletes.
It does and also being the baddest
motherfucker in the room has to be.
Yeah,
you got to be challenged.
Even here with the root ca training when
they're at the root of training camp for
the diego sanchez and we had amazing
guys in there,
like I was in there training with them
everyday.
A benson henderson was in there for an
escadera who just won the ultimate
fighter that year.
A lot of other guys,
division one wrestlers.
Bj just tore through everybody like they
are nothing.
I didn't see one person.
You get the better of him.
Wow.
Imagine a cage filled with like 15 of
these intense,
like hardcore lightweights and bj just
walking through all of them.
His timing was so precise.
Elastic energy in his muscles,
he elastic strength that he had his
explosive power was just remarkable.
His take down the fence when he was at
his very best was absolutely retarded
too.
He'd be able to hop around on one leg.
I mean it just is.
Flexibility is ridiculous.
I tried to take him down many times to
no avail.
Look kind of flexibility to that guy.
Have ridiculous dynamic flexibility.
He'd do a lot of stuff with like rubber
straps and stuff.
Pulling on them and resisting and
stretching this camp.
He was doing all the same stuff that
basically that I'm doing,
you know,
that I do in my guys like the dynamic
stretching,
you know the,
a lot of the exercises on the stability
ball and workouts in the pool.
Stuff they use for rehabilitation,
but you can progress that and use it for
performance as well.
So if it's good for rehabilitation,
you know,
you take it to another level,
it's got to be good for performance.
What is your education background when
it comes to this stuff?
I went to continuation school and high
school,
got obsessed with weird things.
That's about It.
It's continuation school,
you know,
you get kicked out of high school to go
to like had to go to continuation
school.
I didn't,
I've never heard that before.
Yeah,
you have an informal background training
background.
You know,
it's funny.
Mark did to marv.
Marv majored in fine arts from usc.
Really?
Yeah.
And that was my,
that was my major in junior college was
fine.
Arts and psychology,
so everything you learn,
you sort of learn along the way from
reading studies and data.
Rehabilitating my own body after the car
accident that waS,
that was big.
I went to supposedly the best physical
therapists in the area and six months
later I've got a huge bill and no
results so I just took it into my own
hands,
started researching it,
I now what to do and then within a month
or two I'm,
I'm already back at work on.
Great.
So then how long have you been training
fighters now?
How many fighters?
You know,
like a before I started training the
fighters and strictly doing
conditioning,
you know,
I was also working with like football
athletes in soccer.
I've got A ton of college athletes,
you know,
I don't think I can talk about them
because the ncaa rules or whatever,
you can't use them for reference from
promotion.
Exactly.
But um,
some pretty high level ones,
a lot of high school athletes,
but prior to that I had a jujitsu
academy also.
And um,
so I was always,
I've always been in the mix with like
the jujitsu scene and mac,
stuff like that.
So then I just had so much more success
with the conditioning that I had just
gone that direction.
Well,
one of the things I like about this
conversation is there really is no
straight consensus about what's the
right way to train athletes and fighters
and especially fighters.
I think when it comes to strength and
conditioning fighters,
I think did,
it is probably the most varied.
I mean I think the nfl kind of has an
idea of how to train football players.
The nba players train very similar
fashion,
bUt with the fighters man,
it's across the meanness.
It saw the cain velasquez,
cain velasquez,
that motherfucker on the planet and you
saw what he's going through.
And I want to see his leg extensions
now.
Yeah,
you do pull up cain velasquez leg
extension 100 pounds.
I'm just wondering how good this guy
could be with good training.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Well,
he's got great wrestling training and
great kickbox training conditioning.
Let me say that.
I'm just wondering how good he can be.
Like with that.
His fucking conditioning is.
his stamina is insane.
But his speed and his
coordination.
I don't know.
Maybe it can be even at another level.
Who knows?
Wow.
You know what I mean?
Let's put it this way to this.
Oh look at this.
Three hundred pounds on the lakes
extension machine.
What do you think about this?
So it's nice getting help.
I don't know what that's going to help.
I don't know what it's going to build up
his quads.
I guess.
I don't know what part of your extension
on muslim,
I don't know.
Desire to help,
like throw leg kicks or anything now
it's just all caveman shit he looking
at.
This is not even cave man.
This is like nautilus,
like jack lalaine type stuff.
I used to work at a place that I used to
teach people how to do that.
Yeah.
I worked at a place called the boston
athletic club in south boston to teach
people how to lift weights.
Yeah.
Uh,
so when I see that,
I just wonder how much better they could
be.
Good training.
I mean,
I know,
I know it works.
I've been around this stuff for 15,
20 years,
you know,
strength and conditioning and seeing
what works and it just,
I know it works like marv to him and his
brother combined.
Seventy years of experience,
maybe more.
Maybe it's 80 now and they've seen
everything.
Marv was one of the guys responsible for
designing the combine,
the football combine,
you know,
for about 40 years ago.
Amazing.
Yeah.
So he's seen everything to argue with
him about it would be just ridiculous.
Like you're way out of your league,
you know,
it's like talking to helio gracie about
jujitsu,
like there's nothing you're going to
bring to the table that he hasn't seen,
you know,
despite all the monstrous monster
stories that you hear.
Like on espn,
he was one of the worst sports father.
It's all this media did.
It's bullshit.
He's actually one of the most generous
fucking guys in the training of trainers
that I've met.
He's one of the most generous and it was
one of the most transparent guys I've
ever met.
Honest guy.
That's awesome.
I think all about the product.
The problem,
the problem with the espn documentary,
we said his son went off the rails and
when the sun goes off the rails,
everybody looks for someone to blame.
You know that he was too strict,
didn't give his son sugar.
He didn't even let it sunny meet,
right?
Uh,
I think he did.
I don't know.
I don't know about that.
It was something on the documentary.
They were saying,
well it didn't let him have wheat
gluten.
I think.
Really?
Yeah.
Even back then I think they were saying
meet.
I saw it really recently.
Maybe it was certain types of meat.
Yeah.
When I knew I was going to talk to you.
I think that's when I watched it.
Um,
but uh,
it's just,
it's fascinating to see a guy with that
much knowledge take a sun and turn them
into this fucking super freak athlete.
I mean,
as in certain ways it was sort of,
I mean it was vindicated.
His techniques and strategies have been,
look how good is god damn son was until
you go crazy with the drugs and the
partying and all that stuff.
The idea was that the discipline was too
much and he couldn't take it anymore and
then he had to start it.
And
do you want drugs?
You know,
you can blame it on whatever you want
and only put the stuff into his mouth.
You know what I mean?
Right.
That's a good point.
And you could get 10 different
personalities when you know you have a
son,
if you have more kids.
I have three.
They're all,
they come out of the box completely
different.
You know,
they just worried about math.
Like I love my son so much,
I don't know anything different,
you know,
it's,
believe me,
I have two.
My two youngest are completely
different.
I love them equally.
They're totally different,
but there they have their own little
thing going on.
But the point being that it's a
different children,
different humans will react differently
to different forms of diversity that
they face and there's only so much you
could do as a parent,
you know,
you can't really
totally protect them and shield them.
And it seemed like his son has come back
from all that stuff and he's okay now,
right?
Yeah.
But just as an artist man,
his arts pretty bitch until now.
I guess he's living up in Oregon,
you know,
I don't really know todd very well,
but I've actually never even met todd.
So.
But uh,
yeah,
I guess he's living up in Oregon and
it's got some killer art man.
And there's also the reality that when
you push your son or your daughter,
anyone,
any human being,
they,
people have a resistance to some of that
shit and they don't want to do what you
want them to do.
And they developed a distaste for
something,
even something that they're really,
really talented at.
Yeah.
That's possible as well.
Well,
you know what the funny thIng is,
did you ever read that story about his
son run into like a tenncare something
when he was four years old?
No,
they didn't really like an eight minute
mile or something when he's four years
old.
And I asked them about that one day.
I said,
mom,
what the hell is that like,
you know,
like an eight minute mile.
He's like,
so yeah.
You know what?
I can't figure out.
Nick is why everybody thinks I made him
do it.
I didn't make him do it.
That's what he said he wanted to do it.
So he had that drive and that intensity
that,
you know what I mean?
So it's kinda like shed some light on
some things right there.
Well,
hey man,
you know,
whenever someone comes out in a weird
way,
you use a lot of people are trying to
point blame and a lot of different
areas,
whether it's the fram,
the friends of the family or the seemed
like just college coaches had a real
issue with him as well,
right?
Yeah.
Put them in a box.
Yeah,
that's a.
Yeah.
And then he kind of took over and worked
for.
I was made the coach look foolish and
they didn't like that either.
Right.
um,
what is the name of that documentary?
But he wants to watch it like a 30,
30,
and 30 or some of the project.
Wasn't that it?
I think that was at a mars in the
beginning talking about he's an
undefeated wrestler,
undefeated boxer.
That's great man.
A lot of people don't know that about
him.
He was a football player too,
you know?
Uh,
but he was also an undefeated boxer and
wrestler through the army and college
and stuff.
And his,
just,
his fascination with training athletes
was more powerful than his fascination
with competing.
Well,
he wAs.
So I guess mara was sold into
weightlifting and he felt the destroyed
his athleticism once he went to the
raiders and he was competing with the
guys in the weight room human,
he's squatting a thousand pounds and he
said his athleticism had never been
worse.
It was the,
when he was doing that and that just
destroyed his professional career.
That's interesting.
Yeah.
Wow.
And so that,
that was in the sixties,
right?
Like it's got to be in the sixties.
So he figured he had that awakening s 50
years ago.
Wow.
And you know,
he's been developing this stuff for
years.
So nick,
thank you very much for your time matt.
I really appreciate it.
This is a great conversation.
I really,
really enjoyed it.
And uh,
anybody who wants to check out your gym,
what is the name of it?
Whereas he speed of sport,
uh,
you can go to [inaudible] dot com,
speed of sport.com.
[inaudible] dot com.
And is located in torrance,
California and torrance and speed of
sport on twitter.
Yeah,
that's your handle.
Yeah.
Alright.
Very enjoyable conversation.
I really appreciate it.
Thanks.
All right friends.
We'll be back tomorrow.
See you later.
Bye.
That fine.