The Joe Rogan experience
freaks and geeks lovers in children.
What's going on?
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the podcast and our guest
today is the one and only Mr.
Dave Foley Day Foley's in the house.
Thank you.
Holla.
Dave.
Our.
Our podcast is sponsored by fleshlight.
I don't know if you've ever utilize one
of these masturbatory devices.
Can I try that during this interview?
I'm sure that's the butthole version.
That's the.
But I don't recommend you jump right
into the deep end.
It's like trying heroin before you tried
pot,
but it's tight and I don't know.
It's well.
Yeah,
but I usually a live the butthole I
like.
I like someone to apologize to so I
don't know if this is really good for
me.
Yeah,
it might develop some bad social habits.
Forced.
Forced yourself on it.
Just baby.
I know,
baby.
Just let me get through this.
What a terrible,
terrible thing.
What is that?
Is that.
What does the instincts that I dunno,
but anal sex was so popular with the
young people these days.
I think that is because of the porn.
The porn is fuck the kids heads.
I think it's two things as the porn and
it's the Bush administration really,
because there was actually this study
each other said like eight years of,
uh,
of abstinence,
only education in the US.
They got rid of anything other than
abstinence only education in the
schools.
So all these kids have grown up
thinking.
All right,
well if they take it in the ass,
there's still virgins.
Whoa.
Ran.
Yeah.
So all these,
like Christian kids in the Bible belt
are all having anal sex because of this.
But the blowback,
it's unintentional blowback.
There was always a few girls like that
when we were young that did you know
that they were still virgins if they
took in the ass.
There was like one or two girls that you
had heard about,
but they were always like a joke.
Yeah.
I never,
I never met a girl in,
you know,
before both my two marriages.
Not until after.
Not until I became single again.
This third time have I ever met girls
that,
that were in the anal sex really ever.
You can find them.
They're out there.
I know,
but I,
you know,
people that are allergic to peanut
butter,
you don't,
it's not that common that peanut butter
can kill you.
Yeah.
But you're going to meet them.
You're going to meet them.
Yeah.
Especially if you're out there on the
hunt for out there getting crazy looking
to stick things in people's butts.
Oh,
I thought you meant an out on the hunt
for peanut allergy.
People know because that is a sexy.
That is a secretary.
I love fucking me.
Some peanut allergy people.
Yeah.
They,
they don't have a lot of resistance.
No,
no.
They give up easy.
So I'm uh,
Dave and I have known each other since
1994 when I first started doing,
uh,
when I first started acting really news
radio was one of the first acting things
I'd ever done.
We had done one other Sitcom before
that.
You had your own.
Did this cardboard bose?
Yeah,
absolutely.
Terrible,
terrible,
terrible word you've invented.
I'm,
yeah.
I should throw a couple other apps in
there.
It was you and Mike Star,
right?
Yeah.
And um,
there's another guy,
bruce,
I think his name was greenwood.
He's always been,
he was like in star track.
He played Captain Kirk's Dad,
you know,
he's,
he's always doing a bunch of different
things.
There was a few of an alley.
Um,
God,
what's her name?
Uh,
fuck.
I forgot her name,
but she's married to George
Stephanopoulos.
Oh yeah,
I know,
I know what you mean.
Very nice girl.
I remember her name either.
Alexandra Wentworth.
Yes.
And uh,
yeah,
it was terrible show and it was really
funny premise and it was written by
these guys who had written the simpsons
and they'd worked on married with
children.
Kevin Kern and Jeff Martin.
Really funny guys,
but they were very much writers.
They were very quiet guys.
There were little socially awkward and
the network just did not think that they
would be able to handle producing a
show.
So they brought in this ultimate hack.
I don't even remember his name was bill
something or another,
but he was death.
Every joke was death is.
All of his instincts were terrible.
It was just the worst,
most hacky shit.
The guy who never said a funny thing in
his life.
So I got to see the worst aspect of
Hollywood and then,
uh,
I was totally ready to bail and go back
to New York and just go back to doing
standup.
But unfortunately I leased a fucking
apartment because I was convinced that
this show is going to be successful.
Like every idiot.
Yeah.
So,
um,
I'd stayed around and then next thing
you know,
News Radio,
thanks to Ray Romano being fired in
rehearsals.
Yeah.
So what was that like?
You were there in the pilot.
I was not.
Well,
yeah,
what would,
just didn't work out?
Just the wrong character.
I mean,
I guess ray knew things weren't going
well.
I didn't really perceive that he was
having any real problems,
you know,
it makes sense.
But he,
he would rate,
would come up to me like a man,
you gotta help me out here.
You can't go.
I gotta get a joke in here and I gotta I
gotTa make this funny somehow.
And maybe it was just the stench of
nervousness.
Yeah.
So he was like a panic now I guess he
was,
you know.
And then,
uh,
it was then I got the call.
Yeah.
I got that call from Paul and then
saying,
oh,
well we're going to let ray go.
And never.
That's ready though.
All the time thinking that something's
going terrible.
He's like,
one of those guys always thinks that
things are going wrong.
There was a recent,
he did an interview on the Green Room
that Paul provenza show where he said
that still to this day,
he goes onstage and the audience cheers
and he feels like a fraud,
you know,
he steps out there,
they love him,
you know,
fucking 10 years.
A Great Sitcom,
a great standup comic.
Ali's people love him.
They don't even like me.
This is very,
he gets out there and it just weirds out
the fact that all these people actually
like him,
you know.
And then there was the guy that did the
part during the pilot and then just that
was it for him.
They just didn't use them after that.
Yeah.
I forget his name now.
Bill.
I don't even think they considered this
poor fuck.
No,
he was just there as an interim filler.
Yeah.
Which is a horrible position to be in.
So I was in my apartment and uh,
I had a deal with NBC,
some,
some sort of a development deal and they
said,
well there's a show that we would like
you to read for if you're interested.
And then they gave me the tape and I
remember thinking,
Holy Shit,
this is fucking good.
Like,
like this.
No Way I can get on the show.
Like this is like a real show,
like the other hardball show.
At least.
It sort of made sense like why they
picked me with zero acting ever to be on
this Sitcom.
Oh,
because they're idiots and they don't
know what the fuck they doing,
you know?
But all of a sudden this was like this
real NPC show.
And I was like,
Holy Shit,
you know,
I can still remember being there on the
first day of set.
I'm like,
I'm fucking sitting right next to Phil
Hartman.
Like how weird is this?
You know,
I literally had,
when I got my development deal,
they made me take some acting classes.
So I took some one-on-one acting classes
with some crazy failed actress,
woman in New York who was unbelievably
bitter and play like weird psychological
games with you.
They don't give your teaching
certificate unless you're unbelievably
bitter.
She was brutal.
And then she was trying to angle a job.
She kept trying to angle a job to play
my mother.
I'm like,
I don't think there's a mom and this
fucking script.
Crazy bitch.
Well,
if there's a thing that comes up to play
your mom,
you're going to use it right now.
Like,
Oh God.
Yeah.
And all of a sudden we're on news radio.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
It was a.
because we.
Well,
we had a different.
Cause it was a,
uh,
the joe character was different animals.
So the Catherine character was
different.
A different actor playing catherine.
Oh,
reality.
Yeah.
I forgot about that.
Candy both came in at the same time.
Wow,
that's crazy.
I just ran into candy recently at the
airport.
She still looks like she's 30 years old.
I'm raising black.
Don't crack baby.
Some about those genes.
It's amazing.
Yeah.
Looks fantastic.
She's healthy and vibrant,
yet survived as CSI Miami,
and she bolted from that show too.
I told her,
I saw her.
I said,
Oh,
I'm not on that show anymore,
honey.
She's famous for leaving shows.
She is gorgeous.
She's a.
she's a wild bitch.
She's crazy.
And Kenny Alexander is awesome.
I love her when she's legitimately wild.
Like she,
she doesn't take any shit.
She quit newsradio because she wasn't
getting enough jokes.
I mean,
she just decided there's a TV show on
the air and it's doing really well and
she's getting some silly amount of money
every week and she's like,
nope,
I'm not.
They're not appreciating me.
I'm gone.
And the writers were completely in
denial about it.
It was the weirdest thing,
you know,
when it came up and they're like,
well,
that's not true.
Right?
Like,
what the fuck you talking about,
man?
Yeah.
No,
a bunch of white guys from Harvard.
We're not able to write for a,
for a black woman,
a black woman.
Well,
it didn't even seem like it's almost
seemed like they just didn't bother you.
No,
they didn't.
They didn't even try.
It was just,
you know,
they had her there and then if it fit in
they could use her,
but occasionally they put the word honey
at the start of a sentence when you're
on a show and there's eight people as
Sitcom was such a weird environment,
you know,
in eight people are struggling to get
their own little thing in,
you know,
it's a weird little tense environment
can be very strange and for her I guess
it was just disappointing over and over
and over again.
Yeah.
For a lot of people liked that show.
I don't know this,
and this is a very odd pardon history,
but Dave Foley literally wrote half of
that show and half of it on the set.
Like you.
You were like an unaccredited producer.
That's.
I mean it would have never worked the
way it works without you.
Well,
I guess I guess it's.
I'll say it's a generous over
overstatement.
I don't think it is.
I really don't.
You went over every scene.
You didn't just rehearse the scene.
You went over every scene and you went
over with the beats and you came up with
alternatives.
Every single time,
I mean,
I don't think we ever,
unless the scene was absolutely perfect.
I don't think there was ever a time
where we didn't dabble with things.
Yeah,
I know we all.
And again,
I guess everyone does.
I mean a lot of it was.
I mean,
a lot of the cast you had,
you,
you know,
you and me and Phil and Andy were all
used to creating their own stuff.
Right.
You know,
so we,
I think everyone came into it with that,
the ability to think on their feet and
change stuff.
It was amazing that Paul Lettuce as much
as he did.
Yeah.
Know He,
he,
Paul Simms who was a producer of road
who also worked on the Larry Sanders
show before that was a really young guy
at the time and just really bright and
really great writer,
great writer,
and just knew that we could fuck around
and make different things up.
And you know,
when you're actually on the set and
you're acting it out,
sometimes it doesn't come off as the
same as it is on a written page.
And sometimes there's an obvious or not
so obvious alternative,
but it's just amazing that he let us do
it.
Yeah.
Well they.
Because we,
yeah,
we,
we read rework,
Steph turn rehearsals and find different
things we thought were funnier and then
we'd just run it for.
We'd run it for Paul and the other
writers at the end of the day.
And if they liked it,
it would show up in the script the next
day.
It seemed like both of your characters
were pretty much really well written for
you guys because like you to at least I
didn't feel and didn't really seem like
that,
you know,
in real life I would imagine.
But it seemed like you were,
you and you are you in on that show,
which sort of.
I mean,
Dave was more innocent and I was more
retarded.
But you had your theories and stuff like
that have incorporated aspects of our
personalities.
Yeah,
definitely.
I mean,
um,
I mean I was.
Dave Nelson is probably a real mix of me
and fill and fail me and Paul Simms,
you know,
so it'd be depending on who the rightest
felt like mocking more that day.
Yeah.
I was a just a more retarded
version of me with special gifts that I
don't possess.
Yes.
Yeah.
You were.
You were a conspiracy theorist with a
bit of the fonts.
Yeah.
It was a fun gig though.
A lot of fun.
The last year was oddest.
Fuck.
Yeah.
But other than that it was a,
it was a lot of fun and I'm glad we did
the last year because I would've hated
to not see everyone after.
That would've been terrible.
Yeah.
I always assumed we would be hanging out
all the time from now on,
from,
from that point on,
but it really didn't work out that way.
No,
no.
It never does,
you know?
No,
it's true because everybody goes in such
different directions.
I ran into Maura once or twice,
I know a wrench,
but once we had a good time at one of
those NBC functions and I was on news
radio or fear factor and she was on er
and we got drunk together.
It was a great time.
It was like the old days reminded me is
always fun to get drunk.
Oh yeah.
She's one of the best ever.
You know.
She was the one who convinced me to kick
in the craft service door.
All hungry.
Uh,
yeah,
we had some good times and that set
after the set,
after filming we would basically just
drink all night,
you know,
filming would be done at whatever and we
all have our mini fridge is stocked in
our coolers and we were just getting
hammered and just shoot the shit and
have fun and laugh and go over to Dave's
ruined listed some weird music.
Dave voice had some weird chicks that
made you want to cry.
Playing in a few of them lead dated,
you know,
strange,
somber women's voices,
[inaudible] and uh,
and then we,
yeah,
somebody you'd be there till,
till it was time to go to denny's,
right.
Or we would go to a,
down the street when we were at sunset
gower,
we,
we'd go down to that bar.
What was it called?
There was like a,
like an industry bar,
like really catered to people that were
leaving the set.
Oh,
well the mold right next to the peanut.
Was that what it was?
Yeah,
it was to be the Columbia bar and grill.
yeah,
yeah.
It'd be like other people from Fraser
and uh,
that was weird to be there and would go
and it wouldn't be stiff as fuck.
We would be hammered and they would be
all still like doing their actor thing,
you know?
I thought it was a marvelous
performance.
I think he was quite lovely.
Did you know that?
It's on Broadway now.
I'll be amazing.
I've got to see it.
You know,
they were just all completely full of
shit and he would come and try and grab
everybody's Dick.
And Dave and I will be hammered more
yammered yeah.
And Julie being extremely been.
Yeah,
we'd all be laughing and joking around.
Yeah.
It was a great,
great group of humans the most.
That was one of the most fun times of my
entire life.
Those,
those years.
It was amazing.
There was one time I remember we were
about to go and do it.
There was a live audience there and
everybody was getting ready,
getting ready and we were standing in
that little back hallway where they
would introduce us and,
and I said,
you know,
that this is going to be one of those
days.
We're going to look back,
uh,
when we're older and we're going to go,
I can't believe I didn't enjoy this
more.
I can't believe.
I didn't appreciate how crazy.
This is more.
You don't realize what a random stroke
of luck it is to get so cool people
altogether
in one group.
Yeah.
The fact that,
yeah,
we all wanted to spend time together,
uh,
like,
like when work was done,
nobody can go.
Everyone wanted to stay.
We all had fun.
We,
it was a,
it was a really weird environment.
It was a weird environment to in
creatively.
It's just,
it's so rare that a sitcom works.
Yeah.
You know,
I've,
I've been given scripts to sitcoms and
fuck,
I couldn't get into them.
I fucked up in some recent audition,
but a year ago I guess it was,
I just,
I didn't even read it a little bit and
then I looked at him like,
what the fuck am I going to do with
this?
And then it's just,
yeah,
you just,
you,
you feel like,
like you were there when lightening hit
the ground,
you know,
you don't want to be,
you don't wanna you know.
Well,
was that,
it was like we were uh,
from the very first time I think we were
all together on state.
It felt like we'd been there for years.
Like it felt like a group of people who
have been working together for,
for a long time.
It was so weird.
It was such a weird environment.
Such a weird experience for me because
like I said,
I had no acting experience nor
aspirations to act.
It was strictly a by greed alone that I
wound up in Hollywood because they
offered me all this money to be in a
sitcom and I was like,
what the fuck?
Really?
Then all of a sudden I'm here and then
literally less than,
you know,
six months after that show was canceled.
I'm on news radio.
Yeah,
it was,
it was so bizarre.
And it,
you kind of have the same kind of like
thrown into it when you were young when
you started kids in the hall.
I was 28 while I was,
I was 19 when I started working with
Kevin Mcdonald Flower,
but I was 26.
I was 25.
And the series started.
And were you a comic before or were you
doing and kind of Improv as well?
I started,
I quit high school and started
doing standup when I was like 17.
Wow.
Uh,
and then how long did you do it for?
Just for like just let even two years.
About a year and a half.
I had quit when I was just around my
19th birthday.
And that is exactly when you were
getting into kids in the hall.
Yeah.
I quit after I met Kevin Mcdonald and
started doing stuff with him.
I stopped doing standup.
So just focused all your time on
sketches and stuff like that.
Yeah,
we're doing a joint is improv group.
Um,
and then we're like both theater sports
and it was taken like second city
workshops and you know,
and that led pretty I guess fairly
quickly within a few years to the,
uh,
the whole five men version of the kids
in the hall that became the TV show,
which they played nonstop in the United
States on comedy central all the time
back in the day.
And I remember.
Yeah,
I think we were all they had for awhile.
Yeah.
That weekend at Bernie's.
That was a pretty south park.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Wrap your head around that.
Yeah.
How many Central Pre south park?
We were pre comedy central.
I think we were back then there was,
there was the [inaudible] network and
the comedy network.
The Jurassic era.
Yeah.
And then they became comedy central.
My first deal with them was on the
comedy channel.
They these little profiles of Comedians
and they would have you do like.
It's where I met Sharon Levy,
who's the head of spike.
She's one of the heads of programming.
It's she was a pa and we were in a field
that was on a farm for handicapped
animals,
like literally animals that were like,
it's hard to laugh at Handicap van.
Yeah,
you can laugh.
It doesn't matter.
You're going to eat them.
They die,
but it was like,
you know,
like blind sheep and you know,
a cow with a limp and and we were and
she was holding the microphone and I was
doing like,
stand up to these animals.
That was like a campaign program that
they put together.
Yeah,
the comedy channel.
It was.
God,
it's so funny.
Hair fucking flies by and that's
history.
Remember Allen Show?
Yeah.
Alan havey used to.
He would be at pnl every now and then or
whatever the bar was called.
We rent.
Yeah,
yeah.
He was.
Yeah.
He was doing some show that was nearby.
That was the other thing you'd be like
close by and you would also get the
feeds from other,
other,
um.
Oh yeah.
The other shows and other sets we get to
watch other horrible sitcoms.
Greg Geraldo had had a show that was a
good one actually.
A lot.
Yeah.
And so did Joey Lawrence.
Do you remember that?
Oh,
I mostly remember him sitting in his
convertible playing his own cds really
loud.
He always had bad ass cars.
Like Joey Lawrence always had like the
newest Ferrari or the newest Bentley or
whatever the hell it was.
But he'd sit there playing his own music
loud.
Super loud with a Bandanna on.
Okay.
Where is he now?
Man,
you intentionally ripped jeans.
He was just in dancing with the stars
recently.
Well,
I think Dave said it best.
Even back then was someone needs to tell
that young man that he's gay and that's
exactly how you said until we stopped
and we were looking there and there was
a couple of them in you.
You just,
you just stopped and paused and said
someone needs to tell that young man,
he's gay.
We went into work,
I mean he would be right,
you don't know where these,
where these cars were parked and right
directly in front of the building.
So you'd open up the door and basically
be on the set and right behind that is
this fucking guy in his car blaring his
own music from some insane stereo
system.
And if your music is,
the is great,
it's wrong to sit there and listen to
your own music in the car.
Yeah.
Robert Plant is in his car.
Fucking beating the drums to his
steering wheel.
Still be like,
what the fuck?
Really?
Yeah.
You don't get enough attention,
but when you're Joey Lawrence,
how did you get hooked up with the South
Park guys?
Weren't you the Baldwin Brothers on the
South Park movie?
I was,
I met.
Well I met Matt and Trey,
um,
before there's,
before South Park went on the air,
uh,
I met,
they'd done there,
that little Christmas thing that was
going around,
right?
Barton Botox before I bought Bronto and,
and uh,
and Jesus,
which was amazing.
And uh,
and then so I had seen that and then
they got their deal with,
with comedy central comedy central party
somewhere in like a,
one of the good parties,
like the rave parties or.
No,
it was pretty quiet.
There wasn't a small bar.
It was like a tiny.
But they were there.
I remember because I remember a tray was
a wearing a shiny silver.
A jumpsuit serve a,
a jumpsuit.
Yeah.
It was like really shiny,
you know,
it was like Super Dave.
But in silver,
um,
I fucking love those guys.
I love that they exist,
you know,
that there's these guys that are just so
balls out there and shit.
They do.
She's so crazy.
And when I say bigger,
longer,
uncut,
I like because at the time I got,
I don't know what the fuck a South Park
movie is,
I don't know how,
how they're going to do this.
And then I go into the premier and all I
could think of was this is the most punk
rock thing I've ever seen in my life.
This is the most aggressive.
That thing I is the line.
I shit on your God.
It's amazing that they got away with it
when they had Saddam Hussein and the
devil and that whole thing.
Penis when they first cost.
Remember when you first heard like
heartening say fuck or something like
that.
You're like,
whoa.
That was huge.
And then they.
They took it with team America,
world police.
He took them in another direction,
which is fucking incredible.
Another one of my favorite all time
movies.
It's hilarious.
I mean they're just the funniest damn
movie for whatever weird reason doesn't
make me laugh the second and third time.
I don't know.
American America.
Yeah.
I watched it the other day and it's
fucking.
Maybe I'm.
Maybe I'm watching alone.
Maybe I need to watch with friends.
The first time I watched it I thought it
was the funniest thing I've ever seen in
my life by a long shot.
Like I love the scene where the guy
throws up all over himself and throw up.
Just won't stop and it goes on forever.
I was like,
these guys are animals.
Like they don't fuck around.
They go so deep.
Yeah.
Well,
that was the scene in the car is going
well first you're going to have to blow
me.
Just kidding.
No,
I'm serious.
You're really to have to blow.
Did you ever see the uncut version with
the ticket?
Shit.
The girl takes a shit on his chest and
his face crazy sex scene with.
Oh No,
I never studied cut version.
She shits of his chest.
Sensors will like enough already about
censorship.
It was,
yeah,
it was just that.
It's just.
Oh,
come on.
Well,
I think it's also they're very savvy and
they understand the system that you have
to put so many things in order to get
what you actually want so they feel it.
So the sensors feel like they've done
their job.
There was an episode of News Radio about
the word penis and because of this
episode,
this episode had like 30 uses of the
word penis in and they wouldn't air it
one season and we had to wait until the
subsequent season before they started
airing.
Yet you remember that?
I forget.
And then,
yeah.
And then there was still a negotiation.
They had wanted the number of penises
removed.
Yeah,
and the premise of the story was bill
saying that you have to say a bunch of
penises in order to be able to say one
or two compliment.
They literally,
they're like letting everyone in on the
Google and these fuckers still do it.
You know,
these network people are still there.
You're saying it too many times.
Yeah.
If you can say penis once,
why can't you say it a thousand times?
What the fuck is the difference?
If it's relevant,
if it's not like what are you trying to
pull off by saying it over and over
again.
Let's see.
I have bronchitis,
I will.
You have children.
I have children.
And when my daughter will say,
well why is it,
why is it okay to say poor but not shit?
Right.
And my only answer is because most of
the people in the world are stupid,
but
there's no other explanation for it.
They mean the same thing,
you know?
And so I say like,
you know,
language,
all words are supposed to do is convey a
meaning and if the meaning is the same,
the words are the same.
Exactly.
You know,
we have a rear really weird thing in
this culture in this country and this
culture where we're sensitive to secret
words,
you know,
secret special words were very sensitive
to them,
whether it's faggot or nigger or,
or shit or it's all should.
There should be no magical words that
have super power for good or bad.
Yeah.
And then the,
the fuck word,
which is like this sort of like sort of
acceptable,
like not even that bad anymore and
casual conversation,
uh,
you know,
all this fucking guy or you know,
as long as you don't use it too much,
people don't really seem to care as
businessmen will say it in meetings,
absolutely.
Sure.
But children.
Yeah.
But we still send them to school and
tell them,
pretend this still exists.
There was that these words are bad.
There was a photo that I talked about on
the podcast the other day.
I've been talking about this on stage
because it's so ridiculous.
It was a Mexican drug killing.
Chop this guy up into a bunch of pieces,
skinned him,
took his skin off of his face like a
mask,
hung it on a stick.
All of this is on the air and then they
cut his hands off inside.
One of his hands was his dick and his
balls and it was blurred out.
Yeah,
see that.
All I can think is that,
and people say Mexicans are lazy.
That's a lot of work.
You won't see a white killer taking the
time.
True.
He said that he sent a very clear
message and so did the owners of the
website.
That balls are scary,
scary.
Not Skin skulls and hands,
you know,
it's the same thing.
It's like,
what is wrong with us?
Why?
Why do we look at things that way?
Like the other day,
my daughter,
she's taken to saying shit when things
don't go well,
which was what happens when she hears
it,
you know,
they'll imitate their atmosphere.
My wife was horrified.
She was like,
if we stopped now,
she'll stop too.
And I'm like,
and then what?
It's just taking a break,
just taking a break for 10 years and
she's gonna start saying shit again.
Like everybody else.
Like why can't you say it's cute as
hell,
man,
I just told my daughter just just don't
do it at school because there's no
reason.
And I keep saying it's not like there's
any reason for you not to do it.
It's cool other than the fact that
you'll get grief from people.
It's truly amazing that we grew up
knowing they were silly and now we're
adults and still silly and we're
teaching children and they're going to.
It's like this meme takes forever to get
out of our system.
This forbidden word meme now.
Like what?
Why is it still here?
While it's absolutely ridiculous,
we could eliminate so much and still
convey the exact same thoughts.
If we had no bad words that you could
have come on television and everyone
will just get used to it and it would be
fine.
It wouldn't change the world,
you know?
It wouldn't.
It would make people angry,
wouldn't cause crime across the border
into the United States.
I think they will confiscate the word
come from your lexicon if you read it in
order to.
You have to have three different pages,
right sir?
Are you carrying the word continue your
brain now you're,
you've just started to do standup
recently of a fascinating thing to me
because I always thought you'd be a
brilliant standup because you're a great
writer and when we used to do those
little things in the audience,
you remember wearing,
um,
we would talk to the audience before you
would fuck around with them every now
and then and you wouldn't like do it.
Like Phil had a routine that he was
doing,
like Phil actually started doing standup
because of wanting to entertain the
audience.
So he had a bunch of bits that he would
do like Clinton impressions and they
were really good and it was like,
I'm just like,
Holy Shit Dude.
You know,
like a real comic.
Like you're a standup is like kind of
thinking about to get up there.
Phil was like this really unusual human
being.
Very,
very fascinating guy.
You know,
he was the world.
He was a great hobbyist.
Yeah,
he would go so deep he,
he got into flying and which is actually
how I found out about this neighborhood,
you know,
Phil was taking me out into the valley
looking for different places where he
could go and have a nice view and we
went up in this little single engine
plane,
but I remember when he first started
getting into the flying boy,
he was reading book after book in
between rehearsals.
He'd be studying his pilots book.
Like that was the little fake broadcast
booth.
Very.
He was very,
very disciplined.
He would say Phil was like a big league
version of Mark Mckinney from kids in
the hall.
It was really into his flight simulator.
Phil learned to fly a plane.
He loved it.
He learned to fly a plane.
He learned to sail a boat.
He was one of those guys,
you know,
he's only had learned to duck.
Yeah,
my will not even if you learn to just
separate from fucking crazy people I
know had some.
We,
you know,
we all did,
I think had talks with him many times
about divorce.
You know,
like you gotta get Outta that man.
Yeah.
It was one of those things where we
would,
uh,
we would have these parties.
I mean Paul had one party wants and I
remember we were all at this bar
somewhere and Phil showed up with the
wife and she was saying the creepiest
shit and insulting him and talking about
how she likes pickup trucks because they
reminder of,
you know,
boys that she used to bang back when she
was younger and just,
just,
just torturing him.
Just torture.
I'm talking about,
oh well you're not fail.
You know,
it feels too old.
And he just didn't.
He have like women thrown on him all the
time.
It seems like if he was that miserable
that you would have just.
Doesn't matter man,
when you have children with somebody
inexorably attached for bill was.
Yeah.
The thought of being separated from his
kids,
which I understand because at the time I
was separated from my kids.
Yeah.
I know.
I completely see where he was coming
from.
He didn't want a divorce.
He thought his wife is with all her
flaws,
was still very good to the kids and you
know,
and he felt,
felt like he could work it out and then
he really got into pot,
you know,
that was his thing.
He would just get these later.
Yeah.
You sitting in his Mercedes in the
parking space with his one hitter to the
gills stone and you weren't smoking weed
at the time.
He imagined smoking weed with Phil
Hartman.
That would barely use.
Yeah.
He didn't do any drugs.
I would just get drunk.
So I would do.
Yeah.
I was,
uh,
this is,
my,
my old thinking.
I had a lot of thinking leftover from my
martial arts competition days.
It came to drugs.
Pot was one of the worst for motivation.
I was like,
the last thing I wanted in life was to
be a loser.
The last thing I wanted to be with
someone who just couldn't get their shit
together was lazy.
And I knew so many people that were like
that.
With marijuana is I'd always associated
it with losers.
Wasn't needed.
Your focus dealt a little.
I did.
You help them to honestly,
marijuana is here to calm the savage
instincts of man,
you know,
especially certain men,
it's very good to me.
It's the best self medication I've ever
found.
I guess that's why me,
it just turns me into a sponge.
Extra.
Relax.
We were talking about this before the
show that you really should try it when
you write,
you know,
Shit I haven't.
Like,
I'm.
Yeah.
I don't think I've ever written high.
I've written a lot drunk.
That's great to know.
But drunk on an airplane riding is
fantastic.
Yeah.
Just stuck in that seat.
Can't go anywhere and yeah,
the,
the idea is just come.
Yeah.
The sensor shuts down when you're.
When you're drunk.
Yeah.
Oh yeah,
yeah.
Of course.
Man.
That's why so many great writers are
drunks from Hemingway,
a hunter,
s Thompson.
I mean,
so many of them just wanted to escape
or,
or get to it,
escape from themselves and get to
whatever the ideas were,
whatever they were like drink.
It gives you that,
that window where you don't hate
yourself long enough before the,
before the depression of the drinking
sets in,
but that moment where you think I'm
really into and I'm beautiful.
Yeah.
And before the depression sets in,
that was always the,
the news radio set like you want to
leave after three hours.
You didn't want to be there in the
fourth and fifth when all the Irish
blood comes to the floor.
A lot of Irish.
There's so much that she.
Me and I'm Maura.
Oh yeah.
All of us.
Uh,
Maura was mad at me once for a whole
year for something that happened when
she was drunk.
Yeah.
She could hold a grudge,
you know,
and she's so,
you love or you don't want to make up
sources like grudge hurts.
I know I sound more isomer briefly.
So the kids,
she was a shooting a pilot for her show,
a underneath my apartment.
That's what it's.
Oh really has.
Yeah.
Pete's cafe and I live above.
I shouldn't say that on the Internet.
Don't say fucking crazy fucks.
Yeah.
Girls were white.
Makeup on and black lipstick will be
waiting for you.
Yeah,
that's how I started shooting a short
hair.
Her hair was growing back in as a single
woman though,
right?
Yes.
Yeah.
And she's still,
I don't know.
I don't,
don't know what I'm talking
to her in a lot of time.
If you're listening more pickup a phone,
come on boy.
Naked call follow me on twitter.
They had called my agent.
That's the easiest way.
I know you're,
I know you're legit.
You know how to get ahold of the people.
Um,
so,
uh,
you and you were married at the time and
you were getting divorced while we were
doing the show and it was one of the
craziest things I've ever seen in my
life and not just to Phil Hartman
divorced thing scared me,
but dave thing scared me.
And one of the reasons why dave scenes
thing scared me was you do not want to
get fucking married in Canada because
when you break up in Canada,
say you decide you want to get a
divorce,
you can't legally get divorced until
you're separate for a year,
right?
That's correct.
I'm not sure,
I can't even remember.
I believe it was a year.
It's tattooed in my brain because I
remember thinking how crazy this was
that you were fucked.
And what was happening was his wife,
his first wife was at accenture
character and she decided to start
taking the fucking world or a content on
the radio.
I would have gone with that.
You know,
you're a great guy and I want to say
that while she's the mother of your
children.
So yeah,
that doesn't excuse it.
That is not a get out of.
Get out of countries.
Take.
Well,
uh,
she was very odd and uh,
the first season the guys were together
and then I believe by the second season
it was over.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
We split up and so she started.
What she would do is spend all days
money so dave would be working and she
would spend all day.
It's money,
I mean by crazy expensive furniture fly
all around the world all the time.
So whenever Dave wanted to see his kids,
he used to have to get fucking malaria
shots.
Yeah.
Okay.
So one time we were at one of these NBC
things and Dave's fucked up on malaria
medication and gin and tonics or
whatever the fuck you were drinking.
Yeah.
And you get like,
like crazy.
I had to stop Dave from beating a guy
up.
I had to step in between.
Do you remember the big guy with the
long hair with the fucking dawn job,
Tony Tony carry it.
Wasn't I really liked and wasn't that
the guy had done anything wrong.
It was just the malaria medication.
You become a psychotic.
It's a very common uh,
effect.
Especially apparently when you mix it
with alcohol.
Yeah.
Well,
and you.
And then you add to that,
having made two trips to Africa in a
month.
Yes.
Africa and see his fucking kids,
like I had to fly to.
I had to fly to Morocco at Thanksgiving.
And so we have two weeks off.
So I floated,
flew to uh,
and this again.
And she,
when we first separated,
she took the kids.
We said we'd like a summerset mom
divorce.
Whereas like I need to take the children
to the continent and gather my thoughts.
So she traveled through Europe with,
you know,
a six month old baby and a two year,
two and a half year old for six months
and then,
so then Thanksgiving there and Morocco.
So I had to go meet him in Morocco.
So I get spent 10 days in Morocco,
then another 24 hours flying back and
then two weeks later we get our
Christmas break.
So I have to fly to Zimbabwe and uh,
there was nothing you could've done,
like taking your money and you're like,
Hey,
I'm giving it to joe or something like
that.
No,
it was like a old money.
Yeah,
no,
you have to.
You're responsible for taking care of
their wellbeing at the time when I like,
when I made her get out
the therapy,
she's a,
like,
I forced her to get us to get into
couples therapy because I was miserable.
Um,
and,
and so since we got this,
I said,
let's go to therapy.
She said,
well,
I've got to go first.
All right,
you can go see the therapist.
So she goes in and explains to the
therapist that I'm an abusive husband,
uh,
you know,
and then she starts asked,
she asked me being physically abusive
and then she starts like phoning my
family and friends and saying that I'm
physically abusive,
complete fabrications.
Right.
So she's just creating a good friend of
mine,
Steve Hibbert,
when he heard this
said,
that's crazy.
If,
if dave was abusive,
she would be dead.
No,
but no,
but then I go into
therapy and the therapist goes,
you know,
who is prepared for this abusive husband
and to walk in.
And she goes and she explained to me
later,
she said it was very weird because you
walked in and you didn't match the
description of you at all.
And she said when you walked in.
Yeah.
And I saw you two together.
I immediately realized that if anyone in
this couple was abused,
it was,
it was me.
Did the therapist say this to her?
Uh,
I don't know if she ever said it to her
in therapy.
Did you have a one on one with the
therapy?
I had one on one with her.
We both saw her
individually and together and then after
a six months of therapy,
uh,
my wife,
when I thought things were starting to
get better because I was,
I was able to do things like go CD
shopping with Steve,
uh,
without getting,
without that being a huge fight when I
got home,
you know,
so that was like,
oh,
I'm a little bit of freedom here.
I can go out and hang out with,
hang out with my friends for a little
bit without there being a huge fight.
And uh,
but then she was diagnosed as having
borderline personality disorder.
They're not exactly mean.
And why is it borderline personality
disorder?
It's a misnomer.
Really don't like it.
They used to,
they used to think it was because it was
a condition that bordered on being
psychotic.
Um,
and now it's the,
that's they know,
that isn't the condition.
It's not anything to do with psychosis,
but the name has stuck.
The problem with my problem with the
name is when you say borderline
personality disorder,
do you have a fucking personality
disorder or not?
What is borderline?
You're kind of weird because in fact,
borderline's,
a lot of therapists don't even treat
them because they think they're just
impossible to treat and that they're
horrible people to deal with.
You know that they're incredibly
dishonest.
The pathological liars.
How do you define it though?
How can you define certain sets of
mental illness?
I mean,
do,
is it a judgment call?
There's like a,
was it the DSM?
Is that what it's called?
The diagnostic standards manual or
something like that.
And it's got like a checklist and if you
score a certain number on the checklist,
they go,
that's a diagnosis.
And I think,
uh,
she had like nine out of 10 on the
checklist for borderline.
Was she always this way or did she
change?
She was always that way.
She was out.
Yeah,
like basically as soon as we became a
couple,
like before we're couple,
she was my,
um,
before she did,
she was my best friend's girlfriend.
Oh Shit.
You know,
it's Karma son.
Yeah,
that's what happened.
You know,
you got hooked up with Karma and so,
so it was like one of those things where
like,
she break up with him first and then go
out with you.
Are you going to.
Oh No.
It was like one of those things where I
sort of said,
look,
I know we should stop hanging out so
much because um,
you know,
I was like feeling bad about it again.
I was like 20 years old and at that
point kind of lonely and desperate and
said,
look,
I've got these feelings and we should
stop hanging out together alone.
Really?
You actually said I have these feelings
and we should stop hanging out.
Yeah,
you guys would do the very few.
Yeah.
And her,
her reaction to that was the uh,
she just showed me her tits and started
kissing me.
So I was like,
oh,
all right.
Oh,
I tried.
You did give it your best.
So,
um,
so what happens?
Then you go to the buddy and go,
hey bro,
fuck your girlfriend again.
Well,
I tried to cool it,
tried to get out of it,
and I even was out of town for awhile
and tried to stay away from it.
But um,
you know,
he was probably like,
thank God,
thank God.
Yeah.
Well that's the thing is I didn't
realize at the time because I've gone
all right.
All right.
I thought things were okay with them
and,
and uh,
you know,
it,
it wasn't until she and I hooked up
like,
because again,
as soon as we hook,
because borderlines,
when they love you,
you're the most beautiful,
perfect thing in the world.
But then,
uh,
but then after that,
like if anything is wrong,
then you suddenly become the most evil,
dark,
horrible thing in the world and they
can't,
they can't see the two at the same time.
They can't see your flaws and your and
your virtues.
Wow.
I think I've dated somebody.
Every girl you like,
man,
I need to write this fucking guy.
He didn't even know he just got out of
relationship with a penthouse pet of the
year.
Oh,
real it.
It was wonderful for me.
It was like I had my own soap opera
going on,
but it was also just like this where,
where,
when Shit went down,
it was,
it was on or off,
it was no like shuts down.
Maybe we can work through that.
It was just,
that's one of the key signals of a
borderline,
uh,
is that,
that in the they say it's the inability
to recognize the good and bad in the
same person.
You know,
you can shift from being the most evil
person to the greatest person.
I A hundred percent.
Yeah.
So with my first wife before we were a
couple,
when it was just,
you know,
uh,
elicit,
you know,
when it was like this secret feelings,
uh,
you know,
a,
we were friends,
I was the greatest guy ever since she
made me feel like I was the greatest guy
on earth.
So you thought this is the perfect woman
for me,
even though she was with my friend,
you know,
to be there.
There they do.
Of course,
you know,
and then.
But as soon as we became a couple first
thing that like,
sex gone immediately and we didn't have
sex for 11 years,
we were together 11 years and we'd have
sex maybe once a year.
Oh my God.
How did you have two kids a once a year?
Well,
how really?
I have very motel sperm.
Um,
Holy Shit.
We had kids because she decided she
wanted to get pregnant.
And even at that point I thought,
oh,
well,
at least we'll get laid.
And uh,
but what were your friends while this
was all going on?
Well,
what,
uh,
men friends always do,
but depends on the men friends.
They never say anything.
They just sit there and quietly eight
and hate her.
Not Me,
man.
I've learned from the Phil Hartman.
Yeah.
Experience.
I tell people.
Yeah.
And whenever I think that my friends in
a bad situation,
I,
I'll,
I will pull them aside.
I've,
I've offered,
which is risk you should take for a
friend,
you know,
stay at my house.
Dunkin stayed at my house for a few
months after he got out.
You know,
you've got to tell people like,
Bro,
you're stuck and you think for some
reason or other,
this person is a part of your life.
They are not.
This is,
this is a show that you're tuning into
the you can shut off.
For me,
it was like this.
A lot of guilt about how we started the
course.
And then eventually,
eventually,
you know,
I'm going,
I'm almost as crazy as she is after 11
years of no fucking,
your brain doesn't function properly,
you know,
and it's also 11 years of like twice a
month.
Suicide threats,
you know,
God,
you know.
And then I got to the point where I was
so crazy.
I thought,
well,
at least if we have a kid,
you know,
if we have a kid,
she won't kill herself when I leave.
That's how crazy.
And literally within less than a month
after my son was born,
uh,
out of nowhere she goes,
you're not even thinking about it.
And I think if you left me,
even with a baby,
I would still kill myself.
Like so you could read my mind.
Whoa.
I've been thinking about it.
Holy Shit.
It was like,
oh,
really?
You make me feel better about myself,
Dave?
Some really eyeopening moments on that
set.
I learned so much about all sorts of
different types of relationships hanging
out with you guys.
Oh yeah.
Well everyone was pretty fucked up in
those marriages were in bad shape.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
The only one that wasn't.
Well,
I guess Andy Wasn't really married,
right?
Kids married wasn't even with.
I've forgotten her name now.
Lena.
Yes.
You're sort of married,
sort of whatever it was.
They might've jumped over a fucking
broom,
like unreads.
I don't know if it actually made it to
the courtroom and time to sign papers,
but yeah.
Well you know,
how many relationships are right?
Yeah,
you are together,
but I remember being startled when we
all came back from hiatus and the only
one who was divorced was a steve route,
but we thought you were happy.
I know he got fucked.
Hard
to.
Here's another one that I learned from
when Steve,
Steve,
his entire life as a working actor who's
a brilliant actor but had done like a
lot of very small things and never
gotten any notoriety until newsradio.
I mean he was really struggling.
I believe he said he had never made more
than 50 or $60,000
in an entire year ever before news
radio.
Then all of a sudden he does news radio
and he's making really good money and
then his wife gets a divorce and expects
to be paid for half the length of the
relationship,
the money he's making now,
so she just got instantly use like
within a couple months this new
lifestyle and he was giving her $10,000
a month and going fucking crazy.
You know,
I remember just seeing him just couldn't
really pay for,
you know,
lived in a small apartment,
was fucking struggling with trying to
put it together
at that time.
I was like,
when?
When I split up,
she was going through about 50 grand a
month and that was before we had.
That was before we had it like a
separation agreement.
Half a million a year.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
Running,
spending it.
And you have to make a million to spend
a half a million.
Yeah.
She's been so fun.
She was renovating the house constantly
to be heard.
To be heard though.
She rescate redlands had the backyard
landscape twice because she decided she
didn't like where the Koi pond was.
Oh my God.
You know,
that's ponds are pretty awesome.
No.
Yeah,
that's one thing I've always thought
about getting need.
That's nice.
You know,
like you can't really raise a child in a
healthy home without a collective.
That was at her argument,
their argument and it was all for the
kids.
Yeah.
The kids need a Koi pond.
Kids need to go to Morocco.
Yeah.
Worry about getting bitten by a
poisonous insects.
She turned like the third issue kept
renovating this house,
like least spent like another,
like a half a million dollars renovating
it,
fully renovated house.
It's just so straight.
I mean,
like I,
I'm married now and I think about the
legal ramifications of that and I do
have a prenuptial and all that stuff and
I,
and I absolutely think that marriage is
retarded.
I still think it's retarded,
but Mrs Rogan doesn't know and I love
her,
so I was willing to do it for because I
think it's crazy,
but got it everywhere around me is just
people with bullet holes in their heads
and then I'm saying I don't think I
should put this gun in my mouth.
Like,
trust me,
it'll be fine,
but it's just like,
I just see the remanence of,
of divorce everywhere is constantly.
The legal idea of it is just so it seems
so ridiculous that you would get two
people in a relationship and force them
either to be together or to distribute
money.
No,
it's fucking.
It's so crazy.
Yeah.
I'm terrified to get married just
because my own parents getting a divorce
and just stories like this.
It's like I'm scared as fuck my parents
not getting a divorce was equally
terrifying was.
Yeah.
You know,
but no,
it's true.
I mean,
I've been divorced twice now,
you know,
you went it on both ends,
right?
You went back into it after all that you
went back and.
Well,
you know,
motherfucker,
and again,
I didn't really,
it wasn't really.
I don't really believe in marriage
either,
but the US is not set up for you not to
be married if you're Canadian.
Uh,
or no.
Even I think even for Americans,
there's no,
like,
real civil union.
No,
no,
like,
you know.
Okay.
So you're worried about like if you had
to go to the hospital,
she couldn't come visit you.
That's actually seemed like she,
like she almost died in an emergency
ward wants and I couldn't get any
information about her and I couldn't see
her.
Um,
because you weren't married?
Yeah.
Oh fuck.
You know.
And as I,
after that,
in this country,
this country is weird,
but it's not weird because how would
they know if she's in a coma?
That you're not just some creepy fucked
up,
put her in a coma.
You know what I mean?
You could be some weird stalker.
I mean,
unless you're,
you're actually the husband that you're
the current boyfriend,
you could be the ex boyfriend and still
trying to get her back,
but you can see why in that
circumstance.
Why,
why if you're gay,
you're gay marriage,
not sure.
Not just some.
Something similar to get into marriage
and that's to me one of the most
fascinating arguments and immediately
labels you a retard in my book if you
think that it's a bad idea that gay
people shouldn't be married.
I think all marriage is a bad idea.
I agree with gay marriage is no worse
than straight marriage.
Like why would you not?
One people will start talking about
taxes and all I hear is I'm gay and I'm
hiding it or I'm scared of being gay or
I'm humbled that that's all I.
Yeah.
There's a couple of things that somehow
gay marriage is going to hurt their
marriage.
Yeah,
exactly.
You know that he has,
it's going to devalue like,
like you know,
like you're going to flood the market
with marriage.
It's not that Fox show who wants to
marry a millionaire or anything.
I mean,
come on.
Stories like this,
housewives of Beverly Hills,
you know,
if anything devalues marriage.
I mean fucking.
They had a reality show about flavor.
Flave getting married.
You know what I mean?
It wasn't,
you know,
nobody,
nobody protested.
This is devalued.
I'd show up at that rally.
There was two guys.
There's,
there's two guys that I know that live
in down the street and they're okay.
And they have kids.
They adopted it.
They actually didn't adopt a kid stop
combined their sperm together and hired
someone to carry their baby.
And the first woman changed her mind
right after they had paid for everything
and took care of her for nine months and
gave her a salary and the baby comes out
and she goes,
I think I'm going to keep it.
And they're like.
And like they,
they had spent like hundreds of
thousands of dollars.
They had given her a salary for the
entire year and then they had spent all
this money in medical procedures and
taken care of all of her medical bills
and all that stuff.
And then at the end she's like,
psych.
It's,
my kid just took it.
And so they went through the whole
process again and then had a kid,
so there wasn't any kind of like court
thing they could've done or contracts or
nothing you can do.
It's her baby.
It comes out of her body.
You can't take her baby,
you cannot tell.
But there should be like,
hey,
we're giving you this.
Money shouldn't be really.
You don't have to pay it back and the
sperm and there shouldn't be,
you know,
it's,
it's.
I think what she did was,
you know,
I mean probably deceptive maybe,
but who knows,
maybe she just changed her mind.
She was overwhelmed by emotions and
couldn't believe that the idea that
she's going to leave this kid behind in
the world and just go about it.
You wouldn't be able to deal with it.
I see her point of view more than I see
their point of view.
Definitely did was shoot a load and a
spend some money and you have a baby.
It's.
Yeah.
What ultimately when it comes down to
it,
if you can't say goodbye to that baby,
you can't say goodbye to me.
To me,
seeing my wife have kids,
seeing the baby come out of her body
being there,
the moment the baby's born,
seeing the bond,
seeing this,
this,
this moment.
Fuck man.
You can't take the baby away.
The baby has to be in trouble.
If you'd take the baby away,
it has to be some crazy math head or a
bad person.
I mean that's the only way she'd take
her baby away and it's like,
this is our nature bond.
That's a soul stealing bond.
I have a buddy and his ex girlfriend was
a.
She was a stripper when she was 16.
She had a baby and gave it up for
prostitutes or for adoption rather for
prostitution and can you do that?
You decide so early in Taiwan,
you can find them nice pimp and she was.
This poor girl was wrecked for the rest
of her life.
She was devastated.
Whenever she would drink,
whenever she would be out,
she would just think about that baby
that she had when she was 16.
Now that it's out there in the world and
that she's the mother and she just has
this hole in her soul forever and she
couldn't make up no matter what she did,
she couldn't fill it up with drugs.
She couldn't fill it out with Dick.
She couldn't figure out.
She couldn't fill it up.
It just as a whole that.
And so these poor guys down the street,
you know,
they,
they spent the money but they have
money.
They're going to be fun.
You know,
they got ripped off.
No big deal.
Yeah.
They,
they now they have a kid.
It's really fascinating though because
the kid is starting to get a little
older now.
He's like four or five,
you know,
and now when I see him he's trying to
go,
where the fuck is my mother?
Everybody else has a lady around them,
these two dudes all the time.
So I'm sure it's pretty weird for him.
And why is everything so tiny?
It's fashion sense.
I mean what happens with gay guys when
they get divorced?
How does that work?
I mean,
how do you decide who's the wife,
you know,
is it,
is it who's working and who's not,
which ones would you want to,
but as tight in the bud is tighter or
looser?
That never understood the whole top and
bottom thing that I was gay.
I would just,
I would be versatile.
Move it around.
Do you not,
you know,
give and receive it and I don't
understand that.
How rude.
Well,
I think some gay guys liked the rude
guys though,
because we just want to shut up,
get smacked him in the face,
then run out the door and that's what
they're looking for.
They're looking for some weird,
abusive sort of a situation.
I just can't.
I just can't understand me.
The,
the other,
the guy that does the abusive.
Do you know anybody that's a guy that's
getting alimony?
I'm Liz and Maura Pang issue.
I think so.
Really still.
I don't know.
Maybe that was,
that was a crazy situation to more.
I can't be on the podcast and tell us
about it.
She would,
she'd probably wouldn't give it up.
It's a crazy story,
unfortunately.
You're fucked folks.
Yeah.
Um,
yeah,
I know one dude,
I know one dude who married a model and
he was a loser and he was an actor and
she's a very famous model and she's
still paying them and they have kids
together as well and she still has to
pay him.
Sounds Nice.
I never thought about that.
Am I am?
I try to do that.
Sam Arnold.
Tom Arnold got paid a fuckload of money
with a Kirstie alley.
Didn't she pay out?
Did she divorced?
Ditching young skippy.
Yeah,
because she was married to.
What's his name?
Parker Stevenson,
right?
Wasn't he the guy from the hardy boys
when it wasn't cassidy?
Right.
What happened to that guy like Joey
Lawrence right now?
You know that guy that plays cds again?
Fucking completely vanished.
Yeah,
I forgot he even existed until you just
said his name.
Yeah.
Like I might not have thought about him
in 10 years or wherever.
Again,
happens to dudes like that,
that act for a long time and then they
just stop and vanish.
I don't know,
I just keep wondering if it's happened
to me yet in everything.
What?
One of my favorite video games fall out,
like,
oh yeah,
I keep hearing about that.
Been such an awesome game.
I haven't played because I don't play
any video games because I don't know how
well for the longest time you did the
poker show.
Yeah.
And so after news radio,
what did you do after news radio?
Did you try to develop something else?
Had like three or four development deals
after that wrote about.
I wrote like about five pilots for
different networks in different studios
and none of them sold.
And that was it then?
Yeah.
Then it was doing a bunch of movies.
Brain candy.
Yeah.
What brain candy,
your shot while we were doing his radio
is another lesson I learned that I have
to remember before I forget,
um,
that I learned about the movie business.
Dave had a fucking great movie called
the wrong guy.
Yeah.
And it was a great movie and we went to
see it.
I think Brian Callum went to say it with
me and we were fucking howling and I was
like,
Holy Shit,
David's going to be a huge movie star.
There's going to be a huge movie and I
remember watching it going like,
this is one of the best comedies I've
seen in years and then nothing.
Yeah,
Disney shelved it.
Yeah.
Well what happened was how Hollywood
pictures was our distributor at Disney
and they shut Hollywood pictures down in
the middle of production and then when
we're done,
they reopened Hollywood pictures but
with the new president of Hollywood
pictures and he didn't want to touch any
of this stuff that the other guy had
started a like that because if it's
there,
if it's a failure,
it's their failure.
But if it's a success,
it's the other guy success.
So they just don't deal with it.
So they uh,
so it got shelved for like five years.
Like they would even admit they hand it.
So it never had a theatrical release.
Never got theatrical release.
So it's available on DVD,
right?
Can't get it on Amazon.com.
$10 on Amazon right now.
Really?
Well then the people should probably
pick that up.
Yeah,
I'm going to pick it up right now.
What's one click while we're doing the
podcast?
So far that it's actually what I'm.
One of the things I'm proudest of is
that movie,
like creatively comedically.
It was brilliant,
you know,
it was eric goes,
watch this one click.
Oh Don.
It's that easy.
People love Amazon dogs.
Yeah.
That was a brilliant fucking movie.
Was really fun.
I enjoyed the shit out of it and I
remember you guys all coming out to see
it that,
that screening and yeah.
Yeah.
And I remember thinking after is over
after the whole thing where it didn't
work out and it never got.
I'm like,
wow,
well this is,
this business is crazy.
Like this doesn't make any sense.
I know because we really thought we were
clear because we had,
you know,
the big thing was always,
well if you're doing an independent
film,
can you get distribution?
And we went into it with distribution.
We had Disney lined up in the script
phase,
you know,
uh,
so we had distribution lined up.
We had,
we even had a,
we were even in profit in foreign sales
while we were shooting the movie based
on a trailer.
Whoa.
That was taken to can.
So,
uh,
we had,
we had advanced sales,
foreign sales that put the movie in
profit while we were shooting,
but they were all contingent on a US
release.
It seems like you could get a meeting
and talk to the new head and go retail.
We tried it for years.
Thank you.
Will make a big deal.
We'll do press releases and we tried
talking to Disney for a year and they
just wouldn't have anything to do with
now.
Wow.
Other,
there were other people even tried to
buy it from Disney and they wouldn't
sell it.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
Because of the success then they fucked
up.
Yeah.
Wow.
What a creepy fucking business.
You wonder why Dave Chappelle went to
Africa.
Yeah.
Well,
and it's beautiful.
There it is.
Beautiful.
And especially if you can get away from
the hippos.
The flies are nice.
So,
um,
so now you're divorced twice.
Yeah.
And thank God my second ex wife is sane
and decent.
She was very nice person.
I met her a couple times.
I met her at a fucking,
a satanic ritual on,
on,
uh Oh,
I wasn't there for that.
Yeah,
that was that.
It was some six,
six,
six show.
Yeah,
it was the birthday of a famous
satanist.
Levay Danzig was there,
Duncan did performed with a satanic
puppet.
Our friend Duncan,
and your wife was there as like some
devil woman dressed up doing some
singing backup or something crazy.
Yeah.
And Hank Williams,
the third was there.
That was a great show man.
Watch and Hank Williams and Danzig
together hanging backstage and like I'm
hanging out with Danzig.
Right.
Very weird.
Yeah,
that was a fun.
That was a fun Gig.
Yeah,
it was weird.
We were really hammered around a really
high rather around a bunch of fucking
satanist.
Yeah.
Very,
very odd.
That was a weird phase that Duncan,
our friend Doug and went through
[inaudible] for a while.
He was taking me to like graveyards to
like hang out with that Antwan,
the guy doing all.
Yeah,
I'd go to these people's houses and they
would have like a,
you know,
like the dolls with like the whatever.
We put needles in them and stuff and I'm
like,
I,
I was really kind of getting it for
awhile.
It was like,
oh,
I get it now.
It's kind of,
they're doing it
almost as a joke.
Almost like,
you know,
that will be.
Dunkin was about Dunkin was.
Yeah.
But it will satanism to a lot of people
is just a hedonism.
It's just living life and with pleasure
and enjoying all the jelly and against
Christian morality.
Yeah.
I mean it's not really like sacrificing
babies are killing goats or anything
stupid like that.
Yeah.
So do you have to say,
well this is why I brought this up.
So,
uh,
I ran into you on twitter.
I saw you on twitter and one of the
first things I saw you on twitter was
you talking about how you had just
gotten a,
the court had just told you you have to
pay three times your monthly salary in
alimony.
Yeah.
And I guess two time slept,
but I would say is an average because a
lot of months I don't have a salary.
Uh,
no.
Yeah,
they had a,
I have to pay $17,700
a month or go to jail for 10 days every
month that I'm late without warning that
that was the judge's ruling jail for 10
days.
So do you have to bit be exported to
Canada as well?
That's the thing.
I'm here.
So do you know say fuck you.
I live here now and to stay here,
but I,
yeah,
I can't risk going back to Canada or she
will go to jail.
Yeah.
Whoa.
So unless I've come up with $17,700,
which in a month where I haven't earned
anything is a little hard to do man.
So how much are you sending over there?
Are you trying to like whatever.
I'm like yeah,
like I said,
five grand this past month in addition
go crazy.
Twenty grand a few in November to she'd
go crazy and yell at you like you need
more and she hasn't talked to me
directly,
you know,
really sold through lawyers.
But again,
they were trying,
uh,
through this organization called the fro
the family responsibility office in
Ontario that,
and this,
this legal office is really responsible
for handing a lot of men to their death.
Like there's a real problem with like
people committing suicide,
um,
after being prosecuted by these people.
And uh,
they,
uh,
they were trying to get me like in
November,
I was sitting in a court in like
November 20th,
I guess,
sitting in court and thinking at the end
of that day,
I might go to jail for six months.
They were,
they were pushing for me to go to jail
for six months.
This is what the fro was asking,
six month jail sentence if I didn't come
up with half a million dollars that day,
um,
and an additional 30 days for every
month.
I didn't come up with the money.
Oh my God.
So,
and I was saying they're going,
well,
the judge,
if he goes for it,
I in jail for life,
they'll cuff me there that day,
take me to jail and I'll go to jail for
six months.
The end of six months they'll say,
you know,
we'll do you have the half million
dollars and plus the ongoing money that
would accrue over the six months.
And I'd say,
no,
I'd been in jail for six months.
I was,
I supposed to earn any money.
All right.
That's another 30 days to end of that.
Thirty days you get the money.
No,
I've been in jail.
So it's essentially a life sentence.
Unless someone gives $500,000.
Yeah.
How long,
how long,
how much longer do you have for this?
Uh,
well it's really,
it's unending until I pay off the
arrears,
that io or you know,
and that's crazy one then till the kids
are a 22,
if they stay in school so,
and the skin.
And so then the money just keeps adding
up and my dick off tonight.
Yeah.
Like,
I mean,
don't know,
just don't marry Canadian shirk.
Yeah.
I mean in order to pay $17,700,
I have to earn about $40,000
in a month just to pay that.
Just,
you know,
with 20 percent commission,
35 percent tax bracket.
Um,
you know,
so I've got to earn $40,000
just to have $0.
Fuck.
And it's someone you hate.
Yeah.
And who didn't fuck me for 11 years
raising ass laws.
And then when you tell them that you
don't make that much money anymore,
what do they call the judge
pat who made this ruling because they
were asking for the six months.
Right.
And the judge kept saying to the fro
attorney,
uh,
you know,
give me another option because I'm
looking at,
I'm looking at the,
the,
the financial documents and I'm seeing
where all the money,
all the money that has come in,
I'm seeing where it's all gone.
It's all here in this documents,
all the money that's come in and where
it's all gone.
I can see it all in these documents.
So I am convinced that there isn't a
half a million dollars from Mr Foley to
come up with today.
So if you insist on that ruling,
then I would send them to jail and your
client will never see another dime
because Mr Foley's career will be over.
And that's it.
And he kept saying,
give me an option that will get your
client some money.
And the effort refused to say,
well,
we don't have the authority from our
client,
my ex wife,
to make any other offer.
Um,
so for about two hours,
the judge kept asking them to come up
with another.
So all this time when you're sitting
there,
you're going,
I'm going to jail.
Yeah.
And I might be going to jail essentially
forever.
Yeah.
What happened?
Going to jail for being,
for the crime of not earning a million
dollars.
Oh my God.
So what happens if that actually does
happen?
I mean,
if you have guys gone in jail with a
large sum like that and never come out,
I don't know,
but people have definitely gone to jail.
And,
and definitely there's a lot of people
who had been looking at jail time have
just killed themselves.
Uh,
can,
can you get the kids and then have to
stay with it
so that she has the town one bro.
It's alimony or child support.
So child support.
This is all child support.
Yeah.
So whoa.
$70,000
a month in child support.
Yeah,
still the kids.
What the fuck are your kids eating?
A $17,000
iphone or eating iphones.
It's incredible.
Yeah.
17,
$17,700
a month.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
I would.
I would talk to the and be like,
Hey,
come live
with me.
We'll have a TV show together.
I'll get you a podcast and somehow turn
the tables.
Well,
yeah,
I mean get a horse.
I mean get a couple of things about
being on the real house.
Husbands of Beverly Hills.
I'm thinking we can get a reality show
off the ground.
What are you willing to marry?
A Kardashians?
A.
Oh my God.
I've look.
Hey,
I can't marry worse than I have because
they'd probably be a lot better.
Yeah,
crazy.
They're just ambitious.
Yeah.
Fuck man.
So what's the solution?
So you cannot go to Canada and you just
send whatever you have and then you have
to constantly deal with legal payments
because they're constantly trying to
fuck you.
And so I spent like a year and a half
literally going to court every single
month with lawyers.
Just basically having to go to court
every month just to stay out of jail to
go and have them put it over to the next
month.
And the lawyers,
the lawyers,
you know,
I mean the,
people that do family law,
a lot of them are really horrible
people.
Uh,
and they just make money off misery.
And even my own lawyers,
we're just,
you know,
extending this as far as they could
until I ran out of money and like,
and then quit.
So when I went to court for this ruling,
I didn't have,
I didn't have a lawyer because I
couldn't afford one.
So you went by yourself,
was there by myself.
Not only was out there by myself,
but all of the documents that had been
piled up,
all of the evidence that have been
bottled up over the course of a year and
a half sitting in my lawyers office.
Oh my God.
You know.
So you had no evidence and no lawyer.
Yeah.
Did you have records?
Did you have any side?
Nothing.
I had nothing.
God.
So you're just going to there nothing.
I have no money.
I just saw I didn't do.
Yeah,
and they're asking me questions about
files that had been piling up over a
year and a half,
but I don't know.
I don't recall.
I don't know because I don't,
you know,
how do they justify such an exorbitant
amount of money because it's the,
the,
as it was explained to me by my lawyers
was that the courts have a assumption is
that the children should continue to
live at the level they were at,
at the time of the dissolution of the
marriage.
So,
which is crazy because if I were still
married in my income,
dropped their lifestyle would change.
But because we're not married anymore,
their lifestyles should never change no
matter what I'm earning.
Was that the judge,
the ruling that was enforced was by
another judge named judge justice back
outs.
And she's the one who ruled about three,
four years ago when I went back to try
and get it adjusted.
I went to,
um,
to,
uh,
have to have a hearing to have it
adjusted to meet my income.
Um,
and she ruled against me and in her
ruling she said my ability to pay was
not relevant to my obligation.
So it didn't matter to her what I proved
my income to be if my income was zero,
she said I was still obligated to pay as
though I was earning a million dollars.
I know a lot of people saying,
Joe Rogan this day,
fully guy's bothering me the fuck out.
I feel like,
well listen,
this is important shit.
This was my education in,
in relationships.
And then the law regarding relationships
as I was growing up,
literally.
I mean when I was on news radio is a
fresh face boy,
didn't know Jack Shit about the world.
And this is how I learned about
relationships.
This is how I learned about the whole
gamut from divorce to fucking murder
suicide.
And I learned it all.
You are happily married.
Yeah.
Crazy.
What?
You figured it out.
Who?
I'm kind of lucky.
I got lucky.
Could go ugly for me to it.
I would do in your podcast.
I wouldn't probably seriously just move
somewhere like live on a beach in
Jamaica.
He loves his kids.
You get to see your kids.
Not now.
I can't go to Canada so they can't see.
So you don't see him at all?
Was the last time you saw them?
Uh,
was in uh,
November.
Wow.
That would drive me nuts to my size.
Went to see my,
my sons play at school.
It was less than my son.
Was the trick there,
the wife?
No,
she wasn't there.
Thank God.
So you have no communication with her at
all?
No,
no,
no.
You don't have to pay any more alimony?
No,
she didn't seek alimony.
She sought a shout for it because.
Yeah.
But it's none of it got to the kids,
you know,
it all goes to her.
Yeah.
She was getting all this money and then
on top of the child support payment,
which is,
she was also getting something called
section seven expenses,
but just basically anything she chose to
any bills she chose to run up what you
know.
So it'd be like $20,000
for summer camp,
things like that.
Anything that was for the kids that she
chose?
Yeah.
So not just alimony.
Not or not just child support,
child support plus and then all of her
living expenses and the mortgage and
everything,
medical expenses,
everything.
It just makes me,
it's,
it should make you sick.
It's so strange and I don't know if
there's a way around it.
I don't know how to fix it,
but it certainly should not apply to
something as,
as crazy and transient as a Hollywood
job.
The,
the,
the greatest job ever a sitcom job
because those only last a few years and
you usually get one of them your whole
life,
you know,
I mean,
it's rare as fuck how I know.
I mean in the Stephen Root situation was
the same situation.
I mean he just,
he got fucked based on the fact that
that's when he was making the most money
and that's when she decided to get and
was good.
Yeah.
Letting the old assumption that know
it's based on an assumption that's 50
years old,
that women can't take care of
themselves.
They can't,
you know,
it's true.
You know,
they can't.
Alright,
right.
Just pray.
Just pray for breast cancer or not
uncovering this in my standup,
but humorously.
Wow.
Good luck with that.
Yeah,
I mean I think it's much more difficult
for women to take care of themselves,
especially women who have children.
Fucking hardest shit,
man.
How raising kids,
you know,
people that don't think that it's our
job to raise kids.
You never tried to raise kids,
you don't know what you're talking
about.
But I,
I am amazed lot so many people think
that it's okay or that it's no big deal
to have a full time job and have
children.
Like I have a friend of mine who's 36
who's still wanting to have kids and
she's,
you know,
thinking that it's not going to
interrupt her job and I'm like,
you work eight,
10 hours a day,
you're fucking crazy.
You're going to have a new human being.
And she's talking this craziness about
childcare.
I'm like,
listen,
it's an immense,
immense amount of work beyond your
comprehension and it'll specially if
you're traveling through Italy or Africa
with just the one nanny,
just one nanny.
Wow.
How could you do that?
I don't know.
She's roughing it.
Wow.
So I don't mean to bum anybody out and
I'm sorry they already went.
So in depth about the.
Set it down.
Yeah.
No,
we're not going to live and we don't
edit it.
You know,
everyone just go by kids in the hall and
DVD support Dave shows.
Does that money go to you?
A small percentage.
What about the wrong guy?
Because I go to you really well.
Yeah.
Almost nothing.
Almost.
No,
I think I just gave you almost nothing.
There you go.
Yeah.
Well almost like that rarely ever sells
a copy.
So.
So tell me this,
how did you go from doing news radio and
you had a bunch of pilots that didn't
take off?
Well,
how the fuck does that?
Not How do you not wind up on something
else?
How does that not happen?
I don't know.
I did,
I,
you know,
I was in a bunch of pilots,
other people's pilots that I didn't
write a and none of those trailers when,
um,
and then,
uh,
you know,
then I also like was,
it was the judge on a thank God you're
here with an MBC,
which would've been a good money gig.
What does that,
it was an Improv show based on
Australian Improv show.
Oh,
did like seven episodes on,
on NBC.
But then it got canceled.
This was like during the writers strike.
Um,
so,
you know,
Oh yeah,
I remember that,
you know,
and you know,
and then they're just becomes,
you know,
the industry is all about perception
than the perception is just,
Oh,
well,
he's cold.
Ugh.
You know,
how weird is that?
I don't know.
I kind of thought there would be a
problem.
I mean,
I remember talking to Vicky and saying
like,
when news,
I kept saying when,
well,
when news radio gets canceled,
I said I'll probably be the hardest for
me to get work of anyone else.
Well,
I just think that because I was a first
in the credits and the show was never a
hit.
Oh,
that's interesting.
So that's how they do that.
Yeah.
So everyone else was a supporting player
on a critically acclaimed show.
Um,
but I was the,
you know,
supposedly the lead character on a show
that wasn't a hit.
So it'd be,
well he couldn't carry a show.
Wow.
What a weird,
weird to look at it.
People don't know.
A lot of people that don't even realize
news radio wasn't a hit,
but while we were on the air,
we were on the air.
We moved nine times,
nine times over the course of five
seasons and
the guy had the head of programming at,
at,
at a scheduling at NBC.
Hated us.
Why was that?
I don't know.
Remember,
there was that whole thing with,
uh,
the rolling stone article.
Yes.
But that was when we were already
floundering.
Yeah.
But it was also.
But the guy,
this guy,
uh,
but we should tell people what that
means.
What's the rolling?
The rolling start.
Paul Stanley or Paul Stanley Kiss Paul
Simms,
who was the creator,
the show called NBC Thursday night
lineup,
which was their big friends lineup.
They called it a shit sandwich.
He called it.
It was really,
it should have been shit was the button
because they're real sandwich was
friends and then you would have friends
on and then you would have this terrible
show.
No,
it was always on after France.
And uh,
you know,
obviously NBC was very upset that Paul
was calling sex in the city or the
single guy to pieces of shit,
but you know,
they were,
they were terrible shows and then
friends was brilliant show that
everybody tuned into.
So they sort of watch those other shows
just because they were on.
But I guess it got it.
Got Guy gets named Preston Beckmann
hated our show.
Even when we did the pilot,
he didn't want to pick it up really
because we were originally supposed to
get it Thursday slot ourselves.
But this guy who was in charge of the
MVC schedule wouldn't let us have it
Thursday slot.
So then he basically kept trying to find
a slot that would kill us,
so that's why they put us on a.
We are the lead leading,
we're,
we're on with wings and fraser a frazier
and those shows were both doing poorly
when we came along and he put us on with
those shows and we our show,
we boosted the ratings of both shows.
Well all of a sudden it became like a
decent lineup for,
for comedies,
but it was a different time than men.
There was no dvrs shows,
couldn't exist in a,
in a non popular spot.
It had to be a spot where people are
already looking.
Well,
the ratings we were getting in those,
we're getting like 10 million people
tuning in and those ratings in those
days were considered a ratings failure.
Like today,
if you got those ratings here,
the number one show on TV.
Yeah,
it's weird.
There's so many channels now.
At one point in time,
uh,
Lou Martin used to show up at our
writer's meetings at the,
rather at the run the table read was t
with a shirt on with a number of
whatever we were in,
what place we are in and he showed up
and it was 84.
Yes,
we're an 84th place.
And we were like,
what was it,
84,
88.
That's when,
when they finally,
when they put us up against drew Carey,
and then we had Warren littlefield
actually came down to a table read to
let us know that they still loved us.
They surfaced Turkey dinner.
You never learn a warrant like there was
there carving Turkey and Warren
Littlefield,
whatever.
It was a nice guy.
Network head.
Yeah.
He was very nice.
This,
I always remember a 95 Warren
littlefield dancing on the bar in New
York at when we went for the upfronts
and it was like Jay Leno had had just
hit number was the number one late night
show.
Wow.
And I'm more.
Warren was standing on this bar doing
shots and shouting night.
Oh Wow.
That's hilarious.
Was that the one where,
which one did you guys get drunk at?
I didn't go to every event,
but we got kicked out where we weren't
allowed to go.
Was it the SAG awards?
Yeah,
these motherfuckers got so hammered.
They caused so much damage at the sag
awards.
We couldn't go anymore.
We weren't allowed to go.
I've still never been back.
Here's a great one.
We were at the Emmy's and this is after
Phil had been murdered and we're sitting
there and you know,
Phil was nominated for something and uh,
the denominations go and I think the guy
from Frasier,
God,
David Hyde Pierce and Dave turns to me
and goes,
what does Phil have to do to win?
Oh No.
You know,
it was so weird.
It was David.
David Hyde Pierce looks so embarrassed
to be winning.
He was literally up there like,
is all the blood drained out of his
face?
He was just going,
well,
obviously I'm Phil Hartman.
You know,
he didn't,
he couldn't even put a sentence
together.
He was,
yeah.
I wonder what the choice behind that
was.
That was weird.
You know,
don't,
don't kill someone.
And then expect them to win sort of
messages.
You're sending out two murders.
It's cheating,
being murdered as a cheat.
Oh,
what a strange,
strange times.
So what did you guys do at the Sag
Awards?
That got us kicked out forever?
No,
I think,
uh,
most,
at the time,
I guess because we all thought what a
stupid award show,
you know,
this is the first year of the SAG
awards.
Let me say this is ridiculous.
Why actors voting about each other and
giving awards,
those saying who's best,
that's the,
you know,
our union is deciding who is best and it
creates this weird,
this culture of ass kissing and fakery
yeah,
they're all like,
what a wonderful project.
Amazing.
And I think what we do,
I think Maura and I found where the,
uh,
the,
the service bar was a,
have had like the big industrial
corkscrew and everything.
So we've said we're going back there,
just opening up bottles of wine and
bringing them up to the table and I
think,
you know,
and then we had andy with this to a
which was.
So who did want to be doing anything
notable that got us kicked out?
Uh,
I don't really remember.
I think we were just noisy and rude and
stealing.
We were applauding inappropriately.
Like,
oh,
well,
you know,
there was no malaria medicine back then
was there,
drink the malaria medicine.
When he took a reporters over,
the reporter came up to him with a tape
recorder and ask them some questions.
Dave took his microphone,
stuck it in his drink and then pushed
him and that's when we realized like
Dave was off the tracks together,
the woods,
it wasn't dave anymore.
And then Dave was fucking screaming at
this Tony Guy,
you're fucking up my show and my fucking
people.
I fucking work.
And I'm like,
oh my God,
I think Dave's going to hit him.
And I had to get in between them.
I had a,
I had a corner him at a bar.
Like physically,
I had a physically cornered dave to keep
him from attacking this other guy.
Yeah,
but we were always the ones to last to
leave the bar.
The news radio crew was always last to
Yeah.
I think we had this idea.
We felt like we were like the punks of
prime time comedy.
We were the least bullshitty of that,
you know,
there's this whole culture,
this actor,
and it's one of the reasons why I was
willing to do newsradio afterwards,
like the thought of working with actual
actors for five years.
It's like somehow or another I had
managed to see the worst case scenario
with this hardball and then slip into
the best case scenario for five years
and news radio and then it was like
auditions and being around real actors
again.
I'm like,
fuck this man.
What are the other Shit I can do?
And he's really.
It was a casper.
You regularly hear people say,
you know what?
My joke doesn't work.
We should cut my joke that his joke is
the better joke.
Yes.
All the time.
Know it was really an amazing
environment and you would also hear,
don't put that pencil in my current
things like that.
I mean to say the most fucked up shit
ever.
I mean,
if we were,
do you remember the time we had to.
We actually had to sit down and we,
they played that presentation for us,
all of the,
uh,
the sex,
sexual harassment.
Oh,
I felt so badly for that person.
You don't know.
You don't know the group of people
you've just walked in front of it was so
ridiculous.
They have to go over this whole thing of
what's appropriate and what's not
appropriate.
And yeah,
it would have meant basically what it
cut down about 98 percent of all
conversation on our set.
I mean,
we all just sort of a,
you know,
just made an agreement that we wouldn't
see each other.
Like,
okay,
this doesn't,
this doesn't apply.
Right.
But if anybody wanted to.
I mean,
there's been many times on sets where,
uh,
you know,
especially a women actresses feel like
there's too much of that shit going on
and they just fucking fuck this.
I'm getting a lawyer and then there's
payouts,
man.
It becomes like a big issue and you make
a lot of money.
I know because every like you'd have
andy.
Andy will be sitting there and they got
us on a step.
Your pussy leaves the way Vicky wouldn't
be.
Vicky would be laughing.
I remember the very first time I met
Andy and again I'd been acting for a
fucking month.
Right?
I'd done a new,
a new.
No one liked that.
I knew up with fighters and pool
hustlers.
The.
Those are the two worlds that I was most
entrenched in and crazy.
Standup comedians.
They're all nuts.
Right?
And then all of a sudden I'm in this,
this dressing room with Andy and Andy is
sitting cross legged and he has clogs
on,
okay,
and he's got these weird brown corduroy
pants and he's flipping his foot back
and forth.
He goes,
do you think you're going to be famous?
I don't know.
What do you think?
Oh yes,
I know I'm going to be.
Now.
I'm going to be.
I've already decided I'm going to be so
famous.
I can't wait.
I can't wait to be really,
really famous.
Do you think this is gonna be the show
for you or maybe not?
I don't know,
man.
I don't know.
You're gonna be famous.
Oh,
absolutely.
So yeah,
I think it's already happening.
Yeah.
I think the arc of your friendship with
Andy was the most interesting of the
whole cast.
I'd only wish I hadn't marijuana back
then.
Yeah.
I would've found him so much more
fascinating because I had testosterone
and adrenaline and that was just
everyday was just don't kill Andi.
Don't,
don't fucking kill him because he was
just so out of control.
I've never
met someone so out of control,
but on set.
Nobody enjoyed andy more than you did.
I loved him,
like doing scenes like joe had so a show
getting through scenes with him because
they would laugh.
They would bust you up constantly.
He's hilarious.
He's one of the funniest human beings
I've ever met in my life.
Yeah.
There's only been.
There's been a few human beings that
I've ever met in my life where I was
like,
wow,
what a fucking original.
Yeah.
Joey Diaz is one of them and Andy Dick
is one of them don't always funnier than
Andy,
but he's a standup but Andy fucking
Christ,
he was funny and there's no doubt he's
talented is so weird,
but it needs to be handled.
Andy's one of those guys that needs a
Paul Simms and crew behind him,
right for them and you put them in the
end and he's Goddamn gold and after that
was over,
I was like,
I was no one grabbing him and doing
another one of these.
Instead he went and done did that MTV
show,
which was so bizarre for few years on a.
was it less than perfect or wasn't used
on that front?
I hadn't met even been as long as news
radio.
Now he's like living in a garage
somewhere.
It's not on his own property was ex
wives.
I heard a story about him the other day
where he went to like my friend lives in
this apartment building where it's just
like,
you know,
like the courtyards in the middle and
they heard all these people yelling at
like 1:00
AM.
They look outside and I guess Andy was
just like screaming like I need a beer
and some guy upstairs is like,
hey,
are you Andy Dick?
And then he was like,
yeah.
And he's like,
we got beer up here man.
And say he just came up there and party
until like 4:00
AM with these strangers in this
apartment.
So it sounds like an ending.
I got a text recently,
I was like asleep.
Thank God.
And then I woke up and I just got this
text from a friend said that Andy was in
the bar downstairs from where my
apartment is,
just said,
Andy Dick is here and he's making a
complete ass of himself.
And he had,
he was like running through the
restaurant.
He was like grabbing the waitresses tits
and he was like a go,
like stealing food off people's plates.
And a one point he apparently he crawled
under all the tables and was knocking
tables over and then he went into the
kitchen and tried to make out with uh,
you know,
the dishwasher,
how is he in jail?
Yeah,
how has it been?
Rested?
A lot.
But I do a joke about it in my act
because it's so ridiculous.
People go,
keep believe Andy did get arrested.
I'm like,
I can't believe he doesn't get a
resident every day a day that goes by
where he's not arrested in like you
could have a TV show called let's get
any dick arrested and this is what it
would be just everyday you show up
because he is committing a felony
everyday.
Probably poor fucking guy.
But you know,
he needs to be handled.
But even if he's handled,
he's going to go out of control now.
I mean that that's again,
I think news radio is such a good place
for him because none of us really would
take any shit from him that yes.
And also because he never became famous
from that show.
Yeah.
It was always floundering and it never
really became a hit after it was in
syndication.
That's when it began.
But there were some moments,
there were some moments where Andy tried
to get crazy,
you know,
and especially,
he would try not to pay attention or try
to,
you know,
force extra attention on himself or
still delaying things are fucking up
rehearsals or card game to show up on
this.
His son on the set when he left,
drove home and forgot his fucking kid.
It sent this comedy now,
right?
Yeah.
Look,
I think I saw him the other day at an
open mic or give the poor kid a hug.
Yeah.
I got some,
actually did improv with Andy at Improv
Olympic io io.
They call an outback was back when he
had the ankle bracelet on.
So he was sober and he was like,
I,
you know,
it's like,
it's gone.
Wow.
It's weird.
Andy,
I don't know.
It's weird to be around you when you're
now when he's not fucked up.
Yeah.
Last time I saw him,
he was sober.
He came up to the company or to the
Improv rather?
Yeah.
Took a picture of him.
I wasn't really.
I've always said with any of those,
and I never really understood why he
needs so much drugs and booze because I
don't know what inhibitions he's trying
to release was.
That's not what it is.
He's trying to quell the demons of his
past memories.
And,
and I had a long conversation about,
uh,
once we told me he doesn't remember
anything from age,
like eight or nine on anything earlier
than that.
He doesn't remember it.
He doesn't,
he literally doesn't remember his
childhood,
his,
no recollection because it was horribly
traumatic.
He doesn't know his parents.
I mean,
he,
I think he met them after he became
famous.
Yeah,
he's been in the last few years.
It was ugly.
Whatever the fuck happened to him,
you're not going to get the street
straight story from him,
but you don't make an Andy Dick with
love and attention and you know,
you only make one of those fucking
horrible amounts of neglect.
Yeah.
Unfortunately it was an evil Japan,
Andy Dick.
But it's funny how it works that way
when you have to have some sort of a
fucked up life to,
to make a really,
truly brilliantly funny person.
And like everyone that I know Joe was
going to say,
I usually say that the,
the,
the childhood background for Comedians
is basically the same as porn stars
because it is convenience.
Don't usually have the abs for porn.
You of course go against that.
The rule.
I fuck up the whole room.
So you could do porn you've wanted to to
that.
Yeah.
Back when there was money and then I
thought about it.
Yeah.
I know.
Announcer,
discipline my way out of Hollywood.
Fucking do a porno and make millions.
Yeah.
So you have thought about directing
porn.
Really have it?
Yeah.
Do you remember the guy on news radio?
Um,
I do not remember his name,
but he was a writer that also wrote for
porn.
Do you know,
season one because I was living in north
Hollywood at the time and um,
he took me to a set and it was a telling
you,
Kelly and Jeanine.
Yeah.
We went to a,
a lesbian shoot.
And it was back in the vivid days when
they were making a ton of money because
they were selling vhs tapes.
Okay.
They weren't even selling dvds back
then.
It was [inaudible] 94.
Right.
So we went to the set and it was so
oddly clinical and weird.
And the girl Janine,
who wound up marrying Jesse James and
having kids with them.
That was a woman and she'd kept going,
I love my job.
Her job was in eating pussy.
It was just so weird.
No,
wait a minute.
I would love that.
Currently causes cancer.
That's definitely A.
Yeah.
If you get cancer meeting pussy,
you're a pussy.
It's annoying though,
but if I'm going to get mouth cancer
rather yet from,
from,
you know,
looking to push you then transfer back
pack spitting in a cup where they're
also saying now that the coloring and
Coca Cola is causing cancer now and
then.
Or they're thinking about why do they
need to call her coke?
Can it just be clear and tastes like
that didn't really give a fuck what it
looks like.
Great.
And my favorite thing is to drink a coca
cola,
have a pussy.
Right.
So I'm fucked.
Now why do I even get out of bed?
It's over.
You know.
So um.
So Andy Dick stays out of jail somehow
or another.
And occasionally.
Yeah.
Does that pussy cancer thing,
by the way,
does that same one on ass or is it just
like the pussy?
Because it's the Pamplona.
Pamplona in Spain.
Pimp.
What's the name of the virus?
Poloma.
Yeah.
Something like that.
That virus is,
they've that can give you a mouth
cancer.
Wow.
That's crazy shit dude.
Yeah,
I had a wart on my lip.
I got a wart on my lip from the comedy
store because the microphone and the
comments dorm.
I know this what it's from,
from talking to people that you know
from all these different guys use it
because there's a certain spot or the
microphone would always touch my lip.
I'd always have the microphone right
here in my lip and all of a sudden I
started getting this fucking growth on
my lip.
Yeah.
What is this?
And I went to a dermatologist and they
said it was a warrant and they burned a
fucking wart off my lip.
That's disgusting.
Disgusting from the fucking comedy
store.
Thank God I never came back in that
spot.
The exact spot right here.
If you take up wipes now.
Wipes now accepting white.
But no.
You know what?
I really got into probiotics.
I really got into probiotics and I eat a
lot of acidophilus and I drink a lot of
Kombucha tea.
And when I started reading about it that
acidophilus is one of the most
aggressive bacteria is healthy bacteria
is and that it really is an excellent
aid in.
It kills other bacteria that it comes in
contact with.
So it literally coach your skin so it's
on top of your skin.
So if any cold bacteria or any virus,
bacteria tries to fuck with you,
it attacks it.
That's really like having your own
healthy soldiers that live in your body.
And when I was not doing that,
because sounds like soldiers in a good
way,
but when I wasn't doing it when I was
traveling a lot for the UFC and for
comedy,
I'm traveling all the time.
I was getting sick all the time and as
soon as I really got on the Kombucha
tea,
it killed it.
I stopped,
I stopped getting sick.
Yeah.
I should try and learn to the stomach
that stuff.
Kombucha.
You don't like it?
It just tastes like vinegar.
Yeah,
I enjoy it.
Well remember it was the.
Andy was into Kombucha.
Yeah.
And it got me into it that he was
listening to that weird garlic diet.
Remember he would eat them.
Whole cloves of garlic.
Yeah.
And it just smells so bad.
The weird thing about andy was he would
do massive amounts of drugs.
He would also take like every urban
known to man.
He would have like the sorting is
vitamins all day.
It was incredible.
It's like what?
You're so such a contradiction,
you're so into health and you know,
and worried about,
you know,
all these antioxidants that you're
taking in and have fresh wheat grass
juice and all this,
but then you're just doing heroin.
He was trying to combat the,
the drugs,
you know,
it's very sad at that dude wind up in a
shed somewhere.
He was doing comedy for a while.
I'd hear these crazy fucking stories.
Yeah.
He was telling me yesterday he kept was
pulling his residence down and yeah,
we got to get them on the podcast.
No,
I can't have.
Andy knows where I live.
We can do that.
We'll do that.
My students will do it a year now and
he's gonna know where you live,
man.
That's all right.
Be prepared.
Be prepared for that 3:00
AM knocking the door and let me.
And if I live too far away from
Hollywood a,
you'll never be able to walk back.
I can I guess.
But my emotional attachment though to
these radios that is fucked up as he is,
he'll always,
I'll always consider him to be family.
Yes.
You know,
like everyone from news radio,
I always considered to me everyone from
these radios,
you know,
his family to me,
you know?
Yeah,
no doubt.
And it's,
it's,
it's a very unusual bond that we all
have.
Stephen root called me awhile back for
some party that was thrown and I
couldn't make it.
I was going out of town,
but I was like,
wow,
how good is it to talk to this guy
again?
It feels like sometimes we won't see
each other for years,
you know,
but it's like,
but it never feels like.
But whenever I see anyone from news
radio,
it doesn't feel like any time has
passed,
you know,
dude,
you should fucking write something man.
Put it together.
May Be the real producer of a show and
get everybody to go together again.
Even the,
even andy,
maybe that's the rescue.
Andy.
Yeah,
dude names ready?
But podcasting.
Yeah.
Well there was one time when we were uh,
we were talking about doing something.
We were on the set.
It was when Brian Cowen played my
brother and we were talking about doing
something and you're doing it.
And we actually had,
but it's been over there.
Yeah,
the uh,
the Pirelli brothers.
Yeah.
But we never want them doing anything,
which is always how it's like Joey.
But like doing,
uh,
using the.
I remember with Brad Isaac segment using
the news radio cast as like the mercury
theater players,
you know,
like a repertory acting ensemble that
you would just like do like,
you know,
just do like a,
like independent movies would.
But it would only be the cast of news
radio and all these different movies.
That would have been a lot of fun.
We totally should have done a news radio
movie though,
but it was never like.
Because I said well it really wasn't
successful.
Canceled every season,
every season.
And that's what we kept doing season
finale.
We kept doing series finales.
So at the end of every season there
were,
there were so crazy like the space one,
we do these,
the titanic one,
we did a titanic,
won the whole episode of the show took
place in a boat.
So we were like underwater.
Like I,
at the end of the day,
if I had a dive underwater and I have a,
I remember I said that I brought my
three d stereo cameras to that.
She had this great three d photo of you
in the break room set that was in the
swimming pool,
a lake with up to here and this,
the
water spraying past you trying to fix
this really cool photo.
Yeah,
no kidding.
Can you email it to me?
Does it work?
Like.
Yeah,
I could probably,
yeah,
could probably scan it and then you'd
have,
I get scattered is like two side by side
images.
You went from that.
You started doing the poker show,
you know,
and you did a,
you try to do a bunch of pilots and then
you decided recently to start doing
standup.
Yeah,
well actually right after I got the
court ruling,
uh,
I thought,
oh,
you know,
I don't have any,
I'm not,
I'm not making much money these days.
I'm still making a decent living but not
when you have to pay $17,000
a month and about a quarter of what I
need to earn to be broke.
So I figured well,
you know,
maybe stand up at least I can go out and
and if I can put an act together and you
know,
if somebody told me,
said,
well if you got some TV,
if you've got,
if you've got some name recognition for
being on tv,
you can go out and do standup and make
money,
you know.
And I said,
well,
you know,
I guess you could say you don't even
have to be good.
You just,
you know,
people come after a little while.
People will stop showing up to.
But I thought,
well,
all right,
well I'll see what I'll see if I can get
the word gets out quicker today than it
ever has before.
Like screech really couldn't have pulled
it off if he started out today.
Yeah,
yeah.
Back in the day.
Yeah,
we got to tour.
But Steve,
I was doing pretty good though.
He's just got thrown on stage,
but I bet he's funny.
Yeah,
it's pretty crazy.
Did you throw yourself right on stage or
did you kind of do like A.
I don't know,
like small places first was doing that.
Now I'm still working up the AG.
I'm not going out and playing.
How long you been doing that?
Since before Christmas.
And you told me Friday night when I
talked to you that you were going to do
40 minutes?
I did a,
yeah,
just set it a UCB.
I did.
I guess I did almost 50 minutes.
Wow.
And for how long you been doing comedy?
Since December.
Before Christmas?
Yeah.
So just a few months.
A few months.
And you did 40 fucking minutes or an
hour?
Almost less than it did before.
You did above?
I think they said between 45 and 50
minutes.
Holy Shit Dude.
That's incredible.
Yeah.
So are you just doing math and writing
constantly?
Like.
No,
it's just like I kept going down and
doing like doing some sets of place near
my house,
my apartment and bunch of other like
these sort of alternative comedy shows
downtown.
And just sort of saying,
well,
you know,
every time I get up I'll do a do like 20
minutes of new stuff.
Wow.
So I'll try and rate 20 minutes and new
stuff for each time I get up.
Now when you write,
do you,
um,
do you sit down and go,
okay,
today I'm going to write,
stand up.
And do you just like go through the
newspaper or do you have some ideas that
you've already developed or
considered?
Rather?
It'd be Kinda like,
just I,
uh,
I actually started like make keeping a
few notes as,
as like going through the day or also
just keeping ideas in my head for
something that I thought might be funny.
Uh,
sometimes it would be something that
came up in the news,
you know?
Um,
uh,
you know,
it's weird,
but I wouldn't,
I,
I kind of decided that it wasn't going
to do what I did when I was a kid.
I was going to write stuff out word for
word.
I was just kinda like have ideas about
things that are.
Areas that I thought were funny.
Think it through in my head about what,
what I would want to cover A.
I have some jokes in my head,
uh,
and I'd make notes,
sort of point form notes.
I wouldn't let myself write out the
jokes in whole,
just point for form and,
uh,
to try and keep it from feeling like I
was like reading a monologue,
the acting like,
you know,
I didn't want it to feel like acting.
Yeah.
That is the trick of comedy.
Um,
I very rarely write out jokes in like,
you know,
so the other day I'm at the zoo.
I very rarely do that.
I mean I'm,
I'm almost never.
Every now and then I do it as a goof,
like,
as a practice,
like I'll sit and instead of.
Right,
just writing,
just random,
I'll sit and go,
okay,
I'm going to try to write a bit.
And I've done it.
I've done it a few times,
but most of the time I just write,
I just sit down and I write for.
And a lot of it might be depressing and
apocalyptic and then there'll be one
fucking one paragraph chunk.
And I'm like,
Holy Shit,
that's a bit,
you know,
3000 words or here's this one paragraph
that I bet that's a bit,
you know.
So do you do,
do that?
They do just write randomly or do you
write like specific?
Like how do you like when you sit down
to write?
Um,
I guess I'm wearing that just a.
A lot of times the,
the,
the German fit will be just something
that I've said like in conversation all
the time.
I do that to something else.
Somebody says,
man,
all start,
I'll go off on.
I'll go off for a few minutes on
something.
And I go,
well that's funny.
Yeah,
I can work that into something.
You just have to remember it.
Worse is when you're in the middle of
conversation.
Like,
stop,
please don't talk.
I'm going to write this down before I
forget it,
you know?
So now I have to pee.
Can I do that right in there?
Should I bring this with me?
None of them are just right down there.
You guys feel we're going to fill the
time.
Brian actually has recently started
doing standup comedy as well.
And a fucking feed froze on Ustream,
but what else is new?
People are constantly complaining about
that.
You know,
I don't think ustream is designed for a
couple thousand people at a time.
Right?
Yeah.
I don't know what it is.
I don't really know.
But we have Brian.
Anyway,
what I was saying,
I'm Brian fucking killed it this weekend
and Embraer,
you hit a new milestone this weekend.
New stuff.
Give me some new step up and it
definitely figured something out that
Saturday show on.
We were talking about how interesting it
is that he gets this weird opportunity
to do stand up where he did stand up a
bunch of years ago and did the Bob Hope
joke that we've all talked about on the
podcast before.
If you haven't heard the joke,
he got up in front of a room full of old
people and said,
do you think when Bob hope died,
they flew out his body to entertain all
the dead troops to Iraq,
you know,
and it bombed so bad.
He stopped doing standup for like five
years.
More than that.
Actually.
I was thinking about that.
The timing.
I think it was more because it was when
bob hooked,
I was like 2003,
I don't even remember,
but then I didn't get back until like
this year.
So you did a little bit at one point in
time,
remember?
I mean I threw you up in Atlanta.
You went up thought,
right,
right.
Yeah.
You got a new girlfriend and you quit
again.
Yeah.
That was like for like a month or two.
I did it.
It's relationships.
We would get you.
Your relationships would get you and
then you just wouldn't have the time.
Yeah.
Well right now I can't even imagine
being in that same relationship because
I pretty much do stand up once or twice
at night now and I have a podcast on top
of it like I've been up.
This is my second podcast.
They have another one right after.
This just seems so much happier to have.
What did I not just being out of the
relationship,
but do you know you're getting a chance
to express yourself now in a way that
you didn't get a chance to do before you
know?
Back then all you could do is make your
funny videos that's making those videos
killed me.
I mean that's sitting in front of by
yourself editing for till five in the
morning every night and then he did that
all week.
That that's as creative as that is.
It's such a slow process and it makes
you just like,
I was not talking to anybody.
Well,
I think part of the problem is that
you're a real perfectionist.
You know,
we just took some of these things and
edit them together,
sort of like the way Dana White's God
does it for video blogs.
Like we should put a video together if
somebody's like,
I've been,
I don't know if you saw on twitter,
I put up a on twitter.
I put a twitter level.
You're going on stage last night.
Oh really?
I think we just need to keep on doing
that shit.
You know what I mean?
Find finding.
I'll retweet it and we need to do more
videos.
But when I originally hired Brian,
that's what his job was.
A video guy.
Yeah.
Know your podcast cohost slash standup
comedian.
We were getting more listeners with
podcasts and the videos,
but I think you have an immense talent
when it comes to editing video that,
you know,
I mean,
just not being served.
Brian is actually just started doing
stand up himself.
He did it a long time ago and took a
bunch of years off and then got back
into it again.
So,
you know,
that's why I thought this,
um,
the subject is very fascinating to me.
The starting of the routine.
Do you feel comfortable on stage?
Uh,
yeah.
It's said it's weird because,
uh,
I took 30 years off,
you know,
how um,
and it,
it is feeling comfort because I know in
the past when I've done hosting gigs,
I've always felt a little funny,
you know,
like I'm like I'm impersonating someone
doing standup.
And so I think coming at it with a
looser form,
I like going on stage and just trusting
myself to have areas that I want to go
into and trusting myself to be funny,
uh,
is,
it has been fun.
It's been fun to go up and like find out
what the bits are on stage and a lot of
ways.
Yeah,
and that is the thing about standup is
like there's a totally different thing
when it's in front of a live audience
and you're trying to get laughs and your
voice is amplified and they're all
there.
You feel their energy looking at you and
you know,
different synapses fire.
Yeah.
Well if you were in a social setting and
someone talked for 45 minutes straight
without letting anyone else talk,
you would just think even no matter how
entertaining they were,
he'd be on what an asshole
know.
I talk about this on stage.
It's the most ridiculous.
I say that standup is the most
ridiculous job you could ever want to
have and I want to be the only one who
talks for an hour and I want to have my
voice amplified way above everyone
else's and I want to be lit.
Yeah,
that'd be welded as well.
Everyone else is in the dark.
It's also weird just because like
growing up,
I was always the person trying to make
everyone laugh though.
I was like the,
you know,
what I love doing is trying to make
people laugh like at my high school and
middle school and stuff like that.
So I kind of see like class clown,
comedian type thing.
I see that also.
It's not where,
it's not like trying to take over
everybody and be on a microphone stand.
You're just trying to make people happy.
It was most certainly a bunch of
different types of people that become
standup Comedians,
you know?
Uh,
there's,
you know,
I mean to say that it always comes from
one place that's not really true.
Like I had just never comes from a good
place.
Know exactly a huge vista of bad places.
I had always felt for a long time,
like there was something about me that
wasn't legitimate,
that I wasn't a legitimate comment
because I wasn't the same guy as
everybody else.
I wasn't afraid of people.
I was,
I grew up doing martial arts and
fighting and I went from fighting,
you know,
to,
to stand up.
And then it was like this weird thing
like,
I'm,
what am I,
this weird jock thing that's doing
complicated.
Who the fuck am I like,
well,
what is but doesn't just,
you just life has to suck.
And then you have to make funny out of
the suck your life could suck in all
kinds of weird ways.
You know,
like Nat Geo,
Pto,
Hanson's livestock was his father used
to beat the fuck out of him,
you know?
And everybody's is different.
Mine was being abandoned by my father.
You know,
everyone's had their own little weird
thing that you're trying to make up for
what that exorbitant amount of attention
you request on stage,
you know?
Yeah.
But if you don't do,
if you don't have some fucking weird
need,
you never really get there.
You know?
I don't know anyone.
I mean it's.
And I shouldn't say this because of
course it's possible for someone to be a
great comedian with a happy childhood.
It must be.
I mean,
if you're just really smart and figure
it out,
but I've never met that plans.
Don't know.
Yeah.
Anyway,
my childhood was pretty good.
I mean,
my,
my biggest problem is bullies and just
shit like that,
but even that is a big issue mainly wise
dude.
That's the only reason why I got into
martial arts.
I didn't get into martial arts because I
wanted to risk my fucking brain cells
and go out there.
I was terrified of other kids.
I moved around a lot when I was a kid
and we moved at basically every three
years we moved to a new place and I did
that too.
Yeah,
that's another thing.
I mean it's just you don't have a
stability,
you don't feel stable,
so you feel this need to express
yourself exorbitantly,
you know,
you have to get more attention than he
deserved,
you know?
Yeah.
I had a drunk dad who was also diagnosed
as borderline personality disorder.
Fuck Dude.
I found that when my wife,
I told my mom,
well,
she's been diagnosed with borderline
personality goes,
oh,
that's what they said your dad had
really lost.
So you knew breach all these subjects on
stage.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
Talk.
But it's.
I'd say it's probably about maybe 25
percent of its like about my personal
life and stuff.
Another and then maybe more.
Maybe 35.
You're free one and the rest is about a
life about life.
Yeah.
But other things.
You're free Wednesday night and you want
to go up at the Joe Show?
We have.
Oh yeah.
We're doing this thing.
It's sounds comedy whole.
We're doing it pretty much every
Wednesday night in Hollywood.
This is a really tiny club.
This great guy owns.
He's this guy.
He owned a club in New York and then he
opened up a small one in La and it got
closed down because he didn't have a
liquor license,
so now he's got a new one on melrose and
there's a bakery behind it and the own
data as well and they're going to close
that down and it's going to be a huge
place.
So right now it's only like a 80,
80 or 90 seats.
Fuck storied place.
It's right on melrose,
melrose and fuller.
So I'd love if you want to that.
Yeah.
It's fun because I know I'm done.
Are you getting news radio fans like
who?
What kind of people do you guys?
Well,
it's been like,
yeah,
it's been like A.
I meet a lot of this.
Well,
most of the sets I've done I've done
unannounced so far except for these,
these sets of done at ucb and when you
did the UCB ucb,
I guess it was a lot of kids in the hall
and these radio fans definitely that,
you know,
they know all about the show.
That must be great.
A great environment to like what we're
saying about Brian is Brian,
people know him from the podcast now,
so he only went upstage in a prayer this
weekend.
They all cheer and went crazy for them.
Yeah.
So it's like,
it's like even though you're learning
like they like you,
it's good to have that.
Yeah.
It's good to have that come.
I'm cheating.
Cheat Code.
Yeah.
It's definitely good God mode,
but again,
you know,
but then again that,
that last,
that advise you about 30 seconds.
It's true.
When I was on fear factor,
I would dread meeting fear factor fans,
but always be happy when someone said
they love Newsradio.
Yeah.
It was like,
you know,
you and your prostitution Gig,
but now you were awesome when you're
doing that other thing.
Now I was a little fear factor.
It was.
I was just funny to me because it was
all the way through news radio Yo said
next week I do is just called joe gets
paid.
I don't give a fuck what it is.
It's just neat blown it,
dude.
I don't give a fuck.
It's just joe gets paid.
That was.
I was recruiting everyone else there.
We're just going to drink coffee and
we're just going to run the cameras.
It's going to be called joe gets paid.
Really wound up happening.
It's like the secret man.
I had a fast.
You sent the message out to the universe
did dude,
I believe in that man.
Leave.
You can do that.
Did you have any experience with people
who were hooked on the secret?
Do you remember what huge.
Yeah,
and that's essentially.
It was like I'm remembering.
I remember it was like a,
uh,
like,
well my ex wife Chrissy,
she went,
she was wanting to see the film,
but all right,
but it's,
and people will talk,
people talk about,
well,
it scientific and I'd have scientific
scientific about it.
It's complete bullshit.
It's like Rodney Allen rippy fucking
power of positive thinking bullshit.
It's like,
you know,
and it's like,
if you really think that,
so,
uh,
yeah.
So every child dies of starvation just
wasn't putting out enough positive
energy.
Yeah.
I had an argument with a friend of mine
into it,
you know,
so into it.
I go,
okay,
you ready for this?
Babies die in drive bys.
What's going on there?
Yeah,
they manifesting the wrong reality.
That's one.
They're not setting a positive energy in
the universe.
They're not,
they're not.
They're not really thinking about what
they want and apply.
It's so ridiculous and so culty.
But the fascinating thing is that it's
confirmation bias.
You're only looking at what you,
what supports your case,
and there's a bunch of people that are
successful and they're saying,
well,
I envisioned it and that's how I became
successful.
We're the,
we're the fucking people that envisioned
it and they're poor as shit right now
and they're going,
I don't get it.
What's happening?
It's like you're only using the people
that are successful.
You.
You got to show me a dude who's fucking
starving,
and then you apply it to him and then he
goes out in the world and then you come
back in 15 years and go,
okay,
well look,
the guys that are successful and you
gotta show me at least.
Yeah,
you get.
If you take 100,
you've got to have at least more than 50
of them succeed or to be know
statistically meaningful out of a
thousand,
you know,
and that one is,
wants to let you know the secret that
it's all simple.
You've just got to think positive like
any religion,
any religion where people want to
believe that they can do something that
will,
that will give them power over the rest
of creation.
You know,
the rest of creation is going to somehow
fall into line with their wishes because
they prayed to God or they sent out
positive energy.
You know,
I think it's fascinating though and it's
very unfortunate that this,
this craze is so discredited and so the,
the,
the place where they're coming from is
so illogical because the concept of
thinking healthy and positive is very
important for formulating a good life,
for figuring out how to be connected to
the right kind of people and how to send
the right kind of energy out so that you
know,
you foster healthy relationships and
that you're what you're doing and
pursuing in life is something that you
get motivation out of or rather that you
get satisfaction out of feeling poor,
positive.
Having a positive outlook is healthy.
It's better for you,
you know,
you know Jesus.
I mean,
I think living with my first wife,
you know,
so it was just negative about
everything.
Everything was negative.
It's,
it's,
it,
it is horrible for you.
Yes.
I've been there.
I've been there many times in
relationships and in friendships.
I've had friendships where the people
are negative and you're like,
you get away from them and just like
you're catching your breath.
And I'm like,
what is this person doing to me?
They're fucking,
they're draining.
Yeah,
doing something to me.
So it's definitely positive.
Being positive.
That part is great.
Yet.
And there's even,
there is science behind that.
Yes.
There are.
Keeping a positive attitude,
you know,
keeps you healthier,
keeps your immune system functioning
better.
Well,
I've seen it.
I've seen positive and negative thinking
during a dmt trip.
I had a,
uh,
during a psychedelic trip,
I had this weird moment where I was
thinking all these negative things
because psychedelic trips are just so
out of control.
There's so beyond bizarre and they're so
incredibly,
like a self examined a Tory,
if that's not even a word,
but you know,
you're,
you're so introspective.
You're looking at so many different
aspects of your life,
like at a million miles an hour,
then you can,
you can get like a negative thought and
they can blow away.
And that's where bad trips come from.
So in the middle of this negative
thought,
this,
I saw this,
this like dmt is a very visionary,
psychedelic experience and you have a
weird black,
dark,
fucking nasty,
dark green and dark black patterns and
colors.
And then in the middle of it,
I realized what I was doing,
a realize that as being negative and I
took a deep breath and I let go and be
an became positive,
decided to think positive and it
blossomed like flowers in front of me.
And the colors changed and they all
became bright and beautiful and vibrant
and it became light in the patterns
became beautiful.
And I was like,
wow,
this is like a lesson I'm learning from
a psychedelic experience about the real
physical manifestation of negative and
positive thoughts.
They actually have a real effect that
they think they say that,
that,
that if you just force yourself to
smile,
yeah,
you can reduce depression.
Yeah.
Like your depression will fade a little
mountain all the way if you're really
depressed.
But if you can force yourself to smile.
I really like put on a big demo.
Like you just keep it there long enough.
It'll get brain reacts as though you're
happy.
Your brain starts to release the same
chemicals it would if you were actually
amazing.
And it's like.
So it's like,
you know,
the mind,
body connection is true.
It really is real.
What we are is the most fascinating
organic computer that's ever been
created and we don't have a fucking
single book on how to use the operating
system currently.
Now just the Bible Joe's.
Yes,
the Bible.
We are all,
we are all raised by people who are
completely clueless as to how to raise
someone.
I mean,
almost every one of us.
Yeah.
And so we develop and you can get in
these patterns of thinking that your
parents have,
you know,
it's like,
if you grow up around like Mrs Rogan has
a very negative parents,
especially her mom.
Her mom had a very hard life and her mom
is one of those that you can't tell her
a good thing.
Well this is just gonna happen and it's
just going to fall apart.
And then what happens here?
And then what happens there and you
know,
and Jessica,
whoops,
was that her name has managed to avoid
it.
But for the most part,
it's,
it's like if you,
if you develop in a,
in a family,
a household at a bunch of negative
motherfuckers like that shit can,
it,
it becomes like a,
um,
like a path that you get on.
It becomes a track,
you know,
you're on this track.
I grew up in a family where everyone
else might actually metal the brothers,
not that way,
but the rest of my family,
they're all like,
oh,
well,
whatever you do,
the system is going to get you.
You know,
it's like,
it's stacked against you.
You can't win.
You know,
like,
that's,
you know,
I think part of that is my mother was
working class English and that's the way
that you're raised,
you know,
so you know,
well we'll try what you will,
but you really
can't get away from it.
You know,
it's all stacked against you.
So God damn difficult to manufacture an
awesome environment.
And you know,
it's been one of my main focuses as a,
as a grownup,
as an adult,
is to try to manufacture the most
positive atmosphere possible both in
work and friendships and relationships
in everything that I do try to like
steer it towards the most positive place
possible.
You know,
you can,
your life can be really fucking awesome
if you do that correctly.
And it can suck real bad if you don't.
Yeah,
yeah know.
But the secret Nazi shit.
Well as well as the,
I mean,
I believe her that any,
anything that makes you feel like you
have any control over your destiny is an
illusion because then people think,
well,
I,
you know,
I make good choices.
So good things happen.
And they go,
well that's still just pure luck because
every single day you are tied up in a
chain reaction of millions of choices
that are being made all around you every
day.
And all it has to be as one of those
choices be someone wants to shoot you in
the head and that's the choice that's
going to shape your destiny.
So.
And any day that someone doesn't shoot
you in the head,
you know,
it's just luck or a guy with a vest once
a blow up a cafe where you're writing
your novel or somebody sneezes while
driving and goes over the curb or Texas
slams into you and you guys.
Yeah,
for sure.
Yeah.
There's.
I've been considering this idea over the
last few years,
especially that the entire life that we
live is sort of like a mathematical
program and it's like this giant
algorithm that's far too complex for us
to really wrap our heads around it,
but that all these different motions and
all these emotions and actions and all
these different things and circumstances
there,
they're actually literally really like
integers that it's already a part of
something that's creating something
else.
It's like information theory.
Yeah.
It was the idea that the universe is
nothing but information is just the
universe.
The entire universe is just an
information storage device.
It makes sense.
I mean,
when you look at the direction that
humanity is,
and as another thing that's absolutely
fascinating to me,
I'm completely fascinated with the idea
of the singularity and with the idea of,
you know,
I mean,
even the,
the idea of end times,
they're there.
The idea of an apocalyptic scenario,
you know,
you look at like what human beings are
doing.
I equate human beings to be in some
weird sort of a caterpillar who doesn't
know what's going to turn into a
butterfly.
So we are absolutely obsessed with the
newest,
greatest technological innovations and
eventually that that's pushing to a
certain direction and that direction is
some sort of a redefinition of life as
we know it.
Yeah,
I think I was thought that eventually
the,
the earth itself would develop its own
consciousness if it doesn't already
have.
You may already.
And there's actually a theory called the
theory of the Noaa Sphere,
which is that the earth is enveloped in
a,
uh,
just like the stratosphere,
that there's a noaa sphere,
which is a sphere of knowledge of
information.
And that this notice fear exists around
the earth and that,
you know,
people can tap into it.
Yeah.
Well,
not even just around the earth,
that it's a dimension around you all the
time.
That's the idea of the muse.
Is that what you're really doing when
you're,
when you're being completely creative,
is it you are just an antenna to pull in
all this information.
That's what Tesla had said.
Yes.
Slow.
Who's greatest inventor ever was,
was believed that he was receiving
signals from other other life forms that
we're giving them this information.
And now of course,
the weird thing is that a physicists are
starting to toy with these ideas.
You know,
the idea of entanglement and idea of.
Sure.
The idea of consciousness being nonlocal
yeah.
Know that your entire body is actually a
sort of some weird sort of an antenna
and that,
you know,
the,
the hormones and adrenaline and all
these different things and you run it
all the biological instincts that are
there to keep the physical body alive or
no,
it's no more than like maintenance
cycles that you have to run on a BMW.
Have you read about the Princeton did
this huge multi year study of a mind
machine interface?
No.
Uh,
but basically that attention affects
machines and uh,
that they did,
they did these studies where they use a
random number generator.
Okay.
I did hear about this and they just had
these,
had a random number generator and they
had people just focus not anything
specific,
just focus on the machine itself.
And the more and more people focused on
the machine,
the less random the machine became.
It became,
it started having nonrandom patterns.
Human consciousness is something we,
we completely don't understand.
There's,
there's,
there's energy that comes out of people
sometimes that is absolutely tangible.
We just don't have a device to measure
it.
Well,
these,
the other thing they did,
they set up these random number
generators all around the world and so
they sent them all around the world and
then just coincidentally a nine slash 11
happened because they had a theory that
if large numbers of people were thinking
about the same event,
that that would have a larger impact on
these machines and they found the
correlation.
They found that at the time of nine
slash 11 when the towers fell,
um,
these machines all around the world
started generating nonrandom sequences
of numbers.
And what does that mean?
Just that they don't really.
All they know is this is like the men
that they said that,
that just the effect of everyone paying
attention to the same event a affected
these machines.
Okay.
So what you're saying is that all these
people were supposed to be paying
attention to the machines and then the
event of nine slash 11 happened and
because it was such a huge event,
all these people are focusing on this.
And then that stopped being random.
The event.
Yeah.
Just the fact that people were all
focused on the same event affected these
machines.
Wow.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
That's fascinating.
Shit.
Yeah.
And they found it the same thing.
They also found out at a camp that was
in Canada,
Prime Minister Trudeau,
his funeral in Canada,
that when his son was giving the eulogy
that there was a,
an effect because you had almost every
single person in Canada listening to
the,
you know,
the idea is really fascinating to me.
You familiar with ray?
Kurt's we'll do,
you know,
the clarity is near when you know he's,
he's the number one proponent of the
idea of the intelligent computer
eventually taking over and that's what
he deems a singularity to be and what he
thinks is that what immortality is going
to be.
It's going to be able to download your
consciousness into some sort of a
computer and you know,
it sounds completely ridiculous until
you start thinking about the what,
what the fuck is consciousness and what
if they can recreate,
it would,
it,
would have,
you can recreate and create an
artificial version of consciousness down
to the point of it being non local down
to the point of this computer that
you've created being an antenna to tune
in this new sort of conscious.
Yeah.
Well,
it was,
uh,
I remember once talking about computers
continue to advance the rate they're
doing.
I don't remember if it was Chris that
puts for two,
but the idea that,
that eventually there'll be a computer
powerful enough to have stored in his
memory banks,
every single event that has occurred
since the big bang,
which means like every event in every
human being's life,
every,
every interaction of matter throughout
the universe could be stored on a
single,
can be extrapolated based on the current
events and his.
And he said that the program itself
would not be able to distinguish itself
from the original.
Wow.
So each of us would be programmed into
this computer's memory bank and the
program of us would not be able to
distinguish itself from the original,
which means that right now we might
already be that program.
A billion years in the future
may very well be some sort of a parallel
reality.
Well,
we may have,
we may have lived our actual,
a carbon based life a billion years ago.
And right now we might just be the
computer program being run a billion
years later.
So
whoa,
what a mind fuck.
I saw a trip,
I saw a glitch in the matrix the other
day and this is kind of like this.
I,
I was outside in,
it was the moon and there was these
clouds going over it after a rain storm.
Right.
And have you ever seen like on satellite
TV,
like we're like darker scenes,
like blacks and grays.
They're not just black or gray,
it's like kinda like blocky,
like boxes.
I was looking at that and it was doing
that and I'm like,
why am I seeing blocky?
Like your eyes are programmed to see
that.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I do.
I see so much computer and TV that was
doing.
But it was really like I was staring at
going,
there's no reason those are squares.
Those are blocks.
Like the shadowing was off.
And I'm thinking,
wait a second,
this is some kind of say my friend
Duncan hit
me with the ultimate mindfuck once.
And that is the theory that,
that you,
uh,
that your life,
like as the world gets more and more
fucked up and more and more chaotic and
you worry about the future of the world,
that's really your own mortality.
That you're,
you're,
you're tripping on that.
You have created this entire universe
around you.
And even though,
uh,
it seems real because there's a bunch of
people in your life that also seem real.
They in your dream as much as you exist
in there and it's all some sort of a
symbiotic connection,
but that you,
you live and are reborn constantly.
And then every time something happens to
you,
whether it's some sort of a car
accident,
some you know,
you die in a building,
collapsed.
Anything that happens,
you immediately forget it,
forget it.
And you are transported into another
situation where you already have this
life going on and you just step in and
just keep going.
And that it never ends.
And there is no death.
And it's just a constant cycle until you
get your shit together,
until you completely and totally
evolved.
And that this illusion that you've been
around for 40 years or 50 years,
it's all nonsense.
You know,
you'd been around forever.
You've been around forever.
That's the old soul notion.
Yeah.
You know,
look,
we have a very limited amount of
memories that we can,
can access about this life that we're
pretty sure happened,
you know,
and none of them that we can access
during the sleep time.
Just imagine if someone came up with a
drug that would allow you to remember
your sleep and details.
Remember your dreams in.
Absolutely didn't want to see half the
shit.
I don't want to fucking argue was
already with talking today.
How he had a dream the other day about
having sex with his sister.
And I'm like,
oh,
I'd see.
That's the kind of Shit I don't want to
even know that I'm dreaming about.
You know?
Did he say it was good?
It came a couple of times.
Nice.
Yeah.
So David,
if anybody wants to go see you perform,
where can they,
how can they get ahold of you?
I know your,
your twitter is Dave s Foley F o l e y.
and how can they get ahold of you?
You have a website?
Uh,
no I don't,
I,
I've got facebook,
but that's kind of useless.
We're going to have to get a website if
you're going to do standup,
but just the twitter and a.
and so
the plan is to um,
uh,
do some gigs to put together a set and
then go to her and then.
Yeah.
And then actually start playing actual
comedy clubs.
Are you ready?
I mean,
do you felt like you did this thing the
other night?
How would it have to go?
Well,
it was like I under,
I,
I overestimated the amount of stuff that
I had in my notes.
So I was like about 15 minutes shy when
I got,
you know,
then it went all right.
And it's like I just sort of pulled out
some stuff I've been working okay.
But I had like a notes that I hadn't
timed outside as well.
I think this is going to be about 45
minutes of stuff in these notes and turn
out to be half an hour it true.
Yeah.
And um,
so then,
so then I had to sort of quickly just
grabbed and other bits that I hadn't
planned to do as well as I could
remember it.
And then improvise a little digital
recorder set.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
So you're,
your main motivation initially was just
financial,
but now you're enjoying it.
Yeah,
I'm enjoying it.
It's feels good to an extent not,
I've never been a person who,
who like really craves performing,
you know,
I,
I can enjoy it,
but I never like,
I never get this thing,
oh,
I got to be on stage.
Um,
but I've been,
yeah,
it's been really fun,
especially because it's been such a
dark,
horrible year and a half this past year
and a half.
Fuck is,
you know,
it's amazing you saying that because it
was dark and horrible when I knew you in
94 and this was an
and that was nothing like this last year
and a half has been the worst year and a
half of my life.
I'm like,
really?
I'm,
you know,
it's,
I'm not exaggerating when I say I have,
I hadn't gotten through it.
I wouldn't have been surprised,
you know?
Wow.
You know,
it was that you thought about.
Oh yeah.
Suicide.
Oh,
tons.
Tons Times.
Fuck.
Most of the time.
Well you have my number now.
Yeah,
don't do that.
Oh No,
I wouldn't.
I couldn't do it,
you know,
the main thing was,
and it wasn't even like,
look,
I'm going to prevent your suicide.
What a ridiculous.
You have my number now have no more
concerned,
but it really was.
I mean,
I,
you know,
I have an eight year old daughter and a
seven year old daughter.
She'll be eight soon.
It was like gone and it's that thing I
kept getting hurt her so badly,
you know?
And that was,
that was the only thing,
you know,
my teenagers.
I figured they really wouldn't care too
much,
you know.
Do you,
uh,
do you exercise at all?
Huh?
Do you exercise?
Obviously not.
I'm going to start eating.
Yeah.
Well actually,
because I just,
you know,
now I'm actually feeling pretty good.
Standup is making me feel better.
Sure.
Like,
so,
so a huge rush,
you know,
and great just being on stage and being
funny,
remembering the reason I started doing
this,
the reason that I liked doing it as that
it's fun to.
It's funny and it's,
you're creating positive energy and a
positive environment.
You're giving someone something,
you're changing their state.
Yes.
And uh,
and I just booked a pilot which is nice.
Nice.
Was a show called how to be a gentleman.
Which is a good script and funny.
And so obviously these secret does work
because I put out some positive energy
and now I got show.
Well,
maintaining your body is so important.
Your body.
Yeah.
Fucking trick.
You and your body can betray you
whenever there's times of stress,
all those chemicals or they think you're
going to have to fight off a cheetah or
something.
You know what I mean?
Chemicals don't realize that,
oh,
you're just dealing with a legal
entanglement.
So it's like,
and I've spent most of my life going,
okay,
body,
can you take this if I neglect you and
abuse you this way?
Right?
So,
uh,
what do you plan on doing like yogurt or
something like that?
What do you,
what's the idea for what about just
getting on an exercise?
I bike.
I actually joined a gym but I haven't
been but actually have joined like the,
you know,
the gym,
a gym downtown,
a iphone.
Make it so fucking fascinating.
It makes it so much better.
Put on a podcast,
and I know a lot of people listen to
this podcast.
There's probably people ironically at
the gym struggling through it right now,
listening to you on,
on their iphone.
I know there are then.
I'm sorry about the middle part of this
conversation with my harder.
I could probably listen man.
Other people's trauma and struggles.
It's,
it's a,
it's a beneficial.
You can learn from that.
You can learn a lot,
drink a lot.
Like I didn't hide it.
A couple of fucking cats and a dog.
You have no entanglements.
You have no worries.
This should.
I'm
a single mom.
What are you talking about?
I have to fucking take my.
After last night I got pretty drunk and
I will have to wake up at 8:00
AM to let my dog out and sit there with
the worst hangover.
Felt like puking.
Then go back to bed for awhile.
Mother fucker took malaria medication
and went to Morocco and though I'm
saying,
I'm saying like,
it's like I'm a full time single mom and
it's fucking annoying
a baby and you need to join the marine.
You're a baby.
You need to join the fucking marines.
Need to learn some discipline.
Go to have opened the doors.
My Dog can pee.
No,
that's set up there.
I'm anyone.
Yeah.
No having pets.
It really is nothing like having
children is absolutely nothing.
Like I leave my dogs outside all the
time.
I don't give a fuck.
You can't leave my kid anywhere.
No.
That's the thing.
You learn when you do have kids.
It's like,
you know,
you really realize,
oh my pets.
I love them,
but they're disposable.
Can Die.
They can die now and a and I'll feel bad
for a day.
You know,
we use.
It wasn't me.
At least it wasn't me or my family.
Yeah,
but it's amazing when I see women just
suppressing that maternal instinct with
children,
but they have a bunch of fucking cats or
dogs or something like that.
They are.
My children know they aren't your
children.
They don't.
They give dave a fleshlight to bitch.
Yeah,
keep out of trouble.
You're talking about.
Yeah.
If you still too long they'll eat you.
So,
um,
if people want to get ahold of you,
Dave,
s Foley on twitter and you will be
updating people as to where they could
see you doing standup?
Yes.
Yeah.
How often are you going to be doing
this?
I'm,
I'm getting at least a couple,
a couple of times a week and I'm going
to be doing more,
come Wednesday,
getting it more.
I'd like to do the Wednesday.
Do you want to come?
It's fun.
It's really supportive crowd.
I'm going to do a set on doing Doug
Benson show his.
Doug Benson loves movies.
Oh yeah,
I've done that before.
That's great.
Yeah.
I'm doing that tomorrow and then after
that I'm going to do a set,
but I can't remember where.
See that's Wednesday.
Doug's going to be doing it too,
so
yeah,
Doug does it all the time.
Yeah.
So combined if you can in any way.
Listen,
I just want to tell you,
I've worked with a lot of people over my
life over the course of my life and you
were one of my favorite human beings
I've ever met.
Working with you was a huge pleasure and
I really don't think that you get nearly
as much credit as you deserve for,
for news radio.
I don't think it would've ever been what
it was without you.
When I say that you were responsible for
half of what happened on that show.
I'm not exaggerating.
I know you think you will.
I am,
but you just don't remember.
You know,
you were the secret producer of news
radio,
you know,
and you're just a brilliant guy and I'm
glad you did
came on the podcast.
You know,
I love you very much,
you know,
to,
so it's,
it's great to see you,
you know,
so that's fun.
Do you love Brian?
Not yet.
Not yet,
but I'm willing to.
I'm willing to love me.
I'm willing to try.
We can hate women together and I'd love
he doesn't hate when I do a couple of
them,
couple of crazy ones.
And he hates their disease.
It doesn't hate them.
Yeah.
Alright.
And uh,
thanks to the flashlight for sponsoring
the podcast.
You go to Joe Rogan.net
and click the link that's up there.
You can enter in the code name Brogan.
You get 15 percent off.
We offer discounts on our sex toys is
great.
That's how we run.
It won't cost you money for the rest of
your life.
It also keeps people from taking this
podcast too seriously.
It's like,
no man,
we offer up any controversial
revolutionary ideas like,
yeah,
they're sponsored by a rubber posting.
Um,
so,
um,
this,
this weekend,
uh,
actually I got two shows in Australia at
Rudy Hill,
the RSL club,
and uh,
the first one sold out.
The second one.
I still think there's a few tickets that
are available.
So you,
Australian freex get on that shit.
And then,
uh,
next week,
next Wednesday we'll be back at sal's
again.
And um,
we're going to have another podcast this
week.
Probably tomorrow,
but it might be Wednesday and I'll keep
you bitches informed,
so thank you everybody for tuning in and
thank you for everybody for coming out
to Bria this weekend.
We had a great fucking time and that's
it.
Thank you,
Dave Foley.
Thank you everybody.
Thank you.
Thank you all.
You bitches at home love you because
it's
the Joe Rogan experience.