Do we live? Did I say moral technique on
the air? Maybe. Good. I said good things.
I love that dude.
He'll be here on Monday.
This episode of the Joe Rogan experience
podcast is brought to you by ting. Now,
if you've seen the teen news recently,
and let me see, ting dropped their rates.
They uh, to celebrate,
celebrate, celebrate.
They um, dropped their prices
to celebrate two years.
They cut their rates in half. Um,
let me see exactly what they did.
They slashed their prices permanently
there permanently slashing prices to
celebrate their second birthday.
I fucking love shit like that.
When you don't have to do stuff like that
and you'd do it just because you want
people to feel good about
your company. What, uh,
what I enjoy the most about ting is
the feedback. [inaudible] excuse me.
The feedback that we get from people
that have used it, it's all positive.
I haven't had one person say, Eh dated,
but I didn't really see them many.
According to 10, 98% of people save
money. Let's see what exactly they did.
Ting trajectory toward shorter,
I'm trying to find the news just as
drops. Prices. Google it. Oh, I know.
I shouldn't tell you to Google it. I
should have this nose, but I don't,
didn't come. I had to find it online.
It didn't come as a part of the ad thing
anyway,
they dropped their prices a lot.
So since I can't find the
news that quickly, uh,
just accept that permanently
permanently dropped the prices,
which is a fucking tricky thing to say.
You permanently draft
your issue permanently.
What about a hundred fucking
thousand years from now, dude?
How much is that chicken across then?
People got to be careful because
the world will still be around.
Maybe that's what everybody
planted for the apocalypse with.
That motherfucker never comes.
What if it never comes and you stay alive?
Then what bitch? Huh? Then what? Anyway,
this episode brought to
you by Tang and ting.
Would they are is a mobile
company that uses sprint backbone.
They buy time on sprint
and rented out to you,
but they do it in a way that most
cell phone companies don't like.
They don't have any contracts
and live any bullshit.
They don't have any
early termination fees.
They're truly and completely contract
free and they sell the best android phones
in the world. I switched to android
and I'm very happy with it and I also,
I'm even more happier because,
uh,
once we had a end dress Antonopoulos on
the podcast and the day talking to us
about Bitcoin,
um,
he was talking about how the Apple
App for Bitcoin is not very good.
Then apple pulled it.
They actually pulled the fucking app.
Did they give a reason
for why they pulled it?
It's gross because 120,000 people,
it already downloaded that bitcoin app
and they were using it and apple just
decided for whatever fucking reason that
they're not going to let you download
it anymore. It's, I think
gross when you download,
I mean if you have something
that's as mainstream as Bitcoin,
I mean,
I wouldn't say bitcoins mainstream,
but when you get to be 120,000 downloads,
that's pretty,
pretty significant and growing.
It's clearly growing. I mean,
every day I see in the
news things about Bitcoin,
different companies accepting Bitcoin,
Vegas casinos accepting bitcoin.
And so for apple to step in
with no explanation, unless
there's an explanation,
like they don't like the software,
it has vulnerability.
They thought they should
have to tell you that.
But if you just pull it and don't say
a word that's smacks of censorship.
To me that sounds gross.
I don't know what's going on,
but more and more I'm,
I'd lean towards android and,
um,
I just think there's a billion fucking
people that are using cell phones,
probably more in the world.
And something like 80% of them
are on the android platform now.
Something like 80 something percent
smartly. Let me find that out for sure.
How many people use android?
Apple dropped it for a unresolved issue.
What does that mean?
That doesn't mean anything.
You didn't say a word.
She didn't say that we dropped it
for an unresolved issue. Oh, okay.
What does that mean? You want to be king
of the world and it didn't work out yet.
The fuck did you do? Huh?
You sons of bitches? Um,
uh, whatever, it's, whatever the
numbers are, who gives a shit?
It's a very high number of people
that are using a android. It's um,
in, uh, it depends on where
you're at. There's worldwide,
worldwide, it's like 70%.
It looks like,
um,
this is pretty crazy that
the numbers are growing too.
It wasn't one point in time,
like almost all the smartphones,
like good percentage of when the iPhone
and then slowly but surely the enter it
started to get better and better. And now
they, uh, they're actually the majority,
uh, and there's so many
people working on them too.
There's the new ones are pretty
fucking bad ass. So if you're like a,
an iPhone person, uh, and you're
worried you don't have to the uh,
the new ones are pretty fucking dope.
And if you go to a rogan.ting.com
you can save some money.
They have the devices up there.
If you go and look at their website,
they have all the cool ones, like the one
I have, which is the galaxy note three,
just, it's enormous. But I love it
because it's just great for email.
And looking at pictures and shit.
But another one that's smaller,
that's also very bad.
Asses the HTC one or the galaxy s four
all the top of the line phones they sell,
they sell them all at a ting.
Excuse me.
So go to [inaudible] Dot [inaudible]
Dot Com and save 25 bucks.
A super awesome company.
Really, really happy with them.
Really happy with the feedback too, from
having them as a con, uh, podcast sponsor.
So go, go check it out. They also
have a no hold customer support.
You can call them 1-855-TING-FTW.
That's Ting for the win.
That shows you that their lead. You
know what lead is? Do you remember?
[inaudible] that means you're elite.
You understand like tech talk,
Tim for the wind bitches. Okay,
enjoy them.
rogan.ting.com save yourself some money.
Tang also ohms. Hover. Hover is the,
is actually the domain name
company that I use personally. Me,
I'm super easy to use.
A monkey like me got on hover and
registered domain names with no problems
whatsoever.
Very,
very easy to do and they give you a
lot of stuff for free to hover, um,
that you would normally pay for it.
Like who is domain name privacy,
which is pretty important when you were
registering some freaky ass websites.
You don't want people to know where you
sleep. You know what I'm saying, Dawg.
Exactly. Um, also you
can set up emails. Um,
you can have email from your
website. They'll, they'll
set that stuff up for you.
Hover gives you exactly what
you need to get the job done.
You find the perfect domain name for
your idea to live so that you can get
started and move on to the
next thing on your to do list.
I don't know why they
want you to say that.
How do I know if you have a
next thing I used to do this,
I don't want to pressure you mad.
Okay.
If all you need to do is fucking
register your domain name just to that,
don't worry about it. You're going to
be okay. We're all going to be okay.
They have email forwarding
for just five bucks.
You can keep using the same
inbox you're used to and uh,
send them from a way better address.
Sorry for people who don't like me
slurping, it doesn't bother me. However,
has the best customer support around.
Go there and enjoy it and
use the code word freaks.
That is for the month of February.
Um,
why freaks think they want to distinguish
which one of these podcasts you were
listening to when you found out about
their awesome domain name service.
So for this month it's freaks.
I find that all to be very confusing and
I'm not really until you switch around
your fucking passwords, people
get it together. But either way.
Awesome web service. I use it, I enjoy it.
And you should as well
use the code word freaks.
That's hover h a v e r.com the best place
on the net to register your domains.
And we're also brought to you by on it.
I'm Aubrey,
I think you know a thing or two about
honor. You've heard of the company? Yeah,
a little bit controversial
place that sells awesome shit.
And I'm one of the newest
that, uh, I really enjoy.
I've been mixing in my protein shakes.
Is this a the new Greens supplement?
Tell me about that shit.
Well,
what we wanted to do is just get a bunch
of the healthiest stuff you could and
freeze dried powdered format.
So we got a bunch of the actual Greens,
then we got some of the different colored
vegetables like beets and some of the
other things that you might be missing
from your diet. Put in some probiotics,
put in some enzymes,
a few of the herbs that are good for liver
and some of your organs and basically
put together kind of a, Oh shit,
I haven't had my diet right.
Kind of Greens that you can add and make
sure that you're at least covered from
a micronutrient micro vitamin
basis that just has basically all
the good nutrients in it possible.
Well, it's a great mix of stuff too.
Um, I've, I've read the ingredients,
the ingredients list. It's pretty fucking
powerful. How did you, uh, how'd you,
how'd you formulate this?
Well,
one of the key things that we found is I
was looking at antioxidant potential as
well.
And you know,
I'm fairly familiar with Peru and kind
of some of the things that come out of
there and there was a purple corn that
comes out of Peru that they grow pretty
much exclusively in that region and it
has it really, really high or act value.
And Oreck is, is a useful tool.
It's not the end all be all,
but it's an antioxidant measurement.
You know how many free radicals get
quenched by the natural compound.
And that's a process that goes on normally
in the body and it's a really high
amount of that more so than even some
of the other berries like us, I, he,
Barry and all these other barriers that
get really highly touted. So we put,
you know,
a bunch of that in there and then just
went from there and got a bunch of full
spectrum Greens and put it all together.
Everything being food based, you know,
just all the coolest,
best foods that we could get,
which is the best way for your body
to absorb. Absolutely. All this,
the best supplements that you can get
or are food based and which is why those
studies that came out
recently were so stupid
and annoying because if you don't
know the studies we're talking about,
there's a this really bold proclamation
from whatever study vitamins don't work,
they're not worth it. It's
waiting now, not worth your time.
And they're conclusion.
Closed case closed.
Their conclusions were based on two of
the grossest studies ever for saying that
vitamins don't work.
One of them was people over 65 that have
had heart attacks that were fucking old
and had heart attacks and it didn't stop
there. Their progression of, you know,
death or whatever, which is ridiculous.
You're over 65 you have a heart attack,
you're fucking, that's
like saying, you know,
I had a 72 Pontiac with a blown motor.
It was going down the highway and you
change the tire and it didn't fucking fix
my car. Like your machine's
already broken men. You've,
you're having a heart attack at 65
like this shit is close to the end.
The wheels are falling off the ride.
And the other one was physicians who
are over 65 who were showing cognitive
decline. It didn't slow down
their cognitive decline. Okay,
so vitamins don't work because of that.
Like what the fuck man?
People are really gross with that shit
where they want to say it doesn't work.
Doesn't work. Why is that? Because
a lot of stuff doesn't work,
but a lot of stuff does.
All right,
and that's why these vitamins
were made in the first place.
The whole reason why they were extracted
from food analyzed is because people
needed to know what the basic
compounds of nutrients where.
What is it about vitamin C that
keeps people from getting scurvy?
What is it about vitamin B
12 that gives you energy?
What is it about vitamin D that you get
from the sign? All the, this is science.
Like everyone's pretending
that this is all like, oh,
the pseudo science of supplements.
Fuck you. You fat, lazy piece of Shit.
You don't know nothing about your body.
All right, that's what's going on.
All you fucking people that are
like, you know, you don't need that.
Eat a balanced guy. Oh really? Doctor.
Well, why don't you run up a hill with me?
Fuck. Why don't you tell me about
optimum physical performance?
You don't know unless you supplement.
Unless you have a healthy body,
you don't know the difference
between optimum and suboptimum.
You just exist at this sub optimum
state and thanks. Wow. What she,
I have a cup of coffee.
I have my eggs and bacon and I go to
work and I've got no problem whatsoever
with my health. Why? I just
got back from a doctor.
People always want to tell you that I
just got back from the doctor with a clean
Palette health.
I'll fucking strangle.
You know you don't have a clean bill
of health. You're fucking dying, man.
Look at your face has fallen
off your skin. Stop it. Yeah.
There's a difference between being okay
surviving and being optimal and to be
optimal. You got put in, you
know, how are you going to eat?
There's 24 natural ingredients
in this [inaudible].
How are you going to get these
24 ingredients in every day diet?
It's going to be a pain
in the [inaudible].
You could have a 10 inch television
who needs a 55 inch television.
I watch TV on a 10 inch television
and I'm fine. I don't need a new car.
I've got a 1958 Subaru.
Did they even make Subaru's
in 58 probably not.
That's probably all shitty American cars
back then and a couple of Ferrari's.
It's probably all they had either way.
Shut up all of you and go to the blog
that Aubrey wrote about this because it's
a very good blog and is there a
straight link to the blog from the,
the main site? I'm trying to find your
hair, get on it and then blog. Yeah,
get on it and then blog, um, or being,
or being on it and blog if
you've never been on it before,
what we call on it is a human
optimization website. Well, we sell,
whether it's supplements or whether it's
strength and conditioning equipment is
all stuff that we a know works and be
used when it comes to kettle bells when it
comes to battle ropes.
Those are my absolute favorite strength
and conditioning pieces of equipment.
There's nothing to me
better than kettle bells.
I think there's nothing that
I've ever done that, uh,
I feel like I have full control over.
Like I don't, I don't worry about it.
Like there's certain
things that I worry about,
like I've run with sandbags up hills
and I think there's a lot of tricky shit
when you're running up hills and like,
you know,
a rocky terrain and stuff like dirt, dirt
trails when you're running over things.
Like,
I like it.
I think it's a great way to like really
build some serious endurance. But man,
I don't really feel totally in control.
I'm kind of sandbag.
I'm running up a hill, done it with
heavy bags too, like, you know, like, uh,
kicking bags.
But with kettle bells,
I feel like I can get an absolutely
fucking brutal death defying workout in.
And I know what I'm doing.
I use proper technique.
I don't get hurt using kettle bells.
Man.
I can just absolutely say that I have
been using kettle bells for at least a
decade now. I have zero injuries from
training with Kettlebells, kettlebells.
And one of the reasons folks is I got
a trainer, okay. Um, I've had several.
The first one was Jamie Walsh,
my English friend, the night
I, Steve Maxwell also have someone, uh,
Justin Milo's, who's the best love this
fucking guy, the guy I'm using now.
It's a good friend of mine as well.
Find someone who can teach you the
basic fundamentals, whether it's,
you know, a gym that you have to hire
a trainer and let them, you know,
tape you with a cell phone so you can
repeat your movements or watch a video.
If you don't have anybody anywhere near
where you live that has a kettle bells
or understands how you watch
a video and start out light,
use like an 18 pound kettle bell
or 25 pound kettle ball. Trust me,
you will be fucking manly, man. I
don't need a 25 pound kettle. You know,
you'd also don't need torn ligaments.
You don't need to drop a kettle
bell in your head. Stupid.
You don't need to fuck up.
Your Turkey has get up and now you have
a different face. All right? Be careful,
but if you aren't careful,
you will enjoy the fuck out of it and
you'll join the fuck out of everything.
We sell it on it. That's O. N N I t.
Use the codeword Rogan and save
yourself 10% off any n all supplements.
My brother Aubrey Marcus is here.
Yeah, buddy. Same time. Cue The music.
Joe Rogan Experience Joe
Rogan podcast all day.
Okay,
and here we are, ladies and gentlemen.
One more time. Live kicking it.
W never worry whether or not we're going
to run out of shit to talk about it.
I don't ever want you to worry about that.
Before we had this conversation,
obviously we still have
shit to talk about.
We're always going to have shit
to talk about it. There's no,
the world is a crazy fucking place filled
with madness and d is never going to
change and there's, oh,
we shouldn't talk about,
that's the most beautiful
thing about having a podcast.
It's like being a dirt minor now. That's
just fucking dirt everywhere, man.
You can't go wrong. There's always
something to talk about. And Jamie,
you sent me something over this weekend
that was a about the drugs are getting
fucked over or uh, getting
fucked off at. Yeah.
Yeah. It happened this week
actually, I think it was Tuesday. Um,
Cup quite a few congressmen got their
chance to take their shot out. My,
I suppose,
and this is the drugs are under the Obama
administration called the czar is kind
of Russian.
Why are you doing drugs are,
that's a fucking stupid. Do you think
gluten makes us hookers? Columns are, uh,
he probably has some American name.
You'll call me president of the
United States because present though,
they all want to be president,
United States,
all those gangsters that
are running those, you know,
they know Russia is a mess.
You don't want to run that thing.
They should be fucking running America
flying over New York City and fucking
Soluton people. But no trap in that
frozen wasteland with a few goods.
Scott got some stars and stripes boxer
briefs that he pulls out. Bay does.
I bet it does. Basically, he's a
secret. Want to be American, right?
So what did they say to
this fucking Bizarre Colin?
I'm not quite sure the czar gets
his chance to talk back to this guy.
This went on for like an hour and
a half. Quite a few. Like I said,
quite a few guys got their chance at them.
Um,
talk about low hanging fruit.
Well,
shitting on the drugs. Are they
mean if the Zen, it's this effort.
Has there ever been any sort of a company,
any sort of a,
an off,
any sort of an office that has had less
success than the people that look for
the war on drugs? The
abolitionist, a banning alcohol
and the 20s and right. Good.
That's even like less because they
abandoned that one. Yeah, they gave up.
Fuck it.
We tap out.
The war on drugs is like a dude that
just keeps getting his ass kicked.
Just getting up. Keep getting
his ass kicked. Did you,
you're not even close
to winning this fight.
There's no way you're
going to win this fight.
Like the idea of a war on
drugs and being run by Ozar.
Holy Schmoe.
What up fucking what a terrible job.
You guys have done. Out of all
the things we think about, look,
the great thing with the Department
of, uh, what a transportation,
whoever's done the highway
systems, I mean, it's amazing.
You can drive from
California to New York City.
You could do it in four days.
Anybody can do it.
You could drive all the way up to Canada.
You drive down to Florida. I mean,
you could literally make your
way across the entire country,
visit every state by car.
I mean that had to be worked out slowly
but surely. We had a paved roads.
We had to chop down trees, blow holes
through mountains. That was awesome.
They did an amazing job.
I mean,
people that want to complain about
the highway system, dude, what?
You make your own highway. Let's see what
you would do. Yeah. It's not perfect.
It's made by humans. Nothing we do
is perfect, but then the drugs are,
it's like creating a highway where
only people crash. Yeah, that's it.
It's just only crashes and falls apart.
It's just bridges fall down.
You run straight into mountains
where they're supposed to be tunnels.
Sometimes it's concrete. Sometimes it's
paper over Saint Coles don't tell Ya.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean they're their
fate. A total abject failures.
There's never been like EP department
that has failed more like across though.
Even in the fucking immigration,
they stopped some of that shit,
you know they fucking have,
you know,
everybody knows about those
border patrol guys. They,
they have a run across the border if
they want to make it into America.
There's a lot of work and crossing
into from Mexico into America.
It's not a done deal, but the war
on drugs get the fuck outta here.
The amount of damage you've done
to drugs is absolutely zero.
All you've taken a few drugs out
of the system. The fuck you have.
You've just made them more expensive and
a commodity so people can create these
gangster organizations.
Yeah.
Even even crazier that that part
create these Mexican cartels.
Well, you remember when we were kids
in Mexico was a nice place to visit.
Fuck yeah.
I'm going to be telling some stories about
going over just going over the border
of Mexico. This was 15
years ago, 14 years ago.
It wasn't that scary that me and Eddie
Bravo went to a spring break in Mexico at
Cane Kuhn bought it the
first year and that was work.
It was kind crazy. We
got hammered too. It was,
it was a work get way too hammered and
then recover and then fly home disaster
for fucking pounding headache.
I was doing something for MTV.
I'm glad you remember it.
Yeah, I don't think he does,
but, but we had a good time.
Um, but my point is there was no
apprehension. You know, we were like, oh,
it's going to be fun. We're going
to go a see a bunch of concerts.
Like puddle of Mudd was there.
I met the rock and it was the first time
I met the rock who's a skinnier version
of the rock, but I was a skinnier
version of me too. Um, and uh, you know,
met a bunch of people. They were
back. It was fun. It was a big deal.
We're just going to go
to Mexico just like,
you know how I feel like if I would go to
Australia, yeah, it's cool. Here we are.
But now it's like fucking beheadings
and chainsaws and people hanging from
bridges and body bags, plastic hefty
bags filled with chopped up people.
And he leans out from his Cape and says,
you're welcome world.
You're welcome. Could I have done
my fingers? Wave prevented crying.
Imagine what it would be if I wasn't here
and what a shit job.
Because they've literally pumped up
gigantic criminal organizations by keeping
people from legitimately selling
things that they want to sell.
And we're not even done lean.
There's,
there's always gonna be something that
the community doesn't want and there's
always going to be idiots
who want that something,
whether it's smelling paint those crazy
fucks that blow paint into a paper bag
and then they huff it. That's what
they're doing. I mean, they're just,
they're taking fucking paint and they're
smelling it. You can't prevent that.
You can't prevent that kind of
retard. You can't, you can't stop it.
So as long as there are hammers,
there's going to be someone that hits
himself in the fucking face with a hammer.
There's no,
there's no way to prevent that.
So to to make things completely across
the board illegal just because they're
dangerous.
That sets a really fucked up precedent
because you've got to start examining all
the other things that are
legal. Like here, I don't want
to suggest this, but here,
how come you could get a lighter at a
fucking gas station and how come that gas
station has a pump that pours flammable
liquid on it and there's no guards
anywhere.
There's no one to stop you from just
pouring flammable liquid on someone's car
and lighting a match and throwing it on
there. There's no one there to stop that.
But everybody's worried that
people are going to have guns. Oh,
what's the people with the
guns are going to kill,
but they're her walk random and
the people and just kill people.
They could also light you on
fire at the gas station. Okay.
That doesn't happen now, you know? I mean,
we can't stop people from selling saws
at fucking home depot because someone
runs out and just runs into the mall.
Just start sewing at people. We can't.
And the other argument was all loaded
gun is more effective tool. That's true.
So bombs. Okay. And you can
make those. There's the fucking,
you can make real legitimate bombs at
of all the things that you could find
in your average chemical store,
things that are legal and you can make
them bite with the ingredients on the
Internet.
It's out there,
but then you take this back to drugs
and let's say it's not actually,
most of these drugs are not anything
like taking a hammer and hitting yourself
in the head. It's actually, you know,
as we've all seen, and we'll talk about,
I'm sure on this one,
as we always do,
myriad benefits from all of these
different drugs. And not only that,
so let's say it was like a hammer.
Let's say it was punching yourself
in the head with a hammer. Well,
the punishment for doing that to prevent
you from doing that is to throw you in
a box with crazy criminals and completely
dehumanize you where you may or may
not get raped. Who knows? I watched a lot
of Oz. It looks like it sucks and there,
but there's no possible way that that
isn't worse than what you're doing to
yourself when you're taking
some drugs in your house. Yeah.
They're not trying to help you,
not just punishing you and making it
scary for everybody else. And by the way,
I'm not against gun regulations at all.
I should just be real clear about that.
I'm also not against drug regulations.
I think it shouldn't be easy to go
to a doctor and just get oxycontin's.
I think there's a reason why,
and by the way,
whoever sent me some information
about that apparently, uh,
since we had that podcast
with the people from vanguard,
did the oxycontin
express that documentary,
apparently Florida has tightened down
there a drug laws substantially because of
that,
because that documentary exposed how
fucking insane that whole oxycontin
expresses that goes from
Florida to the northern states.
It's just a pipeline of Oxycontin and
the massive amount of people that have
prescriptions for it.
But now it's apparently becoming a real
issue for the people that are addicted
because now they're fucked because
they don't have anything to fill.
That addiction that was created
by the pharmaceutical companies,
making sure that the drug prescription
laws were very lax in Florida,
so they can profit. It's all
fucking bananas. So yeah,
that would help Ibogaine,
um, the, I'm not,
I'm not against regulation. Like, you
know, everybody thinks that it's a,
this is a black and white
thing. It's like, no, it's
not a black and white thing,
but you can't tell people
what to do either. You know,
I'm not against regulation,
but I'm,
I'm against you telling people what to do,
especially if you can't prove your point.
And when,
when you start talking about
marijuana or psychedelics,
when it's mushrooms or even Lsd,
the amount of danger that you are in when
you take LSD and compare the amount of
danger that you take when you eat
salt, you know, you could eat,
we found out 10 ounces of salt.
We'll fucking kill you.
10 ounces. That's it.
Nobody thinks about that.
But you fucking sprinkles salt in your
fries and salt on this and saw it at
fucking salted Carmel ice cream.
It was delicious.
Like we don't think about salt
being murderous and deadly,
but at a certain level it is.
You get to a certain amount of salt,
we'll fuck you up.
So I'll acid and this is an LD 50 for
most things as an LD 50 for mushrooms.
It's quite high.
LD 50 for marijuana,
1500 pounds in 15 minutes.
It's, come on, man.
You when you'd say assault is legal
and 10 ounces will kill you. I Dunno,
I'm beating like two brownies that
I'm pretty sure I'm not a die.
I've been there when I'm like,
I'm not going to be the number one guy,
the first guy to die. I'm going
to fuck up the whole cause. Well,
you know what does die. That was your
ego. That's why I feel like that there's,
people don't understand what a deep
psychedelic experience eating wheat is.
It's insanely psychedelic and really,
especially if you can do
it with an isolation tank,
eating the weed and getting
it to the tag is like,
it was so fucking cyclone a vortex.
It takes you to the center of
the universe and destroys you,
like destroys,
like just highlights everything that you
don't like about everything you've ever
said brings up shit that you said a decade
ago. And he was like, what about this?
Have you cleaned that up yet? What
about that? Do you remember this?
This should make you feel bad.
Bob Marley said it's the mirror that
reveals you to yourself. It really does.
People don't like that,
but you should.
I talked to somebody yesterday and the
only drug he'd ever done was he one time
he smoked weed and he liked it and
he's like, oh, that was awesome.
So he made a bunch of brownies and they
didn't really know what they were doing
and he just ate a bunch of them right?
And then had,
and he was trying to drive somewhere and
meet people and he said it was like the
most miserable experience. He's going
40 miles an hour on the highway.
He's freaking out. He's sweating. It's
the second time he's ever done any,
ate too much. He's like, man, I couldn't
handle any other psychedelic drugs.
I'm like,
listen man,
I've done most of them and eating too
much weed is like the most intense shit
I've ever done. You know what I
mean? From all over the world.
That will fucking get you somewhere.
Yeah, I have to deal with it.
I felt much better after
d and every DMT trip,
every DM t trip I've had has freaked me
out. That taught me a lot about life,
taught me a lot about myself,
given me these weird visions and weird
insights and, but when it's over,
I feel good.
I feel like legitimately good when I
feel like I get raped when I do too much
weed, like I just get mounted by
a demon and have my face fucked,
just clause in my brain.
And
then you sitting there
taking it. Ooh, knowing,
knowing that the end is
without a doubt coming,
whether it's 50 years or
60 years or a hundred year,
however long you think
you're gonna live stupid,
it's common and no one knows what's next.
And your whole life has been running on
this momentum of madness the whole life,
the whole fucking thing right out of the
vagina. Bam, crazy parents, crazy life.
Hong Kong,
beep beep fuck you tonight on the news,
your life madness
and trying to stay afloat.
You know river of fucking crazy people.
Everywhere you go bobbing fucking
crazy maniacs all over television,
all over school.
Every fucking person you date,
every person you stick your
penis inside or they let you,
you stick their penis inside of you.
Whatever it is, they're all fucking crazy.
And guess what? Fuck phase. You're crazy
too. You're crazy. We're all crazy.
And then you take a little dip
where everything can get quiet
and you have this moment of clarity
where you can reflect back on this crazy
circus you've been in and
really think about it.
And then maybe make some
course corrections. Make
some changes pop out of it.
That's what's beautiful about it.
Didn't Zen, they call it Satori.
These moments of clarity and
consciousness and a general circus of life
awareness. So the reset button, that's it.
I'd like to do it once a month,
some way or another. Once a month,
hit the reset and a lot, you know, I
have a huge benefit of having that tank.
Having that tank in my basement
is so gigantic. Hell yeah.
Cause if I ever need to
just go on a a wild one,
I just eat a pot brownie again.
That fucking thing.
Space Cheese fries.
Yeah.
I've become molecules in a never ending
fractal universe before I was, uh,
I, I was in, it's one
vision that was so intense.
The problem with these things is they're
so intense, especially by the way,
when I take Alpha brain,
I've got this new way of, uh,
wherever we've always
talked about the dreams.
Like Alpha brain has a really
intense effect on dreams,
but it also seems to have a very intense
effect on the visualizations that I get
when I eat marijuana.
Like I get it more intense
series of things that I see.
Like when you eat it, like when
you close your eyes, not when I'm,
my eyes are open. There's no
hallucinogenic effects or at least for me,
but what am I close my eyes.
I see things in front of my eyelids
like dancing cartoons that are neon and
they're having sex and breeding and stuff.
I see like weird, crazy shit almost,
you know, like very, very psychedelic.
Like if your eyes were open
and you saw those things,
you would think, wow, I'm on,
I'm on something serious
amounts of mushrooms here.
But having your eyes closed and just
envisioning these things like as a dream
somehow I know that they become
less preposterous or less crazy,
but it's very intensely hallucinogenic
and more so it seems when I Take Alpha
brain, so the eating of the pot,
which is intensely hallucinogenic,
I mean I've had wild experiences eating
it and just being on a plane and closing
my eyes on a plane and seeing just
nutty fucking light shows in front of my
eyelids.
But inside the tank it's just cranks it
up to 10 just find some new gear that
you didn't know existed.
I think seeing those things to me is a
good sign that you're in that state of
presence.
You're in
that state of the nether where you're
just accessing the unconscious realms of
the mind. And that's for me, even
when I meditate with nothing,
that's what I'm kind of shooting for.
It's if I can close my eyes
and start drifting into other,
just following the visions without trying
to direct them or think that's when I
know my mind is shut off and
that's what I know. I'm in a good,
good place and psychedelics tend to have
that characteristic always with them as
well.
And I think it goes hand in hand.
It's just that's what happens when the
mind gets quiet and you're just kind of
floating around looking at these
images as they appear. Yeah. So thing
that you do when you're in a
normal state of consciousness,
we sort of see almost controlling
and defining your reality by your,
your,
your ability to see things clearly.
You know where they are
and you know distances.
You've got everything locked down.
You know where everything is.
You see the people around
you see the objects,
but when you're on a psychedelic
and you're closing your eyes,
or even if you're in like
having meditation, you're
closing your eyes, you, you,
your imagination starts to kick in and
you start to see and dream and feel
things. They don't have to be there.
The idea that they have to be,
you have to put those on
a scale for them to count.
Like you have to take those
ideas and hit them with a hammer.
Otherwise they're not real. No, they're,
they're, they're real. Like the,
the imaginary idea is that you get with
your eyes closed depending on what's
causing them,
whether it's meditation and Yoga,
whether you got punched in the
face and you're seeing stars,
whatever the fuck it is that's
causing it there. There's still,
these visions are still real.
You know,
you could say their hallucinations
and you'd be correct medically.
But if, say, if I gave you a DMT and I,
I told you what I'm going to give you
is a natural psychedelic compound that
your own brain produces and all it
really does when I give it to you is it's
going to fuck with your cerebral cortex.
Fuck with your visual
interpretations of things.
And you're going to see
things all scrambled up.
Like as if like your connectors are
plugged in wrong on your television.
You just can see a bunch of crazy shit.
So don't worry about it.
Doesn't mean anything.
And you come back and you say,
I saw God and he told me the nature
of the universe is love and that the
universe is actually made of of love.
And understanding the suffering only
exists for us to be able to truly
appreciate the love and
as human beings evolve,
the suffering and the and
the love will do battle.
And this is literally the good and evil
of the Bible. And this is what, what,
why this has been interpreted
by every major religion.
This is this internal
struggle that we all know.
This is a reason why it's so admirable
when someone becomes a good person,
because we know how difficult
it is to always choose the
light. No, no, no, no, no,
no. You were just tripping. No, no,
no, no. You don't understand, man.
We gave you a DMT in your brain fucked up.
Now,
if I gave you a another pill and I said,
this is a pill that was brought to us
by angels and it came in this, this,
this beautiful crystal box
and it's directly from God
and it's a door to door to
God's kingdom and you're going to get to
talk to him and hang out with them for
15 minutes and you want to do it, you'd
be like, oh my God, it's from God. Yes,
it's from God. It's from God. It has
a look. The pill is a cross on it.
Take it so you take it,
you go direct and you have the exact
same experience that I described,
the exact same experience as an
experience where the guy told you, oh,
just cerebral cortex is
confused and you're just
seeing shit that's not there in
your imagination.
Creates got the experience is exactly
the same and that's what people have to
understand. Everybody wants to the
same assholes. I want to bite them.
I just don't work. Well, you don't
need them. You'd know maybe shut up.
It's not what the fuck is going on.
This is the exact same reason why there's
this need to dispel any notions that
you're having spiritual experience and
to sort of minimize those experiences,
but it's the same experience.
And if you benefit from that experience
to the same extent as you had benefited
from a real visit with angels,
then then it's just as good dummy.
This is causing the positive effect
that you could only dream to achieve by
doing that. And it's being
duplicated by science to now,
you know the swings Hopkins study and it's
real. This isn't Mormonism, right? Yeah.
This isn't fucking scientists.
Golden tablets like found
in Pennsylvania or whatever.
All you have to do is smoke this
stuff and you fucking travel to other
dimensions. Like, I'm not making
it up. You'd say, I'm making it up,
but every fucking person that's ever
done it comes back to me and goes,
you weren't even making that up. Nope.
I wasn't even making up crazy. Huh.
Crazy that you're hearing about
that from the fear factor guy.
So I was thinking about opening the
archives. I've never talked about it,
but my very first psychedelic experiences
that Kinda got me on this path.
I've told the IOWASCA story,
the bogus story,
but this is all after I've been
somewhat through the initiation cycle.
So I was thinking of getting into
that and where was it? So this was,
I was like between 18 and 22,
so in college and I started my first
one at 18 and I'm going to change the
geographic location just a little bit,
cause in case she's still rocking
and rolling out there anyway.
So go out to the southwest crossover.
Um,
she picks me up in a land cruiser.
Whatever's got a dog and a car and she is,
you know,
kind of that loose showman,
but more of like a more of like a
psychiatric kind of medicine giver,
you know,
not really.
Not trained in these ancient arts
are ways and indigenous people.
She just kind of knew about the medicine,
had a great heart and,
and so she picks me up and I'm pretty
fucking terrified. I've done nothing.
I smoke weed once with my brothers and
had laugh and we ate like the worst food.
What it means you want to do this?
I was like v I'm very curious by nature.
Like I wanted to see what was possibly
get you involved from gay sex and be very
careful. Wow. I haven't been curious
about that yet. They'll get, you know,
feel free to curious because
motherfuckers are tricky.
They're guys remember that always
you might take guys are God. So yeah.
And I was fairly agnostic.
I kind of had a sense that
maybe there was something more,
but I was more borderline
atheist add, there ain't shit.
You know, you go in a box.
All these people are,
cause I knew enough and I know I went to
high school in Texas and they're always
trying to get me to these
Christian ministry things
and I'm asking him question.
They're looking at me like,
Huh, you know, I was like,
this is a bunch of fucking bullshit.
So I was more on the atheist side.
So I decided, you know, as a
connection through the old, you know,
old family friends and I
just decided to go off.
They're kind of like a rite of passage,
so picks me up. I'm nervous as shit.
We get to the place,
there's some nice little mountains and
hills and we got this like little year
that I'm going to stay in a year. It
was a year. Yeah. Built up out there,
no power and anything like that. And uh,
so we're going to do it the next day.
She says, okay, goodnight.
You know, here's everything
you need. So I'm up all night.
Just nervous as shit cause that you feel
like you're about to jump off a cliff.
You have no idea what's going to
go down. And I sometimes, you know,
I get a lot of these people sending me
messages and I forget what I was like
that very first time cause
it's fucking terrifying now.
So I get up early in the morning and I
go for a long walk and I'm just trying to
get my head around this.
I'm so afraid that I'm going to
completely lose touch with reality,
that I'm just, and I may never get
back, you know, that's the fear.
Like you're going to be so
gone. What's there? What's left?
How do you cling to anything? You have no
control, you know? So I'm freaking out.
So on my way back from the hike,
I kind of get my head in a good place
and I pick up this rock and it's rather
flat and I still have it to this
day. And I was like, all right,
I'm going to hold this
rock through the ceremony.
And if ever I feel like I'm completely
out of touch with the earth,
I'm going to have this rock here and
that's going to let me know that there are
rocks.
And one day I'll go back to the world
of the rocks and I'll at least be okay.
So we go and we're about to
start the ceremony. And, um,
my very first ceremony was going to be,
and she was very open with what she was
giving me was going to be a combination
of mushrooms and Mtma pure mdms.
Whoa,
she's candy flipping you
right off the bat off the bat.
So she and we go and we set an intention.
He had me write an intention for what
I was going to do and I'm nervous.
I have no idea. So I read my intention
and I'm already like pretty emotional.
And then we have a tea,
I drink the tea and I take the pill
and I just kind of wait and my heart's
thumping.
I don't know what's going to happen.
And then I think probably the MTMA started
kicking in first and I was like, Ugh,
God damn,
this feels pretty good.
And then then the mushrooms started
really kicking and then the visionary
experience started to happen.
And I remember one of my first visions,
I was walking through like a field of
grass and I was just feeling my hands move
through the grass. Like I was pushing,
pushing right through the grass.
And then I could feel like my breathing
didn't seem that necessary anymore.
And I was almost becoming
disconnected from my breath.
And then I could feel the wind coming
through and all of a sudden the wind just
went right through me and I was,
my physical body no longer
existed in that moment.
It was almost like I am
sure I still was breathing,
but it felt like I absolutely was not
and didn't need to and it didn't matter.
And my spirit was
disconnected from my body.
And at that moment was probably one of
the most defining moments in my life.
Cause I realized,
Holy Shit,
this little meet vehicle that I'm really
attached to is not what I really am.
It's just a car that I'm driving around
and for now and like this other thing
that I'm experiencing and
feeling separate from that body,
that's something different.
And the clarity I had from that moment,
from being able to separate from
my body was immense. You know?
And I realized at some point,
you know, when you're free of,
when you're free of these
bodily confines and the mind,
you're going to be able to look back at
your life and see everything that you've
done,
good or bad.
And if it's good and you've lived well
and you've pushed out as much love and
done the best you can,
you're going to be in a heaven,
in a heavenly state at that point.
It's going to be having, you know,
you've done your job in this earth, you've
had a great time, you spread the light,
spread the love and and done, you know,
done what you were there to do basically.
But if you've lived,
you know,
badly and done harm to people and hurt
people and increase the suffering of the
world at that point,
the blinders are just ripped off your
eyes and you got to stare dead in the face
of all the demons and evil you've
ever done. And that's fucking hell.
That's a hell that's worth no worse than
any fire and brimstone cause there's no
way to not look. It's like one of those
horror movies where they have you,
you know,
your eyes pinned open and you can't not
look at something terrible in front of
you except you're looking back at your
own life. And, and I realized that,
you know,
all,
I had a lot of anger towards Christianity
at that point and I was like,
this is all bullshit. I was like, wait a
minute, maybe there is a heaven and hell,
you know, it just doesn't
involve the demons and the
Sugar Candy Mountain and the
bullshit.
But it's a point where you're reconnected
with spirit and you get to look back
and reflect your life and
nobody else needs a torture.
You or pat you on the back,
wish you to the pearly gates.
That's all going to be through yourself.
And that changed the fucking game forever.
Why was that first experience?
First experience,
not just knocks it out of the park.
I was up and that was,
that was a really cool night
for me. I was up, you know,
all the stars are there were far,
far away from electricity and the
old dog that was in the car was um,
you know, had really bad hips and they
had a main, the main kind of house,
Little Casa that was way warmer
that a bunch of fires and things.
There's nice and cozy out in the year. It
was, you know, much more kind of rural,
not much, not much going. They've
got a really blanket up and uh,
I was pretty vulnerable at that point.
I was out of my body or whatever and the
coyote start coming in at the night and
I remember that the old dog just
stayed right outside my door.
Never spent the night outside cause it's
old arthritic dog and just stayed out
there awake all night with me.
You know,
as I was kind of going through this stuff
and it was just kind of a cool kinship.
I felt probably one of the first times
I felt like a real kinship with another
species, like a different animal
that she was high as fuck.
Cling into reality.
He had a rock and a dog man.
And I was just on a fucking mission.
And so I went back,
I went back to her and did the same
thing, you know, meet her in the airport,
go drive across the border and then,
and then go to these journeys.
I did several different other, you know,
interesting things from that point. Uh,
I snuffed,
I snuffed five Meo DMT,
which was a fucking wild experience.
Snuffed it down in Mexico. Yup.
Snuffed it.
So they created,
I think it was a snuff from the bufo
toxin in some kind of traditional way. Uh,
I'm hoping they harvested it, you know,
friendly from the frog or whatever,
but they created a snuff and you know,
pretty much there was this like
caterpillar looking at amount of powder.
It was like Ruddy Brown. And um,
that was, this was my second,
this is my second journey.
Second time down to see her.
And I guess I had some kind of
straw or something. I was snorting,
it wasn't a rolled up Hundo it was like
some kind of Straw or old kind of seed
tube. And, um, and so I snuffed it.
And how was my first DMT experience?
But of course, as you know, five
Meo DMT is a much different animal.
It's even stronger. Yeah, it was,
it was a really incredibly
personal experience.
So in that experience, I went back
and relived, I had a great child,
I have no complaints,
but my dad had a pretty savage temper
and it would just build up and he would
get really intimidating and start yelling
at me. And I, I guess I built up some,
some issues about that, you know,
it's probably most kids would,
I was pretty young when this would happen
and it fucking put me right back in
the room with one of these most intense
experiences and I was reliving it and my
dad was in the same place just
yelling at me like, blah, blah.
And all of a sudden I is that little
kid like became the man that I was,
I was 1920 and I was like,
you're gonna fucking yell at me
like that now I am. Look at me now.
You want to do that shit to me now?
And it was turning this fear that I
had had into like this standing up for
myself and rage like I fucking dare you.
So you went as an adult almost in
relive the six completely relived it.
But with the strength that I had
accumulated as an adult, you know,
I was doing kickboxing and I was lifting
weights and you know, I was pretty,
pretty athletic at that point,
more so than my father.
And at that point I
just relived it as this,
don't you fucking dare do that to
me? I will. And, and there was shit,
it was really heavy.
Right.
And I was in that fucking
space the whole time.
Like it wasn't like I was
imagining it that was happening.
Like I was in the room and there was
tears. And then ultimately, you know,
ultimately a US kind of forgiveness, you
know, where in my vision he was like,
I'm so sorry. You know, it's
like, I understand. And I was
like, okay. And we kind of,
my relationship with him since then,
for the 12 years after was
that like fixed a huge,
huge divide between us.
You know where I could say I'm a man now
and I'm not scared of you. No matter,
no matter what you try to do,
you know,
and I kind of reversed this thing
that had me a little fearful.
It had me feeling not like a man myself
I guess because I got kind of dominated
in a way by my father figure.
And that was kind of the real
coming of age experience for me.
There was a guy at the park the other day,
I was with my,
my kids when we were playing around.
Some guys playing with his kid
seems real friendly and he says, uh,
hey man, uh, he's gonna you're going to
be raising his hand someday about his son.
Like meaning that his son is going to
be an MMA fighter and I almost want to
tell him like,
not if you do a good job at wall.
I mean it sounds fucked up,
but I mean there's a few guys who had
a real good parents like George Saint
Pierre or John Jones still his parents
come to every fight. And, I mean,
I obviously,
I don't know what the relationship
that they had with their parents was,
but there's a large percentage,
a very large percentage of fighters
who were beaten up and fucked with as a
young kid and not just bullied by,
by their kids at school,
but beaten by their parents. You
know, child abuse. I mean there's,
there's a ton of them. Yeah. Um, there's
a guy who was arrested yesterday,
Tiago Silva. Did you hear this
story standoff with police?
I didn't dig deep armed standoff
with the police in Miami. A parent,
I don't know the whole story,
but apparently involved a woman and a,
I don't know what the fuck happened.
It might have involved drugs.
There's a bunch of different
versions of it. Obviously the dude,
it was a crazy person.
Whatever happened,
there was allegedly some guns
and allegedly some fucking,
he's a murderer. It meaning
they're in the cage. I mean,
Taco Silva is a scary motherfucker.
Fuck yeah. He comes after dudes.
He's imagine that guy
with no referee in a gun.
Holy Jesus Christ. You know, I
don't know what happened. So eat,
but there's a story that someone put
today on the underground about Tiago
Silva's childhood. Uh, the underground
being mixed martial arts.com,
which is one of my favorite,
well my number one favorite website
when it comes to what MMA. Just a,
an awesome forum.
Always has great up to date news.
And I know the guys who run it in
a very, very cool guys, but the,
the actual story of him growing up,
his childhood was fucking horrific.
Horrific to read.
I had to stop reading it.
It's talking about his dad just regularly
beating the fucking shit out of him
and he has a big scar on his head from
when he was a little boy was dad fucking
opened him up. I mean,
terrifying, terrifying shit.
That's how you make a really scary guy.
Like Thiago Silva.
He make a guy who doesn't want
to fucking take it anymore.
He's tired of it and he learns
how to stand up for himself.
But along the way sometimes,
you know,
you can make a fucking monster can,
you can make a monster with abuse.
Yeah, no doubt. It has,
it affected me, my,
one of my best friends is Roger Huerta
and it's no, it's no secret his, you know,
he was abused by pretty much
all the female figures in
his life. Pretty savagely.
Yeah. And you know, it's, it certainly
can contribute. And then there's,
there are those people who are just meant
to be the Samurai of the way, you know,
the Musashi types where it just
suits them. So it's either either or,
you have to have this deep calling from
some archetypal draw to that or there
has to be something that kind of
deflects you in a, in a weird way.
And I wonder if I hadn't done all
these different things, you know,
mine wasn't that severe. As I said, I had
a great fucking child. I'm very blessed.
Um,
but I wonder if I wouldn't have wanted to,
cause I was on the borderline for doing
some fighting and things like that.
If I hadn't gotten that out and really
felt like I could assert myself fully as,
as a man then in that rite of passage,
maybe I would've sought it in
the cage somehow. You know,
maybe that would have had to fulfill
that role for even me. You know,
you never know like where obviously
I was never destined to be a fucking
champion, but maybe I'd have gone
into some smokers or something, but,
but you know,
it's,
it's interesting and the effects that
that can have and really doing the heavy
work, doing the heavy lifting,
that sitting there talking
on a couch to somebody,
you know,
you're not going to get there.
You aren't going to see
it happening and rewrite,
reprogram the history in your brain.
So when I look at that back now,
it's not like poor me. It's, it's,
I'm sorry my dad had to, you know,
inflict that, that's going to be
hurting him, but I'm not affected.
I'm not scared by that anymore.
I overcame that from, you know,
from the help of this,
this medicine. Yeah. The,
the feelings that I had when
I was in high school was,
the big one was I moved around a lot.
And, uh, when I was in high school,
I didn't really get picked on. I went to
a really good school. It's a nice place.
I mean everybody gets
bullied a little bit.
You get fucked with by people
a little bit. But um, my,
my zest for fighting was almost all
entirely based on my childhood is based on
trying to overcome any feelings of,
of weakness or vulnerability
that I had when I was younger.
So as I got less and less vulnerable,
it's my desire to fight
got less and less to,
it was really fascinating to
especially experience in retrospect.
Look back on it like,
um,
once I was out of the house and I
wasn't living with my mom and my stepdad
anymore and it was on my own and just
live in like I have almost a zero
aggression. It was weird. It was
like I wasn't in school anymore.
I didn't know what he was
telling me what to do anymore.
I didn't have this feeling like I was
going to be this a utter complete failure
because I couldn't get through school
without falling asleep, so fucking bored.
But as I got like 19, 20, 21,
then it became about
this intense challenge.
Then it became a much more
healthy appreciation for
competition because when I
was 16 I just wanted to fuck people up
and I met my parents actually didn't want
me to do martial arts because they were
terrified that I was going to become
this angry kid who knew
how to fuck people up.
Whereas before it was just angry kid who
really couldn't do anything. It wasn't,
wasn't dangerous. I was, you know, and
then this 11 year old became 12
and the 12 year olds like, ah,
I want to be like Bruce Lee. You
know, like under the fuck you. No,
I don't think so. You know, didn't want
me having, didn't chucks. I had noon.
Chuck's all the time.
People are just taking shit away from me.
I'd make them in the woodshop.
I tell him that I was making a chair legs,
fucking my chair's grab two broken legs.
Funny that they look exactly like
nunchucks. Mr Jason, who's the,
every kid loved nunchucks.
Everybody did.
Of course the Bruce Lee
movies, man, there were dope.
Let me see him swinging around. I had a
really funny story that happened there.
So there was a kid,
I was like seven and there was a kid,
neighbor kid who was like
12 and he was big, you know,
way bigger than me and he would kind of
pick on me a little bit just because he
was bigger.
But I had a bunch of older brothers so
they would always keep them in line or
whatever.
One day he did something fucked up to me
and again at seven versus 12 so they're
like, Nah, we got a plan.
And I had, you know,
those foam nunchucks that you could
get and they're like playing around.
They had a hard center
and foam on the outside.
So I had those hidden behind my back and
my brother was holding me back and he
says, Ryan, go take your
shots man. I'm fucking sick.
I was Chris and I'm sick of Chris
is bullshit. Go take your shots.
And meanwhile he's holding me,
Lucy and I just have these
nunchucks and this guy's like, yeah,
I'm going to get him an cheap shots.
It goes up to punch me in the stomach
and I just whip them out like fucking
Bruce Lee.
And just go ape shit on this 12 year
old kid and I remember I was like,
I am fucking Bruce Lee's.
Oh yeah,
I could let him up up. They
were hitting him. They,
it was like a fucking swarm of bees.
He just ran into funny.
What a dumb ass. Yeah, I'm holding
my brother back. Come Punch him.
Yeah. I'm an asshole. Believes that
the kid deserves it. He deserves it.
Just that's a lesson the universe
taught him. What are you fucking stupid?
It's not going to hold his brother
and let him let you punch him.
Silly Bitch is Bruce Lee with the nun
chucks and that video will go that
it was fucking people
up with new and trex.
Bruce Lee was the inventor
of the retard wagon train.
It's like one guy stands in the
center and they all take turns,
which fucking never happens in
the real world by the way folks.
They come at you a mass of bodies.
You get Paul centrally located and that
one person grabs you and you maybe get
to punch one or two as they drag it to
the ground and break everything on your
body, stop you in new order.
Fucking apple sauce pub.
There's a lot of myths that I think
came up from those martial arts.
I started watching a little bit of that
UFC documentary, that 20 years thing.
That was kind of cool. This is an
intense, it's fucking almost cried.
I was never thought about what happened.
That was pretty powerful. Yeah.
When we're sitting in talking about it,
and I was talking about how long
I've been doing this and it's weird.
Yeah. 20 fucking years and long ass
time. But meanwhile, in 20 years,
the 20 years of the UFC has
been around 21. Now the world,
the world of martial arts has evolved more
than it hasn't for thousands of years.
Yup. Thousands. Like
people know exactly what
works now. I mean, there's a
few weird as me, Oh, so cute.
There's a few, um, like, um,
techniques that are just starting
to creep in. There's a few, uh,
like taekwondo techniques, like
you rarely, rarely see acts kicks,
but occasionally someone will throw
an ax kick. Uh, this guy, Ama, God,
this guy has been fight in
the UFC I guess is back.
I must've been in taekwondo work,
some karate or something,
but he throws a bunch of fucking wild
kicks and spinning three 60 round kicks
and shit like that. And he does,
he knocked guy with a three 60,
we'll kick wants a in a fight.
It just, what makes those viable,
it seems to me is you have to be good
enough at everything else before you can
attempt that. If you just come in there
and that's what you got and your toolkit,
you gonna get taken down. Yeah, you're
going to get drug into fucking bad places.
You got to have a good ground game
and you've got to have a good takedown
defense. If you don't have a good takedown
defense, you got to have a good guard.
It's one of the Donald Cerrone, so good
[inaudible] he's like a, an expert kicker,
but he also has a wicked guard. Like
if you'd take him down like he fucked,
haven't done them up.
When they went to the ground,
he caught him in a triangle and
just locked it up tight. Yeah,
he's triangles nasty and he likes
fighting. You know, those are those,
that's another good component to Donald's.
Roney but that head kick now kicked that
guy in the neck. Oh my God. Beautiful.
Beautiful Shin to the neck.
Yeah.
Adriano Martine's he fucking caught
them shin to the neck. Ernesto.
Whose style do you just shut off,
man? You Shit just shuts off. Yeah,
that's a, that's what he did. It was
beautiful. That Shinder the neck, man.
It's one of my favorite all
time techniques. Mari Smith,
who's a good buddy of mine, he, uh,
he landed that was like one of the
first head kicks in MMA. He, uh,
he landed on Conan Sylvia era back
in the extreme fighting. You hit him.
Pretty sure he's shunned them in the neck,
but uh,
that Shin to the neck technique,
man, it's a crazy thing that happens.
Your shit shouts off. Game over. Yeah.
That nerve just gets fucking bull lasted.
Here's Serone and Martine's.
This dude fucked. Oh, look at that.
I mean that is just picture perfect.
That is like,
that is exactly how the technique is
supposed to be thrown and exactly how it's
supposed to land and exactly what
happens when you get hit like that.
You just at night night. Donald
was cool too about that. He didn't,
didn't try to throw another one in there.
Yeah,
he could have easily uncorked
that punch. He's very aware. Well,
he's so aware also because
he fight so often. I mean,
he fought four times last year and
you know when you fight that much,
you're much more present.
That's the thing about fighting is
the more often you get in fights,
the more relaxed you'll get
when you're actually fighting,
the more you could fight
up to your ability.
That's why a big layoff when people talk
about ring rust is not just like when
they talk about what it, what is ring
rust, what is octagon rust, whatever it,
what is it?
Well,
what it is is you've got to get
comfortable with that crazy experience.
You've got to have that
experience really close to you.
I go like one of my
best fights ever was a,
I won this a US Open Tournament
and I are, I want it because
I had fought the week before.
I fought in a tournament the week before
and I injured my groin and I thought I
was done for like,
I was like,
I can't compete in this New Hampshire
tournament because I'm just too fucked up.
Like my, my groin is really
fucked up. But Saturday morning,
the day of the tournament,
I always got up early cause I delivered
newspapers and I was delivering
newspapers like five o'clock
in the morning and I was like,
I'm going to fucking fight.
Like I feel good.
I was really a caffeine and sugar buzz
that made me fight because I ate a bunch
of donuts.
I had fucking terrible diet back then,
but I ate a bunch of,
I burned off so many calories.
I had like four and a half percent
body fat, like no bullshit,
four and a half percent body fat.
And I was competing and um, I um,
I ate a couple of doughnuts and
drank a couple of dump of cup.
I drank a full cup of a Dunkin
donuts coffee and these two donuts,
I'll never forget it.
It was a Boston cream donut and
one of those lemon cream ones,
lemon custard ones where it's covered
in white powdered sugar filled donut.
You know,
I was reliant on sugar and I was like,
I'm going to go to New Hampshire
and fuck some people up.
But the reason why I fought so good,
I'm pretty sure it was that I had just
fought seven days ago. So it's like that,
that experience was
still fresh in my mind.
I just gotten through a whole
tournament seven days ago and one,
so I was like going to this tournament,
I was like so used to fighting. It was,
it was like,
it was last week's activity and he,
we're going to do it again this
week, you know? But when I,
one time I tore a muscle and
I had to take a long time off.
I didn't fight for like six months.
That was the longest probably ever.
And I remember when going back
to fight again, I was like,
do don't even know what the
fuck I'm doing. And like,
am I gonna freeze up out here? Like
this is, this is kind of scary. Well,
the mind gets engaged in me.
That's exactly what you don't want care
if that takes you out of the present
moment, you know? I think that's the key
for all of these. All of these sports,
any fucking sport,
you know,
you just got gotta release the mind and
the thinking about pass, pass things,
future things.
You have your game plan,
you know that going in and then just
let it go. That's one aspect of it.
But there's,
the other aspect is technique and
skill and endurance and training and
disciplines.
If you don't have that,
they're equally important
because you could be,
you could think you're a bad motherfucker
and be like totally in the zone and
completely neutral in Zen.
But if you're a white belt,
Marcella Garcia is going to fucking
strangle you. Okay? It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter what's going
through your head. Oh, you know, dude,
I'm different than other
people. I'm in the zone. I'm,
I'm completely tuned the
best of your ability,
but that may not cover the
distance between the worst
of someone else's ability.
And you could catch someone
thinking about, you know,
a girl that just cheated on him
and now I'm fucked in the head.
It's going to be so angry with,
while playing at the worst of
his ability to still smoke,
only so much you could do [inaudible]
still going to break your arm.
Heidrick gracefully is still
gonna choke you. It asleep.
It's just you're not good enough.
You have to be good enough.
And those other things,
which is one of the things
that's so beautiful about
MMA or about Jujitsu or any
martial arts, kickboxing is
it's so hard to get really good.
It's so hard.
There's so many things involved.
It has to be a list of things have to be
in order for you to win championships.
If you, you know, if you
get to be a UFC champion,
you get to be a Chris Weidman,
you get to be a Jon Jones.
So many things have to be in order
for you to get to be that good,
your mind,
your body life experiences,
the will to win the discipline is show
up at the gym, the intelligence night,
eat shitty food. All these, fuck,
I told you about winning the u s open
after you told us drinking coffee.
I was young, I was 19 or 20 I was, yeah,
you get away with a lot when you're
not really young, but the, the,
the list of things that have to be in
perfect order for you to become great and
anything.
That's why it's so fun to pursue
greatness or so enriching to pursue it.
And even if it's just personal
greatness, you know, it doesn't,
you don't have to be the greatest
in the world at anything,
but if you personally
improve at something,
whether it's fucking
playing tennis or anything,
but there was a writing books as humans
prove we were talking about
it right before this podcast.
It doesn't matter what master you meet,
it can be a master of anything.
We were using the context of this
bow hunter, Cameron Hanes. Yeah,
they're just awesome.
To be around.
I don't give a fuck cause I'm
meeting a ton of them with on it now.
It's one of the great things that I love
about it is these excellent people are
coming out of the woodwork saying,
Hey,
I was fucking excellent and I know
what's good and I like your stuff.
It's awesome. It makes me even
better and that's awesome for me.
But what's even better is spending
time with these people. And it's been,
it's such a divergent of mount of skills,
but it's all really the same person
deep down. Just applying that,
that methodology, you know,
as your favorite quote is,
you know, no the way broadly,
and you'll see it in all things.
It doesn't matter what your art is,
but it gets you to a place where you're
a fucking cool person to hang around
with.
Yeah. All those dudes are the same guy.
They're the same guy in different forms,
the same girl,
the same woman in different forms.
It's people that figure out how to get
through this crazy maze of life and uh,
come out with something and they're
real. There's this, the real masters.
There's a real confidence,
then there's something to them.
There's this does present energy.
They're not bullshitting you there.
They're just there, you know,
just, just fucking there. You know?
And this Cameron Hanes guy was totally
like that and it's cool as fuck.
Yeah. Yeah. You've gone
to the edge of the,
of your own darkness because you have to,
you have to go past that to be really
excellent because you have to work your
way through it and you have
that constant resistance.
Resistance is always coming
up and pushing. You know,
as Steven Pressfield
said when we were here,
anytime you go from the lower to the
higher resistance is going and the journey
to mastery is, that's all it is,
is a journey from lower to higher.
So every fucking plateau you're battling
resistance and having to overcome it to
transcend to the next plateau.
So that skill level and being able to do
that applies to the rest of your life.
And it doesn't matter if
it's a retired 70 year old,
used to be a master at something,
they still have that fucking
quality inside of him.
Yeah. And I'm going to read this
email that Cameron sent me today. Uh,
someone sent him,
I won't reveal the guy's name cause
I'm sure he wanted it private,
but he said that, watch you on the
Joe Rogan experience. You're a,
you're an inspiration.
Seeing your approach and philosophy
checks off so many boxes with me.
Seeing someone work hard at something
meaningful to them is wonderful.
Even if I never hunt the idea
that I can say, you know what,
I want to push this area of
my life to the next level.
Can I be in better shape for
this or better mental condition?
And that this doesn't have to apply to
things like winning the Olympic gold,
but just to be better at surfing or
hunting, juggling, it doesn't matter.
And he said, thanks man. I liked
that he got an email. Yeah. It got,
he got that inspiration.
He got that charge. Yup.
And that's what I was saying to Cameron
on the podcast yesterday is that I got
that from him. I got that from watching
his videos. I got, first of all, um,
his positivity,
he's like this really smiley friendly
guy who does like really nice things.
Like he auctioned off his bow and gave
the money to some guy who was battling
cancer and you know,
made this really thankful video about it.
Like his energy is pure.
Like you can see it when he's
communicating and he's a fucking fiend.
The guys workout maniac, he's, the
guy's an animal, he's a savage,
he's out there fucking shooting pointy
sticks at elk and when you're hanging out
with them, couldn't be cooler.
So it's like the, you, you,
when you were around enough
of those people, you start
absorbing a higher ideal.
And I think that we oftentimes we
imitate the people that were around.
We imitate our atmosphere
to a certain extent,
or at very least it sets a watermark.
And, but you meet people like this,
Cameron Hanes guy or hundreds of other
people that have had on this podcast,
it sets a higher watermark.
It gives you more to aspire.
I agree completely. I, you know, I made a
post on my Facebook page that, you know,
I said something like a encouraging,
that same thing, you know, changing,
changing your friends, deciding
who you want to hang out with and,
and trying to hang out with these people
that really inspire you and you know,
so then there was this backlash of
people saying, you know, some people say,
no man,
you're perfect just the way you are.
You shouldn't try to be anything
different. And I was like, well,
I kind of get what you're saying,
but to,
on order to hang out with other people
that inspire you, you can't just be like,
I am what I am, Bro. I'm
not going to fucking try it.
And you gotta be in the same path,
you know, to connect with them,
to really be someone that
they want to hang out with.
You gotta be pushing yourself to,
and that's,
that's part of the process because
they're going to see that, you know,
if you haven't gone out and actively
faced your own demons, that'll be nice.
That'll shake your hand and whatever,
but they're not calling you out for
beers in a game of pool on Saturday.
You know,
they got other people that inspire them
that they want to be around and make
them feel alive from that same kind of
energy and connection. And you know,
I think it's, it's
important. Yes. You know,
some parts of us are perfect as they are,
but nonetheless,
that pursuit of excellence is going to
put you in the class with other people
who were on the same pursuit.
You know, water finds its level.
Yeah. It's an old expression game
recognizes game. Yep. That's, it does.
People who are real, they, you know,
I don't like using that expression.
People who are real because there's
so many fucking abuses of that word.
Real keeping it real, keeping it real. Um,
but those people that are present,
people that are legitimately who they
are projecting their not putting on an
act. When you meet someone who is
putting on an act, God, it's glaring.
It's a sore thumb. It's
just throb, throb, throb.
Just do shyness and Gross Nis and kept
me away from this fucking idiot and just
catching a little lie here and
they're catching a little, you know,
just a little exaggeration, a
little distortion, a little song.
That shit is bad for you. It's bad for
you to be around. You can catch that.
Just like and catch a cold. You
know, you can catch distortion,
lower your standards.
It'll slowly chip away.
If you lived in prison and you were
surrounded by liars and thieves and
murderers, like you were in the worst
prison ever. Everyone was guilty.
No one was set up. No one had a
bad childhood. It's just content.
Just the prison con, con
penitentiary. You know,
your idea of what human
beings are would drop.
Well, it happens. The cops
all the time, you know,
cops are dealing with the worst
of humanity on a regular basis.
So they sometimes suspect,
and I say this because my Stepdad was
on the swat team and he was a cop.
It was a kimono.
And so they see the worst in people so
often that it taints their glasses are a
little ruddy black.
You know,
I mean they're seeing the worst in
everybody just cause that's what they're
conditioned to do.
Yeah. They also have some
of the best sense of humor.
I have some friends that are cops,
cops know that I know from a martial
arts or whatever and the order of deals,
this dark sense of humor man.
Cause they just see, you know,
oh we showed up and this lady's head
was in the middle of the road and yeah.
Oh Jesus,
what else do you do? But you have
to be able to blow off and laugh and
yeah.
And then keep it light.
Be Really Weird about it because you know
when you see something like a horrible
car accident and you see them every day
over and over again and then you get in
your car, okay here we go. No I'm
going to enter into this thing.
That also is shit.
You know,
I saw what happens when everything
goes wrong earlier today,
but now I'm just going to go about my,
I mean they, and they see it every day.
I mean every, most likely, you know,
most days they're going to see something
fucked up. Especially if you're in La,
you know, if you're a
cop in La, Jesus Christ,
what the fuck did those
guys see every day?
That's why I kind of,
from the cops that I've interacted with,
the more heavy shit that
goes on in the neighborhood,
usually the cooler the cop is when they
pull you over for something stupid.
You know,
it's like the cop,
if you get caught in a really neighborhood
but not shit happens and you're going
five miles over the speed
and then there'll be a deck,
a lot of time, you know,
if you're in a place
where they're checking on murders and
risking their life and whatever, I'm like,
oh cool, you turn the Dome light on and
you're giving me your stuff. All right,
cool man. Uh, just slow down, you know,
just got to keep it safe out here
and they'll let you off, you know?
Whereas the other cops are just like,
oh,
look at you because they're
fucking calibration is off.
Obviously generalization,
but I tend to see that it's
hard to be a cop man really is.
And people get mad at me on this podcast
for defining defending cops. You know,
I had a cub fucking shoot my dog. They
were looking for weed. I know of her,
those stories. I've seen the videos.
I know there's cops that that happens.
There's definitely cops are cons.
But I just think overall it's an insanely
hard job that gets zero reward and it
builds up a resentment. And you know,
human beings don't like being resented.
They don't like being, they don't
like that feeling of resentment.
They don't like resenting people
that they don't like the animosity.
They just don't. We were not
designed to absorb animosity. Well,
and you know that animosity that cops
receive and when every good person
generally looks at you and
says, oh, fuck the fucking cops.
Because you're always just
buzzkill in whatever they're doing.
They're putting in a terrible spot.
Having to defend these we'd laws
and psychedelic laws. And you know,
even some of the alcohol laws,
you know, for a 20 year old,
he wants to fucking drink some beers
in his house or whatever, quotas,
ticket quotas, all the, all
of these [inaudible] things
they have to do, you know,
causes people to despise.
Imagine if none of those laws existed
and cops were only there for the stuff
that you really wanted them. Therefore
people would love the cost for like,
oh fucking sweet rate cops are here. And
murder rate, fee, fee, fee, fee delivery.
Yeah. Yeah. You'd be pumped and
be like, yes, the cops are here.
Awesome there around.
I love it when the cops are around,
but because they have to enforce these
terrible laws that you know are bullshit
and it just fucking up your day,
you know,
raising revenue or even worse trying
to bust you for exploring your own
consciousness. You kind of fucking
hate him and resent them. You know,
we could do that would crush almost
every police department all across the
country.
Everybody just drive the speed
limit and obey all traffic laws.
They would,
it would destroy them because they're
so used to pulling in x amount of money
per month that if we
could go a few months,
just a few months of no
track traffic stops ever.
People literally they would, they would
just start false flagging people. Yeah,
they would, they would
have to, they would start,
they would go after you and they would
set up a fake crime and then arrest you
for it. Sort of like the war on drugs,
sort of like, you know, the DEA would do,
I mean, what would they do
if everybody stops on wheat?
They would find retards and talked him
into selling them weed and then arrest
them.
That's what they would do if everybody
just totally stopped selling weed with
the DEA.
Go out of business the fuck it would
if all these Mexican drug cartel said,
listen man,
you know,
we did some Iowasca and we've got
a different point of view and man,
it's not cool to harm people. So, uh,
look, we made a lot of money. We're good,
we're done. We're just getting out of the
business. We're not selling anymore. We,
and then everyone
in America said, you know what,
man? Um, grow your own weed.
I'm not selling any weed. That's it.
We're done. It was no one else to bus.
No one is selling weed. There's no
one to bust. What would they do?
They would set people up, man. They
would, they would keep their job.
There's an organism would preserve its
identity and it would preserve its life.
It would preserve its existence and
the only way to serve the existing,
you've got arrest motherfuckers.
Yeah.
If we didn't have any traffic
violations at all for a few months,
it would bankrupt most police departments.
Isn't that insane?
Like they're dependent on crime.
It least this petty crime of parking.
Sure.
And speeding and not stopping and done.
These private prisons would
start to crumble if, you know,
you took away all of the inmates were
there for these drug charges, you know?
So yeah. And that's,
that was a good point.
There's a documentary of the house I
live in and they make a great, you know,
a great case for that.
How all these private prison systems
need to throw these people in prison at
these overwhelmingly level high levels
compared to the rest of the world is
they're surviving like an organism, like
all these other countries, you know,
big corporations,
they're like an organism that's going
to survive at fucking any costs. Yeah,
and it doesn't have to be like that. You
don't have to be that type of organism,
but it requires some consciousness at
the fucking brain of the organism to make
sure that it's not well and it's so
blatant to when you find out that these
people that need these jobs lobby to make
sure that these jobs are in place and
the way they do that is to make sure the
things are illegal so they can arrest
people like the policemen's,
the the guards,
the prison guards union,
they,
they make sure that they spend money
to make sure the drugs stay illegal.
Like they work actively, they spend money
on making sure that marijuana is legal,
like, well who would do that? Who would
do that based on the facts in hand?
Someone who profits from that.
Right.
Some of the profits from drugs being
illegal and the way they profit is more
people get arrested and then they
keep their job as a prison guard.
That is slavery, no matter
how you slice it. That is it.
Just a tricky way of being a slave master.
What you're doing is you're figuring out
this real sneaky way to enforce slavery
and it, but just not slavery. It's a
choice. You don't want to follow the law.
Shut up stupid.
Shut your fucking internal dialogue right
now because the law is just some shit
that people wrote down.
Nobody wants marijuana to be illegal,
but idiots. No one. When you look
at the actual facts behind it,
if you can't argue the facts, then
it's, there's no conversation.
And when the LD 50 which is a lethal
dose at 50% meaning if there's 20 of us,
we all take the same amount, half of
us would be dead. What's that number?
1500 pounds in 15 minutes.
Okay,
we're done here, right? We're done here.
You don't have to worry about that. Okay,
let's what else he got? Draino people
would drink a drain though. Yeah.
Don't do that. Okay. Yeah, let's make that
not cool. You can't sell draino drinks.
Fuck is wrong with people.
But the idea that someone would
lobby to keep marijuana illegal,
that's what we see.
How laws and things that are written
down on paper can really fuck with people
because it becomes doctrine.
It becomes law.
It becomes what it becomes is this
rigid thing that can't be worked around.
It doesn't have any flexibility. There's
no gray area. It is this, or is that,
and you ended up with this,
this almost doctrine that's based on some,
it's like faith. It's like
a new religion. You know?
It's like saying that you know the urges
to have sex inside you or masturbate or
evil and you need to go to the church.
Okay?
You made something that fucking makes
sure that everybody feels guilty and
everybody needs a priest because
everybody's going to want to touch their
genitals.
So you just figured something out of way
to fucking hack the system so that you
get everybody in some form
of psychic or mental slavery.
And in the prison system.
I've never heard that analogy,
but you're fucking absolutely right.
It's like you're enslaving
them for your own profit. Yeah.
Actively making sure
that people are in jail.
They're making sure that there's laws in
place that will ensure that more people
will get arrested. You know, there's
a movement and the movement is, well,
there's ethical considerations when it
comes to private prisons and laws and
also laws where there's no victim
victims. Fucking victim. I need a job.
I need to keep my family fat to work
we've got to do is we're going to lobby to
make sure drugs are legal,
drugs are bad for families,
and so they have this rhetoric and this
rhetoric fuels the debate and the laws
get passed or the congressmen gets
greased or whatever the fuck happens.
And then the laws stay the same or
even tightened down. In some cases,
more people go to jail
and these fat cats profit,
which is so strange because it's,
it's as easily definable as slavery,
as anything that's ever been.
You look at, yeah, you look at it, I can't
help but draw the parallels. You know,
to religion. So religion,
you get tired or whatever.
You get pap to pay 10% or
whatever the fuck I'm out.
So you're paying for the
church always from the bar,
and then you look at the means that
they went to make sure that everybody
escribed well burning people
at a stake who didn't believe.
That's a pretty good way to ensure that
you're going to get 10% of that person's
money.
And then making sure that they're guilty
always 24 fucking seven because you've
made the urge to have sex, which is
like the urge to eat or take a dump.
It's not going to go away.
You made that as sin and the only way to
absolve it is to get the priest. Well,
yeah. All right, you're going to make
a fucking lot of money doing that.
You know what? Whereas if the
priests were cool and you know,
maybe as if Jesus's teachings
were intended and we're like, hey,
you can find this anywhere you want.
You got to look inside.
You find the truth about God
inside yourself and through
love and through all of
these things, you know, people
would be like, hey, thanks brother,
and they are not going to give you 10%
and let you do all this crazy shit.
You know, it's just
manipulation, manipulation
for profit. Well, that's, I
think the good churches, uh,
probably do 10% that the band churches
pass around baskets and they're
constantly begging and asking for. I mean,
who knows? What do you remember when,
who is a fucking that preacher?
Was it Benny Hinn that had a
rolls Royce and he said they'd go,
God wanted them to drive a Rolls Royce.
It doesn't surprise me one
of those motherfuckers, but
I'm like, that is so bold.
God wanted you to drive a Rolls Royce.
They just bad. They just made shit up.
I mean,
I was,
I was going looking at a horrible
experience going into a dungeon of the
inquisition, right? Italy, boy, darkest,
one of the darkest places I've ever seen.
It's up.
Even the fucking ideas involved in some
of these things and how many of them
involved? You're fucking penis
in your vagina was shocking.
Like 30% of the tortures involve that.
And if they didn't want to do that,
then rape was a way to get cast the
devils out and punish people as well.
So you,
if you are a priest and an inquisitor,
you could rape someone in order to get
it out after you tortured and mutilated
their genitals. Okay,
that sounds pretty good.
That's a holy path.
And even 2000 jobs,
I mean there's parts of Africa where
people are regularly burned to death for
being witches and there's a bunch of
videos of it online of people convincing
people that there witches are there.
Someone is bewitched,
a spell was cast under them and families
are literally selling everything they
have and forcing himself
into indentured servant to,
to pay for which doctor to cure
their children of being witches.
It's a serious,
serious issue that they have over there.
And 2014 this day and
age, it's ideologies, man.
Ideologies and beliefs are incredibly
strong things and it's so easy to
manipulate people because we don't
know. We, we literally, all of us,
the giant mass of us have no
idea what the fuck is going on.
You know as much about what life is all
about is anyone who's ever lived ever.
And that's really hard for people
to swallow. So when we come along,
someone that claims to know something,
they take the place of where our
parents were when we were children.
When you were a child and
you knew almost nothing,
your parents knew more than you, so you
could go to them and they steered you.
Right?
And that's how you got to be alive today.
And the more fear that
you lived with growing up,
the more readily you accept that position,
the more terrified you're
being insecure you'll be you.
You have not found personal sovereignty.
So all of a sudden religion comes along
and fills up this spot where your daddy
used to be. Well, your mommy used
to be. And religion tells you.
And I don't mean just any religion,
I mean witchcraft. I mean everything.
Scientology fill in the blank, you
name it. No one has the answers.
So when someone comes along and they
tell you not only that they have the
answers, but that they need your money
and they need a lot of it and they need,
they have to, you got to behave in very
specific ways that don't make any sense.
Like don't jerk off. Yeah. You know,
the only thing that can count on is
stuff that you can reliably find out
yourself.
Any great spiritual teacher is going to
basically send you on your own quest for
knowledge and then let you
come up with your own truth.
Because if it's not reproducible by
yourself, it's probably bullshit. Yeah.
You know,
if you can't get there doing a
psychedelic meditating going in the tank,
trying to actually pursue this quest
for knowledge and you can't come to that
conclusion,
I say most likely you should discard it.
If someone's just trying to
force feed it down your brain,
it should be reproducible. You should
be able to get there. If you try,
it's also an interactive experience.
You know? It's not like you,
someone gives you information and
then boom, you're a better person now.
You have to be like on a
quest to be a better person,
someone has to say something
that resonates with you.
You have to be able to
internalize what they're saying.
analyze what they're saying.
You have to be able absorb
what they're saying.
You have to think about
your own life and a lot of,
we've got to do a lot of work.
It's not as simple as someone tells
you what's up and then you know,
because if that's almost like winning
the lottery, it's like, you know,
all of a sudden you have this money.
Okay, now what? Well, you got to spend it.
You're fucking crazy. You didn't earn that
shit. You don't know how he got there.
If somebody gives you the perfect
knowledge, it's going to be like, wow,
that totally makes sense. And then off
to off to do heroine. No. Well, yeah man,
I couldn't help myself just fucking, I
just need that crack. Yeah, it's not real.
It doesn't have value.
You gotta be searching.
You gotta be searching to
clean up your own life.
That's one of the things they say about
people when it comes to getting clean.
People that are, they're abusing drugs
or alcohol, getting clean and sober,
like you have to hit your rock bottom
where you realize you got to do something
about your life until you realize it,
all the people in the world telling
you to get your shit together,
it's not going to matter. It doesn't
mean anything. You're just going to,
you're going to placate them. You know
what, man, you're right. I'm done, man.
I'm done. Done fucking use,
man. I'm done. Meanwhile,
as soon as you get away from them, you're
calling up your dealer. You know, Eddie,
Eddie Bravo had, um, uh,
an ex that had a meth problem
and he didn't know about
it and he found out about
it because, uh, I think
he, he was like, he,
she didn't know he was home or something
like that and he was listening to a
phone call and he couldn't
fucking believe it. Like, I think,
I think that was what happened. But like
when he listened to it, he was like,
Holy Shit.
Like living with this check had no idea
she was doing meth and then he leaves
and she's like, yeah, what do you got?
You know I need, I need to get some,
I need to get high. Like
right now I got, you know,
like what he got like and he was like,
whoa.
And then he sort of figured it out and
then confronted her but didn't know,
had no idea. And you know, tell her, hey,
you know, you gotta stop doing this. Yeah.
Yeah, you're right. I'm fucking done. Done
with that shit cause he gone. Okay, good.
I need to get some fucking math right
now. Okay. Not yesterday and then an hour.
I need it now. And if till
that person says, Hey,
I got to stop doing meth. I don't want
to be this person, um, I've fucking,
I'm going to test my will.
I'm going to change my life.
I'm going to steer this battleship.
I'm going to figure out a way off the
rocks until that person makes that
decision, no movement's
going to take place. You'll,
that's why I fucking hate talking with
people when they start talking to me
about losing weight and um,
you know,
but just I think in wanting me to do is
just drop, you know, I just, I guess a,
I see it late at night at, hey,
just fucking do it man. Just stop.
Don't talk to me because
you're just jerking off of
my face. That's what you do.
And this is a form of mental masturbation.
You know, you're, you're, I, I, I get it.
You're trying to look for inspiration.
You, you got to find it in inside of you.
We can have these conversations once,
but if we have them twice and then three
times and then four times and then I
don't see you for six months and you're
fatter, you can go fuck yourself. Okay,
I'm done. And not going to
keep doing this, man. I'm
not going to keep doing this.
You know what you gotta do what?
You got to find something,
and I don't know if freewill
is real because there's the,
there's the big philosophical debate is
there a freewill isn't every decision
you make based on a variety of things
and include genetics, epigenetics,
life experiences.
You know what path you'd going
left as opposed to going, right?
What happened to you before you had any
control over your life when you were a
baby, your whole personality is
formed by the time we were two.
Well then you start factoring on the
getting to that sort of philosophical
debate. That's all good in the
hood. That's all cool in the gang.
But I know for a fact
that some people change,
so either you're going to be
one of those motherfuckers,
it changes or you're not going to be one
of those motherfuckers that's changes.
You can get philosophical all day long.
Say there is no freewill and you know
I'm not going to do it because there's no
free will and hey, I'm just happy being
a way to let yourself off the hook.
It's exactly what it is. You're being
a bitch and I'm here to let you know.
That's what I'm here for. I'm
the, I'm the being a bitch.
You're being a bitch police.
I'm here to let you know I think
William James Cause I was you know,
study a lot of philosophy and his take
on the freewill argument was one of my
favorites and it's like I dunno if there
is free will or not but my life is a
hell of a lot better if
I believe it is true.
You know and I'm going to be fucking
making decisions for myself that are going
to benefit my life and I'm going to act
sure as shit as if there is free will
cause this, watch me, you know and that
was it. It was like whatever you guys,
philosophers want to argue about,
fine. That's cool. Good for you.
But I'd say that there is just because
it's better for me and I'm going to
fucking make shit happen.
I know there is
no, I know there is alarm clocks
bitch. It's that fucking simple.
I exercise my will and determination with
alarm clocks because when alarm clocks
go off,
I fucking get up and I get up.
Not just because of all the newer new
free does just just what I do. No,
I do it on purpose. I know I do
it. I know it's hard to do. I know,
I know I do that and I could
just shut it off. You know,
I could just fucking shut it off,
but unplugged the phone in the hotel and
sleep for a couple of days or I want to
do, I'll fucking call everybody
in a few days. They'll be fine,
they'll freak out a little bit. But if I
want to do that, I'll do it. That, yeah,
you can do it. Do whatever
the fuck you want to do. Man.
I know,
I know in a different way.
And that's just from my
own experiences of being,
of separating myself
from that aton you know,
that robotic mind and just becoming that
higher part of yourself and that that
is the part of you that really
does have free will. You know,
there's this higher consciousness
that can stop everything.
Just say the whole thing.
[inaudible] throw the fucking brakes on
and then make some decisions. You know,
and maybe there's winds that blow
influences currents that are gonna shape
different ideas of thought.
But man,
when you're in that state and you
can really feel connected to that,
to that person driving your ship,
you know that tree will cause
you can fucking feel it.
There's something you can decide to be a
better person. Yeah, you absolutely can.
People had been doing it
from the beginning of time.
You can better yourself.
And that's one of the reasons
why inspirational people
are so important because
you can make choices based on inspiration
that is freewill defined the thing we
were talking about,
about being inspired by people,
surrounding yourself with positive people
and using that positivity to reinforce
your own life and inspire your own life.
That is free will. That is freewill,
broken down to its most beneficial aspect.
The most beneficial aspect of freewill
is the ability to choose to better
yourself,
to be influenced by positive things
where there was love or whatever it is.
Well it would have those things
didn't happen. And you don't,
you wouldn't have free
will because of free will.
It's just you reacting to your
environment. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Everybody says that's weak by the way.
You ever notice that it's not a bunch
of fucking savage champions. Yeah. That,
that don't believe in freewill. Now they
all tell you, you have to test your will.
You have to test it. You know, and and,
and people who've never truly tested
there will be never truly tried to run up
that mountain with that 130
pound rock on your back.
If you never really tried to do Jujitsu
and tried to do battle with another
skilled person for 20 fucking minutes
where you're both your hearts ready to
explode and your chest and your fucking
arms made out of rubber, you don't know.
You don't know about pushing yourself.
You don't, you don't. You haven't,
you haven't really tested yourself.
You've just gotten in your car and driven
to your cubicle every day and put in
your hours and then you want to talk shit.
All right?
But that's not how life works.
The way life works is you get your shit
talking license when you accomplish
something. And Ironically speaking,
once you've accomplished something,
you're least likely to want to talk shit.
That's it. That's the irony of it all.
But then by talking shit, I mean bragging
and, and, and mean. And there is,
there's recanting and re recounting
rather recounting special experiences,
um,
that are fascinating.
Whether I love talking to martial artists
that talk about the greatest victories
I love talking to. And it doesn't,
that doesn't mean they're bragging.
It doesn't mean not,
don't talk about accomplishments,
but most people know the difference
between enacting and react reenacting
experiences and pulling their
lessons out of those experiences.
And people who are just
trying to pump themselves up.
And when you're around someone who's just
trying to pump themselves up and they,
they're bullshitting and it's, it's
a gross oily, feeling it from a need
deep inside to fill up some void.
They fill in their own,
in their own mind and their
own ego and their own mindset.
So that need requires positive
reinforcement from other people,
but that's going to be a vacuous hole
that they're never going to fill.
And so unless they've already conquered
that, they're not going to be that good.
Like you have to get past
that to really be, you know,
one of the true masters in nuts.
There's a rare occasion where, you know,
as we said before,
someone's raw ability is
just so unbelievably savage
on another level that they
do get to be ostensibly a champion.
You know,
without actually having gone through it.
I'm sure there are cases of that where
someone is just so fucking gifted that
they've gotten away with not actually
facing the demons on the journey,
but that's super rare and
I've never encountered,
I think in certain, um, fight sports,
it's actually possible to get incredibly
proficient and not be a true master of
yourself. Mike Tyson, I think is
one of the greatest examples ever.
Mike Tyson has come out and said that he
was on coke through a great part of his
career. Like he was doing coke and
fighting. I mean, and he was cool,
literally out of control.
Whether or not he raped that Desiree
woman who was accused of raping.
I don't know. I wasn't
there, but whatever that was,
you have to take into
consideration a couple of things.
Would that particular case,
one, she had falsely accused,
I'm going to rape just a year before.
Sure. That's one. And you know too,
she took her panties shield off when
she got into the bathroom. Those, those,
both of those things don't
look so good for her.
It doesn't mean that she didn't say
no and he didn't rape her. Okay,
so who knows what actually did happen,
but take away that one experience and
just look at all the crazy shit that guy
did.
He was a maniac.
He was buying Bentleys and Rolls Royces
every day and Punched Mick Green,
Mitch Mitch,
Blood Green at a fucking
Harlem Haberdashery at two
o'clock in the morning and
he wasn't living like some fucking stoic
monk. You saw that show that he did.
He put on. I see it. It's pretty good.
I heard. It's amazing. It's awesome.
My point is he was the
baddest motherfucker of all
time while he was doing all
this craziness.
But the thing that he did do
is insane amounts of work,
insane intensity, insane focus and
determination and a deep, deep,
deep knowledge of his craft.
A huge knowledge.
I mean the reason why he
had that high top fade,
we shave the sides of his head
cause that's what Jack Dempsey did.
He watched Jack Dempsey from
the time he was a fucking child,
like constantly imitated and mimic the
movements of Jack Dempsey gotten much
better in my opinion.
He's way better than Jack Dempsey.
When you watched Jack Dempsey move around
and see if we can pull that up. Jamie,
pull up a video of Jack Dempsey.
Is this a,
a perfect example of how someone can be
inspired by someone who sucks compared
to them?
You know,
because because Tyson was just this spring
loaded like took a piece of metal and
you're just fucking bent it back.
Well he was,
he was boxing when it hit this new
incredible level where so many things were
involved. First of all, there was
decades and decades and decades,
over a hundred years of knowledge
when it came to, you know,
what was effective, what was not
effective is this, this is not a fight.
This isn't like sparring. A
lot of pieces. A fight must be,
well a lot of people would get to watch
that guy train. Yeah, that's a fight.
That's definitely a fight. Jack Dempsey
was a fucking animal looking at various,
it's wailing on this motherfucker
kind of punches like Badr Hari does
know everything showing you everything
trying to crush you. He was a hard
hit and motherfucker to Jack Dempsey,
Mike Tyson.
Oh Jesus.
And they hovered over you back
then after they knocked you down.
That look up bloody. That dude is
oh shit son back then when they, um,
when they knocked you down,
they stood over you and every time you
got up they'd punch you again. No Way.
Yeah. They watched, she hovers over him.
There was no standing eight counts back
then they would drop you and then when
you would get on one knee and as soon as
you need to lift, lifted off the ground,
they fucking punch you in the face again,
which it sounds gangster.
But look at MMA and I, you go to the
ground, I fucking mount your face,
punch you into oblivion.
And that's a way crazier.
So it's funny that people are like,
no way they punched him in the head
while they were down. Yeah, they, they,
they hovered over you.
You do you,
what do you think about the idea that
if they just took off all the gloves,
it could be safe as far as to be wasted?
It's pretty,
pretty scientifically clear right now.
Pull up Mike Tyson versus Marvis Frazier.
This is a, in my opinion,
the best version of a,
of Mike Tyson,
the scariest version of Mike Tyson.
When Mike Tyson fought Marvis Frazier.
It was when he was on his way to the
heavyweight title and he had not been
defeated Trevor Berbick yet, but he
was on his way. But, uh, just pull it,
pull it up so he could just see the fight.
Cause the fight only lasts
for about fucking 10 seconds.
But he swarms that motherfucker in a way
that to this day is the most terrifying
beating I've ever seen
anybody give anybody inside
a boxing ring because Marvis
Frazier had zero chance. He
wasn't a hungry, evil fighter.
He was the son of one of
the greatest of all time.
It didn't really have it himself.
And he was fighting a guy who was going
to be the greatest heavyweight of all
time in his greatest time
when he's surging and coming
up looking for a shot at
the title and he just corners Marvis
Frazier here and just on fucking loads,
Bang, Bang, Bang, Bang.
Every punch is perfect.
Massive amounts of torque and
muscle by an every fist to his face.
And he,
that one combination puts Marvis Frazier
out of boxing for the rest of his life.
I mean he, I think he boxed again after
that, but he was a shadow of himself.
Everyone knew he was never going to be
the heavyweight champion and he was never
going to be able to beat this
fucking monster. I mean, he,
he didn't offer any resistance whatsoever.
And look at these combinations,
how he is so accurate.
So that's way better than Jack Dempsey.
See My, my point, he's like,
you look at Jack Dempsey who inspired
Mike Tyson and Mike Tyson is fucking way
better than Jack Dempsey. I mean
way, way, way, way, way better.
Sam Kennison was inspired by Lenny Bruce,
but if you watch Lenny Bruce and watched
Sam Kennison, he'd go, oh Jesus Christ.
Like Lenny Bruce,
if,
if you like trying to watch
it today as a 2014 comedian,
like if he was a guy like, this is a guy
I heard about, his name is Lenny Bruce.
He'd be like, Oh my God, this
guy's boring. He's so boring.
He's saying the obvious shit.
It wasn't obvious shit in 1950
1950 he was fucking crazy,
groundbreaking stuff.
I mean he was saying things that nobody
had ever even thought you would hear on
stage before he was and he was going to
jail for them and that guy went to jail
countless times just for profanity,
just for just speaking his mind and
and talking about the, the, the,
the language that we use.
I mean he would use profanity in talking
about how odd it is that we have these
restrictions on language.
Sure.
You hear so many people talk about how
they're building off the backs of the
giants from, from times ago, you
know, from whatever, whatever,
whatever it is in science,
in art and in sport and all of that.
You know,
you build off of what created before
and make it generally, you know,
better.
You get to take what they knew and the
best people do is take what they knew,
take how far they went, and then take
it even farther, you know, and then,
then you think about some things like you
look at Graham Hancock's work and then
you wonder,
well what happens if everything just
gets fucking taken away and you have to
start over.
What if all the UFC tapes completely
went out of people's consciousness?
This whole generation, it's only 25
years and this generation gets wiped out.
A new one comes up.
They've got to figure that shit out all
over again and they're going to suck for
a long time. A long time, you know,
because they're not going to have that,
that to build off of.
Whereas now, you know,
people are just going to get more and more
efficient and and capable at this art.
Yeah. If people had to figure out how to
do a wheel kick from scratch, oh yeah.
And land it spin and hit someone
in the head with your head,
it would take forever for them to even
think of it, you know? Yeah. I mean,
it'll take a long time.
Oh, do you? The idea that you
could kick someone in the face,
you could pick up your leg and kick
someone in the face. Like what? No,
you can kick them when they're down
and kick them when they're up here.
Get outta here.
That's not even fucking possible.
And then he showed the Jonelle
Serone video and you're like,
get the fuck outta here.
How did he figure that out?
He fucking hit him with his shin.
Whoa.
And people who don't do
martial arts sometimes a, um,
I have friends that have come to the
UFC and they have no idea what he did to
the guy like a Steve Rinella.
This guy was a, this guy, um,
uh,
a bag routine off was a fighting
this dude who was going for, uh,
the John, John Linacre, John Leonard who
was going for a leg lock on bog routine.
Often it was at the end of the fight,
but off his is sambal master and Linacre
is more of a striker than anything is
Jujitsu sort of.
So,
so and so boggled teen off was like
laughing that this guy was trying to heal,
hook them, waved his
fingers. So he stood up,
he standing there while Linacre
is going after his legs,
not even defending the leg lock.
And he's like going like this,
like standing there and flexing.
And it's ridiculous because you know like,
and so my friend was like,
how did he hold that guy down Rinella
thought the bog routine off was holding
him down with his leg. He was pinning him
with his leg full champion pipe. Yeah.
I'm like, no, he wasn't actually
pinning him with his leg. He's like,
why was I got pin in
that guy and was like,
but that a person who doesn't ever
do Marshall, excuse me, martial arts,
they look at some shit and they don't
know what's happening. They're like, like,
how do he hit him with a
Shin? What the heck? That guy,
he flipped around and he
hit the guy with his shin.
Like they couldn't even recreate it.
If you showed someone and they didn't
have any knowledge of martial arts at all
and you showed them Edson Barboza versus
Terry Adam where Edson Barboza hits him
with this wheel kick from hell.
Like one of the worst wheel case I've
ever seen anybody to absorb in any combat
sport ever. I mean, the guy just got
it. Terry. Adam looked like he got shot.
He got shot with a sniper,
just boom,
stiffens up and down like his head
exploded. If you showed that to somebody,
they'd be like,
what did he do?
What's he flipped around through the air.
The guy flew through the air and
he hit him with his foot, you know,
like how did he hit him on his foot?
I got crazy like just
jumping through the year.
Like you wouldn't even know how that
happened actually when I think it was
hoists.
Gracie right here you're in is right here.
Oh Shit. Are you fucking
kidding me? Like a sniper,
right? That doesn't, you don't ever
land a more perfect, we'll kick boom,
look at that.
I mean that shit is full
flawless technique and he
hit him in the perfect spot.
Any hit him is Edom is moving forward
like Adam steps to him and it just runs
right into that heal.
I saw that thing happen.
I think it was hoists Gracie fighting,
maybe it was Dan Severn or somebody,
but the big guy was on top of hoists.
Hoisin Dan Severn each handled him
and he triangled them and I was,
I had a bunch of people over at the house.
My family loved these things.
We watched him from the start and people
were like, what the fuck happened?
What the fuck happened? Like they couldn't
possibly imagine that the guy on top,
the big guy on top gave up. Why? Why?
How did just what? I don't get it.
I don't get it. You mean you can
be on top and lose? You know,
it was like full ma'am. Nobody
understood it at all. Yeah.
It's like what his legs around the guy's
neck? Yeah. Make them suck is kind of,
can you make him stuck? Is that any theory
was valid at that point? Nobody knew.
I remember watching UFC two was
the first one that ever watched.
I watched it on video
tape was a VHS tape and a,
I just come to Hollywood and it was in
like 94 and I was out here doing TV and I
saw 'em at the video store. They had
like UFC two was it, I don't even know.
UFC One was available.
There was some sort of licensing issue.
You can only rent UFC two at the,
and so,
uh,
I got ahold of it and I watched it and I
had been a martial artist since I was a
young boy. So watching this,
all of a sudden I was like,
oh my God,
everything I know is useless.
I think I really had this feeling
like if that guy got ahold of me,
I'm fucking getting get strangled
just like this big giant guy.
But he's fucking up these big giant guy.
He arm barred chemo, you know, he's,
he's fucking up these guys that are like
way bigger than me that I wouldn't want
to fight and like, Whoa, how's
he doing that? I think I was,
my size is 170 pounds at the time.
It was like,
the fuck is he beating these
guys? I immediately was
like, I got to learn Jujitsu.
And then as soon as I went to Jujitsu,
I got mauled over and over and over again.
Like he just,
it completely got my ass kicked
where I thought like, well,
I've been a martial artist for,
you know, fucking long time.
When I get in there I'm going
to learn easier than most
people. No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no. You're not
going to go in there with any,
I had a little bit of wrestling from
high schools that helped a little bit.
I kind of knew about manipulating
bodies and I knew about leverage,
but I didn't know any of the techniques.
I didn't know what was going on,
especially with the gay dudes are
just grabbing my collar and I'm like,
what's going on here?
And I was like twisting it around my neck
and fucking holding onto it to put my
arm in a position when they get snap
it in half and you're like, Oh God,
I'm so vulnerable. Like it was just
leaving there feeling like, fuck,
I'm so vulnerable.
I didn't know it was this vulnerable.
I thought it was way tougher
than this. Yeah, changes,
changes the world thing.
These techniques,
you don't even know what
a guy is doing to you.
And all of a sudden you and
when it's happening to you,
it's even more confusing because
you can't see what's going on.
Sometimes when you're getting strangled,
well, when you get into arm barred,
like this is,
um,
there's a massive legs and arms and tangle
and you're trying to grapple and all
of a sudden his legs
over across your face,
you don't even seeing what's
happening and you're getting arm bar,
you're not sure,
especially in the beginning,
you don't recognize the
dangerous positions.
You don't know when to
defend or even how to defend.
So when you get stuck in these spots,
it's literally a mystery where your
arm is screaming in pain. Like,
why am I fucking shut? The fuck
happened there? My shoulder,
why is my hand behind my back?
I remember I grappled Mario Charles,
who was like a Jujitsu silver
medalist and somewhere in, in Brazil,
I was in Florida, Annapolis.
And I go to just, I was there.
So I was like, all right,
well fuck all grapple
with somebody really good.
So I go there and I'd
never really wrestled with,
grappled with somebody who had a good
butterfly guard, like a really good one.
And I was just floating along,
getting arm barred and choked constantly.
I felt like I never fucking
got to the ground, you know,
he's just pushing and pulling
and lifting and flip. I was like,
this is a fucking new level.
Yeah, this is a whole new game,
especially with the gay, because with
the g they can hold onto collars.
You only hold on, hold on
to the end of your, uh,
your sleeves and you know those
two things. One Hand in the collar,
one hand the sleeve man, your hands both
feet under your hips, feet on your hips.
So you're flying up in the air.
So you got one arm completely locked out.
You're trying to defend
with this on Jesus Christ.
This arms we were fucking
neck is turned sideways.
Guys got a forum across your neck
holding on tight to your collar.
It's like you've had a video of what
happened to me. That was it. Oh good.
I've been there. John Shock does that
to me still. And I'm a black robe.
The judge Jack, I'm up
in the air man. When you,
you know you feel someone is really good
at getting those butterfly guards in
and flipping you here and there.
It's a skill that you develop,
the ability to lift someone up and
manipulate them and a lot of people don't
understand how high level the top level
Jujitsu guys have achieved because you
only see Jujitsu and MMA and
Jujitsu and MMA is a lot.
It's actually like less advanced than
kickboxing and MMA because there's some,
there's some really like
high level kickboxing that
you see occasionally in MMA
with elite fighters and it's also
kickboxing and MMA is a tad more dangerous
than kickboxing and kickboxing
because the gloves are smaller.
You can't protect the same
way like kickboxing. They can,
they can go in this shell,
they have this like [inaudible].
He's really good at that.
Even the holds up real high with the
shell and they move forward and they throw
kicks and punches to
come back to that Shell,
but that Shell and MMA
punches still getting slipped
through and one will do you
in. It's not like a boxing punch with
that big glove is a different sort of a
thunderous effect that are really hard
puncher with an MMA glove house on.
But when there's no striking,
then you get to see what real
high level Jujitsu is all about.
And you get to see a guy like a shock
or ra or a Hodrick Gracie or crone,
Gracie or Marcello Garcia, these super,
super high level guys going at it.
And you get to see Jujitsu that is on
a level that you almost never see when
there's, you know, punches
involved and kicks involved.
So to someone who doesn't know like what
really high level Jujitsu looks like,
when you,
you know,
you said you think you kind of have
an idea of what the baseline is.
Well you know, I've seen Anderson Silva
tap out channels, sign it on the ground,
so I'm pretty sure I
know what you're just,
it looks like you really don't because
the Anderson Silva gets tapped out if he
goes to Jiu Jitsu tournaments,
there's a video of him getting
tapped out why he was a champion.
You got arm barred. And that's
just, that's the way the world man.
He's is another level, the level,
the super, super high level.
Jujitsu is a,
it's fucking wild to watch
cause these guys are masters,
then they're ninjas and they're hitting
these high speed moves and countering
these moves and he can watch guys like
really like technical guys and you're
watching these wild roles and it's like
Jesus Christ. It's, you know, it's,
it's such a beautiful thing that all of
these arts kinda got a testing ground
and I wish it could be applied to other
things because just in the way that the
UFC made people take the very best from
everything, the very best from karate,
the very best from taekwondo, the
very best from Jujitsu, wrestling,
all these different things.
Judo,
everybody contributed a little piece
to the puzzle. Some pieces way bigger.
Obviously
Jujitsu's pieces of the pie was a big
fucking meaty piece of the pot, you know?
But everything had a little point,
you know,
except for maybe some Weird Kung foods.
It probably contributed maybe only the
tiniest little sliver of something.
I Dunno. But, and then
in life people are still,
because there isn't that proving ground
with like philosophies and meditation
techniques and Yoga Philosophy,
yoga schools,
they get so rigid in defending their way,
their dogma of what they think.
You know,
this is the only way,
just like martial artists used to be
my Dojo is the only way it's the deadly
arts, blah, blah, blah. You know, it's,
it's a shame that there isn't some way
to really have that kind of intercourse
where you test every different skill
and just use what works. But you know,
I think we can do that ourselves anyways.
And I think that's the right philosophy.
Take a little bit from all of
these great religious philosophies,
these schools of thought, Buddhism,
Zen, Hinduism, Christianity,
Judaism, Islam, everybody
has a little verse.
Some might be fatter piece of
the pie for you than others,
but everything has some way to contribute
to this and all these other techniques.
You know, if you'd like
transcendental meditation,
okay, maybe that's a big piece,
but maybe try some of the other meditation
cycles are, if you like Bikram Yoga,
okay, that can be a piece. But
try these other things too.
The same thing needs to be
applied across the fucking board,
but because there's no way for these
people to battle and for people to
ostensibly see it, improve
it, it doesn't happen.
And you get stuck back in 1970s martial
arts where everybody's defending their
stupid Dojo when really the best
way is a little bit of everything.
Zero lot of them
like a, that sort of a
ideology when it comes to yoga.
Bikram Yoga. It's like that
crazy though. Yeah, he's great.
He wears gold chain but he's accused of
like a bunch of sexual assaults. No idea.
I have no personal knowledge of posters
from Amy cause I know that big room yoga
guy I talked to, the guys did
talk to some guys in front of me.
But yeah,
those guys
so rigid about that being the only way
and it's 18 postures and it's at this
fucking degree temperature and
everything else is bullshit.
You're like, uh, okay
if you say so. But yeah,
I kind of like doing some other shit
too. Sexual harassment scandal, rocks,
Yoga community after beak room.
The dude's name is bea crumb chewed Hori.
I don't know if I'm saying that right.
It's slapped with a lawsuit and there's a,
apparently the dude drives
Bentleys and shit. Super baller.
He's a super baller.
He seems like he's a handsome guy.
He's probably gotten mad
yoga pussy because imagine
the yoga pussy that guy gets
was little speedos on doing stretches
with chicks and it's all about releasing
and pressure and positions and just
sliding it into your pussy. Oh.
Oh. Look at them there with two hot
chicks. He probably fucked both of them.
He probably did splits and fuck them.
It was he standing on a chicken.
That one. Yeah. That's insane. Wow.
Let Joey Diaz try that.
I'm not impressed.
I'm impressed with his age though.
The Guy 67 years old,
he's still getting sexual harassment.
That means he's still active.
Congratulations Yoga. It's yoga.
It's like a fucking asshole.
This is the sexy Jurassic
Energy Kundalini.
It's clearly,
he must be a real shit head.
He started beaker him in the early
seventies and now it's turned into this
gigantic fucking huge movement.
It's really good though.
That's the problem with Bikram Yoga.
I mean,
as much of a piece of shit is this guy
may or may not be. I never met him,
obviously. I mean, who knows these people
who are saying he sexually harass them.
They can be fucking nuts. I don't
know. But you know the guy, it's,
it's been around. Yeah, it's good.
I mean, but it's a benefit to it.
There's some other really good
hot yoga too. Yeah, it's a lot.
We'll just show somebody
many positions in Yoga.
And the thing about beacons is they have
this very specific routine to the take
you through this very specific. It's
a fucking great, don't get me wrong.
I love it. I mean it's, it's an amazing,
amazing workout and it's amazing for your,
your thought process and your mind.
He likes standing on bitches.
Look at them and that's fucking
weird. And the Christ pose. Yeah. No,
I think that's warrior one or
something. No, fucking Christ. Suppose
I know warrior one warrior.
I've definitely not snail boy.
Well you're saying stand on a bitch.
Yeah.
Hit the Christ pose and fucker
guy looks good for 67 though.
Man Must be something to that Yoga Shit.
I mean,
I don't know how old these
constantly staring. I checks.
Where's the grossest speedos?
Yeah,
he's like 200 pounds from
looking like a sumo wrestler. No,
I think he's a tiny guy.
I think this is an illusion because
he's standing on a small woman.
I think he's already big
at all. You know, he's,
he's really skinny and super flexible.
I wonder if,
why doesn't he ever stand on any
dude's rude? They'll kick his ass.
I always eat pounds cause he
doesn't want to fuck to dudes too.
He stands on you puts a stinky
feet all over your neck.
You're more likely to let them slip his
dick inside you. Is that the way it goes?
That's what I think in my fantasy world
that I just created with him banging all
these chicks for real.
I don't know what the real story is.
He says he's disappointed in the false
charges made in this lawsuit but will not
comment at this time.
I'm disappointed.
That's my bad Indian accent. It sounded
very, very kind of old visual arts movie.
Very vague, very vague
accent. But this, yeah,
I beat from Missoula is a very,
uh, in, you know, very involved.
There's a lot going on with
that whole beat grim movement.
You know, people loved,
they loved to follow those poses.
Yeah. And you know, and that's,
and that's fine and that can be a big
fucking piece of your yoga puzzle.
You liked that. Cool. There's
nothing wrong with that,
but don't shit on other people who are
finding their own way to do it and maybe
learn something from them too. And you
know, try that every once in a while.
Maybe every fucking fourth
session you try something new.
You ever do yoga on pot?
I have. It's really good.
That's actually one of the best physical
activities to do on pod in my opinion,
is the best to me that in Jujitsu,
but it's,
it's right up there
with Jujitsu because a,
you feel everything and this
weird super sensitive way,
especially eating it when you eat it
and go through all those yoga movements.
Mckenna believed that,
that turns me cannot believe that.
That's really what yoga was all about.
He said it was all about how to eat out,
eat cannabis.
Like he,
he believed that he believed that
the or original origins of yoga.
We're like a cannabis optimization.
Uh, exercise makes sense. I mean,
I naturally, when I smoke or
eat one a stretch generally,
even if I'm not even thinking
about it. Good. It feels good.
And you guys aware of what body,
what's your areas that need work? You,
you want to stretch. And if my teeth are
dirty, I want to brush my teeth. Yeah.
Those are the things. Yeah. I feel
like when I got my feet stink,
I want to get in the shower. Right. Don't
want to be stinky feet when you're hi.
Yeah.
Hey,
pull up that video of the drugs are
getting yelled at because I want to,
I want to hear that.
You want to hear what was sure.
Because this is not something that would
have even happened a few years ago and
this is a, this is some new shit
and I'm going to pee because I got,
I've been drinking
with all due respect to the
fellows on the other side, uh,
that schizophrenia,
which my father was a psychiatrist
and taught me something about,
could be described as a party that talks
about saving money all the time and
have been concerned with deficits
and being totally driven by that,
but not being concerned and saving money
when people are in jail for marijuana
and mandatory minimums that judges have
said were awful and for nonviolent first
time offenders who were serving lifetime
sentences and Jay are costing US
$30,000 a year and to the population of
jails has gone up 800% in the last 30
years that schizophrenia, you're
concerned about cost and cutting costs,
but not when it's jailing a population.
Mr about a Cellie, your hands are tied on,
on schedule one,
but it is ludicrous,
absurd,
crazy,
okay
to have marijuana in the
same level as heroin.
Ask
the Light Phillip Seymour
Hoffman if you could.
Okay.
Nobody dies from marijuana.
People die from heroin.
And every second that we spend in this
country trying to enforce marijuana laws
is a second that we're not
enforcing heroin laws and
heroin and math are the two
drugs that are ravaging our country.
And every death,
including Mister Hoffman's,
is partly the responsibility of the
federal government to drug power.
These for not putting total
emphasis on the drugs that kill,
that caused people to be addicted and
have to steal to support their habit and
heroin and meth is where all
of your priority should be.
Heroin is getting into
the arms of young people,
and when we put marijuana on the same
level as heroin and LSD and meth and crack
and cocaine,
we are telling young people not to listen
to the adults about the ravages and
the problems and they don't listen
because they know you're wrong.
It's all due respect.
You should be listening to the scientist.
I understand the parents who are grieved
because they're dot child died of an
overdose.
They didn't overdose on marijuana
and you're listening to them
rather than the scientist.
Mr Bata Chelly it may go
back to a few good men,
the movie Jack Nicholson,
you can't handle the truth.
The truth is the drug war failed.
Your direction on marijuana is a failure.
Get
to dealing and saving kids
from heroin overdoses.
Now you talked about alcohol and I may,
you may have gotten to this cirrhosis
of the liver. Pretty serious thing.
Violence against spouses and women.
People don't smoke marijuana and
beat up their wives and girlfriends.
Okay.
They get drunk. Sometimes they beat
up their wives and girlfriends.
Maybe the reason there's so many more
people smoking marijuana now is cause
they're not listening and maybe
they're doing the other drugs too,
but also shows that the drug war has been
a failure. It's been a serious failure.
Okay,
boom. That was an ass kicking. No,
he that this guy from Tennessee,
representative of Tennessee.
Yup.
And you would think like one of the most
conservative states in the country and
he's a little belt and yeah,
he's old as fuck too. Yeah.
That's fucking positive sign. I like
that. I like it. Well, it's, it's,
it's unavoidable at this point in time.
It's,
it's gotten to this point where there's
so much information, there's so much,
so many studies have been done.
So much knowledge that there occasionally
they'll throw out a study, uh, you know,
some link to schizophrenia.
If somebody's horse shit,
if there was a link to
schizophrenia and marijuana,
everybody would be schizophrenia because
everyone's smoking weed. I'm not, I'm,
I don't mean anything everyone, but I
mean, God damn a lot of people. Yeah.
You know,
the thing that's so fucking incredibly
frustrating and infuriating is as part of
the criteria for scheduled one,
the drug has to have no
medicinal benefit and oh,
medicinal benefit and countless fucking
medicinal benefits are being shown by a
lot of these drugs.
I mean,
the success rate of them testing
things and getting positive results.
It's only been recent.
They've been able to get access to things
like siliciden and even the marijuana
studies that they've been able,
there's still hardly are ever
able to even work with marijuana.
It's one of the toughest ones to work
with, talking to the people at maps.
But every,
you know,
they're testing these things and
it's coming back amazingly positive.
You something like
that.
Sanjay Gupta completely reversing as
policy because he watched some kid who was
on 14 fucking pharmaceuticals that were
going to kill her and then she smokes
weed cause she had epilepsy,
smokes weed that has high CBD and is doing
better than she ever has in her life.
And he's like, okay, I'm fucking,
I was a Dickhead, I was a doctor.
But now I know what fucking happened.
Good for him because he was saying a lot
of really dumb shit he fucking switched
is you look at the facts and you can't
help but change your opinion that there
is medicinal benefit period.
You cannot leave it in that criteria.
It's almost like the perfect question.
It's almost like how
fucked up is this culture?
We're going to give this culture,
this amazing plant that grows easily,
has no issues with toxicity,
doesn't kill anybody.
Also you can eat it. It provides you
with all the essential amino acids.
It's very high in protein and you can get
high on it and when you get high on it
makes you introspective and
makes you more sensitive.
It makes food actually
taste more delicious.
It makes sex feel better,
makes your body feel more sensitive and
it can help you with Glaucoma and it
makes the best paper and it makes them,
you just run this laundry
list of shit you like.
There's no way that could be illegal.
It's the most illegal thing.
It's the most illegal
thing in our crazy country.
It's like the perfect question to
find out how insane our society do.
We have no meter.
One thing that we can say is the
most beneficial plant on earth.
It's the marijuana plant.
That's the one and that's,
that's schedule one drug elite.
The most illegal amongst the
most illegal things you can buy.
It's like at the circus where you hit
that thing with a mallet and it goes all
the way to the top. That's goes all the
way to the top of the crazy meter. Let's
talk about how nuts it is that that same
drug is also now legal in two states
like the these two. These states have
gotten so fed up Washington and Seattle,
both two of the most awesome
spots in the country.
They've gotten or Washington and Colorado,
they've gotten to this point where
they're like, you know what? Fuck you.
It's legal. Okay. We say it's
legal in our state. It's legal now.
Yet you could sell it in Colorado.
They're going gangster and Seattle.
They're like washing Colorado going,
what's gonna happen there?
But in Colorado they just fucking
salad in it, selling it like crazy.
And then the government's like,
yeah,
well you can't put the
money in the bank then.
And then eventually they re have
revisited that and said, okay,
we're going to let people use the banks
because it's so much fucking money.
There's so much money.
Like what?
You're going to keep that money out of
the bank so the bank fucking failing.
Don't the banks needed money?
What are you guys doing?
Like you got to this emerging industry
and you better look at it as an industry
now because now it's proven itself.
They made $1 million in the first fucking
hour when they were selling marijuana
in Colorado.
They were just fucking going off and
it's only like 12 stores and one day they
made 1 million bucks. Yeah. This is, this
is a really encouraging, I mean, I think
once you start to see water pouring
through the damn like this, it's going to,
it's going to break the dam. The more
they resisted and don't go along with it.
It's just going to fucking,
it's gonna crack it.
I mean it's just information excited.
It's too much information. Yeah.
There's too much absolute irrefutable
information. And the, the,
the cool thing about these states is,
you know,
if you have real good states' rights,
the ability for states to
regulate a lot of these things,
it's going to be a great way to
ensure that some of these draconian,
crazy bullshit laws don't get passed
because some states are going to wake up,
you know,
in this big nationwide consciousness,
it's easier to kind of get enough dummies
circled together from everywhere to
block something. But you
know, in one state, you know,
you have a lot of more flexibility
to actually spread information,
create a new kind of vibe
and create new rules.
Like they decided they're not
supposed to be able to do that.
They're not supposed to be
able to say weed is legal,
but they just said we're just
fucking doing it. You know,
I don't care if the
federal laws say you can't,
we're going to do it and maybe you could
come in with the feds and cause trouble,
but you know we're
going to take that risk.
And I think putting a lot more rights
like that back to the states is,
is the way to go.
Oh, whatsapp. Absolutely.
I mean that's the whole reason why the
whole state situation was set up in the
first place.
In states rights are supposed to supersede
the federal rights or laws rather.
We're supposed to
supersede the federal laws.
And I think we're also saying
this overwhelming wave of
information starting to
shift the way they interact with us
and the way they're forced to deal with
certain situations when it comes to
world events like Syria for example,
when Obama went on TV and was talking
about military action for Syria,
the whole world went, Ooh, Ooh,
you want, you have to do what? Why?
Because somebody poisoned people.
Do you know what you've done?
Do you know a million people are dead
and I racked and many people you'd kill
from drones. It had nothing to do with
the person you were trying to kill.
Shut the fuck up. No, you don't have
to go to Syria now. It's not important.
We invade Syria and then they
stopped talking to him about it.
When was the last time you heard Syria
and the news and that was the last time
you said Siri on CNN.
When was the last time you saw Syria on
Fox News where they were saying if the
invasions eminent the imminent invasion
of Syria? No, no, no, no. It's all gone.
People don't want that.
And that's the thing,
that's another thing that people get
frustrated with how spineless the
politicians are.
But in another way it's
kind of encouraging and
they really have no fucking
backpack. If we really mount up and
say, no, that's bullshit, don't do that.
That's for fucking were over. And we do
that in mass like people did for Syria.
They'll just say, okay cool. Cause
they're going to survive too.
And to survive they have to get elected.
You know? And I know all vote rigging,
blah, blah, blah. Yeah. All right.
Maybe they push things a little bit,
but if it's fucking in mass, you know
they're going to go along with the tide.
We just got to create the tide
and s and make enough motion ourselves
unified that they have to listen.
And I think we've done that with weed.
It's going to continue.
Keep going that way. And we could do
that with a lot of other shit too. Yeah.
This is as long as that.
There's truth
and what we're saying.
Yeah.
In the marijuana truth is something
that seems so impossible and improbable
cause there's so much from the moment
that it was made illegal from the whole
conspiracy to make it illegal by a guy
who was at paper manufacturer and own
newspapers,
William Randolph Hearst.
If you read the story of how
marijuana was made illegal,
I won't bore you with the details because
I've told it on this podcast too many
times,
but it's a guy who owned newspapers.
He made a bunch of fucking stories
up and that's how we became illegal.
And when they made weed illegal,
they didn't even know they
were making hemp illegal.
Now they recently passed this farm bill.
Did you see this where they're going
to allow states that make hemp growing
legal to grow it at universities.
So the universities are going to
be allowed to grow hemp. So in a,
in a way it's sort of making hemp start
to become legal and I don't know if
that's for commercial application.
I don't,
I don't know like what they're
going to be able to do with the ham,
but that's even dumber than the weed law.
If you thought the weed law was bad,
this hemp thing is even fucking
crazier because it is legal.
They just can't grow it,
which is so fucking stupid.
I hear you.
I'm importing a bunch of hemp over fucking
fucking the Canadian border. Every,
every month we're getting to
the hemp seeds from Canada
because we can't grow it.
Do we have shitty soil? No, we don't
have shitty soil. I show it was great.
It could grow. We'd like fucking
anybody else in the world, but nope,
we can't do it.
So many farmers would profit.
So many farmers would benefit.
Just like you seeing this economic boom
in Colorado because of these people
being able to sell marijuana.
Look at that pot shops in Denver,
open door to foreign in
78 $578 million in sales
a year, $578 million. And
that's just the beginning.
That's just the tip of the iceberg.
Those states are going to be
in from the revenue from that.
They're going to be fucking have
cool public areas and parks and art.
The states are going to get cooler
and cooler and cooler till finally
everybody's like, fuck man, we got
to move to one of these cool states.
They got the best parks,
they've got the best fucking public works,
everything's working smooth cause
they got money and everybody's happy.
And that's what's generally going
to happen in the neighboring states.
Going to be like, God Damn Colorado's
fucking got it going on. You know,
and fucking Idaho. I think
I'd know borders Colorado,
right? Idaho's gonna be like,
well fuck this.
You know,
we're not going to like Colorado
would be the ones to win,
so it's going to create this ripple effect
where, you know, I think it's going to,
it's going to spread.
I fucking love Colorado.
I just love it. I loved that
they were the first, you know,
the m and Washington state,
but just Colorado is just,
it's such a fucking gangster,
cowboy state, you know? It's like,
it's such a weird combination of like
western pioneer people who move there and
really cool people who
stayed, you know? It's like
everybody else was going to California
and the people that stopped in Colorado
went, we move. Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Can we just stay here?
Like why don't we just, why are you
guys going to keep going west man,
do you see how beautiful it is here?
Do you really think over there is better?
I mean, what, what? Come on man.
What's listen, go over there.
Make sure you send me a letter. Tell me
how groovy it is. I'll be right here.
Shirt.
When you find a place that's unbelievably
physically beautiful like Colorado,
I always think that for some reason
that is going to accumulate a lot of
intelligent and cool people because
there's a benefit in having beauty around
you. Does the reason why people
spend so much money on art?
Why do people dress so nice?
Why do people have nice cars is do they
have nice cars to drive or do they have
nice cars to look at? What's not just
to dry? Because if it was just to drive,
every car would look like a rock on the
outside and inside of it would just be
this, you know, really opulent luxurious
thing that made you feel good as a,
as a passenger. No, you don't.
Most people don't even worry
about what the inside looks like.
You look on the inside of that car,
they got fucking Jack in the
box wrappers on the ground,
fucking empty soda cans and Starbucks
is flopping around their cup holder and
I'm worried at all but the inside.
But the outside is polished and shiny.
Why is it? Because when you look
at things that are beautiful,
they give you a feeling that give
you a good feeling. That's why,
you know when you're taking your
woman out and you know you go,
you ready and she's like yeah
and she steps out and you
look at it and like Whoa,
he looked great. Like Ooh,
this feeling, this law,
this feeling of of observing beauty.
You know, hopefully you do that.
I mean you might be,
might be unfortunate in that regard but
if you are fortunate in that regard,
if you live in a neighborhood where this
beautiful trees and you see the sunset
and you see it,
you know poking through these trees
and you look over at the lake and it's
fucking beautiful and you see a fish
jump and you're like wow, like that.
It's hitting you. It's
energy. There's a lot of,
and when you live with
that is you probably like a
little on the ball or at the
very least your inspired by all this stuff
being around you inspired by all this
beauty of the info. It definitely makes
a difference. You know, you look at,
I think landscape really plays a
bigger part than people give credit.
I mean you look at some of the,
the hardest harshest places and they're
dry as fuck generally. You know,
like as far as from the,
from a kind of philosophical and religious
and kind of an area that's really
difficult. You know, some of the,
some of the worst kind of ID
said it's not always the case,
but you see a lot in like
really challenging environments
that are really fucked
up. You get people who are really kind
of obstinate and a lot of their ways that
thinking where in the really kind of
beautiful regions like Nepal versus China,
you know, when you're around
that kind of all inspiring,
it's not that often that you
see really crazy, you know,
kind of philosophies that come up.
I Dunno if it's the people move to that
or whether the environment actually
itself kind of has some impact on,
on the psychology of the people who
live around it. And there's also,
of course people that go to
areas where there unbelievable,
there's unbelievable beauty and
exploit them. Europeans, you know,
how many people have gone to the
jungle and exploited the Amazon,
the indigenous people, how many people
have found resources in these strange,
beautiful places and just fucked
over tribe members? You know,
Mckenna was talking about this, um,
slaughter in the Amazon where a,
I forget which country,
where they were killing people for
rubber when they found out about rubber.
It was like in the early,
uh,
early 20th century and they were going
in there and I'm giving these people like
you had to have, he had to bring
back this amount of rubber every day,
and if you didn't,
they would cut that amount of weight
that's missing off in human flesh.
So they slaughtered these
people. I mean, they,
they killed thousands and thousands
of these people. At one point in time,
you know, they had over a hundred
thousand people in this, in this area,
and then they were down to just a
couple thousand by the time, um,
whoever the fuck rescued them.
However, this was, uh, stopped.
I don't recall the entire story,
but this,
the concept of giving them a quota and
then removing that same amount and flesh,
if they didn't reach that quota,
cutting people's arms off kind of be,
and doing it in front of everybody
to make sure that these people were
absolutely terrified to go out and
people are capable of horrible,
horrible things.
But my point is that when they're not,
when society stable, when you're not
dealing with that sort of evil invaders,
Mongol invasion type situation,
when you're in a place that's beautiful.
A lot of times the people
there are pretty cool. Yeah. I,
I tend to find the same thing and
it's interesting how, you know,
some places really do trigger
that over others, you know,
there's no each communities.
Yeah. Then there's,
you just know when you're in a special
place, you know, I don't know what I,
the whole beauty concept is interesting,
you know,
like why is that one place like why
is looking out over the mountains in
Colorado more beautiful than, you
know, the Cedar Trees in Texas.
I live in Texas and I'm
never really inspired by the
beauty of the Texas fucking
hill country. It's nice. I like it.
I love Texas. I love living there,
but it's not the same as when I go to
like a beautiful beach or I go to a
beautiful mountain or I go even if there's
even beautiful like desert landscapes
that I've love.
But it's funny how there's something
that just goes and hits the right buttons
in the brain says this is beautiful.
You know,
they've studied that with people at
people at some form of symmetry and health
and, but with nature it's
even kind of more curious.
It's just more maybe more like there's
a life force or an order to it.
I think we like order,
you know,
maybe we're part of that creating force
and when we do that we like to look at
things that look like they're ordered
and organized by some kind of presence.
I don't know.
We were also trying to figure out the
other day because one of my sponsors is
1-800-FLOWERS.
We're trying to figure out why flowers
are so fucking beautiful. I mean,
what is it about flowers?
What evolutionary advantage is there
to being enthralled by these powerful
colors to lips and roses.
And it's like, ah, but if you see a
beautiful bouquet of flowers, man,
there's a feeling that it gives you this
feeling of like admiration of nature's
artwork that's like, wow, beautiful
thing. And I think for your feeling as a,
a mountain or something that is Huxley,
Huxley,
he had an idea that these visions that
you see in the psychedelic experiences
are generally very colorful environment.
He did a lot of cactus medicines like
Mescalin and, and things like that.
And so the colors get really intensely
vibrant and visual and bright.
And he was saying that we find beautiful,
those things that mimic what we see in,
in that form of experience. You know,
so like in a DMT trip, you know,
the colors are out of this
world are Iowasca trip.
The colors are so vibrant and beautiful
and amazing and they come in a lot of
these, what the, they actually
call it the chrysanthemum,
which is named after a flower cause they
come in these kaleidoscopic patterns of
things that actually
do look like a flower.
So I think there may be
something to that theory,
maybe in whatever realm beyond that you're
accessing or whatever nether regions
of your mind.
If you don't want to go to realm beyond,
there's some ideal of what you see there
and it, and it's looking at a flower,
like a beautiful Blue
Chrysanthemum reminds you of that.
Even if it's subliminally and you don't
have had a psychedelic experience that
triggers whatever you know of some way
back home or some other realm or some
part of your brain that you don't really
access often. Maybe that's what it is.
Maybe flowers remind us of psychedelics.
Yeah, that's kind of interesting.
That's an interesting thought because um,
that's what they call that.
That gateway when you first breakthrough
to DMT and you see that crazy pattern,
they call it the flower of life.
And that that flower of life is,
is a very common geometric pattern that
exists in a lot of religious artwork,
mosques and things are going to,
and God damn, it's beautiful.
And when you see that you just can't help
but just fucking smile and look like,
Holy Shit. That's pretty, yeah, and when
you're having a psych, there's a flood.
It's the, the very rough crude
version of that symbol. But
yeah, you can look up, look up DMT
chrysanthemum or something like that.
That's exactly what you see though. That's
the weirdest thing. It's like when you,
when you're confronted with these
archetypes that exist in, you know,
somewhat in so many different pieces
of artwork and you see it like right in
front of your face, just like, whoa.
Like that's so like so classic.
It's a classic image. Like
wow. It's just, it is,
it is exactly what you've seen that,
you know,
and he said that about gemstones too,
you know?
And that's why the fascination
with these gemstones,
why are gemstone so valuable? Because
that's really back in the ancient days,
okay, water kind of reflects,
but there wasn't all this glass.
And Shit that we created now,
but they would be able to see,
there'd be able to see something
in that gemstone, you know,
all the facets and the colors
and the light and they,
and it was so beautiful to them because
that was something that they could only
see in there, you know, these visions
or that, that Nether region of the mind.
So flowers,
gems, all these things that we prize
or actually hearkening back to those,
you know, those visions
that we have. Yeah.
And for people to think that
it's total complete horseshit,
one of the reasons why they think that
is your brain most certainly produces
psychedelic drugs.
And they,
they think that your brain producing
them in large quantities while you're
dreaming. And so they're, they're
doing some studies on that now.
And the Cottonwood Research
Foundation, which was where, I'm sorry,
how about cough drop in my mouth? Doctor
Rick Strassman who wrote the book Dmt,
the spirit molecule. Um, he was supposed
to be here on the podcast last month,
but he's such a fucking hippie. It
doesn't even have a cell phone. And a,
we were exchanging emails,
but it was a UFC weekend and I was gone.
He hadn't heard from me for a couple of
days because I just don't do my email
for a couple of them just fucking
busy. Right. And so he thought some,
for some reason, another I had my mind
or something like that. It's crazy.
They made other plans. I was
like, dude, what's, get a phone?
It'd be so easy to fix that conversation.
You know, I call you, you called me.
But um, he's in the middle of some, uh,
some new tests and he's
got a new book coming out,
so we'll have monsoon for sure. He's a
really cool guy. I really love Rick. Uh,
but he,
um,
he did some work recently where
they discovered that this is a,
it's always been the big controversy.
Does DMT m and a from the pineal gland,
that what is literally your third eye
that in know the center of the brain has
this eye that this, this thing that in
reptiles actually has a retina and cornea,
you know,
it's this weird fucking Oregon.
And they were the always hypothesis
hypothesized that DMT had come from there.
That's the seat of the soul and ancient
religions and the bent knee injections.
Yeah.
Well then they found out
that they actually can prove
it now rats and live rats
and a live rat, they have gone straight
to the pineal gland and found DMT.
So they know the DMTs coming out
of the pineal gland of live rats.
Pretty sure it's coming out of
ours too. Yeah, most likely.
And if that is the case and your brain
does produce this stuff for sure,
it's in Dodgers to the
human body for sure.
It's produced by the liver and the lungs
and they're pretty sure for sure it's
produced by the pineal gland and
pretty sure that while you're sleeping,
that shit's coming out. So one of
the interesting facets of about, um,
a lot of psychedelic trips, especially
DMT, is that after it's over,
it's very difficult to
hang on to the memories.
Like they drift away and they fade away
so quickly. It's like they're so intense.
And then when they're over there,
this lost feeling.
And I've been really thinking lately
because of my experiences with a Alpha
brain in an isolation tanks that
there might be something to that with
psychedelic trips for,
you know,
having a psychedelic trip while you
are really loaded up with nootropics.
Like we'd have to figure out what is
the optimum blend to give you the most
clarity in recalling experience.
Yeah. Because just like
a dream, DMT disappears.
And so the idea is that when
you're asleep, you know,
we just accept the fact that we
shut off for eight hours a night.
If you're lucky eight hours and
disappear and then wake up and then, oh,
I've got a crazy dream.
I was on a skateboard and there was a
missile coming my way or whatever the fuck
your dream is that that's
about as crazy as it ever got.
But that might not be the case.
You might be in full blown psychadelic
dream state at several times during the
night.
Well you are just like a DMT trip,
just like the most intense mushroom trip
with your eyes closed in a dark room.
Like all those things you, you might be
experiencing that on a regular basis.
And one of my reasons for being inclined
to think that is that every time I've
done DMT I go,
and not even the the Times now,
but the times when I first did
it, I go, Oh, I've been here.
I know this place.
Like the very first time I did it,
I remember that feeling like, Oh, I've
been here before, I know this place.
Like why do I know this place?
And then I'm back to reality.
It is a funny, that sense of familiarity
is funny, especially in that, you know,
cause after a while,
I guess you could say it's because you've
associated positively from going there
during the trip before,
but it really feels like,
it feels like another type of home,
you know,
where you're just in a place
that's really beautiful.
It's communicating in a new
way, you know, they can't,
sometimes words come through
through beings and things like that,
but really it's just some
kind of information is
splashing against this force
field that we have in the
mind and creating these
beautiful colors and passing
along information in some code that we
can't quite decipher, but we know it,
you know, and we know something
about that message and it's,
it's a fucking beautiful place.
It also seems to know that you're not
supposed to be there while your conscious
and so it's trying to give you some
information while you're there. It's,
it seems like,
like I've always felt like when I've
done DMT that while it's happening,
they're like, well can you do in
here? Oh look at you. You're here.
What are you here? You're here now.
So as almost like consciousness,
like being conscious,
being a person who is awake and turning
on your television and hitting your
keyboard is a mode that you're not
supposed to operate that dimension with.
So you're sort of tricking the universe.
When you introduced that
dimension to a conscious mode,
it's like the conscious mode is like,
what the fuck is this all you
don't remember? You don't know.
You all know you don't know.
And then you're like, why
do I know this place? Like,
Oh, you don't know. You don't
know why you know it. We love you.
That's one of the things
I'll never forget.
I had one really intense experience
and they're going, we love you.
600 million, 500,000 times. Look at
this. And it kept saying, look this.
And every time it would say,
look at this,
it would show me something like insanely
crazy, beautiful, impossibly beautiful.
And then the next time it would be like
a million times more beautiful than that.
Like you thought that was as
beautiful as it yet, look at this.
They would show me something else.
Crazy was, I love you 600 million,
500,000 times.
Look at this,
you know, all of the, I've been really
amazed. People think when you encounter,
you know, some kind of entities or beings,
they're going to be real boring. Like,
Whoa, hello, welcome to my realm.
Every time that I've communicated with
any kind of spirit form and one of these
trips there can, they can be
funny. They're interesting.
They're vibrant, you know?
It's like, it's not what you think your
dad. Yeah, yeah, exactly. It's like they,
they have a sense of humor. It's, it's
really interesting how that is, you know,
we were so ridiculous in our
ideas of how the world should be,
how rigid scholars and learned
people are supposed to be. You know,
we have this idea that you, if you, yeah,
if you have knowledge and
wisdom and experience and
if you're somehow or another
quote unquote enlightened, then you're
going to be like bland and flat. Yeah, no,
totally. You know, it reminds me, so one
of the, the third experience I did in,
in New Mexico, I came back and my next up
on the, on the path after the snuffing,
the five Meo DMT was a
mushroom and Syrian rue trip.
And they call that Anna Wasco because
just a candy flipping motherfucker down.
I just did what did, what, what the, did
what the, you know, the woman said, uh,
and this was up on the menu.
This is my next fucking wow journey.
So they call it Ana Wasco because
it's something of an Iowa Ska analog,
even though it's not DMT based mushrooms
and Syrian Rue create that. Well,
mushrooms are five, four locks [inaudible]
trip to tryptamine. Oh really? Yeah.
That's what psilocybin is.
Psilocybin is, is, yeah,
it's Dmt plus something else.
Very interesting.
One of the more fascinating things about
mushrooms itself and then Syrian rue is
a powerful Maoi.
So it's like come kind of combining the
same two forces that are in, yeah. Let me,
Alaska Bruce, I've said it
before and I've said it wrong.
Let me find out. So how do you
spell silicide? P, s I. L. O. C y.
B. I. N. C. Y. B. I n. Um,
either Silverson or psilocybin is
the, uh, the, the actual, yeah,
here it is. Die. Oh boy.
Yeah,
I can't pronounce that.
Okay.
What the point is,
forget about all the science
behind because obviously
I shouldn't be distributed
at, there's Psilocybin, it's Scilla
sin. What's, which one is Tillison.
So Allison has also, um, I don't know,
maybe some other active compound.
Yeah. Yeah. So awesome. Um,
yeah,
is another one that's like really
close to a human neuro transmitters.
These things are, they're just
there. They're super close there.
They're super close to things that the
human brain already has in it. Yup.
So, so anyways, I do this and in
Wasco trip and it was, you know,
I never done Iowasca at that point.
It was my third psychedelic experience
and this one was completely different.
And in this one I was very much like
some of the Iowasca stories I told.
I was riding on the back of a Cobra and
this Cobra was in the jungle and I'm in
the fucking desert. Mexico mountains
here. There's no jungle anywhere.
So the fact that I was in a jungle
was incredibly odd to me anyways,
but I'm riding on the head of this
Cobra and the back of a jungle and I'm
talking with my grandmother who was like
somehow imbued in the spirit of this,
of this Cobra.
And she was still alive by the way,
which is another interesting facet.
But anyway,
so she's imbued in the spirit of this
Cobra and I'm dipping down in the earth
and much like the Iowasca visions, I'm
having bugs come inside me and explode.
And meanwhile I'm laid out on my back and,
um,
I'm shivering and I'm kind
of lifting my chest up.
And I must've looked kind
of crazy to the Shama,
but she must've been kind of used to it
cause I sweating profusely and I needed
blankets.
I was cold and I'm shivering and I'm
going through this and this really intense
vision. But all the while, my
grandfather, who's Aubrey, my grandfather,
Aubrey's out on these rocks and you know,
in a whole different environment
and he's just laughing,
like laughing so warmly and like
kindly cause he's saying, oh,
you're really going through it now.
Oh she's going to take you down there
into the dirt. And he how with laughter.
And he was so happy and
joyous about doing it.
I've never met my grandfather robbery.
He was so happy and joyous about it.
That experience that I started laughing
too because I thought it was hilarious.
Even though spiders or like going into
my eyes and exploding and I'm riding on
the snake and I have no control and
I'm dipping down into the earth and I'm
expelling this sweat. And you
know, Aubrey's just laughing.
So I'm laughing and it was
this whole wild experience.
But the thing that impressed me the
most was just how vibrant and happy it
wasn't. Like, you know, you
see these mediums and it's
all so somber and serious.
Aubrey says to say,
you know,
good luck in your next Algebra test,
or I don't know what the fuck it was,
but he was just happy as shit,
you know?
And that was the kind
of experience that you,
that I tend to find when I
encounter these entities,
but either family or these other things,
it's really, they're full of life.
They're almost that
version in its best self.
That's also what you're
looking for though.
You're looking for love and you're
looking for them to be full of life.
So if you really are creating the
university inside your own mind,
that's what you as a positive person
seeking positive experiences would create
that to create your, all of your
relatives being super cool. Yeah,
it's absolutely true. This is what a
Rick Strassman by the way said silicide.
This is how he explained siliciden that
psilocybin the active ingredient in
magic mushrooms, uh, after being ingested,
the body removes phosphorous atoms
from the silicide been converting it to
Scilla sin.
Sin Listen differs
from dimethyltryptamine Dmt by one oxygen,
uh,
that silicide Silverson eh,
he likes to think of it as orally active
DMT. That's Rick Strassman's take on it.
So that's what,
that's the,
the definition very interested in
it's silicon is the, uh, that's the,
the active, that's what happens when
you, when you take it that it's, uh,
it's four h o d m t
silicide or silicon or it's,
it's spelled a bunch of different cause
this, cause this really was pretty much,
and I lost a trip that I went on.
The differentiators are very,
you know, it's very
similar. It makes sense.
I mean if you're taking him
Mao inhibitor and mushrooms,
I've heard people have horrendous
trips taking pharmaceutical,
Mao inhibitors and mushrooms.
I imagine these mean cause they're
intensely powerful Mao inhibitors.
Like if you take a mild Mao
inhibitor, like say harming, you know,
and compare it and that's what's
in Syria and yeah. Harmfully yeah.
And by the way,
harming when they first,
this was really crazy when
they first found it, they
wanted to call it telepathy,
but they couldn't because they didn't
realize that when they discovered it by
use of these, uh, the IOWASCA showman,
they didn't understand that it had
already been discovered that the,
the chemical component
of it already had a name.
So they couldn't call it telepathy.
But that was what they were inclined
to call it because these people were
tripping their balls out and having
these fucking telepathic experiences.
Shared experiences. Yeah. The problem is
you can't document them. You know, you're,
you're freaking the fuck out. You know,
you know, but you can't show anybody.
He was like, man, your bullshit and
try this and they take it. Okay,
what are we getting maintenance?
How about telepathy?
What a bunch of scientists decided to
name something telepathy. Holy Shit.
You know what,
what are you taking?
And the reason why we don't know about
this folks is not because people are
dying.
The reason why we don't know about this
is because we've been denied by our
daddies.
Buy Our daddy overlords are government.
And they've kept these intensely powerful
and hugely beneficial to some folks.
Hugely beneficial experiences.
Kept them from us.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And you can only imagine how many cool
ways and places in the knowledge that was
out there.
I mean I'm very fortunate I was able to
go with someone who had been doing this,
leading people on these journeys for
20 years, you know, and had experience,
no new kind of the properties of
what to do, knew what to mix new,
the amounts to do it.
And so I could just really trust.
But it gets sketchy if you're trying
to trying to figure this stuff out.
That's why I always recommend people go
with a guide or someone who knows what
to do. And those are sometimes
hard to find, you know?
And that's why the only thing I recommend
now is going to some places where I've
been in Peru and to do Iowasca
so I can trust the, the Shaman,
the Pearson to meister leading
the ceremony. I can trust
the medicine cause it's,
you know,
there's a lot of iffy stuff and that's
another byproduct of making it illegal.
No,
it's because you're forced to make some
challenging choices, both risking
legality, which sucks. You know,
you don't want to wind up in a fucking
cage, you know, or your choice, you know,
forced to deal with something that you
don't know the exact properties of where
you don't know kind of
what you're getting into.
So it's a lot hairier of a situation.
Yeah. And you, if you're a person
who has a job that you like,
you want to keep that job. You
know, you don't want to be fired.
Do you want to be outcasts? Do you want
to make sure you make your mortgage?
You want to keep feeding your family
and then they're gonna Piss test you.
Oh God.
That's what's really crazy.
It's like you could smoke pot on Friday
night when you get home from work and if
they piss test you on Monday,
you're stone cold sober.
You're showing up for work.
Clearheaded Caba coffee newspaper
in your arm and they're like, Bob,
we'd like to see you pee into this cup.
Please. Like, what are you talking about?
What'd you do this weekend? We own you.
We own your body weight on your body.
Did you do something illegal
this weekend, Bob? No, no, no.
Not at all. Oh, you didn't?
Hmm. We don't have a medical
marijuana. Not Federally. Federal.
You don't federal, you don't federally,
it's illegal. So pee in the cup.
And not only that,
we're going to impose our own laws.
We don't want you smoking cigarettes
because that's bad for your health.
We don't smell.
You know what I mean?
Fucking healthcare programs keep
you from smoking cigarettes.
They can tell you to do that. They
could tell you to not smoke marijuana.
They can tell you,
you can't do mushrooms that can tell
you know cocaine in your system.
You did the fucking, they own you. Not
from nine to five, Monday through Friday.
They own you on Saturday and Sunday too.
They own you 24 seven if
you want to work for ups.
So brutal. They Test Your pee. Yeah.
Yeah. And then that whole idea,
if they really were out there for your
benefit and locking you up was for your
benefit.
They'd lock up all the fat people.
They'd lock up all the cigarette smokers.
They'd lock up.
Everybody doing any bad duck
dynasty would go right off the air.
At first they locked
up all the fat people.
Do you know how bad their ratings would
drop the fucking right through the floor.
It'd be like a sinkhole opened up right
under duck dynasty. Same fucking thing.
Obviously obesity kills you
eventually and it kills you faster,
way faster than that.
If it's doing it for your own good,
you should lock up all the fucking
fat people, but that's insane.
So they don't do it, but
it's just as insane with our
locking people up for, yeah,
we don't need a daddy. Stupid. Yup. And
you're not smart enough to be my daddy.
Dumb. Fuck, that's, that's
our real problem, man.
We got a bunch of fucking unenlightened
people that are set in the rules and
we're making it so you can't have these
enlightening experiences and be a guy
that sets the rules.
Because if you are,
well then we discredit
you because you're a guy.
Like we found out that Obama was going
these shamonic trips and doing mushrooms.
We'd be like, what can I get that
fucking guy out of there? Not Us, not us,
but America, the right. You
imagine how fucking Hannity,
those shitheads fucking that Sean
Hannity type dudes. Meanwhile,
it should be the criteria for leading
our goddamn country. You should,
you shouldn't be able to be president
unless you done mushrooms at least once.
The Shit
you shouldn't be allowed
to and you should,
you should have a videotape or you doing
mushrooms so we could prove it like
this is the mushrooms.
Like it should be like,
I need to know you did a big
dose more than four grams. Right?
I want to see you get fucking blown out
in the center of the universe and then
crawl back home. You know,
like really? That's what I
want to say it. If you don't,
if you'd never done that man,
that we're,
we're having some weird conversation
here because everybody who has done that
agrees separate red band was
fucking can't trust that he's done.
He doesn't think it does anything,
but that's him.
But everybody else that I know that
has had like a blown out breakthrough
psychedelic experience,
they believe that it changes lives.
They believe that it enhances
your personality. It gives
you a new perspective,
gives you a new way to look at the world
and is probably hugely beneficial to
your growth as a human being.
But the people that don't,
they're the ones who judge it, that
people that haven't had that experience,
they're the ones who come out against him,
which is so crazy.
It's like blind people getting pissed
that you're looking at things. It's like,
what are you doing? You're looking
at shit. No, no, no, no, no.
I don't trust what you're seeing. What's
right fucking in front of you, man.
The lake's right there says, Ooh. Says
you it crazy person using your eyes.
That's really what,
it's almost like someone who hasn't had
a psychedelic experience trying to tell
you that it's bad for you or that you
shouldn't do it. It's like, are you sure?
Okay. Because I'm okay.
Not only am I okay,
but I'm pretty sure I wouldn't be this
guy if it wasn't for those experiences.
And, um, you're a silly
bitch and you're telling me,
you're telling me what to do
based on nonsense. I think I,
I think I'm going with my instincts here.
I think I'm going to,
I'm going counterculture on Ya.
I'm going counter on a
culture.
There's so many forces that are pushing
us away from being conscious and away
from being awake.
That whole little mini rant you did about
what goes through your daily life from
the phones. So this honk. So
the work, all of this stuff,
it's not like it was back in the old days,
you know back in the old days maybe you
could walk your bare feet on the ground
and you were pretty connected and
you didn't need to take these massive
psychedelic trips,
although they probably did and fucking
loved it all throughout all cultures.
But that's besides the point,
it wasn't maybe as necessary but
now in this crazy weird world,
it's so much easier to get off track.
You know and you look on TV
and it's really frustrate.
I get really physically
antsy and frustrated when I
go somewhere and they have
like real housewives on TV
cause it's like so visible.
The unconsciousness that's going on in
this drama that's all nonsensically ego
based and all of this shit that's being
kind of pushed out and it's filtering
through our consciousness.
And then you know,
to ban the only thing that can really,
we're not the only thing but one of
the most powerful tools to realign you.
It's just a, it's a recipe for fucking
disaster. And it's where we are. Yes.
It's one of the things that makes
life so interesting though because
unfortunately,
because look,
I like to talk a good game and I love it
if everybody was enlightened, but man,
it wouldn't be as fun. One, uh,
one of the things that's
fun about life is that the,
there are a bunch of crazy fucks
out there that don't get it.
And that when you do find people who do
get it, whatever, get it means you're,
you're appreciate them so much more.
It's like you really don't appreciate
the light until you see the dark.
You really don't appreciate. Cool. And
See, hanging out with Douchey. You don't,
you know, you don't appreciate generosity
until you meet a few cons. You know,
and that's, it's
unfortunate, but that's real.
That's one of the things
that makes mushrooms so
beautiful is that people don't
know.
And when you do hit me like how is
this possible that this is illegal?
How is this possible? This is
an on CNN. How is this possible?
The front page of the New York Times
doesn't say stop everything and do
mushrooms. Stop what you're doing.
Stop everything. Stop making laws,
stopped doing the stock market.
Everybody should do mushrooms. Holy Shit.
That should be the front
page of the New York Times.
Stop what you're doing and do mushrooms.
They were,
if they really wanted to give you news,
life changing news, that's the real news.
It's, it's, it's the life changing.
News is not Justin Bieber got arrested.
That's not the life changing news.
Life changing news is there's
these mushrooms that grow,
they grow on cow shit and if you
take them, that might be what God is.
Bieber if you're listening, I can take
you down to Peru with this from my Alaska.
He's young.
He's about 1819 so whenever he's ready,
he's ready. You or I would be dead
if we were that kid. He's lucky.
He has a minimum amount of testosterone
and he weighs 18 pounds because he was,
he was a manly man,
like an Elvis Presley type dude.
A reason why all of us lost fucking mind
and pills cause he, he ran out of com.
Okay, thanks. They sucked
all the come out of his body.
So he just started taking pills. Is
that dangerous? I guess it is there.
You can't fuck everybody. You can. You
mean, look, there's a bottom. You know,
there's like, there's a
comfortable medium. You know,
you could be like Bill Clinton,
you know,
you could be like a serious Dick's linger,
but you can't be like Elvis Presley
Dang made it to ripe old age.
They were allegedly, who knows what
it was like hanging around with them.
I mean the guy did a lot of crazy shit.
Maybe that was why it was launching
flaming bodies over the roof.
The fucking here's out of cons
and crazy and how to calm.
The guy was just calming all day long.
Constantly. I think when you're there,
I mean then by the way,
Gingiss existed in an era without Twitter.
Good luck pulling all that shit off
with Facebook. They'd fucking revolt.
Do you know what he's doing? Jesus
Christ, but the Bieber thing,
it's like this kid is experiencing not
just a level of fame that most human
beings will never experience.
Almost all human beings will
never experience 99.9% of
famous people will never
experience the level of fame that
Justin Bieber is on. Not only that,
he's doing it in the craziest time
ever to be famous.
An era where there is just constant 24
hour images coming in of everything you
do, every time he drives fast,
every time you smoked pot,
every time he gets pulled over,
every time he gets arrested,
every time something crazy happens
and he's clearly out of control.
He's 19 he's got a half I'll
fucking billion dollars in
his pocket and he's just
running around like a maniac with the
Willy Wonka golden ticket. What would,
what would anybody expect this
kid to do differently? Well,
every action needs an equally powerful
reaction and I think if you were in that
very challenge, I'm not going to deny
it's an immensely challenging situation.
You got to go fucking overboard.
The other way to make sure that you keep
some level of sanity or ride that bitch
right into the beach. Justin Bieber
style smoked pot on airplanes.
It's all the pilots have to do
fucking oxygen or to stay on the edge.
You hear about that?
No,
he was on a plane and apparently he was
smoking so much pot on the plane that
the pilots had to put oxygen masks on.
Look at the,
the FAA is looking into allegations
regarding Bieber's flight to New Jersey.
The FAA is investigating it cause he
was on a private jet and he just started
lighting up. He can do whatever
he wants. He probably flew naked.
The entire trip was probably negative
with a hard on. You could probably do it.
Viagara and cocaine together.
Smoking weed. He's a fucking maniac.
And how could he not be?
He has got more money than he could
ever spend in a thousand lifetimes.
And he's 19 and by the way,
everywhere it goes,
girls literally lose their shit,
scream and run at him and try to tear
his clothes off and his songs suck.
So it doesn't even make any sense.
It's not like he's just unbelievable
creative force that made these songs that
are just, you've got to recognize
the genius of this man. I mean,
he's the modern Mozart. He's
fucking, he's Michelangelo.
If he was a singer, he said the
art that he produces it at. No,
it's terrible. It's terrible, stupid
shit. And he sounds like a girl.
He sings like a girl.
He's touching their inner soul
with his own music and they run,
they run like fucking World
War z just charging at them.
You know,
even Alexander the great had it would,
he was not in perfect in any way,
but he had fucking Aristotle,
which was one of the greatest minds in
the universe as his mentor. You know,
to kind of keep that guy in check because
he conquered the fucking known world
at 25 you know,
he had that Justin Bieber s kind of power,
even more crazy, more crazy murderer.
Yeah. Cause he could do whatever,
but he's not going down as Ganga
is one of these terrible PBL.
I'm sure he wasn't fucking
perfect, but he had, you know,
he did some sensible acts because maybe
you had like one of the greatest mentors
of all time and sometimes that fails.
Obviously Seneca wasn't
very successful with Nero.
That thing fucking went straight into
the fucking dirt and didn't really work.
But I just feel like if someone was some
real sense and some good psychedelics
could get to him, he could be a fucking
powerful force for good. Listen,
Willie d from the Geto boys said it
best. You got to let a hoby. Oh, okay.
He can't fix everybody, man. Don't
worry about Justin Bieber. Let's watch,
let's watch him ride that fucking chrome
Ferrari right over the cliff of life.
You know the thing about Alexander
the great too, he's gay, you know,
so maybe a different motivation.
It's that gayish allegedly,
probably a bunch of chicks line
about him. Fucking him. I mean,
he had a boyfriend killed his boyfriend,
boyfriends and girlfriends and he just
fuck everybody. Fuck they're fucked.
Everybody didn't matter.
Well maybe he just didn't have
as much common as gang as con.
Maybe getting his car lasts.
I mean obviously didn't because
Gingiss con is responsible.
Like what does it like fucking
1% of all of Asia is more,
it's like five what percentage?
Some ridiculous. Yeah.
Percentage of the humanity.
Yeah. Let's, let's what
percentage? Kingus Khan. Yes. Kay.
I bet it's like 5%. Okay.
Prolific DNA and prize. Okay.
Ready for this? This is,
this is a real, okay.
Wow.
Holy Shit.
It's one half of 1% of the world today.
Roughly 16 million
descendants living today.
Cause that's not as much as I thought
it was. Maybe it'd be more, um,
more people in China. Yeah. Higher
percentage in those regions. For sure.
Thank you.
Think about how much he altered the
course of history with all the people he
killed. Yeah, no shit man. I mean all
the blood lines he ended, oh, Jesus.
8% Oh my God.
No,
it's way more than that.
It's one half of 1% is just the world.
But uh,
it's 8% of people living
in one part of Asia.
Where is it?
What part of his
Inner Mongolia,
hold on. I'm trying to find, really want
to go to Mongolia? Yeah. Well fuck. Yeah,
man. It'd be fascinating. I think
that, uh, just seeing the wall,
the Great Wall would be fucking amazing
seeing this area where they were,
they were so scared of
these fucking terrorists,
these savages that they
built a giant wall,
one of the greatest walls and
game of Thrones. Literally. Yeah.
8% of all the males living in the regions
of the former Mongolian empire carried
a nearly identical y chromosomes,
suggesting that they were all
direct descendants of gangs. Con.
Wow.
8% that's a gangster to
the to the nth degree,
but it doesn't get any more
gangster than him anyway.
He's fucking sets the east sets the bar,
sets the mark right at the end
of gangster. There's gangs cop,
and I've said this before, but if you,
if you haven't ever listened to it,
you've got to listen to Dan
Carlin's hardcore history,
the wrath of the con in five parts
and it's riveting the whole time.
He's a bad mother fucker. Dan Carlin is
such a bad motherfucker. Hardcore history.
If you don't know fucking fantastic,
fantastic podcast and that's the,
that's the ground.
The grand crowning achievement is that
Gaviscon series a five part fuck doors.
Angels too.
It's fantastic.
All about Martin Luther and Constantine
and the Bible and all the craziness that
went on when they were,
when they converted the
Bible to a phonetic language
and the way he sets it up.
It's just fucking brilliant man.
You have a podcast too,
warrior poet, right? Yup. And is
it on iTunes? If people can get,
do you do a video aspect of it? Sometimes.
Sometimes the bents. Yeah, I have.
Some of them, a lot of them are on
video. And what do you put that?
I put that it's usually stays on Ustream.
Just kind of lives up there on the,
what is the,
the Ustream channel.
I think it's all homogenous warrior
poet us for Facebook, Twitter, you know,
everything. That's kind of my handle. So
I tried to keep it consistent. Beautiful.
So if people can't get enough of Aubrey's
delicious tones, go and listen to it.
Go download it, check it out.
I keep them kind of short too.
So I know we got a lot of good
material to listen to. I'm in the 30,
45 minute range for most of them. So we
get right to it. Well, I don't even flirt.
I just pulled the pants down
and we go deep. That's how
to do it, man. I think, um,
I really think that this
model of hyperconscious,
uh, ethical business like that
you're doing with on it and that,
you know, we like to support as much as
possible when we see outside of on it.
I really think it can inspire a lot more
likeminded souls. A lot more people.
And uh, I think it's, it's
really cool that you do this,
that you put all this stuff out there,
that you put out the blog and
then you put out, he marked,
you write some really cool blogs and that
you put out, you really rarely, I mean,
you, you, you, you put not
just put the time in it,
you put the thought into it and it's all
there. It's all real. You know, you're,
you're really tapping into whatever the
fuck is going on inside your mind and
what you're trying to express. And on top
of running an awesome company, you know,
that's,
that's a very admirable thing.
And it's also very inspirational and
that I think that that tone and that
mindset that that spreads, man,
that shit is contagious. Well,
it's coming from a real place. You know,
if I'm, that's what I feel like, I dunno,
that's what I feel like I've been my
best actualization as all the tools and
everything that I've been
given is to follow that path.
And I like figuring stuff out.
I know that I know pretty much nothing.
And when I start to find little bits and
nuggets and morsels of truth along the
way, it's exciting. And then being
able to share those and then, you know,
not being attached to them either if
something else comes up. Cool. You know,
just really trying to put the best
shit out there and improve the mood of
humanity as a whole and
show that you can still do
this and make money.
You can still do this and be successful.
Like capitalism doesn't always have to
be evil, you know, it can be ethical,
it can be conscious, socially
conscious. It can be like,
it's like friendly capitalism.
Yeah. People have a bad
taste in their mouth about,
you say the Word Corporation and it's
just cause the brains of that thing or rot
or rotted out. But if you get, you know,
good brains and a good conscious and
the right kind of motivation behind it,
I think you could change people's minds.
There's a lot of other ethical companies
out there besides on it too. There are,
there are. Um, I just, uh, I
don't get them on the podcast
that month. Yeah, for sure.
All right. Uh, I appreciate all you
guys who listen and stuff. I mean,
some bad motherfuckers really collected,
some of the coolest people
in the universe are coming,
attaching to this momentum and
creating this wave. You know,
you're a part of all these things
that we show on the pockets,
these things about weed law,
laws being legalized. I mean,
your a nugget of consciousness.
So many of you that are pushing this
forward and that's what we need, you know,
will move the needle,
you know,
as long as soon as the people
move the needles themselves.
So telling your friends and spreading
the word and talking openly, being cool.
That's why podcasts like this exist. I
mean, the reason why, I mean there's a,
there's obviously it's, it's
hitting, it's, there's a resonance.
It's resonating with people,
you know,
and that's the only reason why I exist
if I did this podcast and then every week
it was like, it was fucking terrible. Stop
doing it. But I eventually, I'd be like,
man, I'm gonna stop doing that podcast.
But it beats the positive resonance is,
is as much responsible for,
uh,
these thoughts as anything because
it's reinforcing it. I mean, podcast,
much like stand up comedy,
it's an art form that is
meaningless without an audience,
without an audience who
would just be my edification.
It would just be these conversations,
which I really appreciate that I could
sit down with so many cool people like
you or like Cameron Hanes or like, you
know, fill in the blank. You don't do it.
Graham Hancock,
Dr or mid go swami.
All these really cool people that I've
been able to sit down and talk to the,
that would just be for myself,
you know?
I would've never been able to pull it off
though. I wouldn't be able to say, hey,
could you sit down and talk with
me for three hours? They'd be like,
what the fuck am I? I got an earlier dude.
I don't even know you man. But because,
because I'm going to say,
oh blah blah. But everybody
else can listen. They go, oh,
everybody can listen. Yeah.
Yeah. Everybody, the whole world.
Billions of people there.
All right. All right.
Let's talk and then they'll sit down and
we'll talk to you. It's a cool thing.
So for me, uh, you know,
people say thank you for the
podcast has been so beneficial.
It's changed my life.
It's changed my life too.
It's been hugely beneficial for me
because it's given me this vehicle for
exploring these ideas.
It's giving me this ability to tap
into a million different paths,
different information that's
coming at me all the time.
Different points of view from people that
I deeply respect and I don't think the
way they think and I get to see the way
they think and I wrote, I'm a crier.
You know, even people that don't
agree with people I do agree with.
Like a lot of times people go,
oh,
you don't fucking call
people on their bullshit.
Sometimes I don't call people on
their bullshit. Sometimes I do,
but one of the reasons why I don't,
sometimes I want to hear what they're
thinking.
I instead of constantly judging everything
that comes out of people's mouth,
my mouth,
which I do a lot.
What I like to do sometimes
is I like to let it play out.
I like to hear the full version of it
and then consider it or not consider it.
You know,
there's,
there's a million different ways to
view this life and there's millions of
different eyes to see these things
through. And I'm different from you.
You're different from me. And together
we sort of collectively get, uh, the, we,
we get a middle, we get sort of
collectively, we get an id of like,
what, how's that was a lot of fighters.
It might be, Huh, we'll help each other.
The only way we're going to ever really
get a grip on what the fuck reality
itself is,
is if we all share our on edited,
uncensored opinions on
things and let the truth out.
Sunlight and fresh air. That's not
easy to do, man. It's not easy to do.
It's not easy to find. And in this
world is a very few opportunities.
This podcast has become
an opportunity to do that.
By sheer luck or not. I mean, maybe it's
not. Maybe it's the fucking university,
as you said, we're just good. We're just
good conduits for something greater.
And we just happened to be a well shaped
hoes that whatever infor information
inspiration can kind of float through
and, and that's, and that's it.
We'll keep it together. You dirty fucks.
Love you all. We love you all. Um,
next week we got Monday and mortal,
a mortal technique is going to
come on the podcast, uh, with a,
a gang of friends should be
fucking crazy. Molly crab, apple,
very talented artist
will be here on Tuesday.
A Wednesday war machine is going
to be here. That should be fun.
And, uh, he's awesome of than
people give him credit for it.
I think that dude's going to open up a
lot of people's minds is going to freak
people out. And uh, then
Joey Diaz, uh, so, uh,
that's this week much love.
See you soon.
Enjoy your Sunday or whatever.
Because.