You know, we're early. I
got a tweet this Brian,
because we're early.
So while we're on the air,
I'm going to tweet because
at the beginning of this
shit, no one's audit. Anyway.
Who's the first sponsor? Uh, why don't you
talk about, uh, your, your, your website.
Why don't you plug desk
squad. Dot TV, Brian.
Okay, I'm doing this. Hey Desk. Got
that TV. We do a bunch of podcasts.
We did one with Kevin Pereira.
We deal with Dan Tiara, mine.
We do it with a bunch of people and they
have different podcasts. Comic book,
podcast, video game podcast, and
you can find them all@deathsquad.tv.
We're also going to be at the Avn, uh,
next week with Sam Tripoli's Naddie show.
And that's Thursday night.
And you to get it in on that.
You just get one of the AVN passes
at that vinyl. It's a new nightclub.
It's going to be fun.
We're gonna have a lot of people there
and we have live shows all the time.
We have them almost every Friday here
at the ice house. Uh, we have, um,
we have a new one that's coming up at
an Improv later this month on Melrose.
And so good death squad. Dot. T,
lots of fun shows. Really funny
comics always. Um, if you,
if you see him on a desk squad show
for sure they're funny. And uh, the,
the t shirts that you see everybody
wearing those desk squad, cat tee shirts,
those are also available on desk
squad diff. got.tv. I say that,
that goes Christ enough. Um, and uh,
so go there and support and uh,
also were brought to you by [inaudible]
dot com that's o n n I t don't go to oh
and it because it's a totally
different company and a, I dunno,
it's like they like cell banks or some
shit like that. But uh, what we sell,
we sell manly shit son. Okay.
Kettlebells, battle ropes,
extreme kettlebell Carrio DVDs,
hemp protein vitamins and supplements,
all essentially stuff that I use if we
find out there's anything really cool out
there, we tried to sell it.
Um, that's, that's a, I think
a good philosophy to have.
One of the newest additions
is the BLENDTEC blender.
So when you might've seen
online blending I iPhones,
you could literally can blend an iPhone
with this thing. It's, it's amazing. Uh,
but it's fantastic for a,
for shakes,
for protein shakes or Kale
shakes or for bulletproof coffee.
Neil degrasse Tyson does not know
about the bulletproof coffee.
We'll have to educate him. It was
very important stuff. But, uh,
all that stuff is available. Uh, like,
uh, the, uh, the, the upgraded coffee,
Dave Asprey's stuff we found out about it,
so we started carrying it.
It's awesome. Killer bee
honey. Why killer bee honey?
Because it sounds cool to have
is the only reason to have,
I'm sure it's no better
than regular honey. In fact,
it's probably worse than regular honey,
but it sounds gangster as fuck to
have killer bee honey in your house.
So that's why I have it. And
that's why we sell it. And it's a,
a company that is a,
is as ethical as is possible
and still run a business.
There's an all the supplements,
there is a 100% money back guarantee
of the first 30 pills for 90 days.
After you buy it for 90 days,
you can try it,
try whether it's Alpha brain
or whether it's shroom tech.
You can read the science
behind all of this,
all of it and on it and if you have any
questions about it, there's, there's,
there's always someone who can answer
questions about that on, on, on forums,
but the most important thing is
if you don't feel like it works,
you get your back.
You don't even have to return the product.
No one's trying to rip you off.
Use a cone named Brogan and you'll
save 10% off any and all supplements.
All Right, that's o. N N.
I T. Brian. Cue The music
experience.
Without that it would not be official.
Neil Tyson,
thank you very much for coming on here,
man. This is an honor. This is a blast.
I think the universe is going to explode.
You are for sure the most requested
podcast guest ever in the history of this
podcast.
So Brian and I had been doing this for
three years and we have come full cycle
with your appearance here today.
I have,
I felt the magnetic force of your
fan base pulling me in. You share,
that wasn't what the
Mayans were talking about.
Should that wasn't the universe aligning.
I was so happy when I saw you do this.
Uh, I forget what the interview was,
but someone was talking
about the alignment of the
stars and the galaxies the
first time and you're like, no, it happens
all the time. It happens every year.
I told my friend Eddie Bravo,
who's a beautiful human being,
but he loves himself a conspiracy theory.
He loves that. When I told him, I go,
dude, Neil Tyson says it's bullshit. He
goes like this. Oh, okay. Well, yeah,
probably bullshit.
I don't want the authority of my academic
pedigree to be what makes it bullshit,
right? I mean it's, it's, I want
you to, I want to give people,
I want to arm people intellectually so
that they can then deduce that there's
nothing to it. So when someone says
planets are going to align and earth,
there's going to die, I want to encourage
them to ask, how often do planets align?
And then you get the answer every year.
So you don't even have to do the
calculation. It's that shallow.
I'm sort of a interest in a subject where
it only allows you to regurgitate the
really juicy shit you heard
about the planetary alignment is,
which is so dangerous because when people,
when people are bullshitting,
which is most of the
conversations we get into,
we don't get into serious
academic discussions with
people who've actually done
the homework. He just bullshit with
a dude at work and he's like, yeah,
I heard the fucking planets
are gonna Align. And just like,
I don't even know what's going to
happen. And you're like, Whoa, what?
And you go back to your cubicle
shitting your pants, calling his eye.
The planet's gonna fucking
align to something going
to happen. That's gonna. I,
I tweeted recently that if you're
really successful at bullshitting,
it means you don't hang around enough
people who are smarter than you.
That's a very good point. That's
a very good point. Um, you know,
I think one of the cool things about you
and your approach to science is I think
it's very refreshing that if
someone doesn't know something,
you're not condescending about it.
You're,
you're very enthusiastic about
distributing the information,
but you're not casting a
judgment while you do that.
And that is something that I think has
freaked a lot of people out about really
intelligent people or
scientists or someone who talks
about anything where they
have no experiences.
This is a sort of a condescending sort
of a caring of that knowledge that you
don't have. You make a really
important point. And I, you know,
there's the anti intellectual
movement in society and,
and I don't blame them
entirely for feeling that way
because we all know people,
I have many colleagues where you try
to hang out with them and they make you
feel bad for not knowing what they know.
And if that's what, if that's your,
if that's how you interact with people,
why would anyone want to be that?
It's a problem of associating with
shitty characters. Like they're like,
they're not fun to be around and
unfortunately you're associating something
that's incredible. Like the, the,
the actual measurement
of the universe itself.
You're associating that
with annoying people.
You've got to detach the content from
the deliverer of the information.
I dated a girl and she loved,
uh, Duran Duran. Okay. What else?
In high school and uh, you know,
after the breakup, which always has,
and every high school relationship,
that was eight 80, very eighties.
I remember it was like, Fuck Duran
Duran, man taranda rents sucks.
I could not enjoy their music because I
associate it with this young, late, oh,
you know, psychologically
scarred. Fuck myself.
I couldn't enjoy hungry like the
wolf, bad boys, all those classics.
I removed them from the menu because
this one chick, but that, that,
that can happen with music that
you actually would enjoy. Well,
forget about like mathematics, right?
Right. If it, yeah, if it happens with,
with that, it can happen with everything
up the ladder from there. Right, right,
right. You are your very important, I
don't know if you know how important,
like the cool guy scientist is.
I can't tell you how many times.
So I have evidence of
how important that is.
I can't tell you how many emails I've
gotten or like tweets or they say,
people say that there's a guy who's like
seriously geeked and his girlfriend is
not interested in him and he says what
he does and then shows her videos of me
celebrating the universe and she
says, Oh, is that what you do? Oh,
they resurrect the relationship because
she then sees the potential for watch
the guy can do. That's
fascinating. Wow. Yeah.
It's like by any means necessary,
whatever it takes,
whatever it takes every
takes to stimulate.
So I'm happy to glue people back
together if that's, if that's what it,
what matters here.
Well,
you were the very most important person
when it came to the 2012 movement,
because I was talking to Sony
knuckleheads. I had a guy on the,
remember Pinchbeck I was on the show,
it's something's
definitely going to happen.
It's like he's quoting all these reasons
why things are gonna happen. I'm like,
people love them. Some end
of the world. I mean that's,
I was at a party and the person learned
that I was an astrophysicist and walked
up to me and I hear you're
an astro fan. I said, yes is,
and tell me if this is
like a year ago, right? Uh,
here in the rule is going to end in
2012 and then I explained why it's not.
He walked away dejected
and I said to myself, what,
what is like there's some people
are only happy when they're sad.
There's a thing where people are trying
to uncover mysteries and it becomes more
important, the actual mysteries
of the universe itself.
And you can do simple statistics on this.
So for example,
the world has been here for like billions
of years and you think it's going to
end in your lifetime. That's
awfully humoristic of Youtube. Yeah,
that's pretty bold.
And even if it does,
your world's going to end eventually
anyway. I mean, you're really,
it's so silly to delink fixate on.
So what I think the most effective,
uh,
encouragement I gave people during the,
the,
the Mayan non catastrophe was I said,
all right,
between now and December
20th just convinced the,
your Mayan catastrophe people to sign
over all their assets into your name.
That's what's really crazy. Very
simple. If they don't do it,
they don't really believe
what they're saying.
They don't believe you
get fabulously wealthy.
They're not going to give you
that cash. Yeah, no one, well,
I'm sure some people did go nutty and
like set up shelters and the desert and go
underground and all that. There's a lot
of people that went nutty. Well, every, I,
I've, I did a little research
on this about every 10 years.
Somebody comes up with an end of the
world scenario and you keep in mind that
end of the world scenarios, no one says
the world's going to end in 150 years.
Right,
right.
It doesn't work because you can't get
gain adherence to your cult that you're
building.
It's got to be kind of immediate but
far enough in the future so that you can
prepare but near enough so that you're
not going to forget about it at any time.
And it's really good if you can base it
on some old shit and very few people can
read and everybody thinks that the old
folks really understood the universe when
in fact they did not. Well, they
understood the little bit of it.
But to say that they knew more about
the fate of the cosmos than modern day
astrophysics,
you must've flunked your math class,
your physics classes or
something to think that way.
I don't understand what goes,
what's going on in those mines.
It's the same sort of thinking that
the same thinking that wants to uncover
mysteries and conspiracies. There's uh,
there's, it's a weird excitement too,
like hidden things. Now you are a
moon guy for awhile. Listen, my,
my issues with not believing
that people went on the moon.
A lot of it had to do with a friend who
had an uncle who worked at Rocketdyne
and uh, this guy was convinced
that there was no way to do it.
He was an engineer and he said they were
so far away from doing it that the fact
that they did it and
they did it seven times.
But I since looking at it,
that the weight of all the evidence,
I reserve the possibility that some
things were horseshit based on a lot of
photographic evidence that they did fuck
with. Well, here's the Gemini Photo,
but here it is here.
Here it is.
If you look at like the fuel that was
loaded up into the Saturn five rocket,
you can calculate where that
fuel could take that rocket.
It's to the moon and back.
So it's not going to the Piggly
wiggly in the Saturn five. No,
I'm a retard it. Listen, if,
if anybody has any real sense,
they would look at it and say,
there's no way that that was a hoax.
There's no way,
but it would be harder.
You'd see people think it was actually
hard to get to the moon. Yes. It was hard.
It was hard, certainly. But it
would have been harder to hoax it.
Yes, it today. But the thing
about hoaxing things back then,
the thing that was so compelling to me
was that hoaxing things back then was
really sort of way they did it.
I mean that's how they got into the
Gulf of Tonkin. That the horror stories.
Yeah, there was a lot of fakery
going on back and you're faking news.
The height of the Cold War when
there was a lot of reasons why I, I,
I thought some fuckery was afoot
not and especially all these goddamn
documentaries.
Okay,
so you say you felt justified just
because of the landscape in which other
things had been happening,
Dan and visual stuff like that was the
decade where we lost confidence in our
government.
That was well for good reason.
I mean it was proven with Watergate
and it was proven over and over. No,
about the Gulf of Tonkin incident
over and over and over and over.
It was damaged.
And the idea that they were able to do
that in 1969 but haven't been able to
repeat it since,
of course,
makes it even more delicious and it
makes him even more conspiratorial
attractive. Um, and then
the fact that the, uh,
the rock that they had given to Holland
turned out to be a piece of petrified
wood. You know, there's
a lot of weirdness to,
to the moon landing conspiracy.
And there was a lot of,
not just the people that
were alike that admired it,
but it was almost like a religious thing.
My friend called it a technological
Jesus. He said that if you, if you,
if anything is scientific,
you should be able to question it
and someone would give you an answer.
But there's a bit of a motion
and attachment and pride
with certain historical
accomplishments.
Like one of them being the moon landing,
that forbid people from actually
questioned went beyond science. It wasn't,
it was a cultural achievement.
Every Clinton's quote, what was it?
Clinton Clinton wrote a book.
Um, my life went in, man,
not George. Let's build a guy who was
the president, can George Clinton,
that's the other guy. That's his
opinion is equally valid by the two.
Very different Quinton's yeah.
Uh, I'll find it here for you.
Was it in his book? My Life? Yeah. I
was in his book and it was a, it was,
it was all on the, um, uh, the,
the time where when it happened he was
working with a carpenter. So, well,
why you looking at it? I, well,
the way I reflect on people who
say we didn't go to the moon,
I say what a compliment it
is of our emerging culture,
technological culture,
that they're members of our society that
are so impressed with what we achieved
that they can't believe it. Well, yeah,
I take it as a compliment that people
stand dumbstruck Austrac that it be,
it is beyond their cat
capacity to believe it.
I don't think it's beyond
the capacity to believe it.
I think if you had shown
them, you know, uh,
documentaries that didn't have any of the
stuff that was in the shit that I saw,
whether it was we did the moon,
did we go where there's another one,
a funny thing happened
on the way to the moon,
whether his show over and over again,
all this fucked up footage and it's
very confusing to a non scientifically
minded person. You can get on a long
downward spiral. And this Quinten Clo,
that Clinton quote,
this Fox with me,
just a month before Apollo 11 astronauts
buzz Aldrin and Neil Armstrong had left
their colleague Michael Collins,
uh,
aboard spaceship Columbia and walked
on the moon beating by five months.
President Kennedy's goal of putting a
man on the moon before the end of the
decade. The old carpenter asked me if
I believed it happened. I said, sure.
I saw it on television and he disagreed.
He said that he didn't
believe it for a minute.
That those television fellers can make
things look real that weren't back then.
I thought he was a crank during
my eight years in Washington.
I saw some things on TV that
made me wonder if he wasn't
ahead of his time. Yeah.
Look a mess. It's horrible quote to hear
from the president of the United States.
If you're a confused young man and you
think we may be didn't land on the moon,
you read something like that and you go,
what the fuck does that mean?
People in total give the
government way more credit. Well,
for organized behavior then
they actually ever deserve.
So I think they believe the
government killed Kennedy.
And I think a lot of people believe that
if they did that they could kind of do
a lot of things. Yeah. I
mean so, okay. But you know,
science is going to move on while
you're arguing that and so yeah,
that's what we, there's a point where you
just say, all right, I got to move on.
That's the other thing that makes a
conspiracy so juicy is that science didn't
move on when it came to
man's space landings.
That was the end of the engineering of it.
Yeah.
It was the political will if money
at that level. Right. And, and,
and what's,
what all conspiracy theories have in
common is that there's a point where you
have to bridge a gap in the absence of
actual data and assertion gets laced upon
it to satisfy the,
the claim that it's a con.
It's a conspiracy theory.
So you say, well, well, uh,
they say, well, this is true.
And that's true.
And the only way they can both be true
is if this is covered up in between. So,
so somebody always has to say
there's a coverup when it,
but when there's actual
knowledge about the world,
nobody has to talk about
covered up information.
It's just there and writ large and
ready to be absorbed and embraced.
I agree with you.
The,
the reason why the moon theory is so juicy
for people is because there's so much
of this stuff that you could point to.
And so much of it that looks
like evidence of Fuckery,
you know, whether it's the,
we'll take for example, the,
the assertion that the photos
from the moon lunar surface,
since the moon has no atmosphere
than a daytime picture.
If you're there in the
daytime and the moon,
you see a full night night sky of stars,
even with the sun in the sky as well.
You don't see stars in the daytime on
earth and not because they're not there,
but because the atmosphere is a glow
with scattered light from the sun.
If you take away the atmosphere,
the sun will still be there,
but the sky goes dark.
That's what the folks get when they go
to the edge of the atmosphere and the
calling that the edge of space. But when
you get to the edge of the atmosphere,
the atmosphere is no longer
between you and the rest of the,
and the stars revealed themselves
just as they would at night.
So everyone knew this,
so you'd see these photos from the moon
and there's Neil and buzz and the land
air and there are no stars in the sky.
It's just dark and they'll say,
see, it's fake butter and these are
people who never taken photography.
All right?
If you are exposed for the bright
reflective light of the astronauts and the
lunar surface,
that camera exposure even in the hassle
bladder that they carry to the moon and
youth is too short to take in the dim
light from the stars of the night sky.
If you turn the camera to the sky a much
longer exposure with sensitive film,
you'll get the stars. But then you
overexpose the stuff in the foreground.
So photography one o one
answers that question,
but huge websites given unto this.
And so what that told me was that people
simply wanted to believe that it was a
hoax and then made all the information
fit that need without actually caring
about the scientific truths that with
any evidence would disprove all of what
they were thinking. So at that point I
said people just believe what they want.
And so my task was not to debate
wound hoaxers as an educator.
My task is to get people thinking
straight in the first place so you're no
longer susceptible to the the kinds of
thinking where you become selective about
the data that you choose
to believe or you get.
You get duped by someone who's exploiting
the laws of physics for their own
financial gain. Excuse me.
They're exploiting your
ignorance of the financial,
of the laws of physics for
their own financial gain.
So I see science literacy as a kind of
vaccine against all of the world around
you that would just simply
take advantage of your,
your goodwill and good
nature was certainly with,
with things that can be easily explained
like you're talking about the light and
the, the, the setting of the camera, all
that. That's what they lead with that.
Then I explained that, oh well
then, okay, well then how about,
and they start going down a list and you
know, I'm done. Time to go to dinner,
you know, so that that is a
huge problem where, you know,
and certainly when I watched my
first documentary on the Fox Moon,
the Fox one when the moon landing,
it was a big with the moon did we go
and there was all sorts of compelling
evidence that was really weird,
like photographs from
different spots in the moon,
but they had the same backdrop, you know,
and you know, and using the, you know,
this idea that they had done these inside
some gigantic sound studio and when
you see something like that on television,
you saw like Brian O'leary, who was a,
a an astro. And once again
it's on TV. Yeah. Of course.
Authority built into the medium and then
talking to this dude's uncle or a him
telling me is what his uncle
said. Actually it's just,
it was such a, you know, it,
it's one of those things where you go,
okay,
we know they lied about
this and we know we lied.
They lied about that and they lie about
things. I'll get them in line. Yeah.
They'd have to,
the government have to lie as well as
10,000 scientists and engineers. I mean,
think about, think about
this. Just think about this.
We knew more of just if there were
ever a state secret that the government
wanted to keep,
it would be the behavior of
President Clinton's genitals.
Okay.
But that got out,
that got out and only
three people knew this.
Three.
All right.
You're going to hoax a moon landing by
telling 10,000 scientists and engineers
to keep it secret for 40 years. That's
not how humans behave. What was it?
Who's who was, was it
lemony Snicket who said, oh,
I forgot who the author was of
this quote. He said, the only,
the only way you can keep a secret between
two people is if one of them is dead.
But that's not true
militarily. I mean, we've,
we've kept kept big secrets for
long periods. You can keep sure,
but really delectable secrets don't,
don't last you.
I can keep a secret that there's a
bunker that I'm going to run to. Sure.
But to keep a secret that like aliens
landed and there are DNA experimenting on
it that would get out. That's
what people do. Stuff lesser,
less lesser stuff than that gets out.
Well you like when you hear things about
like area 51 and like the Robert Lasar
interviews. Have you ever
had any of that stuff? True.
Requires that you say someone is
keeping something a secret. So you know,
and I've lost buddies capable of keeping
secrets not on that level. Oh No.
Oh my gosh. I completely disagree. I
think that keep secret. Wait, wait.
Yes. I mean the one, the
quote with the one has to be
dead. That's an exaggeration.
But of course,
but beyond a certain number of people,
the conduct of human beings,
if the secret is really juicy and really,
really tantalizing, uh, I'd, I,
I think the 0% chance that that's likely,
I disagree.
There'd be diaries and there'd be like
people telling their families, you know,
like we didn't go to the moon and the no,
look at the secrets that get out. Yeah.
That they'll listen, listen to, I mean,
for sure. Most secrets get out. However,
I absolutely think it's completely
possible for people to keep secrets.
Actually that's a, it's an experiment
that you can't conduct, right.
To say cause make a fake. No, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no. The statement,
most secrets get out for all, you know,
that's 100% of the secrets it could go.
Yeah, you're right. It's just a
simple untestable fact. We'll do it.
Don't you have any secrets in your
past and you got away with, sure.
A lot of people got away
with some secrets. Yeah.
But I didn't tell it to 10,000 people
and say keep it a secret. Well,
the idea is that if
you're talking about NASA,
the ideal about the moon landings where
they said it was compartmentalized and
you know, the, the, the big one is
that Stanley Kubrick was the, um,
there's actually a documentary,
a fascinating documentary. Again,
fucks with my head because
as I've always said,
it's terrifying when you too
stupid to know who's dumb.
And that is often where I find myself
when I'm watching these things.
And there was this documentary that
was a all about the different sort of,
uh,
techniques that Kubrick we used in 2001.
And how he changed pioneering.
Yeah.
He had changed the way you
reshot gigantic scenes by, uh,
some new process called the,
something about front projection.
I think that was basically what, what
the, the, the name of the process.
And then he showed all the evidence of
front projection footage in the moon
landings. And again, you're fucked
because you're sitting here and I don't,
you know, I'm looking at this, I'm like,
okay, well who's right here? Is this,
what is, have you ever seen the video of
the astronauts on trampolines? No. No.
I never thought in my life that I
would be in the position to have a real
astrophysicist watch a ridiculous video.
And so I want you to pull up astronauts
on trampolines. Bring this up. Okay.
He got to see it. It's beautiful.
I don't think I've seen it. Um,
it's astronauts and the,
the conspiracy is that they are either
on trampolines or they're on some sort of
a wire harness because of the way they're
moving and that they're moving behind
the, uh, the Lunar Rover.
And that's to hide either the trampoline
or hide the, the movement of their feet,
like the way the shot is positioned
and it's a motherfucker. I,
this one drives me bananas,
so shit playing.
I'm checking it out and watch this.
Doesn't that look bad guy?
He just got yanked up in the
air. Look, check this out.
380 pound guy.
That's pretty good.
This fell down.
Look at this.
Come on.
I mean obviously if you're a,
a person who's not scientifically
inclined and you're prone to conspiracy
theories, guilty of both, and you
see something like that, you go,
what the fuck is going on there?
Is that really the moon?
Or they're really jumping around
like they're on trampolines.
It looks like it guys getting yanked
up by wires on the moon. Well,
I'm just saying you look at the
trajectory of the Saturn five rocket,
so that's nice. That doesn't mean a
person was in it. When you watch that.
Doesn't that look weird though?
Well,
okay.
You're saying if you don't know what the
laws of physics would be on the surface
of the moon, one, six gravity.
And when you're watching this,
doesn't that look weird to
you? Okay. So I understand. And
the, the house susceptible one can
be when you're confronted with,
uh, what is given as evidence.
Yes. Yes. And, and, and,
and if I don't otherwise come across that
way, I am sensitive to that, right. To,
to, to, uh, I'm, I'm, uh,
if you don't otherwise have the
tools to analyze information,
then then one is susceptible to all
manner of forces of thoughts that go on
around you. And like I say
that, but by then for me, it's,
I don't have the energy to
fight all of that, but I just,
I just teach people to how to think about
information and then I walk away and
then they, they make a life of the
vote for, with it, whoever they want.
But they're there. They've got
intellectual defenses. And so,
uh, so that's how I, the other people
who take them on head to head, you know,
I like Michael Shermer big
skeptics and more power to him.
He's got the patience and the,
he's got good at analogies and goodwill
and he can present to you the evidence
that that psychological evidence
of why we're susceptible to this.
He's got a whole book called why, why we
believe weird things. You know, I mean,
that's uh, it's, it's,
you think it's weird to look at
the video and think it's looks odd.
It'd be weird if you otherwise
knew what it looked at.
A 33 story rocket filled with fuel
launch from Cape Canaveral took several
orbits around Earth,
went to the moon,
took pictures from the front side of
the moon, the backside of the moon,
images from the surface of the moon.
A week later it comes back.
An aircraft carrier goes into
the Pacific to pick up a,
a capsule out of the ocean.
People get out of the capsule,
get on the spacecraft.
The president meets them.
Life magazine writes profiles.
That's all emotional,
but it all built it.
Do you get to a certain plot just saying
it builds and then someone shows you a
video and says, well maybe all of that
didn't, you know, that was all fake. Well,
you know, the idea is not even that at
all. Didn't happen. A lot of the, the,
the idea of proposing the
cubic documentary was that
the footage was fucked up
and then they made a lot of extra
footage and then a lot of what you see is
faked footage where they were worried
that they weren't gonna be able to do it.
So they decided to fake it and
som to see if they could fake it.
That there was two schools of thought.
Okay, that's a whole other thing.
That's all I'm going to go.
But they just, but they,
they needed a movie director to
help out the, the view. Well,
they see, you ever see the,
the Michael Collins photos,
and these are really annoying, but I'll
show them to you where this was a Gemini,
Gemini 10 Joan, I tend spacewalk
but it wasn't really a space walk.
It was a simulation and they just blacked
out the background and used it as a
NASA uses it is like press clippings.
So when conspiracy people get
ahold of that, they go, ah,
it's probably just they needed a photo.
They didn't have one.
The fucking guy really did
a space walk, uh, you know,
and they just decided to just say,
just do a little fuckery. Just say,
say the guy's walking around space when
you closest photo on the shelf and then
pre Photoshop. So that's quite
a free photo. They painted
it. Right. So like you,
you see something like that with your
knowledge of physics and with your
understanding of vacuums in zero gravity,
that doesn't launch completely straight.
It's completely looks totally normal.
Well, yeah, it depends on how, how
quickly they return to the ground. I mean,
these are, you have to sort
of judge that. And, uh, so,
uh, but you know, I'd want
to see more, I mean, it's,
this is a pretty tight shot and other
things wanted to look at how far away the
horizon is. The course earth is smaller,
the moon is smaller than earth. So,
uh,
I want to save dust was kicked up.
And does the dust fall at the slower
rate that the astronaut falls?
I don't see the dust in this.
So I'd say this is not enough information.
If I thought it was cold presented
today, if somebody, because you can't,
you can't put wires on dust.
Right, right. And, and, and,
and suspend the dust and have it descend
as slowly as an astronaut bounce. Right.
So you mean like the Lunar Rover
for dust? Well, yeah. Or what any,
every time they step the dust came up.
So,
so you'd look at all of these cues and
there's so many cues that would happen
naturally if it actually happened that
you'd have to think up and get perfectly
to,
to fool an expert who knows what
they're looking at if they know it.
That's why it had been easier to simply
go to the moon than to fake all of that.
That's my point. This is the one where it
looks like the guy gets yanked up by a,
why are we were seeing this? Check
this out. Oh, that's on the ground.
Yeah. He fell forward. And
just back up what people,
I think especially, uh, people like myself
would have to wrap their heads around,
I guess is that this isn't just a vacuum,
but it's also a vacuum and one six earth
gravity side dealing with a completely
alien environment. How much, so how much
do you weigh right now? One 91 nineties.
You packing it in there.
So how rude Neil Tyson,
just send them fat.
Don't let me show you my six pack on
the Budweiser on the side of
the table. How rude. Again,
this is damaging to my
confidence. Uh, so yeah,
so you have muscles to accommodate
your hundred 90 pound. Fuck yeah, I do.
All right, so it's shit. So now,
so now let's add a 200 pound pack on.
You backpacked,
and now you weigh 400
pounds, right? Right. Well,
he said three 35 but I'll give
you that. Okay? Yeah, just round.
She sits around the set. Let's
get big round numbers. Okay.
So let's say you now weigh 420 pounds.
You're slugging your way. You're
sluggish here on earth, right?
I put you on the moon,
your muscles that normally are accustomed
to 190 pounds now are now are carrying
or maneuvering,
r, r, r, r, r, r,
uh, lighting, manipulating,
one sixth of 420 pounds,
which is 70 pounds,
right?
Imagine how awesome you would be, how
awesome you were. [inaudible] 70 pounds.
If you have this musculature and you
weighed 70 pounds, you'd be superman.
You couldn't crack an egg dough.
You'd hit people,
they'd laugh at you and you know,
you would be super,
may have to have a really good tech. You
have pop up, you would just on your toes,
you'd, you'd jump to the
ceiling. So it's cool.
So what,
what I'm,
what I'm confusing is what would
happen in an earth's environment.
That's your life experience.
So this is the bias you bring to it.
It's an understandable bias and that's
what makes the world that the moon and
other worldly place.
So 70 does down seats that literally you
literally could spring up as if you are
pulled by a court.
Good luck club.
You could swing better because the court
has to make you feel like you're 70
pounds, but now you are 70 pounds
so you just, you just do it.
I really enjoyed mythbusters
version of it. Um, they,
they went into depth about a flag waving
and I thought it was really fascinating
to watch when the,
where they actually created a vacuum
and had the flag wave in a vacuum.
And it's a, it's weird
because it doesn't, you know,
we have an idea in our head of what
it looks like when a flag waves,
well that's obviously the wind moving
that flag, but there's wind here, there,
there's, there's nothing,
there's zero atmosphere.
Now when someone would run
by a flag in zero atmosphere,
does it create any wind? Israel? Nothing.
So if a guy hops by a flag and
the flag blows in the breeze,
what's causing that? Is that a faked
footage? It depends. Video, yeah.
Yes. If you walk by a flag and no, it's
not, has nothing to do with zero g,
it has to do with no atmosphere.
Right. So you walk by a flag,
there is no breeze that, that is left
behind you in the work of your steps.
And uh,
depending on how much air you
displace things next to you might,
might respond to that. If
there's no atmosphere, no,
there's no way to get that information
to the flag. So no that up, pull it up.
Flag blowing in the breeze.
I'll, I'll tell you the video.
It is what you have here is with,
with the American flag that set up there,
there's sort of residual
stiffness to the flag.
There's residual stiffness to the,
to the,
to the beam that has to hold the flag
otherwise. Right. Hang Limp. Yeah.
It was a shaft through the
top of, exactly. There's a
famous quote by Arthur C.
Clarke who,
uh,
and at one point I had
tweeted this where he said,
it's in space where there
is no air flag cannot wave.
So maybe space is not a place
where flags belong. Whoa.
Yeah. Apollo 15 is, this
is the, the one, um,
it's really fascinating because they
stick it into the ground and then the dude
hops by it. And when he hops by
it, it wiggles in the breeze.
Like there you can see clearly that the
shaft is just stuck it in the ground.
Yeah, exactly. No, no. I'm saying
the shaft is in it and it's,
it's in place and it's still sort of
reacting to the environment. Sure.
Now Watch what happens when
the guy gets behind it.
Now he's sort of moving along and he
gets in front of it and when he hops in
front of it, the flag follows him.
Like it, it goes in the breeze.
How long is this video? No, his
nothing touches anything and pull it,
pull it ahead. Well, if it does move,
the evidence would suggest that
something touched it. Right,
right. So something she is, how close his
foot is to the base where the video is.
Keep going. Okay. Keep going. Get it
to the part where the guy goes around.
Yeah,
he's taking some pictures here.
Right. So here's the weird,
it would have been much
better if we queue this up.
Clute queued up to like right there. Okay.
Okay. Okay. But I can go watch. Okay.
Then back it up. You missed it, you
back. It's announced. Where wiggling.
Just get it to right when
the guy hops in front of it.
Yeah.
Dude, you suck at Youtube. You really
sucky. You told him he just, he missed it.
I don't give a fuck. Jesus Christ.
The guy goes hopping in front of it.
Here it goes.
I see a wiggle in the one nine.
Miss [inaudible] can you do that stuff
on the screen there and an ad popped up?
Say that? Yeah. It looks like
a breeze. Blew it. Yeah. So
possible that that's fake.
Yes. So either either, uh,
all of this got faked or something
touched the flag that was not okay.
No, that's not true either.
It's not either. It could
have easily been that the,
some of the footage didn't come out
well or they fake some of the footage or
that was phase two. That might not have
been even real Apollo footage. No, no, no,
no, no. What? I mean,
that might have been something that
someone made and then put it up as a goof
and then everyone like me is saying,
that's exactly. So here's my point.
So here's my point.
So there's a lot of fakery out there,
official and otherwise, right, right. And,
and the most susceptible
field of investigation to
fakery is euphology ology.
Right. Okay, sure. So, so
here's my point or ghosts. Okay.
You're looking at a picture
that's relatively low
quality that doesn't see the
entire zone around the flag that,
that you're,
you don't have full information.
So someone goes by and the flag wiggles.
Either this was faked and there is air
and the flag is responding to air or
there's something, uh, and, and the
whole Apollo 15 mission didn't happen.
If you want to take it to an extreme to
extreme limit or there's something that
didn't make it into this photo.
Yes.
That's all. It's not, it's not going
to have been like as he jumped,
maybe a piece of dust kicked
up and read it. Precisely.
But we don't see it because it's such
low rise or is equipment touches it?
He looks like he's pretty. Exactly. You
don't have far away from it. No. No.
You have no depth, depth cue. But look,
the things in the ground right there.
Let's see the guy go by
[inaudible] you do have have depth.
If you watched the whole good, it's not
good to have then he's got a backpack.
Yeah, it's so, so I can't lose
sleep over that. Yeah. Yeah.
I just, I no I don't, I'm
definitely not losing sleep over it.
I just wanted you to look at a guy
hopping in front of a flag blowing in the
breeze. A atmosphere list. Moon. Yeah.
I mean these videos are
one of the reasons why so.
So I,
I sympathize with some of that.
Uh,
but it doesn't necessarily mean
that it did no one, I mean,
if some piece of footage is fake, it
doesn't mean the whole mission was fake.
I'm not only that,
but I would say that it is so hard to
fake every little thing that would need to
happen. It's just, it's, it's easier
to just go to the moon really.
Would it be,
why would it be so hard to make video
footage and photography photographic
footage and then release it?
I'll give you another reason why you
can't put the sun for all intents and
purposes in a photograph, is
that infinity, which means
all shadows are parallel.
All right?
So if you,
if you photograph them in the
correct way so that you don't have a
foreshortening of an angle, you will see
that that shadows are, are parallel. Okay?
They point to one point,
they referenced one point at Infinity.
You can't fake that. In fact,
that's how I know in Hollywood,
if they've artificially lit a scene and
pretend that it's the sun because they
can't actually put their light
source at infinity. And so I give,
I let it go because it's
Hollywood and they got,
it's the pretend that it's daytime when
they're filming at three o'clock in the
morning when there's no traffic. That's a
hilarious statement though. I let it go.
I pretend, you know, I have to equate in
my head, the sun's that affinity, these,
these dire,
they want to bullshit people trying,
but you had to talk about suspension
of disbelief with me. I'm like, Eh,
maybe she really couldn't kill that
dragon with a sword, but fuck it.
I'm at the movies with you. It's
like, no, I'm, I'm, I look for,
you know,
they can't control the sun.
So one part of the scene in the morning
and another part in the afternoon,
the shadow is pointing in a different
direction and they want you to think of
just happened 10 minutes later.
They can't control the sun.
So they fake the sun in a sound studio
and you, and they have the right color,
color temperature of the sun,
so it feels like sunlight and it has
that sort of brightness. Then you get,
so I let that go. It's, there's so much
you'd have to fake. I'd swear to you.
It's easier to just go to the damn moon.
That's how I understand
exactly what you're saying.
But it sounds crazy if you think that
people actually couldn't get to the moon,
then know that if they actually
physically couldn't survive out in the
atmosphere of deep space and couldn't
survive the, the what? The, the, the,
the talk is that the solar radiation,
any solar flares,
any solar activity would be instant death.
And this has sort of been
kind of acknowledged by NASA
that they rolled the dice
with with solar radiation.
So the people that are believing that
it's impossible to get through the van
Allen radiation belts,
for you to say to them,
what's was that it would be just his
fault. It's just you could, yes. However,
I don't spend much time getting
through them. So radiation doses,
not simply is it there, it's how
much time. It's tiny exposure to it.
The intensity plus time gives
you total dose. Right? But these,
these people that believe that no humans
have ever done it before because the
only people that did it
with the Apollo astronauts,
and there's no one's
been able to do it since.
And every single space station flight,
every space shuttle flight,
all of them are within what, 400
miles? Easily. I mean space station.
It's two something humble's a little
higher, right? But three, six,
eight miles the right.
But these are the only times where
human beings have ever been passed.
That was the Apollo program.
So for the conspiracy minded,
of course that comes up. Well, no,
you can't survive in deep space.
No one's ever done.
It accepts the people in the 60s
and no one believes that today.
And the reason why you can't get out
there is because of solar flares and
radiation, all this jazz. So if they're
right, then it would be easier to fake it.
As you say,
they're not right because van Allen says
it's safe to go through the belts and
then they went through the top, the
doughnut hole. But realistically, when,
when people look at human beings that
have actually been through the last time
someone did,
it was 1972 there was the last time a
human being has been more than 400 miles
from the earth's surface.
That freaks people out.
Every single technological achievement
from 1969 is easier, cheaper,
and faster to reproduce today. Except,
well, no, it had its own trajectory.
I mean in 1969 the computer was
still half the size of the room. So,
and that's one thing, the same computer
that it's like not even an iPhone. Right,
exactly.
Or the computing power that's in
a birthday singing birthday card.
So what Kubrick got wrong in 2001 in
the midst of all the rest that was
visionary was the assumption that
the future would be one big computer
controlling the one big ship.
The notion of distributed computing
where you would have the power of a
mainframe sitting on
your hip was unimagined
at the time. So, so yeah,
things got systematically
more powerful, but that's uh,
I mean, uh, this was,
that's a natural progression of
technology that's been going on since the
industrial revolution, right? That alone
doesn't, shouldn't surprise anybody. No,
that doesn't surprise anyone.
The argument is that the up the man space
flight is the only thing that has an
advanced. If you watch these movies
for the 1970s, they talked about 2010,
my God, who's going to be space stations
on the moon and there was space 1999.
You remember that show? Of course. Yeah.
But the reality is RFC man space ended.
I'll tell you why. Money. Uh,
yes, that's the, that's the clean,
that's the clean, clear answer.
But there's a more subtle answer.
All right. When we went to the moon,
everyone assumed because of the way it
was marketed, there was the, the, the,
the, the profiles and life
magazine of each of the astronauts.
And you saw their families and it was,
the president said, we should do it. And,
and it was this grand mission from NASA,
a civilian space agency and, and, uh,
the world's fair in New York,
1964 was all about inventing a future.
So we were living that romance.
All right.
What we were not reminding ourselves is
that the only reason why we went to the
moon is because we were at war
with Russia, with the Soviet Union.
That is the only reason.
Not at all.
If you don't carry
that motivation with you and you're only
thinking that this is simply the next
technological thing to do,
that when we learned that
Russia's not going to the moon,
therefore we have no reason
to continue and we stop you,
then you cry foul and you say, well,
wait a minute. How about the future?
How about Mars? And how
about the rest of that? Well,
the rest of that was not ever in the
plan unless Mars had planned to, I mean,
unless Russia had planned to do it.
And so it was not a natural flow of what
our technology would have done because
it didn't flow out of
our economic creativity.
It came out of our urge to not die.
And so when you have that scenario,
of course we didn't go
past the moon after 1972,
we were no longer competing
with Russia to do that.
I understand what you're saying.
And uh,
if I was more conspiratorially binded,
I would argue that that's a, a
nice, convenient thing to say.
But the reality is we still kept up
as far as other avenues of military,
whether it's a building better
bombs or faster playing.
And it was all about military superiority.
Of course.
Wouldn't we be the first to
set up a base on the moon?
Wouldn't we'd be the first to, it's not
necessary unless Russia does. Right.
In fact, most of what we did in
space was reactive to Russia.
We were not the first in space.
Russia was,
we weren't the first ascent a
life form into space. Russia was,
Russia spent sent a dog. We weren't the
first humans in space. Russia's Russians,
we're Russians even put the first
black person in space. It was a Cuban,
uh, acumen. Cosmonaut the
achievements in space or what we did,
we got to the moon first
and then we say we win.
And so we have re painted that error
in our memory as we are the pioneers.
And we did it because we explore.
No,
we did it because that's a nice,
after the fact window dressing
you can put on that achievement.
But we did it because we were at war.
There's no,
once you understand that, it allows
you to understand why we stopped.
I completely hear what he Sam,
but you are fueling to conspiracy fires
and the people right now thinking Neil
Tyson is working for the man. This is
what's going on. He's come on this show.
It's tried to explain things and
I'm not authorized sickle way.
Look at him when it's
tricky facts and logic,
the muddying information
about history. Um, the,
I agree with you, but I still see Rome.
It still, it means the room for fucker.
It means Mars is not in our future unless,
unless one of two conditions
are satisfied either.
China says they want to put military
bases on Mars. We're on Mars nine months,
10 months after that, one month to
design, build and, and, and, and,
and launch a Mars worthy craft and
nine months to get there. All right,
that's a,
China says they want to put military
bases on Mars where they are tomorrow.
All right.
That's one way to get there.
Another way we find some economic
justification for doing it.
We're motivated by, I don't want to
die and I don't want to die poor,
but aren't there like massive
resources just on the moon? I mean,
haven't they found a titanium entirely?
So that's a frontier and space. Uh,
what's the name of this new
venture space? Resources, space.
Resources Incorporated there.
I think that's their name.
I think if I've got it wrong,
but they just do a Google on it,
you'll find it immediately.
This is a group of folks,
their astronauts and aerospace engineers
and scientists and entrepreneurs who
say,
you know,
an asteroid the size of size of a
football field has more minor bubble rare
elements than have ever been mined in
the history of the world. And if you,
if you, if you tow that
thing to earth, there you go.
The size of a football field or less,
less size of a barn.
So there are platinum group there.
Ash.
See Nature already did the sorting of
the elements for us. All right there,
there were,
there was something called planetesimals
objects that didn't quite grow big
enough to become planets and then there
was susceptible to being shattered back
into asteroids. Uh, [inaudible].
So when you make a planet
and it's still molten,
the heavy stuff goes to the middle,
right?
Cause it sinks and the light stuff
floats. Well, what's heavy? Iron is heavy.
Platinum is heavy, iridium
is heavy. Uranium is heavy.
All the heavy stuff is heavy.
So nature then sorts it,
the geologist calls it differentiation.
It sorts it.
Now you have this cosmic object
that later on gets shattered.
You now have asteroids made of crust and
asteroids made of core material and the
core material has got all
the elements and all those,
all those rare earth metals that we value.
An industry that we value in,
in jewelry,
it is pre collected for us.
So if you get one of these
platinum group asteroids and,
and bring it back to earth, there
it is. It's a whole new marketplace.
Need like a wonder woman jet with a net,
some rolling.
She was the net shit and I remember that.
Or you corral the asteroid and use
it for other operations in space,
which is a much more financially,
um,
a feasible thing to do would involve
deep space travel, deep space.
Not only that space travel or robotic
way, be able to do it. You can do robots.
Sure. If you, if we can perfect robot,
let the robot look the best way to do
it anyway. You don't have to feed them.
They don't, you know, they don't want
to come home after that. You, yeah.
Unless we flee this planet,
like unless we have to go all Battlestar
Galactica [inaudible] most likely we're
not going to need to send people to
explore things and we have something like
the rover. Well, why take a
chance on human biological life?
I want humans to go to Mars.
I think that's a good thing to do for uh,
because you build heroes that way.
There's no ticker tape parades for robots.
They're going to be heroes.
They go that far without jerking off
because you're on that thing for like nine
months. Yeah, the air and back and they're
all being video camera the whole time.
We're going to find some real heroes,
see some real people that really weep
the first time to get into a tent.
What you might do just in couples and
then you'd get rid of that problem.
Then they fight.
Can't have that.
That's a terrible [inaudible] sex in
space and new couples, what does that,
what's the, that's even worse. You
don't have any history together.
What are the odds that
they're going to work out?
How many new couples stick around
for nine months? That's a hard one.
That's a hard one. They have found
planets and our meat entirely of diamonds.
Diamond
is pure carbon. If, if the,
if anyone didn't remember that a diamond
comes in like carbonated compression,
right? We have five or six varieties and
one of them is what's in your pencils?
That graphite and very soft and, and,
and that's a diamond smooth. No, no, no,
but it's, it's carbon in a, uh,
the lattices is layered in
Vr in the smooth layers.
That's slide off one another.
That's why a pencil,
as you touch the pencil to
the page and drag it you,
what you're doing is you're dragging
layers of carbon lattice off of the
graphite and the thought of it that way.
It's actually pretty cool. That's very
cool. Yeah. It's almost essential, right?
Yeah.
Who layers of graph,
that's like a sculpture almost
laid to the page two d sculpture,
obeying your every command allowing
you to communicate with other humans.
There is a pencil. What's,
what's going on inside.
What we call the lead pencil lead is,
is just the,
the term for what the graphite that's
in a pencil has nothing to do with the
element led. So other forms of carbon,
uh, lately we discovered the Bucky Ball.
It's carbon 60, 60 carbon
atoms that are, that are,
that make a sheet that
has curved into a sphere,
the shell of the sphere.
And it's essentially the
lattice points of a soccer ball.
There's 60 of them if it's,
if you do it right and then you get what
we call a Bucky ball because it, it's,
it's buckyballs named after
Buckminster Fuller and he, you know,
remember the geodesic dome.
You remember those? Okay.
So the lattice of this is,
um,
uh,
is,
is costs to image that
what that what the Bucky,
you say that again? Fall?
Yeah. So the, the, the, the,
uh, the geodesic domes, which,
but Buckminster Fuller made popular,
I guess in the 1960s,
or they predated him by the way. He's
credited with inventing it, but he didn't,
it was invented by Zeiss, the planetary
manufacturers in East Germany.
There were some engineers there. They
invented this. But this is an aside,
but I think it's a pretty cool aside.
They invented a new way to
project stars on the ceiling,
the first optical projector and they put
it on their ceiling and say, you know,
this would be cooler if the
ceiling were round, you know,
do we have any round ceilings? No.
Okay, well here's a couple of dollars.
Go build one or invent one.
And they invented the geodesic dome just
for the purpose of showing a dome where
the stars would be. And this was in
1923 it was pretty cool. That's amazing.
So anyhow, so carbon carbon, so you put
the carbon atoms at the, at the lattice,
at the intersection points of a
geodesic dome and you'd basically get a
something that resembles the Bucky ball.
It's a new form of carbon.
That's one of the forums. And one of them
is diamond and diamond. The lattice is,
is,
is very tightly bound.
So no part of a diamond will
slide off of any other part.
And diamond is the hardest
natural substance known.
And that's why you have diamond drills.
You have diamond anvils and a diamond.
Because it's transparent
and it's also very dense.
Light actually slows
down inside of a diamond.
It is only 40% as fast in a diamond
as it is in the vacuum of space.
And because of that,
it bends so severely in the cuts of
the diamond that you can get double and
triple reflections inside.
So light from one direction comes
out in a different direction.
Making the diamond look like
it's radiant on your finger.
Ah,
pure carbon.
It is the same stuff that's in
coal except treated differently.
W there was a man who,
they,
they wrote an article about him in wired
magazine a few years back where he had
acquired some sort of technology from
the Soviet Union where they had figured
out how to make diamonds. They're making
them now. And I did a, I hosted Nova, uh,
Nova Science. Now I don't anymore,
but in my, in my tenure as host, uh,
we visited,
they blindfolded me because they don't
want to de Beers to know about it and
took me to a secret factory w uh,
uh,
a manufacturing plant where they're
layering carbon onto a lattice.
And just the way a diamond is created
and there just building diamond,
they blindfolded you.
Oh yeah.
In fact they took away my iPhone because
my iPhone has the track that the,
you know,
the inertial memory of where it has been.
So that had to be turned off and I was
blindfold and then we do the interview in
the, uh, in the factory and we
looked inside the, uh, you know,
the special patented
devices where they make it.
Now here's what's the real weird thing
about that. Oh, by the way, go ahead.
I'll wait.
Then I took some of the
samples of diamonds that
they made and went on to 47th
street in New York,
which is the diamond capital of the world.
And I showed it to the guys there and
they were pure than any of the diamond.
They had been hauled from Earth.
This is how ridiculous checks are.
The swelling gets home. My wife says
she wouldn't want one of those diamonds.
Why? Because cause
they're artificial. Well,
so I spoke to the morale crazy that
I spoke to the merchants and I said,
what are you going to do if there's a
flood of these diamonds on the market?
They said,
people are not going to want them the
time that he sounds like your wife.
Exactly.
Because they want to know that it was
forged in the fires of the belly of the
earth. Yeah. And not just
out of somebody's back lab.
And I said, okay, but you know,
these are pure diamonds than
anything earth is creating.
Cause we can do a better job making
diamonds, dinner Cam. And so for me,
I take the artificial diamonds,
some poor African kid doesn't have a chip
it out of a rock with his good points.
Very important. It's just technology
replacing human labor. Once again, please.
Not a winter. Good way.
Does it freak you out when,
I mean obviously you're very
technologically minded, but when you,
you realize that where these
conflict minerals come from and the,
the actual stuff that's in your iPhone,
someone might have dug it out of a
hill in a poor community in Africa.
I mean it's incredibly
ironic. Yeah. But it's the,
it's not uniquely poor as a community
that's exploited for some economic gain.
So, so my issue wouldn't be, oh,
I'm concerned about these minerals are
concerned about all the places where
that's happening. So, so, uh,
you know, how many lights,
it is ironic that the most technologically
advanced shit we have needs to come
that way. You know, that
that's where in 2012, you know,
until they've started reforming these
areas, that's where it was coming from.
Getting to it. I wouldn't call a
diamond technologically advanced.
When I think of technology I
think is my conflict minerals.
I meant conflict and arrested
her and lithium ion. Oh yeah.
She had a cold and your cell
phones. Okay. Right, right,
right, right. Yeah. Yeah. So,
uh, so diamond, uh, so, so yes, getting
back to what started the diamonds,
getting back to what started this,
uh, carbon is a, is is the forthright,
but fourth most co carbon is the fourth
most common ingredient in the cosmos.
And so in the cosmos is full of places
where there's high temperature and high
pressure. And a lot of time and
we are not, we are delighted,
but not entirely surprised that
there are places in the universe,
even entire planets where a large part
of their composition would be pure
diamond. How long does it take to create
a diamond in the earth inside? I, I,
I'm not up on the very, uh, because
the pressure matters here as well.
And that you can change one and that
affects what you'd need for the other.
And I, I don't have that map memorized
in my head, but it takes a long time.
Way longer than your
lifetime. So, uh, you, you,
once you run out of diamonds in the earth,
you're not getting any more diamonds.
You're going to have to make them
yourself or find them elsewhere in the
university. And how long does it
take their machines to make them? Uh,
you can make one in about a week. Whoa. Oh
yeah. You just lay it down. You're done.
How big is it? Like a duck? It's hard to
make a big one. They make one. Um, yeah.
I'm not carrot fluent,
but the size of a BB, uh,
so one that could easily fit in
a, in a, in a, in a post earring.
So that's it.
They can't get a big fat,
crazy charter type Blah and Elizabeth
Taylor. No, no, they're not there yet.
No, no. They're not the
Kardashians. Those are rare. Anyway.
Those are extremely rare anyway. And the
most common diamonds are small. So yeah,
they can certainly compete
in that marketplace.
It doesn't DeBeers have like the rumor
is the conspiracy theory is we should
play that. Here's, here's of the theme
going throughout the podcast. The,
um, uh, the, the theory is that
there's a warehouse that they keep,
there's so many diamonds that they,
they artificially inflate the price by,
you know, slowly releasing them to
the market place. Is that true? Yeah.
I think there's not a pure market
in diamonds when, and I think in,
in the lingo of economics,
if there's a market in something,
it means it is traded often enough so
that the price at any given moment is the
actual price,
the actual valuation of that,
that object in the world at that time.
And it presupposes that there's a full
access to supplies and demand and nothing
is being withheld. So, uh,
yes de Beers is withholding if not to be
or someone else is withholding diamonds
from the marketplace to assure
a circuit certain price.
If they flooded the market, the
price would drop. God dammit,
this is rogue and he listened to this
shit. You don't need a real diamond.
Well here's the scary parts,
but the universe here we are killing
each other over resources buried in the
ground and in the sands when
the including sources of energy,
chemical energy in that case,
whereas in the universe has an
unlimited supply of everything.
So why is it an energy?
Why isn't that reflected in the budget
that we put in this space? Travel?
It seems ridiculous and
short sighted. And, I mean,
it seems like you can take all this
military industrial money and say, listen,
you fuckers want to get really rich. Let's
get crazy. Let's go space cowboy style.
And it's go Lazu some rock. This space
resources company is doing exactly that.
They're marketing face resources. They,
they, they're targeting asteroids for EC,
economic exploitation.
How does that work?
Or does it look like his
space is eventually going
to be like the homesteaders
back in the 18 hundreds where you would
move there and get a plot of land?
Are you gonna be able to claim
plots of spanx currently space law,
which is an interesting
frontier. And, and you know,
and at the UN and in other places, space
law has certain rules and regulations.
One of them I think is unrealistic and
it has to do with the waging of war.
And I'll get to that in a minute, but
the other one is Leeann's space, Huh?
No, it forbids a warfare, uh, uh,
sort of forbid space from
serving as a platform for war.
But I think that's completely
naive and unrealistic.
And I'll tell you why in
a minute. But, uh, and,
and people saying what space should
be peaceful, a peaceful place.
I think that is naive.
That's naive bordering on stupid.
They obviously haven't seen
thoust target cause yeah.
So, so, so, uh, in in
space. So the way the laws,
the books now read that could
change with emerging consensus.
The weight now reads is you
cannot own anything off the earth.
However,
no one can stop you from putting a
flag on it and no one can stop you from
mining resources from it.
You just can't claim to own it and require
that someone else pay you to use it.
Okay.
So in other words,
there's no private property and
there's no private objects in space,
but if you do acquire an
object and you bring it pat,
can you use it for profit that hasn't
been fully explored legally yet? Yeah.
If you invested all the money,
I think the,
the laws are going to go in the
favor of free market capitalism.
And this is why conspiracy
theories will step in and say it's,
that's why Obama's
moving towards socialism,
that trying to control all
the resources in space,
they want to pull it all those
minerals and diamonds, et cetera.
When the Jews and their marketplace
stranglehold on the diamond industry,
except the rate at which
Obama's plan to return to space,
Disney slow is not commensurate
with that as a viable in less see,
take into account the conspiracy theory
to keep the elites alive forever and
start killing off people with eugenics
and wars. There's a lot of people that,
that's another very
fine conspiracy theory,
crop circles and chem trails.
I don't know if you're familiar
with either one of those.
I don't know about chem trails,
but certainly crop circles.
Everybody knows about crop circles. I
mean, come on. I know about chem trail.
I don't need to introduce
you to Eddie Bravo.
What chem trails are is one of the
easily the silliest conspiracy theories.
Um, there's a something, there's
validity to it. Unfortunately in there,
first of all, cloud seeding
has been done in many cultures.
It's done on a regular open basis.
In the United Arab Emirates and Abu Dhabi,
they made it rain 50 times last year.
Like they're doing it every
week. They can. You can do it.
We know that scientifically.
But what they're claiming is that the,
the government is spraying shit out of
planes and these are not regular planes
and those contracts that lasts forever.
Those are actually chem trails.
Those are fake clouds.
And there's all sorts of different
things they're spraying that control the
populace through spraying.
What is it me? What is, how,
in what way is it controlling it? So what
is asked? What is the key? Too many fat.
You've already gone too far with this.
I had to talk to a pilot. I said, okay,
like this is driving me crazy. You know,
cause he was like, when we were kids, man,
those clouds in the sky,
when a pub plane would fly over,
they would dissipate really quickly.
But now they stay forever.
They're fucking spraying us with Shit,
man. This is how crazy people are.
So then I talked to a pilot and I said,
okay, what is, what, why is it, what's,
how come? Sometimes the clouds go away
and sometimes the persistence of contrail,
it says it's amount of how
much atmosphere, how much
water's in the atmosphere,
which varies. Yeah. Yeah. And I go,
thank you. That's all I need to know.
So when the jet engine flies through,
it makes it an artificial cloud.
It really does. It spirals up the
water and the wind and in it's wake,
it leaves this temporary cloud and it
has to cool in order for the to condense.
And if you look immediately
outside of the engine,
there's an interval where it is not
clouded, it's completely transparent.
And then it cools reaching the
temperature of the surrounding air
and then it condenses out. But the,
the levels of moisture at different,
at different altitudes.
So a plane will not leave the same
contrail at all altitudes from near an
airport up to 40
exactly. Just as like some areas it
rains in some areas or desert. There's,
there's areas of, and it
shouldn't be, it should be it,
but people and people get really wacky
with that one. That's a weird one.
When it's another one where there's
very little looking into the possible
answers. It's like they want
it to be, they want, you
want it to be, want it to be.
They want it to be cancer causing things
that the government sprang on us in
order to lower the population numbers
because there's too many of us. Right.
That's why there's lithium and the water
supply and Neil Tyson have you like I
had this conversation with someone,
I said,
did you know there's antidepressants
in the water supply? And I go,
well that's cause people flush their
antidepressants and they might pick they
pee and some of it's, I go, but
the amount is so tiny. I go,
this is nothing that you could ever late.
It's not psychoactive amounts to kind of,
you know that man. How do you know that?
I'm like, I don't know
how to, you know, man,
go get some water and bring it to a
fucking testing facility and you can test
this. Stop freaking me out. There's
enough real shit to freak me out.
What drives me nuts is like end
of the world. People. I would, uh,
I would have conversations with them and
they were convinced this mind thing and
all societies all headed towards a
certain thing. It's really obvious.
And I'm like, do you ever pay
attention to super volcanoes? Yeah.
The real issues to be contended with here.
Some real shit going on in Yellowstone.
Yeah.
Like yellow stone every six to 800,000
years essentially kills half the
continent off.
Do you know that? We were,
when we were growing up,
old faithful was called old faithful
and it was faithful to the clock.
And then there was some geologic stuff
that happened and now it will still blow,
but it's not regular.
I saw this some graph. I don't know if
they'd media. Yeah. Sometimes faithful,
you know. Well, he held it
together for a long time. Yeah.
You got to get some credit.
They had, uh, yeah, the, um,
there was a national geographic piece
on Yellowstone where it was right when
they sort of figured out that
Yellowstone was a called Damn volcano.
They figured out how large it was
and they were talking about the,
the frequency of earthquakes and it
was over like a six month period or
something like that.
There was 2000 earthquakes in Yellowstone.
Trends are what your threshold is for
measuring an earthquake. Yeah. Most,
most earthquakes in the world,
if they happen right under your feet,
you wouldn't notice it.
And so because there's,
their energy level is so low that they
don't even get past the absorbers in your
knee. You got new knees or new hips. What
did you get? Ligaments. Ligaments. Yeah.
Almost no matter the
condition of your knees,
you wouldn't feel an
earthquake up to two or three.
And in New York City with a subway
rumbling under foot with where I live, uh,
that's like 4.5 on the Richter
scale. Yeah. It's something, in fact,
when the World Trade Center
collapsed, uh, that triggered, I made,
I was four blocks away when it
happened. Uh, that triggered,
I paid very close attention to
everything that was happening,
including what kind of vibration
in the ground that caused.
And it was about like the a
train going 30 miles an hour, uh,
just below your feet. So when the
train goes, you feel it. Oh yeah. Yeah.
And you don't, and you ignore it because
it's the normal vibrations of life.
So that's city living. Yeah, it's
the three to three and four. So,
and so you look at the
earthquake accounting,
there are tons of these and so they
don't really matter until it can
structurally hurt something. And then you
talk about it becomes a news item. So,
so the count of earthquakes
is not interesting.
You want the number of
earthquakes above seven,
above six and a half above five.
They start getting interesting.
Uh, but not lethal yet,
you know? So, uh, yeah.
You want it set your threshold
then give me the number.
So are those earthquakes of
small ones like the Elson once,
are they going on everywhere? It's just
they're measuring it and Yellowstone.
Yeah. Well some, there's more. It
goes, some places are more GL active,
geologically active than others.
Places that are geologically active where
you get the occasional seven, eight,
nine or seven and eight on the Richter
scale or whatever the scale is called
today. Uh, those places you getting these
low ones practically all the time. Yeah.
Oh, all the time. Okay.
So freaking out about Yellowstone having
2000 earthquakes like really should
freak out about 2007.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
And this is another one of
these things where, uh, it's,
it's partial information scaled up
into a catastrophe scenario that feeds
people's fears and that the kind
of fear that people delight in, uh,
people say, Oh, you don't,
Manhattan has a fault line
running right down the middle.
Manhattan were 3 million
people live and work and yeah,
it does.
And it's been dead for a million years.
That's a geologically dead fault.
Okay. So it hasn't moved in a million.
I don't know the number,
but it's, it's dead. I mean,
it's nothing happening there.
We've, we've got, you know, the
place swings on it. There's not,
and part of it is what created Harlem
Heights, which overlooks Harlem. In fact,
when Columbia moved in, they renamed
it. It's, it's actually called, um,
they call it, uh, Morningside heights,
but it's actually Harlem heights and uh,
that's a raised part of Manhattan.
It's a well above the lower areas where
the rest of Harlem is. It's, it's,
it's a cool, so at Manhattan's has
some remnant geologic features.
Not all of it has been a bulldoze over
to put skyscrapers. That's fascinating.
I didn't know that it was actually above
it because of, of Oh, because of a fault.
It's a fault line.
Fascinating.
Fault line is some of that
was retained in central park.
They left some geologically
interesting features there. Uh,
but the point is there
earthquakes down to level two.
What were measurable there.
It happens all the time in most places
and they ha they happen often in most
places and and practically continuously
where you are geologically active and
for folks don't know what we were talking
about earlier when we set a called
Darryl volcano. Essentially what it
is is a volcano that when it blows,
it leaves like almost like a crater.
It leaves like a gigantic,
I think it's 300 kilometers
wide in a super volcano.
You basically repave
major land areas of earth.
Do you know Venus has very few craters
on it and given its age and the fact that
there is no rain or weather
systems that could erode them,
you can ask,
well what's going on there?
And further analysis shows that Venus
completely repaved it's surface at regular
intervals that if you
can pull enough lava,
which is just liquid rock
right it liquid rock,
you pull it out of the liquified layers
of the planet and put it on the surface,
it'll spill out,
spread around and cover up all craters
that might've been there before.
Do you know what we see?
You know the sea of tranquility?
What does that tell everybody?
Spot in the moon it's, it's,
it's a place on the moon.
It's called a c because back before
we knew anything about the moon,
it was a large dark area,
flat, dark area of the moon.
And we imagined that maybe there's
water there and if there's water there,
and so we,
there's their regions called cs.
You know what these actually are there.
They're volcanic basins.
When the moon was geologically active,
lava spilled out but spread all over the
surface of the moon as far as it could
reach.
And these became what we,
today we call seeds and you know the
CS happened very late because they have
fewer craters then adjacent areas
where the lava did not spill in.
So you could date the surface of the,
of the moon based on how many craters
there are within a given area.
Do you ever feel like,
you mean since your fascination is
space quite sensitive to finish that?
So on Venus where there are
very few craters, when we
know there should be many,
that tells us that the entire surface
suffers from fresh and volcanic flow.
Unlike the moon with the last
time it laid out, the CS is,
is billions of years ago.
So he's been is just constant
Superbowl constantly essentially. Yeah.
When you see something like the moon,
which is completely covered in uh,
in,
in meteor impacts,
it's one of the things that really sets
into my mind or it gives me a reference
point for time because we've,
we out,
we aren't seeing these big
impacts on a regular basis.
And in fact we've only recorded a few
of them. What the recent one in Jupiter,
this massive one which was by yeah.
Which an amateur astronomer, right? Yeah.
Caught it. And the, uh, the, the blonde,
there's a flash of light on Jupiter
just by accident. Car. Yeah. Yeah.
And then there was the other one, the one
that was observed and it was a 94. Yeah.
The big one. Uh, when was that? Yeah, so
that one was commit shoemaker. Levy nine.
Yeah.
And that one,
it was a comment that the tidal forces
of Jupiter on a previous pass had broken
that solid comment up into two smaller,
but still significant
chunks of content material.
And it had a trajectory that was headed
straight for Jupiter and we were ready
for it. And the Hubble telescope was
in place and everybody was aiming.
And each one of these blobs of
comment that fell into Jupiter,
it plunged into the atmosphere and
exploded with more energy than all the
atomic, all the bombs in the
American arsenal. And so the,
the,
sorry,
a better way to say that is it plunged
with more energy than the impact that
rendered the dinosaurs that rendered
the dinosaurs extinct on earth.
And so to get a sense of the energetics
of the solar system is extraordinary.
And this,
so the solar system to get to your point
is a shooting gallery and moon the moon,
which is sitting right
in front of our nose.
It's our nearest neighbor that writ
large is the evidence of what earth plows
through daily. And we are protected
by our atmosphere from most of it.
And, um, the, my other point was
that when you see that and
you see all the impacts,
that there's so many impacts when you
try to wrap your head around how many
years, a million years is how many
years a billion people have. It's, it's,
it's one of the hardest possible.
Our brains are
wired for understanding whether we'll
be eaten by a tiger or lion or right,
or whether you know,
the space and time our minds interact
with it in very terrestrial ways.
With the advent of the telescope and our
understandings of the laws of physics,
we've had to come to an understanding
of the depth of time and the expanse of
space that completely transcends what
it is natural for us to contemplate.
And so you have to almost grow accustomed
to these facts rather than take them
into your heart because they fall so far
beyond anything we've been trained to
think about.
And that's why it's so hard for anyone
to believe that you can go from micro
organism to a giraffe or a human being
over the billions of years in the cycle
of life. Do you believe in evolution?
I, it's not a matter of belief.
It's what the evidence shows. And,
and when I'm given the choice,
I'm going with the evidence.
And that's silly.
That's a ridiculous way to live.
Um, whatever the depth, the depth of time,
just like a piece of rock, like the
moon, where you see all those impacts,
you think, how long is that? What
am I looking at? I mean, how much,
how much time did it take for all those
rocks to fly at a space and hit that?
And as a temporary organism,
you being a human being who has this
sort of terrestrial fascination,
it's gotta be like almost like a mad
race to collect information and an imp.
Infinitely impossible universe.
We are like mayflies in the
cosmos. Yeah. And not even that.
Think about it. A may fly.
Not even that. That's right.
I think of what doesn't mayfly
know of a change of seasons. Yeah.
For change of years.
These are unfathomably long timescales
to the lifecycle of a mayfly generations.
Yeah.
And so under moms and so here we are.
We're not for the methods
and tools of science,
we would have no clue about the universe
of time and the universe of space that
exists beyond the,
the physical accessibility
of our biological form.
So, uh, when you, so,
so interesting analogy to this I think
is when you look up at a puffy cloud to
you, it's just a cloud sitting
there and it has a shape,
but we've all seen timelapse of clouds.
It's particularly rainclouds
that's a turbulent place. The,
the bubbles of cloud and
particularly the Cumulonimbus,
they're just gurgling up there boiling
up through the center and it keeps
regenerating and rain is
coming out the bottom.
And that doesn't take much of a
time lapsed a video to capture,
uh, 10 minutes, 15 minutes. But that's
not our understanding of clouds.
Our understanding is that there are just
these things peacefully floating there
and that's just human perception
versus a 15 minute time lapse video.
Imagine human perception versus the
billions of years of cosmic evolution than
it really is a shooting gallery. We
don't stand a chance when when you, you,
you see the, you're
right on that fella. Yup.
What happened when you see the potential,
uh,
have hazards and catastrophes a space and
you think about the temporary lifespan
of the human being, does it,
does it frustrate you at all,
miss it as if it does it seem like, God,
I'm going to miss a lot of shit. Well,
there's several consequences.
One of them is we don't know
how to understand those dangers.
If I say a killer asteroid is going
to come every hundred million years,
you'll say, ah, don't worry
about it. But when it comes,
it'll render you extinct and we don't
know when it's going to come between now
and a hundred million years from now,
do you even have the temerity to say,
well,
I'd better build a protection plan and
on the possibility that it comes in my
lifetime or in the lifetime of all my
loved generation generations that follow,
we, we don't know how to react.
We're not wired for some thought.
Let me tell you how badly we're
not wired for that thought.
What happens after a hurricane devastates
a coastline where rebuild, we rebuild,
oh, it's not going to happen to me. Oh,
this is stuff within your lifetime, right?
This is the, the 20 year hurricane,
the 30 year hurricane, not the,
not the 200 year, 500,000
year hurricane. So are,
unfortunately,
our brains aren't wired for this.
So it's a good thing that we have methods
and tools that can compensate for this
shortcoming.
Do we have any sort of scientific plan
to handle asteroid impacts to a paper?
Oh yeah. We've got a total
solution. Worked out in paper.
Completely unfunded at the moment.
And when you say on paper,
is it for like you can do the engineering,
you can do the engineering and,
and it's, it's, it'll work. What do they,
physics and engineering, what do they do?
They knock it out of orbit or something.
You know, if you're macho, if you're,
if you're below the sucker out, that's
just the loan approach, I guess.
I forgot it been hawking and we
came to an MMA guy here, right?
Or would it Jujitsu? So
though the different solutions
that the problem is, yeah,
we could conceivably blow the thing up.
But as Americans,
we're really good at blowing stuff up
and we're less good at knowing where the
pieces land afterwards.
So I don't want to blow this thing into
six pieces and still have all those six
pieces headed towards earth.
Right. All right, so the kinder,
gentler solution is to deflect it from
harm's way and there's something called a
gravitational tractor beam essentially.
I mean,
that's the poetic way to say the
Saifai way to say it, but really you,
you put up a space pod out there that
has a gravitational field that attracts
slowly, attracts the asteroid
into a slightly different orbit.
And if you get there early enough,
you don't have to deflect
it by much because that
deflection accumulates and all
you needed to do is Miss Earth. Now it's
still out there to harm you another day.
But if you get good at this, you just
have, you know, just like you have the,
the block protection nighttime protection
force, you know, in the neighborhood.
Well,
you'd have the asteroid protection for
us and that would be protecting earth
from asteroids. And Jupiter protects
us from most asteroids. Right?
Well for most of the things that haul
their way in from outside the solar system
comets, most asteroids are
within the orbit of Jupiter.
So Jupiter doesn't need to protect us
from them. Well, we, we would want it to.
It just doesn't because they know their
orbits don't reach Jupiter for enough to
Jupiter to bat it into a new place.
But comments that come from far,
far beyond the orbit of
Jupiter, Jupiter's, they,
when they come near Jupiter,
they feel Jupiter's titanic gravitational
field and Jupiter basically bends them
into a new orbit.
And so many of them don't even make it
past Earth's orbit on its way towards the
Sun. I mean, they,
so these new orbits clears the space
for our survival here on earth.
And so Jupiter is our
friend. It's, it's our,
it's our friend that takes care
of the bullies in the school yard.
Do we know enough about,
uh,
other solar systems to know whether
or not this is a typical setup?
It was our urge,
given what's called the Copernican
principle to say that we're not special,
where average and if we're average than
other solar systems should look like us
because the sun is kind
of average and you know,
we're not on the little list planet or
the biggest planet you just so you make
some some assumptions.
As the star systems
came into the catalogs,
as our techniques and methods to observe
other planets in the solar system arose,
we started to learn that our
solar system is not typical,
that most solar systems,
most star systems have a Jupiter size
object much closer to their host star.
Then our Jupiter is. So
then we say, well way,
well then why is our star system different
from theirs? And so it's a frontier.
It's an active frontier and no one is
putting their bets on any one kind of
solar system as being the most
representative. And, and we're,
we're building the catalog now.
So,
so the catalog that has
700 or so exoplanets in it,
that's only 500 star systems met,
we're,
we're now building the catalogs of the
secondary tertiary planets in the star
systems that we've already discovered.
So that's quite a lot of binary
star systems as well, right?
Where there's more than one son. Oh, well
first, if you look up at the night sky,
almost half of all the
dots of light you see,
if you pull out a telescope will reveal
themselves to be binary or triple star
systems.
It is a,
it is as common as the breeze in the
universe with the challenge here is what
happens to a planet in orbit around
a binary or multiple star system.
That's the challenge. And is the
atmosphere stable enough to support that?
That would be a concern no
matter where the planet is.
But here's the challenge with a multi
star star system as the planet orbits,
maybe it'll get really close to one
star and really far from another,
and maybe the orbit is entangled between
the two of them trying to do figure
eights,
that if you have an unstable orbit,
you're likely to eject the planet
forever into interstellar space.
And in fact,
data are now showing that interstellar
space may have more rogue planets that
had been ejected at for having misbehaved
orbits from their star system than
there are stars within planetary systems
themselves. Blew my fucking mind.
They're called rogue planets. No, no.
Let me, no, I didn't even know. No, I,
I'm just beginning here.
So Watch.
So we also know that many planets have
still retained their heat of formation
long after they, they've,
they've come into existence.
Earth still has heat churning a source
of energy that is not traceable to the
sun. This is what creates the magma
that's sitting below Earth's crust.
The son didn't eat that.
That's heat generated within the earth.
Some is leftover from formation.
Others is created from
radioactive decay of elements.
But we've got an energy source and our
biology books from decades ago said,
life needs sunlight. No, no,
no, no. Life needs energy.
It doesn't care if it comes from the sun
and all Kanick vents at the bottom of
the sea with no sunlight.
For example,
the the Juan de Fuca
Ridge off of the coast of,
of Washington is a vent in the bottom
of the ocean that is releasing the heat
from below and it's an energy source.
It's at the bottom of the ocean where the,
where the sun don't shine,
where the sun don't reach,
and yet there's life form thriving.
Their existing on a form
of Geo chemical energy.
It's got nothing to do with the son.
The fact that we've discovered exotic
life on earth has broadened the net that
we have cast into space in our
search for life in the universe.
No longer do we need to look for the
72 degree pond in an oxygen atmosphere
planet in our search for life.
It so this goldilocks zone where
everything had to be perfect.
We've got life thriving in
places that would kill us.
And we are not the measure,
the ultimate measure of what the
conditions that life requires to survive.
So now that we're looking
with this very broad net,
we can say to ourselves
for these vagabond planets,
if they still have their source
of energy churning within,
maybe there's life there.
And if that's the case,
the galaxy could be teeming with life.
And the fact that we're focusing our
search on planets around stars may simply
be limiting all that we
can discover in the cosmos.
So these planets could essentially be
spaceships filled with life forms headed
our way and they might even slam into
us. Well, metaphorical space ships. Yeah.
And the problem is since they're,
they're homeless,
there's nothing to eliminate them.
So their pitch black fly into the galaxy.
And now if some of the
heat reaches the surface,
you can use infrared telescopes
that might pick them up.
But we don't, we wouldn't
even know where to look. Well,
isn't that the thought about the,
uh,
the object that they believe is
somewhere outside of the Kuyper belt?
Is that what I say it
wiper Kuyper. Yeah. Yeah,
so this is an astronomer and mid 20th
century who hypothesized that beyond the
outermost planet,
they would be sort of the leftovers of
the solar system that didn't collect into
a bonafide red blooded planet,
but it should still,
the residue should still be out there
because if you're a residue in an orbit
where red blooded planet exists,
you're going to collide with that planet.
Eventually you're going to merge with
the planet and make that planet even
bigger.
This is one of the failed criteria
for Pluto being classified as a planet
because it is in a zone in the solar
system that has not cleared its orbit.
It is in the Kuyper belt in
the inner edge of it. Yes,
but it is.
It is.
It is joined by countless
thousands of other icy bodies.
Earth. Yes, we plow through crap in
the, in our, in our orbit, but it's,
it is the ratio of the mass of the
stuff we plow into to mass is like gnats
flying into an elephant. All right?
It doesn't knock over the elephant.
It is of no concern to the elephant.
Anything that could still possibly
collide with us earth won't even care,
will care because it'll affect
the echo system. But Earth,
the planet is so much more massive than
anything we would ever collide with.
From now to the end of the solar system,
we have basically cleared our orbit
of anything dangerous Pluto has not.
So that was a damning fact in the ruling
that got demoted from planet to planet,
that it doesn't have enough mass to
attract all the other objects that are
nearby and neither does anything else.
And so it's just a swarm of comments.
The Kuyper belt of comments.
So now if you go beyond the Kuiper belt,
you're so far from the sun.
If you're going to talk to us,
it would be through reflected
sunlight. But he's so far away. Yeah,
it's the [inaudible]. These things
are really dark objects to begin with.
So how do they find
them? Well, it'd be hard.
So it's possible you can have a big
object. Well beyond the Kuyper belt.
It would just be really hard to
find. Um, and I can say without,
without hesitation that if
there's a huge objects out there,
it's gravity is of no
consequence to anything that's
going on between us and the
Kuyper belt.
I just thought it was fascinating because
the idea was that there was a Jupiter
sized planets so far outside of our solar
system or what we consider our solar
system,
that it was causing some sort of a
gravitational effect on the Kuyper belt.
Knows what you might be remembering is,
uh,
the nemesis object. What does that, okay.
You didn't anybody remember him? Okay,
now,
now I'm feeding your my doom and gloom.
You're doing let the record show the
man's eyebrows moved up into his forehead.
So,
um,
there was an analysis of the extinction
episodes in the history of the earth
that suggested that perhaps
they were episodic or periodic,
every sort of 20 million years or so.
There was a little dip in the
fossil record and we said,
well, all right, you know,
by the way,
geologists look for indicators in the
fossil record and in the rock record to
demark where one error, one period,
one epoch begins. And another one ends.
So for example, the dinosaurs
croaked at the beginning, Eh,
65 million years ago at the KT boundary,
it's got some other name lately.
I haven't kept up with that, but that
boundary, they knew it was a boundary.
So they dated, they called
that a different geologic, um,
zone that which followed 65 million years
ago compared to that which came before
it and did they did that long before
they knew what the hell happened there.
We would later learn that an asteroid
struck and there might've been there,
surely worse, some super
volcano activity, uh,
and it would've called the Deccan traps.
And so there's a lot of bad stuff
going on in the earth at that time.
So it was a hostile to life.
We lost 70% of the world's life
species in that period of time,
right? 65 million years ago
was devastating. So, uh, the,
the awesome for us because that's
how we hear, right? Yeah. In fact,
flowering plants, so asteroids are
a friend. They reset the world.
They had a fucked up environment.
It was a bad neighborhood.
Dinosaurs were everywhere. We
bad for us. We were just wrapped.
We were scurrying underfoot
as early rodents. Yes.
And we were just hors d'oeuvres
for t racks basically.
And you take them out
of the ecological niche,
we can then aspire to, to evolve to
something more interesting than a treat,
something that can consider the
Kuyper belt test. And so, so,
so it was imagine that maybe there's
an object out there that's so far away,
you can't see it,
but it's on this huge looping orbit that
comes by the Sun every 20 million years
because that's the cycle of
these extinction episodes.
And if that's the case, no,
it doesn't hit us.
It has to stay around for the next cycle.
So what does it do?
It has a gravitational field that perturbs
these outer comets and sends a reign
of comments down into
the inner solar system,
creating impact extinctions on a
cycle of every 20 million years.
This was proposed back in the 1980s but
it's not an object that anyone has ever
seen.
It's an object whose existence
was in inferred for or,
or asserted based on the record of
extinction in the fossil record of further
analysis of the fossil record doesn't
actually hold up this cyclical extinction
pattern. It's more, it's more erratic than
that. And so you can't really, so it's,
it's evaporated as a, as an
idea, but it was clever and,
and intriguing and got a lot
of headlines at the time.
I think it's the same thing that I'm,
what I read, what I read was from 2010,
it was something about the Oort cloud
who o r t cloud. Yeah. That's a,
that's a swarm swarm of comets and
not quite halfway to the nearest star,
but very far out there.
That is the sort of the outer reaches
of the gravitational grasp of the sun.
This is the case.
If you go much beyond that,
you're gravitational allegiances uncertain
and you could fall into the next star,
uh, rather than fall towards
the sun. The guys were,
I don't know if you've
heard of these guys.
Astrophysicist John mattise and Daniel
Whitmore from the University of Louisiana
came up with a theory that said that
something smaller than a Jovian mass would
not be strong enough to perform this task.
They believe that there's
something up to 25% of them.
Okay?
It's four times as big as Jupiter could
be responsible for sending these objects
in our direction. This is just a random
theory that these guys put together.
It wasn't completely accepted what they're
doing. What? No, no, no, no. There's no,
there's no known such object what you,
what people are doing,
and I don't fault them for it.
It's creative.
It would make awesome science fiction.
Storytelling is,
there's something you need to explain
here on earth. Somebody went extinct.
There were some wave of comments.
There's some observation
that never repeated.
There's some thing you got to
come up with and so you say, well,
we know the Oort cloud exists.
We know you can perturb those orbits and,
and send them careening down towards
the inner solar system and those,
that Jupiter doesn't bat
away like batting practice,
those that get through Jupiter's
gravitational shield could wreak havoc on
earth. Yeah. Yeah. But
that's, it's, it's, it's,
it's inventing a lot to explain
something you don't know. Right.
So it's inventing more
of what you don't know.
That could be true to explain what you
don't write that which you don't have any
other evidence to support. So it's fun
speculation, fund speculation. Exactly.
Beyond that to saying, oh, it's
real, it must be happening. No, no.
It's just let someone write
a good Scifi story on it.
Here's what's fun about it and
this is why I bring it up. Um,
most people I've talked to this
about this subject to many,
many people and, uh, I, myself
personally, I'm not immune to this.
I find it very fascinating.
However,
how much have I looked into the actual
planets that we absolutely know are real?
Not that much,
but I'm worried about this fucking
fake planet that may or may not exist,
do they might've found another planet.
It's this idea of something
hidden and mysterious,
which is so compelling and attractive.
Nothing fascinating.
Psychological observation.
It's a weird thing.
We want to believe there's something
mysterious that we don't understand and
could be there,
but we don't know anything about yet
where there's plenty of things we do know
something about, but we want to know
more. Why don't you help? Yes. All right.
And by the way,
the universe is far more wondrous
than anything we can imagine.
And so,
so to say,
I need your creativity
and you know, uh, to,
to keep your life interesting.
No,
we got black holes that are
flaying stars layer by layer.
We've got, do you realize that
if you fall into a black hole,
you will see the entire future of the
universe unfold in front of you in a
matter of moments.
And you will emerge into another space
time created by the singularity of the
black hole you just fell into.
He just broke the,
broke the Hogan and that right there.
So, so let's talk about that. All right.
Yeah.
You know,
why are we wasting time talking about
whether the Saturn five rocket, I mean,
cause we're fascinated by shit that's
unproven, mysterious shit. Look,
I got a broken brain. Okay?
There's a reason for me. You
want some more cool stuff?
All right.
Mars once had liquid running water
coursing on its surface unquestionably has
geologic Marzel logic.
Features that are, are, are,
are, are, are Vic,
the correspond in every way
to the geologic features.
You see when you fly over the
Mississippi River, you see,
you see tributaries leading to larger
rivers. You see me hindering pathways.
You See River deltas at the,
at the end of the river basin,
you see lake beds, you see all
of this. But Mars is bone dry.
Today something happened to the water.
We don't know what we're pretty sure
it's sunk down beneath the surface and a
kind of permafrost.
My point is if anytime in the past
Mars had liquid running water,
every place on earth, there's
liquid running water, there's life.
There is evidence to think that Mara's
was habitable with liquid running water
before earth was. We'll see. Then you
just started up another conspiracy theory.
That's the Richard Hoagland
Group of people that believe
that there was pyramids
and a face on Mars and there
was civilization. I have
something better than that.
All right? That if Mars was
fertile for life before earth,
something we learned recently
in the last 10 years,
that asteroid impacts Panspermia.
There you go. I can be strong.
It can be violent enough that they can
fling surrounding rocks with escape
philocity into interplanetary space
where they will drift until they are
attracted by the gravity of some other
planet and they will then fall and land
on its surface.
If Mars was fertile and
formed life microbial,
though it may only have been
it's microbial life that
can survive dehydration,
high radiation,
absence of con,
we have found what we call
extreme of files on earth. Like I,
like I said a moment ago, that that thrive
under conditions that would kill us.
High pressure, low pressure,
high temperature, low
temperature, high radiation, uh,
all of these conditions the microbes
would have encountered on Mars bidding,
thrust into space and
making that journey well,
if that's possible.
And if that's the case,
then life on earth could have been seeded
by life on Mars making every life form
on earth,
a descendant of Martians.
More importantly,
why do we have bacteria that could
survive high radiation in the first place?
What business does that have here
beneath Earth's protective atmosphere?
Thriving in places where
there isn't high radiation,
we have life forms that can survive.
What that trip through
space would have subject,
what a trip through space would would've,
what it would have been subjected
to by a trip through space.
So you have it on now,
by the way,
life does not evolve the way
anyone typically thinks it does.
You're not some organism that then adapts
to a new environment. No, you just die.
The variation in organisms allows some
to thrive in conditions that would
otherwise kill you. And it's my
genetic offspring that continue.
Nobody adapted to anything.
Nature is selecting that subset of
the variation in a generation that has
survival properties for that
next assault in the environment.
So if Mars is teeming with life and
microbes are flying into the atmosphere,
flying into space as stowaways and
the nooks and crannies of rocks,
then that population will be selected
for those microbes that can survive that
journey through space.
Does a planet need any sort
of an atmosphere in order
to support life or they
just need water?
Uh,
all we know is what can support life
as we know it, right? All right.
I don't know if we're inventive enough
to invent other kinds of life form,
but life as we know,
it requires liquid water because that,
that is allows nutrients to move
through our vessel that we call our,
our bodies.
And right on down to microorganisms.
We all thrive and use liquid water
and we need a, a heat source.
And more specifically a heat gradient.
There has to be a place where there's
more energy in one place than somewhere
else.
When you have a gradient,
then you can create and sustain
life as we know it. Without that,
there's no known way to do it.
So the entropy laws work
against you to make life so.
So your point is that these,
it's possible that organisms could
be growing even on asteroids then.
Oh, sorry. So your point was do
we need an atmosphere? Yeah. Well,
Le recent evidence suggests that possibly
more than half of the mass of biology,
the biomass of earth lives and
thrives beneath earth's surface,
not on its surface.
If that's the case,
what's going on in the atmosphere
is relatively irrelevant.
If you're thriving deep within a nook
and cranny of a rock my mile down, uh,
you know, don't they have
some air down? Yeah, yeah,
there's some air. But you know,
it's not cycling with what's
going on in our air, you know,
so the rules become broader or,
or,
or altered from what you would
presume the life requires.
So to talk about a planet being habitable,
we should no longer think only of what
the surface of that planet supplies.
We need to think more broadly about what
could go on deep within its surface as
well.
We're pretty sure there
are no large macroscopic
organisms lumbering around like
an journey to the center of the Earth,
uh,
of Jules Verne where they're
creatures down there, you
know, no hollow earth. Yeah.
Hollow Earth. Now there's no
evidence that we have huge creatures.
The pressures and the behavior of
material doesn't allow there to be huge
cavities that haven't over the billions
of years completely been filled in.
When I say huge, I mean, you know,
uh, you know, hundreds of miles large,
no,
the,
the system would collapse
into that rapidly and you
can get smaller cabinet like
Carlsbad caverns, that sort of
thing. But, but nothing, you know,
a staggeringly large now when you consider
all the possibilities for life in the
universe, which are, you know,
almost infinite, right? Yeah.
They're probably more ways to make life
than we haven't thought of then the way
to make life that is,
that we know of, you know,
here on earth w it would just not
imaginative. We just don't, uh,
you know, I'm reminded of if
I get a little literate on
you for the moment, uh, in,
uh,
the late 18th century,
there's a book published
called Cosmo Pharaohs by um,
a Christian Huggins.
And he was a,
he was a polymath that he was a great
in math and physics and biology.
He wrote a book exploring what life might
be like on all the planets and listen
to this reasoning. This is, this is
hilarious. He said Jupiter, well,
it's clear it's got an atmosphere because
through a telescope you see bands of
gas moving across its surface.
Well, if it has an atmosphere,
then life forms,
they're a,
would probably exploit that atmosphere
the way we do because it has an
atmosphere. It means it probably has
rain because we get rain out of habit.
Our atmosphere, if it has rain, it
must have oceans. If it has oceans,
they must need a means for gathering,
for traveling.
So they would build ships with sales,
and if those ships have sales, they would
need rope. So they probably have him.
Wow. So this was obviously
extrapolation to an extreme. Right.
But just it analyze that
for one split second,
every supposition was founded rooted
in what we do as humans and there's no
greater hubris than to presume that what
we find somewhere else would be just
like us or act just like us
or have the same needs as us.
I always felt that way about,
or even have the same
number of senses as us.
They could have fewer,
they could have more. Hmm.
Think about how much of
our lives are influenced,
how much of our society is
built on services that bring
pleasure to our senses,
our sense of touch. We can go,
you go get a massage. Damn right.
You can know the right place.
Our, our sense of taste.
There is food brought to x high
cuisine, right? Our sense of hearing.
Sure. We make beautiful music, our
sense of sight. We make great art.
So much of what we do is to satisfy
our five traditional senses.
Imagine if we had 10 senses
or 20 I have a theory on that.
It's called the fart principle.
I have no understanding of how that
principal could relate to this, but
I'm all yours. So this is why, um,
if you did not have a nose and you could
live your whole life without a sense of
smell in the year 2012,
it's very possible if you,
if someone farted in front of you, you'd
have no idea that this terrible gas is,
you're inhaling, it's in your, no, you
wouldn't have that sense of smell. Okay.
So you could exist and not have any
idea because gas is invisible. Okay.
That's a bad example. And I'll tell you
why. It's okay. No, no. I'll tell you why.
Could be alien life form all around us
all the time that we don't have the sense
to like,
it's like worms can't see.
So two things. So first, uh, it's a,
it's a good example in the sense that
no pun intended in the sense of that
without,
if who knows what senses were missing
and therefore who knows what there is to
measure in our world around us that we
are completely missing. Right. All right.
I'll get back to that in a minute.
Regarding your FARC theory. Yes.
Here's the problem. All right. The my
theories of for peer review, right?
That it is totally getting
peer reviewed. The good. Nice.
It's the right thing to call it too.
It's a legitimate hypothesis. Thank you.
It's out on the table now. Here you
go. You Ready? It's my last, uh,
one of the active ingredients in the
smell of a fart is hydrogen sulfide.
It turns out hydrogen
sulfide is extremely lethal,
is one of the most lethal
gasses that exists.
Well, why do we have such a
good sense of smell for that?
Why don't we smell other get, why don't
we smell nitrogen? [inaudible] well,
we don't need to smell nitrogen because
it's not going to kill us because it's
78% of what you breathe.
Anyway.
[inaudible] we have
evolved a hypersensitive
sense for the smell of hydrogen sulfide.
If,
if, if there was a gender, if you
gave birth to someone who said,
hydrogen sulfide smells beautiful
and let's smell more of it,
let's get canisters of it.
If you're dead 10 minutes later,
no longer able to propagate the gene
that liked the smell of hydrogen sulfide.
We had to not like that smell.
Otherwise we would not have
survived the, uh, by the way,
hydrogen sulfide is a byproduct of the,
the digestive activity
of anaerobic microbes.
That's why it comes out of your lower
intestine with not only where the sun
don't shine, where oxygen doesn't exist,
the microbes to thrive down there,
they are an aerobic and hydrogen
sulfide is one of their byproducts.
It has been theorized that there have
been places and times on earth where the
ocean currents stopped.
And when ocean current stop oxygen at the
surface of the ocean never makes it to
the bottom.
So you can't sustain oxygen
lifeforms at the bottom of the ocean.
There are no fish.
There wouldn't be any fishes down there
if the ocean currents stopped because
the ocean currents not only go from
one place to another in the world they
circle, they circulate
top to bottom. All right?
So it's a two dimensional thing going
on at three dimensions actually. So,
so if something happens on earth
where you stopped the oceanic cycles,
you can create a condition
in the lower ocean.
We're anaerobic lifeforms thrive.
If they thrive,
they out gas and one of the
out gases is hydrogen sulfide.
It will gurgle up from the bottom of
the ocean, rise up near the shores,
turning shorelines into
the smell of cesspools.
If you were alive at the time
and didn't run away from that,
you would have simply died from it.
That is all well and
good. Therefore, the nose,
the nose theory that if
we didn't have a nose,
we could all just fart
and we didn't have a nose.
We wouldn't have noticed hydrogen sulfide
and humans would not have survived it
and some other creature would be
having this interview right now.
I agree with you and disagree with
you. At the same time, it's a,
here's why what you're saying involves
real people and real life adaptation to
our environment.
What I'm talking about is
aliens that are just like farts.
That's why so you gave
me a crazy long winded,
really an in depth explanation,
but you still don't discredit
the possibility that just
like the sense of smell.
It exists,
but it is invisible.
There could be many things around
us that are also invisible,
but we have not developed any
means to detect that. Okay.
You were being metaphor. She works
right? Wifi. Yeah. Wait, wait, wait.
So you're being metaphorical
with your father sang live.
No one would have had to
have a known artist says,
I overanalyze you are a theory.
That was cool. It was cool. By the way,
one global warming scenario
is the currents. Yes.
Did you see the day after tomorrow? Did
you see that? Unbelievably horrible. Yeah.
That one was, was that went
to no clothes. So good.
It was bad when there was the cancer
baby and everybody else is dead outside,
but there she's surviving with the cancer
baby and she's going to stay there for
the kid. We, while 100 billion people
are dead. It's an awesome, awesome.
Let me get back to your nose. Your
partner is crazy. Okay, so now here's why.
You're probably not right.
Well, I'm definitely not right.
Look, it's a ridiculous idea.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no.
But there's a reason
why you're probably not. Right. Okay.
Because beginning in the 16 hundreds,
we learned that our senses are not only,
they not fool us,
they and occasionally don't work.
They're not all that the
universe tells us they are not.
They don't have the capacity to recognize
all that's going on in the universe
will certainly on a microscopic level.
Well, that's my point. That's my point.
So in the early 16 hundreds
to the important advances, uh,
actually late 1500,
you had the invention of the microscope
and you had the invention of the
telescope.
This is really the first steps to
enhance our senses beyond what our human
biology in doubt us with.
And upon doing so,
we discovered things about the world
that were previously oblivious to us.
We discovered knows farts.
When Lou, you wouldn't leave.
Windhoek brought his telescope of his
microscope to UB drop of pond water and
saw what we were called Anna macules.
What else were you going
to call the little things?
Paramecium had protozoa
thriving in a drop of water.
That was a nose fart.
Good con keeping with your vocabulary.
That was something that previously
no one had any idea was there.
And my point is beginning in 1600 and
with an ever improving march forward,
the methods and tools of science
have served to enhance our senses,
increase our senses,
increased the range of our senses,
but more importantly,
give us whole kinds of senses that
your five senses could have never even
imagined that our human biology
couldn't even approximate.
So as so, so what's an example? Um,
yeah.
Uh,
we don't have senses to
detect magnetic field at all.
That's why you can sit in a Mri
Chamber and sit there and you know,
whistle Dixie and you'll have no idea
the strength of the magnetic field that's
being cast across your body.
We don't have sensors for it.
You don't have sensors for radio?
Uh, we're radio waves. What the,
the difference there is we do have sensors
for one aspect of the electromagnetic
spectrum.
We have sensors for infrared visible
and a delayed sense for ultraviolet.
Does that mean, oh wow. Sorry. That's
pretty loud. And creative ringtone.
Just like mine aren't
dangerous. He goes, oh yeah.
Uh, so, uh,
so the point is the radio waves are part
of the entire electromagnetic spectrum.
We, we have access to some of that
and we call that for obvious reasons,
visible light.
But outside of the range of visible light,
you have ultraviolet x rays, gamma
rays, radio waves, microwaves. So yes,
we see radio waves,
but that would just be an extension of
our senses in the way Jordy and star
Trek,
the next generation had his visor
though that visor allowed him to see the
entire go star track. I got it. I had
to go there just because I had, uh,
and my sideburns or star Trek sideburns.
I don't know if he, uh, so he puts the,
well, he, that visor enabled him to see
the entire electromagnetic spectrum.
If we were thusly equipped,
you'd walk down the street and the
microwave towers would be a blaze with
microwaves and you tune into
sort of ultraviolet. And if you,
you think twice about going to the beach
because that's the stuff that gives you
skin cancer, especially people
with lighter skin. If you, if, um,
if you want to see, uh, what would it be?
A good example if you want to see if
there's a burglar entering your house,
just shift over to infrared.
If the burglar is warm blooded,
they will show up even if all the lights
are out, like the Predator. Uh, exactly,
exactly. It's another way to
detect the light. So, so we have,
so science has broadened our senses and
given us senses that are human biology
could not have even
thought of or invented.
So the notion at this day and age that
something is happening on this tabletop
that is eluding us,
I think is just simply unlikely because
we're so good now at finding things that
previously,
uh,
escaped our notice right
in front of us right now.
That frontier is that the energy
extremes of the cern accelerator in
Switzerland.
That frontier is at the James Webb space
telescope where we're going to look at
the earliest formation of matter
in the history of the universe.
These are the extremes of our
measurements of nature today.
The biological limitations
of human beings, uh,
the birth and the death. You know, the
fact that we are all born and we all die.
Do we apply those to the universe for
a reason or do we know that there was a
birth?
Is that,
is that 100% sure that had
before the big bang there was no,
but there was something.
So do we know that? Yeah.
So we don't know. We don't know
what happened before the Big Bang.
So that's my first and
highest level answer to you.
That doesn't mean some people
don't have some creative ideas,
but the only real answer is we don't know.
And we have top people working on it.
All right,
so now some of the creative
ideas are quantum physics,
which is the most successful
theory of physics there ever was.
Quantum theory tells us that the early
universe may have been a fluctuation in
the laws of physics,
allowing other fluctuations at
the same time so that we are,
but one bubble of many comprising an
infinite set of bubbles deserving the
retrospectively obvious name multiverse.
The multiverse theories
a scare the multiverse.
And so if there's a multiverse then,
then we're just one bubble and this
multiverse is just churning them out.
Some of them by the way, who were on a one
way expansion trip. Other universities,
the laws of physics might be
slightly different with a condition.
The initial conditions might be slightly
altered from ours and it would expand
it and we collapse.
They'd have a big squeeze at the end.
Some universities might might be
created without any matter at all.
So you have a universe with
no one to contemplate it.
We happen to have a universe with a
matter and energy within it assembled and
achieved consciousness.
So a universe where
there's no matter at all,
but it's infinite and self
comprised like it is the universe.
You can't get here from there.
And not that we know of,
but that could be a way we might be able
to invent the multiverse transport kit
where you leave your universe
and enter another other.
But I don't recommend
that because if the laws,
if the laws of physics are even slightly
different, the charge on the electron,
the,
the mass of the neutron,
if any of these are slightly different
than everything that holds you together,
all the physical laws that
come together to make you,
including all the forces of nature,
they would just completely collapse in
the existence if you stepped into the
zone of this other universe where they
take on some other form or shape that we
can't even imagine. So yeah, I
don't want to, I, I, you know,
that's when he flipped.
You send in a probe or something,
but you don't send yourself. So that's
why I joke about this half seriously,
that if an alien comes to visit,
I want to make sure in advance that
they're not made of anti-matter.
So I flipped a coin and that catch it.
If they don't explode together in
isolation, then I'll shake their hands.
So let him mad. I say welcome
to Earth. When they explode,
just touching the ground then. Ah,
yeah. Well they might have hover, hover,
glide or something, you
know, I don't lie. Well,
plus they're touching the
atmosphere, which is matter. So,
so if I meet him in space,
let's say [inaudible] and you shake hands,
everybody dies. You completely
an island. That's correct. Yeah.
So that's what happens in
our own universe. Imagine,
uh, some other universe.
There's no telling. How are laws of
physics would interact with each other.
So you ask what's before the universe?
It may be the multiverse, but now,
now, now when you played
that thing, I get nervous.
So there's,
there's good,
there's cogent physics reasons to think
that there's a multiverse and quantum
physics.
It takes us there.
There's also good philosophical reason
to think that there's a multiverse
because in our experience,
discovering the cosmos,
the universe never makes anything
in ones when we thought earth is it.
No earth is just one of many
other planet. Well, the sun is,
but no sun is one of 100 billion
stars in the galaxy. Well,
the Milky Way,
and I know there's 100 billion
other galaxies in the universe.
Well, the universe, well, we'd
been there before, right? Right.
Am I going to say there's
one universe? I'm a little,
I'm all Stanley. Isn't there?
Just one university?
We'll get verse consisting of billions
and billions of infant. I'm getting there.
So what's, so watch the vocabulary,
right? So we have this one universe,
but I don't want to think there's one
universe because of the trend line says
differently. All right, so
maybe there's this multiverse.
Well that just continues to push
the question a little deeply.
If the universe never
makes, if the, if the,
this entity never makes anything in ones,
then why would it only make one
multiverse takes us. So then,
so,
so maybe there are multiple multiverses.
Okay, so that would, so,
and then it's turtles all
the way down as they say. So,
so we, like I said, we don't
have a handle on it yet,
but we have,
we've solved other origin problems because
what started this was your question
about birth and death. There's a time
and we didn't know how the earth began.
We have a good idea of that now and
how are the, how the moon foreign,
we've got that, how the sun
formed. We got that. No,
we weren't around 5 billion years ago
to watch it. But you don't need to be,
they're very clever ways to
know what happened in the past.
Geologist had been doing it, but you know,
ever since the field was born, you have,
there's a,
there's a record writ for geologists
in the rocks telling you where they've
been,
what temperature they were exposed to
and how long they've been sitting there.
We look at the sun. No, we
can't go back in time with it,
but we can look at other stars.
We, we look out in the galaxy.
There's so many stars,
but catching some being born
but catching others dying.
We're catching some in orbit around each
other and we're seeing some that don't
exist anymore because by the
time they're light reaches us,
they've already faded out. There'll be
some of them that in fact at this instant,
no longer exist and that information
has yet to reach us. That's insane.
And by the way,
that happens several hundred times a year.
We observe what are called supernovae
stars that ask you about stars that
explode. We watched them explode and we
date them from when we see them explode.
But hell, they'd exploded long
ago, depending on their distance,
if there are thousand light years away,
they exploded a thousand years ago.
It was,
you had no knowledge of it until today.
There was a fantastic documentary on
hyper novas and it was so mind boggling
because they went back to the birth
of the discovery of hyper Novas.
And when they initially were theorizing
that it was warfare in space,
I'll tell you what that story was.
So in the 1970s after the
United States and Russia,
the Soviet Union signed a test ban
treaty where you couldn't test nuclear
weapons on her surface. Uh, we, you know,
there's the old military, uh, Credo
Trust, but verify. We said, all right,
we'll sign this treaty,
but we're gonna keep on eye on you.
So we got together the engineers
and the physicist and we may, my,
my brethren of the day,
uh, invented a telescope,
a kind of detector that was
sensitive to gamma rays.
That's one of these bands in
the electromagnetic spectrum,
the highest energy band for which we
have a word to describe it. Gamma rays,
by the way, that's what Dr Banner
was exposed to that made a, Oh,
don't you think I'm not
aware. Big, green and ugly.
So actually that's not actually what
would happen to you if you're exposed to
Mac, but we'll give the comics of
the, the, the scientific latitude. So,
so you have this, um,
so, so, so what happens?
So they launched this detector
and you know, seven, eight, nine,
10 times a week,
this satellite with this detector on
board detects burst of gamma rays and the
Pentagon scrambled and they said,
you know, what's, what's going on?
Are they actually detonating these
weapons? And they looked at satellite,
other satellite, secondary,
tertiary information.
So he union was silent. There was no
evidence of any nuclear testing at all.
And that was the birth that day to the
day of the publication of that paper that
reported on these daily bursts.
That was the birth of the field of
astrophysics called gamma ray astronomy.
And we now have other gamma ray
telescopes out there studying these.
They are explosions and they're
happening at the edge of the universe.
And these are the sorts, the, their
sources are of what you're hyper Novae.
We needed a word bigger
than supernovae and we,
these are the biggest explosions
known in the universe.
And so we call them hyper Novi and the
amount of power produced by a hyper Nova.
Oh yeah. It's extraordinary. What,
uh, what matters more than that,
it's a lot of power is that it's very
focused. It comes out in two beams,
one in one direction and one in the other.
And if we happen to be in the beam,
that's, that's all she wrote. Yeah.
If there were a hyper Novi
anywhere in our galaxy,
everybody's done in the entire galaxy
and it was being towards earth.
We're toast, literal and figurative.
Literally around that kids,
there's $100 billion stars at least.
Right. And this galaxy. But most,
I mean a hyper, no, it was a very
special and rare kind of star.
And we times a day, we now well know
in the universe. Yeah. No, eight times.
Eight times a week. Eight times a week.
Yeah. Yeah. Between 75 times a week.
Once a day in the entire universe.
Wow. So, so, so that, that's,
but that tells you how rare it is.
It takes 150 to 100 billion galaxies,
each with 100 billion
stars to give you hate.
Are these a week? Yeah. So by the way,
there's an interesting way
that this will render us toast.
So the first rave of gamma rays,
we'll take out our ozone layer.
The ozone absorbs high, high
energy radiation. That's
what PR protects us from.
Uh, it's what absorbed most of the
ultraviolet from the sun. Otherwise,
ultra is hostile to life,
to life on the surface.
And we wouldn't be life as we know it
if without this ozone layer on earth.
All right? So, so if, but you
can overrun the ozone layer.
The ozone is oxygen. It's o three, right?
The air you breathe has o two in it.
The molecule [inaudible] ozone is both
three and ultra violet photon comes in,
slams into o three breaks
it apart into o plus o two.
There you go. It ups, it took the,
the ultraviolet light out of the,
out of the picture, it's gone.
That's why protects us. Okay,
so if there's a gamma ray burst,
more high energy,
photons will hit us.
Then there are oh three
molecules in our ozone layer.
So they all hit and they break apart the
o threes and it's like the first wave
of, of, of a cat. What are the cavalry
who the first ones on the, in the battle?
Um, the first they get all shot up, right?
I mean in the old fashioned they run in,
they get shot up. Okay.
The first way it comes in,
we'd protects us from some of it,
but in overruns, the ozone layer,
the rest come in and basically
starts breaking apart the molecular,
the complex molecules that
exist on earth surface.
That's how high energy the light is.
And generally we think of life as complex
chemistry and the most complex form of
chemistry we know,
and so we would not survive that.
That would be an extinction episode
for all life on Earth and now what?
Now if you, you could burrow
underground, that'd be cool. Go there.
I wouldn't want to,
I'd rather just stop.
It's just too much to ask to
survive something like grab a beer,
get out your lawn chair and watch it
come like anything you want to survive.
It seems like you have to sort of give
in to the reality that the greater good
of the universe will be fine.
It's time for the rats and roaches
to rise up in ourF or whatever.
Then it's like our own consciousness is
so strung up on the idea of staying in
this form, you know, physically
alive and keep this thing, whatever.
This is going right.
Because of our survival instincts,
it really sort of confuses and it dilutes
the whole idea of perception that the
universe itself is not just infinite,
but infinitely fractal. Yeah.
Well No.
The average life expectancy of a mammal
species is about 3 million years,
and I'm sure there's some of us out there
who are thinking that we'll live for
billions of years and and
planet hop and star hop,
and then there are people are saying,
well,
we better learn how to terraform Mars
because earth is about to be completely
messed up. And those folks I
think are misguided in their, in
their thinking. Can I tell
you why? Sure. Please.
It's not who doesn't want to
terraform Mars. Okay, that's
they did. They did it on.
I got kids, another planet to visit.
That'd be fun. Vacation, vacation spot.
I have no issues, but don't do that. Be
Close. You want another place to live,
to escape the fact that we're
destroying our own earth. All right?
Did the environment and the
oceans and the atmosphere.
Here's why is every very simple argument.
If we have the power to convert Mars
into something that looks like earth,
then we have the power to fix our oceans,
our oceans, and our own atmosphere,
right? If you see if you have
the power of geoengineering,
you don't have to leave the planet,
your arm turn another one into earth
and move there. The fixer earth. Yes,
thank you. It seems like just a
step in the stage of innovation.
As long as human beings
have access to energy,
we're going to figure out how to get
energy from pollution and get energy from
this going to be with the massive amounts
of progress that have been made just
in the last 200 years.
I always like to describe to people if
they really have a hard time wrapping
their head around it that 200 years ago
if you wanted a picture of something you
had to draw it. I'll just stop and
look at that. Great, great observation.
It's such a small amount of time that a
massive amount of stuff has happened and
if you stop and think about what
we're capable of like [inaudible] man,
who knows? I mean, I don't know
the answer to overpopulation.
I don't know the answer,
but I do know that I would've never
figured out why Phi on my own.
I would've never figured out
how to send a satellite signal.
Who the fuck even understands what's
going on. When you get online,
it's just think about what's
going on in your car's gps. Right?
So it's talking to a satellite and mixing
your location on earth surface with
information that's in the later
versions of it on your car,
updated from the Internet
about what direction the
traffic flows on a street you
happened to be driving on and whether
the Dunkin donuts is open late. Yeah.
As long as there's money
in fixing the environment,
we're going to fix the environment.
Well that's the challenge.
The trick is to make it so that people
can actually find some benefit in a
capitalist economy. That's,
that's the driver of it all. Yeah.
It pushes things and it also,
you know,
it leaves a lot of bullshit in its wake
and a lot of pollution and problems that,
I mean, I hope we figure it out before
we eat up the rain forest. I really do.
But if we don't, we could probably
make a new rain forest one day.
We could probably figure
it out. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
it's a fucked up way to look at things
like, well figure it out, don't worry.
But I think the doom and gloom
analysis of we're doomed.
There's no way we're going to,
uh, we're gonna run out of food.
I think that's kind of a
silly way to look at it too.
I think it seems to me that if you
fly over just the United States alone,
God is a lot of space to do
shit. Yeah, that's correct.
And if you wanted to do some
shit on the moon or on Mars,
he could kind of do it in Nevada as well.
You know, you could find some spots,
Utah and nobody's
there and you could put up a
dome and grow some vegetables.
What happened is earth keeps warming.
So the news that last year was by far
the longest that the warmest year ever by
far a 2012 the warmest year on earth.
So if that want warm as here for,
since when, uh, I, well,
I didn't read the full depth
of the article, but certainly
the warmest on record,
right? Is that we've been keeping records
now warm. The earth has been, but, uh,
not since like Jurassic, right, right. No,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
In any time that, that it would
have been concerned about this.
And so if that's unstoppable
for whatever reasons,
political, cultural, economic, whatever,
what that will do is simply redraw the
map of what does Arabelle and what is not
in the world. So we'll live in
Antarctica, it'll read, distribute,
uh, where, where we think of as
the heartland and the, the wheat,
you know, well, we know about the,
we know now about Greenland and underneath
all that ice there. Yeah. Stuff that,
the climate that once was, I
mean, there's a day when, uh,
earth had no ice poles and no, no ice
caps at all. Well, there was a day,
just 15, 16,000 years ago that half
of North America was covered in ice.
I liked the way he said,
just 15,000.
I'm Craig Lawson in the version of the
universe that was silly lives. And,
uh, there's good evidence to say
that Earth had the early earth had,
was complete snowball where the ice caps
were so large that the north ice cap
met this south ice camp at the equator
and it's called snowball earth.
When was this? Very cool. I forgot the
exact time that they've been. It's,
it's geologist plus, you know, some, uh,
w if you look at the history of the
sun or the sun wasn't always the same
temperature.
So you have to fold that into what's
going on on earth at the time and what the
Greek, the state of the
greenhouse effect is on earth.
Because that also influences the,
the, the tracking, the, the, uh, how,
how high the temperature is versus
what earth is doing with the energy it
received. When you're a
snowball, most of earth,
the Sun's light is reflected
rather than absorbed. See that.
And so that's how you can get
a runaway snowball, right?
So the ice caps grow a little
bit and they said, we are,
this is like global climate change. And
the other direction, the way worse, right?
It grows a little bit and
then less sunlight gets
absorbed by the earth because
ice is white. And so it
freezes up a little more. Oh.
And then even less sunlight gets kept
and then it freezes up a little more.
So you can have a runaway ice ball just
as you can have a runaway greenhouse.
That's incredible. That's,
that's interesting that,
that these two possibilities exist.
And the glacier is when they melt and
they create water and the water acts as a
reflector and the light goes to the
water and melting glaciers quicker.
And so for example,
if their,
if their greenhouse gas is dissolved in
the rocks are in the oceans and they're
happy and nobody's disturbing them,
then you maintain your atmospheric
temperature and the energy balance of
sunlight hitting the earth. Some
getting absorbed, others getting other,
other parts getting reflected.
But if you tip that balance,
by the way, that can shift, that's not
a like a razor edge balance. I mean,
there's no slop in there.
Uh, restorative forces exist.
But if you go outside of what a
restorative force can give you,
then you overrun the capacity to bring
you back to any place where you once were
and then you get a runaway phenomenon.
And so you heat and when you heat
something, it out gases, right?
If you heat your soda, the Co two
comes out of it. It doesn't stay in.
That's why we'd like drinking
cold carbonated beverages.
So if you heat earth then
and greenhouse gases are,
are dissolved within it,
then you start releasing those greenhouse
gases that makes earth retain even
more.
Heat makes it hotter and it makes it
hotter even more greenhouse gas has come
out. And so you can imagine a situation
where you have a runaway greenhouse where
everything goes really hot. Is that
where we're at? No, it's everybody do.
We're not.
Runaway Earth has been this hot before
and has recovered from it over time as
much longer than anybody's life lifetime.
That's another problem here. Right?
Earth has been much harder than this.
It just was much hotter before
humans are much more stream. Yeah.
Before human history. Yeah. And so,
and we have great evidence for this.
So the issue is not will earth survive.
It is whether we as we have set up culture
and civilization and economies and,
and it's all been set up assuming a
certain constancy of the conduct of nature
and if we now become a force
in that in nature's equation,
creating a cycling of phenomenon that
would normally have taken 10,000 or
100,000 years and we're doing
it on a scale of centuries,
then we better be prepared
to face those consequences.
Much like your analogy of the
clouds in a timelapse fashion,
the idea of living by the beach
would be so fucking ridiculous.
If you ever saw the, the actual
like Pangea change into continental.
Send me the last bit. Yeah. Cause that's
like why would you live near the water?
What are you crazy? But that's 80% of our
population. Right? Exactly. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. On because cities are
based typically near water,
soft water sources on river mouths or,
or were transportation was useful in the
days before we live in New York City,
in Manhattan,
lower Manhattan.
Are you concerned about like sandy and
the impact that it had that this might
flood zone a and zone Aa was four
blocks from me, from my zone,
which was zoned. See, I walked four
blocks, five blocks away and oh,
should tire underground
parking garages were flooded.
Cars were bobbing out, up, out of the
exit doors of these parking garages.
Have you thought about Utah or maybe
perhaps not Colorado mountains to stay
because if you plan for the end of the
world, I'm going where you're going.
I'm going to call you up.
Dude.
You better be straight with
me telling me where to. Hi,
tell you a cute story. A friend
of mine, Rick Binsel, who's, uh,
who's at a planetary astronomer,
uh,
he also created the risk scale for judging
the likelihood of an asteroid that's
recently,
recently been discovered.
He created the risk scale that will
tell you the likelihood of that hitting
earth. Okay. Now he and I like to
drink wine when we're together.
So he has, so if, if he's thinking
that an asteroid is gonna come one day,
what's the first thing you ask
him about his wine collection?
What's the first thing you ask him?
Uh, what are you going to drink?
Exactly what bottle of wine and you have
that you're going to pull out the day,
you know,
the asteroid's coming.
So he was thinking maybe
he could attach a little,
a little a sensor behind that bottle.
Okay.
And it goes into my place
and other friends of his, so
pose that bottle out, I'm red
light starts flashing and you know,
cause he would be the first to know this.
It's his calculation if it gets sent to
the media that gets sent to the press.
Oh, okay. Um, speaking of calculations,
I have to talk to you
about the conversation that
you had was his, the men,
the man's named Claude Shannon
was that the guy knows talky,
but what is the name Claude? Well,
I'm trying to remember what the, uh,
the scientist's name that
was discovering or that, uh,
was talking to you about
the discovery of computers.
A computer. Oh, Jim Gates. Gym. Yup.
Professor, uh, Jim, uh, Jim Gates. Oh,
there's a professor of physics
at the University of Maryland
in College Park Correcting Computer Code
found in the computations of quantum
physics,
physics.
What the fuck does that
mean? Yeah. So he found an,
I don't claim expertise in everything
he said. I had him on a panel. Uh,
we have an annual, uh, an annual, uh, uh,
event at the American
Museum of natural history.
That's my day job there as director
of the Hayden Planetarium. Uh, and,
uh,
once a year we have this panel and I
bring on my colleagues who are active on
the bleeding frontier of some topic
and I put them on stage and we all just
fight about who's right or is there
enough data where and where is,
should I believe you should I not?
And so it's the annual Isaac Asimov
panel debate and it's designed to, uh,
to expose an aspect of science
that the public hardly ever sees.
They usually see that the
perfectly written paper and
the news report on it and
everything is tidally discovered.
They don't see the bloody bleeding edge
where the fisticuffs. Um, come out.
And so on this particular
case, he, uh, Jim Gates,
uh,
discovered that there's a certain in
our representation of the universe.
Quantum theory, yes, yes. Uh, in, in, in,
in the way we have come to understand
the universe and our methods and tools
deep down within that is necessary a
code rit in Zeros and ones that is a s a
particular kind of error checking,
uh,
algorithm that we invoke daily and the
movement of data from one system to
another and it's called a checksum. Or
you might've seen that in an error code.
If anytime an error dump happens
on your screen, go look in there,
you'll see the word checks
on him in multiple places.
It's one word checksum and it's a way to,
it's like the idiot check on did this
bulk of data get through this portal.
All right,
so you know,
you're looking at that sort of the
gross thing you can check for, you know,
how many total bits were there?
I don't know if they're the right bits,
but I know how many total bitch
should've come. So let me check for that.
So that's the kind of thing
you do in a check sum.
So he asserts that this exists deep
within what we need to represent the
operations of nature at its deepest,
most fundamental levels.
It is the matrix re deep and so,
so all right.
So that's so I,
so I was astonished by this and I paused
and actually there's a youtube video of
me in gas.
I'm interrogating him and,
and now I don't know that it's seen
peer review yet. I've got a [inaudible],
he's a friend of mine so I
can just call him up. But uh,
for before you start getting excited
about it or bent out of shape about it or
disturbed about it,
you wanted to see peer review and that
the level of expertise in that analysis
is above my pay scale.
So it's got to go to peers who do exactly
that kind of mathematical physics.
And if they come out with
a consensus and they agree,
then I'm good to go and I'll,
and I'll invest more energy
and coming to understand it.
But for every correct idea
of how the universe works,
there's hundreds and in some cases,
thousands of ideas that end up in
the trash bin of creative thinking.
And so, so I, I have to
allocate my energies and my, my,
my budget of time.
And so it's intriguing and um,
and I'm happy to know that it exists,
but to take it beyond that and wax
philosophically poetic about it.
Maybe over a beer at a bar, but no, not,
not in an actual setting where I'm
talking about science. So it's,
or maybe when you're hot,
you know, it's great.
It's great fodder for conversation when
you think you're being deep, right?
When you get done with your
chem trails talk, that's,
I'm talking about computer simulation.
The universe is on a hard drive.
The multiverse is on a backup drive,
like a raid drives. Oh, the, all
the backup drives of the multiverse.
That's why it doesn't have
all the information as the
same universe because it
only takes the base so it can like back.
He's going to make you dumb.
If you keep going to him, he will propose
some things that will ruin your brain.
The computer simulation has been
bandied about in a bunch
of different forms.
And the idea being that one day we'll
have infinite amounts of processing power
and we will be able to create a reality
that is indiscernible from this reality.
And once that is done,
how will we know when we're in it?
And could we be in it right now?
And this is sounds like more
high horse shit nonsense,
but this is being bandied about by some
of the smartest people on the planet.
Yeah, I remain unconvinced.
I mean of what I've read.
And you're talking about basically
Kurt's while in the singularity, no,
not necessarily, but it's, it folds in,
so sort of requires the acceptance that
the day will come where our computing
power in our storage power because it's
growing exponentially with Moore's law.
It doubles every 18 months or
so in capacity and speed and,
and all the metrics that
matter when you're doing. Uh,
and when you're an information technology,
the hypothesis that one day we can
just upload our entire brain into her
computer or a computer can simulate
your brain in some fundamental way.
Then what do we need you for
if we can now just simulate it.
I mean the here in La,
the actor's version of that is they've
just digitize your body in every angle,
doing everything.
What do we need you for
exactly what they don't and we
need to get rid of most actors.
They need to be outsourced. I don't
think the actor's union is happy about,
they can suck it. They're
unnecessary humans for the most part.
Some of them are beautiful and
they're the, for every Samuel Jackson,
you got a million Douche bags. That's
reality. So that flawed institution
would you say buddy? He said blue,
blue cigarettes. I'll Stephen Dorff.
You ever seen those ads?
No. Proof of this. All La.
There's a broad spectrum of intelligent
life on this planet itself and you need
to see the ad for blue cigarettes.
It's a black and white ad where Stephen
Dorff is telling you how cool it is to
smoke electronic cigarettes.
It's the second douchey is
commercial that's ever existed.
The first is Brad Pitt's Chanel
number five commercial. Have you seen,
I've only seen the stills and all of that.
You want to become a dumber
person for a few more.
I can show you that can make you dumber,
not just slightly dumb or like
1000000th of 1% dumber. Oh,
we're running out of time. Just let's
show him that we'll end with stupidity.
Listen, man, you're,
you're a brilliant person.
Thank you very much for not just being
here, but for what you do. You know,
even Mrs Rogan was excited that
you were on the podcast today.
It's a big on science as you can tell.
She wants a real diamond.
Tell I'll word mixed animal, smuggle
one out under blindfold for, let's see,
what else would I can do?
Your,
your passion for knowledge and your
passion for distributing it. And it's,
it's so infectious and
it's so fascinating.
And I got a lot of Twitter messages today
about you coming on and a lot of them
were from people who said that you
ignited their passion for science and you
made them pursue specific career goals.
And I got to do,
sent me this message
about who's an engineer.
I became an engineer because
listening to you, I'm
deeply appreciative of,
but let me pose that and let me analyze
that in a slightly different way.
I already know that the universe
is an extraordinary place,
but not everyone else does.
So part of what I do is serve as a conduit
between the curiosity in our culture
that is embedded there,
even if you forgotten it,
because I know it's within us all because
it's there in all of us when we're
children, Aka, you're a bad motherfucker.
I do is park the curtains for people
to recognize the awesomeness of the
universe that is there with or without me.
Well,
you have a beautiful way of looking at
it and I really appreciate your humility
in that, in that respect. Um, but it,
that perfect storm of personality
and knowledge is very rare and I just
appreciate you for being who you are.
And I thank you very much for being on
the can I just say, you know why I'm out?
I'm in la now because we're,
we're beginning to shoot the old things
through the applause in the corner. We,
we are, we are creating
the next generation cosmos.
A Cosmos for the 21st century.
Yes.
The Carl Sagan time
with them all over that.
But that was from 1980 it's been 33 years.
So we're doing it now. It's gonna
be another 13 episodes. It's cosmos,
a spacetime Odyssey. Is it
PBS as well? No, it's not.
PBS would have a hugely larger market
exposure because it's going to appear
likely in primetime, but we're not sure
that yet, but it's going to air on Fox.
Holy Shit on Fox. A strong. That is,
that's amazing. God, that's going to
be so good. We've got Seth macfarlane,
who's our, it's sort of broker,
he, he brought us to Fox. I had,
I became latter day friends with him and
he's a fan of Cosmos and he loves Carl
Sagan. He's a fan of my work.
He's a fan of wheat to hubs.
The lead, a powerful Seth
Macfarlane, the council.
Those conversations I've had with him
that perhaps some counselors conversation
of, he came to it, Neil, I got to
talk to you. I said, let's have lunch.
We have lunch.
He asked me all these questions about
the big bang and the cosmic microwave
background and the early universe and
I said, okay, you're, you're good now.
He said, yeah, I'm good. And then three
months later there's an episode with Stu.
We went back to the big bang and I
get a full card credit at the end.
His science advisor, no, I was like
lunchtime entertainment for her,
but it was like a science advisor episode.
One of the greatest things about creating
this podcast has been the opportunity
to have these kinds of conversations.
I could've never corralled you and said,
hey man. Yeah, I know the conversation.
The guy who hosts the UFC and fear factor
wants to sit down with you for three
hours. He'd be like, yeah, tell
that dude, I got shit to do.
But the fact that I could
pick your brain for this low,
the fact that you even have this curiosity
and it's and you've nurtured it in
your fan base is great. So great to be
on your show. Thank you. So I really,
really appreciate it.
And you can follow Neil on Twitter.
It's a n e I l Tyson on Twitter.
And follow him,
you Fox and let them show them some
love please. Uh, thank you very much
for being here.
Thanks everybody for all the messages
on Twitter and Facebook and all the
various comedy shows, speaking of
which this weekend, this Friday night,
two shows, uh, here at
the Ice House in Pasadena,
eight 30 and 10 30 with a Ari Shaffir.
You comment, you want to, you want it.
I might not be around my
house and posting lined up,
but I'm me and Ari will be there and
we'll probably have some other local guys,
whoever's in town, I think Callans and
towel. I'll get him to come by. But uh,
we're here. We're going to
have a good fucking time. Um,
thank you very much for coming
by and watching our podcast.
Thanks to on it for sponsoring it.
Go to o n n I t use the code named Brogan
and save yourself 10% off any and all
supplements.
Also,
thanks to death squad.tv though
the Brian Red Band Empire and uh,
go there and you can buy one of those
cool cat tee shirts and you can also find
out what podcasts he has and when
they're going to be there and what,
what shows they have coming up as
well. Always great comics, great.
A lot of like previously unknown local
guys that, uh, Brian, uh, gives a shot,
uh, uh, at a big exposure and a
really good, really good comics.
And tonight after this podcast is over,
he has one of my favorite podcasts,
uh, on the Internet today. It's
a pointless with Kevin Pereira,
and that will be a also available
only on death squad on iTunes.
And who's the guest today?
Uh, we got, uh,
Mike. Yeah, Mike. Hey, Kevin.
Prayers here, Ladies and gentlemen,
science bitches. All right. This
podcast is over. Go Fuck Yourself.
We'll see you soon.
We love the shit out of you.
I love you more than you love
yourself in the multi-verse. Finches.