Ladies and gentlemen.
That's right. We're back.
This episode is brought to
you by the dollar shave club.
Dollar Shave Club has the
funniest ads that they send
you. What's this? They have?
Why are razors so damn expensive?
Damn Spelled d a m and that is highlighted
and then above it it says note to
host priests.
Personalize highlighted areas.
I wouldn't say damn.
Why are reasons?
I would say fucking most
people would write why?
Why are these razors so fucking expensive?
But they have a good point. It's,
this is a great fucking idea.
This guy's a wizard. He really,
he cracked the code to smart move.
Razors are really expensive.
If he could sell you raisers
that are just ridiculously cheap,
why wouldn't you do it and just have
them delivered to you and tell me their
good qualities too and you can,
you can go for a dollar a month or even
know that the $6 or a $9 the executive,
guess what folks are Grandpa's all got
by on that dollar a month type razor.
They were fine.
They didn't need five fucking blades.
They need vibrating handles that you
stick up your ass. Why is it needed?
Why is this one called
the lover's blade though?
I don't cause he vibrate the
handle. You stick it up. I Dunno.
Lovers like it really smooth. I Dunno.
That's going to get you in trouble.
You're going to have to keep that up.
It's like when you show up at a chick's
house with a dozen roses in the first
day, you got to maintain that
Sun. All right? If you, uh,
if you have the lover's blade and you're
all super smooth with like 15 blades
and shit, that's the $6 a month with me.
But even that, think about that folks.
$6 a fucking month.
That's like if you use the same razor for
a whole month and you shave every day,
you're a fucking pig. All right?
You're a disgusting person.
He probably spreading diseases.
So this is the way to do it.
Every month you get a
new one if you use one.
I know dudes that use the same razor
for like four months at a time.
This.
This one says that you will love this
razor and your girlfriend can use it too.
That's the worst when
it girl uses a razor,
has that cold water in it and
it's got that little goal harder.
It's got the cares.
If cold water comes from Deb Pontes,
I use the same razor a for years. I use
an electric razor. I use it once a week.
I have a ritual right before I have to
go like to the UFC. If I gotta go work.
Most of the time I hit it on Wednesday
or Thursday and I just banging out
Wednesday and Thursday every week.
Just give it a quick wham, wham.
Ran through the head at the same time.
I do the head sometimes to do the body
hair. Occasionally I trimmed approves.
You have the right kind of hair for that
cause my hair does not work on electric
razors. It just doesn't get close. Yeah,
you got to have a rugged face on for
everybody else. Dollar Shave club.com
this is the way to go though for real.
If you are,
if you're thinking about like
saving money, like how can I,
if you're looking at all
your bills and you go on,
there's gotta be some waste in here
for sure. Your razors are a waste.
If you could walk it down to a buck a
month. Also they have manly but wipes.
Wow.
Dr Carver's.
Easy shave butter n one wipe Charlies
one one Charlie's in the manly,
but wipes are a way more hygienic for
your booty hole. Mr Hotel, they were the,
they were the hardest to kill a nom.
The one wipe Charlies
fire and forget one wipe
Charlies gentleman used wipes.
The problem is gentleman
don't have persons to carry
these fucking wipes around.
What they need to do is have like a ma,
like a single use size one wipe Charlie
that comes in like a business card
holder type size. It's a good idea. Yeah.
You Peel that bitch open wipe first.
You know if you have to take a road shit.
Yeah.
That the businessman,
this is a time is a time and every man's
life we have to shit in a restaurant.
I don't want to do this, but I
got to do this. I gotta do this.
And you head in there unload and if you
had a little one wipe Charlie in your
pocket,
of course you can make your own single
use with a small Ziploc bag that you use
for sandwiches or drugs. Actually,
I have a, I have a thing,
a little small travel size one in my
car I use for it before I go to massage
parlors if I don't consider
it Brian, that's, you know,
a lot of people say that. That's the
whole thing about prostitution is that uh,
you know, men want to abuse women
but you don't, you're so considerate.
Even the smell, anything. You hit your
one one. Yeah, they don't need to know.
They didn't even know nothing.
Uh, one, one wipe Charlies as is,
uh, everything else
available@dollarshaveclub.com.
And if you go to dollar
shave club.com Rogan,
you can get the party started, shaved time
and shave money. That's, that's awesome.
They sat that there are so wacky.
Have you seen the commercial?
The actual guy who was the president
does a commercial. It's funny.
They're fucking funny. They're over the
top. I mean, so they send you razors.
Is that, that's great for a
buck. That's great. Boom. Done.
Because that's always the one thing
you're like, ah, do I have a rate?
And then they're coming in the mail
that says, if you're a four blade guy,
let's say you, uh, you get
six bucks for a four pack.
So one a week for a month. Wow. $6 to
dollar one. Now the one for a buck,
it says this, Razer does not front.
What does that even mean? Urban?
It's a good question.
What are they trying to do?
No front and step on the fat.
Yeah.
I wrote a don't sleep on a tweet and
people were debating when I was trying to,
if I meant I meant the rapper way, don't
sleep on that shit. Don't sleep, son.
That's what I meant. I didn't mean like
don't go to sleep. I sleep all the time.
You should sleep. Sleep
is important. Anyway,
don't front on that razor.
Is that raising for a bag that humble
twin don't front the humble twin son and
you get that shit for a buck a month.
I mean my I,
our parents had those screw
down one razor of death. Yes.
Well those are the ones people
used to use to commit suicide.
This is not good rate. That's
the green mile razor. Oh whoa.
You ever watch those like lockdown shows?
I think once a week they get to
shave and it's like this big, like,
it's like almost
like a, a Japanese tea ceremony.
The guy like, you know, you know,
whatever cuff up and they put his hands
out, they put the lotion, you know,
and then they give them like this
lady bic or something, you know,
it's like totally a,
you know,
generic razor and then he's the next
thing and the place is just, you know,
that's all I'm with feces,
live life broke down to that.
Your big thrill every week. Wow.
If you lived in the Roman times,
like having a hot shower,
you would have to be God
to have a hot shower. Yet.
When everybody gets in a motel six he
just turn on that Faucet and stand there
and just lather up. That feels
tremendous. When you've had a tired day.
It's amazing. Exactly. Yeah. We take it
for granted. They had nothing. No shaving,
not thing.
I think they were pluckers actually. I
think they, they like the gladiator guys.
They would just tweet him over. They
would tweeze or something. Spartacus.
I forget.
I'm not surprised. Yeah, I think that's
what I would do if I was living back then.
I would tweet a fuck the commercials.
Commercials over a dollar Shave club.com
I don't even have to do right now.
Sorry. I'm just say you have a Gig to
promote. I tell comic con beautiful.
This us Friday night am at the
Lobero theater with Joey Diaz,
but I think it's sold out. Holla,
dollar shave club.com Dave.
Mother fucking what's up man.
Thanks for having me.
Thanks for being here,
man. I'm pleading. Love it.
You know. Can I say it like this is the
third location that we've done. This box.
We're sneaky dog. It's goal moving. I'm
moving again. You're running around man,
man, lock you down. Well,
what I'm also doing is, um,
I'm slowly building a man cave and the
next one's going to have an archery range.
This one has a pool table, but I've
decided that I need like a full warehouse.
An archery. Yeah. Way to go. And
I'm going to do a Corolla style.
Like Adam Carolla has a, a,
a soundproof podcast studio.
He's amazing. Like he's, he's a carpenter,
you know, like a real, yeah, he is.
He's like a master carpenter and really
knows his shit. So he builds everything.
He built his own record desk that
he communicates out of there.
He built like the walls where he has
like this plexiglass thing that separates
them from the producers. It's like
really fucking high tech Shit. But
I was there last week, I was there a
couple of days ago, something like that.
And you're absolutely right.
It's like a building.
I've never seen anything like that
inside the building. He built this
like, you know, I could contain thing.
He's a bad motherfucker.
That guy I think constantly going to,
he's a renaissance man. Yeah. I mean he's,
he's got so many like things that
he's really knowledgeable about. Cars,
talked to that guy about cars.
He does a car, podcast, cars, uh,
wood crafting, boxing, boxing
a lot about boxing. Man.
He's a really good boxer. Like I
saw him teaching guy like a MMA guy,
I believe it was Uriah Faber.
I'm pretty sure he was holding the myths
forum and really I'm a instruction.
Yeah, he's a fucking really good
boxer. He really knows his shit.
Well rounded dude.
Very weird dude that Adam Carolla.
I can't think of another Adam Corolla.
You know what I'm saying? Like
I can't think of another day.
We'll tell either.
But you're right here and I don't want
to make you uncomfortable and when you
start talking about you, I like that.
I've got some big shoes to fill,
which Adam probably could make shoes.
He makes his own shoes
following Adam's credit.
He probably kills his own cows or some
up on the barn. You like this belt?
I did it myself. Leather
tans the high. Yeah.
He's very fucking knowledgeable about
houses and he's got that show now on spike
where they bust people who are bad
contractors. Oh, cool. Catch a contractor.
Have you seen it?
That's, that's doing God's work because
that is a, that's a hard deal man.
I've know that myself.
Like you've got a guy in,
yeah, he's a bad
motherfucker. He was on, um,
what does that show a guest?
It was love line.
And he had a ty Pennington guy who builds
those houses and he started out like
quizzing him about questions
about like how to build houses.
But the guys like a TV show host,
he probably knows a little bit
about houses cause he's around them.
But he didn't get the Gig
because he's like a contractor.
So Corollas starts throwing all
these questions. I didn't know shit.
He uh, well just the name
alone. Ty Pennington, you know,
this guy doesn't know his way around
dry wall or anything like that.
That's the look too fancy.
I would say he'd either be an awesome
baseball player or maybe a figure skater.
Yeah. Or Butler in between the
ty Pennington, you'd be a butler.
I think you've got a Butler service tie.
If you,
whenever someone's party and they had
a butler, would you just turn around
it really, it really would
depend what kind of Butler it is.
If it's the old English type, I'd love
it. But if it's like this new kind of like
kid hanging out. Yeah. My name's
butler. I wouldn't like it.
That could be a new gig.
Great personalities at walk
you around at their party.
Temporary Butler Kig you know,
I think, uh, you know, the cool thing
about a out here, you know, I'm,
I'm east coast is that like
when you come out here,
everybody has somebody helping
them do something and you,
and you really do need it because of
all the driving and stuff like that.
And like a, you know, I was in my
hotel and like my door wasn't working,
so the guy came down to help me
out and then he's like, oh man,
I don't know how to do doors. So he
had to get the other guy. So I'm like,
even he has like a little assistant,
you know? I really, I really, you know,
I don't know.
I'm always mystified when I come out here.
The amount of jobs there are, there's
like jobs in la that aren't anywhere else,
you know?
Well, there's another numbers
of humans here is insane. Yes.
Like la is not the biggest city per se,
but it's the bay area because
there's not really one city.
It's like you never get away.
You keep going.
It goes deeper and deeper and deeper
as far as like traffic and population.
Do you know how like if you're living,
if you're in New York,
once you get outside of New York
and then you hit Connecticut,
like things lighten up could
substantially, exactly. You know the, the,
the amount of people that you
see lightens up. It spreads out.
Cities are less populated.
That's not the case with La.
Not at all.
I know that I'm kind of out of La
when I see a party store center,
like a party store center and no
one's there. Then I know I'm like,
I must be heading to Sacramento or
I'm in the math area of California.
I don't know what it is. Yeah.
Dollar store. Yeah. One of
those weird, you know, whatever.
Weird cell phone company
that no one understands how
they're selling cell phones,
cell phone repo shop
or something like that.
They have those weird little ones
at those strip malls. We like,
what are they doing? They're all selling
cell phones. All like cool calling cards.
Like, yeah. It's like you can talk
to Nairobi and that's it. You know,
there's no other place where this
phone works. Those um, those,
those little stalls that they have at
the mall or another one too. It's like,
you know, you could buy a phone right
here. You just going to set it up here.
Like we're out in the middle
of everything. I know.
How can you fucking do,
you don't even have an office. He's going
to turn my phone on here. This is crazy.
I love the kiosk people because you know,
I'm like,
I'm kind of rushing and looking and I
always feel like that's my next gig.
We're going to kiosk, you know, flying
up flying remote control helicopter.
No one needs. That would actually
be a good show you think? Yeah.
If you had a camera on you just set up
a camera and leave it there and you a
cell cell phone covers those
glittery cell phone covers. Yeah,
you need one of those but everybody goes,
did David Tell you David towl like
Yap there's my new show made some,
we made some bad choices. Here
I am. Do you want one or not?
I really think that a really funny guy
like yourself would be enjoyable if that
was the only show you would find the
funny in it just by talking to different
people.
He did it a few hours a day.
I guarantee you would get more funny out
of that than your average Sitcom if you
filmed four days of just a few
hours a day. A kiosk. Yeah.
It would be hilarious by like day three,
you would have an act you had
already know like how to, you know,
things that you could say to people that
were hilarious on camera. But you know,
here's the rub because I'm older now
and like I have to go to the bathroom
pretty much like every 35 minutes.
So who would watch my kiosk?
Well you get one of those things that
dude's use when they race car drive.
Oh it's like a condom catheter.
You're wrapped.
I'd like a diaper or something. Okay.
Oh it's like it's a condom. It goes,
it goes over,
he goes into a bag and you uh,
you can keep the bag like strapped
to your side like a pistol.
You can hold onto it like a briefcase
or a bowling ball bag or just get a
courtesy bucket or then people
are going to smell piss.
What about a good neighbor?
Maybe the guy at the kiosks
down and help me out his mouth.
Hey Lady who's selling a moisturizer?
No one needs, can you watch my kiosk?
Don't worry.
There's no business for either one of us.
You could definitely do that because
it would be a television show.
So because it's television show,
you could actually get people that were
like customers to watch the kiosk for
you.
Oh,
you should totally do it and put a camera
on him and see if they steal money. Oh,
that's cool. Yeah, that'd be good.
Yeah. I just tell you, this is the code.
If anybody buys anything, you know,
just, you know how to count, right?
God gives you 20 giving back $4 and 64
cents. Right? You don't want to do that.
You know what's cool? Because some
of those chaos, they really do like,
they have like these, you know,
uh, they're selling things
now that are really, I guess you could
say like old school sorcery, you know,
like just magic. And they'll
be like, look at this,
look at this glitter thing right now.
We're going to make it look like, uh,
you know, do you miss
your dead grandma? Okay,
now we can put that on a shirt and have
her talk. I'm like, wow, this is great.
Where's Houdini to debunk this?
Yeah. They've got going to have
shirts that talked to you. Right.
I'm telling you they did a new thing.
It's the new merge. It's a new,
a level of merge where you like run your
hand across your chest and to go step
pitch. Yeah. It's for the,
it's for the dubstep kids that would
just keep your mouth shut and you, your,
your shirt talks, you know, or if
it was Red Fox on your shirt, oh,
that would be the best.
You big dummy
kids today. They don't know shit
about Redd Foxx do that day.
They don't. They really don't. That was
one of my favorite albums. Red Fox. Uh,
the uh, hello dummy for, uh,
uh, Don Rickles, which is
all crowd work by the way.
It was like groundbreaking
with all that crowd work.
So when you're a little kid mind,
you have to imagine a crowd.
Wow. Yeah. I only heard
when I was a little kid,
the comedy albums I heard for the longest
time were all just like Cheech and
Chong type stuff. Really. I heard
Cheech and Chong and bill Cosby,
but I can't remember if bill Cosby, he
must have done it with an audience, right?
Oh yeah, yeah, no, he
was, he was rock hard man.
He was already doing like those big
theater shows and stuff like that.
I mean maybe there's like once from the
60s, the early sixties where it was like,
you know, like he's really
super polite now cause you know,
like he had to come in through the
kitchen, you know, back segregation style,
you know, like one of those kinds
of things. But other than that,
I remember his stuff and it was
always like a big event, you know?
Yeah.
He,
he's a guy who probably doesn't get
enough credit like as a standup comic.
Yeah. You know, he's a story teller comic
and I think that's, that's kind of cool.
But I always liked what you said,
like a red flag. I liked the guys.
Those were like cold party tapes or
party albums and like, you know, uh,
if you will listen to that,
that meant that you were
cool. Like, wow, man, this is,
this is jazz.
Yeah.
Red Fox was like jazz comedy.
Did you ever hear any of the
Red Fox comedy club tapes?
No, I've never heard that.
Oh Dude.
Red Fox at one point in time had a comedy
club apparently where and I don't know
like it's gotta be one of those
like cool, like Topeka, Kansas.
No, I think it was probably
like Peoria, Illinois and um,
I we should find out, find out
where Red Fox is coming close. Uh,
but he had Richard Pryor on stage all
the time and they would record them and
you'd buy m and cassettes and I,
I've not seen them online.
I used to own them over really
sad at one point in time,
but they were these great old
sets where prior was just,
it was a small crowd and prior was just
fucking around like he'd be making shit
up. Like as he was going along. You can
totally tell he was making shit. Yeah.
Was he famous then or was it like,
I think he was like famous,
like maybe like us famous,
like not real famous.
Not like Richard Pryor Fam.
Exactly.
He was on his way to become
an Richard Pryor famous wow.
And he would fuck around
in these, these, uh,
small clubs like Red Fox club. And
it was just, ah, man, as a comic,
I remember I was an open miker and I
would drive to gigs and listen to them.
Oh Man,
I'm jealous for that.
I'm ready now. Flip Wilson's book, you
know, flip was another guy who like,
he asked anybody under 40, they'll
be like, whoa, who's that? Yeah,
I remember he, he, uh, you know, I'm,
I'm, I'm not through the whole book yet,
but him and Red Fox had this kind of like,
love,
hate relationship because Redd Foxx was
like hardcore and flip Wilson was like,
you know, the up and coming guy. And, uh,
supposedly like red was really kind
of like tough love and on a flip.
And then a flip was like, you
know, he'd borrow money from me.
He wouldn't even recognize me. Like,
you know, you walk in the club and like,
he wouldn't even say hello
or anything like that. And
then he got a call, uh, from,
um, flip, uh, no. Uh, Red Fox
was on Carson and he said,
who is the funniest guy in the
country? Johnny asked him, he goes,
Flip Wilson and the next day he got a
call to be on the show and that kind of
started his whole career. So He owes his
whole career to Red Fox. Isn't that cool?
That's amazing.
That is cool.
That's very cool. He's fucking show
was funny man. Flip Wilson show. Oh,
red's. Yeah. Okay. But Flip
Wilson was funny too, man.
I remember Flip Wilson
from back in the day.
Yeah. You know, like when you read
the book and you read like what he,
what he went through and all that
kind of stuff. It was like, you know,
that the trials and
tribulations of like the early,
early road plus the segregation and all
that stuff. I mean like it, it really,
it really is kind of a
really interesting story.
Almost like a hobbit journey adventure,
you know,
have ups and downs and stuff like that.
But a Red Fox is definitely the guy
he was, he was hardcore, you know,
and you got to love hardcore
what are unique American perspective to
be a black man who grew up in that era
and then became a huge celebrity.
Yeah.
Like what a shift of things that must've
been for him and how strange it must
have been to go through.
Like when you're talking about Cosby
having to go through the kitchen.
That really rang a bell with me.
I'm, I'm thinking about that.
I wasn't saying it to be anything. I
mean I'm like, they really had to like,
you know, and this stuff, the stuff that
they like, you know, like traveling,
you know, like think about
it back then. Segregation.
Like they couldn't wait in
the train station, you know,
they had to like catch it on the way out
or something. You know, it's really late.
You know,
it's incredible that it was in our
lifetime. Oh absolutely. Yeah. It's not,
it's just hard to wrap your head around
the idea that people were capable of
judging people just by the color
of their skin just a few years ago.
And really today too.
There's plenty of people that do it today.
They just can't do it as openly as,
you know,
whites only faucets and shit like that.
While this sterling thing, I mean,
everybody's talking about what do you
think about this? There's an old dude,
man [inaudible] or old racist man.
There's a lot of old guys that grew
up in that era. You know what I mean?
Think about if you're 82 years old.
That's how that guy is been
around. Absolutely. You know,
so 40 years ago,
40 years ago,
we're talking about the 1970s, you
know, the sixties before that when he
was like our age. Yeah. That
guy who's, he's old as fuck man.
Well I hope it doesn't make everybody
think that all 82 year old Jewish, uh,
cause it's called Jelly and managers of
NBA teams with a super hot 22 year old
girlfriend,
our race.
You know, the dude
obviously got set up. Yeah.
But isn't it weird that like what if we
find that more people think like that?
Like what if, what if were were
persecuting this guy now, right.
Because he said it. Yeah, but what if
we find out like sometime in the future,
you know,
just have a guy sit down and stare into
a screen for a couple of seconds and
they read your eyeballs and go,
oh, you fucking hate black people.
And like you turns out that like this
shit has been in your head the whole time.
People have been saying
things the whole time he,
it starts like reading your memory of all
the different times of the past we had
called someone a nigger,
you're like, ah shit.
And it just starts pulling it out
of your brain and like, hey man,
you did everything you
persecuted that guy for.
I think there's a lot of people doing
that and there's a lot of people that are
jumping up to blame the guy. Yeah,
he's definitely a racist. Yeah.
He definitely shouldn't be working
with the NBA, but he's an old dude.
It's more sad than anything.
Well that's funny how you
bring it up. Like, you know,
like how racist is somebody?
Like I think if you watch
the winter Olympics,
you're a racist because that is the
whitest thing. You know what I'm saying?
All that ice skating and ski and
that's all white. It's just whiteness.
That's a very good point.
Yeah. So it's like if you know
a Sochi and the, I'm like,
there you go.
Yeah.
This is probably racist that move far
north just to get away from black people.
Like they know they're going
to be around white people.
Only white people are crazy enough to
want to ski all the time. White flight.
At first I was thinking, now what if
he has like early signs of autism?
The other one. Yeah. Where are you can't
now I care. Really think of Amnesia. Uh,
Alzheimer's. Alzheimer's. Yeah.
Cause I know when my great grandmother
had Alzheimer's, she was racist as fuck.
And she thought I was her, her
husband, and like it was just,
and she sounded normal. She's
like, oh, you're Brian. Oh,
come here, baby. Getting,
you know, like, well that's a good point
really, because anyone who gets older,
that old you brains compromised.
There's just no doubt about it.
It's a sad thing to witness. You know,
they get dementia, they get real wacky.
It's a sad thing to witness but
it's inevitable it seems like,
and it doesn't seem,
they've never figured out anything to uh,
to slow it down either. Once that shit
starts it's like, you know, it's gonna,
it's gonna keep going bad. It's even
scarier also to think that what that,
how horrible that woman was in it.
Like she just made me mad cause you
could tell how much she was fishing that
poor guy, you know. But how
many girls do that like record,
like get to an end of a relationship.
Like you know what,
I'm going to ruin this guy by recording
them and posting their text messages.
He's a multibillionaire who says a lot
of racist shit and she's half black,
you know? I mean, how do you think that
feels to her? She was being half white,
half black.
I think she's half Mexican too.
Oh really beautiful girl.
Wow. She is. She um, you know,
she probably felt like,
fuck this old racist asshole that I've
been blowing for the past couple of years.
Really. I mean like how old is she?
She's her twenties. Right. I don't know,
but it's portrayed in a black cock
need to get together with her. Well,
it's already happened.
That was one of the things that I thought
was hilarious about the recording was
that the dude said, I don't care
if you're fucked them. Yeah.
Well he wants a watch. Maybe now
might be all cut. Coldy yeah.
There's dudes that are purposely
targeting her, their addiction,
like guided missiles, giant
athletes. Well, I don't know.
She should have thought it out also
because I'm sure they broke up right.
Was just going to find another 82 year
old billionaire Jewish owner of a NBA
team. I mean, if that's her style,
her, her, her guy, you know,
it's really hilarious that
prostitution is illegal.
It really is hilarious because
of prostitution wasn't illegal.
None of this would be a problem.
That guy look their relationship mean.
Who knows what it was
at one point in time.
But it's safe to say that when it
boils down to a chick recording you and
baiting you to talk bad about black
people, that fuck of relationship is like,
she doesn't really like you anymore,
you know, obviously right. She, in fact,
she's trying to get,
get back. Come on man.
So she targeted him for money and yeah,
for sure.
But the crazy thing is that like his
wife was trying to get the money back now
saying that she embezzled it. Look,
that's it. That's how it goes.
If you're an old wrinkly dude
and you want to bang a hot chick,
you've got to give her something.
Yeah.
But if you have grandchildren older than
your girlfriend because he has to have
grandchildren that are older than
her, probably does. But that's weird.
But what do we care?
You know,
I don't know if she wants to fuck
him and he promises her a condo.
I don't give a fuck. I think it's
an important point though, to, uh,
to get the guy out of the MBA.
I think that's an important point.
I think it's awesome that they did that.
They banned him for real quick.
Gets the fuck that guy,
man.
Fuck that feeling that someone around
you who owns the team feels like that
about black people's. God
Damn. How does he get, Oh,
she's beautiful. That's ridiculous.
That's how it works, man.
If you want to get one of those, you
got to pay. He doesn't look 82 to me.
He looks somebody for, yeah, he was good.
He looks about as bad as you can look.
It's still be alive.
But remember he's a billionaire
so that that's like, that's money.
You know what I'm saying? That's that
kind of money. I'm like, you know,
I guess I'll have to buy an island and be
a king. I mean, what is it going to do?
You know when it he did
he, he fucked up. Okay.
Because he in some ways didn't
recognize the relationship,
didn't recognize what was going on there.
In some ways he must been like roped
into the romance of it all. Sure.
What he should have done is he's got
so much fucking money and let's be
realistic. Not much fucking time.
How much time does that guy have?
Powerful rich guys.
For some reason that gives you like
another seven years or something.
It's like a reverse of smoking
and that was just like evil power.
It gives you another seven years.
I don't think that he's using it.
He can't be $1 billion.
It's like a person who's
30 would have a really hard
time spending $1 billion when you have
to be a real fucking asshole to go
through $1 billion.
I think this cat,
if he just was a little bit
more generous with his money,
recognize the situation and said,
listen, you know I've got $1 billion.
That's a thousand million.
How am I throw a couple million your way?
He should've thrown a gold bar.
Her head.
That's massage.
Be the massage.
Both. They're wearing crowns like real
crowns, not like chuck cheese crowns.
Real crowded.
I couldn't hear you.
I'm wearing a gold crown.
He sits around the house in a bathrobe.
Rodney Dangerfield style.
His Dick hanging out.
Yeah, that was the bet. Rodney.
God bless them. You know? Ah God,
the La. The last few years of
Rodney. Rodney was great man. He,
he, you know, you got to say one thing,
like there's some guys who get famous
and can't handle it. He handled it,
he loved it.
He loved it.
You know why he was already an older man
came famous and he had worked like he'd
given up on show business for a long time.
Went back to work.
Oh right.
Yeah.
Yo, he was like an aluminum
side or something like that.
Someone was on the show was talked about.
God, I wish I could remember who it was.
They might've been Fitzsimmons I'll find
out a, he'll be here on Thursday. Um,
but Rodney went back and kept writing so
when he went back to calm me after all
those years off,
he had like notebook upon notebook upon
notebook filled with jokes. Yeah, he,
it was, it was Hinchcliffe. That's
who it was. It was Tony Hinchcliffe.
Oh, okay. Cause Yeah, told me Tony
actually is a great joke writer.
He's fucking hilarious.
He was with me and Bray this
weekend and you're rocking it out
with me all the time. He calls it on
the role. That's excellent. See, that's,
that's what I like about you
man. It's like, you know,
like I'm doing this company
underground show. I didn't,
I don't want it to sell wrong or anything,
but like it's about like getting
the new guys don't really fit yet.
Like anywhere. Like, you know,
they're, they're like new,
getting them out there and letting
them do like a raw, uncensored set.
That's really important. You've
been doing that for years. So dude,
excellent tip your hat.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Well, you know what I would,
when I did was when I first
started coming up and doing comedy,
I had a really hard
time getting gigs right?
Because I was dirty and it had
a lot of people tell me like,
did I had to clean my act up or clean
my act up now? And then, you know,
once you make it,
then you can do whatever you want,
but until you're a headliner and people
come to see you, you can't do that.
And I never understood then I get
it now from their point of view.
So it makes it really hard for
these guys to work. You know,
like a guy like Diaz or garlic already.
Nobody wanted Da's to open for them.
No one. But uh, for me
I thought like this guy,
I mean I think, how does a guy like that
get an outlet in less? It's the Internet.
I mean how you can't put that guy on
regular shows. He doesn't come through.
But she would, he's
really does. Absolutely.
And Joey's a hitter. He is, he's
a, he's a headliner. Both names.
He just said Ari and Joey,
they're both headliners.
So to bring them out on the road,
it's,
it's great because you're like
opening up to a whole new audience.
You know what I'm saying?
Like,
cause I know my own needs,
it's very cool with like rough comedy,
but they also like really good comedy and,
and they can take a joke.
They're not like groaners really,
you know?
So when I bring out the guys and they
do their rough stuff, they like it,
they want to hear it and they know
that it's David tell approved exactly.
Kind of what Rodney,
did you know when Rodney did those Hbo
Young Comedian Specials? Absolutely.
It's really the same thing.
You know,
those things stick in my head more than
almost any other specialists like seeing
like the bill Hicks and the dice man.
Like just seeing them do their
thing in those short doses.
Cause you think about it now it's like
you used to like a long redux of both of
them but let's see and um,
do like a little short set.
Like you don't see that much,
you know,
cause they were like in your
mind they are like mega stars.
But back then they were like guys
just trying to break in, you know.
And they all broke through me. Think
about those old HBO specials you had.
Dom I rarer, right. Excellent.
Yeah. Dom or a dice clay.
Bill Hicks, Sam Kennison, Bob
Nelson member, Bob Nelson,
Bob Nelson.
I'm from Long Island.
He was a legend there for 20 years
before I even started comedy.
So when I first met him I was like, oh
my God, it's Bob Nelson. Bob. I'd be,
I got a manager. Sussman became my
manager because of Bob Nelson. Really?
Bob Nelson decided to go super Jesus.
Yes.
And a sober, you know, with,
uh, like a, a guy who would do,
it'd be like a prayer buddy
and the prayer prayer buddy.
We came as manager I guess. I don't
know. I don't know if that's true.
He met a woman in the, any, any uh, got
rebaptized or whatever that is, you know,
and he, uh, he,
he totally did like a family friendly act
and nobody was really digging it and I
was like, you know, Bob was never that
dirty. No. I was like, I don't know what,
you know, he didn't have to
change anything. Yeah. And
for some reason I guess, no,
I think he wouldn't do certain places
because they served alcohol or something.
Oh, one of those things. Yeah. Maybe
I, I don't really know the whole story,
but I do know that it was a heartache when
he stopped doing it. Oh Wow. It's that.
Wow. That's crazy. Yeah.
He was a funny guy, man.
He was so like Jeff's gym.
It's funny bits.
Those are the things where like
when you put the balloons, you know,
to make the shoulder pads and all that
stuff, that was the thing where like,
you're like,
I feel sorry for the next guy who has to
follow that because this is going to be
like a, like almost a tank
being on tanking. Jamie,
can you just a Mike so that people
could see Dave's, sorry. It's okay.
But this is like, yeah, I tried to got
it. Camera. Yeah, that's good. Perfect.
Thank you. Thanks man. All right.
It's weird when you think back to those
guys that sort of just dropped off that
were really, really fine. Creed.
Remember him? I do remember creed.
Yeah.
I like these names because they're like,
I always think of them as like long
island. I'm very like precious. Not like,
you know, I'm sure you talked
about this cause you, you know,
you're a supporter of, of comedy,
but w auto and George who, you know,
I called into Ona and I go, uh, you
know, I think I asked Norman, I go,
did he ever work, you know, uh,
did he ever work la? And he's like,
no, I got, well he must have worked
Vegas. And I'm like, ah, for those,
you know, the fans listening and all
that, he was a, he recently passed away.
He was a great ventriloquists.
There was no one like him. And uh,
I wish I had seen one
of those Vegas shows.
That must have been awesome
because he is not a Vegas Act.
No, no, no, he's not. I did danger
fields with him. I did the prom shows.
We got like five weeks in a
row. Can you oh, prom shows.
See now that's the bootleg. I want to
hear. Oh my God. We had so much fun.
It was a crazy, do you remember danger
fields? Yeah. Do you remember, uh,
the big Scottish guy that used to
run it before the son took over
Scottish power lifter.
He was fucking hilarious.
He was funnier than 90% of the comedians
there. And he was, he was a, a massive,
massive guy.
And he would do like these barbarian
fucking power lifts in his backyard.
He had like Olympic weights
in his backyard. He'd do
dead lifts and Shit all day.
The guy was enormous,
but like not like a bodybuilder,
just like this huge barrel of meat.
He would grab kids.
Like I saw him grab a kid by the neck,
grabbed his neck and his pants and
lifted them up during one of the prompts
shows cause they were allowed kids
get those long island Bronx kids. Yes.
They get crazy aggressive.
Kid went on stage,
took al Lulubelle's microphone away
from Laos and blew smoke in his face.
Wow. Yeah. And Aloe Bell had a meltdown
and then no one knew what the fuck to do.
That was insanity.
Nobody stopped it.
Was he naked at that point?
Cause you know,
he takes off his clothes
at the end of his act.
He stopped doing that. That's when
he stopped doing that. You know,
after the guy takes your microphone
then continue with your jokes.
You can't really a whip your cock
out then yeah. Those prompts shows,
I think every comic has to go through
those years of the prom shows at like a,
you know, there's two things that happened
at the branch. I, one of them is that,
uh, you know, you're like, what high
school is this? You know, these kids,
like they're already there drink,
you know,
like they're there too
adult for what you think.
And then you get really old and you're
like, wow, this is a, this is weird.
But now that those kinds of kids to fun
kids, like you know, the, the bad kids,
that's, that's like over it now. Like the
kids come out, they're all rolling on,
you know, Adderall and you
know, they've got their, their
phones out, they're happy,
you know,
they're just glad to be out.
I had a cheap thing that I would do
where I would get him on my side.
Like right away we'll do a prompt shows.
I don't remember the exact wording,
but it was something along the lines of,
you know what,
what you guys are right now is adults
that don't know anything and all these
mother fuckers that are adults
that are telling you what to do,
look at their lives. Look, I'm miserable.
They are, and stop, stop the whole thing.
Take it from here.
You know,
it's basically like a Soundation of my
philosophy that I formed over light,
but this was when I was 21 and I
really just fucking wait, wait,
too stupid to have opinions. That was
an idiot. I feel like the older brother,
I was probably a little older than
21 because it was in New York,
so it must have been 24 God,
those days were crazy.
Don't even know if they don't.
They do like promising so different now
they're like political statements and
stuff, so it's like I'm bringing a spotted
owl as my date because I believe in,
you know the highway. We're
not even going to go out.
If you took them to danger fields today
and they, someone told a bunch of jokes,
Oh God lord,
it would be@thefrontpageofsalon.com
club would be shut down.
What's that showed that they improv does
once in a while where they bring all
those kids from a camp and you're
like in front of 11 year olds. Right.
I did that once and they didn't
even tell me to tone it down.
Ari went up in front of
me and got crazy dirty.
I mean Ari was just, all he wanted to
talk about was like, who? Here's Heather.
Dick socked. Raise your hand. Oh
Wow. Awesome. Awesome. It's awesome.
If you have it, you should try it.
And people were going nuts. Red faced.
Everybody's freaking out. Worse. I
forget the exact words he was using,
but it was something along
those lines like ask them like,
have you figured a girl yet?
Wow. All the comics were
like, I'm not changing my
material. I'm not going to like,
so everyone just did it like
dirty and the kids love it.
But what was more uncomfortable
with watching the,
the chaperones cause they're like,
well what are we supposed to do?
We're going to get fired. That's a long
bus ride back to the camp ice cream.
Stop shaking.
Who wants ice cream?
That I would love to see already
in that situation. Cause you know,
sometimes even, or he makes me feel
uncomfortable when I'm watching them.
I'm an adult.
When we,
when we would do the prom shows,
they wouldn't rotate out the audience.
So there's 200 people in the crowd,
right? Date fields holds about 200 right?
Not about room. It's not a big
room. It's a dark room though. Very,
you really don't know. Very cool room.
Anyway, they would get those people in.
Then they would just start shoving new
people in and they wanted you to do like
what? They would do a rotation, you know?
So it'd be like auto and George, me, Alan,
Lubell,
couple of other guys,
and that you would do a lineup and then
when the show, well the lineup was over,
they would just reintroduce your first
comedian and you were supposed to tell
the exact same jokes to the same people.
They would leave.
That was their strategy for crowd
control. So the guy says to me, he goes,
I think his name's Darren. He goes, you've
got to stop telling new jokes. I go,
what? He goes, he goes, because you're
doing like five shows a night. He goes,
you've got to stop telling you jokes
trying to get these people out here.
You go back to the same junk.
So, oh my God, I'm not. I'm a,
you can't tell me what to do. You can't
tell him what to say. Like this is,
we have our job descriptions
confused here. I'm a, I'm a comedian,
you know you hire me
like I'm a subcontractor.
That's why you don't pay me insurance.
I go on for 30 minutes and
you don't tell me what to do.
You're either hire me or you don't.
That danger fields club.
I'm glad you brought that up because
they have like rules there that like no,
no other club.
Like did you ever bring up like why
is this such a big piano on stage?
And then they'll be like, oh you got to
understand that this was the original.
Like they have all these different things
like don't even like ask for a fork
there. It's like we don't allow
for, since the blood up, you know,
everything is like this long
historical story and um,
I just know like to get booked there you
have to call him like almost six months
in advance. It's like really? It's like,
how's your, how's your 2015 looking?
I was like,
I don't know.
I don't even know if I'm going
to be doing comedy by that. I,
that's the last time I called it out and
it's like we try and book like a month
in advance and like in comedy you
go week to week, you know if that,
you know in cities in the cities
book,
like a a Club headliner club on xannies
and Nashville or something along those
lines.
But if it's like New York or La Yeah,
for like a $20 pottery back then I
think it was like 15 maybe 12 bucks or
something like that. But to go like
what are you doing next month? And like,
you know, in your mind you're like,
I know I'm available because I suck,
but like what if something
amazing happens, you know?
Yeah.
You can't pick out that far in advance.
Well there's so old school they're
like from a different that they,
they have a different era appeal
to them. Yes. The whole place does.
You feel like you're in a time
capsule when you walk into it.
That's like the comedy store in La.
Like that.
He's the most clubby field club in this
town. And like whenever I go in there,
I always feel like a little bit more
relaxed, you know? And like a, you know,
I'm not,
I'm not putting down the other clubs,
but I'd say like that's his clubby and
New York clubby as it as it gets here,
you know?
Yeah, I agree. You know,
that's the, the darkest. Yeah,
it's also the least intrusive and
sometimes it goes bad because it's La and
there's a lot of people in la that
wanted a lot of fucking attention.
There's a lot of people in la that don't
make good audience members because they
want a lot of attention and there's
no crowd control at the comedy store.
It's all comics work in there. So, you
know, I mean, that's how Mitzi wanted it.
She wanted the lunatics to run the asylum.
I just thought that would create the
most common, which it probably did.
But you know, you're dealing
with so many dick wads there.
If you put that club and other city, like
if that club was in New York, you know,
same look, same feel to it, you
probably get better audiences.
There's this different, there's definitely
a difference in the audience out here.
And I'm not, I'm not, I'm not
saying it's wrong or anything,
but there's a lot more watchers
here than actual, like, you know,
you feel like they're there.
They're like, you know,
like you don't know if they're having
a good time because it just kind of
sitting and watching. Whereas in New York
there's a little bit more interaction.
There's a little bit more give and
take. But I would say on, on a whole,
I'm sure you're already in,
is live.
When you go on the road or like you play
like the ice house, something like that,
they're, they're pumped.
Like, I don't feel that, like
nowadays I feel like they're,
you know, they're like, okay,
let's give this a whirl.
Let's give it a try, you know?
And, uh, you know, I, uh, you know, I,
I hope it's worth my time because there's
a lot of great clips I want to watch,
you know. Um, I uh, on my feed,
I know. I don't know. I'm so old,
I don't even, I'll look right
terms. I think that audiences are
better now than they have in
years because we only, Jeanette,
I think people are more comedy
fans I've ever been before.
I hope you're right. I I feel like
especially that like that cool,
that cool audience that really
likes, you know, like the, the,
the hard dirty like I feel like they
had to like an endangered species.
I feel like where are these people?
What happened in the last Mohicans?
Where are they?
We have preserved, we have
game preserves, we keep them,
we have to bring them out
for death squad shows.
Oh, well that's good that you
connect with them like that.
And I know your fans like, like it that
way. But I'm saying like, you know,
especially when I did the
comedy underground, you
know, I was like, I was like,
you know, this is, this is the last
roundup of the rough, dirty, you know,
I really felt that way.
Well, it's not that the audience
isn't there, man. It's just the,
the amount of connection that
you have to the audience.
Like I've got a good connection
with Twitter and a good
connection with Facebook
and social media and podcasting,
so, right. I'm, I'm always like,
so they know where to find me,
right.
I'm saying where it's like there's a
lot of those comedy dirty comedy fans,
they might just might not hear you're in
town, they might not hear you're coming.
It might not know.
People that work in offices,
people that have jobs and mortgages
and kids and they're fucking busy.
They don't have time to, and then they'll
like, oh David, tell us in town, ah, fuck,
we missed him. And that happens
all the time. It's going to happen.
You know what's funny,
like you said,
all those different things which are
all like now they're not choices.
You have to do all those things.
Then I was like in my head flashing
back to like how he man doll.
You remember when he was
doing those hour specials?
It's like he put on that big fake
hand. It's like I'm there, I'm there,
get the car ready, we're going.
This guy's wearing a crazy hand.
He blew up a balloon with, yeah,
look at that. What is that?
Yeah, he would do it with his nose, right?
He would put it over his whole
head and blow it up with his nose.
When I was,
when I was young and like you know,
you know like that that like in your
twenties when like you got some money but
you got no money but like you got money
for like something dumb. So it was like,
I was like, you know like uncle Floyd is
in town. Oh Dude, I got to see this guy.
It's like pay my student
loan that can wait.
I have to see this guy who
is some kind of like weird.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
Yeah,
dude, I bombed going on
after uncle Floyd. Oh Wow.
What a cool story to actually
go on after him. Yeah, I never,
I had no idea who he was and I was in
New Jersey apparently. He's a legend.
Yes.
New Jersey
in parts of New Jersey.
And I thought,
I thought I was going to kill. I was
like, oh, this is going to be great.
I'm going to go on after this old dude.
Oh my God.
They loved him screaming out like all of
these phrases and sayings and I didn't
understand.
I never heard of
he, he is, uh, he's definitely
like a local, like almost like,
you know how like there
was a million Bozos,
like clowns that were like in your
rate on your TVs. He's that guy.
He was like our, um, you know,
our kids show before, you
know, I guess Nickelodeon,
but it wasn't an adult kid show,
but what was he on?
Was he on cable access?
No, he was on like channel nine. It
was like local, whatever that was.
I think it was like right before cable.
It was like right before cable.
If you're on any real local
shows anymore are there,
they're just like no local new
shutters. Nothing, but there's no,
it would never be like, do you
remember when stern had um, that yes.
Local show in New York,
so that was great.
He was on like a late night
channel or something like that.
That was his variety show. I don't know
all the particulars on that cause I,
I just remember it fleetingly.
But that was great.
You'd always tune and like there was some,
some, I guess you could say a
carnival freak about to do something.
He brought all that into the show.
It was great. And it was just some,
I don't know what channel it was,
but it wasn't like NBC or snow.
It was like local channel nine or channel
three or something like that in New
York. No, no, it was WPIX
maybe. Yeah. I mean there's
probably like a cable channel,
right? It was it a cable show
that might've been cable,
that might have been cable. How about
bill box? Do you remember him? Bill Boggs,
the baseball player? No, bill box was
the local, another guy in New York,
this is all east coast.
I apologize guys.
But like he was another guy who was like,
he was somewhere between
like Regis and Maury Povich.
He was like this kind of Nice Guy.
But then he did like a comedy variety
show and that was I think the first show
that I bet I met Dana Gould
there. Um, what's his name? Uh,
there was like a couple of,
uh,
great comics that were like hanging
out there and like Dana Gould,
who was like a boy comic, you know that
right? And like 17 or something like that.
Yeah. He was on that show and I was like,
wow, man, this guy knows what he's doing.
I'm gonna contain a way, way, way back
in the day in Boston. And then, uh,
that was before he stopped doing comedy.
Like he was just about to do his showtime
special. Uh, he had a showtime special,
I believe, and he was just
about to do it. It was great.
This was your years and
years and years ago.
And then he's just stopped doing
comedy and he's writing I think for the
Simpsons writing for the Simpsons
for, for like, I think over 10 years.
And I saw him at that comedy meltdown
and I was like, whoa too. Where,
where have you been? You know, cause
I always loved his, his act, you know,
it's weird when a guy comes
back. Right. Well, you know,
you guys were all married with
families and stuff like that. You know,
I'm amazed to ever see you guys like out
on a Tuesday night, you know, I'm like,
Whoa, look at what it is. You know, I come
out and yeah, you like to do your time.
I gotta do time.
If you don't,
I feel like if you don't do sets like
regular weekends or weekdays sets,
you have to do them, then you have to
like pop in at the Improv. You have to,
you know, do spots at the ice house.
We do the ice house all the time.
That is such a cool hang man.
Oh that's excellent. Yeah.
The Ice House was the best. The
vibe of the place. It's fantastic.
And the fact that we've done how many men,
how many podcasts we've done from there?
Shit,
we're almost at a hundred and the
funder pussy shows we do there.
Oh my God. Do you ever do like a
question to answer when you crowd? Yeah,
I saw Seinfeld do at once. Then
there's what I stole the idea from him.
Seinfeld I saw stifled when
I was an open miker. Uh,
I was just about to do comedy like I
think I was like like a week before or a
week after,
whatever it was.
And I saw him with his chick that he used
to bang from high school. It's crazy.
We're back together again at 21 you ever,
do you ever check your bank when
you're 17 all of a sudden, boom.
The both of your 21 I got
adults driving around.
You're going to give it to her anyway,
so we're going to see Seinfeld,
exciting night. And so he comes
out, he does the set kills,
gets this big round of applause leaves
and then comes back out for our question
and answer. And the
question answer, he would,
people would ask things and he would
just start riffing or telling jokes about
like that subject. Yeah. I
love that. I kind of do that,
I guess. Yeah. I'm a lot of
companies. We all do that.
Yeah, I've done it. I used to
do it a lot after shows. Um,
but this is the whole show. Is that
from the beginning to the end. Oh Wow.
Don't material. Wow. What it
is is they yell out, you know,
talk about the fucking clippers
owner. That's cool. Hi.
This fucking guy. And then,
you know,
you'd be amazed at how much
comedy gets improvised Saturday.
I love it. Actually use, I've got dude,
I've got two really good bits from that.
We got to set that up for Friday.
I'm in Santa Barbara.
The fuck it. Let's do it
Saturday, Saturday that can
you move it to Saturday? Yeah.
Yeah. Move Friday, Saturday.
And I'm in fucking Ruben's pre Bridgewater
move to show judge for you. Um,
pre tweeting.
You guys [inaudible]
it's cool that you brought up stuff.
I'll have you done his show.
The cars and coffee.
I call it millionaires wearing seat belts.
I'm not putting anyone down,
but I like how in the beginning
they will have to look like, okay,
now we're getting our own coffee.
Is that what this is?
Pretend you're not in
a helicopter right now.
He had $1 million Porsche. He was
driving around. How cool is that?
73 1973 Carrera rs.
You're not a car guy like
that. Ours. I don't have it
like that. Yeah, that's crazy.
I have a couple of cars that's cool to
have a couple of cars but I mean you're
not like a classic car dude.
No, I don't like old shit. Yeah.
I like,
I like the new shit really.
Technology like I have a Porsche and it
has a like the Porsche's technologies
really old. This car's a 2007. It's a
seven year old car anyway, but their uh,
their navigation systems,
their dog shit,
they don't have updates where they
get like traffic. You need all that.
I mean it's out there. Why wouldn't
you have it? Like I've said,
I have a friend who has one of the
brand new Porsche's and it doesn't have
traffic updates like, well what is
this? I go, this is some 2006 shit.
Like why do you have, I had like a
traffic warning like four years ago.
I was like three or four
years ago and one of my cars.
So I always put like new shit in
there. I think that's, you know
that that to me is like when people go
like, what's the road like? I'm like,
have you ever smelled a road
comics car that there is? No,
it's somewhere between submarine and like,
I mean it smells like 15 different types
of Taco bell from like different states.
Jimmy John's mix them with Dell tie,
you know,
it's like the Charlie wipes
would give up on that.
There would be nothing like the Guy Shat
and their fucked in there. You know,
he cried in there, you know, it's, we see
Ralphie base car. No, I didn't receive it.
It's ruthless. It's really about the
road car smell. They like, you know it,
it's impossible.
Is that stern? Yeah. Howard Stern's on
the latest episodes and what it look nice,
he buys. This is what I don't like
is that these cars are all classic.
I mean for him it must be like really fun
because he's in an efficient Natto but
I'm, I guess I'm not that kind of an
efficient, I don't, I don't like old cars.
That is a cool call. Nope, it's fuck,
that's a GTO. He's a Porsche guy.
I know that he had,
he collects Porsches and I think a lot
of these cars that he used on the show,
he actually just rents for the
show because, uh, he's had one,
a couple of breakdown before and he's
just like, oh, they, they, they're,
they're going to send us another one.
So I think maybe he just gets
to these cars for just the show.
Maybe you're right. Well,
I know you had Letterman.
Letterman has a souped up Volvo.
They did a show.
He has a Volvo with like a fucking 450
horsepower engine in it and a six speed
transmission. Yeah, no, it's great.
I'm going to do a show a lot.
Shit, man. He took a lot of shit for
only having white people on a show.
Then he had Chris rock on. Only
white men. We just say a Duchenne.
I'm going to do a comics
walking to pink dot after the,
so how did it go over there? I didn't get
on. All right, let's get a snickers bar.
The Walk to pink dot. Up Sunset.
That is my favorite walk.
[inaudible] it's Saturday night at two
o'clock in the morning or norms with don
berries. That police
crackles, dude. Pink Dot.
The whole that whole strip from,
from that we'll trolley cart place that
sells cheeseburgers. What's that place?
Carney's carnies from carnies on up that
plays. Crackles like it's got a feeling.
It's like there's a vortex
that's been created there.
You know, cause I don't live here. Like
I'll, I'll be walking like after the show,
like I'll just be walking around
cause I'm New York time, you know,
I want it later and all
that. And like, you know,
in New York if you're up late
and somebody comes up to you,
they usually want money or, or
they're up to no good. You know,
it might be like a psychotic or something,
but if you're within like I'd say a half
a mile of the comedy store on a Monday
night you're going to walk into a comic.
So like I would come up,
it's like I'm a huge fan. I'm like,
what? It's like wearing a hoodie.
Like I didn't even see them.
How many guys
you get to hitting you up to
ask to open for you on the road?
Um, I get, I get a lot of guys that uh,
that kind of like I worked with,
but I really kind of have like
a small pool of dudes that I,
I want to throw work too.
Like this weekend in Bray,
it was Tony as we talked about and Sean
rouse who I think have you ever had
shown on here showing me you really
should have money or he is like,
he is like an amazing dude, you
know, uh, his rheumatoid arthritis,
so he can't really travel that
much, but his act, and you'll,
you'll back me up on this.
I mean like he's an amazing joke writer
and he also is like, he, he is hardcore.
He does not give a shit. And
uh, you know, east coast,
I have other guys that do that,
but now they're all like headliner.
So I feel like I've done my job with them,
but I like to use local guys too
because I feel like, you know,
a lot of guys rolled into town,
they bring their own support and
then these local guys who like,
I never get on my own stage,
you know, it's my home club.
So I try and use the local guys
to middle or at least two guests.
That's very cool. Have you, I gave
up on that and your tail. Well,
you must be hit on like, you
know, a thousand dudes. Well,
it's not just that I just had too many
bad experiences with local dudes and I
didn't know like what was wrong.
There are shitty material that I
couldn't believe I had to listen to or,
um, uh, just do shit guys. Like,
remember when we did that
Maxim tour with Charlie Murphy?
I remember that one guy that we ran into
in Boston that was so fucking creepy.
He was like hanging around
the green room and he was hammered and
he was like staring at us sideways and he
was just like creepy, jealous act like
a dick. And we're sharing agreement.
Me and Charlie Murphy and
John Heffron two great guys,
but Sharon is green room with this idiot.
And then they just, they kicked him out.
He was fucking trouble plastered.
And was he and he was the opener or
what was he? He was in every town.
We would take a local guy. That's how I
met Segura. Socorro was doing Phoenix.
Oh really?
I mean it wasn't local,
but you know,
for whatever reason they chose him and
maybe he was in the area or something
like that. And I was like,
Holy Shit, is this guy funny?
So then I started taking
him on the road too. Yeah,
they had local comedy competitions.
And so I think Tom just like
applied for that comedy competition,
won it and then got he's,
he murdered it.
He was the number one guy like at all
the people that were local guys that
opened up for us. Oh that's
right. But Mcdermott,
we met in Phoenix that he was a,
he did an open mic night.
That's where we met Mcdermott
or a contest. The contest.
It was a different contest, wasn't
it? I thought it was a man of comedy.
I don't think it was because,
um,
it was at the Improv and the show was
at the Phoenix theater and that was, uh,
it was just a regular sheet.
Yeah, the celebrity theater.
It was with the one that's in the round.
It was just a regular show,
but it was some sort of a contest to Josh
McDermitt killed it. And we were like,
Holy Shit,
this guy funny.
And then I was one of those weekends
that Joey vanished on us because I,
there was a series of weekends over the
years were Diaz. Joe would just vanish.
And then, you know, sometimes you go
with, fuck, did you go, I told you dog,
I couldn't do that gay guy.
I told you I never had fuck fucking goes.
And that's the classic story.
But so I used to bring two
guys in the road with me then.
So one guy could cover it
spread if Joey would Vanna.
Okay. There you go.
You've got your backup.
Well cause I didn't want to stop
using Joey. It's like the president,
he's got those two helicopters, you
know, just in case the Justin Case guy.
Well I'm like you, it's like
I, I feel like I have a,
an obligation to support
these kind of guys. Yeah, no,
you're very good to you dudes.
And I would say that like
when I see a guy on the road,
like I let the club picked the opener.
A lot of time I go like whoever,
whoever the guy is that you want to do.
Cause I, I always feel that like, uh,
you know,
even if the guy is rough that like at
least we'll get to perform in front of a
real crowd, which is sometimes
difficult to get that going for.
And usually like a lot of
the cleaner acts, you know,
the straight ahead acts don't want a dirty
open, they don't want to dirty opener.
You know that is true, you
know. Well that's a real issue.
That was an issue for
shift here for a long time.
Guys didn't want to Middlin oh yeah,
exactly.
As guys don't want Diaz middle like Diaz
middled for a couple of people at the
Miami in Providence.
It was just the most horrific thing you
could ever win foam there. That's his,
that's his thing.
Do half his act in Spanish and they
would go fucking crazy. And he's Cuban.
He's got a Cuban Spanish
accent so they know. You know,
they know he's one of them.
They,
I never seen anybody murder 200
people the way Joey Diaz Murray,
200 people in front of a,
what is his name to sings?
I don't care. I don't care. Kevin Meeney.
Yeah, yeah. That's it. That's like
one of those like how did, who made,
who made the lineup
some asshole decided to Joey Diaz
in Miami open up for Kevin. Meaning
yeah.
The worst thing is like you do like a
casino show or something like that and
like you're like, who can I get to open?
Cause it's like a casino town. You know,
so then you're like, you
know, like, you know,
like some guys will
drive for it of course,
but then there's gotta be like
some local guy like, you know,
just degenerate gambler guy that
you're like trying to like call up. Oh,
I didn't know you lived in Reno, you know,
or something like that. So, but yeah, no,
it's good that you do it. And I
think all the comics, like they,
they know it's important like
that, uh, you know, they, they,
they tip the respect back up. So this
guy in the green one with the trauma,
I don't know what that was about.
I mean, he was just a crazy, he was older
than us too. It probably was bitter.
He probably really,
really better.
He wasn't very funny either and
he was just whatever the guy was.
It wasn't Boston.
Well I feel like it wasn't Boston now,
but wherever the fuck it was,
the guy was a dick and it was like,
that's the risky take. We,
you know, we did 22 dates.
Everybody was nice and friendly,
met a lot of cool comics,
and then we got one shithead.
But that one shit had just turned
me off to it so much. I'm like, oh,
cause it was the worst kind of shit head,
you know, the, the Jealous Shithead,
the creepy super drunk jealous shithead.
Yeah. You're going to do, yeah.
It's,
it's,
it's also like you feel like you
get upset if you bring someone,
you know, or you have someone local open
and it doesn't work out and you're like,
I could had Tony Hinchcliffe.
Yeah. I could have had, you know,
I could've brought Ari with me.
I could've brought Dunkin with me.
It's like there's only so much time.
I mean, at up we had like probably
four guest spots plus Sean plus Tony.
And like it was a long
shot. But you know, uh,
the crowd really was
digging the fact that like,
it was like all these fresh faces
coming up and then we're like, wow,
somebody else, you know,
like, and you know,
it's the door guys and
all that kind of stuff.
And like when I worked the door at the
Improv back in the eighties whatever,
that was like our big moment when somebody
called like, hey, you can go on stage.
You know, like you got five minutes
clear these people out, whatever it is,
and I was like, you know, it's, it's
cool that some clubs are into that.
Some clubs are not, they're more
like a, you know what I'm saying?
Like Appleby style, like, well, we've got
to get him Outta here. Yeah, right, right,
right.
So Applebee's.
Yeah.
Plug where you're like looking at
the food coming out of the kitchen.
You're like,
this is a food club that does comedy.
It's not a comedy club with food.
You know?
They definitely have those,
man.
It's a weird thing when you're doing
comedy and looking down and people are
cutting into a state when they're
looking up at you and I go, this is what,
they're barely paying attention.
They're reading, they're fucking food.
They're barely paying attention. It's
just such a silly way to, to do comedy,
but it's a good way to maximize
money and time. Absolutely.
Especially for people that want
to go on a date and dinner.
They don't have the time.
I was like,
let's go to a comic couple of feet
of the club. They have good food.
I really don't want to get
a steak but that's funny.
The state cause it's like was that
in this some guys man fantasy.
I'm going to go eat up big flank steak
and here's some dirty material and then
I'm going to bang the shit out of my lady
if we win the raffle for free tickets
to see if you
steak too like I mean it's going
to slow you down a little bit.
Exactly.
You know that's a full Tom
watching some comedy with
a full tummy in Tucson.
I had to do one of those rooms were half
the crowd was standing. I was so pissed.
Oh it's so bad for those people standing.
What do you think of standing shows?
I didn't know how bad it was
until we went to see Stan hope.
Where do we go stay on a here in Los
Angeles that was lucky club or Asian.
I don't remember the name of the place,
but anyway,
stand hopes on stage and there was a very
small amount of seats and then there's
a back area near the bar that
we were all standing out.
It's me and Brian and who else
can they can go and maybe Stan.
Anyway, um, so Stan hope and um, I
think Brendan Walsh opened for him.
Stan hope and solace, you know, about an
hour and a half, the whole show total,
something like that. And by the time
20 minutes was going on, I was like,
my fucking back hurts. My
feet hurt. This is stupid.
We're just standing here
like we're not even moving.
So when when you're standing you not
even move. It's like a static exercise,
you know, like you don't realize it until
like 20 minutes and you're like, oh,
this is uncomfortable. Like just
standing in one spot. This fucking sucks.
It's trying not to lock my legs. I didn't
want to get, I think Aiken walking out.
I've been told we've watched it.
I'm sorry.
I've been trying to talk to Doug for like
a couple of weeks now. I know, like he,
he's on the, like a super big club
tour. I mean, like a bar tour, but, uh,
there's a show on history town, you love
history stuff. I called the evolution of,
of, of Hitler or the evolution
of Nazis or something like that.
And it shows like Hitler, like the early
years, kind of like the, uh, you know, um,
the Westman called saved by the bell,
the early years,
and it shows him like
young Hitler and he's like,
it's just him and I believe it's a knocker
balls, but a, who's the Big Fat Guy? Uh,
you know, talking about the
Lou Carla Gun, uh, whatever.
So it's just shows him like in,
in these like pubs talking
his talk and I just,
people standing and they're drinking.
I'm like, that's a Doug Stanhope show.
That's a Doug Stanhope show right there.
They're like into it and they're
heckling him and he's yelling at him.
And I'm like, that is Doug Stan hope
in the, and Hitler Times. And then,
you know, he worked his way up to Munich,
which I guess was the biggest, you know,
that was a big thing. You can do.
Yeah. Even had choreographed audiences,
it would do the boot thing. He
had a whole crowd of him. He,
I'm sure he said to girls life, it goes,
how many seats are empty? How many,
how many of those are comps?
Did they pay for the room?
Is it a paper out there? But a false,
these people stand up to stand.
Hope's a opener. A junior stop.
Do you know this guy? He's on the,
on the ground and like a, you know,
it was cool because comedy central,
we went back and forth with the list on
who's on the show like and uh, you know,
uh, I said, you've got to get this junior
guy on. And everybody was like super,
super impressed with him
because he is so different.
He's Doug's opener and he is just,
I met him in Chicago and I was like,
he blew me away.
He was great.
Yeah, he's good man. And
he's, you know, really like,
like you see him and Stan hope together,
they match
well. Yes, they did.
Well, it's the perfect guy for
that crowd. He's a funny guy.
Doug does the same thing. You know,
I think it's really important,
but I think we all,
none of us came up without assistance,
you know,
all of us in,
in comedy.
Like we got to see other people work and
we learn from them and we talk to them
and they gave us advice on
who to call and, you know,
we all got help from the other
headliners. We all did, you know,
as we were becoming professional.
But I, I never waited for help. I mean,
I really was so obsessed with
doing material and like, you know,
getting on, I think that they
kind of saw it like, hey,
this guy really wants to do
it. So, you know, they kind of,
you know what I'm saying? Cause I
never would get in their face. Like,
I remember just like asking a guy like,
you know, I hate to ask you this, but, uh,
you know, like, do you know any like
open mics and like, you know, uh,
they were like, yeah, no, that's, that's
a good question. And then, you know,
I would do, and you know,
they sent me to the office,
Mike and then I didn't see the next guy,
that guy again for like five years,
you know, it was cause I was doing
open mics know he was like a big comic,
you know. Wow. That's very cool. When
you run into someone like that. Yeah.
I mean like you know, whenever, whenever
they come up to you and go like, you know,
I'm thinking of doing
comedy and then you go like,
you know you should try it here. And in
the, they always have that look of like,
well I thought that you were going to
get me on stage right now. And it's like,
well you know, this isn't
bagger Vance. You know,
like you got to make an effort
on your own too. You know,
I talked to this kid once,
I hosted the open mic night
once at the comedy store and a,
a kid went up for his first time
and he was funny. And, and I,
and I remember saying to the audience
like, like that kid has talent.
Like if he really wants to do it,
like if you really want to do it, man,
you could really be a comic.
And he was like, thanks so much.
That means so much in. The audience
clapped and everybody's really happy.
I was like, that's awesome. It's so
cool to see. Like we may one day,
see that guy might be
professional comedian.
Then I ran into him in England like
years later and he's, he's on the road.
Oh that's great. Doing stand up. I
wish I could remember his name. Sorry.
Eddie is wasn't funny enough for
me to remember his name. He was,
I just have too many people.
I was kind of hoping for the other story.
Then I run over to pink dot. 10 years
later was sandwiches, sandwiches.
Look on his face. He's like, you could
have saved me the kiosk. You could help.
But by you saying that that made
his like night. It made his week.
It made his month. I mean that, that
was cool that you like, you know,
and you weren't like, you know, just like
blowing smoke up his ass. You were like,
you really liked him.
Yeah, no, he was really
funny. You know, I've had it,
I hadn't happened to me a bunch of times
when I was an open miker whether it's
someone who gives you a bump,
you just say says something nice to you
and it just gives you this big Marin did
it once for the longest time, Marin.
And I like, I didn't go after him.
Like he would say like stupid shit about
me and I like let it slide because you
know, he's, he's crazy. He gets,
he gets, I think he's awesome.
I love the guy, but you know, he is
what he is. He's got his own thing.
And so for the longest time we had like
this little negative thing back and
forth until I actually wound up having
a conversation with them and doing the
podcast. Now I love the guy. I really
do. I think it's awesome. But um,
the reason why I wouldn't go after him
is because when I was an open miker he
pulled me aside one day
after my set and just said,
hey know you're doing the right thing.
This is great. It's really cool to see,
you know, just, uh, keep
doing your thing, man. Don't,
don't let anybody tell you
any differently. Like, you've
got something cool here.
And I was like, wow, that's
awesome. You know? So for me
that was like, that's great.
Yeah. I laughed and I was like,
Whoa, I could do this. You know,
like I could be a fucking comedian.
A real comedian just told
me I could be a comedian.
Wow. So mark, where was this an
ls was, no, no, this was Boston
88.
Mark had come back from the comedy
store when he was on our podcast.
He told some of the craziest
fucking Kennison story about,
um, the comedy store and
the coke days. He was,
he had left that and come back to Boston.
So he was there for like the,
the hay day of kinisons cocaine
binge. It's, which is like the s 86,
like in that era, and then came
back into Boston. So I met him then.
And so he was an established comedian
in Boston. He was like, you know,
you'd work at the comedy connection
or Nicks or any of these clubs.
And I was just starting out so,
well what I was started in New York and
then I met mark and Tom Roads where the
two guys that like we're,
I was foot found them like incredibly
mysterious cause they had already lived in
other cities for like a few years.
I like,
I didn't even know that was possible in
comedy because I was stuck in this open
mic world. I was like, really?
And he's like, yeah, no I
was in San Francisco, man,
you should check out that town. It's
great. And I'm like, like what did you do?
He's like, no man, you just
hang out and like, you know,
you stay in a friend's couch and do all
these great sets and all that kind of
stuff. So I didn't even know that that
was possible. I thought like, you know,
I'm in New York,
I don't want to,
I don't want to lose my chance of maybe
getting a spot next week. You know,
like it was one of those things like
where the spots controlled your life.
It's like, well I can't, you know,
I know that's a holiday and all the
real comics will be with their family,
so it's going to be great for me. I'm
going to get on twice. You remember that?
It was like thanksgiving. Everybody's with
their families. Are you available? Yes.
We had a guy who came from Minneapolis
to Boston and just immediately was
accepted. This guy was a
comic in Minneapolis. Ah,
wow. Well that was Hedberg he
worked over there. Yeah, heavily.
Hedberg was in Minneapolis.
Minneapolis. Was that acme? I,
I assume it was from acme and then he went
to Florida. So he was like two comics.
He was a Florida comic and it was or
whatever. And he came up to New York,
I think even to New York
before we went to La. Right.
Um, I don't know. I didn't
meet him until La. Okay. Yeah.
So like in New York. I know he was there
for a couple of years and uh, then he,
he popped out to La and then I
think it was just by coastal.
I mean they were on the road pretty much.
I didn't go to know that guy. Really? Oh,
for some reason I thought
you guys had known. No,
I mean we were both good friends
with Stan hope and uh, I,
I mean he was real friendly. I met him
one night at the, uh, at the comedy store.
We went back to back at the comedy store.
I would have loved to have seen him there.
That would be cool.
That would have been a cool shit.
It was a cool show because there was
only like 50 people in the crowd and they
were like speckled, you know,
scattered out. And it was, she was,
those are some of the best shows,
the,
that people commonly store shows and the
or, you know, what's cool about the, uh,
the, the comedy store? Just like when,
when the crowd is there really to laugh
and not just because they made a mistake
and they went in there
because they thought it was a,
like the parking garage for the Hyatt.
Don't you ever feel like there's people
sitting there going like, wait a minute,
this is in the Hyatt, you know, I
can't believe what happened here.
Where's my room? Yeah, like the elevator.
But when they're there to really like
just hang out and like let the experience
wash over. They are the coolest
crowd and sound. They are.
It's a great room and the room has energy.
There's an energy in that room where it's,
you're talking about so many fucking
decades of laughter permeated the walls.
The problem is just too many douchebags
that pass through that whole area on the
strip is just filled with fuck
heads, you know? Uh, the, uh,
just like people walking around like
house of Blues People. Yeah. There's that.
And then there's also like,
just like Ellie actors,
you know like people who are like,
just like I was saying earlier,
they're like a little
needy cause attention.
They don't make the best audience members.
Like I've seen more heckling at the
store than any more on the planet. Right.
You agree with that one club
where there's been more heckling?
There's not, nothing is maybe
something in Florida. I don't know.
Maybe the place in Miami, they
probably exist anymore. It's gone.
What about to close her down? What about
like at a heavy play? Her most to be.
Of course you do. Yeah. Comedy Magic Club.
I think if you heckle there because
they are so they'll pull you out on the
street sheet in the back of the head.
They serve you, they put you on a spit.
Like will not accept anything
like zero tolerance. Yeah.
He doesn't want any assholes there. He
didn't, he won't serve shots either.
You won't let you get fucked up.
None of that.
Cause it's like a museum that does comedy.
It really is a museum of comedy.
He's what? A fucking
great guy. He's the best.
Those those guys that had been there
for that long and like that club's been
around since the 70s
right? Yeah, I think so.
And all the guys that like the legends
that play there like channeling Atlanta
went stuff guide I guess.
I assume they had played there when they
were younger and they just like came up
through this like amazing system of like,
you know,
they were already kind of famous or they
would like the best comics in town or
something like that and they would do
the new material there and it's a great
place for it to close. Always done that
Sunday night gig. He does it last now.
Like a lot of the Sundays other guys
doing, I've done a couple of them, um,
because he's doing the road now.
Leno's uh, he's out there slinging it.
I wonder how much tickets are because I
really would like to see where he is a
lot. Like how much, like a
high Phelps, a hundred. Wow.
For like just like a shitty seat.
I don't know.
A hundred but a hundred dollars
a says a lot. That is a lot.
I always do that math in my
head. I'm like, you know,
I was a young guy and like 30 bucks plus,
you know,
of course you're going to get
drunk and then say that. Actually,
now that I'm thinking about it because
someone told me that, so let's find out.
I bet you his tickets are. I
would, let's take bets on it.
I would say you can get a
75 but you really looking
at a 125 to 50 right upfront
the Ip. Wow. Okay.
I would say I want to stick with
my guns and say a hundred bucks.
I'll bet 20 bucks on it right
now. Oh, here we go. Friday
at the Silver Creek events
center and four wins.
New Buffalo, Buffalo, Michigan. Uh,
the tickets are $98 50 cents.
There's 14 tickets left.
I just want some money,
but there are other ones.
The tickets go as high as 120 bucks.
There you go.
One of them is tickets are
from 216 bucks to 42 to 49 wow.
Yeah. Some of his tickets are $249 in
new buffalo. You can downtown Diggle it.
That's what you're trading for it.
Oh, he's at the Mirage in Vegas.
The Terry Fator theater. I do that same
theater. I think I charged 40 bucks.
Have you seen Terry Fator?
I just can't imagine someone
charging $248 for a ticket.
It says priced from,
let's see what tickets are available.
I bet he's got some like stupid ones in
the front row that costs like ass. Fuck.
Tons of money Terry. Or
for J. For J. Yeah. Um,
look at this shirt.
Okay.
I'm going to give a filter
from two 50 to $1 million.
The guys both had the exact same shirt
at the same comedy club almost. Who May,
oh, look at that. Look Joe. There's, wow.
We don't look like the sound people at
all, dude. Look at you. Who are you?
I was a also a Bollywood actor.
That's how you know who you look like.
You look like Don,
my rarest son.
Look at me really trying to,
come on guys. Come on. Oh,
you remind me of someone else to
God damn that Hermon's father.
I look like a coat hanger.
Look how
my body looks so completely
out of proportion.
I didn't lift any weights at all back
then. I just had this goofy frame.
You look like your slain dick though
with that Tony Danza style. Yeah.
You're looking at, you'll Cox's fuck. I
look sexy as fuck how much hair I had. Oh,
Gloria. It's funny how our shirts
district, it's funny how our shirts,
our shirts make that
sign kind of relevant.
Where your wacky magnum Pi Shit here guys,
this is the 90s right?
I don't think this has gotta
be the nine nineties yeah.
If it was the 80s I would be like
rascals was a cray fucker. Where is that?
Yeah. Rascal's comedy in
Jersey. Rascal's comedy hour.
It is New York City.
I guess the highest the tickets go
is two 50 that's the highest they go
two 50 back at that club you could buy
a pretty much everybody in the room and
drink.
If you could buy the comics,
keep us 250 bucks.
You can have me for a couple of days.
I know I'm not a,
I know I'm not worth anything more than
what I'm getting right now. Like that.
These guys are like, you know, let's
push up to, I'm like gross. Yeah,
I get that argument every six months.
We really should raise our prices. Like,
nope, I can't do it. It's a lot of money.
It's like it's always the venue that like,
you know,
well if you want to make something
you got to raise it. I'm like,
well what happened from Latin?
What'd you guys put in a pool?
I mean really what's going on here?
This is also a problem in that like,
you know the people that are
asking to raise the rates,
they're not connecting with the audience.
They're just on the outside and they're
like, hey, you can get more out of that.
I can get more out of that.
And that's like their objective is to,
but your objective is to maintain
a good relationship and come back,
come back to the club eventually.
Yeah.
And you are one of the first guys
that I talked to a long time ago.
We were talking about a Gig that was
getting offered to you and you're like,
I can't go back there.
I was just there six months ago.
I need to give them some new shit. I just
can't go back that quick. That's like,
that's an important little piece
of integrity when it comes to a,
the connection that you have with
an audience that a lot of agents,
they don't understand that.
They just understand that they see
there's money there to be made. Dave,
there's a lot of gold in that whole
[inaudible] come on, we got buckets,
rain and money and you're like, no, I
know these people. I think the more,
I think like for me like a nice,
a nice resting.
The fields would be 14 months,
14 months,
and then like maybe give it
another six months. Yeah.
I'm really afraid to go back too soon.
I really am afraid. You know, I like a,
when I have it like um,
it looks like I'm going to do my next
comedy special at the comedy works in
Denver. That's what I'm planning
on doing. Fantastic. Yeah,
the big room where the little room,
but that's a great one.
I've got to figure out how to do it.
And your idea with Gopros and the
audience is fucking brilliant. It's cool.
I think I'm going to stick some
stuff on the ceiling, you know, and,
and just keep the, I want to,
I want it to be packed on.
I don't want any seats to
be missing because of the
cameras. You know, they could,
that could just distract
you from the actual show.
I want us to be as non
distracting as possible. No
lighting. That's any different.
Everything exactly the same.
The Guy who did my special Scott,
he was like the director and we both like,
you know,
we both figuring out how to do it.
Like what's it like?
I knew I didn't want it to look like
a theater show with the pans and the,
and the booming all the boom shots.
So we,
we did it over a little
cameras and then the Gopros,
which were like kind of cool because
we gave it to the audience so they were
right there.
So it gives you like the ultimate
like seat in the house by watching it.
But I'm telling you,
dude,
it's so cool because it really does
make me look like a better comic.
It really does. It's
like, I'm like, whoa dude.
That's like a Lenny
Bruce move right there.
And it's really just
me doing my shitty act.
But it looks so much better on
the Gopro, you know? Well the,
the idea of doing it with the audience
holding up the cameras is fucking gene
banks, man. That's
good. Didn't you do, um,
did you do skanks for the
memories in Denver? I did.
Skanks there and I have to tell you that
that is one of the best audiences in
the country. Clubs. The uh, the,
that is just a great, and you know,
now that weed is like super legal there.
I am dying to go back.
I just want to see like, what is,
what's happening. I want to move there.
I've been wanting to move back to Colorado
for a long time, man. I don't know. No,
we lived through the show. Yeah. I only
lived there for a few months till my eye.
My super sperm got to me
wife saying you made a baby.
It's very high altitude.
You can't live at high outs.
Who when you're pregnant
it's fucking real tough on,
on the, on the lasses.
Okay. Very tough. Uh,
but that club was fantastic when I was
living there just for the three months,
four months, whatever it was that I
was there. It's fucking great club.
They have real comics there.
They have like local Denver
comics that are legit and they're,
they're building talent and
that's Bob, you know, she,
she does it on a regular basis.
Wendy is another is another,
uh,
like I guess you could say
unsung heroes in comedy.
Cause like her club is
about the comics and like,
even though even though like she doesn't
get as much attention as like some of
these other like bigger,
she really is important and
she's built some great comic.
Yeah, she has man, you know,
she's been around for a long time and
she is responsible for the majority of
that scene.
Like those clubs,
her system of open mics and getting
open mikes and then turning them into
features or turning them into MCS rather
than the features and then eventually
the headliners. That's uh, you know,
that's an important part of the
whole scene there in, in Denver
and Denver. And now like I was just
have wise guys in Salt Lake City.
Have you been there? No I haven't,
but I know you would love this club.
It's a great club. It's uh,
it's, it was like, oh, it's
Mormon now they're drinking.
It's like the Jack Mormons are out there.
It's a great club.
I tell this to Chris Rock,
I'm like, you know, dude,
if you guys want to go and like work
on material, like these crowds are fun.
They get it. And it's so cool. Like when
you, when you play like a refreshing,
like every show was cool, you know,
every show I was trying new jokes.
It was great.
Used to be that there was real
shit parts of the country.
You would go there and you
go, oh, this spot sucks.
But that's way less now because the kids
that we're dealing with grew up with
the Internet. Right? Everywhere you go,
you're going to get a certain amount
of people that get it. It's just,
I think that's probably the
best indication of how much
different the world is.
Our country is culturally.
Then it was like back in the 70s and the
eighties and the nineties without the
Internet. It's like you would go to
places where people didn't know shit,
but anywhere you go now people
have an internet connection.
Kids are sharing information.
They're just more informed.
They know good comedy too.
Like they appreciate good Cami
and they'll come out to see you.
They'll come out and see
you everywhere you go.
Well, I think, uh, you know, I think it's,
there's so much other stuff
now that they're like,
they're being inundated with just like,
you know,
videos and clips and the apps and all
kinds of stuff that like, you know,
really getting them off that is, is,
you know, I say it on every radio thing,
it's just like, it's amazing when
they show up. It really is. It is.
It's incredible. But it's, they're
just not the same Hicks. Oh, that,
that thing. Everybody's been
citified everybody's metro now.
There's an Einstein bagels and out
of Bama, I was used to say that.
It's like you got an Einstein
Bagel down here, you know,
and then, uh, you know, the,
the places that do kind of stink now
are La and New York because those are
become like, they're not even like urban
anymore. They're like international,
like at the comedy cellar,
you know,
you'll be playing to people
who are from like, you know,
Staten Island and also like countries
that you've only heard about on game of
Thrones, like just crazy
weird Transylvania, Stan, or
something like that, you know.
And, uh, you know, in a
way it's kind of cool,
but in the way to show you that American
comedy, you know, people want to see it.
You know, they came over here. I
want to see what this is about.
Well there's, it's very different
than comedy and other places. I mean,
I know they don't have any full English
people like to talk shit about like that
Guy Stewart Lee had a funny thing that
he was doing about a American comics and
you know,
the American comics sort of been surpassed
by guys from England and Australia
and I'm like, that's hilarious. It's
really cute. Good luck with all that.
Really get the fuck Outta here.
Let's meet,
let's meet halfway at the equator
and see how that works. Well,
how about just go on after you at
the Improv, give it a shot. Uh,
Doug, who is my guy of like, you
know, he goes to England for like,
I don't know what it is.
They haven't been a theater there for
like eight weeks or something like that.
And he goes like,
you know,
it's amazing because these guys have
to have like a whole new hour to tour
through England every time.
And it's really like, you know,
like they're so like they're
crowds there are pretty,
are pretty cool with both po political
stuff and all that kinda stuff.
But they're also incredibly judgmental.
Like they see it as like a theater show
or something like that. So, you know,
it was like, Oh, who would want to
go through that grief, you know,
just to be playing in Piccadilly circus.
But now like, you know, this French guy,
that comedian, he's like this kind of like
racist guy, you know, he does the, uh,
the Holocaust jokes. No. So that's
the guy that we have to go, like,
we have to meet at the Hague and I
do a to do a smack down with him.
A French guy does holocaust
jokes. Yeah. Now in France,
like I guess in French you're not
supposed to talk about the Holocaust or
something like that. So he,
he makes a big deal about it,
about like freedom of speech.
And he, he's also half,
half black or something like that.
So he talks about how like the
Moroccans are not treated well.
I don't know the whole story,
but the whole idea is that like,
he does these jokes and um,
you know,
like he's kind of like their renegade
comics. So, you know, we need to,
we need to see, I want to hear them.
Once he brought Russell Peters,
he's kind of like without the money
France to ban antisemetic comedian.
Yeah. See, there you go. Is he funny?
Well, that's the first thing I said.
And then I listened to some clips.
I'm like, well, it's not good.
Well that's the problem. See if it was
really funny, really funny on the side.
And George and George, I
worked, uh, I did Jersey shore,
those Bob Gunzel gigs with auto and
George and I, you know, also did the, uh,
I told you I did the
Dangerfield shows with him,
but he had a meltdown one night
on stage. What are, you know,
we was going off about
Oprah and Oprah Winfrey.
I forget the fucking joke. I, I
don't don't remember it, but he,
he went, it was gone on this rampage
about fucking her with his wedding cock,
you know, these hung like
a paddle, a Kayak, paddle.
And I mean just,
just saying some horrible
racist but hall Larry to Shit,
black people in the audience were fucking
crying, laughing. Everyone was crying,
laughing. It was really racist but fucking
hilarious. If it's good, it's good.
He was talking about someone and two
other people in the hot tub being like a
scene from gorillas and the minutes it,
I knew you were going to say it. What,
what was the joke? Do you remember
the joke? Um, it could be,
it could be a cause that was like one
of those like long island standards,
you know, like, uh, I just saw
monster's ball. It looked like a scene
from gorillas in the mist or you know,
right at this, you know, name
a black movie. And he's like,
I dunno if I was watching
that or gorillas in the mist.
Well,
he told me at one point in time I was
doing a Kennedy bit and he told me at one
point in time it was trying to rig how to
make blood scored out of George's head.
Yeah. Cause his wig would fall
back. It was brain would be exposed.
Do you remember that? He would do a bit,
we would throw George's head head back.
That was his closer and, and you
would see his brains and like people,
you could see people like going like
why did I eat if I was going to see the
brains of what he's
saying is the president.
But I remember him coming
up to me afterwards.
I think it was like one of
the first time I met him.
It was right after his show and he and
the, he didn't smooth back the hair yet,
so it was like, hey, what's up auto?
How's it going man? I'm a huge fan.
Blah Blah Blah.
And the brains were like
right there. So it was cool. I got
to see the whole like the whole,
ah pyrotechnic various,
yeah, could put it on.
Let's hear some of that. Some of
it. Well, this is a later one. Yeah.
Hey George, did you, uh, did
you see Brokeback mountain?
Yeah. What'd you think?
Loved him or hated him? All right.
You don't need original title, et.
Al is off this Bullock testicles. Hi. No,
four minutes.
And you're throwing a shadow here.
Try and get me in this building
tomorrow, Jeff. Pat. Oh, okay. All right.
George,
do you like playing travel manage sucks.
I think to get on an airplane
sitting next to look cute girl.
I'm always sitting next to some old guy
to wants to talk and I'll lay up. Ron,
what are you going? Where am I going?
We'll get you a ticket. That's cool.
We're all guard.
Yeah.
I like to sing your song
for Valentine's Day.
This is the love song from the movie jaws.
Suddenly I'm not half the man I the
good crowd, right? Yeah. And
Sonny Bono's a good skier.
I love George. George was a great movie.
Now that he authored, he's seen in joy's,
this drunk girl.
Go swimming naked and John
got it. And then you'd
hear data and Todd on, ah,
come on.
I had a lot of his grade dot.
Broadhead. Him. Yo Zack.
Yeah. Yeah. Zach. Hi.
Is Anybody here from New Jersey,
New Jersey?
Kill yourself.
Polluted
New Jersey is no New Jersey
where our farm is refreshing.
You sleep. Oh, um,
I wrote about Jersey. It's called
pollution. It's a poem. Go ahead.
I an Arrow
into the air.
It stuck
and that's, that's on TV. Yeah, that'd be
super Watertown you want to see? Yeah. No,
no, no, no. It's okay. I love those
classic setups. Like, you know,
do a fly much. I love
this. Like everybody,
it doesn't matter how they have
to do that kind of question.
Some comics will get mad if other comics
do jokes about plane travel. Like, oh,
he does a joke about plane
travel. A hack. What year is this?
This one's really all done.
You can it in 1988 I might not have seen.
Okay,
that's lawn mowers.
Cock suckers. They got real
what years? This 1980 oh wow. Young.
See that twilight zone
episode? Yeah. Shut it.
It's my favorite show.
Yeah.
I wonder why I met Rod Charlene lunch.
He had a huge cock.
Would I browse on it?
Right?
You like Porno Molly?
I need one.
It's a fuck wit all puppets.
It's called calendula bran and Holly.
Miss piggy in this moly.
I
got out of the areas.
I bought that bitch.
Yeah. Don't you think he's
a nice audience? Yeah,
I seem happy faces and firing squad.
I drive the cab for a living here in
New York and she faster take hands.
See if you recognize me.
Yeah.
Oh, you want me to get my feet back in the
chair? I'm fucking swinging here. Sorry.
All right. Make my ass look real.
Okay. We don't walk in a lotion.
Go in here. All right.
Okay. How's your girlfriend?
Oh, that slut. What do you call it,
ed for this browse a slot.
One time.
She spread her legs and
a Greyhound bus pay now.
Okay.
Do you imagine that killing
at pimps like this crazy hips?
Remember pips never performed there.
Peaked in once instead of,
let me get the fuck out of here.
Actually, I just smelled the devil.
That is is a demonic presence in this.
Joey Cola told me it was on Steve's
there and a guy flashing a gun. Yeah,
that was, that was Brooklyn. Brooklyn.
Yeah. He's on stage and some guy,
the hipsters. Then he's gone.
He's gone. Fuck you. Fuck you.
And he shows him his gun, pulls up his
shirt and showed him his gun. That was,
that was the club that I think I got
to play one time and then I was like,
you know,
it's such a long train ride from like
where I was living in Brooklyn too,
but it was like such a long train
and like I was so bad compared
to everybody else there.
I was like, man, like I,
I felt like they would throw me a beaten
just being bad, like the Colombian.
I'm like, how dare you? How dare you
young? No, no. It's gone. It's all gone.
What about GRANDPA's on Staten Island?
So that's,
I never played there. I don't think
I did. Maybe I did. I don't know,
but I'll just say no,
I don't think that is.
I did that place a long fucking time ago.
God Damn.
There's so many of those little satellite
clubs in and around New York that were
great,
but compared to Boston now,
I just played the governor's recently
fuck fucking great. That's a great club.
The guys who were on governor's
uh, you know, they, they really,
they really are another like, you
know, they're really cool about comedy.
They really want it to be like
what it was and like, you know,
the audience has to come down and see it,
but they really are into like,
they got their own
radio thing going there.
They always trying to give like new
guys like a day, like, which is so cool.
They give a guy like, you
come in on a Wednesday, dude,
dude, do whatever you want.
Uh, Colin Quinn I think worked his
one man show out there for a bit.
Is the brokerage still around the
brokerage, I think is where he did. Yeah.
That's a great club.
I think Ari just did that recently.
I think it is still around.
I got to see already on the road.
I want to see what that looks
like. Fucking, he's doing
great. Yeah. So nice to see.
You just got picked up. Awesome.
Yeah. He's got a college Rocco.
Yeah. And I love how he, he did that show.
He started out doing comedy nights,
did nights like at the Improv or whatever
with the storytellers shows he'd do
the little room with the Improv. Then
he moved to the big room at the Improv.
Then he moved to comedy central online.
And now,
I mean he likes develop this
thing from the seeds. So awesome.
So cool to say man.
So cool to see.
And that storytelling thing,
like his stuff, his stuff,
really rock sack cause we've talked
about it and like, uh, you know,
it definitely is.
There's an audience for that and it's
cool that he's on top of that. You know,
he's like the only guy I can think
of that really does it like that.
Well it's a smart move and
it was his sort of idea,
I believe it was like to encourage
like that style of comedy,
like a storyteller style.
So it help his storytelling and also
just has like a creative exercise.
You don't have guys go up and tell stories
and tell them instead of just telling
their act. I said, you know, it's a
great idea man. It's fucking great idea.
It's um, it's just so cool to
comedy central's picking up. Yeah.
It's so cool that they're smart,
you know,
like I love that they picked up
your show too. It's a great idea.
Like you're doing a new version of
the Rodney Dangerfield show mean it's
essentially very similar.
I like to think it's more
Caroline's comedy. Yeah, no, it's,
it's like it's a showcase
show and it wasn't my idea,
but it was definitely something
that I thought needed to be done,
especially if it's uncensored and uh,
thank you man. Yeah. What do you call it?
It's called comedy on the ground.
It's at the village underground.
That's where we shoot it in New York City.
It's not underground comedy.
It's not like subversive mumble
core or anything like that.
Cause we had like trouble with like
thinking of a good name for it, you know?
Oh that's cool. The village undergrounds
downstairs to get to the set.
This is downstairs. This is like
around the block from the seller.
It's also a lot of the same people are
involved in it. This is a great shot.
That was the first show Jay. Oh Kristin.
Have you seen him? He is amazing.
I haven't had a chance to grade. Uh, he's
also great. Jermaine in jail. They really,
everybody rocked out on the show. Oh this
is incredible. You see that's a club.
That's real cool. We didn't build
that set. That's a real club.
And a club is amazing. This looks
a lot like, uh, my special here,
which is like me on stage, you
know, in this club. And uh,
I have to tell you that like, the
crowd got it right away and they, uh,
really stepped up. So, you know,
let's hope there is a big crowd for this
kind of stuff. The uncensored club shut
there is man there.
I guarantee there is just,
it's not like it stopped being good.
It's just people stop having as
much access to it when you know,
Kennison died and dice went away for a
little while and it's just like, you know,
there's, they just probably didn't know
where to get is that j and j is rocking.
What a great club man. I mean, this,
of course Chris Rock's kind of dirty,
but he's also, he's too smart to just
be considered just a dirty comedian too.
He wears the gloves like dice.
He looks like he's,
he looks like he's like a given
them the uh, like, you know,
you don't like the scared straight and
high school. I've done Tom don't myth.
I know how to Cook Meth, don't do
it. But Jay is a great comic man.
He really is like one of my
favorites and uh, you know,
I've talked with him a bunch. He's just,
he's just a pleasure all the way around.
Club on this is on third
street in Manhattan.
Third between McDougall and six ave.
How long has it been around for this club?
The village underground.
They do plenty of shows there if you ever
want to do when they'd love to have it.
It's been around forever.
It's the black fat pussy cat is the bar
and then they have music there most of
the time. But they just started doing
comedy a couple of years back and she,
I heard about them doing comedy
there before. See, this is all,
this is all the style, like of the
special where you see the audience,
but you all see the comic closeup.
There's no,
there's no like shots for
no reason really. It's, it's
like it's all promoting it,
moving it forward and uh, it
just makes, it looks way better.
And we had tons of Camden
problems on the show.
It took me forever to edit this stuff,
but it looks better. It looks way better.
That's a, that's a
perfect stage. So perfect.
I love the sign to that
old sign behind though.
Yeah, no, they put that in there. The
underground thing. But other than that,
that's the classic stage. You've seen it.
Yeah, I know. I told them that too. Idiot.
He wanted to take it down. They didn't
want it. Why not now? Well, let's see.
I Dunno.
Sign is awesome.
I got to get out of my house
and have it in your house now.
That's always the thing,
like it's like, hey,
you want it then I'm picking up the show.
So did you guys make that
sign for the show? Oh they
did. Oh my God. It's perfect.
It's cool. But it's fake
old. I don't know. I really,
I knew that it fell off.
They fake older. Did it still looks
bad. It's still does look bad ass.
But now that I know you
shouldn't have told me man.
It's like telling your kid Santa
Clause. Oh Dude, I'm sorry.
All you know it's bright.
Wow. Wow. British brine.
Who shut the fuck up. No, the
real look. Hit your head on it.
Yeah, we had a, I had this
installed. You did rex.
He didn't hear what's behind
the curtain over there
late or don't show you later.
The massage room,
oranges and warm and the oil
up right now, you know, uh,
that show the other ground, like this
week it's on late, like 1:00 AM Saturday,
you know,
running him Saturday and this week is
Ralphie may who we were talking about
earlier, April Macy and Lunelle.
Do you know Lunelle? No.
Lunelle was in the bore at movie.
She's a 17, the bore out movie. Okay,
well you know Hulu now lays right?
No, no, I've seen the boy, that movie I
haven't seen, I worked with turtle movie.
I haven't seen,
I worked with her a bunch in San
Francisco and she is like so cool man.
And you know, like that, that was cool to
get all this different styles, you know,
cause raw Ralphie's is super hardcore
headliner. I mean he, he's rock hard,
you know.
And April I've worked with a bunch too.
She really knows how to throw in a joke
and Lunelle like takes it in a different
direction. So it was good to
give that balance. You know,
how much time is everybody doing? About
four or five minutes. That was all part.
I said cut me down.
So yeah,
I said cut me down because I want
them to do their solid acts, you know,
four or five minutes and they would
roll out 1250 minutes. So it was all
well yeah,
the network wanted to do it and I said,
I just let me take a look at it,
you know, if I will look at it,
it'd be a little bit smoother than if
the network did it let you edit it? Yeah,
they, they eventually I
jumped in on it. Right.
Well that's cool that they're
lending. You edit it, you know,
the more power they give you,
the more control over it.
You obsess about shit man.
I really do. I remember when we did that
porn show together. You, you uh, I was,
couldn't believe how much you obsessing
like the various aspects of what worked
and what didn't work. What, what's
the next scene we should watch?
He had notes and notes and notes.
I figured it was a show you just show up.
No, we, we really wanted it. I
wanted it to be so like tribute show.
Funny show. I mean it was
unscripted, but you're right.
We were obsessing because we
did all this prep work on like,
well this movie was an important movie
for our star and this one was like a
movie. They direct it. So we were
trying to tell like this half ass story.
But you're right. I obsessed. I take all
the fun out of every fucking thing I do.
It's not the fun out of it. You just
have a great connection to your work.
You know you really want it
to come out good. Which is,
thanks for saying that
man is so important, man.
It's a very inspiring because it's very
uninspiring when you're around someone
who doesn't, right. It doesn't give a
shit. It doesn't mean anything to them.
So when I see a guy like you with a
big stack of ruffled notes and you're
fucking riding on this and you've
got producers coming over and giving
suggestions and you're trying to
piece together, I'm like, wow,
this is like way more.
It was not just way more effort,
but the like your intent
was really kind of noble.
Like you really were trying to respect
these people and pay tribute to them.
Like when you had like a Ginger Lynn on.
That was one of my favorite episodes. You
and ginger. That was fun. It really was.
Yeah. I've known her from the comedy
store days from way back in the day.
I said very nice, very nice person.
So always been a very nice person.
She's a sweetheart and,
and you know,
I wish that show was still going cause
that was definitely one of the funnest
things I've ever done. And I
really do feel like, you know,
when say like you're obsessing
and stuff like that,
it's like,
it usually takes any show about
a season to figure itself out.
Maybe not so much now because I,
I guess like people are
better at television or
something like that. But like,
you know, even when you're the guy who
comes up with the idea and like, ah,
I can't with that, I deal with Stuart
Bailey who was a great dude and like we,
even though we,
we thought it out and we got it,
we got it together and all that
kind of stuff, you still don't know.
You still don't know.
And that's why like editing
is so important and like
learning from your mistakes
and like trying to make it better every
week. And I think that a lot of that is,
that is kind of like gone on the wayside
now because people are just pumping up
product.
Yeah, no, I think you're right.
I think it's just, well the,
the idea that you came up with
to just a fucking great idea.
The floating couch over
the dicks and stuff.
Yeah, no. And all that stuff was just
like, edit in the editing room, hey,
let's try this. Let's try
it. You know, like whatever,
like Reese's peanut butter
cup, you try this, I'll try
it. You know? And then like,
it just happened and it was so good.
It was so good that we're like,
can we do that again and
like you can't afford it.
That was the whole thing about editing
and doing it on your own budget.
It really is like how much can I afford,
you know?
Yeah, no, it's a, so I have to learn
how to edit, why they stopped doing it.
They didn't want another season.
I Dunno. And I have great tapes.
I have auto and George on there. I
have Doug, Stan hope I have a j more.
I have like all these great people who
like did not get a chance to get on there.
I've David Allen career. I have a,
just all these great comics, you know.
You mean you have them on film that
you did it with? Yeah. Oh my God,
I can't, no, not toward that.
Your apartment got broken
into and all got online.
Okay. That's what I heard. Okay. I'll
thank you. Yes. Did you know that?
I didn't know that it's going to be on
bitcoin and a couple of days I've heard.
Okay. All right. We're Vimeo.
Yeah, we can. Uh, that's,
is that how you drop it now?
Okay. That's what I heard. No,
it's until I own the rights again until
I own the rights again. It really is a,
you know, uh, it's kind of like
one of those things where like,
I really don't know what you know,
what to say cause there are fans of it,
you know, they're like, when are we going
to see this? When are we going to so,
but right now I'm just so glad not
to be editing, so that's great.
I'm sure.
I'm sure it's relief.
Have you ever like had to like do that
kind of thing where you do the post
production on a project too?
Yes. Yeah. It's not that fun.
What project would it be like a
special Rogan questions. Everything.
I did a little bit on that. There you
go. Right. Never on a comedy special.
I mean of obviously edited
my specials special,
which is another form of torture
by the way, looking at yourself.
It's not that it's not good for your head.
It's definitely isn't because I
don't like watching myself, but I'll,
I don't mind listening to myself
if I'm working on new material,
but if you watch yourself too much, you
listen to yourself too much and be like,
oh, like, oh, like you don't
want to watch this anymore.
You don't like yourself anymore and you
don't want to hear the same jokes coming
out of your own mouth over. No.
It's one thing if you get talent,
but another thing if
you watch them as well.
Yeah, like all my bad
habits, I can see all that.
Like even when you're showing the old
clip of me as a boy, Davey, it's l,
I was like, oh, look at that. Look
at the bad there before smoking.
Yeah, no, it's so true. I
think that it's good though.
It's good to see those bad things.
He kind of tightens up your act.
It tightens up my act when I don't
like it. You know what I don't like.
It forces me to like cut out the fat,
pick up the pace,
put a little more juice into this. Little
more writing into that a little more.
You know,
it's all the whole process I think is um,
the review part of it is a big part of it
for creating new stuff. And if I don't,
I mean I don't do it just because I
don't like it because it makes you
uncomfortable to watch myself or
listen to myself, which by the way,
almost every comic I know feels the same.
Really. Okay, good. Cause I,
I've seen guys laugh at their own tapes
and I'm like how did he do that? Who are,
they must have been raised right
that you really love yourself.
Why are those fucking Weirdos never that.
I've seen a guy like he's watching
himself on TV and he's like, ah
yeah, good. That's good. And
if he is good, he's annoying.
He's one of those guys could onstage
but annoying as fuck off stage.
Like wants to tell you about
his new bits all the time. Oh,
if you want to try them out on you site,
tell me if you think
there's something in this.
The other day I see this and you're like,
oh my God,
you're going to do your fucking material
on me. What are you doing? Oh Wow.
You ever have that? Yup. Yeah,
and they think it's hilarious.
They'll listen to our own shit.
Yeah.
Like if it's a long bit,
they'll show you the notes,
listen to shit. I'm working
on it. Look at this. Oh Wow.
Now the only time I bring up
a bit of that go like, do you,
do you have a joke like this or do you,
it's called Joe checking.
But other than that, like you know,
like there's some guys like Mike,
Vicky on these great joke
writer. I'll be like, ah, okay,
let's work on it and let's
work on some jokes, you know?
And then like we'll just go
spit ball back and forth.
Yeah, joke checking is very
important because sometimes
you'll, you go, God damn,
this joke seems too easy.
So many I'm on Youtube helped me out.
Or on Twitter rather,
I was talking about this new,
I have this new bid and in the bit there's
a thing about milk substitutes like
almond milk and you know, and I said
Amazon of tits, that's not milk.
But apparently Lewis Black and already
had almost the same joke with soy.
It was last time he saw soy tits, you
know, it's not milk, it's, it was there.
I didn't see it quick enough. He saw
it first, so I got checked by Twitter.
That's cool. Nice. Yeah, it's very cool.
And that's cool that the fans helped you
out on that because, uh, you know, I,
I do think that like due diligence, you
know, and you can't, you can't like,
you know, sometimes, you know, whatever.
Well,
one of those things like that's something
that if you gave that subject to 100
guys and said, hey, uh, what do
you think about milk substitutes?
10 of them are going to say, you
know, Ahmond's don't have tits. Right?
They're just going to think,
well, what's their milk? Okay.
Windmill comfort comes from nipples.
Nipples was kind of funny.
Almonds have nipples with the fuck
are you talking about? And that's,
it's right there. It's like,
here's, follow the normal neck.
Exactly. It's like water going.
It's going to go to, it's low.
It's where it belongs.
That's where that joke belong.
It's a parallel thinking.
It's like it's going to happen with that.
What's something along those lines
or you know, fill in the blank.
There's always a, remember those metal
alert. I'm, I've fallen, I can't get up.
You remember that they had a commercial?
Do you remember that commercial?
There was a, a metal alert
was a thing that an old lady,
they would fall down and they press a
button and they would go and they would
yell into it. It was like a little walkie
talkie. I've fallen and I can't. Yeah.
And I can't get up jokes. Where
Dad was, that was a monster.
You had to have an, I can't get
up joke like every comic in 1988,
1989 had a fallen and
I can't get up choke.
It became hack within like six months.
Like Tinder now are
people that Tinder jokes.
Everyone has a Tinder joke and then
it's like all these new apps. Yeah.
Joke jokes.
I think,
I don't even know if I just heard this
recently come out of my own mouth. No,
it was, uh, the woman from
the iPhone I can't get up,
was also the woman from the clapper. And
I think this is someone else's joke. I,
it's like this lady can't get a break.
And I know somebody said that and
I was like, ah. I was like, wow,
I didn't know both things were
still in play, you know, clapper.
Well it was one of those things
where comics would have to, uh,
they would have to like get onstage
first because they wanted to be the first
guy to do,
I've fallen and I can't get up joke
because you didn't want to be the middle.
You have to open or did the I've
fallen and I can't get up joke.
Then he can't tell you big closer.
Well that's the thing about headlining
when you're, when you realize that like,
you know, the sweet spot on
the show is always the middle.
The opener has it rough and you
have it rough. But the Middle Guy,
like he can roll through 50
premises and leave you with nothing,
you know, and then you're like, wow,
now nowadays a job and you've got the
check spot. And that's, that's the thing,
like with the middle of walk off stage,
it's like, yeah, they were good. I'm like,
yeah, of course they were. That
was like fishing, you know,
that was like fishing forever over
up there. I mean like, you know,
there was no like a, you don't
need a license, you know,
you can just put the nets in and they're
jumping in the boat and this is how you
left me.
Nothing.
Well, the opener is definitely
the hardest spot. Oh, absolutely.
Especially the first 10 minutes.
Can you get everybody rolling? Yeah.
You've got to come out of the gate strong.
You got us to end.
You can't be too needy out of the gate.
You got to like establish control of the
stage and then get everybody into the
trance and get them all laughing.
Well, I was like, you know, a energy
open. Like I use it, the energy.
I think that's cool.
And then, uh, you know,
they should do a couple of jokes of that.
People know it's not a rally, you know.
Yeah. That would be a nice
thing. That would be a nice idea.
Rally. Is there a, I thought we were
looking at the clapper commercial.
Oh No, no. We can pull it up if you want
pictures of you from back in the day.
I'll get that. Get that ugly,
disgusting. Get it off please. Oh,
do you like living in New York? I hate
it. Do you really? Oh No, I live in,
in New York.
I liked New York over La.
I guess just because I'm not a big
driver or whatever, but, uh, you know,
take subways. What do you do?
I take a cab. I like to, uh,
rent a bike. I don't know if
going to, I don't think that
wind power. I never, I feel like I
had never lived anywhere. You know,
I always felt like, you know, I
live in New York, uh, you know,
family stuff and all that kind
of stuff there and all that.
And then I go out to la for work, but
I, I really do feel that like, you know,
it's cool. It'll be cool to
have like the third location,
like a Costa Rica or something like
that. You know, these comments.
Do you have like a two weeks? Like they
go to Italy or something like that?
I mean it's really cool.
Yeah, I would like to do that too. Where
would you pick? What would be your answer?
Locate Alaska. Really? Wow.
Go to fucking anchorage.
Get a fat spread outside of
Anchorage and life below zero.
But during the summer, well dude, it's
first of all, it's light out all day.
I know I've been, doesn't get dark
at two o'clock in the morning.
It's light out your, I'm walking around.
It's light out. People are cool as fuck.
And if you want it to be a place where
you could hang out in the summer,
like a retreat, it's the best spot. He
couldn't come up with a better spot. Yeah,
it's beautiful up there. Oh, it's fucking,
it's glorious. Anchorage is glorious.
I can't wait to get back there.
I've got to schedule another gig.
I was there in July.
Yeah.
I'm thinking to do a new year's
next year there to show cute.
Charlie's flying in on January.
Just come in guns blazing.
Fuck it. I love that breeze
below zero. It gives a shit.
No sunlight ever fall. Gay heads,
guns blazing and dot, dot, dot, dot,
dot. That is a good crowd. Practice.
Archery during the day. Do shows at night.
That's the second archery reference
you've made to catch a fish with spears.
Really?
The second one?
No. In the beginning we were talking
about our, and I was wondering, do you,
do you do archery?
Yeah. Yeah, but I've been doing it for
a little while now for a few months.
Like we doing it,
I guess about a year now
because I was just added sporting good
store and like I was saying it at the
club, I got like, you
know, they'll lock up guns,
but like Boeing Arrows go free range,
free range. It's like, you know, like,
you know, you bring in the Daddy,
bring your daughter in. Like, Hey,
you wanna play hunger games. Yeah. Get
grab a bone out like did just out there,
you know, I think that's cool. And
they've got like some super cool Bose now,
you know.
Oh that's what I said earlier. I was
talking about the archery range in the,
in the um, the club studio.
Yeah. You could go to a place
to place. I went to, um,
well there's a great place in, in
Springfield, Oregon called the bow rack.
This guy's got this insane set
up and he tunes all my bows.
He tunes him up and then
send them down to me.
But he's got an indoor range that also
has some sort of a pull that up because
it's kind of crazy. It's like a three
d range where, uh, it's a video.
The video pops up and you
shoot arrows at and shit
rack in Springfield, Oregon. But uh,
I buy my hours from that guy to
and from a hunter's friend.com.
I buy them from them. They make arrows
for you cause you gotta like arrows.
They get fucked up.
Some of them snap.
I should sometimes you shoot an arrow
into another hour when they explode your
Robin Hood. Um, otherwise,
uh, you know, they'll,
they'll go through the target and hit
the metal post behind a target shatter.
Wow. Yeah. If you miss and hit a rock,
they're doomed. Oh, this is cool.
Is this going on right now? Is
this what it is? What is this?
She says archery three d range. No, no,
no. Go to the bow rack. In Springfield,
Oregon,
they have a website and on the website
they have a description of this whole
thing that they do where I don't know
how they do it as some sort of a game.
And you shoot bows and arrows.
If these moving targets,
like a big screen that you would like
shoot bows and arrows out like a video
game.
I don't know how it works.
Oh, I wonder if like, you know everyone of
these movies, you see the flaming arrow.
Yeah. I wonder if that
like really like, oh,
it's got to be some kind of like tar
or something they put on it. Right.
It can't just be like, you know, he
put some rags on that shit. I mean,
it's all you'd have to, that'd be
the worst. Like when you see those,
like in the movies, the dragon
breath, whatever is going to do it.
Yeah. I mean like, you know, it seems
to work in the movies all the time,
but I don't remember me and
my kid, my friends, his kids
like trying to do that. So
yeah, find the, uh, it's, it's in there
somewhere. Find it on the website, not,
don't look under videos, look under
like, um, whatever the fuck it is.
You'll find it. You're smart. I know
you, you could do a kid, but uh,
it's uh, it's a fun way to
clear your head. You ever do it?
But when I'm like in the scouts,
maybe that would be a cool thing
to know how to do really well. Like
bow and Arrow, like, yeah, well it's fun.
It's like while you're doing it, you know,
trying to just locate that target
and put an Arrow in the target.
It's really odd.
Like,
it frees your mind and I think it probably
connects us with like some fucking
ancient Janick memory of, you know, bows
and arrows, like taking out animals.
What is the yard like? Yardage of like a
football field. Can you kill something?
And if,
okay,
well if you could,
but it wouldn't be ethical because the
idea of you hitting it is not so good.
I understand. But I'm saying like, what's,
what's the range on a bone
are like know slingshot.
They usually say like 50
feet, whatever. No fee.
Well,
okay.
I know of a guy who killed a deer
at 140 yards with a bow and arrow.
Yeah. He's just this crazy
archer. And this was, uh,
at this place, and I forget the,
forget the name of the, uh, the, uh,
archery pro shop and Orange County where
this guy works out of, I'll find it,
but that could, yeah, yeah, yeah. He's a,
he's a real professional archer. And, uh,
it's like one of his pet tricks
is that he can kill a deer,
like over a hundred yards,
which is very rare.
Most shots you make if you're going
to shoot a deer is like 20 yards.
40 yards is a fairly long shot.
Like there's a big difference
between 20 and 40 yards with a rifle.
It's nothing with a rifle. 40 yards
is, is an easy shot. But with a bow,
it's very hard.
I figured. And what about
that? Always that one shot.
You've seen every movie where they get
it through their calf and now they're
limping. That's like every movie. This.
I was like, oh, I got it in my calf.
Rip It out.
The reality is it would blow right through
your leg. Yeah, I can imagine. Yeah.
It blows through Alex. Like if you,
uh, like my friend Cameron Hanes,
he's this famous bow hunter that's a,
you saw the picture of him in the front
of that aside as he's pulling it up, he,
he blows holes through elk, like
a 1200 pound elk. Well, shoot,
the Arrow goes right through their body.
They call it a pass through. And what's,
what's the, what's the arrowhead
like what is the blade?
It's a series of three razor blades.
Like shit three. Yeah, they're,
they're called broadhead blades and
there's three of them and there they're
attached to this steel tip and they
just cut right through the animals
go through like a,
would it go through armor?
No, no. Okay. No, no, that's, it
wouldn't, it would go through, you know,
a sheet of metal. Oh, newt. A thin
sheet of metal that is a cold.
How far away it is. Yeah. Well it's
a, it's a very challenging way,
uh, to try to acquire your meat
if that's what you wanted to do.
You wanted to just be a guy who was just,
especially if you use like
an old school recurve bow,
there's dudes out there that hunt with
old school, like you know, no sites,
just a long bow and they're shooting
arrows into animals and that's where they
get all their meat from. It's
pretty fucking caveman of, yeah,
that's, that's, that's the real deal.
I mean, maybe that's your next show,
maybe the crossbow that's like that.
The kind of suburban guys, you know,
what's it a little easier?
There's a lot of complaints about cross
paths because they're allowing people to
hunt with crossbows now doing archery
season in Wisconsin, it's a big,
a big point of contention because the
regular archer's know how difficult it is
to get good with a bow and
Arrow with a cross ball.
All you have to do is point that bitch
look on the site. Yeah. It's very similar.
Well, the walking dead thing, like
revitalize that whole love affair. Yeah.
Everybody gets excited about
Darryl's crossbow. Yeah.
Yeah. The walking dead. I can't believe
how good that show got this season.
I thought it was going to die. I
thought it was over. I was like,
this show I'm done with it,
but this season it came back so strong.
It's like they just revitalized it.
They figured out what they did wrong.
Yeah. That is. I never read the novel,
the graphic novel or anything like that,
but it is definitely riveting.
You know I
graphic novel because it doesn't
exist. It's fucking comic books. Dorks.
I was trying to be graphic
novel is trying to,
I'm tired of the people saying that.
The graphic novel,
you know what the fuck that his son
did? They talk a little bubbles. Yeah.
That's called the comic book.
But it's like, it's like a, it's
like a $30 comic book. That's a lot.
That's a lot of add on my paper route.
If you put it in little kid money,
that's a lot of saving
up at the lemonade stand.
Well I used to love those.
Uh, the old school ones,
they used to be these big ones called
creepy and eerie to remember those.
They were really good drawings
and black and white and you know,
they were kind of like graphic novels too.
That was, that was definitely
like the heavy metal years. Yeah.
Like that kind of heavy metal.
Remember the heavy metal because of
mental con comic books. It was a magazine,
right? Yup. And it was like, it was like,
it was like pouring light because they
had all this cool checks in it and then
it had like the cool like you know,
trippy shit.
They shall show like those like, you
know, whatever those like, you know,
savage princesses,
fights and all that kind of stuff.
So I was still a lot of that.
That's right. Remember the movie,
Remember Heavy Metal, the movie?
Yes. You remember that? Yeah.
My friend worked on it. Uh, her mom did.
Did the scene with the
corvette read a luxe, uh,
with like the hot chick and pull some
of that up. I don't even remember that.
Wow. There was a time when they were
making like animated adult movies.
Do you remember wizards? Yeah. Do you
remember wizards? I just saw that reason.
It was a great fucking, for the
longest time I had a wizard's poster
that was like a big movie,
you
know, about like war and like,
you know, music. Well, whatever.
But that's the one where they had like
the Hitler speeches would create evil and
then the other, the, yeah, I
recently just saw it. I probably,
that was like one of those things
that it's like on that, you know,
like weird on demand scrolls I haven't
seen in forever, but now I want to see it.
Yeah, that's crazy. You can't,
it's a bit weird how there's memories
that you normally can't access,
but all sudden you go down a road
and you're like, oh, what does this,
do you find it on the ground?
Oh, wizard, whoa. You know,
it's like if you had asked me, you
know, there was an animated film, uh,
it was from the 1970s and it's about
any bugged the fuck you talking about.
Like normally without
going down this road,
I would never have access to that map,
but we're going down the heavy
metal road as soon as you, you know,
we went from creepy and eerie
to heavy metal, heavy metal,
heavy metal, the movie,
it's animated movies for
adults and then boom, wizards.
The future to a universe you've
never seen. This is definitely,
wow.
It looks great.
They used a different kind of form of
animation where they actually drew over
real stuff. So that's why the
people to kind of weird, realistic,
they just drew over like it's okay man.
If there's one thing,
I know how to drive ratable,
I need to watch this movie again too.
I saw this in the movies.
Let your hands work. The
big midnight show. Yeah, no,
I saw lizard from the movie theater to,
Oh
wow. This is wild. Wow. Good landing man.
This is what,
it's an eighties right?
80 81
holy shit.
This was my freshman year of
high school. This is it. Yeah.
This scene hand over your cash. Really?
They stayed. He drew. Oh, that's right.
He cooked the guy.
They use something called Rodo scoping
where that's actually a guide underneath
their acting. Wow. Fantasies. Boy,
the voiceovers off.
What a good kid.
Everybody's so deaf. That was before it.
Fake tickets. Those are real son, Huh?
Oh, the soft porn. That's
what it was. That was great.
I tricked you there. It was every guy's
fantasy. Justin spaceships and tits.
Just enough when you're 16
yeah. Wow. I ships and teds.
That was the working title.
Great.
Fucking my pipe that I haven't
done the movie preview though.
I guess this is it. This is,
it's all been yet. You know,
so this is the one where she
fights the evil on that weird bird.
This was the game of Thrones
before game of Thrones
and there was that weird
theme song to write
Bob Credible to see this is great.
1981 south park
remade.
It was probably one of the
earliest episodes or, wow.
That was with the cat piss right where
they go into the crazy universe. I want,
I have to must see things
now that and wizards wizards.
But Robert Bakshi,
is that what the guy's name was?
Wizard has a lot of message to it. Yeah.
I don't really remember the message,
but that was even before heavy metal I
saw wizard does is my stepdad when I was
like that ain't it? Yes, it's outflux
vertically. This is South Park Guy.
Kenny gets high on on cat piss and then
goes through the heavy metal world right
into the movie.
That's the song. Yeah, that's his son.
Okay.
This is amazing.
Wow.
This guys, this is for the
people listening. This is a,
you need to watch on Youtube.
That's a convertible Trans Samson
with the ego on the, on the hood.
The real world.
The Burt Reynolds one,
they uh, they sold one of those
on that she'll fast and loud.
You ever see that show fast and
loud? Yes. The car show, the,
they actually have one like that.
They sold a real old school.
Burt Reynolds smoking the exam and Burt
Reynolds signed it. He signed the Dash,
the uh,
they flew down to Florida and met him
at his house and held the dashboard out
for me. Sign it for them. It's pretty
cool. That would be, would he be like,
when are your ultimate guests
think Burt Reynolds? Yeah, he's,
he's hurting these days man and
a lot of physical pain. He's uh,
like if you see him,
he's bent over and he walks with a cane.
He's really hunched over.
Yeah. But it'd be cool to get,
I'm like, I mean like really,
if he would want to come in,
I think that would be like a great guest.
He would definitely be a great gas,
but I feel like,
I mean I would really have
to talk to him too. Yeah.
I feel like someone who's mean he's,
when I saw him on fast and loud,
see if he could pull it up Brian cause
it's crazy to see. Oh we did show that.
That's right. He's so hunched over
that it looks like the guys in agony.
So I wouldn't want to have
uh, you know, tell me about
Sally fields. Pussy. Oh yeah.
Know what I mean?
What I liked about Burt Reynolds and
I only was he like the ultimate like,
you know, sex God, whatever kind of dude.
Like you know, whatever that was. But he,
he also was like another guy who like,
he directed like he was
like one of those guys,
like he crossed over to be like
the director like really early on.
Like I think he was like a franchise guy.
Like you know,
like smoking in the band and the whatever
it was, he would definitely, he made,
he made that jump cause
he was that biggest star.
So he was like one of the last big
stores you could do whatever you want it.
He was pretty huge star. Awesome
fucking actor, man. I mean,
people only know him from the smokey and
the bandit days are some of the other
crazy shit that he did, but he'd go way
back to to fucking deliverance. Man.
Remember when deliverance, he used
a bow and Arrow to shoot that dude.
Oh Shit. Bring it on back to bows
and arrows. Yeah, there you go.
Oh God. He still looks very good. I'll
look at that man. See his posture.
That's so hard to see. He was a
football player, man. Guy Was a stud and
to see him, you know this broken
down bent knees, walking with a cane,
probably in real agony there.
That doesn't look right.
I wouldn't want to be on a fucking
podcast if I looked back down and I don't
think he leaves Florida either. I think
he just chills right now. It's rough.
See any heroes slowly rot away before
your eyes Dave Attell. Exactly.
Is this wizard wizards
also a film the same
way using rotoscoping,
which is real actors underneath these
people just they get real goblins.
Well that you could tell
her that is the motion.
This is some scary moments in this one,
by the way. Good fucking movie, man.
It was fun. It was a little
kid. You're like, well,
what's happening here and what's going on?
What's it like?
One guy who's the good guy and
the other guy's brother was evil,
the good wizard and then the bad one.
He's from the day they were born. Wow.
Who rules the peaceful
kingdom of God with wisdom?
Science and technology were outlawed
many of the years. The Brooklyn Wizard.
Well, the future feeling. Wow.
Rediscovers the ancient
secrets of propaganda
technology
and sends out his mutant armies
in a rain of unimaginable town.
Those are the good people in their
little else. Wizards will also
Mortez concerns.
They were free in the 70s
peace, Black Wolf's evil robot
pinch. What year was this?
Was transformed into an avenging
instrument of justice 87 really?
Wow. That's cool that
it's later. No, no, no.
I'm making 70 77 years from.
That makes sense.
Yeah, cause I was, I saw it when I
was really young. I remember that.
I guess I was 10 that's crazy.
They should be showing it in schools.
Each kid about propaganda.
I know, right? Well it's,
well it's also to teach them
about the evolution of a,
of culture and art and you just look at
those movies like the heavy metal movie
and that movie, like there was so much
more, it was weird like there were,
they had to do things like that because
they didn't have the kind of Cgi we had
today.
So it was almost like their alternative
was to go artistic and make this fantasy
world.
They're all drawing and animation and
you know ways where you didn't have to
totally make it real. You could still
enjoy it instead of having a B, you know,
like if you went back to like really
shitty like old school King Kong King Kong
from the thirties animation.
Oh that's, yes. That's kind of
what they had from those days.
But I love that really old old
animation with the like a, you know,
the steamboat Willie. I like what he's
like ink, just all black and white.
I like that. I like that. It's
like amazing drawing, you know?
Do you ever see those guys do those stop
motion claymation things that they used
to do for that King Kong and he's to
do each frame, move it a little each
frame, move it a little. What's his name?
Ray Harryhausen.
Is that as the guy's name was?
Did you ever see the wizard?
What's the wizards? The wizard.
That's maybe you should check
out like here's a, here's a thing
that one of the best clips from it.
However
this dates cheesy.
You're the wizard.
He is this guy.
I don't get it.
Is he like a poster child for someone
who are information butthead?
He's had it for the video
championships in Los Angeles.
Remember this? No. Well he's just a
really good video game player. Yeah.
This is when video games first came out.
Wow. So what year is
this? This is 89 again.
He gave me one watch this.
I'm good at all of them.
I have 97 of them. Wow.
You know all 97 of them.
Remember the power low power glove
for a video. Remember any of that?
Did they actually used to sell this? I
know what? Yeah, it was horrible though.
What was it,
four?
It used to be used to be able to
control certain video games with it,
but it was really poorly designed
and watched. He plays a game called,
I think rad race or something like that.
Narco trafficker,
89 87
so this guys hooking the console up to
the TV. A big giant TV. I should add TV.
Looks like a house,
a racer.
So He's two glove. Wow. Look at the graph.
Oh my God. This is hilarious. Your
gps is more exciting now than that.
Look at this.
This kid is steering with his glove
and everyone's getting intimidated.
He's the best.
He's the best I've ever seen.
That's the wonder kid. Got Fred
savage. He's like dead now. Right?
How old is he getting his? He
attack. Well, how old is he now?
I don't know. But back then everyone was
shitting themselves when they saw this,
you know? Yeah. This is incredible.
The way steering and the music,
inspirational music.
Oh my God,
there's a petsmart.
I loved power glove.
Whoa.
It puts it right up his ass. You know? He
does. Just keep it powered. Close off her.
There you go, Fred. There
you go, Fred. Wow. Wow.
That's gross. Um, the guy's
name was Willis O'Brien.
He was the one who did the stop motion
animation in 1933 1933 King Kong.
Have you seen a trailer for
Godzilla? Yeah, the new fucking like,
I haven't seen it. Do you watch old
school movies, Dave? Uh, yeah, I do.
Do you ever watch old school movies and
imagine trying to live in that time?
Yes. Awesome. Yeah, I was like a better,
although there's some place,
sometimes you, I would never
like the colonial times.
I find that the most boring times
ever. That movie, that new show turn.
It's like spies and co colonial
time. Who Cares? What is it?
I don't know what you're talking. Okay,
well it's like revolutionary war era.
Spy Ring, you know the Americans,
but they have great dialogue.
It's like you have to leave, you
have to get to Delaware. You know,
it's like all like local stuff that you
can get there like on a bus ride now.
But it's like,
I don't know,
it's gonna take me three days to get to
Jersey and then you know, like they're,
they're a colonial spy, so it's
like boring. But uh, you know,
it's like educational.
So that's the big show now on,
in between walking dead
seasons. It's on AMC. Yeah.
If you're going to go back through time,
you want to go like cowboys and Indians.
Fun Time. That's a good time. Way Deep.
You want to go like, you know, mid evil,
evil times, Roman times, gladiator
times the colonial times.
Not much colonial times. Probably Pretty
fucking boring. I'm not interested. Yeah,
he's, I'm telling you right now what
a bad choice. Well, but it's all like,
you know, there's spy,
so it's like weird stuff.
Like they'll write like the
guy's name on an egg, you know,
but it's colonial times
sing. They'll never have a show on civil
war. What are you talking about? Oh,
like a civil war show where they
show like they fall around the south.
All the soldiers around make it a common,
people were fighting for slavery.
Those guys, you know,
they like the old days.
The Hogan Heroes Days they could make,
they had a show about
the goddamn hall crop.
Then it was a sitcom about a
concentration camp in Germany.
American soldiers who were always
tricking those dumb Jeremy.
But klink was one of the stars.
You know Colonel Kurtz.
He was one of the stars are no Colonel
Klink and what's Schultz and Schultz is
one of the stars. They were stars.
He's German and they were buffoons
Hitler ever come on the show?
Was he ever a part of the show?
They would have him drive drive.
Like they'd be like the fear is in that
car and like you'd never see him or
they'd high Kyle the car and then he let
go. I think that was an excellent move.
Like you never really get to see him
but Hogan was always well fed and he
always looks fine cause he's always
tricking him and he's always tricking
them. That was a ridiculous show.
Like could you imagine someone
pitching a show like that today?
What's the season finale? It didn't end
good. Did it? Was there a season finale?
Yeah,
they all got gas.
They all got a joke is on you whole again.
The end of the shows series is 30 years
after the fact.
Some guys a Holocaust denier
and he's mocking it all and
then they fade to black.
That's a weird, that's some weird fucking
thinking. It's Holocaust deniers that's,
I've had some, uh, some people send me
videos. Just watch this with an open mind.
Not really going to do that.
You think they could ever do a
sitcom, you know, like, like,
like a comedy with Hitler,
like a Hitler knows best where he's like
married or something and they try and
do that. Where in England because
they usually have cooler, you know,
up until recently. Like they,
their TV was way ahead of us,
but what does it nowhere, like Hitler
had retired and he was living in England.
It's like a 80 show, I believe. Yeah.
Like you remember Mel Brooks
Springtime for Hitler? Yeah.
It was something like that. There
was no that story. What is it? He uh,
one of his movies. What was the movie?
Do you remember the movie springtime,
the producers, the producers, producers.
He had all this money that he's trying.
He was trying to make,
for whatever reason,
trying to make this a
Broadway musical fail.
He was trying to make like the
worst Broadway music lover,
so he made springtime for
Hitler. Yeah. Ideal is like that.
It would be a musical about Hitler,
but people loved it.
It became like a smash hit. It's just us.
I think it's called hell honey at home.
Yeah. Hell honey, I'm home.
Get the fuck out and I got
to see the opening things.
How Huntington at home under the billing,
not so much a sitcom where, oh my God.
Unfortunately neither Brendan nor the
series we're heard of again until now.
A chance discovery in a Burbank backlog
has revealed the lost tapes in Burbank,
not my house.
Hi honey.
I'm home tapes that we believe
vindicate Brandon's Unsung Comic Vision.
Wow. Okay. Let's see what the opening,
I kind of see the opening show.
Okay.
Hi honey.
I'm home.
This is a real,
I don't believe this at all.
No, this is, yeah. I'm
not sure if this parity.
Hi honey. Me. Why did I do know? Oh China,
you will make an Schnitzel. What a
judge. It must be real mad at me, honey.
I'm a very, very bad
Hitler. Kill me a baby.
Don't touch me. You been late for
your dinner every night. This week.
A Babe please on the bureau.
Is He,
man,
I can't just walk off the job at five
o'clock Monday you had to meet with
gerbils Tuesday by ribbon.
Trump Wednesday clouds
and gem or who's clubs?
Katzenjammer. Here's my Taylor.
You should see the Tux. Honey.
One's more important than neighbor
will let me tell you something.
Mr Schickl Garoba you may
be big stuff in Germany,
but I knew you when you were
just a house painter. Wow.
Oh my God. You're almost out of Hitler
jokes. Oh my God, that is awful. Right?
They're almost out of all the Hitler
jokes. It's like two minutes in.
That doesn't even seem real.
I don't think that's what I,
I think that there was something
else like the English version,
cause that seems like that was just
done like a couple of years ago.
That seems like it was just like,
here's the sketch. I guess it's a
real shift from England.
Seven episodes.
One aired in seven unaired episodes.
Ys Seven. Oh, that's hilarious.
Seven an air and it's cool
that they gave it a shot
after one episode air.
They canceled it.
It immediately and like that they found
the tapes in Burbank and some that's
funny.
Yeah, of course they canceled. And the
guy who made it, what happened to him,
Brandon with a Jewish ceremony.
Huh?
Could you imagine pitching that to the
network? It's balls. It's just so stupid.
And then not have any jokes to go
with it. You know, that's, I mean,
you'd have to have some like
really good stuff to go with it.
I Bet Trey Parker and Matt stone
could do it. They did it with like,
remember when they did that George Bush.
So that was pretty fucking funny.
That might,
that's my Bush are ready.
That show wasn't that good. I liked it
that I didn't think it was that good.
I didn't, don't pull it up. All right. Um,
I just didn't think it was like, I
mean, I think their best stuff, I mean,
I shouldn't say that. I was gonna say
their best stuff doesn't have real people,
but I like the Mormon musical,
that thing rocks.
I W I can't even get tickets for that.
That's like sold out for like a
year or something. It's really that,
that's successful.
Yeah.
Yeah. I saw it early on
it, it's really funny man.
Somebody said that like, that's one
of the only adult shows on Broadway.
Like where, what used to be like,
you know, you and your mistress,
she'd go out and you see like, you
know, you know, like, uh, whatever.
Sammy Davis junior and like,
you know, crazy like adults.
Then it became a little kid, a five very
Disney, you know, like these, these, uh,
these shows now are like all about like,
just like singing to,
and you already know,
you know, and uh, that,
that's like an original concept
and it's really, it's really cool.
It's supposedly really dark and funny.
So,
well,
it's probably the first one of those
whose phone zone that's mine.
It'll go on me if I don't turn.
Keep telling to get all. Still
have flip a flip phone. Oh my God.
What year did you buy that phone?
When did heavy metal come out?
Do you print out directions?
I just, yeah, I do.
Why don't you still have a
phone like that? I just like it.
I like having a burner on me. I
don't know. I guess a burner. Yeah,
throw in the ocean
closes in.
It's a, it's, it's a great, it's a
watch. It's a conversation starter.
Why is that pulled out in front
of chicks and they go, oh, Dave.
Oh grandpa. He's so eccentric. Yeah.
Yeah. I was at a, do you guys, might've
I ever sick? Can I cigarette? Yeah,
you're going to have a cigarette.
You can have a cigarette here.
We'll turn the fan on, but don't
fire went up as well, Brian.
It's towards disgusting for your
body. You need to quit. David.
Tell you know what,
I totally agree with you now because,
uh, I don't know. How do you,
how do you handle like stress?
Like you work out a lot, right?
But like when you're stressed, you find
that that's when you grabbed for the,
you know, like you know the cigarette or
whatever, like the drink or something.
What do you do?
Um, well look, everybody
experiences stress.
It's just a matter of if you can,
if you have the time.
Exercises to me is always the best
way to manage the whole thing. Right.
You have a filter on there.
Like a hunters Thompson. Yeah.
Look at you like that bitch. What's that
for? It's supposed to keep you alive.
Another couple of,
yeah,
no, you got to see the torque coming
out. I like that. There's some about it.
I find that site. That's
cool. Like I'm pulling for it.
No, I definitely think that
taking care of your body,
it helps mitigate a of the
stress that everybody feels.
Especially when you do a lot of
things like I do and travel a lot.
Like I do involve in a lot of
different things. A lot of,
a lot of plates are spinning.
There's a lot of thinking.
Yeah,
well that's why I feel like I started
doing some kettle bells and stuff like
that.
And I immediately felt horrible,
but then I started feeling better
just because like it's, it's,
it really is like a stress reliever,
but nothing beats cigarettes. I'm sorry.
I think he'll back me up when you
blow it on me. Yeah, exactly. Well,
I know this is a long run dude.
It's just terrible for
everybody else in the room.
But you guys love it so much talking
about sacrifice for everybody else in the
room,
but it's amazing.
It's amazing that like cigarette people
are like that. Like you love it so much.
It's so important to you that you want
everybody else to suck in the smoky. Yeah,
but come on. Or a smoky air and
this 20 foot room. All right.
I mean I give you the green light.
It's all good.
We've got to get Adam to acknowledge
the filtration system. Well,
we have a filter behind you. That's what
it's for. Oh really? From one vice was Z.
Oh,
I wonder, I wonder how much he smokes a
day and I don't think he smokes anymore.
Smokes. I thought he'd quit. Smokes.
Smokes again. I give it up. Oh,
I gave it up and then I gave up given up.
David be tried doing the
electronic cigarettes.
Like the baby's not doing that now.
Are you going to walk around with
that wizard wand can do this.
Like in a hotel room, you can do
this in a restaurant if you're not,
I bet you I bet. Ya know like in a
year from now though, the whole thing,
you liked the smell of deal. What do
you like about it? What, what, what?
Like when you light up,
when you liked that it smells like death.
It's like just pure, just waste.
Do you worry about your health?
I could care less at this point. No,
I do well could care less as the run,
you know that. No, but
I'm just saying that like,
the whole idea with the
cigarette is that uh, you know,
they'll do these things right?
They'll do this thing and then of course
somebody won't like that and then it'll
be easy to jump on the electronic
cigarettes, electronic cigarettes.
But it's like,
do you understand that people are doing
electronic cigarette because they can't
do this and which is worse.
So it's like give them a break
for at least the year of like,
let them smoke these electronic cigarettes
before you clamp down again on them
for that.
You know,
the problem with electronic
cigarettes is not the standard ones.
Like those little blues that push out
vapor. Some of them push out a smell.
Like there's, there's something
distinguishable about it. And I'm like,
well what am I breathing in here? I
felt like chemicals, like Brian's,
Brian's is like, it's this Tiramisu,
it's a big cloud that comes out of it.
Like it's not like a mist. It's
more of a smoke. Like that's a,
it seems like a better smoking cigarettes,
but still a smoke like puff puff on it.
Let me see what it looks like.
My battery died years
me, but uh, you know, the, the
uh, they have flavored stuff.
It was all these like weird twinkie,
crunchy flavors. You know, Teddy bear
worried about your health at
all, man. And he, of course I do.
What would the cigarettes,
if you ever tried to not do it anymore?
I quit.
I quit before,
but I, you know, at this point,
like when I brought up the
stress and stuff like that,
like I'm out, I'm, you know,
like super hardcore promoting and all that
kind of stuff. It's like, it's like a,
you know, it's just all stressed right
now, so. Yeah. Yeah. That's what it is.
Johnny Carson Story. Right. Cause
I have a genetic emphysema. Yeah.
He couldn't even talk,
but all he would say it's
those damn cigarettes up
taking his was walking around
with an oxygen tank.
Hoses in his nose.
Yeah. But what a life, but what
a life, what a life before that.
Hmm. I guess that's what you got to,
you know, is that what you gotta do?
The cigarettes really made it juicy,
right?
I don't know. I guess we live in a
culture where we have to live forever now.
I don't,
I don't really understand
about living forever. It's about
maintaining your health. It's a horrible,
it's a horrible end,
that's for sure. Mike, uh,
Mike Lacey from the comedy Magic Club
pulled Brian Aside once it was explained
to him what it was like at the end
and made me cry.
But you know,
I would have one of the biggest things
I miss when I do quit when I tried doing
these electronic cigarettes or I try
not to smoke is the smoking gun tough
period.
You know,
where your outs side talking to other
smokers and there was like something to
that camaraderie. We all
killing yourself together. Yeah,
I'm definitely going to try
and quit again. But it's,
it's a lot harder than non quitters think.
I mean then a nonsmokers thing to quit.
It's not like, it's not like, you know,
whatever, you know, it really is.
I, I, there's truth to the, uh,
you know, cigarettes are harder
to quit than like, you know,
heroin or something like that. I
mean there, there really is like,
cigarettes are so ingrained
usually in people that smoke, but,
but for people that don't smoke, it
must blow you away. The fact that like,
we're doing this like incredible.
The suicidal thing.
Well, I'm fascinated by it.
And the reason why I asked you,
it's not because I want to pester you,
but because everybody is, my mom smokes.
That's smart.
Like you,
I always feel compelled to try to get
their point of view and see if they have a
point of view. If they just deal with
it, they car compartmentalize it.
They don't think about it.
Like I'm fascinated by addiction.
Some I'm really fascinated by, uh,
especially things that I don't do,
like cigarettes, gambling,
coke, you know, Shit like that.
I'm fascinated by those things.
So I'm always fascinated by the mindset
because I don't totally understand it.
Right. You know, so I just,
what a guy like you is a smart guy
and I see doing it and you'd love it.
You fucking can't wait to for,
can I fire this up? Oh, well
I mean we have been here
three hours right now.
I would've smoked half a pack if
you were out on the street. I could,
I could tell you like how many cigarettes,
like if you, how much do you smoke? Uh,
probably two bags today.
Yeah. Wow. That's a lot. Huh? Yeah. Well,
every 10 minutes you think you made me?
No, it's, it's, it's, uh, less than that
because I don't sleep. I get up to smoke.
Yeah. How much do you
sleep? Maybe now that I'm,
I'm doing all this crazy stuff. Uh,
three hours. Three hours? Yeah. Wow.
What do you normally sleep if you weren't
a lot of hours? If I'm lucky. Wow.
Four hours maybe. Well you're juiced
up on nicotine all the time. No,
it has to do with, I have to
work editing, like, you know,
like I have to do the notes at night
so that they can edit during the day.
And then I go in at night and
then now like with all these,
like with radio as you know,
like radio and all that stuff,
it's like there's a weird schedule to all
of that. And then doing shows at night,
cause I never stopped doing
shows, you know, of course.
But I meant like when you're not doing
this and you said five hours. Yeah,
like five hours maybe because you're all
juiced up with nicotine all the time.
I think cause I'm old and my prostate
tells me it's time to get up.
I take a leak. Yeah. Hours. And
you're good if I'm lucky, you know,
get some palm palm juice. Have you
tried some of those pills that help?
What is this?
Doctor Oz gives a shit.
It's like we were just watching
heavy metal and there's like a, uh,
a Caribou carcass here. It's
like, have you ever thought
of like, who gives a shit?
It's part of getting old guys. Get
used to it. Get used to it. Joe,
you're old enough to start now and not
have any probably any problems from
smoking.
You'll never write out for a year.
You would never see anybody who like was
an athlete in their youth or like stole
is involved in athletics.
Like smoking is a no,
my cardio was very important to me.
Yeah. Yeah, I understand that. You know,
never fuck around with that, but I'd
get it. I do love like uh, you know,
smokers do like, I'm just talking
about like my dad and his friends,
like they would have amazing like smoke
smoker superpowers where it's like, no,
they couldn't do anything. But like if
there was like something like, you know,
hey, I need your help. What happened?
My car fell in a ditch and like they
would just like come out with a cigarette
in the mouth and like lift up the car. I
was like, man, that's so cool. You know,
we'll do it. Always work on cars with a
cigarette dangling out of their mouth,
gasoline everywhere. Oil, everything on,
yeah, no, just like there's a smoker dude.
Super Proud.
Like I guess I'm mad men.
You see some of it too where like
they're constantly smoking all the time,
doing whatever they do. But those
are like real cigarettes by the way.
It is no organic. That was, yeah,
it was like more roles and
camels and Lucky's smoke.
Do you do the organic organic now?
So I think that they,
they helped me just because they taste
horrible. Like, like the, the, you know,
the reds were like the best taste and
say that's like candy. Tastes good. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Don't you feel like
with the, the American spirits,
so when you wake up you have more of
like, that's a thicker smoke, you know,
it doesn't have all the
chemicals probably help the
cigarettes evaporate better.
I'm just saying that like,
I can usually tell like three hours,
that would have been probably
coming up on half a pack.
So that's like 10 cigarettes.
You still smoke?
Newports Newports I don't smoke Newports
and that funny, but he's a brand.
That's funny. That was my
point. I wanted to make a point.
There's a brand that if
you say, it's funny, like
what do you drive a
Yugo new or for Asians?
The Asians like Newports no, that
was urban. Newport's were for urban.
They would even like, they
were like, this is like racist.
Like the ad was like two beautiful black
people smoking a Newport and they're
like, this is racist. You
know, come up with a race
racist Newport ad, Google that.
It's gotta be one on Youtube,
cigarette racist. Uh, quitting.
Add that that they were playing right
now and people are saying is racist. Uh,
hold on, let me see if I can find
it right here. Right here we go.
Menthol cigarette quitting
at. Oh, I've seen that. Yeah,
that was definitely racist.
But why is it racist to be accurate?
Are we trying to put the black people
don't enjoy a menthol on occasion.
I mean how many black
people like menthols.
That's the sound of Dave cigarette
lighter. Horrible old phone.
He's thinking about firing. Went up again.
It's north Hollywood. Crank that up.
So this is,
we need more than that.
Oh No, no, no, no, no. This is the wrong
one. Yeah, this is the wrong one. They,
oh they knew or at least the new one.
He's the only one.
What? A bunch of jump. Here's the,
I think they originally saw it.
The guy pulls the teeth out. Yeah,
but that's not really racist.
The fact that you ordered menthols.
Okay.
Well if you were going to
say a pack of cigarettes,
you wouldn't just say a pack of smokes
because they would say what kind? Yeah.
So he goes pack of menthols.
It's almost like he has to
and he pulls his tooth out.
It's not enough.
What's the pack of menthols cost you teeth
smoking menthols a regular cigarettes
can cause serious gum disease that
makes you more likely to lose them.
And that was a black guy's voice.
The via, how do you know? No,
he sounded yeah to, you know, I think
I worked with him at the Improv.
I tried to talk to somebody once
and they wouldn't admit that.
You could tell the difference when a black
guys on the phone sometimes there was
this a white liberal woman. She's
like, I'm really don't see that.
I'm going to get the fuck out of
here. You're telling me that you, you,
you can't talk to someone. She
goes, what are you trying to say?
Like she doesn't try to pin it on me and
trying to say that black people don't
talk like word. No. And
that's what I'm trying to say.
I'm trying to say that with an intelligent
articulate person with a law degree
that happens to be black.
Most Times you can tell, wow.
It doesn't mean that
they're not intelligent,
but that's no different than you being
able to tell. If someone's from New York,
are you being able to tell that
someone is from Florida or the south?
That's a real thing.
It doesn't make them less intelligent.
You don't have to pussyfoot around that.
Black people sometimes on the phone
have a different way of talking.
Is that mostly because of reception?
You could tell they have a shitty phone
service. They have a different plan.
He went under the table.
He hit under is under is off the table.
You piece of shit.
No,
that's not what it means at all,
Brian. They have a way of talking.
You know what I'm talking about Brian,
but sometimes there is that there's
basically, there's a situation here.
Jurisdiction is in your court.
You know there's a way,
I mean you're not always right, but
you'd be really freaked out. This is how,
this is the difference.
If you heard a black guy talking and
you thought that he was a white guy and
then you met him and you realize
he was black, you'd be like, wow,
that's kind of interesting.
It's way worse when you talk to a guy on
the phone, you think it's a black guy.
You show up, it's a white guy and you
go, oh Christ, if guy's a fucking idiot,
there's almost always an
idiot on the other end.
If you run into a white guy that's
talking like a black guy on the phone,
like you're convinced you're about to
meet a black guy and it's a white guy,
99% of the time,
that guy's a moron.
But if you're talking to a guy on the
phone and it's a black guy and you know
you don't know it's black guy
because he sounds like a white guy,
he's usually just a regular guy, you
know? It's like nothing wrong with them,
you know? Right. I can
always tell, go with it.
I can always tell a Mexican because they
have that little Mexican twain to him.
When a black,
unless a white dude was raised by black
people sequestered like in a scientific
experiment, they like talk took him
only around black people his whole life.
Then I can understand them talking
like that. Willie Hunter, he,
I know if you remember the
comedian Willie Hunter,
he's been on a few desk squad shows.
He's a perfect example of,
you had him on the phone, you
would think he's white. Yeah.
There's a lot of guys like that. How
about Tyler night? Remember Tyler Knight?
He's, I mean, Yay. So smarty songs
like a white guy, you know, that's,
that's racist, but it's not racist
to just make an observation.
It's like it's saying that's
racist is like saying, you know,
a lot of chicks get more freckles
Irish when they're out in the sun.
That's fucking true.
It's not,
it's not racist to say that Irish people
have a problem with the Sun Pale people
who have a really white skin and
they get burnt really easily.
That's not racist either.
It's an observation,
but I think with accents,
like when we're talking about,
like you could tell the
guys from a certain button,
it's like I'm from Long Island. Like we
used to have this distinct to accent.
I like Boston has this thing and
they said that like these accidents,
now we're starting to like, you know,
homogenized homogenize until like,
I guess this just like, you know,
Mulligan stew of like one bad, you know,
whatever it is. But, uh,
there's very few places now where you can
actually hear like, oh, that's Kentucky.
You know, whenever, you know,
I'd love when I go someplace
and I hear a real accent.
Like I love going to New York and like
the waiter to New York. I'd look you, uh,
this is the menu. Can I introduce
you to our specials? Yes.
That's a real love that I
love New York accent. Yeah.
I love hearing an accent that
I especially probably, cause I
pretty aware that those aren't gonna
be around forever in the future.
A thousand years from now,
it's not gonna be any accents.
Well I can gangs of New York,
you know, when they had like
the different, you know,
cause they were like Irish
but they were in New York.
So like they had to kind of think of
this kind of turn of the century New York
kind of like really, really
down and dirty uh, accent.
So it sounded more like it was, it was
wherever like Ireland then it was there.
But it was cool to hear because
you're thinking like, you know,
when did we really started talking?
Like we talk instead of like the English
talky talk, you know like in England.
So it's like when was the crossover?
Yeah. And what caused the
crossover? Was it just like,
cause all these different languages
were learning English when they got to
America,
that paces like
probably radio, like radio, liquid,
everybody started hearing what
everybody outside of the light.
That's when they started like probably
mimicking it. And then that became like,
because there probably
was a technology thing
you're going to, you know why
you're right. Makes a lot of sense.
Like that's when the accident started
dying down. And then like with TV,
same thing, you know? Yeah.
No Shit. Right. That's
fascinating. But I'm, no, I'm no,
whatever that's called a
scientist or something. But yeah,
I assume it's like when everybody started
really hearing each other like a lot.
Well,
when I heard myself,
I was 19 and I heard myself on
television for the first time.
I realized how gross my accent
sounded. Boston I started, yeah,
I started working on getting rid of it.
I never minded that happened. Oh yeah.
But mine was hard. It wasn't good.
I was a, it was talking about a,
I was interviewed after a tournament
and I was talking about putting in hard
work, rabbit, nick,
listen to myself going,
well, I love all that Boston like a
pattern though. Hey Sweetheart, that's up.
Chappy.
I love Alexa.
Yeah,
there's a lot of e's on the end.
A lot of nicknames is
solely and Fitzy and fucking
wait on.
People suffer places where people suffer.
The senses of humor are
going to be a bit stronger.
It's going to be a bit more character
in the air. You know, if you,
if face adversity in a place
like that New York too, you know,
it gets cold as fuck in the winter,
you know, you faced a lot of adversity.
Yeah. New York though, like a New
York now is very, very international,
very uh, you know, very metro. So you
know, if you hear an accident like that,
that must mean you're paying
money to see it because I,
I've never heard anybody recently with
the Brooklyn, like that's my daughter.
We go to like a restaurant and
like a real town restaurant.
The guy is serving you
has a Brooklyn accent.
No, I, I really liked those
kind of classic, you know,
like the westies Irish mob,
like that kind of stuff. You really
don't hear that much anymore. You know,
like occasionally you'll see a guy that
you knew was like a Westie and you'll be
like, what's up? And I'll have that
like, you know, that cool accent.
Like Colin Quinn consequent has the great,
you know,
and he's like the most intelligent
guy. No, I mean he's just so smart.
He has that cool like that, that thing
too. His voice is like, it's very sexy.
It's very, it's very
good. It's cruise Madec
yeah. Collins a fascinating guy. He's um,
he's a very funny on Twitter to God.
Like,
it's funny when people don't know that
he's just fucking around like joke.
If you know his sense of humor, you
know, it's really funny. But you know,
if you're some 16 year old kid in the
middle of nowhere and you read it,
you're like, lol dumb ass.
That's not even how it works.
He'll say things that are so preposterous.
Did he do look a history show?
Yes. Yeah. One man show. I knew one
woman show. Uh, what, what is it called?
Cause that is, I saw that, I saw that
like over July to July weekend last year.
It was really good. You
know, he's really, really,
really intelligent man and like a I,
that would be great.
That'd be a great thing for him to do.
Like continuously,
just like these really cool high
end woman shows. Long story short.
Now that's, that's the, uh,
that's another thing he did
five minute history lesson.
Does he ever do standup specials?
Yeah.
Um, I, I think so. I know that like,
once again,
like he's been working on this,
like putting a one man show
together is like endless.
So I know he was working on at
workshopping it. Like, like I said,
he would do it in these different clubs
but now it's done and I think he's
touring it and hopefully it'll be,
it'll be sold and like you can
see it on like HBO or something.
Like I don't even know how that works.
Like a one man.
How do you sell a one man show?
I'm,
well it seems like kind of show that you
would want to see all over the country.
Like he get tourist city for a few months
at a time and do it just sort of like,
uh, like the book of Mormon, like that
kind of a thing you'd go to see it.
Cause it's, it's just different
than just pure standup comedy.
Like ultimately like that's like the
perfect kind of thing for like England
where you were talking about like
they expect a show, you know,
that would be like the
perfect kind of thing.
It's about the bill of rights
and it's about like, you know,
our constitution and stuff like that.
And I didn't want to like, I don't,
I definitely do not want to like talk
more about it because I don't really know
exactly, you know? Yeah. It
really is. It's so intricate.
It is taking something that is really
dry and kind of unfunny and really making
it funny and uh, you know, he, he's
just that good at this. I mean,
it really is a great show. He's going
to be in town, uh, in California.
I think he's here now. Yeah. We
should get him on. Where's he at?
And May 1st he's in grass valley, May 2nd
Santa Cruz and May 3rd uh, Irvine. Cal.
Oh well we'll try to get them May 3rd
or around May 3rd. He's the best man.
We were fucking booked up that
week, son. Buck Gun. Yeah, no,
he is.
He's a very underrated standup too.
Like I've heard people say they don't
think he's funny. I'm like, well,
you've never seen him live.
If you've seen them live,
you would know how fucking funny
that guy has his warmups for his show
politically, whatever it was.
Glass, tough crowd. Tough crowd.
You confuse it with politically incorrect.
There was fucking one of the best
warmups I ever saw anybody do ever.
It was him just fucking around with the
crowd doing stand up and then he would
go to do the show. It was like I was
watching, I was like, wow, you know what,
this is the best part of the show.
The best part of the show was him
fucking around with the crowd.
Like that was the funniest part.
Like us sitting down,
these hurried rushed topics would go to,
you know really quickly on the panel
wasn't as good as him doing his little
stick and he a crowd.
He is so good and like his, his, you know,
I don't even want to be smirch about his
crowd work is so like it's so ahead of,
I'd be,
I,
I basically learned how to work route
by watching him at the comedy cellar and
other places that he was so classy and
so intelligent that like it would take
you a minute to get the
reference cause he was so,
he wasn't going for the easy joke.
He would never go for the easy joke and
like he really did take it to a whole
new level.
So he was like,
he was really influential on me and
especially on that kind of stuff.
And he also has like a really,
really, really like master of timing.
Like he really is good at like crafting
a joke and then telling it the right way.
So
you ever heard Jay Morris impression to
him? No. That's uncanny. It's uncanny.
He really uncanny the best impressions
I've ever heard. It's amazing.
Jay's a buddy of mine. He's, his
impressions are incredible that that one,
at least the comp, when one's amazing.
I'm not, the other ones aren't.
But I know of the Collin Quinn one,
it's pretty amazing. It's like,
it's sounds like Collin,
I mean it's like exact,
you should add when Konan comes in and
you should ask him the same thing about
accidents cause he has
like all the good acts.
It's like guys,
they were doing you for awhile.
There was a lot of guys that would like,
I would see guys doing a tell. Right.
It was that flattering
or did that bother you?
I don't know.
People would always tell me,
tell me they were doing me and then I'd
be like, you know, I Kinda, I kinda like,
there's really nothing you can do
about it. I mean, like, you know,
it did help me move forward in comedy
of like, you know, well I better,
I better too. I better get better.
You know? Like if somebody said to me,
but I don't think there's anything like,
I dunno, I was never allowed to like,
hey dog, you're doing my, you know,
get your hands out of my pocket.
Get your hands out of my pocket.
Is that the people that
they're stealing his essence?
You know, it's like you have no respect
for somebody who's doing it, you know,
like they always say it's flattery.
It's like I think it's laziness.
I mean like do your own thing, you
know, it's been a tagine. But you know,
the thing about it is like when you,
when you first start out,
you will like mimic the guy
that you love the most and then,
but you're supposed to move
past that and that's all thing.
It's like you have your
own unique thing you do.
I'm trying to do my own unique
thing and that eventually,
like when you get strong enough then
you got to kind of like say like,
well that's too much like this guy and
that's not like me and I should do this.
But uh, you know, it did
make me go like, you know,
I have a lot of bad habits that I
really need to drop that people are just
mimicking.
No,
they were not bad habits.
No, no. I, I, I do know, like a lot of the
turns that I did like other guys would do,
you know, like my turns, I always
think that there might be things,
but they're probably everybody's turns
into, you know what I'm talking about.
Yeah. For a bit to bit to be the, it
was a style of delivery, you know,
thing you do.
Stan hope does that to me all the time.
I don't do that anymore.
But you know why I would do that because
like when I first started out doing
comedy,
timing is so important of like,
so I was hanging out and now you've got
to, here comes the joke part, you know,
there, you know and like
that was the thing and behind
all that energy was also a
really horrible crowd,
like talking and yelling.
So that's why it's all so like
bang, Bang, Bang, like that. Well
that was the great thing about doing
claws. My special. Yeah. I love,
is that the stress factory? Yeah,
it's a stress fracture in New Jersey.
What a great, that's a great,
yeah, there's is a fee.
He does phone calls from the step,
just like these prank phone calls.
If I was a rich guy,
I would have one of those in my house.
I think Kandi would
come out to make a call.
You call them people right
there? Well, yeah. Say Dave,
I'm calling somebody for a joke.
Yeah.
There was a lot of guys that
were coming up a few years back.
There were imitating you.
It was,
it was kind of annoying because I
would hear it all the time at clubs,
so I was like, oh my God,
this guy's doing to tell.
Like they would be doing
their own material but be
doing it like you and you're
like, oh, come on man, you, it's free.
You develop that in the trenches and
you, you figured out a way to, you know,
to get the point across and have like
a compelling rhythm that's fun to watch
captivates people get some locked in
and someone just came along and gag that
shit.
But I don't think I really do that that
much anymore because like I always felt
like that was hacked, that I was
doing that kind of rhythm. No,
it's cool that you guys
said that, but, but I, I,
I have walked into like a room and I'll
see you guys doing and I'll be like, oh,
I guess he's a fan. You
know, there really is no,
I always feel like I need to get better
and that these other people like that
they're on their own
journey, you know, like,
I guess that's the coolest Zen way to
look at all of this stuff. You know,
they're on their journey.
I'm on my own, you know,
experienced through
comedy and, uh, you know,
hopefully I'll get better and now I'll
look back on that and laugh and I kind of
do now where it's just like,
you know, everybody kind of,
everybody kind of sounds a little bit
the same and then you'll see that one guy
that like stands out and you're like,
wow, you know, we all need to step up, or,
you know, yeah. You, I think
what you're doing like that,
that sort of way of thinking,
it's the most empowering way.
Yeah. Oh yeah. You take control of it.
Yeah. Well it's, you,
you see it for what it is and you move
forward and use it as inspiration instead
of like, there's certain guys that like,
someone will sound like I'm in there.
Like we were talking about Dane
freaking out at uh, uh, he did it.
Steve Byrne and then
he did it for crystal.
Leah told them that they're
stealing his absence.
He said that Chris two pulls him aside.
You're stealing my assets. Really.
I could really do that
to me.
I know guys who I've taken that
on the road and they start to,
they start to mimic like me.
But you hear about people doing
standup all the time. Yeah, absolutely.
He's got a very distinctive
style delivery too. Yeah.
Oh,
the Hedberg Hedberg one always bothered
me the most when I would hear a guy like
Mitch Hedberg cause you know, it's
like, you know, I have a little respect,
especially after he's dead. And
then they'll always go like, yeah,
but I was doing this before.
I was like, I doubt it.
I doubt you were doing this
before Mitch Hedberg. You know,
they'll always like try and cover what
like no, as a baby. I sounded like that.
Yeah, it was cool. It's like, dude,
like now you know like now like you know,
wake up and do your own thing,
but they always like, no man.
You know? Like they'll like, no,
you don't understand what I'm doing.
It's nothing like that. And it's like,
it's exactly like it dude.
Dare her comics. I know it's
very difficult to let a bit go,
especially if that bit works.
Right? Sometimes you'll,
you'll come up with a bid on your own,
horrible and it works,
but then you find out another guy's
doing it. You got to drop that.
You got to look at, you've got to be
able to look at yourself honestly.
And if you sound too much
like Mitch Hedberg, you got
to fucking change that up.
You can't do that. You can't. People are
going to know and then they're going to,
they're going to always look at you is
that is that guy that used to sound like
Mitch Hedberg?
Yeah.
You know like if they dig in their heels
and their and their and it takes about
it.
But,
and then there's the guys who like fake
tribute comics by doing their immature
and they feel like Patrice Patrice. Oh,
I didn't know. I thought it was a trip.
Do they say after caught him on it,
but
I was just like, you know
dude's Oh, you're talking
about the guy on Youtube? Yeah.
That guy. Oh, that guy's a piece of shit.
Yeah. And it was like, you know what,
it's like,
it's one thing to be a fan
and it's another thing to
bit pay tribute to do what
you're doing without,
you know,
like luckily the true comedy
fans were on him and that was,
that was really cool that they did that.
I really made me feel good.
Boss was ridiculous.
It was like sober boasts and overbearing
offensive and didn't own it at all.
I was trying to pretend that the whole
thing was completely innocent and
contribute and you know, and all
aggressive while he's doing it like this.
You've non artists stop
cause I'm not that good.
But I'll tell you one thing about Patrice.
If he had lived more fuck up about
that. God Damn, please hop five.
I got a problem with you man. No,
but I'll just say this, Joe, Patrice,
if he had lived another five years,
people would have actually
gotten what he was doing.
I really do think like he's the guy
who was about to pop. Oh you know,
I just think, I mean he was
great. He got in his own way,
but he still was like that.
Good.
Oh he was hilarious. He had this
great fucking joke about when you,
if you going to be my girlfriend,
you applying for a job and this is the
position that's available to position.
Well let's see what I got here.
I got,
I'm open at 2:00 AM for an hour. You Suck
my Dick and I steal your last Snapple.
Are you interested? Well pitch tablets,
the position, what was the fate of both?
Oh my God, I love that
pit. It's such a funny bit.
Cause there you could almost see
Patrice actually saying that to a chick.
He would not back down. And every,
every comic you've seen now you're like,
what happened to that? Everybody
now is so like, you know, hey man,
it's very like you know,
nonthreatening,
got onstage,
we played it after he died and he got
not on stage whether on television
defending jokes like tea.
There was this woman who was talking
about how horrible a joke was and he was
like, cause you know you ain't coming
from it from the language of funny. Yeah,
that's right. You don't understand funny.
Like it's all comes from the same place.
He was trying to be funny.
Yeah it didn't work out.
But it all comes from the same place.
The ones that are good and that joke all
comes from the same place and like she
couldn't understand it and then
you know, she's like, you know,
and then he did a joke about kicking
a girl, like a pirate style kicker.
And a and coming in her, I just
hopping around on one leg, one eye
and the lady like didn't
want to laugh but he, no,
he said it on TV like kicking her in the
Shinder Jackie late in her eye and then
we were like,
oh my God.
It was the perfect example of something
that's ridiculous and hilarious and you
know, it's violence against woman.
It's, that's a violence joke.
That's a joke about kicking a woman and
coming in her eye and it's still funny.
The angry pirate. Oh he's so
funny man. He was so funny.
So yeah, I do think that
like if he, you know,
like he was probably one more special
away from like people going like, man,
this is crazy cause elephant
in the room is a classic,
I think elephant in the room.
I think there's a lot of guys that
unfortunately they slipped away.
People knowing about them like kicks
became much more famous after he died was
when he was alive.
Yeah,
they used to bother me. Now, it doesn't
bother me at all because I was like,
at least at least people, you
know, at his stuff, his stuff,
like there's so much raw stuff and
then there's the actual like great,
great specialists, you know, so you know,
like people like have been like, you know,
they'll talk about the raw stuff and I'm
like, that's cool. They even like that,
you know, I guess if you're a super
fan and you're like everything,
who's the first guy that you ever saw
that made you go, I want to be a comic.
I want to be a comic. I think
it was listening. Um, you know,
the one, you know, I, I can't think
of like the, I want to be a comic.
If I put the one guy that I did see
that uh, did make me think like,
oh my God, that's what a real
comic is, will be Bill Hicks.
I did see him and I had already been doing
it for a little bit where I was like,
you know, I'm doing the open mics.
I'm trying to get the jokes together.
But then when I saw him do it,
because I already was like,
like one of those fans where you're like,
you know,
you don't even want to make eye contact
with the guy because you're like,
don't want to get into space. You respect
him that much. And I was like, you know,
when I saw him live I was like,
wow, that that is just it man.
He was just throwing away jokes
that like you would, you would,
you would blow a dude for, I mean they
were like, just like, it goes, all right,
let me just air some stuff out
here. No, it's crowd, his crowd,
the way he handled the crowd
also maybe like it was cool
and you probably saw him
when he was sober, right?
Probably. Yeah. I never,
I never in the Texas days,
yeah. The sober days were
when he was really putting
in a lot of work and he was,
he went from a guy who was this wild
drug taking maniacal due to dude who's
really, really focus on
leaving behind a body of work.
Like he would talk about that. It's almost
like he knew his time was coming out,
so he was constantly
writing and it was at the,
he was ahead of the curve
with a lot of ideas.
There's a lot of ideas that he talked
about during the Bush administration,
Bush Sr there during that administration
that's totally relevant today as far as
like jokes about the military and
jokes about, you know, war. And
that was cool that he did that. But
as a comic, that was not my favorite.
My favorite part was when he was
like in the shit handling the crowd.
And then the jokes has his jokes, like
the Letterman jokes that like, you know,
like his first a couple of parents is let
him to judge. You're like, he's Joseph,
just great. And I like, you're like, this
is what it's about. These jokes. Great.
And then, you know, you listen
to, uh, I remember like somebody,
basically we had a tape of his,
I don't even know,
I don't even remember what it was.
And I was like, wow dude, that,
that is just like his smoking jokes.
And I was talking about like his
[inaudible] drugs still blow away.
Everyone else's smoker.
Well those got ripped off too.
Yeah, those jokes got ripped off.
And the uh, the whole like, you know,
I like to play tricks, you know,
the whole thing like a guy and the guy
hits the Pencil. You know that joke,
like the practical joker joke. I don't
remember that. Oh, that's a great one.
Where with the, um, you know,
uh, you know, guy pulls out my,
in high school I was in the class clown,
the guy pulls out my seat,
I fall down every laugh, so I figured
I'd get them back. So like, you know,
I whip a pencil, goes
right in his eye, you know,
he's got an eye patch now and
then another then else happened.
Then this guy where he pulls out the seat,
breaks his back.
So like the two of them walking around,
one of the eyepatch these wheel and the
other guy was like, there he goes to fun.
He got, I'm butchering the joke. That's
what it is. It's like one of his, like,
you know, it's one of his takes on like
a classic, like kind of like, you know,
like mundane topic. And it was just
like seeing that you're like, wow,
this guy really thinks he really thinks
one of my favorite bits was, uh, when
I'm Clarence Thomas was going, uh,
in front of a whatever committee to
get them to Supreme Court and they were
investigating the, uh, the,
the whole, um, remember that?
What was that whole thing where you pubic
hair, cute care and a coke for Anita.
What was her name? Anita Hill.
Right. It's an Etl. Yeah. Yeah.
And he had a whole bit about,
uh,
just it made him realize that he
would never run for office, you know,
cause all the shit they have. I
miss the Hicks. Yeah, I do know.
Did you own clam lap as volumes
one through 90. And I was like,
Whoa, one through 90. I don't recall.
Like you have to listen to the bed.
I'm not doing it doing,
it certainly went into this whole
thing about loving pornography.
It was like a misdirect and they don't
realize like while the misdirect is going
on that he is still in
front of the committee.
Oh well thank you for your opinion
Mr. Hicks. But you have to,
I'm not doing the bit justice.
You've got to listen to it.
I don't know the exact verbage of it,
but it was fucking awesome.
And like his special a, which is the one
where he comes out, he's wearing the hat.
Relentless. I think England. I
thought it was a whatever bay,
Arizona Bang I have just on a bay was
a CD. Is that okay now? I'm sorry.
Where you remember like what
they think goes up again?
That where the hat is fire and
he's in England. I don't remember.
I don't remember. Let's look
it up. But that was a good one.
Yeah. It was like, I was like, you know,
this fits him. This really does fit him,
you know?
Yeah.
I'm talking about,
you know,
theater versus club.
Cause like I also consider him
like a rock hard club clawback.
Well that was when he went to England.
He became way more famous than
he ever recovered him. Yeah.
Cause people here could give a shit.
Yeah, I know, right. It was weird.
Well then you know,
the whole leary thing,
but also Letterman also like his first
couple of appearances on Letterman, like,
you know, I was in college
or something like that. I was
like, wow, this is really,
this guy's amazing,
you know?
Yeah. And his w Denis Leary's
in his Wikipedia page. Ooh.
That's when you know you fucked up.
You wind up in the Hicks Wikipedia
page and not flatteringly.
Uh Oh yeah. What did Daddy, oh, I
remember that contrast revelations. Yeah.
It was revelations. Remember
I saw it live. You did? Yeah.
Leary was my favorite comedian for like
six months. I thought leary was awesome.
Then I saw hex and I was like,
what the fuck is going on here?
Why am I seeing the same jokes?
And then I got all the information for
everybody else and I was like, wow,
that was hard.
That's fine as well.
Especially when I was telling everybody
how great leary was, you know,
very would murder dude.
Oh my God.
Back in those days in Boston
and the Boston area. Yeah. Yeah.
And the Boston Boston days, it
was, you know, it was just a,
it was a sad thing to say.
It's sad when you think of guys just
this genius thinker and then you find out
he's a parrot. You know, it's just taking
somebody else's things towards that,
right? Oh yeah. Yeah. It was brutal.
I mean he's on this Wikipedia page
for a fucking reason, man. You know,
it's not,
it's just no cure for cancer
or word that I don't know. Man.
I don't even really want to talk about
because I've talked about him so many
times and he got angry that I did before.
But Hey man,
it is what it is and he
doesn't want to address it.
But it's a part of comedy history. It
just does. There's no getting around it.
Especially with a guy like, hey, cause
it was just such an innovator man.
He was such a unique style.
And then he was a guy who changed comedy
a lot of ways because he opened up a
whole new door for people.
Kennison did to Kennison opened
up a whole new door comedy.
The Kennison now is,
is the guy that I wish,
I think we talked about this
the last time, when was like,
that's the one guy wish I saw live.
I really do like of all
the people I never saw him.
I really wish I had seen that, that
just that power. Like I would, I would,
I would be the guy like let's call you.
Okay.
Cha and I mean like I wouldn't be, you
know, like if when I would want to see,
oh,
the whole like deal,
like the whole like rough comedy
store show would be the best.
Like before he was famous or something.
Yeah. That would be the
time to see him. The, yeah.
Probably right before he's famous.
I got to see him after he was famous
and just wasn't, was that good?
Was it a stadium show or to act, you
know, like really quickly after his, uh,
after his HBO special who was on the
road, he couldn't do the same jokes. He's,
everybody knew them.
So we had to come up with a whole new act.
And just it's too much party and,
and coke and, but like I've said,
the chickens coming out with
it, the twins. And he would
call people at the end.
Yeah, Paul Guy's girlfriend. You fuck it.
He was a phone on stage.
He was the first comic I ever
saw. Talk about like, you know,
you know party and people, I'm
doing this, I'm doing that,
but I'm doing it for the material. I'm
doing it for you people. All right.
Remember that when I'm balls deep like,
but that was like,
that's the first time I ever heard of
comic actually on stage talking about
writing material because like none of
them ever would talk about that, you know?
And then like finally he was
like the guy who would say it,
even though it was part of his,
his kind of like drug joke.
It was still funny to hear like wow,
he writes material too.
David tell we're out of time. That's
it. We're going to turn into a pumpkin.
We'd been here for three hours. Dude,
thank you so much Robbie. Jo, please.
You're the best and you're
your show a comedy underground.
So what is called comedy underground
Saturday 1:00 AM Saturday, 1:00 AM comedy,
central uncensored, just totally
raw, right, unfiltered, uncensored.
He let you do whatever you want
after midnight on comedy central,
which is fucking amazing. Comedy
central's the new Hbo Comedy Hour Really,
and a lot of ways. Let's hope. Yeah.
Yeah, and dude, best of luck with it.
Will help tweet it. Will pump it up.
Thank you. And Operation Purple guys.
Remember that?
And also my Special Deva told ladies
and gentlemen following my line,
a towel on Twitter,
a t t t e l l
two t's and Improv this
weekend with Allie.
Oh Jesus Christ son that some
of the comedy on the ground.
Time Shave money folks.
Dollar Shave club.com forward slash Rogen.
Thank you to them.
Thanks also to onnit.com o.
N n I t use the code word rogue and
save 10% off any and all supplements.
We'll see dirty bitches at the
Lobero theater. Me With Mad Flavor,
Aka Planet Rock, Aka
Joey Diaz. Junot Diaz.
Jewy Huh? That's going to be
fine. Yeah, that Santa Barbara.
I might escape the Santa Barbara some day.
I can't take Los Angeles anymore.
That's the move. All right.
You fucks. We'll be back. Uh,
tomorrow. Uh, Brian and I are
going to go shoot some shit.
We're going to go shoot some
hard drives and then, uh,
Thursday we're back with Greg Fitzsimmons
and uh, after Greg Fitzsimmons,
we're doing Brian Cowen and Brennan Shop.
We're going to do a UFC wrap up.
All right. Much love to everybody. Thanks
for all the positive energy. Thanks.
Everybody came out and Baltimore,
we had a great fucking time. It was,
it was an amazing show. An awesome
audience. All right. You guys are shit.
We love you big kiss. I'm,
I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, Huh?
Okay.