The general experience.
Yeah.
That's the problem.
Those guys aren't woke once.
Everyone's all woke.
It'll be great.
It's a dangerous word to use.
I feel like people got to mock it in the
future.
Woke woke.
Yeah.
I felt like using woke now like
unironically super slippery.
I see a trap coming.
You do.
The jujitsu practitioner in me is like,
I don't like this move.
This is a.
I know where this leads.
That's how I feel.
I see that woke thing.
I'm like,
what are you woke?
What the fuck does that even mean?
I don't look up.
You woke up.
What do you 12?
Well,
it comes from my 16 year old,
so yeah,
it's kids today.
But what does it mean?
It means your brain is open.
You're open to stuff.
The problem is there's no real
quantification.
There's no real.
There's no test you take to show that if
you're woke.
Right?
Right.
Like if you want to be a mathematician,
you have the fucking show that you know
how to do math.
The professor said,
check your work.
Like you get through like,
yes,
congratulations Tom.
Papa.
You are a mathematician.
Phd In mathematics,
it says right here on the paper and
you're like,
God damn it,
I'm going to put this shit on my walls.
You understand?
I know how this stuff works.
Yeah,
but wokeness,
anybody can claim to be a master of
wokeness.
It's like Kung Fu without fighting.
It's very dangerous.
Yeah.
No one's defined what's woke and what's
preposterous.
No one's defined what's,
what's just not racist and sexist and
not homophobic,
but open minded and aware of the,
the,
the failings and the misgivings of all
sides of us and with no bias.
Right.
Is that.
Well,
because it doesn't seem like it is.
Isn't that woke?
I don't know.
I don't think so.
I think you just described what I
thought it was.
I would like that,
but too many people could jump in.
There's no.
There's no real clear understanding of
like what makes an constitutes someone
being woke like.
Yeah.
How many of those boxes do you have to
check where it was like,
stop Tom.
Papa had a woke academy and you took
these people.
It would just mean to you like bread or
bread claiming wokeness super slippery.
What's his Jamie?
62 New York Times magazine or
crazy gotta.
Dig It.
Look,
if you're woke,
you dig it.
Almost the perfect definition right
there.
If you're woke,
you dig it.
That is insane.
That was my fox man.
And you were copying my taste and grit.
Don't jump salty on me.
Whoa.
Look how they talked back then they were
trying to talk people into talking the
way that made them seem more
interesting.
I'm going to say it the way I would say
that if I lived back then.
Hey,
make it bigger so I can see why you'd be
the guy on the left.
Jamie.
No,
no,
no.
Scrolling.
So we could read the comments.
What he's saying.
Up Top.
Yeah.
Okay.
That was,
that was my facts man.
And you were coding grace and grit.
So how would you say that now?
That was my fox man.
Maybe cop in my taste.
And of course it's girl on girl.
And you're saying no,
that's what they said.
Oh,
would you use.
What words would you use today?
Yeah.
He would say the fuck he doing with my
girlfriend.
Dickhead.
And he said,
don't jump salty on me.
I would say,
hey,
we're cool.
No worries,
no worries.
Stop being such a bitch.
It's all good.
Yeah.
And then it'd be like,
what?
Someone's a bitch.
And then next thing you know,
people will be hitting each other.
That's the darkest snowman.
I think what you're saying is one very
important point that we need to move
past the military gatekeepers of tech.
No
big tech which are at advertising
agencies in social media,
the things that are constantly
predicting your next purchase,
right?
Yeah.
Because if you think,
if you think about it,
and I'm in even in a semi democracy look
like we have in the US,
I mean those who control the
brainwashing of the public in essence
control who votes for what and who
controls the brainwashing of the public
is advertising agencies and who
increasingly are the biggest advertising
agencies are,
are the big tech companies who are
accumulating everybody's data and using
it to,
to program their minds to buy things.
So this is what's programmed the global
brain of,
of,
of the human race.
And of course there are close links
between big tech and the military.
Let's look at.
Amazon has $25,000 person headquarters
in Crystal City,
Virginia right next to the Pentagon.
And in China it's even more direct and
unapologetic.
Right?
So it's a new military industrial
advertising complex,
which is guiding the evolution of the
global brain on the planet,
which that with this past election,
right,
with all the intrusion by foreign
entities trying to influence the
election that they've,
these giant houses set up to write bad
stories about whoever they don't want to
be in office.
Yeah.
In a way that's almost a red herring,
but it,
I mean the Russian stuff is almost a red
herring.
But it revealed what the processes are,
which,
which are used to program.
Oh,
because I think the whatever programming
of the American's minds is done by the
Russians is minuscule compared to the
programming of Americans' minds by the
American American corporate and
government elite.
Not that anybody's even jumping in as
well as African elite.
So my dad,
my dad dance limbo,
right?
My Dad was the baddest limbo dance on
the planet.
Really.
And he did some crazy,
crazy stuff.
You might need to try it again.
It didn't.
I think.
Oh,
probably when I closed my phone.
Okay.
There we go.
Waiting for Jamie to grab it and I'll
leave it open.
I'm no,
my dad used to dance limbo and I'm limos
when you go onto the stick.
Yes.
And um,
he,
I don't wanna I don't to ruin it.
Right.
But he was the best jokes from like 88,
like the year before he died.
Wow.
Yeah.
So like,
I dunno,
it just reminds me of some of the thing
and my family.
Anytime I did something that I thought
was cool,
they would just be like,
yeah,
like,
so wait,
your dad,
your dad would do that was like,
fuck,
like I could never get out of his
shadow,
but this is your dad.
That's my dad.
Oh,
shit was fire.
Yeah.
Damn,
how the fuck is he doing that?
That is insane.
That's insane.
Yeah.
He did this for like tons of.
If you did it from everybody wanted to
see him do this.
He did it in front of Mandela.
Did in front of the queen know if he's
going to go under it there.
Yeah.
But it gets better than this whole lot.
Do you eat the fuck is he doing that?
You don't.
Kind of.
Core strength.
That takes blown far.
But this right here now this is where it
gets ridiculous.
This is like,
I see this and I'm like,
yeah,
that's my dad.
Like he's going to go what?
So this is on fire folks in this.
This thing is I'm not bullshitting.
And he's got to flaming pizzas in his
hand and he's like that.
That might be what?
13,
14 inches off the ground and he's going
under it.
That's insane.
And he spit and fire while he's doing
it.
Holy Shit.
You weren't joking?
No,
my dad was a bad ass.
That's crazy.
How crazy they are looking at this old
vhs footage digitized.
It's not that long ago,
man.
No,
and that's a different world and that,
that,
that kind of thing.
My Dad Kinda.
I mean I was always with.
I used to love being with him.
You know,
he's like my best friend.
I remember I was telling my son this
story about him,
so I had this thing with my kid and I'm
recording this conversation with me and
my son and I'm like,
what would you do if you go back in
time?
And he's like,
what?
I was like,
if you had a time machine you can go
anywhere,
where would you go?
He's like,
I don't know,
the 19 hundreds.
And I'm like,
I grew up in the 1900,
what are you talking about?
Like last week.
And then I told him the story.
I was like,
yeah,
remember I was little.
My Dad used to,
I used to bring you on stage to do that.
I was like four or five years old.
No,
I was like four years old and he would
pick me up and carried me under the,
under the bar.
Right.
And one time he brings me on stage.
He's like,
this is my son.
And he presents me in the spotlight's on
me and I'm shy.
And I'm like,
oh.
And he was kind of disappointed,
really disappointed me that day.
And then,
um,
a couple of weeks later I was with him
again.
He's like,
I was like,
Daddy,
you bring it back on stage and he brings
me on stage and um,
he's about to pick me up and I'm like,
I could walk away and I go back to my
seat.
I did.
He loved it.
You know what I told my son that story.
My Dad was like,
he people afterwards,
we walked through the hotel to go back
and he has me on his shoulders and he's
just so proud.
He's like,
you see my boy and he's like,
you know,
I told my son about that and my son was
like,
it was like 40 minutes later in the
conversation and my son is like that.
If I had a time machine,
I'd go back and hang out with you when
your dad was like,
that was like,
that was like the best moment of my
life.
Message it.
That's done.
You examine your fucking brain and that
takes some hard work and suffering.
If you're not really do that.
I'm sorry.
And it seems like there's no way to do
that as a bystander.
You can't watch it,
man.
You got to get out there and like,
oh,
this hurts,
this hurts real fucking bad.
I don't think this is smart.
And then guess what happens?
The body will just,
it will adjust if it goes well.
Then the next question again,
but time when it doesn't adjust to I
guess some of the stupidest shit man,
like don't,
don't take with a grain of fucking salt
people.
Those questions that people that are
wanting to quit.
Yes.
And that's what I say.
When should I quit that?
God.
Did you ever like feel like no,
shut the fuck up.
Stop.
I don't want to like that.
There's always that next question.
No,
don't take it.
Like go out there and run through a
brick wall.
So many times you can.
No,
I'm not saying be me.
Don't run towards you.
And five miles at one time.
I'm not saying do that.
I'm saying start to learn.
The mind is powerful.
It's powerful,
man.
It's unbelievable.
But people need,
they need a thing to get them going.
Right?
They need a thing,
right?
I need a goal.
They need.
They need A.
I'm like,
it's sometimes the first step is the
hardest.
It's hard to take that 1 million,
step two,
but sometimes the first step is the Mo
is something about the,
what do I do?
They start going over their phone and
start calling people.
They don't get out of the house and
there's something about procrastination.
So like,
you know,
it's painful.
You know you should be doing things,
but you just keep doing it.
You keep itching that
I procrastinate like a motherfucker man.
Every day I want to do this shit.
That's what's so funny,
man.
People looking like on some damn
superhero that came down from the Gods,
from the heavens and earth.
No Man,
I don't want to do this shit.
I'm looking at my shoes for 30 minutes.
Sometimes they can fuck man.
People.
People look up to your Goggins fucked
him.
I'm like,
Oh,
do this shit man.
What do you do it?
I'm going to do it as long as you do it
and that's what I know about it.
That's why I stopped doing it.
I'm thinking,
Oh man,
you gonna fucking sit here and you look
at your shoes for 30,
40 minutes.
You Go,
you gotta think about all day long you
go do it anyway.
And sometimes you don't have the time to
look issues for 30 minutes.
Those are the,
those are the beautiful days.
Yes.
It's,
you know,
you just have to go.
That's right.
And so like there's no room for
procrastination and that's when I,
when I was in the military,
I love my because I knew it'd be work at
7:00.
So you got to get your ass up at 4:00.
Marissa get your shit in brother,
because I had to get my shit and before
I got my shit in know.
So that was my mentality back then.
Manual.
Like I,
I had to get the miles and get
everything in man and,
and get to work.
Man.
I'm a competing with the Alpha males.