Greetings, ladies and gentlemen and people
who consider yourself neither. Folks,
it's them's that we live in strange times.
Sometimes people don't want to be
defined by a gender or anything.
They're in it and I support
that. You go it, you go,
girl, you go, boy, you go,
whatever the fuck you want to be.
You go furries.
You go mascots.
This episode is brought
to you by legal zoom.
Legal Zoom is a website that allows you
to take care of many of your legal needs
without leaving your home.
Legal.
zoom.com has been helping
America's America's Americans
get personalized wills,
powers of attorney living
trust for over 10 years.
They have an a plus from
the better business bureau.
That is a fantastic recommendation
right there. You can get an LLC,
you can start a corporation, trademarks,
real estate documents, and more.
The service was developed by some of
the best legal minds in the country,
allegedly. I don't know if that's true.
You should fucking allegedly that.
I don't know who the best
start that they have a contest.
Is there a gold medal and legal minds?
Excellent legal minds. How about that?
Awesome legal minds that you can trust
and they make it painless for you to get
the best legal protection that you can
get without ever leaving your home,
which is the beautiful thing about it.
You can do it all through legal zoom and
take care of so many different things.
Start a business,
you know,
form your own LLC and a legal zoom
also will connect you to a third party
attorney if the whole process
becomes confusing and you're saying,
I don't know if what I'm doing is legal.
Legal Zoom will connect you to an
independent attorney. It's not a law firm,
but they can provide you with self
help services that will make your life
infinitely easier.
You don't have to make an appointment,
you don't have to go anywhere,
you don't have to pay someone
some ridiculous amount of money.
You can form an LLC starting at 99 bucks.
Boom,
POW will never leave your house. Do it all
drunk and naked. No one could stop you.
And for special savings at checkout and
to the Codeword Rogan in the referral
box at checkout.
That's legal zoom.com and use the code
word Rogan legal zoom is how Brian
started the desk squad podcast network.
It's how he incorporated his how
on it was originally incorporated.
I know many people that have used
legal zoom. It is an excellent service.
It's very easy to use and you could
even get divorced and legal zoom.
I don't think it's likely you know much.
It's probably going to
take a lot more than that.
If you've caught yourself in the legal
entanglement in the quagmire and the
octopus has tentacles that is divorced,
but for most things,
legal zoom can handle it. Go there,
check it out. You will enjoy it.
Legal zoom.com and then use the codeword
Rogan in the referral box at checkout
and I can't,
I can't recommend them enough,
especially with that a plus
from the better business bureau.
It's a fantastic legalzoom.com
use the code word Rogan. We only
have one sponsor today. Why?
Fuck around. It's cube's music.
Jamie. Stefan Molyneux is here.
Experience,
gentlemen from the dark north of Canada,
the white north enjoying
the fabulous sun here. Well,
it's sunny where you are too now, right?
That's all right. Staggeringly beautiful,
beautiful in the summertime is fantastic.
She is a seductive bitch into
summer Canada. She really
is. She's like, hey come.
No problem. Yeah, come on. Set up a
house, built some stuff, couple of bugs,
no biggie. And then Bam, ice vista snow
around your hot for all the tenants. Yeah.
I have friends that live several
hours north of Edmonton. Oh yeah.
Oh. And uh, I visited them in the spring
and it's fantastic. It's just called.
Okay. I just green and the
walleyes fishing is absolutely how,
how do you end up living a few hours?
Like did they disturb them?
I mean to me that they get cursed in
some horrifying way. But what happened?
That's a good question there from there.
Oh, they streck dodging villagers.
They're really nice folks. Wow. Um,
and uh, they're, they're from there.
My friend Johnny Rivet
and Janny Rivet and uh,
they actually run a hunting camp up there.
So they do a lot of their business
up in the, in the bush, as they say,
Canadian Bush, but it's so beautiful up
there in the spring and summer. Oh yeah,
it's fantastic. And for, you know, for
a little bit in the winter, you know,
pretty sparkly and then after awhile it
just becomes this ice dungeon and you're
like, chew your way out like a
Ferritin, an upturned aquarium. Yeah.
That's how you really would
not good for your health,
like your mental health at least to be
trapped in those environments. But what,
you know, so after, uh, after
high school I wanted to,
college had broke and I got a job as a
gold pan or a prospect or I spent about
18 months, like fly in camps, uh,
looking for debt, getting soil samples,
looking for gold and stuff like that.
And Yeah, you're in a tent for, you know,
four or five months with the same people.
And I, they were smokers too,
so I basically, it was like
this little co, you know,
I'm up north, it's so clear.
It's so pristine. I was a
little tent sale, tent sites,
cube of smoke for six months.
I think it's going to have permanent
health effects even now. Yeah.
That is one of the weird things about
smokers is that they're more than willing
to impose that on other people. That's
a strange thing that they don't find.
Like it would bother me if I was a
smoker and I was sitting in a box with
somebody and just
subjecting them to my toxin.
I know it's minus 40
but c'mon step outside.
I mean how often do you go to
a pool party and say, you know,
I don't feel like going inside to
pee so I'm just going to let it go.
You know what I mean?
There's no non piece side to that pool
and there's no nonsmoking side to a
restaurant anyway. Yeah. Smoking.
And the other thing about smokers is
there's a lot of them that don't have any
problem with littering and I think it
has something to do with the fact that
they're their
fucking,
their body up.
So this is like cognitive dissonance
of like there's something involved in,
like you have to have a separation of
clarity. If you're willing to, you,
it's your will. You're
lighting the cigarette, you're
putting it up to your lips,
you're sucking in poison.
And they,
so many of them throw their cigarettes
on the ground. So many of them,
and I really think there's a connection
because it's very rare that you see
someone drink a soda and then
throw the cat on the ground.
But I in front of people,
you'll see someone take a
cigarette, throw the ground,
step on it, and just walk away. Like
as if it's out of sight, out of mind.
I think it has a direct connection
to this, this connection.
You could test that, you know,
you, you could go to like
the healthiest food store,
like up the street, there's this, a
Vegan, uh, sit down food store, whatever.
You get a cafe,
Vegan cafe.
It'd be interesting to see if people come
out of that with the Care Kale shakes
and just throw crap on the ground.
I bet you that almost nobody would.
But you know you're hanging outside some,
you know skeevy pool hall with a bunch
of smokers and it's all that her out
front. Yeah. Your body is the world
is all that kind of stuff. I think.
Yeah.
It's like the one thing where like it's
really common to litter with like that's
the like if you like if you have like
survey says if you were on family feud,
most common thing to litter,
I'm on doing the old dude who's dead.
Meanwhile it's been like five guys.
Richard Dawson, Dawson Hogan's heroes,
remember? Yeah. But now it's Steve
Harvey. Yeah. It's not the same. But yeah,
I would think that that would be like the
number one thing. It's like cigarettes.
So you were stuck in this tent with these
dudes and they didn't have any problem
smoking in front of you in a tent
just nonstop. And they were
like, they weren't even like,
like they would like light cigarettes
off the previous cigarette.
Like I think they,
the kind of smokers who
other than sleeping had not
had a breath of fresh air in
about 10 years.
Like they hadn't had anything coming
into their lungs that wasn't tar based.
And I said,
I know one of them's dead now and uh,
I'm not sure where the other one is,
but uh,
yeah, that's, if you were an alien
and you were studying human behavior,
cigarettes would be one
of the weirdest ones.
One of the weirdest things
you'd have to pay attention to.
Like how the fuck did that
take root on so many people?
Oh, it's a, it's a,
it's a legitimate payback for the like
smallpox laced blankets that the early
settlers gave the Indian.
It's like, okay, fine.
Yt you can give us a TB lice
blankets here, smoke this.
And like, Ooh, that's good.
Well let's get a wipe out
more of us than a view.
But it'll take time and it'll
go with a smile on her face.
Well, I'm wondering, I don't think
they use tobacco in the same way.
I think most native
tribes that use tobacco,
they use it like a cigar or like
a pipe or they're not inhaling it.
They just get it into their mouth.
And when you get into your mouth,
it gets into your bloodstream,
you get the nicotine. Okay.
That's why you can get cancer
from cigars when it's more rare.
Even people that are like really branding
Freud in cancer cause he like,
he had like 20 cigars a day and he got,
I think half is cheeky in a
way with cancer and stuff like
to what's going on in his life.
Yeah.
A lot of the chewers get that to those
people that keep that stuff like in
between their lip
and gum. Weird evidence.
Yeah. But, uh, it's,
it's not that common with pipe smokers,
pipe smokers.
That's the original way to do it. You just
sort of take in the nicotine. In fact,
nicotine is like a part of a, a lot
of psychedelic rituals in the Amazon.
They below nicotine smoke that blowed
tobacco smoke on the people that are going
through these psychedelic rituals. Yeah.
Yeah. I don't know. For whatever reason,
I don't know how the fuck we got on
this stuff, but, so, uh, I was on,
uh, Ana Kasparian show your, you're good
buddy. You're good friends. Yesterday.
And we had,
we had some interesting conversations
and part of it was about you and um,
and I appreciate that. I know you
were talking just before the show.
I don't care what you say about me.
Just make sure you spell my name right.
Well that's what I was telling her
in a way. I was saying, you know,
she was getting upset,
you know,
the things that you had said about
what she had said and I said,
well you got to lick.
This is a weird thing that goes on
where people make these sort of call out
videos.
You know,
everybody likes to do a call out video
but nobody likes to call out video turned
on them.
And what Anna did is essentially she
listened to Adam Carolla's rant about
conservatism and she made a rant about
that and then you made a rant about her
rant and then she's pissed a, your
rant about her rant about Adam's rant.
And I'm like,
first of all,
this is like incredibly ineffective
way to communicate. You know,
when people like I, I, it's one of the
things that I don't like about blogs.
I think blog entries are
great in some ways, uh,
because I think it gives someone to,
uh,
an opportunity to really
expand on their thoughts.
And you can put a lot of energy and
effort into writing something down.
Whereas I think you might be able to get
into deeper detail than you would in a
conversation where you perhaps searching
for words or trying to clarify the
position.
A lot of things you need to look up and
you can't do that and necessarily in a
debate. So it's nice having a back and
forth debt when it's database, sorry,
go ahead. But it's a massive amount
of time involved and it's, it's,
it doesn't give the other person the
opportunity to respond. And when you,
you do it,
like one person goes on this long rant
describing you in very disparaging terms
and you know, minimize is
you, and then, you know,
you have to respond to that and then
you go that it's way better to just sit
down and talk through ideas. So
there's a lot of these ideas that, um,
you have said that are very controversial
that we're going to give you
opportunities. He's no way. I know,
it's crazy. And to be fair, I mean, um,
I was working on the flight down,
I was working on a response.
I was hoping to go in and talk to them.
We,
we knew we needed them and emailed them
and said maybe we could go and have a
debate. I think that would be
interesting and fun and useful,
very important issues that
are being talked about. But,
um, we didn't hit a bank,
so, yeah. Well, you probably pissed
her off, you know, that's what,
that's what I mean, if you're not
annoyed, it's not a good debate.
That means it's not that important. Right.
I guess. Yeah. I guess, um, the, the, the,
the core of the conversation was Adam's
position on being a conservative and how
the term has become
a pejorative and then the term
conservative is become a negative way of
describing a person's behavior
and a person's thoughts.
It's more like,
it seems that it's become,
um,
uh,
maybe like a badge of callousness or
a descriptive term of someone who's
insensitive or who does not
care about the underclass.
It does not care about poverty, does not
care about poor people. And you know,
she had this take on it and then
you had to take on her take on it.
Um, uh, you, can you consider
yourself conservative?
You consider yourself a libertarian,
right? I'm an anarchist. An anarchist.
And what is that exactly,
exactly. Well, I mean, so,
and I was resistant anarchist.
Like for me, I was 20 years,
what's called like a mineral cast.
It came sort of out of the
objectivist iron ran school, uh,
where your government is basically
law and national defense.
Maybe a court system, maybe that's
sort of tiny, tiny government.
It's called the night watchman
state, which is, you know, keep,
keep other people's Mitsoff my staff and
keep their shifts out of my kidney kind
of thing. That's, that's
the basic function of
government. And I was like, ah,
but it always bothered me because that's,
that would still have to be
funded through taxation, right?
Taxation philosophically, morally
is the initiation of force, right?
I mean it's like I have a good idea.
You have to pay for it and
if you don't pay for it,
you are going to get some letters.
And if you don't pay for it still we're
going to send some people over to your
house and blue costumes. And if
you don't pay for, it's still,
they're going to take you off to jail.
And so it is the initiation of force.
And that always bothered me.
And uh,
I guess it was about a
2006, uh, I just, um,
I just gave up the ghost as
far as that goes. If you like,
nobody wants to go with these particular
directions. It's just principles, right?
You have to sort of hang on your
principles no matter what, right?
So if you're into the non initiation of
force, right? That, that self defense,
perfectly moral,
legitimate,
but you can't go around pop and people
in the head without provocation,
you can't go around
stealing people's stuff.
So the non initiation of force and if
you accept that as a principal and if you
try to get philosophy as close to like
the physical sciences, physical sciences,
they don't have exceptions, you know,
they say, well, this Rockwell, but we'll,
we'll fall this fast in,
in know Kazakhstan and this
fast in Philadelphia, I
mean this universal, right?
So if you're going to go with
the nonaggression principle,
then the concept of government,
it's um,
morally illegitimate because the
government is that group of people in a
geographical area that initiate
the use of force against others.
And some, some people agree
with it and some people don't,
but those who don't, uh,
do end up being on the receiving end
to force that they don't agree with it.
So in an anarchist state,
the,
the idea would be that
there would be no taxes.
So how would people fund roads?
Would they voluntarily donate?
How would they fund education? How
would, how would things get done?
Well. Um, the first answer is I
have no idea if I, because I mean,
if you could design a future,
then everyone should put me in
charge of everything and right.
That wouldn't make any sense. People
build roads, government don't build roads.
Right? And, and it's not, there's
no entity called government.
It's like this big a morphous flag
that goes around and lays the tarmac.
It's just people who receive money.
So I mean,
if you're going to build a bunch of
houses, you have to build a road there.
I mean, I mean, malls build parking lots,
a air, air, airport spray, build roads.
It's not government, it's
all private. And you know,
I in a gps you could charge people,
you know,
there's a private highway
up in Canada way, you know,
they take a photo of your license
plate or if you have a transponder,
it's even cheaper. And they just judge
you when you go on. And however, you know,
when you go off, then they charge you for
that. So isn't that taxing you? Well, no,
because that's volunteering
for use. Well, it's volunteering. You can
use it, but if you have to get over there,
is there other options without paying?
Sure.
Those are these other roads that mean
because that will be competition, right?
I mean hopefully,
well not to the point of wasteful
duplication because that would not be very
efficient economically.
And if there's a hundred rows
going to the exact same direction,
I'll say my side one costs
a dollar a lot competition.
I haven't seen a tree in
four days or I'd be like,
you know the movie Brazil where they have
those billboards maybe on either side.
So I think you pretty open in the
idea that you don't have a solution,
but what you're doing is saying that
the current problem is unacceptable.
Is that a fair way of assessing
your, your take on current? Yeah.
I mean technically it's not good
philosophy to have a universal caught the
nonaggression principle.
But you and I and this fine fellow here
in the listeners, we all accept, right?
We all here voluntarily. You don't
force anyone to come to your shows.
I didn't force anyone
to listen to what I do.
So we all accept that at a personal level.
And that's what we teach our kids,
right? Yeah. Don't hit, don't take
other people's stuff. Don't push.
Do you know that kind of stuff.
And so if we're going to have these rules,
you know, much like science, like
how far can we push these rules?
Now I think that it's kind of wrong
to say, well, we have these rules,
but right up to here will completely
abandon them and go to the opposite. Um,
or at least we need to acknowledge
that it's what's going on in society.
So if we say that the nonaggression
principle is the way that we should live,
well the government is just people.
How do they get this?
Get Out of jail free card where they can
do stuff that is specifically illegal
for the private citizens,
like print money,
like take out debts on behalf of other
people and you and I can't do that.
I can't go buy a car and send you the
bill. And they can invade countries.
They can force people to pay for things
so they can incarcerate huge numbers of
people. Largely on a whim. They can tell
people who are doing things like drugs,
which is a purely voluntary form
of enjoyment and stuff. Medication,
they can throw them in jail. I
can't do that. You can't do that.
If I'm on a pay for my kids' education,
I don't get to walk up and down the
street with a machete saying pay or die.
I mean, but this is the way
that we've set up or the wave.
You've inherited society. Sorry, I
don't want to go on to big Aranda. No,
but it's a good rent.
It's a good point as well.
The idea that it's society has
been sort of inherited, you know,
that we have sort of been born into
this system that is really not that well
engineered and has massive flaws in
it. And uh, it's a very good point.
When you talk about the
reinforce the um, uh, the,
the taxes,
like enforcing tax laws that you can
lock people in jail for owing money.
It's one of the only times where someone
gets locked in a cage because they owe
money even if you choose
to pay that money. Yeah.
Wesley snipes is a perfect example.
The actor chose to not pay his
taxes based on an erroneous belief.
He had this belief that
the constitution does not,
does not force you to pay taxes and
that it's a misunderstanding that if you
fight it in court, you would, when
he had these terrible advisors.
So he decided to not pay taxes for a long
time and he made a really large sum of
money.
And that is when they go after you,
when you're one of those people
that is already the privileged few,
making an exorbitant amount of money and
then you step up and say you don't have
to pay taxes and you do it blatantly
didn't even matter if he tried to pay the
money back,
they were going to lock him in jail
no matter what it felt like this is,
it's not, it's a crime and it's the only
time it's a crime to owe money. You know,
every other time it's like we
have a debt and you know what,
you have to pay that debt off. Like, say,
if I loaned you 100 bucks and we went to
court and the court found out that you
didn't pay me that a hundred bucks,
you don't go to jail,
you just have to pay me 100 bucks.
But if you're the government 100 bucks,
they have the option
to lock you in a cage.
And that to me is sort of akin to
shitty parenting. You know, like you're,
you're a, a strong believer in, uh,
not hitting kids and
not screaming at them.
And if you're tired and you're dumb
and your kid doesn't want to listen,
one of the best ways to get them to
listen to you is violent force or fear.
Those are the best ways. And it's, uh,
it's been a huge problem throughout.
You know, it's, it's, as far
as recorded history, I mean,
people have been beating their kids.
People have been yelling at their kids,
people who've actually even defended it.
You know?
And I think that this lazy use of force
is very similar to what the government
does. It's almost like they
feel like their hands are tied.
There's 350 million people
they have to get money from.
What's the best way to do it? Scare
the fuck out of him. The block,
that actor in jail, that Wesley
Snipes, he put him in a cage.
Make an example out of him and
anybody else that steps out of line,
lock them in cage too.
Lauren Hill to Lauren Hill,
the food just solo artist.
Fantastic singer and yeah,
she's serenading like
James Brown and the in the,
and the echoing holes of
the incarceration station
talks about that either she didn't never
heard anybody, she didn't do anything.
She's got some wacky ideas I've
ever heard that broad talk.
Ooh,
well if you're pretty and talented,
sometimes people don't step up to say.
But the other thing too is that there
are things that I find extremely morally
objectionable, like, like at a skin
crawling, visceral base of the spine,
the electrification kind of feeling like,
I hate the imperialism of a
lot of the western countries,
particularly in America right there,
the invasions of Iraq and, and all that.
I just, I find that stuff unbelievably
reprehensible. And as you can see,
the entire society has disintegrated.
Now. I hate the war on drugs.
I really, I mean at a very
fundamental level, I think, um,
it is absolutely abhorrent and
destructive. You know, we saw some of the,
I think the shake out of that
and Ferguson, Missouri recently,
which I think a war on drugs
had a lot to do with that stuff.
And the fact that I'm forced to,
to fund this,
it goes violently against my
conscience and I feel very helpless to,
um,
to,
to not support the things that I find
incredibly objectionable and incredibly
destructive, uh, to, uh, to particularly
minorities is unbelievably horrendous.
And I'd like to have the right to say no,
I really would like to have the right
to say no to that kind of stuff.
There's lots,
I mean,
I do charitable work and I give away
my shows for free and I'm very happy to
share whatever goodies I've accumulated
in life with people who are less
fortunate or needy.
But there's so much that goes on in the
world that governments do that I find
just so horrendous.
And I would really like none of
the above as one of the options.
Yeah. None of the above. But how
do these things get funded then?
How would they fund war? How would they
fund, you know, that would be very tricky.
They would have to get creative. Yeah.
I was listening to hardcore history.
You ever listen to hardcore history,
Dan Collins? Yeah. Oh yeah, yeah.
We've done some shows together. Yeah,
he's fantastic show. I really love it.
And he's got a new episode and it's about
World War One and it goes into great
detail about the massive
losses that were just,
just racking the French forces and the
the German artillery and all this shit
that was going on and how it was becoming
increasingly difficult to get people
to sign up for the war,
especially with English.
The English folks trying
to get them to sign up,
like had gotten to the point
where he had lost 500,000 people,
500,000 casualties in a short
period of time. And you know it,
it gets to that point where
people aren't buying it anymore.
Like in the beginning it was easy to
sort of coerce people into doing it by,
he was actually going into depth about
people with shame. People like women,
like pretty white feathers. Yeah, yeah.
They would put a white feather
on you if you weren't in uniform.
If you weren't a military person,
you weren't,
you were a coward and you were
considered to be a coward.
And it was so much so that they had
to kind of figure out a way not to,
because there were many people that are
involved in the war effort that weren't
soldiers,
that people that were building munitions
and people that were making guns and
people that were involved in all sorts
of different levels of government that
weren't cowards in their eyes.
But you know,
they were getting attack the
same way everybody else was.
It was sort of like a feeding frenzy and
it's, it's, it's interesting to see, uh,
especially when you're talking about the
early 19 hundreds of the essentially a
hundred years ago,
the talking about this,
the use of manipulation of trying
to get people to go along with war,
especially back then when there was so
much less information available to the
average person,
whereas today,
trying to get someone to go along
with wars far more difficult,
far more problematic.
Well, and this is terrible, um, power
that the government has to money at will,
which
the first World War Lashley and gendered
in the first World War could not have
been fought on the gold reserves
that the country has had at the time.
It would have been over
in six to 12 months.
And so right now they can just create
this money out of thin air. Right.
So I mean the, the war in Iraq
did not come with equivalent.
The war on terror did not
come with equivalent massive
tax increases to pay for
it cause they just printed all this
money and this messed up the economy.
It was inefficient contribution to the
housing crash and all of the mass that's
gone ever since then. And
so for me, it's like, well,
wouldn't this weight make war more
difficult if you had sort of privatized a
defense systems? It's like, yes, yes,
yes. That's what we want. Let's make more,
more difficult to, to embark on and
pursue and make sure that it's defensive.
Aggressive was a very expensive defensive
wards are relatively cheap. I mean,
look at what defeated in a sense,
the American military in Iraq,
I mean,
what was the cost?
How much did America spend versus how
much did the people defending themselves
spent a look at, uh, a Vietnam,
what people were defending themselves and
around the inceptions essentially as a
blood bath though, but, and just,
I'm terms of dollar cost, right?
So you can bring down a $20 million plane,
but the $20,000 Stinger missile
attacking is very expensive.
Defending is very cheap. But look at how
poor a job they did a defending, I mean,
a million civilians were wiped out.
Their entire country was
essentially taken over.
The only reason why they don't the United
States is now full power of Iraq is
because that was never the
objective in the first place.
And because we abandoned
it and pulled out, right,
I mean their defense of the military,
the United States military
was woefully ineffective.
So like saying that it's inexpensive,
it's kind of silly. I don't know.
I just want to 10 credibly in effective.
Well,
but the goal again is a stated goal of
the leaders of al Qaeda was to provoke
America into the same kind of war that
Russia got into in Afghanistan that broke
the Russian economy and
collapsed their empire.
It was to get America to start waging
war in a way that was much more costly to
the Americans. I mean, human
side, I agree with you.
I mean a rack is just a complete mess and,
and not just physical,
but genetic damage from all of
these depleted uranium shells.
They've wiped out the genetics of
an entire population. Uh, birth,
birth defects and leukemia.
And I mean, it's unbel.
It's literally like hell since
Desert Storm since the first year,
since the first one.
But even more so I think in the second,
but from a pure dollars
and cents standpoint,
their goal was get America into these
unwinnable wars against these insurgents
because I mean this is what the CIA taught
to be enlightened in the 80s with the
Mujahideen was gold,
gold.
Get the Russians to come in and then just
keep pinging them off and picking them
off and picking them
off until they go broke.
What we're talking about two completely
different locations now we're talking
about Iraq and Afghanistan,
two completely different
environments and Afghanistan.
One of the reasons why it's almost an
entirely unwinnable war is because of the
terrain.
I mean,
Afghanistan is like trying
to fight a battle in the
rocky mountains. It's insane.
Yeah. I mean if you look at the terrain
that these people were involved with it,
it's just crazy.
It's mountains and there's no cities.
You have war lords that our own,
you know,
these particular parcels of land and it's,
it's a crazy,
crazy place. The idea of taking
over Afghanistan. I mean,
you would literally have to comb the
mountain side and pull everybody out and,
and camp them or something. I mean,
there's no way you can't, there's no,
there's no cities to take over.
You know,
it's a completely unwinnable
geographic situation. But Iraq,
totally different story. I mean,
Iraq to death, it was cities. Yeah,
for the most part. Right. So you've got
a lot of places you can take over, but,
but we,
if we were invaded like that in
this anarchist version of society,
what would you do? I mean, you,
you obviously could enforce your version
of society on other people if you have
dictatorships,
like say North Korea or something along
those lines that has a strong military
power and decided to invade. What are
you doing? An anarchist society? I mean,
that's, you know, let's
say you have, you have a,
an advocate society and next all you have
some status society. Right? Okay. I mean,
there's a couple of answers,
which you know, who knows, right?
But one of the answers is that invading
an anarchist country is pretty tough
because what are you going to take over?
So if you look at countries
that invade other countries,
they they take over the tax system.
Natural Resources. Well, to some degree,
one of the main reasons why we in vain
countries, it's like if the hugest reason,
well I'm not sure if, I mean that doesn't
really explain much about Afghanistan,
although there are some arguments
that massive amounts of minerals,
trillions of dollars in minerals, but
you can get that trade, right? I mean,
you don't have to go and invade and why
would you do that when you can just take
it?
If you have no cities,
you have cobble and then you have like
a bunch of dudes with goats and you go,
yeah, I think we're going to just go
over there and take your shit. Right.
Why would you do that when you're this
giant military force and you also make
money in invading,
right?
Because the people that are contractors
that get government funds to go over
there and spend money on tanks and
planes and it's a huge business.
The business of the military
industrial complex cannot be denied.
But he was a mass made money because
I know that there's the theory have.
So who's, who's made
money from the invasion of
Afghanistan? Of all Halliburton,
Halliburton, no, no, that's mass amounts
of money. But in terms of the minerals,
like in terms of getting the minerals,
because I know that they're for sure, yes,
but who's actually making money from it?
Well,
they haven't yet because they have to
figure out a way to extract them. Lithium,
there's a lot of minerals that we need
for Tesla cars and cell phones and all
the battery operated things that we use.
For the most part, we use lithium ion.
That's the current technology and the
trillions of dollars worth of that stuff
in Afghanistan when the biggest supplies
of it in the world. Right. So. Okay,
so they located it and it's like
even if it hasn't been extracted,
it's like we're not going to let anybody
else go over and control that area
because you're talking about massive,
massive amounts of money and resources.
Well,
it sort of remains to be seen because if
the argument is why they wouldn't have
had the resources, they've been
in there for what, 12 years now,
and if they still haven't extracted
the resources, that argument,
I think it's much more around Halliburton
and the military industrial complex,
making a huge amount of money by basically
picking the pockets of the unborn for
inflation and debt.
So I think that's much more immediate.
I think that's like a 12 or 15
year plan to get the resources.
I think that's maybe something
that's in the back pocket,
but I think they really make money off
the Fed. That's Fed Brinton, right?
Yeah. That's certainly the current way
that they're making money, but it's,
I don't think it's an either or.
I think without a doubt there's,
there's plans on trying to figure
out how to get those resources.
But I think that's the main reason
why people invade countries.
It's natural resources.
They don't invade because they want to
control the population for no reason and
turn them into slaves.
They invade because they need
something that the other people have.
Okay. So, I mean it Germany,
but generally invade countries that when
they invaded Czechoslovakia and Austria
and France and so on,
they invaded and took over the tax base
so that they got all the tax money and
they've got the gold and all that.
So if there's no tax structure,
then it's less profitable to
invade and take over a country.
That's not a final argument.
That's sort of one, one thing.
It's sort of like if you've got two areas,
uh,
that you're thinking of taking over one
of them as a farm and the other one is
just a forest with nothing there you'd
want to take over the farm because
everyone's already domesticated and
there's already a system of production so
that like the farm is like the government
system where the, the human livestock,
the tax lifestyle already domesticated,
the whole system of payment is all set
up and so on. So it's more profitable.
Usually if you want to just get money
and resources to go and into an existing
country with the state to go into a
country without a state, it's, it's tough.
You can still do it,
but you don't have that farm domestication
production system all set up for you
to take over.
The second thing is that new nuclear
weapons generally mean you don't get
invaded, right? I mean this, why did
Europe suddenly find Kumbaya? You know,
let's hold hands and be peaceful after
Ken billion years of warfare because they
got nuclear weapons and the
Post Second World War period,
and with nuclear weapons, suddenly it's
like blessed are the Peacemakers. So most,
you know, if you get
a couple of nukes, uh,
then you're most likely not going to be
in the how those new skid fund they get
funded by still will pay
taxes. I know, isn't it?
But this is the thing,
right? I mean, because,
and this is what I was making
the beef fat with Anna as well.
This is something needs
to be done going to say,
therefore we need a coercive
redistributionist. Yx State is,
to me, sort of similar to saying, well,
where do we come from? What God made us?
It's not really much of
an answer, right? So, yes,
you'll need nukes now running a nuke
for a population of any kind of size,
having a couple of nukes will
cost you like five bucks a year,
10 bucks a year for everyone to chip in.
People will generally do that.
People tip waiters, right? I mean, you've
worked in nightclubs. The waiters. Dot.
Starving and Mac ate it.
Right.
So people will generally pay for things
that can be shown, have a value to them.
But aren't you?
I mean the nonviolent principal,
aren't you the person that doesn't
advocate violence doesn't want war
on initiation?
Self defense is different.
Okay, so you were in favor of using
nuclear weapons for self defense.
I think it's one possibility. It's one
possibility. Execution of nuclear weapons.
I would absolutely view that
as a last resort for sure.
Because of course there's so many
innocence who get caught up in that.
Let me give you another
couple of possibilities.
There are weapons you can create that
are targeted to people specific DNA.
In other words,
you can release an illness that only
will kill somebody specific DNA. Oh,
that sounds like a fucking dream. That
doesn't seem like it would be possible.
I'm telling you, I'm telling you I've
been done. Is that a proof of concept?
Does that,
I'm not sure if it's been done,
but there's some are certainly ways of
targeting from the start of a movie where
shit gets terribly out of control
and then it's mad max well,
but whether or not right when you
have a bunch of people who all have
governments invading each other,
there's kind of an unwritten
rule which says don't tag it,
the leaders because they don't want
that to happen. On the other hand, uh,
an anarchic societies,
perfectly comfortable targeting leaders,
which would really be
the best thing to do.
I would much rather target a leader and
disabled that person or even kill them
if that leader was initiating a
aggression against a free society. Uh,
that to me would be the way to go and
that would be a significant disincentive.
That seems like,
that sounds like a beautiful idea,
but that seems cool daily. I
mean, past the first hurdle. Yeah.
But doesn't that seem highly unlikely
that anybody would be able to engineer
genetic disease that's going to
cause piece that seems like, I mean,
if that's the way to go about doing this,
I mean is that the only way if you can
target the leaders of people who are
going to invade you, that just seems to
me like the best sense, right? I mean why,
why,
why all the while all the surfs killing
each other in France in the first world
war. It's the leaders who started at all
whom, you know, that old pink Floyd sign,
you know, a general sat by the lines
on the map move from side to side.
I mean it's the general suicide in
the war. Well, it's a different time.
You know that back then it's completely
different because the only way you were
getting information was through
newspapers and we weren't able to have
independent journalists giving you
the full facts of the situation.
Like we're able to today.
But if you did do that,
you create a power vacuum.
One of the things that
people don't understand about
what's going on in Chicago.
Everyone's like,
why is there so much violence in Chicago?
I talked to a cop when I was in Chicago
and he gave me a unique point of view
and what he said was,
what happened is they arrested
some of the big Dame drug dealers.
They arrested some of the top dogs.
When they arrested these guys,
they created a power vacuum and boom.
That's what's going on.
That's also what we see going on
in the Middle East with Isis. Yeah.
With that is is we see a power vacuum.
The United States is pulling out of Iraq
and then we're being forced to go back
in there now and try to deal with this.
That was that journalist that was just
beheaded. Fucking crazy shit going on.
These guys, the isis videos that
they're putting out on youtube,
it's like they're taking extremism
to a completely new level.
They're taking violence and they're taking
the shockingness of it. All the, the,
the, the fear tactics. They're
taking it to a whole new level,
putting these execution videos on
youtube. Brutal, brutal videos.
I don't know how they're on youtube got
taken down right away. But they weren't
though.
There was over a hundred thousand views
in a bit up for a couple of months.
It's one that I watched. Yeah, it
had been up for at least 30 days.
I know that for a fact.
And it was over a hundred thousand views
and it was brutal. Was Execution Style.
There was shooting these guys that were
on the ground and they cut this guy's
head off while he was alive. That's
a power vacuum. I mean that's,
that's the result of a power vacuum
from the United States pulling out.
I don't know. I mean, I think this,
this idea of this anarchistic
society is interesting.
It's an interesting alternative.
It's certainly, look,
the society that we have
right now is massive flaws.
It's certainly open for
improvement, but I dunno. Uhm,
I dunno how you fight off bad
guys, you know, I just don't know.
Well, but we had a state,
but, but that is, is, um,
to not view set and aspects of the
state as the bad guys. Right. So, uh,
to me,
I think there's better ways to protect
my property than giving people the right
to take half of it away at gunpoint.
You know,
that three with you seem sort of logical.
I'm,
and I don't know how it's going to go,
but let me give you an analogy and
I've used this before and I'll,
I'll keep it brief,
but we've learned how to do without evil
and problematic institutions before.
I mean the institution
of slavery obviously was,
was central throughout human history
all throughout the world, uh,
for all of human history that
has ever been known or recorded.
So like 100,000 years,
basically people had slaves and then
there was a crazy bunch of people who came
along and said this stuff
is wrong and bad and so on.
And people spent a lot of time and
energy and money to end slavery.
And now we have, I think, some fantastic
benefits from that. You know, we have, um,
I mean obviously a more moral society,
we have a better economic efficiency
and all that kind of slaves was very
inefficient. So we do end to subjugation
of women. And things like that.
Like there's things where we've said,
or serfdom or or,
or bondage share for, um, for debt.
There's things that we've done away with
that haven't created necessarily the
same kind of power vacuum.
Like when we get away with
things from a moral standpoint,
they usually isn't a power vacuum.
If there's some decapitation of
power without principles behind it,
then people ration to to fix it.
But I think we're not done yet as a
species. I think we have more to go.
And I think the question of the state
is one that we really need to examine.
So if you were to say to somebody and
like the 17th century, you say, okay,
wait a second.
Almost like basically all agricultural
productivity is down by slaves.
So if you get rid of slaves,
what's going to happen? Right.
And if I were to say to you,
Oh man, I got a great idea,
here's how it's going to work.
We're going to have these giant robots
that goes sweeping through the fields,
which have the energy of a
thousand horses and they rush,
they run on the crushed tree juice
from the dinosaur era and you'd say,
what the hell are you talking about?
That's impossible. It makes no sense.
It could never happen, but that is what
happened. We got these giant combine,
half assist that run on gasoline and
oil that comes out of crushed trees from
hundreds of millions of years ago.
So what happens when you get rid of
an immoral institution is ungraspable.
And we don't know you used
to be because you'd say what?
Look 80% of people that
are involved in farming.
So if you're going to get rid of slaves,
first of all,
nobody's going to pick the crops because
it's unpleasant work or whatever.
And 80% of people will, you know,
40% of them will be out of a job.
But now like 2% of people that are
involved in farming because we got rid of
slavery and it became much more efficient
to invest in machinery rather than
maintain the value of slaves
by relying on manual labor.
So what I'm saying is we
focus on the principles. The
non initiation of force is,
I think a universal principle.
What happens on the other side of that
is absolutely and guessable it's like
saying what a phone is going to be
like in 200 years. Like nobody knows.
Right. So you're saying that the most
important things to get rid of what is
essentially a corrupt
and evil institution.
Get rid of that and then figure it out.
I mean, did you didn't? No, you didn't.
And nobody ended slavery because
things would be better afterwards.
We ended slavery because it was an
Mrl institution. Right. And the state,
which relies on the initiation
of force is fundamentally Mr.
But isn't there a difference
between ending slavery,
which is essentially a crime against
humanity and ending government because
government is essentially
how we keep order and is in
our countries. They really,
as far as like you're bathing in
an excess of order these days,
I don't feel like it's perfect,
but it's more order than chaos.
So I don't think that it's
ideal. No, absolutely not.
But is it some form of an order?
Clearly it's flawed.
Clearly I don't like the tax scenario.
I mean the tax situation is,
is grotesque.
I mean the idea of being forced to pay
money for crimes against humanity in
other countries,
which is essentially what,
when you see thousands of people that
are innocent, that got killed by drones,
a million innocence killed in Iraq,
if that's not a crime against humanity,
what is a crime against humanity?
If millions of people dying
isn't a crime against humanity?
What's a crime against
humanity? I don't, well,
clearly slavery was a co a crime
against humanity, taking people,
locking them up, making them work against
their will, selling them as objects,
as property abolishing that is not
the same as abolishing any form of
government.
It was a foundation for all of human
society, all the way throughout history,
and it was central.
It was central to how the economy worked.
Like why was that no industrial
revolution and the ancient Greek and Roman
civilizations,
they'd even discovered the steam engine.
They knew all about this stuff. Why?
Why was there no industrial revolution?
Which was really the basis
of all the wealth we have
now because they had slaves.
And so when you buy a bunch of slaves,
you don't want to invest
in labor saving machinery.
You have to get rid of slavery in order
for machinery to do the work of slaves
or of of human beings, because then it
becomes cost efficient and cost effective.
So it's central to how society's south
organized. Slavery was a central,
I would argue to historical as government
is. It's how everything was done.
You know, that's an old story about,
about Rome where one guy, one,
one, Patricia was saying, I don't know,
I can do some bizarre upper class
Roman accent. I don't know much,
but that would be like, I don't even
know what the shot, it's always English.
Just pretend some British
guy. I was like, oh my God.
I was walking down the street
and I said hello to a slave.
I don't even know which one's a
slaves and which ones aren't slaves.
We should make them all way
yellow tags on their shoulders.
So none of us ended up talking to slaves
and the other guy said, are you crazy?
We can't put yellow tags on the slaves.
Otherwise they'll see how many
there are and how few we are. Right?
So like 70 80% of the population
in some cultures were slaves.
And so it was as central to the ancient
world and to a lot of the modern
societies up until sort of the 17th
18th century as government is to now.
And it says incomprehensible for them
to think post slavery as it is for us to
think post state.
But the moral principles I think have
to win out rather than consequentialism.
Like because we can't possibly guess
what will happen in terms of spontaneous
self organization when you get
rid of the coercion of the state.
The problem with your analogy though is
that during the same time that the south
had slavery, the North had
abolished slavery. So then
in the north was prospering.
So they were Cohen coexisting.
So there was not,
not only was there a clear example of
a profitable forward moving society
without slavery, it was connected on the
same continental mass. I mean, it was,
it was a part of North America.
It was the country.
It was even a part of the actual union.
It was, they were trying to succeed,
but they had,
I mean the,
the North had no slavery and they had
excellent cities and they had buildings
and they were building ships and
it was all done through paid labor,
whereas at the same time,
the south had slavery. I've,
I saw something that I thought was really
fascinating that you argued and you
argued that the south should
have been allowed to succeed.
And then if the north wanted
the slaves to be free,
they should have purchased
them from the south.
Oh, that's how slavery ended
up or where else? I mean,
the British government and the British
taxpayers paid for a lot of the slaves
that's record or some
British, um, priest. A bishop,
I think was paid like 12,000
pounds for his slaves. Basically,
the way that slavery ended throughout
most of the rest of the world was the
government stopped catching slaves.
And when the government stops
catching slaves, they just,
it has to be socialized.
You can't go around chasing slaves
who are running all over the place.
It doesn't work anymore. The government
and slaves that are escaping. Yeah. Yeah.
So if, if the government
stops catching the slaves,
then it's not cost efficient to keep them.
You have to socialize that cost and the
cost. The government at the end of south,
uh, the government forced, uh,
white people to go on slave
patrols all the time. Oh,
they'd throw them in jail.
Right. So looking for slim.
Yeah. Looking for slaves.
They hated that.
Uh,
so did it take 600,000
people dying to end slavery?
Well,
only in America
did that. Was that a requirement?
Everywhere else it was,
it was money, uh, and um,
uh, moral brow beating and all
that kind of stuff and legislation.
It was the only in America. Was
that a required? Isn't that,
wouldn't it be required that they
would agree to that though? I mean,
what if they didn't want to
give up their free labor?
I mean the whole idea was you're saying
that the reason why certain societies
did not advance past a certain position
was because they relied on slavery.
And if you come along and you say,
hey,
we're going to buy all the slaves
from the south, what if they say, no,
we want to keep our free labor.
It's more profitable for us to keep
these slaves and make them work.
But You keep bidding up until it's
more profitable to sell them. Well,
how do they, where's the United
States get all this money?
Them might not have the north get
the money to buy all those slaves.
Where does that money come from? It comes
from not having 600,000 people dead.
Right. And when does it come from
taxes? Before the people are dead?
There's no debt of death.
No, but what I mean, I said,
yeah, it was hugely expensive,
right?
I'm just saying from a cost standpoint,
it would have been much less expensive
to buy the slaves then it would be who
would have been to a wage that entire war.
That's a hindsight is 2020
argument though, isn't it?
Because no one knew how many people were
going to die in the war and no one knew
how expensive it was going to be.
They just decided that they were going
to go to war and they were going to win.
Right.
And that's how a lot of wars are fought.
That's how we got an Iraq and that's how
a million people are dead and countless
amounts of money have been spent.
I mean we,
who fucking knows how much money was
spent and our rabidly since 2001 I think
that if it didn't,
they just fly over like giant crates,
full of hundred dollar bills and basically
just throw them into the wind. I mean,
there's just huge amounts of
of cash itself just went there.
But that's the big lesson of history is
that once you let slip the dogs of war,
you don't know who they're
going to take down.
You don't know how long it's gonna last.
You don't know what the
blow back is going to be.
That's one of the big lessons is that
there's very few examples of contained
wars in very few examples of wars that
match the expectations that people going
in. So with hindsight being 20,
20, and 600,000 people dying.
And what were the actual numbers of
slaves that were eventually freed?
Do we know how many, I've done a whole
video on the history of slavery. Yeah.
I can't remember honestly.
Then I feel sometimes like a,
a pipe with through which knowledge,
pastas leaving no residue like to do
these presentations. You know what I mean?
You've had, you know, hundreds and
hundreds of great conversation,
but somebody said, oh, what
did the podcast one thing to
do. Yeah. My memory sucks.
I mean, it's pretty good,
but it sucks compared to what
I would like it to be. Oh,
I'd love to be this giant,
you know, Museum of everything
that happened. But, uh, uh,
so documents I think a pretty strong that
it would have been much cheaper, uh, to,
to simply by the method.
The other option of course is that you
let them succeed and you let them have
their slaves.
Uh,
and then the north gets more and more
prosperous and the south generally stays
or it becomes less and less
prosperous relative to handle.
Allow that on your watch. How can you
allow people to be enslaved? I mean, if,
if there's anything that you as
a person with morals and ethics,
a person that wants the,
the human race to advance and evolve,
there's anything that you would
want to stop. It would be slavery.
That's one of the first things.
First, you know, uh, abusive children,
child slavery. I mean, in
that order it's slavery.
It's like number one,
it'd be one of the murder and slavery
would be like right next to each other.
Those are the things you would
want to stop, but you can't,
you can't fight slavery with conscription.
Conscription meaning what?
Meaning that you are forcing people to
come and fight your war because that's
even worse than slavery.
Okay.
So did there's a six and a half to
be pulled up during the civil war?
Is that a draft situation? So they force
people to fight against the south? Look,
it wasn't a good plan.
It didn't work out well.
The only good part of it was that the
slaves were freed and slavery's illegal.
Yeah. And I mean I would
lie. I think that's a way,
like I never advocate violence
with regards to the state.
It's something we outgrow.
Its something we reasoned about.
It's something we discussed. It's
something we look for alternatives for.
And you can see a lot of
these things showing up.
Even in Detroit there's a private to
police forces now cause the police that
basically said, you know, if you call
and you get an answering machine,
you're lucky.
Right?
I mean the police had basically abandoned
sections of Detroit that are wild dogs
going through there that people have set
up their own bus systems where you can
have a beer and there's Wifi on them.
I mean there's lots of things that rush
into to take the place of a decaying or
diminishing state systems. And
I, it's just something we act,
grow over time through a compensation
and it is a multigenerational change.
It's not going to happen anytime soon.
But I do think that we are still a long
way from don as far as a really great
society goes and um, I look at the
biggest institutions around and I,
I think that everything is
open to question. I think
you do as well, but I just,
I can't sort of say,
well what's on the other side of a
truly free society where people are not
subject to the initiation of force known
as the state? I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know either. And I like
having these conversations with you.
I like having these conversations in this
sort of a diff, a form. We're bouncing,
bouncing these ideas back and
forth and we admit we don't know.
And there are possibilities when
you do your videos, whoever you're,
you're doing these essentially these hour
long pieces and you're very eloquent.
You are very good speaker and it's,
it's very unusual how
eloquent you are because you,
you don't use ums or Uhs, you don't
stammer a lot and no jump cuts. Right.
It's not like I had to be in the cuts.
You're obviously very impressed with
yourself doing that. I'm just mentioning.
I am happy with it.
They're good. You're great.
I haven't looked at it for awhile so,
but in that aren't a lot of these ideas.
They're not, it's, it's not, these aren't
essentially black and white issues.
And when you state them as if
they are black and white issues,
that's what opens up all these
portals of debate and dissent.
And there's just quite a few places
online where people were upset at you and
quite a few things that you've
said in these hour long,
eloquent pieces that people
are vehemently opposed.
Yeah. And I'm annoyed that it's not
more like really, I'm really, I want Eh,
people don't you try to stop them,
stop them. Don't you pull videos down,
don't you like whole videos for copyright
infringement and tell people to not
make video? Oh No, no, no,
no. Oh, this, sorry. This just
recently happened. So yeah,
this is a guy who worked at FDR.
Um,
there was a trial out there who
IDR free domain. Main radio.
Yeah. So there was a, I'm a guy,
I'm going to say trawl is going
to poison the well, right.
There was a fellow out there I
think in the man, a gentleman, oh,
have a trolley persuasion. Um, and he,
I do these colon chose when people call
and we talk about sort of philosophy and
ideas and whatever else.
And he had gotten some of those calls
and it through means I don't pretend to
understand. He had, you
know, doxing where you,
you start revealing people's
personal information.
He'd got pictures of their kids.
He'd found out where they lived.
He had just done stuff where he was,
um,
someone just called in and he
got pictures of their kids.
What can I tell you what
I mean? I do, I do. I can,
can I pretend to know why people do
this now when this person called in,
but I want to elaborate
or sorry to interrupt,
but with these people
being threatening with a,
criticizing you and some
sort of an, oh, I know, I,
I think we were just having a
conversation about something,
trying to get this information about
their families. Well, so, so I,
let's say I call someone named
Barb called in. Okay. And then, um,
someone took that slice of
our conversation and work
like crazy to try and find
everything out about Bob and then
publish videos with pictures of Barb and
pretty personal. So everybody uses
my staff and I don't care about it.
And you're going to do a search on
youtube for my staff and everybody and
everybody who said, I'd really
like to reuse your stuff.
I'm like, Hey, go for it.
Right. But we had a number of listeners
who called in and said, listen,
this guy's doing some pretty creepy
stuff with my personal info here. It,
I'm not comfortable with it. So we
use that mechanism to take that down.
It's got nothing to do with
copyright or anything like that.
I just felt that listeners were being
acted against in a negative way,
significantly negative ways.
So that's what we did.
But it's nothing to do with copyright
or anything like that and people,
people use my stuff all the time.
That's incredibly bizarre. So this was,
was this a scare tactic to threaten
people that were criticizing you was no,
no, it, it's, it's a scare tactic to try
and get people to not call into my shell.
Like,
so we'll target people who tried to call
into your show and then we will start
trying to find out personal
information about them and so on.
And it's only one or two people
and it's only happened once,
but that's why we did
that. Uh, that's why, uh,
Mike decided to do that thing on youtube,
which I fully agree with.
I think it's a terrible use of uh,
uh,
of time and it's a negative thing
to do and someone else but people,
I mean if I was, if I
was interested in, in,
in taking down people's who use my stuff,
then why on earth would there be so many
of my videos re posted all over youtube.
Do you think that maybe part of the
problem with your perception, your Po,
the public perception of you is that
you don't engage in these kinds of
conversations where you're allowed to
elaborate on your question on things and
people get to see a more
nuanced perspective on what
do you mean big instead of
this like hour long echo chamber
where you do these videos, he just,
it's your thoughts. Bang,
Bang, Bang, Bang, Bang. Thank
you. Good night. W you know,
it's like, uh, there's a,
there's a bit that I've done
about on stage where like it's,
it's amazing that you can get someone to
sit down and listen to you talk for an
hour because most of the times
when people are talking it's,
they're having a conversation. It's a
very unnatural form to have like, uh, uh,
like a long rant or a lecture.
It's a fairly recent thing
in human history, right?
And that most of the times when people
are talking for an hour, you're like far,
I got some shit to say to.
And that's isn't that what's kind of
going on with a lot of the criticism
against you?
I do six to seven hours of
colon shows a week. Right?
So I am not like a, it's not like a one
way street in what it is that I do. Right.
And we've had a standing policy for I
think three years that if you have a
criticism of me, you go to
the front of the line. I mean,
we were booking people into the winter
now who want to talk on this show on
unfree to main radio. Uh, people
are booked up until November,
but if you have a criticism of me, you
get to the front, you bump everyone,
you get to the front of the line.
So as far as people who have issues with
me or disagree with things that I say,
you'll have better reason than evidence.
Fantastic. I mean, I've done entire shows,
what I've read out,
somebody's criticisms of media and
things that I got wrong and all that.
I am very open to correction.
Lord knows,
I mean I'm at one human being with
some researchers and all that, so yeah,
make mistakes are made and I've
admitted to mistakes that I've made in
researching and so on,
but if people want to tell me that I'm
doing something wrong or want to debate
with me, they get to the very
front of the line every time.
But they just never really show up.
But it's not necessarily things
that you're getting wrong.
It's people disagreeing with
positions that you have that it's,
you can't say it's right or wrong,
but these are very strong positions that
you have. For one. There's a video of,
you were talking about being an,
you consider yourself an
an arco capitalist that the
best way to describe it,
and you were telling people
that if they weren't,
if their friends were not
also a narco capitalists,
they should abandon those friends.
They should cut those
friends out of their lives.
I don't think I've ever said there's
one time in sort of an eight year show
history where I said to someone,
I think you need to not have
these people in your life.
And that's because he was suicidal.
But
there is a principle that is I
think really important, right?
And it is part of a long term
conversation that you have with people.
So let's say that, uh, I
like to smoke marijuana.
Let's just go out on a limb here and
say, I like to smoke marijuana. Now,
people who support the war
on drugs literally do support
me being thrown in jail
for the peaceful activity
of smoking marijuana.
Now that's a very real thing.
People who
support the war on drugs to
support me being thrown in jail.
And that is a pretty aggressive thing to
have around you. Now, this doesn't mean,
oh, you disagree with me, I'm
never going to talk to you again.
I talk all the time to
people who disagree with me,
but I will say that in my
very personal relationships,
in sort of my close friends
and family and so on,
I really can't it myself.
I can't get past this idea that I have.
If I have people in my life who say,
staff,
if you disagree with me
about the welfare state,
I think the welfare state is a complete
disaster and incredibly destructive to
the poor. Then you must pay the
taxes for the welfare state.
Or I support you being thrown in jail.
Or if people are pro the war in Iraq,
I would say, I mean I'm Canadian,
but let's say I was in America.
And if people say to me,
Steph,
I think you should be thrown in jail
for not supporting the war in Iraq.
Well that would be a pretty aggressive
action for somebody to sort of eyeball
you and say, yes, people should
come and throw you in jail.
Were God awful things are
going to happen to you.
That to me is a very aggressive
and very real thing that happens.
And if you are committed to a belief
system, then in the long run, again,
this is not a short term scenario,
and I've done speeches, full speeches,
there's one in Liberty Apia 2010 where
I've sort of go into this in more detail,
but if you are committed to something,
like let's say you're against racism,
which is of course a wonderful
thing to be against at some point,
if you got friends in the KKK, you gotta
make a choice. You have to make a choice.
If you say, well, I really want
the friends in the KKK, then fine,
then you're just not that much of an
antiracist, right? I get it. Right?
But if you say,
well,
I want to be a committed antiracist and
I want to maintain my friendships in the
KKK, this kind of a problem, right?
So it's, and, and so I say, look,
if you want to hang around with a bunch
of people who want you thrown in jail
for following your conscience,
do it. That's completely fine,
but don't say that you're committed
to the belief system then. Right?
If you are committed to the belief system,
this is going to be a collision
at some point. I mean, I don't,
that's not something I'm making up.
That seems to me to be pretty true,
but that's sort of where people get upset.
I don't think that's very controversial.
I think what you're saying is very
reasonable. It makes a lot of sense.
But the video that I saw was you talking
about people that support the state
saying that if you support the state,
you support people that want you dead.
These are exactly what laws
the state wants you dead.
That's what laws are though.
If you disobey laws and
you resist police officer,
but wow, sword it from you.
Which laws are you talking about?
I mean this state encompasses a broad
range of laws that range from traffic
lights too. You know what I mean?
There's a lot going on there.
Supporting the state mean if
you're not in a narco capitalist,
you support the state and you were saying
that you should cut those people out
of your life.
Anyone who supports the state,
I mean that is a incredibly
generalized position,
but you're boiling down like a,
I gave you a sort of very compressed
did there right now, but in the video
that I watched, it's you, you're,
you were going on and on about cutting
people out of your life that support the
state and essentially this idea of
this philosophy that you have about how
to live life being the one that these
people should have spouse and everything
else is dangerous and you should cut
these people out of your life.
Well,
was that at the end of me making the
argument? I mean, if that's sort of, if,
if somebody just takes out
of the tail end, right?
So I sort of gave you the argument here
that if you're an antiracist at some
point you got to stop hanging with the
KKK people or give up on your anti racism.
I mean that's so, uh, it
calling it the state is such a,
it's such a crazy term.
It's such a broad term saying that
anyone who supports the state,
you need to cut out of your life.
What does, there's no, you're not,
you don't feel that way.
So should I play the video so you can
listen to what it is that you said would
be?
Probably because I'm sort of trying to
tie him up to 3000 records or whatever,
but yeah, that's here. Okay. Let's
see. Can you a I s I emailed it to you,
right Jamie, let's, uh, cause uh,
it's a fascinating clip and I think you
elaborating on it and enlightened or
illuminates rather, your positions
are these things and it's hot.
It's easy to like say something in a rant
and then have people go and all sorts
of different directions with it. So
it's, uh, let's listen to what it says
by this time tomorrow, you call up
the people, you know, when you say,
I've got a question to ask you,
I know it's going to be uncomfortable,
then you know something about my beliefs.
And I don't mean to put you in the, uh,
put you on the spot, but you kind
of got a gun against my temple.
So I just want to talk about that.
I know we've talked a lot about all
the abstract things in the universe,
but I want to ask you a question directly
and it's better to talk to people face
to face.
It's harder to point a gun at
somebody face to face even.
Yeah,
in an abstract manner.
I talked to them face to face,
go sit down with them at
a coffee shop and say,
so I just want to understand
the basis of our relationship.
So you claim to have some affection
from me, some love for me,
some respect from me or whatever.
And you assume that something positive
for the relationship and you say to them,
sitting across from
them, you say, excuse me.
You say, do you support the
use of violence against me?
Yeah.
And they all of course. No, of
course not. It's like, oh, okay.
So then we're on the same ground.
So
you don't support the use of violence
just against me or do you support the use
of violence against everyone
except me. I was like, no,
I don't support the use of
violence against anyone. It's like,
well then you must be an anarchist or
at an ACO capitalist or voluntary as to
whatever the hell you must be.
A philosopher gonna speak basically decent
and they say, well, no, I don't want
to. I still believe in the state.
I still believe in taxation.
I still believe in government.
I still believe in front Paul.
Okay,
well then you do support the
use of violence against me.
They will do whatever they can
to disconnect these two things,
theory and practice
so they can get all the emotional
comforts of conformity with the theory.
None of the emotional discomforts of
actually advocating somebody getting shot,
which people that others are
totally uncomfortable with,
but don't let them have their cake and
eat it too. It's not because you're mean.
That's just reality. If you support me
getting shot, at least have the courage,
the balls to look me in the eye
and say, staff, I support you.
Getting shot and then I can get
you the fuck out of my life.
Cause how can I have even
a shred of self esteem,
a shred of pride in my own existence if
I'm willing to hang out with people who
want the shot
that's sick.
That is how the basement self grovelling
self denigration of the most revolting.
Well I know that you want to be shocked
but uh hey can I maybe get a little more
meatloaf?
And if we're not willing to do that,
like if we're not willing to put our
personal relationships to the test,
if we're not willing to do that, if we're
not willing to do that, that's fine.
Nobody has to do anything.
But don't imagine you have
anything to do with libertarianism.
And I'm don't imagine that
you have anything to do with
third that you are using
these ideas to play as a clever
card to play the cool car,
to play the alternative card to play the
I am smarter and know more than you and
I'm out of the Matrix and you're in the
Matrix and we play all this nonsense.
Don't try and use philosophy.
Don't try and use ethics for your own
personal comfort and to feel superior and
avoid the anxiety of asking people
that basic central question,
which you yourself bring up,
you yourself bring this question up
that our taxation of violence as the
initiation of use of what you bring it up.
Other people don't bring this to
the conversation you bring into the
conversation.
So do it.
Bring it to the conversation.
Yeah.
Okay. I think we got the
gist of it there. Yeah.
I didn't tell anyone to leave anyone.
I said if you are committed to
the nonaggression principle then,
and I said at the beginning,
I said,
we've talked about these
things many times before,
so this isn't sort of like the first
time you sit down and chat with someone
when it takes a long time
to have these conversations.
It took me years to get anywhere useful
in philosophy. So yeah, I mean I,
I'm always sort of curious
about, you know, people say,
oh this is terrible stuff that you said,
not that you were saying that,
oh this is really controversial
stuff that you said.
And then they play it and we're like,
did I say something really crazy?
And then I watch it? I'm like, yeah,
like I still believe even
more of that now than I did.
This is probably back in
2008 because I want you dead.
This is my problem with it.
The state doesn't want you dead.
The state wants order
over 350 million people.
They want to figure out
how to keep schools in
roads, in order law
enforcement in order. That's,
that's what they're trying to do. They
might be doing a really shitty job of it,
but the idea that they want you dead,
it's,
they don't want their population dead. If
everyone was dead, there'd be no money.
There'd be no live to be no civilization.
It's not. It's, it's, in my opinion,
that's not an effective way to phrase
that and it's leading misleading, in fact,
because it's not,
the goal of the state is to kill you.
You keep saying the state wants you dead.
That's an unfair way of
describing their position. No, no.
Wasn't describing that. The state
wants you dead in that clip. Okay.
What I was describing was, um, so again,
if I like marijuana and you think I
should be thrown in jail for marijuana,
then I must comply with the laws
that you support or I will get shot.
I mean at the base of every law is a gun.
I mean that's,
that's what the state is.
That's how it's different
from a restaurant or a the
boy scouts or I mean at the
bottom of what the state does is again,
that it's the initiation of force that
is the, the, the upside down pyramid.
That restaurant is a bullet.
And so when people say,
I want the government to do this
or the government should do that,
what they're saying is that violence,
the initiation of violence is how
we're going to solve this problem.
And that initiation of violence goes
against specific individuals. And so if,
if you're for the war on
drugs and I enjoy using drugs,
then you want forced
to be used against me.
You want people to come and use force
against me to prevent me doing my peaceful
activity. And that is, I mean
stripped of all the rhetoric.
And all of the flag waving
and all of the Matrix.
He stuff that goes on there that were
raised with law is an opinion with a gun.
That's what government
law fundamentally is. And
to resist the state is to risk death.
I mean we've seen this
over and over again.
Do you, do you regret saying
it the way you said it?
Do you think that it could
be perhaps said in a,
in a way that more illuminates
that position rather than
this continuing use of
this phrase.
They want you dead,
they want you dead and then you separate
from the people that support people
that want you dead.
Cause that's one of the things that
people were worried about with you is that
they think that you're,
you have this main principle that you
bring up about cutting people out of your
life,
cutting family members out of your life,
cutting people out of your life that
disagree with your views on the state,
cutting people out of
your life and disagree.
And by doing that you're separating these
folks from their friends and that that
is the foundation of cults.
That that is a big part of cults is
that cults separate you from your,
your friends that might
disagree with the cult,
separate you from your loved ones,
separate you,
your family that may have some sort of
a control and bond over you so that the
con, the cult can have more
control over you. Like this is the,
so are you saying I'm running a Celt,
is that men on me saying
that that is the argument.
If I thought you were running a cult,
I wouldn't be having a
conversation with you. But people,
that is a main principle of cults that
they separate you from all the descent
from their ideas, the, the,
anybody that would disagree.
Anybody that would be no fear
what their control anybody with.
So when you're saying things like,
like what,
why would you say to someone like anybody
who agrees with the state cut them out
of your life? Like what, what
would be the goal of that?
Just to try to enhance that person's
life to try to say like, look,
my advice to you,
because Joe, it's a true
statement. It's not,
it has no sort of effect or
intent in that particular thing.
It is a true statement.
If people are concerned about
being separated from families,
they should be a hell of a lot more
concerned about the war on drugs than
anything. Some Internet podcasts is
saying, you know as well as I do,
how many families are smashed
up by the war on drugs, right?
So if somebody is for the war on drugs
than they are for people getting ripped
out of their homes, separated from
their children, thrown in prison,
that smashes up families.
If people are for family cohesion,
which you know, I'm married,
I have a child and love it.
If there for family cohesion,
they should be against the
military industrial complex,
which separates people from their
families, sends them overseas,
guests them traumatized,
has them come back,
dumps them back in with very little
support into society as a whole.
If people are very much
into family cohesion,
then forcing parents to pay for government
schools where parents and children
are separated from each other
for seven or eight hours a day,
that is a significant issue.
So I'm sort of a little baffled
sometimes when people say,
when I, when I say, look,
if you're going to take a
committed stand on a moral issue,
at some point your personal relationships
are going to have to become part of
that equation.
If you now,
if you don't want to take a
committed stand on a moral issue,
that's perfectly fine and I said
that right there in the video,
you know if then den and
give up this philosophy,
if if you want to keep your
relationships that's perfectly fine,
but if you do want to take
a moral stand on an issue,
then at some point your personal
relationships are going to be part of the
equation. Otherwise you're kind of
a hypocrite, right? You're saying,
well this is non aggression
principle is really important to me,
but all the people who want me thrown
in jail for following my conscience,
well that's okay,
but do they want you thrown in jail
just by simply saying that they re they
support quote unquote the state?
Is that what they're saying?
Or they're saying that they want you in
jail. They don't want you breaking laws.
But did they want you in jail?
I mean,
are they saying they really want you
dead or are they saying that they,
they don't think that it's the worst
situation ever to have a government?
Well, no, but you see again in
this, the clip that you, I said,
I've talked to [inaudible]. I said, when
you sit down with that person, you say,
I've talked about this
for years, right? Right.
So at some point people do have to get
down to the essence of what's being
talked about when we talk about the
state and what is being talked about
fundamentally in essence
is the initiation of force.
It is the only agency in society that
is able to initiate the use of force and
do that, which is illegal
for private citizens to do.
And that is a great and deep and I
argue terrible power in the world.
It gets like,
yeah,
if I was erm,
I don't mean to push and pull the j Chi,
but let's just say the j card,
the Jewish. Right. So,
but let's say that, um,
uh, I don't think anybody's
ever said that somebody was a,
somebody was talking about I'm a
Holocaust is not a big deal or who cares.
Right. And I this is an extreme example
and it's, I mean obviously it's, it's um,
contentious.
But
yeah,
at some point if somebody was
a holocaust denier and, uh, uh,
I would at some point have to say, look,
I mean this is really not acceptable.
I mean we can't write or I can say,
well, I'm not, you know, for reality,
your true for Judaism or
anything like that anymore.
That is the reality of having a
committed moral principle. If,
if you are in the 18th century and you
are for the end of slavery and everyone
around you is like,
I think slavery is unnecessary and
moral institution and you had years of
conversation with them about the moral
reality and you've shown them the
pictures.
In the 20th century alone,
Joe governments murdered a
quarter of a billion human beings,
not including war,
a quarter of a billion human beings.
250 million human beings were murdered
by governments. In the 20th century.
That is some serious shit
that goes down that is like,
I don't even know how many Holocaust.
Right?
And so people who support the state,
and I'm talking about after
years of conversation, right?
Because it takes a long time
to change these paradigms,
but at some point if you are
committed to a moral goal,
then people who are happy or comfortable
or positive or pro the initiation of
force against you in
pursuit of that moral goal.
I think that I cannot have people
in my life who are going to,
after I have explained it and after they
have agreed with the general principles,
as I said in the, uh, the
clip that you just played,
I can't have those people in my life.
I can't have people in my life who at
want me thrown in jail for following my
conscience.
When you say support the state,
you don't want people in your
life to support the site.
To what end do they dissent?
I mean saying you don't agree with war
is fairly commonplace yet there's war
everywhere saying you don't
agree with taxes. Pretty much.
Most Americans don't agree
with the current tax structure,
but what are the options? I mean by
saying you don't agree with them,
that's all you require or do you require
action like by saying you don't
support the state, nothing gets done.
There's nothing different.
If you don't pay your taxes,
you will get thrown in jail.
You will get in trouble.
And what happens if you resist?
You get thrown in jail.
What happens if you resist the people
who come to throw you in jail probably
shoot you. That's what I'm talking about.
No ones. Even if you don't support that,
like what do you do?
What do the doing pot well that's doing
everything because otherwise you're just
saying you don't support it but
you are supporting it. Right.
You know by saying do you support the
state? If you send in your tax dollars,
you support the state. If you follow
the laws, you do support the state.
I mean you are essentially, yeah. No,
I mean they're bidding but that's the,
I think that's using the, you know,
if, if a slave doesn't run away,
he doesn't support slavery.
Reminisce recognizes who has the whip.
But if you're saying that you're going
to cut people out of your life that
support the state, to what extent do you
have to not support the state? I mean,
what if you're paying taxes,
you're supporting the state.
If you're following the laws,
you're essentially supporting the state.
You're falling laws that you don't agree
with, right? Like when someone says,
I don't support the state, what the fuck
does that even mean? I mean, come on Joe.
I mean someone who's in a concentration
camp is not supporting the regime even
if they're not fighting it.
So are we all in a concentration
camp just paying the tax?
I'm analogizing that obedience
to force is not supported.
I understand that of force, right? I
pay my taxes, I obey all the law. Right?
But then the descent of
though that obedience,
the disallowing of the state or the
disapproving rather of the state.
Like what? To what extent do you
require to maintain a friendship?
All I all I require for
friendships with me.
All they require is for somebody to say,
I do not support the use of force against
you for a piece of, of activities.
That's all I require.
They don't have to do anything.
They don't have to join a march.
They don't have to chain
themselves to an IRS officer,
haven't anything like that.
All I require is for people to say,
I do not want you shot for
following your conscience.
I reject the use of force against you
for peaceful activities. That's it.
That's the magic key to the Kingdom
of me. Well, that, that's all very,
very reasonable. And in saying
that, but also saying that you,
you also are following the laws,
you're still sort of supporting the state,
aren't you? Yeah. Again, we're
back to this question of support.
I don't think that enforced compliance
could be considered since support.
Otherwise, you know? Right.
There's no such thing as rape because
if the woman's not fighting back, right.
Obviously it's, you know, a
terrible situation. So now I just,
all I requires for people
to say it is coercion and I,
I think it's wrong that that's all.
I mean nobody has to do anything. Uh,
because I think that once
everybody gets that, then
evil is a very tough thing to fight
because most people like once,
once someone identify something as
evil, it's usually done. Like what?
Once immorality is clear to people,
it's usually over and done with.
Like that's why nobody says let's
get bring back slavery because everybody
recognizes what a social immorality it
is. So it has no power, which had
huge power throughout most of history.
Slavery now has no power all let's say,
let's take away the rights of women.
Now nobody suggests that
cause it would be wrong,
but it was format a lot of history.
That was how a lot of societies function.
So once people see
immorality for what it is,
it loses all of its power and
society fundamentally changes.
That's why all I want is for people to
see what I call the gun in the room.
That when people are
talking about the state,
they are at the bottom talking about
the use of violence in the initiation of
violence. When people, if people see that,
then that is,
I think that and peaceful parenting
is the very best way to bring about a
peaceful change. Revolution suck. I mean,
I think maybe three times in human history
they ended up with something better
and most times it's
just terrible. And, um,
and of course most people who do follow
the state follow the state just as I did
and, and prove approve of and appraisal
state because that's how they're raised.
And that's, you know, so it takes years
of conversations to change people's minds.
But at some point, you know, again,
committed to all people have to say is
they reject the use of force against me.
And um, that's great. Yeah.
I think that the issue that people have
with it is this is the stern stance of
cutting folks out of your life.
I mean that seems to come up over and
over again in the criticisms of you is
this idea of cutting family
members out of your life,
cutting your parents out of
your life. And that, you know,
even people that have thought that
they had happy relationships with their
family,
you don't believe they're
happy relationships and you
don't believe that these,
these people,
you,
you essentially have talked
about childhood in a lot
of folks as being like a
prison.
Well, I mean technically it kind of here's
my daughter can't, can't go anywhere.
It's not wrong. It's just that, you know,
she's completely dependent
on me and she has no rights.
She has no economic
independence and someone,
so that's more a biological
description of dependence rather than,
it's terrible like a government prison.
Hmm. Yeah. I don't think I would
ever describe it as a prison.
I think I would more describe it as
someone developing and more of like,
you know,
a scenario where you're mentoring and
raising them and protecting them and then
slowly nurturing them
to the point with her
pendant. Yeah. I mean, I
considered that prison. No.
And I can't remember if and where and
when I've said anything like that.
But I mean I obviously I'm a parent and,
and I'd been a stay at home parent
for five and a half years now.
And you've caught
parents out, your wife has cut
her parents out and you've,
you've recommended this
to many other folks.
No, no, no, no, no, no. I haven't.
No, I didn't recommend it in that.
I say there are consequences to
holding certain beliefs. Right?
And if you want to keep people in your
life who had destructive towards you,
that's absolutely your choice. But then
don't say you're against destruction.
That's all. If you want
to keep, and this is, um,
the consequences of beliefs.
I've really,
really want people to
take philosophy seriously.
Don't want it to be like
a dilettante's science.
I don't want it to be a a or habit.
I mean, when you hold moral beliefs,
they have very serious,
very, very important.
And that's how things change in the world
is people who take their moral beliefs
incredibly seriously and are willing to
go to the wall for them. Yeah. Right?
And so if you hold
moral beliefs, then, um,
they have to inform your relationships.
Otherwise, it's pretty hypocritical. Now,
if you want to hang
onto your relationships,
as I've said millions of times before,
fantastic,
then recognize that you don't really
hold those beliefs. That's fine.
No one can tell anyone what to do in
that regard. But if you hold the beliefs,
they have consequences in your life.
Otherwise they're just noise.
They're just talk.
So essentially what you're saying
is that your idealistic view,
your Utopian view must
be in somehow acted upon.
And that if you have this idea of what
is correct, what is morally correct,
what is ethically correct, what is
the, the best way to live your life?
If there are any impediments to that,
that you're enforcing or even nurturing,
you need to remove them from your life?
The impediments to progress.
I think there's, there's, there's,
there's a certain amount of real,
there's a certain amount of momentum
that we were raised with. Um,
I think many of us, I mean, I can
give you my own personal example.
We were raised by people who were raised
by people who really didn't know much.
And a lot of how we developed
and a lot of how we were,
we're taught around the home was
by people that really didn't,
they weren't aware of the
consequences of their actions.
They're essentially acting in the
momentum of how they were raised and,
and also what is convenient. They're
working all day, they're tired.
They want you to shut the fuck up. And
so they yell at you to shut the fuck up.
And is it that they're evil or is it that
they didn't really know what the fuck
they were doing?
You know?
And I think that taking a stand to
do things differently is incredibly
important.
And if you have grandparents or parents
or whatever that are destructive to the,
to your children,
or they give your children,
put bad thoughts in their heads or
teach them that what you're saying is
incorrect and that this,
these ethics and morals that you're
teaching them that you feel so strongly
about or in fact against the Bible,
or I could see cutting those
types of folks out of your life.
I honestly can see that,
but I think people have a problem
with you saying it because you're so
charismatic because you're so eloquent.
Because when I hear someone
talk that talks better than me,
I assume that person's smarter than me.
I want to listen to that person more
than one to listen to my own mind because
most people's minds are filled
with doubt and insecurity,
and it's one of the reasons why colt
cults get formed in the first place.
If someone can talk
clearly and confidently,
and I say this with all knowledge that
I've been accused of fucking starting my
own cult, all right, I'm not, I'm
not any sort of a leader whatsoever.
What I am is entirely
a person who is curious
and who asks questions.
And I give advice based on
what I've learned about myself.
And I tried to be as open and honest
about all my flaws and all the mistakes
that I've made totally in the,
in the interest of disclosure so that
other people can learn from the mistakes
that I've made without
having to make them yourself.
But I think that when people hear
that this idea of cutting people off,
d fooling as you call it, cutting
people off, it makes them nervous. Why?
Because that's why the polls, it's
principal directive about cults. It's not,
it's not, that's the why
of your life. No, no,
isn't it though? Listen, isn't the
thing, let me ask you this, Joe,
do you think that a woman
who's being abused by her
husband should stay or leave?
No. Stay. She should stay? No, of course.
No. She said leave. Yes, of course.
Yes. So, um, why is it any
different between adult
children and their parents? No,
you're right. You know,
if your parents abuse you,
I absolutely 100% whole heartedly agree.
If you had an abusive asshole parents,
you should cut them off. And
furthermore, I strongly suggest,
and I've been to therapy myself and I
think it's a wonderful discipline. Uh,
if you get a great therapist,
I have consistently said,
if you have problems with your parents,
sit down with them and talk about them.
Screw the philosophy,
screw this. You know,
all this other stuff we've been talking
about the state and so on, right?
If you have issues with your parents,
like if they beat you up or if they
never paid any attention to you,
sit down and talk with them and air
your grievances because you have to be
honest in relationships.
If you're going to have a relationship,
I agree and have conversations
with them and talk with them.
If the abuse escalates,
if it gets worse,
try and continue to have the conversation
until you just can't take it anymore.
If you're considering family
separation, talk to a therapist. It's,
and don't do it without a therapist
has been my consistent mantra for eight
years. Go Talk to a therapist, uh, and,
and make sure a therapist reviews
the whole situation with you,
goes with you through the whole process.
Now that's a heck of a lot more than
women who are being abused by their
husbands usually get in terms
of advice, right? But, um,
as far as I know, it, uh,
the people who have left their families
have done so under the care of a
therapist,
which I think is really essential and
important because it is a challenging
thing to do. And Fss said at the
beginning of the show, I mean,
it's all about principles. It's all
about the extension of principles.
Women who were abused by their husbands
chose those relationships for bad
reasons,
obviously,
and probably for own personal histories
of abuse as children and so on.
Women who chose their husbands are in
those relationships voluntarily and can
leave at any time and have massive support
systems around in the world to leave.
Now when you're a child, you really
can't leave your parents, right? I mean,
that's why I was,
I think half jokingly referred to it as
like a prison because you can't leave.
You can't get out.
Now,
if you were abused by your parents when
you're a child, you couldn't leave.
You couldn't get out. I mean,
where are you going to go?
And so then you become an adult and
the behavior has not reformed and the
parents are still negative or
difficult or abusive. Absolutely.
Sit down and air your grievances with
them. If they continue to be abusive,
you don't have to stay.
Well, how do you define abuse of
though what? What is abusive? I mean,
there's a broad range of
many would consider abusive.
There are, um, so, uh,
minor little pitch here.
Um,
the FDR [inaudible] dot com slash bib
is my presentation on the bomb in the
brain where I go through what's called
the adverse childhood experiences,
which is a test developed by Dr. Vincent
Felitti, who's also been on my show.
And I think it's a nine or 11 part
questionnaire about things that you
experienced as a child that are
considered to be a abusive, uh,
so being beaten,
uh,
not receiving proper medical
care or food or shelter, um,
and living with a family member who was
incarcerated or mentally ill or addicted
to various substances and so on. So, um,
there is a pretty objective
questions out there. You know,
how comprehensive I didn't develop them.
I haven't,
obviously you vetted them compared to
what I don't do. Excuse me. I don't know.
But there are sort of standards out there
by which people can sort of find out
to some degree whether or not they have,
uh, uh, experienced abuse as a child.
This, but this practice of
[inaudible], um, this is, I mean,
it's pretty widely criticized, right? I
mean, your wife got in trouble for this,
for advocating this on your, on your
show, right? No, she didn't. No,
didn't, she gets suspended and
she'd have no, none of that is true.
So that's just lies she online.
Yeah. None of it. That is true. She was
never suspended, have practice continued.
They had some questions about the podcast
and in the end of it they said, listen,
we thought that maybe you had been
given advice without giving a full, um,
uh,
psychological question or workup.
The quote that I had wrote and written
down was that she had been told her
statements are in,
uh,
in support of deferring or not
supported by current professional now or
consistent with a,
that was in the complaints.
The final result was that a defunding
is perfectly consistent with best
psychological practices.
So this was just in the complaint.
So people are taking this out of context.
Can you believe it?
Something that it's being taken well,
that's very illuminating, then that
makes people feel a lot better. Um,
because that,
that,
that mean that is the one thing that
people consistently have issue with a lot
of the teachings of you and your,
well, let's, let's look at it this
way. Right? So in, in the 60s,
I'm sorry to drop it. In the 60s, there
was, I mean, it's great. I'm really,
I appreciate you bringing
all this stuff up. I mean,
because it's interesting stuff. So, um,
in the 1960s,
uh,
feminists and I think really great
feminists came along and said to women,
don't put up with abuse. Right? I had
this, a woman on my show, she's a, uh,
Aaron [inaudible] or she, she created
the a woman's shelter, uh, in, in England
and women would come beaten up
and broken down to her shelter.
And everybody was appalled.
Absolutely appalled until death do
us part was the mantra, right? Uh,
that you can't leave your
husband no matter how abusive,
no matter how terrible,
no matter how drunk and no
matter how, what effort. Right.
Okay.
And she basically said, well,
I don't think that's right.
I think that you should not stay
in abusive relationships. Now,
if the only people you ever
talked to with the husbands,
the abusive husbands that
these women had left,
what would they say about this
woman? Yeah, no, I see your point.
It's not the children,
it's not the adult children who are
complaining about this. It's the parents.
Well, my mom, what you, I
mean, what would you expect?
I mean if you promote volunteerism in
relationships and then people go to a
therapist and um, you know, like I was a,
I think I kind of hope 2000 and
whatever it was years and years ago,
there was some write up in the newspapers,
a about some guy who left his family.
He was a therapist,
was helping him through the whole process
and the therapist was recommending it
and the therapist was the one who
was helping him through the process.
But somehow it's the podcast in Canada
that is the sole cause of all this stuff.
Well, I certainly think there's arguments
for cutting people out of your life,
whether it's a fee, a sister or
a brother or a mother or father,
they are abusive people that you are
unfortunately just given a relationship
with. You don't choose them. They
are just a part of your life.
And I think it certainly can be argued
that an engineered life where you choose
the people in your life,
when you choose the positive influences
that you have can be more rewarding,
more satisfying,
more beneficial than being committed
to this blood is thicker than water
bullshit where you have a bunch of people
in your life that are fucking assholes.
Um,
I think that
in illuminating it like this and speaking
about it in this sort of a form where
you get a chance to go back
and forth with someone,
people will get a better idea of your
point of view and your perspective on it.
And it's really easy to look at
what you've said and say, oh,
this guy's fucking starting a call. This
guy's telling people, cut everybody out.
If you don't, if you support the
state, cut them out of your life.
Cut everybody out. If, uh, if
you, if your mom, you know,
yelled at you to do your
homework and called you a loser,
cut her out of your life. Everybody cut
out. Come to me, send me your money.
Get in my inner circle. I need about 50
bucks a month come to come to my house.
We're going to have POW wows when I
sit around the campfire and I'll wax
eloquently while you all stare and
I,
uh,
I will give you access to the basement
of fertile women and then everything will
be set there in the basement. Yeah.
No, I mean, look, it's a podcast.
I'm making arguments, right? Every
philosopher throughout history,
and I'm not trying to put myself
in such illustrious company,
but every philosopher throughout history
has accused of corrupting the young,
right? I mean, that's, if
you're not accused of that,
you're just not even in the
remotely. Right. You're not
trying hard enough. Yeah.
You're just not,
not doing hard labor.
Zero lazy philosopher and, um, well,
it's, sorry, go ahead. No, I'm sorry.
It was just, there is, without a doubt,
there's problems with the society at
large and many of the problems are because
it has not been engineered in a,
a very
ethical or moral way.
It's been engineered out of convenience
and it's been engineered out of momentum.
It's been engineered by the
ignorance of the past. That's it.
It's just history. It's industry,
right? It's just what we've inherited.
[inaudible] we've got this
brain that's like, you know,
it's like the lizard bit and then there's
like a bit above the list or if that's
an amphibian and then we've got this
monkey and now we're trying to operate on
this like post monkey Beta expansion
pack of the frontal Cortex,
which is all layered on crap and it's,
you know, it's kind of unwieldy. We,
you know,
we evolved from some pretty primitive
lifeforms and it's not like that stuff's
all vanished,
which is actually quite a good thing then.
Well all these discussions and these
conversations in these heated debates,
what they essentially do is they bring
up very important points and they allow
people to give opinions and
bounce ideas back and forth.
And that's very important.
And that's one of the major things that
society benefits from when it comes to
philosophy.
Well,
I certainly hope that is the case and I'm
very much into a consistency and I was
raised that if you're in abusive
relationships, you should leave them.
That's how I was raised.
I mean because I saw that all the time.
You know the movie of the week,
the woman in peril,
the husband is a creep
and and she just gets out.
Why do you think there's been
this blow back against you then?
Why do you think people take
these clips out of context?
Put them up and make it look like?
Like I've always talked about like I
guess jokes are very different because it
should be inherently known that when
someone's joking that most likely they
aren't serious,
but people love to take someones jokes,
take the words in quotes on and put
them down in text form completely out of
context.
And some of the things that people say
look absolutely horrible because of that
and that that's not exactly
what they're doing with you,
but they're doing their,
they're trying to label you in a
certain way and trying to label you as a
destructive influence. Why
do you think that is? Well,
I think I am at destructive implements
to them, to their interests,
but is it the interest of who is the
interest of the state interest of the
family? A lot of these folks are
not, they don't care about me.
You don't know what I'm saying?
A lot of these folks, they might,
if you keep getting bigger,
see, we'll see. It'll be happy.
One day of the state cares about you.
You've made it. Oh yeah, that's right.
Hey look, Lazarus. Yay. I the ride.
I've arrived, I'm sweating. Um,
but what,
why do you think that these folks who've
left and start these blogs against you
and all this nonsense? Like what
or where she didn't say nonsense,
all this criticism.
What do you think that's about?
Well, I think that, um,
the of volunteerism in any relationship
harms the interest of those who are
relying on things other than volunteerism.
God, that's a bad way of putting it.
Does that even make any sense? A little
bit? Okay. So let's say that, um,
I don't know. Let's say that the UFC
has issues in New York with a union.
You probably never heard of
anything like this, but let's say,
let's say that the UFC has a,
has problems with a union, right?
I mean, don't you have to go
to New Jersey to see a UFC?
Like you can't go to New York
and, and, and why? So why,
why is this union now so
negative towards the UFC?
Well, I'll give you the full
details. It's the culinary union.
The reason why the culinary union is
against the UFC and the UFC is owned by
[inaudible] Zoo for the
parent company of the UFC,
also own station casino station casinos.
There's 20 plus station
casinos and they are non union.
So the Culinary Union
does not control them.
They don't reap benefits and
rewards and money from them.
It would be worth upwards of,
according to many sources,
more than $15 million a year.
So they spend an exorbitant amount,
exorbitant amounts of money
to make the UFC look terrible,
to highlight anything that any fighter
says that's politically incorrect and
harp on it and pay off politicians
to keep it out in New York state.
That's the last place where it's illegal.
But it's also just New York is a
deeply rooted, corrupt institution.
I mean it's, it's showing it, I mean,
some of the people that
have commented on the UFC,
they have done so with complete
disregard to the truth,
to the facts of the competition
itself, to the, the,
the laws and the regulations and the
safety record of the UFC. I mean,
they're distorted perceptions are
distorted depictions rather of the mixed
martial arts.
I've been just grossly inaccurate and
willfully and they've done so because they
were being paid to do that.
Right?
Yeah.
So something that UFC is doing is to
their perception negative to their
interests and therefore they become
very hostile towards the, uh, the UFC.
Now this doesn't mean that everyone
who's upset with me is in this category.
I'm sure there's many legitimate reasons
to, to have a negative opinion of me.
But, uh, I think that the people who
are the most upset of the people who,
um, their, their adult children
listened to my show. And I said,
I'm just, as everyone has been
telling women for 50 years, I said,
you don't have to put up with abuse,
but you should sit down,
talk with your parents,
and you should get a therapist if
you're going to think about separating.
So you think it's just people that are
like the parents of these people that are
separating,
that are pissed off at you because you're
challenging the rule that they have
over their children.
I know a lot of the people,
uh, who, uh, have, uh, um,
who have a websites. In fact, one
of them was even on my show and I'm,
so, it's not a huge mystery to me
as to what their identity is. Now,
the other thing to remember is that I
don't have a lot of shows about this.
I've done 3000 shows of which three or
four have been me talking about this
topic, right? So this is not any
kind of central focus of what it is.
It's just if people ask me
where the principles apply,
I have to say where I think the
principles apply and I have to provide my
arguments. So I does not a big
topic for me. I understand.
Of course it's a big topic for
other people and so if you have, um,
if you are a parent and your child
has had significant issues with you,
that child has grown up, that child has
listened to me and they have sat down.
Like if I have any influence over someone,
then what they should do that say
is do what I say, which is sit down,
talk with your parents,
try and work things out.
Remember that adult relationships are
voluntary and engage with the therapist.
If you're thinking of separating,
like if people listen,
if people listen to me then
that's what they'll do.
But if people aren't listening to me,
then don't claim I have any influence.
Like if somebody just says,
well I listened to three podcasts
and I walked right out of my family,
then that's not me. And because they're
not doing what I recommend then. Right.
So if I have influence by definition,
then the onus shifts to the
parents and the therapist. Right.
Because that's what I'm saying.
Go talk to your parents and
engage with the therapist.
If you're thinking of family separation,
it's what I did.
And so if I have influence,
then it shifts to the parents because
people are quote to doing what I tell them
to do and go on to talk to their parents.
And then the owners shifts
to the therapist because I
say go and don't do this.
Don't even think of doing any
of this without a therapist.
I'd recommend that in divorce
and stuff like that too.
I think it's beneficial in
those situations. So the
people who have hate ons, well
I mean they,
if
there's not like a hard on
with hey is it's your own term,
they giant foreskin of horror.
But say your own term. Hate
on hate on, I guess so.
Yeah. I don't know Jamie. All right.
If you've got a raging hate on wow,
how does one rage with the heat on?
So I dunno,
but I assume it involves thigh high
leather boots and acts on the nipples and
stuff like that. But, um, yeah, so if,
if your kids came to you when they
were adults and they say, listen,
I had all these problems and you
didn't listen and you got angry and you
escalate and they went to a therapist
and the therapist said, wow,
this is a really toxic relationship.
You should try and get out. Well,
is it easier? They can't even
find the therapist? Probably Ryan,
who's the easiest person to
target and by definition,
if they're just pouring
hate and vitriol on me,
is it really that surprising as to why
their kids might not want to be in their
lives? Like if this is what they
do in response to a challenge,
it's they just create hate sites and
pour all this venom and scour around and
manipulate and cut things out of context
and like then maybe this is something
to do
do with why their kid
signed in their lives.
I think as this thing went down with
Adam Carolla and then Adam was criticized
by Anna and Anna was criticized by you.
I think part of the issue is when people
communicate in essentially an echo
chamber,
there's one person talking for long
periods of time and you could take any one
of those chunks and decide this is
something you want to highlight and out of
the context of the entire,
you might be able to manipulate it and
make it look in a way that it's entirely
negative. Your position. However, what
you're saying now on this podcast,
obviously I haven't
listened to all your shows.
I've seen many of your things online, but
I haven't listened to. I quite honestly,
I don't think I've ever listened to any
of your positions on d fooling with your
family.
I think
anything I was talking about it that much.
Everything I've gotten from
is just communicating with
you and then reading the
criticisms of it.
But your position on this podcast,
I think it's very difficult to argue. I
think it's very reasonable. It's very,
and if I've done wrong,
if people can tell me,
but then the problem is it has
to go to everyone. Then I just,
I can't slice and dice ethics. I'm
so sorry Jeff. I was just, uh, I,
I've never really had a chance to talk
about this kind of stuff and I don't
really address it,
but I'm excited to be able to,
I'm glad we're talking about it because
I think it's important sometimes to give
people an opportunity. Like
I've had people email me, like,
why are you friends with Stefan Molyneux?
That guy's a dick. And I'm like,
like Peter Joseph fucking very
upset at you. Peter Joseph the
PJ.
Yeah.
I liked that guy.
I think he's got some great ideas,
but he was very upset with
you as well. Um, but whatever,
that's not important. Um,
I think that it's important to
have these kinds of conversations.
I think I need to have them too, with
people to where I go over my own ideas.
You know,
when you have someone disagree with you,
when you get a chance to look at your
position from a different angle as well,
and look at the perceptions
of your positions, you know,
one of your positions to get criticized,
or one of the other things that gets
tossed at you as the term misogynist.
And I'm sure that's, uh, that's
upsetting to you as well, right?
You're not a massage done.
Sorry.
I don't even like if people
could define to me what that,
if it means general hatred of all women,
that I made a really bad choice of
who to get married too. Isn't it
though? That's what it besides
just means. It's like if,
if you criticize anyone who's gay,
you're a homophobe.
If you have issue with someone who's
black who does something stupid like Al
Sharpton, you're a racist, you know, it's,
it's a cute way of dismembering your
argument or dismembering your position
right away.
But you said some stuff about women that
I have even disagreed with and one of
them,
you did this thing recently.
We were talking about how the way
to get assholes out of society,
it's women's responsibility cause women
are breeding with these assholes and
they're making,
it's the only women's responsibility,
right?
It's a key part of the equation that
I think is not discussed enough,
which is the sexual choices of women.
That expression or that, that,
that sentence is really critical.
It's not only women's responsibility,
but in what I saw,
the thing that you went off on,
you were talking,
I think it was the Elliot Rogers thing,
is that what it was?
We were talking about that fucking crazy
kid up in Santa Barbara that killed
everybody by the way.
He killed more men than he did women.
It's one of the things that I found
fascinating that that soul, yes.
All Women Hashtag yes,
all women thing came out after four men
were murdered in and two women and that
guy was a piece of, regardless of
gender and gender had very little to do.
He was mad at the men that women
found attractive. This is not a,
it's not an even game,
this life, you know,
there's people that were born and they
look like Beyonce and then there's people
that are born that looked like Bridget,
the midget and you know,
I didn't even know who that is.
Is the onsite or bridge of the images.
The second one, I dare you pretend you
don't know who that is. She's a porn star.
Oh yeah. She's a small person. Porn
Star. All right, my, but point being,
you know, it's, we didn't,
it's not like you've earned being beyond
size looks, you know, no one earned that.
No one worked really hard. She might've
worked really hard to get that body,
but she's a beautiful person. She was
born extremely physically attractive.
And if you're voice yes, I mean,
you know, good practice forever.
Onca sounded like that in this
Elliot Rodger Guy was, uh, you know,
he was socially awkward and probably
mentally there was something wrong with
them. Asberger's whatever the fuck it was.
I don't know what was wrong with them,
but if you watch his
videos where he's talking,
there's clearly some sort of
a weird social disconnect.
He had a really hard time connecting
with people and, and couldn't,
couldn't get a woman to like
him for various reasons,
blamed them for his hate and is feeling.
That's when people see,
when they look around,
they see all these people
that are attractive.
They see all these people that are,
that are attracted to each other
and then they're left out of that.
They are frustrated, they're
angry. It drives him fucking crazy.
And I think that's where this
Elliot Rogers guy fit in.
And when this, yes, all women
thing came about on one hand,
I agree with it. I, it's got to be
way more difficult to be a woman.
Way more difficult to constantly
worry about your own physical safety,
worry about men wanting
to sexually assault you,
which is very rare for a man to
fear. I mean, maybe in prison, yeah.
But in real life it's very rare for men
to worry about other men physically,
sexually abusing them or
wanting to get them somewhere,
roofie them up and sexually abused them.
But for women,
it's a super common occurrence.
It's a,
women in bars are always worried about
covering their drink. I've talked to,
it leaves five women over the course of
my life that believe or ward definitely
roof feed or we're definitely
drugged by someone with unknown drug.
They woke up in someone's hotel room.
It's disgusting and evil and creepy and
it's something that men don't have to
worry about, but women do. Um,
but when a guy like that comes along,
I think the,
it's not a matter of,
it's a matter of a mental illness
is what it is. I mean that guy,
it was a mentally ill person.
I don't know what causes a person
like that to be mentally ill.
But I don't think that women can
prevent that by not breeding.
I don't think that women can prevent a
guy like that from being born. I mean,
I don't think his parents were abusive.
I've never read anything that said
that his parents anything evil to him.
So how does an evil guy like that come
about is mentally, he's mentally ill.
Something happened during his childhood
and I don't think anybody could have
prevented that by being a woman,
not allowing him to have sex
with them or whatever. You know,
what you were talking about. I think
especially in this particular example,
that guy was sick.
There's something wrong with him.
There's sick people all the time.
You can go down the street and there's
a guy who pushes his car to car talks to
himself. And I don't think
it's, cause no one fucked him.
I think that guy's got something wrong.
There's an issue there.
And I think that was what this Elliot
Rodger Guy, there's an issue with him.
That guy was a monster. That guy was
an asshole and it's no woman's fault.
Well,
okay.
So let's pull back from Elliot Rodger
because we don't know much about his
childhood.
We know that he had some complaints
about the way his step mom treated him.
But I went over that in the video.
So,
so a study came out recently and again,
I had the guy on my show to talk about
it and what he did was he went to a solid
middle class neighborhood and went
to a daycare and he said to the women
listening, I really want to study
aggression, yelling, whatever in families,
I need you to wear this recorder before,
I don't know,
a week or 10 days or
whatever it was. And, uh,
so he had the women wear this recorder
and then he got the footage back or the
audio back and he found that the
women were hitting the children a lot.
A lot like 936 times a year.
An average of three times a day from 16
months to four years of age where it was
this study. Where is it taking
place? Some, I can't remember where,
but it was sitting. Yeah. I'll give you
the link for, maybe Micah can dig it up.
I'll give you the link for the show.
how many people were involved
in the study? I think 40 or so.
So it's not comprehensive,
but this is a middle class neighborhood
conferences and even poor, right.
40 is a pretty good number.
And out of those 40 people,
what percentage of them
were hitting their kids?
I think all but two and the other
two were verbally aggressive. Whoa.
So the idea that women are not part of
the cycle of violence to me seems a,
and again, this doesn't explain Elliot
Rodger of competent, you know, but, but,
but the reality is that uh,
women and men to like, again,
not all women, right? My wife
has an incredible mom. Uh,
but um, there is a lot of aggression
coming from women to towards children.
Now it's funny because
when people talk about,
when I talk about this kind of stuff,
people will say, well, what about men?
It's like, but we know about men. We need
to look at the stuff that's not seen.
Right. Because right
now it's like, you know,
like it's just man at ist and men need
to change. Yes, men need to change.
Absolutely.
Of course men need to change,
but saying that women are not part of
the cycle of violence is not correct with
the data.
And I am committed against all calumny,
against all insults,
against all hates and trolls.
I am to doing everything I can
to maximize peace in the world.
I know that sounds like crappy
and diluted and all that,
but that is my commitment,
you know, in life.
And if we can get women
to stop hitting children,
the world will become a much more
peaceful place if we can get men to stop
hitting children. Absolutely. But we,
the male aggression has
already been focused on so
much that there is this blind
spot,
which is the degree to which women use
aggression in the raising of children.
80% of British mothers spank their
child before the child is one year old.
Wow.
I mean it's,
it's mad centers and those of us who
have great wives and peaceful girlfriends
and all that, there is a whole
world out there of people who,
and men and women. But again,
we've talked about the mental,
I'd focus on the women.
Damn it. Well that just dad is very
different than what we're talking about.
You know, we're talking about
is a, is horrific. You know,
we're talking about is just,
that's any,
anytime you're getting a
fucking baby that's sick.
And the fact that so many people
do it is really hard to believe.
I don't have any access to any statistics
and I believe you. I'm not, I'm not,
well again, people can look, I had the,
I grilled the guy on my show and a
so people can can listen to it. Um,
but uh, Mike is going to put it out
on Twitter. My Twitter handle this,
Stefan Molyneux. Uh, but
um, yeah, people can,
can look at the study and this is all
lots of studies around this study.
I'll retweet that study cause
that's, that's incredibly
disturbing. And when kids,
the issue of course is that when
kids are hit by their loved ones,
they are way more likely to hit their
loved ones. They're wearing my Leica,
you accept violence.
Some of the scariest kids are ever,
or kids that were abused at home.
And I remember growing up with this kid
that was a abused at home and he was so
quick to violence and it's, it's super
cool. We find it in the UFC as well.
Some of the best fighters were
bullied when they were younger.
They were beaten up by their brothers.
Some of the scariest guys or guys who
had older brothers used to kick their
asses because they get used to having
that from their family and their loved
ones. And they have a certain tolerance
to violence and a certain tolerance to
aggression that other folks don't have.
They have a peace with it, you know,
so they're not as afraid of fighting.
They're not as afraid of competition
as the other folks are. And um, yeah,
that's a,
that's a terrible cycle to be a part of.
And those numbers are absolutely
incredibly disturbing.
But that's not exactly what I had
read what I had read where you were,
you were essentially talking about women's
attraction to assholes and that this
was the cause of their being
more assholes. And if women
just stood up and said,
they're not going to be
with assholes anymore,
we wouldn't have any assholes
in the world. And I just,
well, look, I mean, when, when,
when it stated as a completing an isolated
absolute, I get that. It sounds do.
Right, right, right. And I, you know,
I certainly held men's feet to the fire
as far as aggression and violence goes
as well. And I've talked to dads
not to hit their kids and all that.
I'm not saying, well, no, I don't
need to talk to you. You're the dead.
Let me talk to the only person who
was ever aggressive to children,
which must be the woman.
But the reality is, I think,
and I think this is somewhat debatable,
I think it's fairly well established that
in general men ask women out and women
say yes or no.
That's generally how it works.
And there are exceptions and
all that, right? But in studies,
I've read about 90% of
dates or initiated by men.
And so women are doing the choosing.
And I'm saying to women,
one of the ways that women can incredibly
contribute to reducing the cycle of
violence is to choose better man. Because
there's a part of women, and again,
this is fairly well established as
least as well as these things can be
established. There's a part of women that
likes the Alpha Guy, right? That the,
the guy who's kind of cold and,
and efficient and I mean I'm plowing
my way through 50 shades of grey.
God helped me how to you if you know
it, I'm telling you. Oh, you, oh,
I'm sorry he's not a midget porn star,
but yes, this is all I got. Right? But,
um,
and I get that,
I mean men are attracted to particular
physical things which indicate fertility
and women are attracted to particular
male traits that indicate good provider.
And again, there's nothing wrong with
any of that. That's perfectly natural.
But the reality is that we do need to be
wise in who we choose to raise our kids
with and who we choose to have kids with.
And I berate men all the time
for choosing looks over virtue.
I mean,
on my show,
I'm horrendous on men for choosing looks
over virtue and we've all been there,
we've all done it. And we all know
what a mistake then is, right?
What is it that someone says,
I don't care how good looking she is.
There's some guy out there who's
tired of screwing her. Right?
And so I talked to Matt about
don't just go for virtue. You know,
virtue is the big tits of philosophy,
right?
I mean that's what you want to to go
for when you're going to get married.
And for women, I say the
same thing, go for virtue,
but I think men's tendency to choose on
shallow standards is fairly well known.
And again, I'm just trying
to sort of shine the light
on that other side and say,
look,
if like you need to sort of cross your
legs and grit your teeth and say he may
be sexy but he's not a good guy,
I'm not going to have kids with him.
And I think that will help a lot. I
mean, I want to empower women to be like,
not to be victims alone, right? I mean I'm
trying to empower, once you give people,
like if you say,
look,
women are part of the cycle of violence
than women aren't helpless and just need
to sit on their knees and
beg men not to be violent.
Women can actually talk amongst
themselves and be empowered to do things,
to help reduce the prevalence of
violence in society. Choose better men.
Don't punish your kids, don't
yell at them, don't hit it
them reasoned with them.
That gives women something to do rather
than cross their fingers and hope that
men get better.
You.
Um,
you also did this thing on Robin
Williams and you do a lot of these,
the truth about people and you do these
a one hour long pieces where you stare
at the camera and explain and
I don't even various, yeah,
don't even blink. My eyes
are so dry. It you, uh,
just before, I'm so sorry to interrupt.
Um, uh, and we'll get right back to the,
go ahead to Robin, but a, so this
is from the doctor Phil website.
I had this bookmarked and that
up. Dr Phil. No, but look,
Dr Phil has on his advisory board,
all of the top stars,
Dr. Phillips in the Bardo who was
past head of the APA and all that.
So he's got the top guys. And this is
what he says. If you were abused, right.
And I'll just read the last bit,
right. And we can tweet this as well.
Um,
do what is best for you.
Consider the possibility that it may
not be healthy to have any sort of
relationship with your parents.
It's a difficult pill to swallow and
it should be used as the last option.
However, it may be the option
that helps you. The most.
Doctor Phil also said that if a
man is masturbating to a video,
that's just as much of a betrayal as
if he had another woman in that room.
Actually that's Jesus. Uh, channel
and talk to Phyllis. No, but I mean,
so that's not his psychological science.
Right. But I just know about videos, um,
so ahead of his time anyway,
so I just wanted this,
this question is sort of voluntary
family stuff. Uh, you know,
people can get mad at Dr Fail, but I'm
basically just echoing what I'm, what
I think people should get married. A
Doctor Phil just for his fucking mustache.
How about that? All right. Sorry.
Back to, no worries. Um, yeah.
About back to Robin Williams.
E what are these videos that you do?
I think they're very interesting.
But to do a biography on someone requires
an extensive amount of preparation and
massive amounts of research.
So when you do the truth and the word
the truth is a very tricky thing because
there's many truths as many versions.
Like I've had conversations with people,
they'll say, oh, you know,
I heard that this person met this
person and that person was an asshole.
And I'm like, well, actually I was there
and that's not what happened at all.
That person was annoying as fuck and
the other person was trying to get away
from them. And that's why, you know,
they looked like an asshole. Um,
you did this,
the true thing about Robin Williams and
your conclusion was that Robin Williams
died because of women's addiction
to free stuff and that he,
he essentially killed himself because of
the fact that he owed money because the
fact that he spent a lot of money in
his, a alimony. Um, I think that's a,
I think that's an irresponsible statement
because, uh, I think first of all,
it may have been a factor. It's certainly
was a factor in his unhappiness,
but we're not even aware of what kind of
behavior he had in those relationships.
It was probably also a factor in
the breakup of the relationship.
Also a factor in the antagonism that he
shared with his ex wives if and when,
whether or not that did take place,
but also his alcoholism,
his drug dependency has medical
state, the state of the, just the,
the natural body and brain chemistry
after years and years of abusing drugs and
then going back into it
and then depression itself.
Then on top of that Parkinson's disease.
Then on top of that, whatever medication,
then he was taken for
Parkinson's disease disease,
which many have been proven
to cause depression in people.
So to boil it all down to Robin Williams
died because of women's addiction to
free stuff.
I think that's irresponsible.
Well,
I'm in and again,
I said at the beginning of the video
that this is not all set in stone.
It's just my, my thoughts,
but I think that's a good
case to be made. I really do.
I mean,
because the timing to me is like right
after his show was canceled and he's
paying $600,000 a year to
his first wife from the 80s.
I mean that, that's what the settler,
he hadn't, he had a prenup with her,
but it got thrown out. Right. And
um, has prenup get thrown out?
How's that work out if the judge
thinks it's not reasonable?
I mean people sort of, cause people
post it back to me and said, well,
you should've gotten a prenup.
Prenup is not bullet proof. I mean,
how many things happened that on
Congress is supposed to declare war?
How many was this Congress to care
like three out of the hundred wars that
America has been involved with. It's just
part of the law. So a prenup. Um, um,
Steven Spielberg's wife, I
think Amy Irving, they've
been married for four years.
They had a prenup and uh, she ended
up taking 100 million from him.
Yeah. A cell prenup is not a
reasonable, yeah. A prenup is not a,
it's not a magic.
Yeah.
Bullet. Weird. She hasn't worked since
one of why lost all over ambition.
Denny's probably isn't hiring.
So you know, how dare you,
she was an accomplished actress,
right?
And he's a lucky guy.
Shelter 20 to 30 million bucks in alimony,
so made 200 and something million
over the course of his career.
He made an insane amount of money, the
to the, the fact that he's broke. Um,
even if he did have to
pay out $30 million,
it can't be totally attributed to the
fact that his ex wives took an incredible
amount of money. It has to be attributed
also to poor management of his finances.
It has to be attributed to just the
overall recklessness that he exhibited in
his life. He was a very impulsive
guy. As many great comics are, it's a,
it's an attribute that many great comics
share is this wild, impulsive behavior.
I've struggled with it myself.
Most of my friends have struggled
with it or aren't struggling.
They're just fucking embrace it.
Um,
it's a part of what makes someone
a comic in the first place,
and that is as much of Robin's problem,
his poor financial management.
Um, as the divorce settlements,
cause if he had just,
if he had been prudent with
his finances and had been, um,
like really good at managing his career,
he would still have a shit fuck ton of
money even after giving away 30 million
bucks. But the 30 million bucks don't
mean something that sucks. Sucks. Sucks.
Sucks. Now, because that was 60
years old. You think that's just,
I don't know what just is,
I don't know if it's just that someone
makes $300 million by making people laugh.
I mean, I think if you looked
at, in terms of commerce,
it clearly is because people paid
to see his movies. He was a draw.
Everybody wanted to go see Robin Williams.
He's a hilarious guy.
He's a lovable personality.
I think the real tragedy is not as
much that he had to pay so much money.
It's that here's a guy who the world
loved who died alone, hanging himself.
Cause he was sad.
I mean that's the real tragedy and the
factors that led to him taking his own
life by cutting his wrists and hanging
himself. I mean, that's a fucking guy.
Wanted to be dead. Those there's,
there's many, many, many, many, many,
many factors in that poor
choices, a life of regret. Uh,
accusations of plagiarism that haunted
his professional standup comedy career.
All the various things that were
wrong in the life of Robin Williams,
that the alcoholism, the cocaine abuse,
and then of course, is health failing.
There's so many different
things that were wrong there.
The $30 million certainly hurt,
but Robin Williams made an ungodly
sum of money throughout his career.
He was a huge fucking star.
He was making shitloads of money.
He could have been fine if he had
managed his, his, his resources better.
I don't think you can say that the $30
million that he gave his wives was the
problem. Well, it was a problem for sure,
and probably wasn't other than the
real estate, right. I mean, he had,
I think a $30 million ranch
that he was trying to offload,
but he was trying to get rid of it,
but he could have just for,
he could have let them foreclose on that,
you know? I mean, he just didn't want,
he didn't want the shame of losing the
home. And by the way, he still had money.
He wasn't destitute.
It was not like we're talking about Robin
Williams is living in some fucking no,
no. He's bag motel somewhere. Set himself.
He took the TV Gig for
the money short did. Yeah.
Because he wanted to keep his
lifestyle the way it was. And look,
it's still fucking TV gig. It's not like
someone told him to work in a coal mine.
No, no, no. I'm not CBS. I get
that. Yeah, no, I can. I mean,
it's a great job and it failed.
And one of the reasons why it failed
had nothing to do with his ex wife and
nothing people said that
he looked like he was sad.
Like people watch the sitcoms said
that he looked tired, he looked sad.
He didn't have the energetic persona
that everyone who he was, except he,
it was a downsizing to him.
And it was a downsizing professionally
in a way that's embarrassing to many film
actors when film actors go from
film to television, it's a loss.
And it's so hilarious, like it's like my
God, you're on fucking television show.
But the hierarchy of of stars is no.
If Jack Nicholson all sudden started doing
a sitcom, everybody be like, oh, check.
But if I come down right, but if I
did a sitcom, everybody be like, Hey,
congratulations on your comp.
You know what I mean?
It's not a consolation prize for you,
but it would be d level celebrity.
So if I did a sitcom, it would be,
you know, it'd be a bump up I B a c,
you know, you know what I'm
saying? But with an Aa guy,
like Robin Williams does a Sitcom, all
of a sudden he's a B or whatever. Right?
Now let's just start hierarchy
of things.
To be fair,
I also talked a lot about the stuff
that happened in his childhood that he
himself had talked about that uh, he
felt that he had to be, what I call it,
the me plus, you know, like in
order to get people's attention,
in order to get their positive response,
I can't just be me.
I have to be me with a show.
I have to be me with money.
I have to be me with good looks. I
have whatever it's going to be. Right.
And I think that stuff comes out of,
uh,
I think that stuff came
out of his childhood.
Now that you can't be
definitive about that stuff.
I would love to have chatted with him,
but sadly that never will happen. But, um,
I think that stuff came out of a lot
of his, uh, his childhood issues.
And I think that's really tragic.
And I really wanted to, you know,
there is no external solution to the
problem of insecurity to the problems of
feeling unlovable to the problems of
feeling not enough people will try,
I think until the end of time.
It seems like people would try to stop
the holes in their heart with whatever
they can grab from talent or money
your looks or fame or whatever it is.
But it really, you know, I've
really tried to urge people,
you have to look inside and deal with
that stuff in a very proactive way, uh,
because the idea that you can just
basically glue eyeballs of attention to
yourself and become whole I think
is a very dangerous myth on there.
It is a very dangerous math,
but it's also what propels
great comics to become great.
And that's where it's ironic
that a guy like Robin Williams,
his horrific childhood, it wasn't
horrific. It just wasn't good.
But that childhood, I mean,
he was wealthy. He is, it
was just ignored. But that,
that the lack that he had in his
childhood was what led him to be this
magnanimous, just energetic, explosive.
Like, look at me, look at me.
And he was just look at me guy, because
no one was looking at him. You know,
I know this from my own personal
experience of becoming a standup comedian.
My parents were,
they broke up when I was five years
old and my father was very physically
abusive, violent, very
terrifying. And then, you know,
my stepfather was very young when my
parents got together. And there's like,
I was ignored a lot, you know, and
that's what led me to become a fighter.
It a part of is being bullied.
I was small.
And the other part was what led me to
become a comic was this lack of attention.
And I figured out a way to,
to manage it and I figured out a way with,
you know,
constant objective analysis of myself
constantly pushing myself towards new
goals, constant research. It's in,
in terms of like psychology,
in terms of philosophy,
in terms of meditation,
in terms of psychedelic experiences and
all sorts of different things that I've
done to try to manage my
own particular insanity.
But my particular insanity
was more manageable than
someone who's a drug addict.
The people that are drug addicts
with that particular insanity.
The real problem is you're also creating
this massive chemical imbalance in your
main, and I could be argued
that I've been drug addicts,
some people set up my drug
addict because I liked pot.
But I disagree because I
don't smoke it every day.
And I have quit for weeks on end and
it doesn't bother me. I like pot.
I think it's like saying I'm a coffee
addict or I'm an I'm a dick in the coffee
again. Nope, you can take my coffee. I'm
not addicted to stake, but I love it.
You know, I love weed too. I think
it's a beautiful calming, insightful,
introspective drug. I think it makes
food taste better. I think it's,
there's a lot of benefits to it as
far as the way you deal with people.
It makes you more compassionate and
I believe it makes you more creative.
I think it's a tool that mother
nature has given human beings,
but it's not a physically addictive in,
in terms of the,
what it does to your neurochemistry
and what it dumps it does to,
your body's like actual need for it,
where you have to go in a fucking rehab.
If you go into Rehab for weed,
you're either some sort of a weird case,
like one of those people that's a
allergic to sweat or something like that.
Or you know, there are people
that are allergic to their wives,
the wives who are allergic to their
husband's sperm. I've heard of this.
That's not just a line. Yeah,
that's, that's what I would say.
I would say it's a time, but
no, it is true. Are there,
there's medical proof that some women
are actually allergic to their husband's
sperm, allegedly. What am
I a doctor? Medical proof.
But my point is Robin had a physical
addiction to chemicals without a doubt.
And one of the big ones was cocaine.
He did a fuck load of cocaine.
And I personally have had,
um,
several friends that have had real
problems with cocaine and it is a Goddamn
rollercoaster ride.
And the downs are awful.
And when they go up, you know, they're,
they're riding this manic
wave and when they crashed,
they are fucking day are just miserable.
It's horrible to watch.
The best way to keep people from doing
coke is to put them around someone who's
done coke because it is just seeing how
fucked up they are when they're high and
seeing how low they are when they're low.
And you know,
that that was without a doubt, a problem
with Robin. He filled up his whole,
not just with the tension, but he
did it with hardcore damaging drugs.
And there's, uh, there's
this Vancouver physician, um,
I can recommend your listeners to check
out his book. His name is [inaudible], m,
a, t, e, and he's written a book called
in the realm of hungry ghosts. And, uh,
he's, uh, specializes in treating
people with significant drug addictions.
He's a doctor in Vancouver's drug area,
drug district and so on.
And, uh, he sort of noticed
this pattern that the,
particularly the women who were heroin
addicts had all been sexually abused as
children.
And you noticed this relationship between
childhood trauma and Adult Addiction.
And this book, uh, I won't obviously do
any kind of justice summarizing it here,
but it goes into,
and I've had him on the show too,
but it goes into a significant amount
of detail about the biochemistry of
addiction that generally,
if people have gone through these very
hard childhoods and neglect is underrated
as far as how harmful it
can be for, for someone, uh,
which is why children act
out in order to get hit.
They'd rather get hit than being
neglected, uh, for, for, for in many ways.
And his basic idea is that when you
have a, a neglected or abused childhood,
the, your brain is missing particular
receptors for certain chemicals.
And then when you take drugs,
you begin normal.
You feel normal because you,
you finally feel what it's like what
everyone else feels who didn't have those
kinds of childhoods. And that's why the
addiction is so strongly their, you know,
personal, regular happiness. Like just
make up a number of happen as hundred.
They'd take coke,
they go to one 50,
they go back down to 95 and
then they settle around that.
But somebody has got to happen as of 30.
They go to one 10.
They feel like normal happiness and what
everyone else feels for the first time.
And then when they crash
back down their life,
which formerly was just
normal now feels unbearable.
And that's one of the reasons why there's
this drive for addiction. Uh, and, uh,
I did a whole speech of this
sorta college in Canada recently,
so I won't go into the details,
but I think there is a lot of ways
in which you can see really difficult
childhoods producing a brains that are
very susceptible to getting the REApps
from external substances that should be
naturally occurring but didn't develop
as a result of childhood trauma.
No question whatsoever.
And we're learning more [inaudible] we,
they are learning the people that study
that are learning more about that every
day and it's a fairly new
science over the last, you know,
x amount of decades they've just started
sorta delve into these responses and
then understanding genes and understanding
how you could actually pass on
depression and pass on these tours, sorts
of behavior patterns to your children.
And a guy like Robin Williams
clearly had demons and I,
there was, there was many,
many, many, many issues. The
divorce part was something,
it was definitely something,
but you know,
it bothered me listening to you talk
about that because I've had friends that
were depressed. I know that, you know,
it's going very clearly
against the current of modern
medical thinking in which
recognizes depression as a disease to
say that this guy was killed because of
divorce. You know, when he died, he still
had millions of dollars. It wasn't, yeah.
Well, you know, and I think
in listening to you talk,
I think I will retract what I said.
I think I went too far
in saying that that was,
if I said that that was the sole
course, that's, that's wrong. Yeah. I,
I can't definitively say of course, that
that was the sole cause. So for those, uh,
foot hope for saying, if I
said that, I'm sure I did.
You've listened to it more recently than
I have then. Yeah, I would track that.
That's going too far.
You think you just got worked up
over this idea of a alimony, this,
this idea, which I agree with you
that it's, it's a very strange thing.
And the way you put it I think was a
good way that you said that if people get
fired from a job, you know, you
don't get fired and say, well,
I still want money. I want you to continue
to pay me even though I've been fired.
But if someone is married,
um,
I have friend who was married and
I talked about this yesterday,
but I'll briefly, he, uh, his wife,
not only did she divorce him,
but she planned it out for several
months and went to all the best divorce
attorneys and consulted with them so that
he couldn't consult with them because
it would be a conflict of interest. And
she, uh, they don't have any children,
but they were married for a while and,
uh,
she will never get married
again because she did,
she wouldn't receive these payments.
So she has her boyfriend living in his
old house and when they send inspectors
over there, the guy moves
out. He gets a shit out,
like weights around the corner with a u
haul. She calls them, the inspectors gone.
He turns around and you know,
my friend knows about it. He,
and it drives me fucking crazy because
he worked 12 hours a day while she was at
home doing Jack Shit. She never had
a kid, had a little dog, you know,
the whole deal,
you know,
got her nails done every day and he's
just a fucking workaholic maniac.
And she benefited from it greatly.
And to this day,
his lifestyle is impaired because he
has to send her money and he's not Robin
Williams, he's not making that kind of
money. He, he did very well for himself,
but the guy earned every fucking
penny with labor. I mean,
he's a hard worker and he's got this
fucking ex wife that's an anchor tied to
his neck and uh, he can't get
free of it no matter what he does.
It's something Norman Mailer you
American writer, he said, uh, he said,
you never know your wife till you meet
her in court. And I think, you know,
I think that's pretty cynical
for all wives, but uh,
I think he's the guy who
stabbed his wife and he said,
as long as you're still using a knife,
there's still some love there.
It's only a knife. But no, I
think that the alimony thing,
it's funny because it actually is pretty
not that common throughout history.
It really came out of the Catholic
Church until death do us part. You can't,
right.
The reason that the alimony
thing basically got its
root in western common law
was because the Catholic Church didn't
allow divorce and so people would just
kind of separate the way it used to work.
As you take a dowery for marrying a woman,
if you're devoted,
you had to give the dowery back.
But that was about it.
But then this idea of until death do us
part kind of came out of the Catholic
Church and that's sort of
where it came from. And uh,
it is brutal and he has some
people got upset and say,
well are you saying that being a
wife was only a job? Well, kind of.
And being a husband is kind of a job too,
right?
I mean there is a financial
aspect to marriage that, you know,
it's foolish to ignore and um, I think
it is a, I think it is pretty terrible.
I think that's also something that breaks
up a lot of families too because um,
uh, more than half of people
who are considering divorce,
if they stick it out five years later,
they say, I'm really glad I did. You know,
there's a lot of um, uh, people
who go through challenges,
rough spots, tough spots,
transitions. You never know
you get sick or, or you know,
you lose some money or you lose your job.
But I mean,
things can happen that are really tough.
People have affairs and,
but the majority of people who stick
out their marriages, and again,
it's not like 99%,
but certainly more than 50 majority people
who stick out there and he would just
yell or we're very happy that they
did. I hate using those terms. It's
terms,
I hate saying the majority of when you're
dealing with individual relationships,
because they vary so widely that I don't
think that you can really narrow them
down to statistics.
I think every individual interaction
between two unique people is unique in and
of itself.
And that person,
I'm different with my wife than I've
been with anybody I've ever dated.
And I think that that's
how it is with most people.
Sometimes you find someone who's
compatible and it works great for you,
but there's other times
where you're thinking about
getting away from them where
that's probably the best fucking
decision you could ever make.
And I know people that say,
why does divorce cost so much?
Cause it's fucking worth it. You know?
There's a lot of people think that too.
Yeah.
I agree with you though,
that there are some ridiculous alimony
settlements that are just unreasonable
and don't make any fucking
sense why as well. And Europe,
I mean really no such thing. Yeah. Like,
and people can check out the movie divorce
Corp, I felt like I'm having to wait.
I don't get any money from this stuff,
but I think it's a good movie and they
sort of compare what goes on in Europe.
So in Europe,
the worst that can happen is you have to
pay alimony during the period that the
divorce is going through it.
But once it's done, it's done.
Now they can't be child support and so
on. But it's not much. It's a weird thing,
this idea that once a woman has separated
from her husband that she's no longer
able to live her life as an independent.
That's so strange.
I don't understand how that ever came to
be and this idea that you have to keep
her in the same fashion and style and
the style in which she has become a cast.
That's so crazy. Like, if you,
if you're a woman and you are used to
being a waitress and you're used to living
in an apartment and there's
nothing wrong with that.
And then all of a sudden you meet some
guy who's some real estate mogul who's
worth $1 billion and he puts you up in
his Beverly hills mansion and you live
with them for a year and you get married.
Uh,
should you discount the 30 years of your
life that you lived as a waitress or
should there be an average, you know, like
one of the things that we talked about,
um, the last time we were
here was, um, we were,
we were talking about poverty and we're
talking about people in poverty work
shockingly small amount.
And you were saying that people that
built live below the poverty line work an
average of 16 hours a week. And my
argument to two people, two people,
people in my argument with that is
also of course that you're dealing with
people that mostly are unemployed.
So if you have one person works 80
hours a week, one person works zero,
you meet those two in the middle and the,
you find out what the averages.
So it's not like most people would just
saying, oh, I want to work one day a week.
Most of them were unemployed.
And when you're dealing with something,
when it comes to like alimony,
when you, you want it,
someone in the style of
had been accustomed to,
you should take into account their
whole fucking life. You know,
you shouldn't take into account the
style they've been accustomed to over the
last 12 months living with this crazy
rich guy, right? Like that's preposterous.
The idea that somehow or another,
this man that you married who's worth
$1 billion that you helped earn him,
you know, half of what he made during
the year that you were together.
Where's the evidence that you've ever
been successful at making that kind of
money in the past? Why should you
be entitled to that kind of money?
And I think the same is true with men.
When Kevin Federline was
married to Britney spears,
that mother fucker never made a nickel.
Okay.
And I've seen him drive a
Ferrari and that fat bitch
didn't earn that Ferrari on his own. He
ended off the bat getting his rap career.
I think at least for you, I'd like to,
unfortunately, it's burned into my brain.
It's the whitest thing I've ever seen.
There's two cases,
Kevin Federline and Tom Arnold,
we won on both of those cases.
Those cases are all men.
But remember,
it's only 3% of alimony payments
are men to women. Sorry,
women. Women to men. Yeah.
And,
and it $10 billion a year.
It's a $10 billion and billion
a year in money transfer thing.
It's pretty brutal. I think it's brutal
on man. And I think it's brutal on women.
I mean, free stuff is, it's bad
for the brain unless you were like,
it's fabulous soul for the soul, you
know, free stuff a again, hey, you know,
I mean you, you're injured, you know,
absolutely charity and all that.
But the focus on free stuff,
I think a personality is like a
muscle. It needs resistance. You know,
you need to have challenges in life
actually wanted if you have another topic.
No, no, no. We can go on.
So one of the questions I get quite a
lot and in my colon shows is people who
say, I lack motivation. I like, you know,
I don't know what I don't want to do
with my life and I want you to get your
thoughts because you seem to be a guy
who's almost vibrating with work and
projects and you know, like you're
like this tuning fork that never stops.
What do you think is it that really
gets your juices going and gets you
committed and focused on achieving
the things that you achieve? Well,
I don't think
in terms of achievement,
I think of it in terms of interests.
What things fascinate me. You know,
I'm fascinated by martial arts.
I'm fascinated by comedy. I'm fascinated
by many, many different things.
I don't understand when people say
they're bored because if I had the time to
live a hundred lives,
I'd be speaking different languages.
I'd be living in different countries.
I would,
I would try a number of different
careers because I think there's a lot of
unbelievably fascinating,
puzzling,
complex things that you
could study in this world.
That's just me and my personality,
but that's a personality also
that have cultivated over years.
What do you like that as a kid too?
While I was involved in
martial arts very early,
and I think that is one of the things
that motivated me to explore difficult
tasks because through difficult tasks,
you learn an incredible amount about
yourself and you through through the fire
of competition,
you get to understand,
you get to understand motivation.
You get to understand the resistance
that you have inside your mind to doing
hard work. You get to understand
the rewards of discipline.
Like you don't truly appreciate
relaxation unless you've worked hard.
And that is the Yin and the Yang of life.
And I've said this to,
to the point of people getting sick of it,
but one of the worst
decisions a man can make,
I can only speak for men obviously,
um, is to be comfortable.
I don't think you should
try to be comfortable.
I think what you should try to do
is try to earn comfort and if you,
if you get a day off where you you,
you've worked hard and you've accomplished
goals that day off, we'll be so sweet.
When I work hard and I sit in front
of the TV, I enjoy the shit out of it.
I put my feet up, I have a nice
drink, you know, I enjoy my free time.
It's your back or something like that.
One of those. Those are great. All right.
Right now I don't use it that much though.
Honestly I'm more of a workaholic
than I should be probably if, if the,
the balance was I probably
should relax more than I do,
but I never feel like I earned it,
but that's part of the reason why
when I do feel like I earned it,
I can enjoy it.
It's because I am more connected
to the idea that I need to,
to accomplish things and to,
and it's not like for anybody else has
benefit other than my own or anybody
else's approval other than my own. I just,
when I have a task, whether it's a I,
today I'm going to write a thousand words,
you know,
or 2000 or whatever the number is.
If I don't do that, I don't, I'm not,
I write things down,
like I'll write down the list of
things that get accomplished that day.
And if I don't accomplish
that, I'll get sick. Like I'll,
it'll drive me fucking crazy if I can't
fill out that list that drives me nuts,
you know? But that's what led me to be
a championship level martial artists.
That's what led me to achieve the,
it's like that.
It's the reinforcement of those goals,
like understanding that you can achieve
those goals, it's going to be difficult.
You're going to push through
the difficulty and then
you've got to understand
what difficulty truly is and
how much of it is just mental.
How much of it is just in your mind,
this adversity to,
to a difficult task or to struggle. You
know? And a lot of people have that,
they're scared, they're
scared of, of complications.
They're scared of failure. Failure is
a big one that people are afraid of.
But failure is one of the most important
things you could ever have as far as
like the motivation to
do things differently.
One of the reasons why I think that I'm
good at friendships and relationships is
because I failed at them in the past.
One of the things that I'm good at
comedies because I bombed on stage.
One of the reasons why I'm good at work
is because I've been a shitty worker in
the past and I know the feeling
of failure, the feeling of, uh,
of shame of being like a week
non-motivated lazy person.
It's a weak feeling. It's an you
don't respect yourself. You know,
and I have this phrase that I use all
the time to people to try to motivate
people. I say that, be the
hero in your own movie.
Pretend that if your life was a
movie and your life started now,
what would the hero do?
What would the person that you respect,
what would the person that you admire,
person that inspires you?
What would they do? We'll do
that shit. And if you do that,
you slowly build momentum. You like
today I did what I wanted to do today.
I started a class in Yoga,
I did this,
I did all these things that I was saying
I wasn't going to do and now I feel
momentum and momentum is a very
important point in people's lives.
That's why some folks don't like to take
days off because they feel like they're
losing momentum and they sort of have
to restart the wheel up again after a
vacation. It's like what they
say, if you want something done,
give it to the busy guy.
Yeah,
it's true because he's in motion.
He'll get some things done.
That's true.
There's certain people that I know that
just are lazy as fuck and they can never
get anything done. You're like, did you
do that thing? Nah, it was just getting,
didn't get to it. Like what are you
talking about? You didn't get to it.
What did you do?
You wear out instagraming pictures of
you at a strip club two days ago, right?
Like how the fuck did you
not get that done? Right?
Like you had all the time to
do all these other things,
but you don't have the time to do the
thing that's going to enhance your life.
It's going to benefit you, that's going
to move forward, your career, your life,
your prospects, your art, whatever
it is you're working on. You know?
And I think that it's,
it's hard for people because we
operate on the momentum of the past.
And a lot of times our past has been to
just fucking, just a graveyard, uh, uh,
just, uh, a wreck of
disasters one after the other.
And you look at that and you go,
well, that's who I am. I'm a failure.
I drank too much. I fall asleep
at work, I do this, I do that.
And we put kids in these schools where
they just sit there passively receiving
stuff rather than actively doing stuff.
And then we wonder why they may,
some of them lack motivation
when they get older.
And I think there's a big
problem in the fact that the,
the job of being a teacher should be
a revered position that's incredibly
difficult to earn.
I think it should be just like you know,
being someone who is in charge.
I mean being someone who is in charge
of the development of the mind of your
child is such an incredible
position and an incredible,
the just the,
the amount of responsibility involved
in influencing a young developing mind
can't be under overestimated.
Do you have teachers that you
remember when you were a kid? Yeah,
I do like good stand out like yeah,
like, like, like the sun in the sky.
You can't see any kind see any star.
I can't see the other teachers in my
head for the few good ones that I had.
What an incredible,
if they could all be like,
and obviously it'd be great but I mean
teach us. Yeah. Awesome responsibility.
Yeah.
I had some great ones.
I had a few great ones that were just
really good people that were smart and
kind and they, they, they profoundly,
I had a science teacher in seventh
grade that I had a discussion with him,
just me and him one day
and I never forgot it.
We were talking about space and he was
a really interesting guy. You know,
it was a bad neighborhood. We
lived in, I lived in Jamaica plain,
which was like this, um,
neighborhood in Boston,
just outside of, um, uh, Boston.
It's just a really shit
neighborhood at the time.
It's become a little bit gentrified now,
but back then it was just really sketchy,
very poor kids.
And there was a kid that was in my class,
I can't. So seventh grade eight went,
ninth is a high school is eighth grade
because it was right before high school.
And this kid was 17 years old
in the fucking eighth grade.
I mean it was crazy cause they were just,
they would be there for the beginning of
the year and then they would drop out.
And uh, the science teacher was, you
know, in this shit school system,
but he was just genuinely kind,
curious patient man.
And he talked to me about space and,
and I'd never considered the
idea that space is never ending.
And he was explaining the concept of
infinity to me and that there truly is no
boundary. And if you
really, I remember he said,
you ever really want
to make your head hurt?
Just stare at the sky and try to wrap
your head around the idea that it never
ends.
And we had this long conversation about
it and they inbetween classes one day,
not even a long, you
know, 10 minutes maybe,
but enough that I thought about that for
years to this day. I remember that guy
that's a great to Richard Fiman was
this a physicist, a fantastic guy.
And uh, he said, told about
his father that his, you know,
he was pulling some wagon and they hit
balls in the wagon. He said, you know,
it's when you pull the wagon,
the bowl stay for a bit,
and then they bump up and then you
stop the wagon. They keep going.
So he was talking about
momentum and physics and all
that. And so like all kids,
he said, well, why, why, why?
And then he got to a point with his
father where he said, well, why?
And his father said that nobody
knows. Like, why is that gravity?
I mean that nobody knows. And, uh,
I think those kinds of questions where
you really stimulate your mind I think is
a great idea.
I was telling my daughter a couple of
I made made two months ago about a,
there's an old Spanish
proverb that says, Whoa, um,
habits begin as cobwebs and end up
has chains way easier to break in the
beginning than later off. Right. Way To
put it. It's a great way to put it. Wow.
And uh, anyway, she just, she just
brought this up, uh, you know, um,
we were talking about
someone she knew and,
and to something that she didn't like
that they did and she said, yeah,
but they're still pretty much in the
cob web phase so they can probably still
change it at him. She was like, well, I
even, I didn't remember it. She was like,
Oh yeah, the cob webs and
change things. Like she really,
that sunk in her and she's like five.
And she can remember those things that
can really take you through life and give
you real clarity.
I think that stuff is great.
And I remember those people who gave me
those important lessons as, as a kid.
Yeah, that's a great statement. That's
a big one man. Cause that is so true.
If you can break them in the beginning
they say that if you do something for 90
days it, it can become a habit.
It becomes an ingrained, negative,
positive or negative as why I've run into
people that all of a sudden they just,
you look at them, they look great. I've
lost all this weight. Like what'd you do?
I just started every day doing
this. I started walking, I
started eating, you know,
healthy vegetables and all this
different shit. And now look at me.
90 days later I'm all healthy. You
know, you can't, it can be done.
It's just very difficult.
And it sort of flies in the face of a
lot of people like to harp on free will
and determinism and there is no
freewill and these sort of, you know,
I think those can be fascinating
philosophical debates.
But I think as far as like your own life,
it could be a massive distraction.
This idea, this concept that
there is no free will. Yeah,
throw that shit out the window and just
fucking get off your lazy ass and get
shit done.
Cause this cause that's
like this pontificating of
whether or not freewill is a
real thing. It's not going to
fucking help you. Well and for me,
I mean I act as if I have
free will because I know
it's going to get me a better
life and if I don't have freewill it was
pretty determined that I'm going to act
as if I have free will. So I don't
lose anything that way either way.
So I mean I'm just going to pretend like
I have free will maximize it as much as
I can.
And if it turns out I don't,
then I was pretty determined
to believe that anyway.
I said, yeah, I don't understand it.
I mean the argument one way or the
other that can be proven and in each,
well Sam Harris will be on soon.
I'll have a conversation
with him about it because he,
he can go into it from a neuroscientific
standpoint because apparently they can
determine that. You make decisions
before you make decisions
down in the Amygdala, like the base
and the brain, top of the spine.
That impulse is there.
And then people make the decision and
they experienced a decision up here.
But the decision is happening down here.
I don't think that means
that's inevitable for everyone.
That's part of self knowledge is learning
what your emotional triggers are so
that you can make decisions right
now you're not just ex post facto
rationalizing stuff that you want to
do anyway. You learn about yourself.
And I think that you can expand
free well by through self knowledge.
It's what Socrates said at the
very beginning of philosophy. Uh,
the first commandment is know thyself
and that way you can figure out your own
cognitive biases and you can figure out
what blocks you and what, what your um,
prejudices are.
And then I think you get choices.
But I don't think you get
choices just for having a brain.
You really have to explore it.
Like you don't know a country
just by falling into it.
You out of a plane land somewhere, you
have to explore it. You have to map it,
you have to know the terrain and
then you're competent at the country.
And I think that freewill is,
is pursued through south
knowledge and that gives you
the choice. Um, but so yeah,
if you think you can, you think
you can't, you're right. I mean,
if you think you have free will or you
think you can't, you can't have, right.
Yeah.
And did that impulse,
I would love to know if there's been any
studies done on whether or not people
ignore that impulse because there's a
lot of impulses that you have that you
never act on.
Right.
Do you have a quarter second
sign? Typically you have
a quarter second to the,
around to interrupt an impulse.
How much research has been done on that?
Like how many people were observed
and how through uh, how, uh,
how many different complicated periods
of their life where they've been forced
to have weird situation. How many people
wanted to strangle somebody and didn't,
you know, I mean, how many times now?
I think most people given how few
strangulations there aren't worth,
I think most people manage to, you know,
slapped down the strangle hands, you know,
and it's really important.
Wouldn't that be like the number one
argument against free will is how few
people get strangled. We've all
been there, we've all been there.
Now what about,
but what about the days when do you
have two days where you're just like,
the elephant of inertia sits on your
chest and just fucks up your nose and you
just don't want to get anything
done? I mean, how'd he,
how'd he do deal with those? I mean, you
just let them ride. I mean, how do you,
I don't have those days that much.
No, no. I don't know if they do,
I'm usually sick. Okay. It's usually
like a health thing. And if I'm sick,
I'm pretty good. I'm, I've gotten really
good at not doing shit when I'm sick,
but just drinking liquids and eating
healthy foods and relaxing and I'll go in
the isolation tank and meditate
and I don't, I'm a, I'm not a big,
I think if there's something
wrong, like I'm like, Ooh,
I usually don't do anything.
I just usually let everything recover.
Your listen to your body, but it's
basically a saying, we need some downtime,
we need some recharge.
Well, that's where my energy comes from
because my mind is usually pretty damn
energetic.
My mind is always filled with a bunch
of different things I don't try to
accomplish and different things that
I'm interested in pursuing. But My,
if I'm down, usually it's
my body. Right? You know,
maybe I get that.
Sometimes I've worked out too hard.
If I'm overtrained I get exhausted,
but it just, I just recover, you know?
But I don't discount peoples,
the mental blockades and the different
issues that some folks do have with
motivation and with, uh,
with depression and a that,
whether that depression comes from
chemical abuse, abusing substances,
or whether it comes from
a biological perspective.
Kara Santa Maria and will be on
next week on the first and uh,
uh, no, I mean, uh, soon. Next
week. Yeah, next Monday I think.
Um, and she's a neuroscientist as
well and she's had issues the 25th,
that's when she's coming on and she's
had issues herself with depression and
she's pretty open about it and she,
she understands,
understands it much more
from a chemical standpoint,
from what's going on inside the mind.
And there's a,
there's a lot going on there that keeps
people on that fucking couch. And, uh,
it's,
what's interesting is it doesn't exist
in all cultures and that it may be also
the society that we live in,
that this is a very unnatural way
to live your life and that the,
the human body's not essentially,
essentially not designed for sitting in
cubicles, sitting in cars, no motion.
And they've also shown that exercise
has been as effective at mitigating
depression, has have antidepressants
as an Ssri, which I think,
I think the physical exercise
plus therapy is, you know,
your best times for longterm recovery
from the data that I've read with regards
to depression.
Yeah. I think people need to get their
juices flowing. I think it's, it's so,
it's so underrated and um,
it's associated with vanity.
It's associated with all sorts
of insecurities about, you know,
your body that you're trying to
pump yourself up and your ego,
but put all that out of the
window. I mean, God damn,
I put a fucking a bubble outfit over your
head so you don't have to look at your
body if you're really tweaking on that.
It's not about that. It's about movement.
It's about getting all
your endorphins flowing.
It's about getting your body into a
natural state because the body's natural
state is in motion.
We're not supposed to be sitting
around doing nothing all day.
We're supposed to be hunting
and gathering. And that's
how our body was designed.
And do you know,
I mean,
we're not the strongest species and
we don't have the biggest teeth.
But you know,
one thing that human beings have is
like ridiculous physical endurance.
Like what I've read is
that the ancient hunters,
do you know how they used to
get their assistance hunting?
Yeah. You just, you, you,
you chase that animal until it's hard,
just fucking explodes in its chest.
And then you're like, I win. And
any drag it back to camp, like,
like 20 miles of running and then the
zebras hot just dies and you get him.
We're also in Africa because it's
extremely hot and they don't sweat animals
sweat from their tongue.
That's why a has his tongue hanging
out when it's hot, their body
doesn't sweat water, right?
So they overheat very quickly.
Right? So they're good for sprints,
but they're not good for long term
long endurance runs. And that's what
being bipeds right. I mean, um,
I think I read somewhere that one of
the ways that we were able to get,
I'm most expensive organ is the brain.
Right?
But one of the reasons we're able to
have the brain is because when we were on
all fours,
more of our back was exposed to sunlight.
And so we had to spend more of the
water and energy cooling ourselves off.
Once we went by Piddle,
much less sun is hitting the body so you
have more water available to grow the
brain. Because the brain requires a lot
of energy and water and just really cool
things. I love that biological
development stuff I think is really,
really fascinating.
Unbelievably fascinating.
The development of the human brain as
opposed to the brains of lower hominids is
one of the biggest
mysteries in all science.
There's so many different things have
been attributed to what caused the human
brain to grow double in brain size over
a period of 2 million years is pretty
fascinating.
But thank God it happened I guess.
But this conversation probably be a
lot less entertaining if a grunting and
pounding our head forehead into the
microphone. And not only that, if,
if it was the same conversation,
who the fuck would listen drew that they
wouldn't be able to understand? Yeah,
I think,
I think that's a huge amount of human
potential that's locked up in people's
insecurities and inertia.
And uh, I, I really, um,
uh, I really would love to find
a way and you know, to just get,
get people to understand how much fun
being in motion is and how much fun
exploring and challenging yourself and
challenging the world. How much fun it is,
but I think that there's just
a lot of, I dunno, negativity,
hostility of course on the Internet
as we were talking about earlier,
it's kind of not all over the place,
but it's definitely there and I just wish
people could understand that there is
very little to be afraid of in life.
I mean other than death,
which is going to happen whether
you're busy or not. What's interesting,
we're were talking about essentially
like if we could talk to Robin Williams,
if we could pull Robin Williams aside
before he committed suicide and have these
conversations with them. If you
look at that guy, he is in a way,
a great example of someone who
paper should be unbelievably happy.
He's been insanely successful.
He is loved by millions
and yet still not happy.
And one of the reasons is you look at
his life and it's this series of things
that went wrong,
series of coke binges and alcoholism and
breakups of the marriage and regret for
the way he was raised by his parents
and all these different things that you
carry around with you like weight. And
it's very difficult to shed that weight.
I don't know what he
did besides counseling.
I Dunno if he was an exercise guy or if
he did yoga or what his diet was like.
But there's a lot of people out there
that are dragged down by their past that
right now their heart's beating,
their breathing out of their mouth,
their fucking brain is functioning,
but they're just burdened.
They're burdened by their past.
And it's a huge issue with folks
like getting a fresh start,
like getting a reset,
getting this, you know, this,
this escaping all the bullshit
of their past. It's very,
very hard for folks to do.
When I was a twine to
yeah, to went back 20, uh,
I was at the national theater school
studying acting and playwriting,
and I was in a play King Lear and we
had this delightfully insane director,
uh, who was, and, and that, so something
bad happen on stage in the play.
And, uh, we were all
method actress, you know,
I grew up on Brando and stuff like that.
So it was all internal and we were just,
uh, and so he said basically he stopped
the rehearsal when this thing happened in
the play and he said,
why isn't anyone reacting?
And we said, we all said Paul, but I felt
it inside. And he's like, this is theater,
right? Nobody has a window into your
head. You've got to do something.
And he got himself when he actually
ended up throwing chairs, he's like,
just do something to anything.
I don't care. Do a somersault.
Produce a dove from inside your cloak.
I bet do something.
So the audience knows that
something is happening.
Don't just stand there and
expect them to be mind readers.
And I think that that had a big impact
on me just in terms of life as a whole.
You have to be out there doing stuff.
I mean,
the what goes on in our heads is great,
but if it's not out there in the world,
we'll take it with us when we die and
nobody will ever know anything about it.
And a,
I just never really wanted to have a life
where I could sort of go through life
and into death like a spear into a still
like, you know, barely leaving a ripple.
Uh,
and I think that um,
the challenges of an active and
challenging life where you're, you know,
messing with society's perceptions and
trying to advance the moral course that
you are passionate about is so worth it.
I wish people could just live one
day on the other side of that fear.
I wish that people could live one day
in motion and then they would never be
satisfied with the inertia of their lives.
But until you get there,
I think it's really half the
really tough for people to,
to picture what it's like. I mean, you
know, we were talking before the show.
I mean you've, you've got a special
coming up. I mean you're doing this, you,
I mean you, you, your ferociously busy.
And I think if people who are in Nerc
could live a day in your shoes and
recognize just how much fun it is and
what a great challenge it is and how
wonderful it is to be testing yourself
on the edges of your capacities. A,
a suit for significant periods of time.
I think that they would go back and say,
oh, can't do this anymore. But I
think until you've experienced it,
that's the tough thing
until you've experienced it.
I think the inertia feels safer and
better, if that makes any sense.
Also important to surround yourself with
other people that are also trying to
accomplish things. When you surround
yourself with lazy people, it's it,
it's very taxing. And you surround
yourself that self sabotaging people.
They kind of cocked buck your
ambitions a little bit too, right?
Cause they're like, oh, I don't
know if that'll be a good idea.
I don't know if that'll work.
I don't know. Yeah, well
I lost my spinal fluid. I can't
feel my legs this. So there's a
negative aspect of them being around,
but there's certainly not the positive
aspect of being around ambitious people.
If you're around happy,
fun people that are full of energy,
you feel happy and fun and
you're full of energy as well.
With standup Comedians as a really
important factor. Like we, we,
we grow the best, we grow the most
when we're around others like us,
like the best comedy communities.
It's not one comic that stands out,
you know,
there's not,
like I started out in Boston and there
was like 10 12 great comics where I was
and one of the things about that place
as you would see all these great comics
and they went inspire you and there's
other towns where there are no great
comics and there's no great comics coming
up and you'll see like the local guys
and their dog shit,
their acts are terrible and the reason
why is they have no one to emulate.
There's no one around to build them up.
There's no community and standup comedy.
It's very important to have a community.
I did all my growing as a comic in the
communities of Boston than New York and
then La,
the two to three rather strongest
communities in the country.
Boston not so much anymore,
but at the time huge.
And now New York is still just as giant
and La is giant and those being in those
clubs and being around
those guys and seeing those,
those other people that are out
there writing new jokes and,
and constantly expanding and creating
and growing and getting better at the art
form inspires people and that's um,
that cannot be underestimated.
Surround yourself with positive
people and you will be positive.
Surround yourself with shit heads and
you'll be a shithead or at least you'll be
fighting against being a shithead.
Yeah.
I mean nobody expects to become a great
tennis player if they pay light people
who can't play. Yeah, I mean you, you
have to match yourself against the best.
And this is another thing,
last random promise of the day,
but the people who have low
expectations and low ambitions,
I also find a little frustrating at times.
I mean,
I think aim, aim your sights as high
as humanly possible. I mean there's,
there's no Schwartz and egger films unless
that crazy bastard from Austria comes
and says, I didn't barely
speak the language, but I'm
going to go marry a Kennedy,
Ran California and make some great movies.
We don't forget it. Fuck my main, well,
there's that aspect to have that aspect.
It,
that's the problem with hyper ambition.
It manifests itself and sometimes an
unfortunate and uncomfortable to literally
check the Alpha. But, um, uh, but
the people who, I mean, again,
I sort of feel like, um, you know,
I was sick last year and
confronting mortality and
all that and it's sort of how
I've lived as a whole is
whether you're great or not,
whether your ambitions are high or low,
death's going to take you either way. And,
uh,
I think that it adds to the human capital
of the world to strive to communicate,
passion, power, magic, creativity, virtue,
whatever it is that you're good at,
it adds to the human capital of the world.
We all inherit this stuff that comes
rolling down the mountain of history from
all the great people who've
come before us add a little bit.
Anything that you can do that human
momentum of, of energy and positivity.
I think that's so important. And the
people who want to do a little or get by.
I just wish I,
it's the biggest regret that people have
when their oldest that they played at
small and they didn't take the risks
that they wanted to because there's this
disaster on the other side of risk that
never seems to materialize. And um,
really it's like you're in some fight to
the battle with your own hand puppets,
you know, a fight to the death
with your own hand puppets.
I think that people just take those
gloves off and go and take life and,
and have high ambitions and forget
everybody who ridicules you for high
ambitions and great things.
Uh, they don't matter.
And that's a great speech that Robin
Williams has. I forget them. Forget them.
He says to the man who's talking
about the sweaty tooth madmen,
the boy who's got the poetic imagination,
he said, forget them. Forget them.
Focus on, on your creativity and what
is making you great. And I would really,
I think the human potential is the great
untapped resource of the planet. And uh,
I wish that there was ways to communicate.
I tried to do this of
course as best I can,
but ways to communicate to people
just how amazing a life can be,
which is a, an active, enthusiastic,
passionate and challenging.
And, um, we get this
incredibly brief opportunity.
And I said recently in a podcast,
uh,
the universe has repulsively fucked
itself senseless to give you life. I mean,
in order for us to be here,
like one single celled organisms
had to meet with each other. I mean,
that's gross.
I don't even know where they put white,
but it's really disgusting stuff that
goes on in a magnifying glass that's like
the worst porn ever.
But we're all here because
of this incredible striving
for billions of years of
this life and to not embrace
that gift of existence.
In this brief time that we have.
It just seems to me such a waste and such
a disrespect to the incredible odds of
us actually being here and being in this
relatively free country and being in
this incredible time of communication,
technology and human opportunity.
I really want people to try and
grab that as much as possible. Uh,
you do not save up points that you get to
redeem after your dad spend everything,
leave nothing on the table. And that's
what I hope people can find a way to do.
But I think by living your life,
I liked
that you set an example that
people can be inspired by.
And I think that having
these conversations and
and having something that
someone can listen to when they, they,
they hear this and they go, you know what?
I'm going to go fucking run up a hill.
I'm going to go do something.
And people do do that.
I get messages from people that
do hear these conversations at an,
it enhances their life.
And I've had so many people come up
to me after the show and say that the
podcast changed their life because they
become motivated because they never had
anybody around them that
was inspiring in any way.
And then all of a sudden they get to
hear conversations with inspirational
people and they take these conversations
and it fuels them it. And we need that.
You know, if you can't have that
community in your neighborhood, you can,
you can have that community online now.
You can have that community by having
access to these kinds of conversations,
by listening to songs that fire you up
by a book that gets you going by hearing
a conversation by there's,
there's many, many,
many methods and it's all about just
having the access to these influences by
having the access to these positive
things. And you can enhance your life.
What one man can do and what one woman
can do another man and woman can do.
And yeah, nobody needs to be denied a
great life, but you will not come to you.
You have to at least go and meet
it halfway. And I hope that people,
I know that your show gets a lot of
people roused and gets a lot of people
energetic. And that I hugely
applaud you for, I think it's a,
it's a fantastic contribution to the
world to be able to inspire people
certainly in your comedy. I mean,
which is fantastic. I mean, by the way,
if you haven't seen Joe,
go see Joe. But, uh,
I think that that energy is
incredibly positive and uh,
I think people who grew up around
negative people are neutral people.
They don't even know what it's like to
have any kind of incandescence around
them.
And if they see that,
then it awakens in them a possibility
that probably was not possible even within
their own imaginations before.
And I think that social media and
the Internet and Youtube,
it's giving people access to conversations
that they probably have been sealed
off from a it for who knows how many
generations in sectors of society have not
had access to enthusiasm, positivity,
competence, efficiency, energy.
And now there's this amazing
cross pollination of an energetic,
enthusiastic people.
We can pollinate people who otherwise
would never have had access to it.
I think what an amazing
opportunity that is for a,
for a to unleash more human potential.
Yeah. We live in awesome times. And, uh,
I want to thank you for addressing all
the criticisms and all the different
things that I,
I've been fielding and I think we
really illuminated a lot of these. Uh,
I appreciate the opportunities and,
uh, if someone wants to follow you,
it's Stefan Molyneux on Twitter.
Can you spell that out for folks?
Uh, can I give the secret handshake
cling on to enter the Celt compound?
That's most important to me.
So they can go to free domain radio.
They can youtube.com/free domain radio.
Um,
Twitter is stiff and a free
domain radio and um, yeah,
and Stefan Molyneux,
the spelling is,
it's an f s t e f a n m o l y n.
E. U. X. Amen to that. You,
that's right. That's it.
All right, well thank you very much man.
That was a lot of fun. I enjoyed it. And,
uh, thanks to our sponsor.
Thank you to legal zoom.com.
Go to legal zoom.com and use the code
word Rogan at the referral box at checkout
to save yourself some cash. Uh, we will
be back next week. As I said, Monday,
Kara Santa Maria, Tuesday,
Steve Rinella returns.
And we got some other podcasts for
later in the week as well. Denver,
see you guys soon.
I'm coming this weekend.
Recording my comedy central special
Saturday night comedy works in Denver
downtown. Wow. Big Kiss. See Ya.
Okay.