Hello,
freak bitches.
My mom was a wonderful man.
I just spent.
Oh,
you know,
she's getting old and stuff and I,
I,
I took her to see Dolly Parton and Tampa
and a Dolly Parton have seen three times
in two months.
Man,
she smells like she smells like cotton
candy and baby powder and a high note
here,
let me try to hit you.
Always hit me to cool shit.
Dolly Parton is 70 years old.
She did a three hour fucking show.
She didn't sit in one place.
You moved all over the stage.
He played piano,
Guitar,
Banjo,
flute,
and then at one point she blew a
saxophone.
Now she didn't just a saxophone,
like I had a few notes.
She played Yakety Sax,
which is like grand an,
an,
an in it that requires some fucking lung
power.
She's 70 years old.
I took my 70 year old mother to see her
and like mom's got a cane and we had to
get a people mover and stuff like that.
Like she's,
it's crazy man.
So like I took mom to go see Dolly.
Pardon my mother.
You know,
God love her,
she's amazing.
One of my favorite people in the world,
but you know,
she's like tiger,
you finally made it and I was like,
why?
And she's like,
because like we got to meet Dolly
Parton,
I was like,
mom,
you could have met Dolly.
Pardon?
Any old title and that's not a sign of
prosperity or success or something like
that.
Like that happened back on clerks or
something.
But those days when Dolly Parton was on
TV,
there was only like three channels.
Yeah.
She fills arenas like it's crazy.
It's a massive.
And just watching somebody like,
you know,
I saw,
I saw when I went up to Vancouver to
shoot an episode of the Flash,
I went and I was like,
Holy Shit.
Then there's a part of me,
of course,
I'm not a big country guy,
but my old man loved country and Western
even though we came from New Jersey and
we weren't even from like Southern
Jersey.
We're from Central Jersey.
He loved country,
West country and western.
I hated it growing up.
And he's now dead for like 12,
13 years.
And naturally the older one gets,
you hear that music,
it takes you not to the president,
but right back to your childhood.
So lately,
even though I've never been a country
person,
I find more country leaking into my life
and it has everything to do with my
father or something like that.
So I went to see the show and it was
like I might as well taking my dad with
me.
He's been dead so long.
But like that was his dream show.
Like he loved Dolly parties,
big country music fan generally love
Dolly Parton.
So I went to see the show the first time
because I was like,
I got nothing to do,
let's go.
And then I was blown away by her
showmanship,
a storyteller as well.
She doesn't just sit there and play the
music between songs.
She'll sit there and tell you a story
about growing up in the rocky mountains.
She's fucking funny dude.
I know she's got like patterns she's
probably been doing for years,
but she talks about.
She's like,
when I was a little girl,
like we went into town and they grew up
fucking poor and she's one of 13
children or something like that and
she's like,
I saw this woman,
beautiful woman,
and she's painted like an angel and she
had pretty clothes and real big,
pretty hair burn heels and a lot of
makeup.
And I said,
Mama,
who's that?
And her mom is like,
that's the town Trav,
that girl is nothing but trash.
And she goes,
I said,
that's what I want to be when I grow up.
So that's why,
that's why she's got the look.
She's got it.
She's like,
it cost a lot of money to look this
cheap.
So she's hilarious.
It's a true like even if you're not like
a Dolly Parton Fan,
like what a true night of entertainment
like,
and you just want to appreciate.
I saw her like last weekend I took mom
to see her in Tampa.
And so once innovate time I saw at the
Hollywood bowl and then uh,
like a month ago.
And then I took mom to see her in Tampa
and that was more like,
Hey,
dad would love this,
you know,
but she had this weird moment where she
met Dolly in like,
you're talking about two,
seven year old women.
And my mom went in for a fucking kiss.
Not like,
like,
I want a friendship,
but just like the way you would kiss a
friend.
But,
and then you could see Dolly who's like
had to politically maneuver strangers
for 50 years or so.
Figure out,
do I say,
Hey,
I don't kiss strangers or do I just have
her lips were going for the lips of what
she was going for.
It was awkward dude.
There was a moment where they were the
exparel.
And then finally they hugged and uh,
you know,
she was like,
my husband loved your music and shit.
It's really fucking beautiful the see.
But mom,
I love mom to death.
But mom is like such A.
Everybody's mother is very singular
individual.
But mom had this thing I was trying to
figure out.
I was like,
when did this person die?
I think we were talking about Barbara.
I was like,
when did aunt Barbara di and my mom's
like,
oh,
hold on,
and she had this thing when we were
kids,
like she get a calendar from church and
she wouldn't write on it your birthday
or a relative's birthday.
She'd write the day that they died.
So like this day was the day uncle Andy
die this day and Connie died.
So my mom keeps all that information.
So she goes,
hold on.
She comes out with a box of like funeral
mass cards.
Like when somebody dies,
you go to a funeral,
there's a little trading card that has
picture of St John.
The bag has a person's name and when
they were born,
when they were dead,
my mom has like a collection,
the way you would collect baseball cards
and shit and we spread them all out on
the table is 12 significant deaths in
our family.
She had lots more,
but the ones that would matter to both
me and her in our immediate zone,
a family and between 12 deaths I was
able to quiz my mother like who died in
1980 and she was like,
oh,
that was grandpa Smith.
Like she is my mom's obsessed with death
but not in a like death is metal.
When she was a child in Catholic school,
they tried to explain hell her,
you know,
as you do in Catholic school,
and she was fucking far too young to get
the idea.
So death has been her obsession her
whole life.
Staving it off,
stopping it from taking not just her but
her family,
you know,
she lost her husband to it.
We all.
Death is just a natural part of the
process.
My mom finds it like she's terrified,
but now I as a,
as a creative person,
and I wonder if you feel the same way
and I fancy myself a creative person.
Some people like you,
not very creative,
but I fancy myself a creative person.
No caveats.
Death to me is not scary as much as like
a repugnant idea where you're like,
what?
Stop all this.
Like I'm just getting the hang of it.
I'm just learning like I got so many
more jokes to tell and Shit like that.
Like death to people who make stuff like
us and that's why you might be the
exception because you deal with death on
a regular basis.
Like with hunting and shit like that.
Like it's just something that probably
enters your purview farm with a month,
but it is like one of those things,
man,
were you like wow,
I hadn't really thought about that too
often,
but she's thinks about.
Often when I think of death I'm
irritated by it because I'm like,
it's unfair.
Like why?
Like.
But I imagine if I was by my
grandmother,
my grandmother lost her sight 12,
14 years before she died and I loved
hanging out with her.
I just play cards with her and shit like
that.
And then when she lost her sight,
she did.
She was no longer interested in living.
So she would sit around and be like,
how are you gram?
You go visit her,
she'd be sitting in the dark and shit,
listen to the radio,
maybe no longer crocheting like she used
to.
We used to play cards,
can do any of that shit.
So she just sat there and he'd be like,
how are you?
And she'd be like,
well I asked him to take me and he said
he didn't answer,
still not today.
And I was like,
Ooh Graham.
She's like Jesus every day I pray that
he finally take me and I'm still here.
And she grew slowly,
grew to be bitter about life and shit.
Now,
from where I sit right now,
I'm the guy that's like,
I never want this party to an oh shit.
But I guess there could be a time in my
life where you know,
everyone you know and love is past and
you just get to a place where you're
like,
you know what?
I'm okay.
Like who was it a,
the singer that that just passed a law
was the guy that sang Hallelujah.
Leonard Cohen,
Leonard Cohen didn't interview like
before he passed like five months,
five weeks,
maybe 40 past where he was like,
yeah,
I'm ready for death.
He's pretty much done everything I
wanted to do and I'm,
I'm ready for it,
and he went fairly short there.
Shortly thereafter.
Grandma didn't Ms. Young on for a while
but wanted to die.
I hope I'm never that person.