Let's, we're going to get to
this next and I, I respect you.
I want you guys to yell at each other
for three minutes while I go pee.
I gotta pee too. Okay. We'll do it in
shifts. We'll do it. I'll go first. Okay.
Anyways,
you are someone that I could talk
to about the flat earth conspiracy.
You don't believe in flat earth,
but you can kind of understand
where I'm coming from.
What if I finance a research
ship and make a documentary?
I can't go away for three months. I will
pay one of them. Which one can you race?
We're going to need a, you guys go
into the moon or in orbit, okay.
Raised the money for a trip. Okay. You out
this the deal. Just go pee. Go Pee, man.
So I'm going to, we're going to do this.
So Joe Rogan. Yeah, no, no.
We're going to do this gentleman.
You're going to find the edge of
the world. They ice caps, caps.
They're knocking things off the drop
off with my iPhone. Go Pee, man.
Hopi. Don't you have to go? We're
going to send someone else. Alex. Hey,
I got to back them up to be the
one that goes, wait a minute,
let me tell you something right now.
I came here and I proved they're
keeping babies alive and dangler organs.
How did you prove that Jamie pulled
some shit. They admitted that.
Normalizing it. No, the fuck the governor.
You really think there's people out there
campaigning for late term abortions.
You'd think that Shit's real.
You. They say six rounded Monday.
Who would campaign for it that they lost
their fucking Kelly already catch.
So you're telling me it isn't real when
they had a fucking Goddamn fucking set
it.
That's a conspiracy theory
that you're fucking top
of your about to get it.
They're killing it already born babies.
Stop fucking lying. God fucking damn.
I'm getting pissed out. Don't
get pissed. You saw the dude.
It's fucking
fucking
fucking owls.
Let me claim the course.
I believe that we went into
a long conversation about
we played. I heard it. Okay.
You heard it.
I heard the whole podcast,
but come on at you in my psychosis is
reality is so crazy that I always thought
I was so tough. That doesn't have to pay
anymore. It'll piss a little bit out.
Point is the point is, is
that the point is, is that,
why are we debating whether the
earth is flat? Dude, they're keeping,
they have human animal hybrids.
Okay.