The joe rogan experience. You know,
I remember coming back and, um,
this kid beat the shit out of me.
Bobby Buckley and my father said,
what are you doing at home? You
got to go back out there. What?
I'm going to go back out and fight them
against fucking all right. Yeah. But I,
you know,
there's a lot of different ways to be like
in Charlestown grown up. I mean, I was,
I grew up with some guys that were like
unbelievable. Like, you know, there's a,
there's a whole moral thing maybe or a
social thing about say robbing a bank.
I mean, would that ever
fricking cross your mind? No,
but that's a Charles town thing. That's
one thing that is true about that movie,
that town, but, but what I was in awe
of people that would do it. It's like,
where do you get the boss?
You know?
And I'll never forget this friend of mine,
Joey Rocco's no longer with us.
So I see him up at government some.
You remember government center? Yeah.
So I see him up there and he's got
like his lunch and I said, Joe,
how you doing? And he's kind of blew me
off and I seen him a week later. He said,
say Swayne's, what's up? I said,
what's up? You blew me off a week ago.
He said, Oh, I'm so sorry.
I was waiting to Rob Crimson travel and
I had my gun there and I was into cause
interrupting his work.
So he came into Nick's
comedy stop to 400 people.
I did fantastic. I was like practically
a standing ovation, whatever.
So Joe's in the audience, right. And
I, I, so I talked to him afterwards.
So there's a number of things he could
say like, Jeez, I liked his show.
I didn't like your show.
Good for you getting out of Charlestown.
He gave me this look. I was like, wow,
it's got to be a lot of money in here.
I said, you think I'm here
to case the joint for you?
It was unbelievable.
We used to,
a part of the thing that bugged shots
down growing up was he had a shoplifter
that was, did you do that when
you were a kid? Like, shit,
I got caught shoplifting candy.
Why Andy? Yeah, you were bad.
You probably was terrified. Right? Again,
I got brought into a manager's office,
I think it was 12. Oh yeah, I
got in trouble. I was terrible
too. I was so paranoid.
But anyway,
there was a department store called
Jordan Marsh and my job was to catch a
football. They throw me the football,
I'd catch it and run down Tremont street.
So we've just, you know,
stolen a football. Right.
So that's, that was the Gig.
So one time I'm up there and uh,
saw the kid system, he pick up the end
of this cannula. I said what? He said,
grab the end of the cannula still in a
fucking Canoga what's all walking down?
Wash the student Boston with a canoe
right now. I don't know where you're from,
but it's not a big item.
And Charlestown canoes and the projects,
you know what I mean?
It's like not something that you
felt you couldn't fence it then.
Nothing's like the four of us though.
The chemistry with the finance can't.
You can't fuck with it.
No.
It is the best and it's the most fun
by far is the most fun to watch, right?
Different dynamic. Yeah, but the talking
over, my God, I tried to listen to it.
You did.
I tried to listen to something that
you do because I want to know what it
sounded like. We were talking
over everybody. It's terrible.
I haven't been that drunk and high
and a long time and it was awesome.
People for whatever reason,
love those kind of chaos shows like
that Alex Jones show, they love chaos.
They'll love it.
They'll love a straw and stoned and an
interdimensional child molesters and
fucking, they love all that shit.
They love it off the charts. Nuts.
That Alex Jones one though.
I told you I've never been a fan of his.
Then I watched it. I'm like got
gotta like them now. People are mad.
Some people are mad at me, but you know
there's nothing I can do about that.
There's going to be mad at me anyway.
But one of the things that they were
saying was, you know, fuck you for, uh,
there were saying, giving them a platform
for normalizing him. And I'm like,
you've got to understand. That's how
I know him. I know him like that.
That's how I know him. I know that guy.
That guy. Yes. That guy that came on here,
and this is the guy that,
by the way on his show said he was
gonna kick my ass and break my legs and
fucking all kinds of crazy shit and
I want to find him in the UFC fight.
I'm a offer him $1
million. Like I, I knew,
I knew him. I know the real him. I'm like,
well, we're not in front of each other.
You could say crazy shit. And
like I'm immune man. I don't care.
It doesn't bother me. I
don't care anymore. Let's,
he's doing an entertainment show.
He is doing entertainment but,
but when I know is the Alex
Jones, those here, and by the way,
he was right about a lot of shit.
A lot of the crazy shit that he's saying
about about fucking human pig hybrids
that they're working on those and
actually making human pig hybrid fetuses.
That's real.
They really aren't.
The problem is he throws so much
shit out there all at one time.
I don't know what to
believe in what exactly.
And you got to slow down to look into all
of that and you got to go sweat. Whoa,
Whoa, Whoa, whoa. Let's take
start. Start over again. What,
what's happening on the moon?
He's for sure crazy. I like him,
but he's,
he's crazy.
But I think the crazy is okay and it's
entertaining and I'm not a fucking child.
So if you want a nerf the world and
make the world so that only children can
watch everybody cause like make,
make things their own that are safe
for everyone, including children. Well,
I don't want that. I want,
I'm a discerning adults.
I'm pretty rational and I can figure
out what's real and what's nonsense.
But I don't look at the political spectrum
of people when I'm looking at you.
You have a bias,
you're biased and you are,
you're targeting specific
individuals because your rule
support this perspective.
No. Well, can you be clear though and
like what rules support that perse,
but specifically the,
the easiest one is mis-gendering right?
Because that's so clearly ideological.
If you ask a conservative
what is mis-gendering,
they'll say if someone is biologically
male and you call them, you know,
she a biologic and man you called
the machine that's mis-gender as a
conservative view, the, the, the
progressive view is inverted.
So now you actually have in your
policies a rule against the conservative
perspective.
I have a rule against the
abuse and harassment of
trans people on our platform.
That's what my rule is.
Can we just give context in the
background as to why the why that is.
And I brought some,
some research.
So we obviously received
a lot of feedback.
So we don't make these roles in a vacuum.
And just to be clear,
we have a bunch of people all around the
world to give us context and the types
of behavior they're seeing,
how that translates into real world harm.
And they give us feedback and they tell
us like you should consider different
types of rules, different types of
perspectives, different. Like for example,
when we try to enforce hateful conduct
in a are hateful conduct policy and in
particular country,
we are not going to know all the slur
words that are used to target people of a
particular race or a particular religion.
So we're going to rely on building out
a team of experts all around the world
who are going to help
us enforce our rules.
So in the particular case
of Ms Generating, I'm just
trying to pull up, um,
some of the studies that we looked at,
but we looked at the American Association
of Pediatrics and looked at the number
of transgender youths that were
committing suicide. It's an astronomical,
I'm sorry, I can't find it right
now in front of me. It's a really,
really high statistic.
That's like 10 times what the normal
suicide rate is of normal teenagers.
And we looked at the causes of what that
was happening and a lot of it was not
just violence towards those individuals,
but it was bullying behavior and what was,
what were those bullying behaviors
that were contributing to that.
And that's why we made this rule because
we thought and we believe that those
types of behaviors were happening on
our platform and we wanted to stop it.
Now there are exceptions to this
rule. We don't, and this is all,
this isn't about like public figures and
there's always gonna be public figures
that you're going to want to talk
about and that's, that's fine.
But this is about are you doing something
with the intention of abusing and
harassing a trans person on the platform
and are they viewing it that way and
reporting it to us so that we take action.
So I will just state,
I actually agree with the rule on,
from my point of view,
I agree that bullying and harassing
Trans People's in higher, entirely wrong.
I disagree with it,
but I just want to make sure it's
clear to everybody who's listening.
My point is simply that,
you know,
Ben Shapiro went on a talk show and
absolutely refused and that's his shtick,
you know, and he's one of the
biggest podcasts in the world.
So if you have all of his millions upon
millions of followers who are looking at
this rule saying,
this goes against my view of the world
and it's literally 60 plus million in
this country, you do have a rule that's
ideologically bent and, and it's,
it's true. You, you did the
research, you believe this.
Well then you have Ben Shapiro who did
his risk research and doesn't believe it.
Yeah. And I relied on the
American Association of
Pediatrics and uh, you know,
human rights council and other,
and I'm sure he has his sources too,
for when he gives his statements.
The point is,
I just wonder if they have
that context. I mean, that's,
and that's where we have also failed.
It's just explaining the
why behind a lot of reasons.
I would agree.
And I think it's fine.
You did research and you
found this to be true,
but we can't simply say maybe Ben Shapiro
and the other conservatives who feel
this way, don't know.
We have to. We can't.
You know the point I'm trying to make us.
It's simply whether you believe it,
whether you justified or not is
not the point. The point is you do,
you do have this role. That role is at
odds with conservatives, period. Well,
I think, I think that
you're, you're generalizing,
but I think it is really important as
Jack said, to the why behind these things,
the why is to protect people from
abuse and harassment on our plot.
No, I understand. But you've
essentially created a protected class.
If this is the case, because despite
these studies and what you know,
these studies are showing
there's a gigantic suicide
rate amongst trans people,
period. It's a 40% it's an
outrageously large. Now,
whether that is because of
gender dysphoria with us
because of the complications
from sexual surgery,
sexual transition surgery,
whether it's because of bullying,
whether it's because of this awful
feeling of being born in the wrong gender,
whether that all that
is yet to be determined.
The fact that they've shown that there's
a large amount of trans people that are
committing suicide,
I don't necessarily think that that makes,
that makes sense in terms of
people from someone's perspective,
like a Ben Shapiro saying that
if you are biologically female,
if you are born with
a double x chromosome,
you will never be x, y.
If he says that that's,
that's a violation of
your policy and this is,
you are creating a protected class too
to be fair targeted
or we're targeting to
express that opinion.
So would it be selling entitled
to express that opinion? You know,
our bodies will be living differently in
a world that's two degrees warmer than
they are today. We can't really
predict what those impacts will be,
but it could be quite dramatic.
And they could be things that we can't
even imagine today because they're,
you know,
by some counts,
millions of bacteria inside us that
we haven't even identified yet.
Okay.
Jesus Christ, you're freaking
me out, David. God dammit.
It's a crazy world out there.
It will, not just crazy,
but it seems like when you're
talking about things like this,
when you're talking about climate change
affecting our actual gut parasites or
our gut biome, and that this literally
could change the way human beings behave.
I mean,
these are all things that I've
never heard discussed and it just,
it's really terrifying,
really is, you know, I mean,
and part of the problem is people hear
like, oh, relax, everything's fine.
This is this constant thing that we do
where if it's not affecting us currently,
right now in the moment,
there's not a fire in front of us.
We don't worry about it.
It's a weird compartment,
compartmentalization thing
that human beings do.
Yeah. And, um, it's, you know,
you'd think that evolution would
have trained us differently.
You think that evolution would have
trained us over time to have at least some
longterm
capacity. And I guess we do have some
long term planning capacity, but it's um,
we choose to think we're in really
short term ways just about all the time.
People don't understand.
They think just because someone doesn't
have the best vocabulary or because they
don't have a, a comprehensive
education that they're not intelligent.
And that's a big mistake.
No Tyson, Tyson's intelligent. Uh,
I remember going to the
Catskills when I was, uh,
I won the world junior championships
in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.
And I remember the
American team was saying,
oh well you never fought the best of them.
I couldn't find the best.
I thought American sent them
best team. Yeah. But one guy,
he doesn't like taking plans in this.
Managers don't like taking plans either.
Cause I'm like, who's that? And he
told me it was Mike Tyson custom model.
So me and my trainer, we left Canada
and we drove all the way up there.
And while we were up there, raise the
Roderick was up there and they said, oh,
raise really came to inspire with
us. So okay, I spar with the,
I'm here for four days.
So first time Tyson actually met me,
you know, he was Nice Guy, really
nice guy, took me in his room,
showed me some old flicks I've never seen
before of old time fighters would tell
me about each fighter, like he
studied them and then, um, you know,
this is where he got his old star is
his style of fighting from. And uh,
first day in the first day in the gym,
Bell went,
he came across and he was trying
to kill me. Like, you know,
I did my Muhammad Ali thing,
obviously stayed away from his power,
but the first day was really hectic and
then the second day was a little hectic
and that got better as it went along.
And the last day is I got actually
the better of him the last day.
And I remember Costa Motto and Mike,
you're going to meet him some day,
don't you do that?
And that always echoed in my
mind that will we ever fight?
Will we have a fight? Cause custom model
said that we're going to fight. Well,
and it did happen. And there's
footage of it. Yeah. Wow.
Lennox has the footage of it. Footage
of the training sessions, barring,
how old was Tyson at the time?
Tyson was like, uh, he was about 52.
No, no. How old was he at the time?
Oh, at the time. 15. Um, he was,
he was younger than me. I was
on Sunday. He's about 17. Wow.