Yeah,
my oldest one's super.
Here we go.
Five,
four,
three,
two,
one.
Ben Aspirin,
ladies,
gentlemen.
Dude,
I've talked about you on this podcast at
least a dozen times.
You are the number one guy that I'm most
disappointed.
Never fought in UFC.
Yeah,
I always get,
whenever you talk about me,
I get like 15 texts.
Like,
hey joe,
joe is talking about you now and you
know,
they'll send me clips or whatever.
So obviously appreciate that.
Um,
the.
Yeah,
I never,
I never really got to fight those top
guys.
And it was for reasons beyond my
control.
Yeah,
and you're done now.
I saw,
I said,
I said I don't want to say I'm done,
period.
I said I'm done.
Excluding the fact that I get to fight
and prove I'm number one.
That would be the excluding fest.
So if you could get in the UFC you'd be
willing to do it again.
I mean,
I don't care where it is,
right?
I,
I really genuinely don't.
And obviously that would be the thing
that makes sense,
but there is legislation like the Ali
[inaudible] and the things going
through.
So I don't know that maybe,
you know,
I'm still 33 so I'm not old and you
know,
polluted GSP took four years off from
one flight to next fight.
So I'm not saying I'm an age overnight.
Well your style to you avoided so much
damage I think.
I think you hit one once this until
2017.
So yeah,
I didn't get hit once in three fights.
I should tell people you were fighting
in one FC,
which is a big Asian organizations like
the Asian version of the UFC.
Yeah.
So one FC started in 2012,
I think.
Um,
obviously my contract with Belcher came
up in 2013 and then there was that
negotiation process since I obviously
went south.
And what happened there?
You were the champ of belt tour and then
all of a sudden you left and everyone
was like,
so you're,
you're still undefeated,
right?
I'm undefeated.
18 went off,
what the fuck happened?
That beltour let go.
That wasn't what happened.
So there's,
there's so much misinformation out there
and you know,
uh,
I'm popular but I'm not that popular.
And so a,
lots of times in my story gets missed
toll because I get spoken over by other
people.
Right.
And they don't hear what I say.
So here,
here's what happened.
I'm obviously so prior to me and Bella
tour,
hector and Eddie were the ones that
left,
right?
There were.
Hector was the Lombard and Eddie
Alvarez.
Alvarez was the UFC.
Both of them.
Both the middleweight champion.
Then the lightweight champion.
They both got taken care of pretty well.
But if you,
if you remembered Eddie situation,
I don't know if you remember this,
he got an offer from the UFC still under
the matching period.
Beltre beltre says we matched it.
Right.
And in terms of what was in the
contract,
it was matched.
Right?
But because Belterra has no paper view
venue,
well if UFC says we'll pay you and pay
per view belts as well.
We will too.
But that's not real life,
right?
That's what they've done to pay per view
shows ever.
And they've never met any type of
threshold.
So you know,
they say imagine what it doesn't say.
I don't know if you remember that they
went to court over it and the UFC one,
Eddie has got the right to.
I'm sorry he didn't.
When he,
he somehow did like a one more fight in
bellator and then with the UFC,
I don't know exactly what the finality
of that case was,
but anyways,
when that happened,
his,
his
contract became public knowledge.
Right.
And so a lot of UFC fighters were pissed
because he,
they gave him a whole bunch of money and
so when I was 12 and now I've had my
last fight in Bellator,
Oregon.
Sandra crush coughed July 30th,
May 31st of 2013,
beat him up pretty good.
And then I had a 12 month matching
period.
And so what was expressed to me by the
UFC brass was that you need to get rid
of your matching clause and we will make
you an offer,
but we will not make you an offer until
that happens.
Get rid of your matching.
Yes.
How do you do that?
Well,
here,
here's how I went about doing it exist
12 months,
right?
That's a frequent.
I'm not going to sell it for 12 months,
so I'd called Buerger's did it and say,
hey bjorn,
I'm not going to resign.
Please let me this guy who was running
belt or correct.
Yeah.
And now he got fired.
Um,
and bjorn had a terrible reputation,
but I never,
I had a decent relationship with them.
I never like butted heads too bad.
So every they said,
bjorn,
let me go.
I'm not coming back.
And then so everyone says,
well,
Bell tour didn't want to resign me.
Well that's not true at all.
Every day is bjorn.
Let me go.
If you aren't,
let me go because,
you know,
I love challenges.
What I love more than anything in the
world is a challenge myself.
If you look at my wrestling career,
that's what it's all about.
Taking the next best thing every single
time.
And so yeah.
So finally in,
and I'll just time Dana and the UFC is
saying we want to ask when we were up in
the outskirt I'm ranked number seven in
the world or you know,
somewhere around there 12 and now.
And so I remember I was going to the
Asian food store cause I was gonna make
some tom cost soup and bjorn calls me
and said,
you're released full,
full,
you're released,
you can go.
And I say,
I appreciate that.
So Friday morning was Thursday night,
Friday morning,
it's in November,
sometime in May,
mid November,
I'm morning,
they fax over the release,
my management faxes it to UFC
headquarters and all of a sudden that
afternoon there's a little scrum
wherever was asking the questions and
the data says we're not interested in
Ben Aspirin.
And I said,
wait,
what just happened there?
Right?
Because for the last three months they
were saying we were interested,
where's your where's?
And now I finally produced this full
release for Bella tour that I got and
now they're not interested.
And so I said,
wow,
I just got caught in the middle of this.
And was there a reason given also.
Okay,
so the Monday.
So then I say F that I buy.
So I bought a plane ticket to Vegas for
Monday,
so that was Friday.
That happens.
I say,
fuck that.
I'm going to vegas.
I'm not taking this shit,
you know,
so a Monday I buy my plane ticket to
Vegas,
I fly out to Vegas.
Do you have to headquarters a lot.
I met with Lorenzo.
Dana was on the little speakerphone
daily and they offered me a contract but
it will be confidential and I would have
to fight one fight for the world series
of fighting,
which is like,
well that's bizarre.
What?
Yeah.
And fight for the world series a funding
relationship with the world series.
Like a feeder
organization at that time
thing.
Yeah.
Marlin Mariah's.
Just engage you.
Both those guys came from champs over
there.
Yeah.
I think the relationship is very hazy
between the old world series of fighting
in the UFC because there was also.
People don't want the other way.
Right.
Andre Arlovski gets dropped in the FC
goes to world series.
Anthony Johnson,
boom.
All these people.
So they say one fight,
one fight,
world series of fighting.
We will pay Zoopla.
We'll pay you what you do.
One fight.
I say let that's F it up,
but okay.
I said,
I don't think anyone's gonna go for it,
but I'll do it.
So I leave and uh,
about six hours later I got a phone call
and says,
that deal is no longer available.
We're not going to make you an offer.
Yeah.
So wow.
And you have no idea why?
Well,
I,
so I,
here's my guess.
I've never got to sit face to face
meeting and say,
what was your problem with me?
I think there's four things.
My mind,
number one,
he didn't really like me.
I'm stemming from the.
I called them out on the steroid thing
where he said,
it's impossible and this is where I
disagree,
is impossible to test all UFC athletes.
I said,
well,
that's not true.
You started does it all over the world
for all kinds of athletes.
Right.
You can do it.
It's just expensive,
but let's just call it what it is.
You're a private business.
You don't have to do drug tests.
It's good.
Obviously they do it now.
Do it now.
Do it through Usada.
So you were totally right.
Yeah.
So I was correct and now.
But that was,
you know,
when Dana is wrong in an argument and
he's got this huge army that follows him
and he said I'd rather hit.
I think his quote was bet because I'd
rather watch fucked and better ask him
fight,
you know,
I think he said something like
ambien takes.
Ben Asked her if it goes asleep.
Yeah,
there there's a few of them.
So the personal attacks started.
Right.
So that,
that's number one.
Number two,
my fighting style is not highly
attractive,
but I also think that's a little bit of
fake news because if you look at
Georgetown peers to consistently knobs,
Mcgregor's trumped him,
but only a couple of times,
but if you will,
a consistent basis.
George Saint Pierre is the number one
draw of all time.
He heavily relied on takedowns and
ground and pound.
I mean he didn't have a finish in like
five years or something.
Let me
say what my take has always been on you
and that style is that it's important
and that it really.
It really works.
What you're able to do really works.
And I've always said this,
and it was proven on a Saturday night in
this deep Emile Francis and modified
wrestling is the most important part of
MMA.
Absolutely.
Ability to take the fight to the ground.
Obviously Steve Bay has a lot of other
attributes.
He took tremendous punches in that
fight.
I mean,
I know you didn't get a chance to watch
it,
but I saw some highlights that.
Holy Shit,
I mean the first round was chaos.
I mean Francis and Ghana was a
terrifying guy and Steve Bay took the
shots,
use great movement.
You striking of his own,
but most importantly after awhile he got
his wrestling going and then once he got
in to the ground and gone,
I didn't have any answers.
He didn't know what to do.
What your,
what you've been able to do to guys like
Douglas Lema,
who just fought rory macdonald for the
bell to our title.
Really good fight chorus goff,
who is another fantastic fight who was
beaten a lot of really top guys.
You're able to use your wrestling and
completely nullify all their striking
and offense.
Yeah,
that's a huge part of fighting.
Fighting is not what's exciting for
people to watch,
fighting is what actually works and what
you've been able to do time and time
again is take these guys who looked like
world beaters and completely nullify
their offense,
taken to the ground and beat the shit
out of him.
That's huge.
That's very,
very important.
Yeah,
absolutely.
And so,
you know,
not so we can get back to the UFC thing,
but.
So yeah,
I mean when I started fighting,
right,
it was just like,
hey,
let's go fight.
I,
I didn't really have a coaching and so I
didn't move to Duke's until two.
One soup.
Rufus.
Yes.
Until 2010 I think.
So I started.
No,
2011.
I'm sorry,
because I was in Arizona.
I was coaching for Arizona State
University,
but when I moved there,
I know,
hey,
the uh,
there's a lot of elite strikers in this
gym.
I said,
I'm,
I'm never going to be elite striker,
but if no one can hit me,
they can't beat me.
They're not going to last me.
They're not going to have crap on me.
They're not going to beat me if they
can't knock me out,
they're not going to beat me.
Plain and simple.
So my whole goal was how do I not get
hit,
not I,
I don't need to be a great striker
hitting people.
I just need to not get hit.
If you can't knock me out,
I'm going to eventually get you on the
ground and I'm going to beat your ass.
Right?
Right.
And so that was kind of my whole goal
when I got an MBA.
It's how do I not get knocked out?
Right.
And so you said,
obviously I found a really good way to
do that and it added a lot of longevity
in my career where I wasn't taking
damage a lot of other people were
taking.
And I think there's also a lot of other
things to being a really high level
wrestler that you know,
besides obviously you can control where
the fight happens,
right?
But there's a lot of other things that
high level wrestling provides us,
right?
That came from that world that other
disciplines don't get a lot of
competition.
We compete thousands of times.
Right?
How to get our mind right.
I'm these wrestlers are just strong and
there's just a different strength.
I just actually I got to go workout with
term burrows last week because a midtown
world champ and it's like,
you forget how strong wrestlers are.
Like you grabbed them.
You're like,
good God.
This guy is like,
you know,
I don't feel that from and people.
I grabbed him and I'm like,
oh my.
Everywhere.
It's like,
there's no worries week.
I'm very,
very disciplined,
right?
Because wrestlers like we've been in the
system from youth wrestling high school
wrestling to college said,
well we're under,
you know,
coaches and have a very strict training
plan and understand how to put a
training regimen together where a lot of
other martial arts don't have that kind
of structured system.
So I think there's a lot of advantages
that we as a wrestlers have when we come
into mixed martial arts.
And if I could add to that,
the intention is pure.
It's pure for competition because
there's no financial reward.
It's not a bunch of people that are
getting into wrestling because they want
to get rich.
It's a bunch of people that really want
to prove that they're the best and so
you have so many top flight guys that
are incredibly mentally strong feeding
off of each other,
knowing that they're going to be
competing against each other and almost
no financial possibilities except for
coaching.
Well yeah,
there's.
I mean now so 2018 to 20 2008 when I was
wrestling and then when I decided to
make that jump mma
there is a lot better financial
structure for senior level athletes now.
None of them are getting rich and
there's only about a dozen of them
making a decent living.
Right.
And so,
which is crazy.
There's thousands of wrestlers.
Exactly.
So your points mostly correct,
but there are a handful of top United
States athletes now who can do nothing
but Russell where when I was in in 2008
when I was trained,
that wasn't even the case.
I had to go do camps.
I was coaching at Missouri,
so I was doing other things in addition
to wrestling.
So like an Olympic athlete.
What,
what else would they do to make money?
Well,
so like in 2008 I was doing a lot of
camps,
right?
You can travel around the country,
do,
can't make money.
I'm coach a college team that was making
money that way.
So the handful of things like that,
like wow,
it wasn't just wake up and train every
single day,
but the athletes of today that you were
saying,
now that's what they're doing.
That's it coaching and bunch of
different things here.
No,
no,
no.
Some of them don't have jobs saying that
just do it from where are they getting
the money?
Jordan burroughs and James Green,
for example,
sponsorships are slightly more lucrative
than they were.
Then there's something called the
regional training center system,
um,
which,
you know,
most major colleges have one that's a
lot more lucrative and that's
fundraising,
right?
They're not,
they're not earning money that the RTC
people go say,
hey,
rich guy,
would you like to fund this program?
That'll help us develop Olympic
athletes.
Sure.
Okay.
Right.
And then the United States,
a USC has slightly more funding given to
USA wrestling than in the past.
Well,
it's the tragic story of John Dupont.
I mean,
that's literally why that whole,
if people have seen that movie,
what movie?
Carl Fox.
Fox catcher.
Yeah.
Awful too crazy story of Dave and Mark
Schultz and this millionaire or
billionaire crazy guy wound up shooting
Dave Schultz and uh,
was just Weirdo guy that was running
this camp and these guys kind of got
stuck training with this gap because I
mean,
and that's 96 was when Schultz got shot.
Right?
And so that's 12 years prior to my
Olympic birth and,
and so then it's even worse.
I mean these guys are literally making
nothing.
And then,
you know,
let me go back to the argument of
amateurism and the Olympics is stupid,
which was abolished like 92 with the
dream team was kind of totally abolished
with amateurism.
But yeah,
those guys in that era,
the 84,
88,
92 90,
they were making nothing.
And so when this guy,
John Dupont offers them money and
stipends and places to live,
they don't really have a better option
and it's freaking sad to be honest about
it.
And then obviously USA wrestling
sanctioned him because he gave you as a
resident a lot of money.
So yeah,
it was really bad thing.
And,
and so we're doing a lot better in 2018
than we were 10 years ago and way,
way better than we were doing 20 years
ago.
Yeah.
The Olympic thing where they try to
treat the Olympics,
like it's an amateur sport event,
it's a business you're making absolutely
aliens and billions of dollars off these
athletes who get paid zero is to me it's
disgusting.
It's just this relic of ancient thinking
and these guys are using it to steal
money from young athletes.
That's what I think.
I
think the other thing is theft.
Yeah.
I usually don't know who ma,
who's more evil than us or the IOC or
the NCA because NCA runs right along the
same lines and I think both are pretty
evil in both are archaic and both DDB
changed.
And you know,
if you could abolish the NCAA and the
IOC,
that'd be fantastic for athletes
worldwide.
Yeah.
Well,
especially when you look at the football
teams that are getting literally
billions and billions of dollars every
year and these athletes are ruined in
their lives.
I mean football players that may be play
one,
two seasons,
if they're lucky,
they get their back blown out,
their legs get blown out and then they
never have an nfl career and meanwhile
the university has made tons of money,
tons of money and they make nothing.
Yeah,
and to make that even worse because I
actually had to.
I had a whole podcast about this
argument with someone and to make that,
and we're on the same side of this,
but to make it even worse,
if you're an ncaa athlete,
Joe,
you can't even make money off your own
image and likeness.
Yeah.
You can't have a youtube channel where
you can say it's crazy.
So not only will they not pay you
anything,
which I think we can debate and argue on
that,
but the fact that they can't make money
off their own name,
own image and likeness,
that's should be criminal for that to
happen.
Jim,
you were telling me about this right?
Like a guy got in trouble for having a
youtube channel where punter for like a
college football team or a kicker to
remember his name.
I don't remember his name at all and
there was a.
There was a wrestler from the University
of I to say University of Minnesota.
He made a rap album and he had to either
quit the wrestling team or or donate all
the money back or something like that.
It's like Rah Rah rap in wrestling.
Have they have nothing to do with each
other.
The fact that he can't go make money off
freaking recording an album is
mindblowing.
It's disgusting because you're keeping a
kid from being industrious.
Keeping a a young guy.
I was trying to find his way through the
world.
You keeping them from being successful,
but though that kind of success,
like figuring out a way to make some
money off of our name,
doing rap that could lead to all sorts
of paths in life.
Like he's.
He's learning as a young guy like,
hey look,
I could be industrious.
I can go do this.
I can be creative.
I can go do that.
Like,
this is what we should be encouraging
people to do to take chances and make
money.
The idea that you're saying like somehow
or another this spoils his amateur
athletic standing.
It's just stupidity.
I think it's fucking disgusting.
It drives me nuts.
Agree.
One hundred percent.
It just drives me crazy.
So we're back to your situation with the
UFC.
So the UFC says we're not interested in,
you know,
offer no offer.
So Bella tours released you.
So I,
I had spent three months.
Do you think you,
do you feel like the use might've
played?
They played me her cell.
Okay.
So number the reasons David doesn't like
me,
number one.
Number two,
my style and not that great,
right?
Didn't you say something like he's a
bald steroid.
So it was mostly after the fact that,
you know,
after that went down that I really
torture.
Um,
but,
um,
you know,
but the original one was he's lying
about the Usada thing.
So that was the simpler the.
So those people who say me and Dana had
beef prior to me
not getting an offer.
Have you met him?
Yeah,
I mean,
yeah.
Talk to them.
We've never had a length conversation.
So great guy.
A lot.
When you get the wrong impression of
him.
I mean,
I really love the guy.
Yeah,
you and I have had different
experiences.
I just feel like I should be there when
people have experienced.
Let me let you know the Dana.
I know.
Yeah.
So,
um,
so that would be two.
Number three,
I think obviously stealing a key piece
away from Bella tour was important to
them.
Um,
and then number four,
I think they thought I really had the
ability to be their champion and if
someone can be a belt or champion and
make this transition directly to the IFC
and then be the UFC champion.
I,
you know,
didn't remember this when they're going
on right down.
Spike now that bell toward.
Use that to say,
look,
we're the same.
He was a champion.
He's a champion there.
So I think those four things are.
And I've had,
I've never got to sit down face to face
Dana and say,
why was there no offer that I've never
gotten?
You know,
like when Anthony Pettis was the champ
and I'm helping coach him,
or Tyra was,
I've haven't had more than five words a
day in passing.
Right.
And so it will be really interesting to
me to sit down and say what was the tell
me for real because I have my
assumptions on what the deal was,
but I don't really know.
And then if I have to add number five,
number five is I think he got the idea
that I would never be a yes man,
which I'm not going to be.
Never would be where Dana really kind of
likes the yes man champion to me.
You see he's got,
he's got some heat with Tyron,
he's got some heat with steep bay as we
saw on Saturday night and he dated.
Really struggles with the personalities
that won't cater to what he wants to
happen.
Well,
fighters very rarely are.
Yes men.
Then that's by nature of who they are a
little bit.
Yeah.
Especially the really good ones,
especially as things start going well
and start going their way.
They realize they're the fucking man.
I mean this is.
If you're the guy who running the
division,
you're the guy who's running the
you're not going to take any shit from
anybody.
Yeah,
but that's [inaudible] you see as some
of these guys ascend right up the ranks,
they do.
Like John Jones started having trouble
with Dana.
Right.
But didn't have it.
He was.
Jones was having trouble with
everybody's.
His problems I think had very little to
do with Dana and more to do with his
actions outside of the cage.
I mean inside the octagon he was.
And the way he was promoted,
he was promoted.
Fantastic.
But he's just crazy.
Yeah.
John's crazy.
You know John Is.
John needs a babysitter.
That means the baddest motherfucker at
205 ever.
He just had to let him drive a car
anymore.
When you got that much money is beyond
me like pace to pay your body 40 grand a
year and have him drive you permanently.
Like why he was driving his own car.
Yeah.
That one's beyond me.
Well,
they didn't know until they bought them
a Bentley and then he wrapped it around
a tree,
but that's when.
That's when they should have known and
then,
but then there was the other one where
he hit and that was the hit and run was
after that one.
Yep.
The hit and run was after that one and
then there was the other one.
We got pulled over,
speeding and he told the cop to go fuck
himself.
Terrible decisions.
He's a fucking wild.
That's why he's so good.
But one of the reasons why he's
absolutely.
But then you put,
you've got to put safeguards in place,
right?
Like,
like you're making how many million a
year?
Multiple.
At least for sure.
You can't pay someone 40 grand to drive
you around this and you're preaching to
the choir.
I mean,
I wish I could clone me and send me all
to all these stamps.
John,
listen to me.
Everything's gonna be fine.
I've got a driver.
We got a cadillac escalade out here.
Wherever you want to go,
we're going to have some fun,
but no driving,
no driving.
We don't need driving.
We've got me.
We've got fun.
Let's go.
Oh my gosh.
I mean,
seriously.
Yeah.
Well,
that's what you would have if you had
like,
you know,
it's,
I don't know what he's doing.
I don't know.
I never been to albuquerque.
I don't know how he's living,
but he can't,
he can't babysit everybody.
You got the UFC has 500 fighters on its
roster.
I mean,
how many of those guys are prone to wild
behavior?
I would say three of them.
Yeah.
And most of them,
right?
Yeah.
High risk males that play a sport where
you have potential to be hurt every
single time you step out on the job.
Yeah.
But when you're making millions of
dollars,
you got to put safeguards against
yourself.
Yeah.
But I think also what makes John so good
is this self confidence and he probably
was like,
I got it.
Yeah.
Fucked up before when I got it now.
So I'm really into sports psychology and
I want someone to write this book
because no one's ever written it,
but I think there's this,
uh,
I call it the hypocritical elite
athlete.
So there's two sides to every coin.
Right?
And if you're a really elite athlete,
you need both sides of those corner.
And I'll give you a great example
because it's kind of what you're talking
about.
There's these guys who are ultra elite
prepares to eat right,
sleep right,
they train,
right?
They do everything right,
But then if one little thing goes wrong
and it messes with them,
right?
If they don't get the right food or
their weight cuts bad,
they start panicking,
right?
And then on the opposite side of the
coin,
there's these cowboys,
right?
And they're just like,
I'm not going to eat right.
I'm not going to sleep right.
I'm not gonna do anything right?
But one time step in the cage,
I'm a fight my ass off and nothing's
going to bother me.
Right?
And so you need,
you need both sides of those coins to
make,
to make it whole.
And so you want someone ideally who does
everything right?
But at the same time when when something
goes wrong or their toe hurts or
whatever,
they could just say,
well,
it doesn't really matter.
I'm going to go compete anyways.
Right?
You want to have both sides of those and
that's where I think a lot of the UFC
fighters are more on the cowboy side of
it.
Like,
well,
I'm not going to do a lot of things
right,
but I'm just going to go.
I'm on firearms,
going to fight like cowboy example and
yeah,
the namesake of my argument.
Yeah.
Yeah,
that's a good point.
And it,
it is a,
it's probably one of the more
fascinating things about any form of
high stress,
high level competition is there's no
real guidelines of how to prepare your
mind.
You know,
I mean everybody teaches you how to
wrestle and it teaches you how to
kickbox.
There's all these martial arts schools
that teach you.
Technique is very few real like rock
solid program of,
uh,
how to,
how to manage your mind.
Absolutely.
I think you should be taught almost like
in,
in a step by step basis.
Like,
Hey,
you get a flat tire.
Do you kick,
you scream?
Or do you just go,
this is what it is.
And Hey,
I could have been born in Ethiopia with
Noah,
right?
I could be living in a fucking coal mine
somewhere.
No,
I'm lucky.
I'm fortunate.
Nothing.
This is a minor setback.
Know.
And so like I,
I actually started going to graduate
school for sports psychology.
I got nine of the 36 credits done and
then I actually got a scholarship to go
further and get it paid for.
Um,
but I was just,
I was traveling so much that was 2007,
eight when I was trying to make the
Olympic team and I was gone all the
time.
And then once I was out of school for a
year,
I was just like,
there's no freaking way I'm going,
I'm not going back to school.
Not going to sit in a class.
You're not going to freaking write
papers.
I'll still study sports psych on my own.
Right.
And so actually every Monday I do
something called a mental Monday,
one of my facebook pages and just people
messaged me questions and I talk about
the mental aspect because you're right,
there aren't enough people to talk about
it.
And then,
you know,
in wrestling is actually this company
that's been highly successful.
I'll call wrestling mindset and they
have a training program for athletes'
minds because there's nothing out there.
Is there a website for this?
Yeah,
right.
It's wrestling mindset.com.
No kidding.
That's great ends.
They're starting to.
That'll apply to everything.
Well,
they're starting to expand,
expand and in different disciplines.
But you're right.
I think,
I think there's these general principles
of sports psych which can kind of go
into any domain.
Right.
And you're,
you're a hundred percent correct that
every single individual is different.
Right.
And one of the,
like for me,
uh,
I'm,
I'm an overthinker,
right?
I'm obsessive.
I'll do something over and over and over
and over it again.
Right.
And so like when I was 14 I was at the
big national tournament and I was
obsessing about who I'd have to wrestle
and all this stuff and it warmed me up
mentally.
I got my ass kicked right.
And my coach said,
hey,
I was that person many,
many years ago and it helped me just
talk about fishing.
Right?
Because that maybe because I,
if I don think I don't want to think
about what I'm going to do,
I'm not one of those guys because I
think about it too much.
All obsessed.
And so ever since age 15,
I've,
I've always taught myself to train
myself to not think about the
competition within like,
you know,
six hours,
right?
So maybe the day before I can think of a
couple of days before I can think about
it.
But like even when I'm in MMA locker
room,
I'm not thinking about my fight my minds
off of it because if I'm not federal
understand what my strategy is going to
be by six hours before.
And I haven't trained myself by six
hours before a fucked.
I'm already fucked.
Like what am I going to do?
Six hours a brilliant strategy in six
hours,
you know,
so like $6,
I,
I intentionally fly people to my fights
who are just my friends who have no
intention of telling me what to do mma
wise and just want to bullshit
backstage,
right?
Because really smart keeps me really
calm because otherwise I started
obsessing and that's going to lead to
some really negative.
So that's like one thing is where,
you know,
but some people are the opposite,
like the f off too much.
You kinda gotta bring them back to
focus.
Right.
You know,
in other sports,
that concept is,
is what they'll learn.
You do.
You want going into the competition.
Some people you got to get them amped
up.
Some people,
most people you've got to calm them down
quite a bit.
Like let's relax,
let's execute because we need to.
Anthony
and I execute.
Right.
So I think there's a lot of these sports
psych concepts that can crossover many
different genres,
but you're right,
no one trains you about it.
I think it's a huge part of the sport
and it's,
it's,
it's overlooked because the sport is not
just.
And I think this is true with every
sport,
the sport's not just the movements that
you make,
it's what's going on inside the machine,
who the manager of the body is the mind.
And if the manager is like poorly formed
and the structures all out of whack and
you have like whenever a problem comes
up,
you fall right into a pit and do all
these things should be addressed and you
should develop this mindset and develop
the ability to manage your mindset.
And He,
I think at a young age,
I think it's really critical.
Yeah.
No,
I totally agree.
And you know,
I think,
I think one issue thing,
which I don't know if it's going to
happen,
man,
or now we'll see,
right.
There's very few people who came from a
wrestling background that are head
coaches of MMA teams.
Right?
Who came from this very,
very structured environment of college
wrestling.
It's like you go to,
I want you to remember my first training
camp to American top team in Florida and
I show up.
It's 11:00
practice chill,
but 11:00.
Where's,
where's everyone at?
Right.
And then we start at 1145,
like 45 minutes late and that's the next
day.
I'm like,
well am I am and 1145 or should I show
up at 11?
Because we say 1145,
I can show up,
blah,
so I show up at 1130 and then they
started 1120,
you know like what the hell.
Whereas in college wrestling,
if you're a minute late you're going to
get punished to college wrestling.
Right.
It's a very structured,
organized system,
so I'm very curious to see the day where
there is an MMA team that is very
structured like a college wrestling team
would be.
I think it would be very effective
towards performance for athletes and.
But then again you are going to have is
a different structure because called
dressers are poor,
right?
Where are you gonna?
Have a bunch of MMA fighters who get
rich and then say,
well I don't want to do what you're
saying right now.
How are you going to make them?
Right?
They're the one paying your paycheck.
So it does become an interesting
circumstance,
but I think if there was someone who ran
a highly structured,
mixed martial arts team as structured as
a college team,
I think they would have a gigantic
amount of success.
I think their guys would get a lot
better,
a lot faster.
Um,
and I think you'd see a really
interesting dynamic developed between
the high level athletes and the coaches.
Well,
I think they're still trying to,
trying to figure out what's the best way
to coach fighters.
Everybody's got their own way of doing
it,
you know,
for us,
uh,
hobbies,
ways different than the way they do it
at American top team,
Matt Hume was doing a different than the
way duke does it.
Everybody's got their own way.
And the only way you could tell us how
well the athletes compete,
that's the only way you really find out
who's correct and who's not,
who needs to make adjustments.
Yeah.
And it's really hard in fighting because
I mean,
even your highest level camps,
how many say Bella torn ucl?
Ha.
How many high level MMA fights do they
have per year?
Maybe 30.
I think there'd be a lot for most of
these teams.
Right?
And so you only get 30 samples sizes,
right?
Whereas in college wrestling team,
you're going to have,
between everybody on the team,
the all 40 guys,
you're going to have at least a thousand
matches every single year,
minimum,
right.
And then obviously every event is scored
by team.
Every deal made is scored by team,
every Ncaa Championship scored by team,
so you get a very good indication of
what coaches are doing it right and what
coaches are doing it wrong.
And then obviously with recruiting
process,
the coaching I'm doing right now get the
next crop of the best talent.
Right.
And so you have a very good idea of
what's working,
what is not working.
We're in MMA.
I think we struggled with it because the
sample size isn't large enough to give
us a really,
really direct correlation.
Now you were able to instigate your
strategy in pretty much every single one
of your mma fights the only fight where
you really struggled as a fight.
Yeah.
That was,
that was a close fight.
What was different in that fight?
Well,
so that was my first fight at dukes.
Um,
obviously J is pretty damn good too,
but we don't wanna take that away from
him.
I think he was right,
number 16 in the world.
There's something at that point in time.
So that was my first fight at dukes.
I think the biggest mistake I made,
I mean,
and obviously at that time,
I'm literally two years into my fighting
career,
so I stopped wrestling completely.
Um,
I didn't do one wrestling practice.
I moved to Duke's August for a while.
I moved to Wisconsin August,
first searching and Duke's August first.
I fought a three months later at the end
of October.
I literally did not do one wrestling
practice.
So what were you doing?
A,
I was just striking like six times a
week.
I was doing Jujitsu a handful of times a
week and then I was doing conditioning
instead after that fight my rest.
Well,
and then actually I went to,
my brother was living in New York at the
time who,
my brother is also an ncaa champ and
went to visit him for thanksgiving.
He whooped my ass and I'm like,
I freaking suck at wrestling.
Like,
you know,
like I went cold Turkey and so it's
like,
okay,
I don't need to wrestle every day to be
great at wrestling anymore,
but I need,
I need to wrestle once a week,
twice a week with high level
competition.
So at that point in time,
and for pretty much the rest of my
career,
I would go to one of the local colleges
once a week or twice a week just to keep
my skills sharp.
And so I think that was the biggest
mistake I made in Toronto.
I didn't wrestle at all prior to it.
Um,
but Jim Rohn was good.
He was also a division one college
wrestlers.
He knew what he was doing also.
Um,
but I think if I,
if I had to pinpoint one thing that,
that would be it.
Isn't it fascinating that a guy with as
much wrestling experiences you have,
all you have to do is take some time off
and everything degrades.
Let's timing
sell timing.
Right?
So you take three months off your time.
Who's going to go to.
I mean literally,
it's amazing.
Tell you I wasn't doing one practice and
so it's like,
but that was also what helped me get the
striking thing down as I was doing,
and this is what I think you actually
made this point a,
who the hell are you talking to about
wrestlers are willing to go to the
environment.
I was striking six to seven times a
week.
How many strikers go and wrestle?
Six to seven times a week
problem.
None of them do.
They literally,
they refused to.
Well there was Francis in Ghana is
training camp.
When I talk to people outside
afterwards,
it's crazy.
Before everyone's saying,
oh my God,
he's in tremendous shape.
Everything's amazing.
And then afterwards there was like,
he doesn't turn on the ground.
What he crazy training on the ground.
Like all he wants to do is,
yeah,
well you can't let them do that.
You can't.
You can't let him.
He's going to fight and a division one
wrestler,
like,
how is he going to do this?
How is he going to,
how is he gonna stand up.
He's going to somehow or another
magically stuff.
All the take downs,
you have to train that,
you have to train it.
Yeah and well and that,
but you got to train it,
but then even when people train it,
the strikers,
strikers,
they don't want to do it.
Right.
Like I said,
when I go to Duke's,
when I started at dukes and it went down
to four times a week where we are
striking,
right,
but in the beginning it was six or seven
times a week sessions a week.
I'm striking.
Right?
And so I'm immersed in that culture.
I have to learn.
You can't not learn.
We're doing six to seven times a week
and.
But the strikers,
they want to do one wrestling practice a
week to wrestling practices a week.
Well,
if you're here and they're here,
how are you going to catch them by doing
one practice a week?
It's freaking impossible.
You need to.
I mean if I,
if I got to like be in charge of an MMA
guys camp and I don't know,
I coach wrestling.
I love coaching the kids.
I don't know if I ever want to coach mma
people I would consider for someone like
high level,
but you got to immerse yourself.
You literally have to take three months
and freaking wrestle every single day
because Russell,
you've got to bill,
you have to build those skills.
You're not going to work,
you're not going to learn something.
Well do it one time a week,
you are going to do it,
period.
No,
I completely agree and I think that it.
It all depends on what the athlete
brings to the table.
Like some guys have like a little bit of
wrestling and then maybe they need to
work more on submissions.
Maybe some guys need to work more on
their striking that get hit too much.
I mean it's,
it's every single fighter is that
there's a different recipe and you have
to figure out what that recipe is and
it's hard because it's like you only way
you find out is how well they perform in
competition and how many times you even
get the chance to do that.
Three a year,
three a year maybe.
Yeah.
And so that,
you know,
that's,
that's that and listen,
so I'm not saying,
I'm not saying a stryker has to do six
sessions a week for three years
straight,
but I'm saying take three months,
six months,
immerse yourself in that,
be obsessed,
learn those skills,
figure it out.
And then after that it might be once a
week,
twice a week,
three times a week.
But then when,
when,
when we start considering the,
the cte factors,
which I'm not totally sold on cte yet as
you don't get hit poster boy for
wrestling,
martial art,
if you really think about.
I know for sure.
But.
So I watched,
I watched concussion.
Well I was actually flying in my fight
in April of 2016.
I'll watch.
I said,
shit,
that's scary.
I did.
I sparked two more times the rest of my
career.
So my crew was 19 months.
I sparred twice.
I just didn't,
I didn't do it just because you didn't
want to get hit.
Uh,
yeah,
I felt as an,
an,
an unnecessary risk.
Well there was a recent study that came
out just a few days ago that said that
it's repeated subconcussive hits and
they're causing cte,
not concussions.
Yeah.
So the.
But the study that made me really
question the cte phenomenon was they,
they did that study where they studied a
whole bunch of professional football
players and it was like 100 per se.
It was like 99 percent have ct.
Right?
But then they studied people who had
played football for any length of time,
any length of time and it was like still
like 80 percent of the people and it's
like,
well,
if I can't live my life in a bubble,
like are like,
how can 80 percent of people who have
ever played football,
I mean how many american males,
what percent of american males walking
around at 40 years old today put some
level of football?
It's like got to be 80 percent.
So you'Re telling me 70 percent of
americans walking around with cte or the
american males,
like that's crazy.
But that's real.
That's really is what's happening.
No,
I got you got to think there's gotta be
some kind of low threshold because
otherwise 40 years down the road if
everybody played football and everyone
who played football has cte,
everyone's going to be walking.
A lot of people are walking around like
that.
That's what's going on.
Or is it might be the diet coke.
Little bit,
a little bit of that.
I think way more people have some form
of brain damage than real estate.
Yes,
I do.
Well,
I think in the world of martial arts,
I know so many guys.
Yeah,
but let's talk about not martial arts
are just regular people,
ballplayers.
I think football players,
it's even worse because you're running,
you're running at each other clashing
heads.
I mean you watch football.
I mean the damage those guys take his
crate.
It's once in a ufc you'll see like a
wild head kit,
care boom and football games.
These guys are literally running at each
other.
I mean it's crazy.
One team's running this way,
the other teams running that way and
they slam into each other and these guys
are 250,
300 pounds that,
that impact that the jarring of your
brain.
Plus they have helmets on which allows
them to be more confident clashing into
each other.
I think a giant percentage of those
guys.
But you think.
But so like I said,
so if that one study said it was
something around 80 percent of anyone
who ever played any level of football,
length of time for I like that has cte.
That means like,
I mean if we take the american
population,
at least 80 percent of american men
played football
point in their life.
They have ct.
So we're talking about like a gigantic
population.
I think there's levels of cte though.
I mean I think,
you know,
you get to the point where you look,
Joe Frazier,
he could barely talk before he died.
He rest in peace,
but then you also get two guys that are
just like a little forgetful and don't
know why,
or impulsive and don't know why.
You know what I mean?
There's a lot of them,
there's a lot of weird stuff that comes
with cte.
I've studied it pretty extensively and
the more studies that I've read on it,
the more have gotten really
derBy.
So do you think there's maybe just a low
threshold for what they call cte?
Well,
there's also genes that certain people
have.
Um,
what was that gene?
Rhonda?
Patrick talked about it.
Uh,
I don't remember what it was.
Fantastic.
She's amazing,
right?
yeah.
And she was talking about uh,
some jeans make you more susceptible for
traumatic brain injury than other ones,
like if you have it,
you are many times more likely to
develop cte.
But then also.
And then so the other thing that I would
is out of curiosity to me when they did
a ct studies,
especially with they're doing,
you know,
after death with these football players,
right,
were sent out,
they're dying their pipeline in the
sixties,
seventies,
eighties,
that time period,
a steroid use very,
very high and drug use is also very high
in that culture and so and,
and alcohol including drugs.
So it's like,
did those things contribute,
contribute?
Is it a,
you know,
is it like a mitigating factor or is it
like going to create this crazy storm of
brain damage that you're.
You're going freaking running into
people like this.
Then you're doing steroids,
then you're a fricking and drinking a
pack of beer.
Then you're doing some cocaine
that can't be good for you.
Can.
that would be good for you?
Can't be.
No,
it can't be.
Yeah.
Especially the pills.
A lot of them get caught with the pain
pills.
I'm caught up on pain pills.
That's a.
That's a big one,
man.
We just found out a tom petty died from
fucking pain pills.
My wife and I were talking about sad.
That was that a man.
He couldn't have a sense of a
because that my wife and I both love tom
petty music,
but how he did,
how at 66 years old,
he was still like not so okay with
himself,
that he was jamming pills down his
throat,
you know,
that he didn't have a sense of,
I have had great accomplishments.
I've had a great life.
You know,
I have people around me that love me,
that,
you know,
I mean,
it's got to be a sad,
lonely thing when you're overdosing on
pills.
I would have to assume.
I mean,
I don't want to guess,
but I would,
I would imagine he's in some kind of
pain if we freeze taken those opiates
hip fracture.
He was recovering from a.
You got hooked on something,
man.
My friend from amber from the ufc,
she hurt her ankle recently.
She blew out her achilles and she said
the doctor immediately tried to
prescribe oxycontin was like,
get the fuck outta here.
Yeah.
she's like,
I'm not taking that shit.
No.
And you know,
um,
it happens man.
Doctors just try to shove pills down
your throat.
It's a real common thing.
And if you have any sort of serious
injury and they put you on that stuff,
one of the things they put tom petty on
was fentanyl and fentanyl is that shit
that's fucking killing every bitch with
meth.
Meth are very similar.
No heroin.
It's heroin dream.
Really potent opiate.
It's,
it's much more much more potent than
heroin.
I know many,
many hundreds of times more potent and
so they give these people fentanyl
patches and then they're taken
oxycontin's too and who knows what else
taken and I mean I,
I feel terrible for someone who has bad
pain like from a broken hip or something
like that,
but jesus christ take the pain rather
than death.
Seriously.
This shit you could take cbd,
you can take cbd doesn't even have a
psychoactive effect and as radical pain
reducing properties to.
Yeah.
And I,
and I,
I,
I don't do drugs,
but the fact that people are so actively
prescribing these,
these heavy,
really heavy hard drugs to patients,
people kill people and weed is still
illegal and I don't smoke weed so I'm
not even like for myself,
but just for other people.
well,
it's crazy.
We need to be a pain reliever really.
I've heard a lot of people say no.
A lot of people do say that.
It's just maybe,
I don't know.
I'm the one of those people that you're
in pain if you're in pain,
just be in pain.
Just like just,
just.
Yes,
just relax,
you know?
I mean,
I remember one time though,
I got my knee operated on,
I had a acl reconstruction and they gave
me one of those buttons in the hospital
when you press it and you get more fun.
It was when,
uh,
they,
they had my leg on this motion machine,
right.
So,
like right after surgery,
they're trying to get your blood moving
and so there's a couple screws in there
and they'd taken my patella tendon and
cut it and put it inside and drilled it
all in place and everything.
And then I'm sitting at this thing just,
it's this throbbing pain and they gave
me this little button.
I'm like,
claire,
but I'm like,
I'm in the hospital,
I'm not going to overdose.
But uh,
I remember thinking,
wow,
this could be really fucking dangerous
if you had this in life.
Like it was like a little button on your
hip and you just press it and you get a
dose of morphine.
but it was a wonderful feeling.
I've only done it once while I was in
the hospital.
I got it for that brief moment.
I was like,
wow,
this is an amazing feeling.
You feel like,
like you're floating through a cloud of
love and just flying through the air.
Like,
ah.
I went from being in exacerbating pain
too.
So how,
how do you feel?
Then we got into this discussion.
We're talking about cte.
So now like,
okay,
I think mma is a terrible career path
and people ask me all the time and as a
professional,
don't defeat it in two different,
two different organizations,
a couple people.
It's probably the right career path for
majority of people.
Probably not a great career path,
but.
So,
you know,
how do you feel about it when you think
that.
I mean you're obviously saying and I'm
on the fence,
but you're saying I think a lot of these
people are getting cte clearly.
How do you feel about being involved
with acs?
That's like in my future I could
probably coach them mma,
but I struggle with it because it's
like,
well,
should I really recommend this person to
have a mayor?
Should I not?
Because are they going to end up fucked
up and not be able to take care of the
kids are aware.
I don't think you should ever recommend
mma to anybody.
Okay,
good.
I usually don't.
I don't think anybody should recommend
an.
But I think some people,
it's their destiny.
Yeah.
There's a few people out there that they
want to look.
I don't think you should recommend
skydiving to anybody either though.
I mean,
my friend andy stump is a world record
holder in the world flying.
That's,
that's the death.
Did you ever read there was that book
called,
uh,
somethIng chasing superman or do you
remember if it was about people like kim
and how it almost always ends up very
poorly becAuse you need this bigger rush
and this bigger rush and this bigger
rush and tell big wave surfers and the
flying suit and all this.
I was talking about the psychology
behind it and how like it ends up poorly
very,
very often because these people need
bigger rushes and more challenges and
then the fucking themselves up.
It only makes sense.
I never
encourage anyone to do that,
but for him,
I mean he's a retired navy seal and this
is just another level psychotic
shit that he can do to fill his time
with,
but he's got a bunch of sponsors and he
actually makes a living doing that.
I would never recommend that to anybody.
I wouldn't recommend skiing.
Think you know,
my kids like skiing.
I don't even like skiing.
I go skiing with them every time I
skied,
like,
no,
I've never gotten hurt,
but I'm like,
fuck that.
Every time I'm skiing though,
I'm like,
don't get hurt.
Don't get hurt.
Who wouldn't get hurt?
I think it's sonny bono.
Oh,
who else?
One of the kennedy's and a tree.
Right?
Then maybe that was a.
That could have been false flag.
No,
don't push them into the tree.
Fucking took it.
Ski out with a sniper rifle right when
he got too close to the woods.
Yeah.
I think that there's a lot of very,
very dAngerous career and I think if you
feel compelled to do that,
no one should be talking to you into
that,
but I don't think anybody should stop
you.
Like I liked the fact that boxing
exists,
you know,
would never want to tell,
facility lowman,
chanko don't fight.
Sure.
I would never want to tell them don't
fight.
I want to see him fight.
Well,
what if they,
what if,
uh,
it gets proven without a shadow of a
doubt that these things cause he,
he cte.
Do you think the government is going to
ban them?
No,
I don't think they can really.
How could they be?
Are they going to ban banning
everything?
They really do.
They like banning things that cost them
money or the cost people who donate to
them money.
Fair.
Now the banning of the drugs is really
tied to pharmaceutical drugs.
More than that,
they're not banning it because they're
trying to save us that they're banning
it because someone's putting pressure on
them to ban it or put it in the past and
they're banning skateboarding.
No one's trying to ban bmx ride.
Those guys get fucked up.
I mean,
I was watching this video the other day
of those guys doing the ramp with the
skateboard and the guy got to the top of
the ramp and didn't catch it right and
fell like $100.
Awful.
oh jesus christ.
I mean,
they get beat the foot.
That's up.
That's another one where the damn book
was chasing superman or being sued or
something.
Getting superman.
Superman is a decoding superman.
It was called the coating superman.
Yeah.
Okay.
So like if you go back and watch the
rachel x games when I was a kid,
I don't remember what year it is,
nineties at some point.
And uh,
oh,
the rise of the superman,
decoding the science of ultimate human
performance.
This is a,
this is a freaking fantastic book.
I mean it's like,
it's so awesome.
I'm so.
I'm obsessed with sports psych,
like I said,
I'm sure.
Oh,
steven kotler.
Yeah,
that guy's interesting.
Yeah.
But.
So if you look like the original x game
stuff and then you go to like the x
games today.
Oh yeah.
It's different world,
totally different events,
so much work stream because there has to
be this advance advance,
advance advance,
but then all of a sudden people are
getting eft up.
Yeah.
You get to a certain point where you can
only do so many flips in the air with
your bike.
Apparently they keep trying to do one
rotation.
Everybody go,
this is crazy.
Somebody that comes along with two and
then now they're doing three.
Wasn't there?
The movIe about tony hawk was like the
first one did the 7:20
or something,
but now they go way more,
don't they?
Yeah,
they're.
They're going to be more in every year
and if you watch any of those par core
kids that are jumping from building to
building and and we've had one of them
are in here.
What was his name?
James
was a.
The
find it.
I don't remember that one.
I would mostly.
You're a political ones.
I think some of the people who are
highly fascinating.
Yeah.
It's an interesting time.
I get labeled all right.
I know it's bizarre,
but everybody's so quick to label people
today.
it's such a strange time.
Finger pointing and putting people in
boxes,
disingenuously.
It's more divisive of these leftist.
They want to,
uh,
you know,
they want to say,
well,
I'm trying to make people less racist,
but what they're really doing,
they're being very divisive.
Yeah.
You know,
and like I would,
I think you identify aS libertarian.
I w I identify more as a libertarian
than republican or democrat.
But yeah,
a lot of people say I'm all right or
love trump so much and it's,
well I'm more libertarian than anything,
you know,
I think less government,
less invasion invasion into our lives,
but people want to put you into a little
box because you don't agree with what
they're saying.
Yeah.
It's a weird time for that.
And that's what I think what you were
saying about shaming.
They try to shame you and racist or
shame,
but you're not doing that if you're
pretending someone's racist when you
know they're not.
Or if you're pretending that someone is
a sexist or homophobic or whatever.
When you know that you're just there.
people are,
they're ignoring nuance and what's what
they're really doing also is they're
making.
They're making people afrAid to speak
their minds.
Right.
And really how,
if you and I had a disagreement on
something,
how we come to a common ground is by
discussing it,
I'd say,
well,
I think you're a reasonable person.
What do you believe?
You'd say that as well,
I don't agree with that and this is why.
And eventually we would talk it out and
maybe we still disagree,
but we'd come to a common ground.
Right?
But instead the people on the one side,
they're not saying that they're saying,
what'd you say?
You're racist or sexist or homophobic,
your name one.
Right.
And then ended discussion.
Then there's no discussion at all,
right?
YeAh.
They're trying to win.
Yeah,
exactly.
They just turned them when they're
trying to label you and then get the
upper hand when.
Yeah,
I think there's a real problem with
people not being reasonable and I think
that you should be able to have
conversations like I've had people have
criticized me,
like even in person I've taught,
like why would you have that guy on your
show?
Which one?
Any guy like a milo yiannopoulos per
sample and I'm like,
well look what happened.
I mean we got to see how the guy thinks.
Got all,
all of his weird issues that came up in
his book deal falling apart.
A lot of that had to do with
conversations I had with them.
Yeah.
It's like now you get a chance to see
how the guy.
Actually,
I don't think there's anything wrong
with the way things.
I think it's a,
he's a provocateur.
I mean it's not how I think.
Yeah.
But I think that everybody has this
perspective on who he is that is
exaggerated because of this public
persona that he does to be outrageous.
So I think that's a double edged sword
because I think Alex Jones does it as
well.
Aware,
way crazier than well,
but okay.
But same idea,
right?
Is part of their persona is a show is a
show.
It's making it more extreme because they
want to say that one thing that's
totally effing crazy.
IT'll catch a headline somewhere.
Right.
And so they have these beliefs,
but then they kind of go beyond them
because it is a show because they will
make more money if they get more
followers or more people clicking on the
articles or videos or whatever.
So I think it is.
But then,
you know,
you go to someone like bret weinstein
guy,
I think he's fascinating people calling
him a racist and you know,
he was strong liberal.
Well he's as progressive as it gets.
He's as far from a racist as you could
ever get it.
Yeah.
There's a,
there's this need to label people.
well alex is alex showman and,
but also like he says,
some things that are pretty fucked up,
like the sandy hook stuff.
You know what I'm saying?
That sandy hook was a.
He's looking for conspiracies
everywhere.
Everywhere.
He finds them someplace.
So sometimes he's right,
exactly.
Sometimes it,
right?
Yeah.
But the problem with looking for
conspiracies everywhere as you going
gonna you're gonna make people feel
terrible.
I meaN,
if there was an article that I read
about a guy who was a conspiracy
theorist until his son was killed in
sandy hook,
people were tellIng him that his son was
killed and that is some sort of a
government actor and this guy was
devastated,
you know?
Of course the people that are really the
nutty conspiracy theorist.
Oh,
vulgar,
no undercover still.
He's still under grover.
there's people out there that look for
conspiracies and everything and it
becomes a real problem because it
muddies up the water and I think,
I think at the same time you,
at least for me,
and I think we have similar thought
processes,
you can't just take what makes you made,
it tells you and say,
well I guess that's how it happened.
Right?
So as an end in some situations,
but in sandy hook you have dead kids.
People grieving,
you have bodies.
Autopsy reports.
Yeah.
It happened.
No guns.
You had a mentally ill person who had
access to these gut.
Then if you take that same thought
process on say,
stephen paddock in the las vegas
shooting,
well we still don't know how that turned
out.
The las vegas shooting is complicated,
but as we know one guy did do that.
Well now we're coming out with new
stuff.
I think there was other people involved
and he might've gotten help from people,
whether it's willingly or unwillingly,
but or wittingly or unwittingly,
but I don't think there was other people
shooting.
They've said that,
so I don't know.
Right,
and that's what the law of these
conspiracies,
you have to understand that you're never
really gonna know what the real truth,
right?
You have to keep an open mind and you'll
say,
okay,
well this person says this.
What does this person say?
They do these things check out with each
other,
and it's like how many different types
of.
They changed the las vegas shootings
timeline,
right?
And then it was kind of weird that it
went way out of mainstream media.
Like I'll send you heard about it for a
week and then you didn't hear about it
again for one of the times.
I think the news cycle today is about
billing hours.
Yeah.
But you would think people want answers.
I mean
that's the largest mass shooting in
United States history that we'd want
some more clear answers on what really
happened and how it happened and why it
happened and we never really got those.
And I know there's been a few new
articles on it recently and so maybe
we're going to find out more
information,
but it's an incredibly confusing story
because the guy was clearly a psycho
clearly fucked up.
I'm clearly planned this out for a long
time.
I mean,
he,
he got hotel rooms overlooking music
festivals and other places.
Yeah.
And I was planning out how to do this
for a long time.
He had a note in his,
uh,
in his hotel room that had all the
ballistics calculation so he knew like
bullet drop from x amount of yards and
he was calculating how to kill all these
people.
He was on some weird antidepressants and
anti,
not anti anti anxiety medication,
which does all kinds of weird shit to
your head.
There's a guy that was prone to fits of
rage.
He was a a calculated professional
gambler.
There's a lot of weird stuff with this
guy.
The fact that he accumulated these
weapons over years.
Yeah,
and maybe did it knowing that he was
going to do this so you don't.
There's a.
Whenever there's a mass shooting or
anything,
that's crazy.
You have two things happen.
One,
everybody wants answers to.
Everybody forgets about it really quick
because of new shit happens in the news
and if it wasn't your family that got
shot.
It wasn't someone who.
You're close to the gunshot.
I know people that got shot there.
Yeah,
I know people that I met them.
I met people in vegas that that got shot
there.
I talked to them after it was over.
It was complete and total chaos and when
there's complete and total chaos,
you get all sorts of conflicting
reports.
People were running into other casinos
saying that there's a shooter because
they ran out of that area and so then
people were calling and police reports
because the shooter in monte carlo,
there's a shooter in this and so those
things get reported as fact when many
times it's part of the confusion of a
chaotic mass shooting like that vegas
event.
I don't know what happened other than
the fact that this one guy definitely
killed a bunch of people,
but whether or not someone was helping
him or whether or not there was other
people involved or I think they're still
investigating.
I still.
yeah,
but so I guess my greater point there
would be that,
uh,
if you're an intelligent individual,
you can't just take what cvs tells you
to be complete fact,
right?
You,
you go do some investigation yourself,
you try to read from different sources
and then,
hey,
sandy hook.
I think there's like a 99 point nine,
nine,
nine percent chance of the sandy hook
was real.
Right.
Is there some crazy in the impetus,
really small chance that didn't happen?
Sure.
Right.
But I think that,
I think there is,
I think it's very unlikely and vegas was
a zero percent chance.
Sandy sandy hook didn't happen.
Percent looked into it pretty,
you know,
it's just sad to me.
And you're a dad,
you know,
the idea of your kid going to school and
getting their school getting shot up by
some psychopath.
Yeah.
Imagine if someone was saying that that
was fake.
Yeah.
After your kid's dead,
you'd be frustrated,
infuriated.
You wouldn't even know where to turn.
And these that's actually happening to
these people and they're,
they're getting labeled as frauds and
people are emailing them and saying,
how could you do this?
You're defrauding the american people.
You're A part of the illuminati or.
Yeah.
So.
Well I think so.
I think there's obviously those people
who are on right?
The way one side of it,
there's.
So there's.
So if you go a spectrum for me,
right,
there's the american who's drinking diet
coke and eaten frozen pizza and
listening to ever cbs says.
And then the total opposite of the
spectrum.
There's the group that thinks every
single thing that ever happens in
America as a planet conspiracy by the
new world order.
So those are two ends of the spectrum
right now.
We can fall anywhere in the middle
there.
But so I think as an intelligent
individual,
we look at situations independently and
say,
well,
there's some sketchy things.
They're not sketchy things there.
That's probably true,
right?
And kind of independently think about
stuff by ourselves and that's,
that's how I do it.
And so,
you know,
That's a wise way to approach it.
and uh,
I think cbs or nbc or you know,
any name,
your new source,
they're run by people and if they
weren't there,
they only have access to a certain
amount of information and sometimes they
get bad information and sometimes they
don't necessarily know.
I don't know how much of it as a part of
some grand conspiracy rather than how
much of it is a part of the chaos of
these moments.
The lack Of information and people
drawing conclusions and then also
witnesses on the scene on people on the
scene of something that's crazy.
They give all sorts of weird accounts
and they're just,
they're filled with adrenaline.
They don't know how to handle the
situation.
People.
People don't handle chaotic events very
well.
Yeah,
but I don't think the earth is flat,
if that's fair.
Oh,
good for you.
Yeah.
What do you possibly believe in?
that might be crazy.
Can I take a piss and I'll tell you I go
fast.
Go ahead.
No worries man.
I wonder if there's something wrong with
my bladder.
You can hold it.
Yeah.
Do you think I've trained it?
I mean sure.
Just that guy is going to try to shoot
himseLf to see the flat earth and a
couple of days guys shooting himself up
and go into the space.
Don't take one mark second.
James kingston was dead.
James kingston.
Thank you.
Sorry james.
Yeah.
Bam.
Yeah,
it's a dunbar.
There is dunbar's number,
brother.
You can only keep 150 people in your
brain at any time.
Look at that fucking picture.
We're looking at a picture for the audio
folks.
Have james kingston on the top of this
tower and I don't know how many fucking
stories he's up there,
but it's insane because below him and I
mean way below him are skyscrapers.
that's probably like dubai or something.
Right.
Do you think that dunbar's number,
it could apply to other things besides
people like websites or chore numbers of
instructions that can.
Yeah,
yeah,
I think so.
You know,
I think it applies to too many things.
Uh,
it applies.
I just think for names,
names and people.
I'm,
I'm struggling.
I think I'm getting like I have an
overflowing pot.
Like,
um,
I'm shane burgos
and calvin cater.
We're fighting this weekend and I called
calvin cater chris cater after he won,
even though I'm a fan of his,
like he wanted,
I went chris cater and then I'm like,
it's fucking name's calvin.
Dunk con.
Like I just don't.
I think we're running out of space in my
head for names.
So my apologies to calvin cater.
I'm running out of names and I,
we're talking about dunbar's number,
how you can only keep so many people in
your brain.
My brain's overflowed.
I don't have any hard drive space left.
I didn't know.
So I thought it was the is that the guy
says you can only keep track of 150
people like what's going on in their
relationships in that kind of stuff.
You only have so much room in your.
In your hard drive space.
Yeah.
It's based on a tribal societies.
Like our brains are sort of designed to
keep track of 150 people.
That's how we evolved and then over the
last,
you know,
x amount of hundreds of years.
Now all of a sudden you have to keep
track of many,
many multiples of that.
Especially if you're someone like you or
I that runs into so many people who you
meet on a regular basis.
You've got to keep those people on your
brain.
But is it,
is it.
So I guess I haven't read that much.
Is it that you have to just know their
names and faces or is it that you have
to know like what's going on in their
life?
I think you're supposed to be able to
track them,
like have a,
some sort of a,
whether it's intimate or personal
relationship with these people know
them.
Yeah,
so it's like there's only something
like,
especially if you think about a
commentating on fights,
I have to pay attention to these guys
and what they're doing and their career
and there's hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of 500 fighters now.
500 fighters that's active and then how
manY of them get new guys come in,
old guy go away.
I still keep them all in my head.
Hey,
what's sean sherk up to these days?
They're all still in the head and it's
like there's not,
there's only so much room and after
awhile you'll,
you'll wonder.
You're like,
Wow,
where are these people going?
Yeah.
I found that obviously with a,
It's sad like,
you know,
college friends.
It's like,
yeah,
you know,
and it's good because you see them and
it's like no time has passed.
Right?
But it's like I,
if I,
if I know if I was living in two minutes
away,
we'd probably be best friends still.
Right?
Right.
Right now I get to see you once a year,
twice a year maybe.
I can't keep up with you.
It's super challenging.
I totally agree.
And now max and I run.
The rest of the academy is my brother.
We have three in Wisconsin and it's like
this fall was my first wife fulltime,
worked at one and so now I'm really
immersed in the one academy whereas I
was kind of loosely keeping track of all
three,
but now that I'm kind of totally
immersed in the one,
I find it a lot harder to keep track of
what's going on at the other two.
Whereas kind of bed right before when I
wasn't so immersed in one.
Yeah,
I can only imagine.
Eddie bravo is 100 schools.
That's crazy.
Right?
As a 110 plans.
Jujitsu's worldwide.
Like how he can't keep track all kennY?
I don't know.
I'd have to ask him.
I know he travels to all of them.
He travels.
He's constantly traveling.
He travels constantly.
He's doing seminars at all of them.
Got always traveling.
Yeah.
Once the sodium to do like one time a
year for each facility
or something.
I don't know.
It's a good question because that would
be columbia.
He's going,
he's going,
I mean probably wouldn't even be once a
year.
Yeah,
he didn't want three years.
Singapore now he was out in st paul when
I was there and one of my fights this
year,
it was maybe the.
Maybe the may fight dick.
Yeah.
He was out there doing it as a 10
seminar and now that now they have a
10th planet program at evolve is crazy.
Evolve as supposed to be an amazing
facility.
I've heard some things.
Yeah.
I mean the nicest mma facility I've ever
been to and so they have.
They actually just opened their fourth
location.
Justin,
Singapore,
Singapore is a city state,
right?
It's 6 million people in a,
on a really,
really small island.
But some of their,
some of their academies are only a mile
or two apart.
Like they're not far apart,
but the population density is such that,
you know,
they listened.
They start classes at I think at 6:00
AM and they end class at 11:00
PM and you can freaking stop in anytime
of day and there'll be a class there
that's full with muay thai or jujitsu or
whatever you name it.
It'll be going on.
That's crazy.
Yeah.
Well manhattan is kind of like that a
lot of ways,
right?
Manhattan as how many jujitsu schools
are in manhattan?
I mean obviously marcel.
Yeah,
there's hundreds but run big ones.
Handles got a huge one.
Marcel has got a huge one,
so yeah,
there's a lot right there.
I mean those are huge places.
Enormous.
Hundreds and hundreds of students.
I thought that.
I know.
I thought it was thousands.
That's what someone told me.
Hands over a thousand students in the
main New York city location and I think
it's,
you know,
it ain't cheap because you got to pay
for rent and so they're probably paying
a couple hundred bucks a month.
Yeah.
So evolve is I think $350 a month.
Wow.
But obviously,
so Singapore is one of the most wealthy
countries on the planet,
so you have to take that into account
for which everyone that lives there,
he has a,
a decent amount of wealth and they spend
it differently in Singapore is a
fascinating country if you,
I,
you know,
I was there 15 times or whatever,
so I got kind of immersed in the culture
and that ended up reading the books
about lee kuan yew,
the guy who started the country.
And so,
you know,
there was a whole bunch of those asian
countries,
they're got independence in the 19
fifties and sixties.
I'm in Singapore,
I believe was founded in 1965.
It could be off by one year,
there may be,
um,
but you know,
a lot of those countries are not doing
super well economically.
And sIngapore is like,
this is freaking standout country who's
like top five world per person wealth
and why,
why,
why are they doing so much better?
Uh,
and so this is me from an outsider's
perspective.
So,
um,
they really do a lot of kind of.
It's kind of like self tracking,
right?
And so every month a bunch of your check
comes out to a,
you know,
like we would pay taxes,
right?
Bunch of mannequins,
other check,
but so they can spend it.
This is fascinating.
They spend their money on three things.
It goes into this fund,
right?
Education,
healthcare,
and housing.
Okay.
And so if you want cheaper,
if any one of those,
if you want the cheapest form of it,
right?
It's very government subsidized and it
comes out of your fund,
right?
So only a little bit of mine comes out
if you want the nicest healthcare,
the nicest housing are nice,
then it's only a tiny percent government
subsidized.
Right?
So the more expensive stuff gets,
whether it's education or housing or
healthcare,
the less subsidized it gets in,
the cheaper it gets,
the more subsidized it gets.
And so everyone kind of,
you know,
they pay,
they pay into this fund so everyone has
this personal fund that they can use and
then you know,
into those three things.
And so I think a lot of people have,
I think they feel like they have more
control over their lives.
And,
and you know,
obviously it is very strict regulations
and laws,
but from what I've seen and I've spent a
lot of time there,
everyone seems pretty happy.
That's interest.
Yeah.
That's an interesting way to go.
I mean,
I don't think there's any one good way
to government to govern people.
Yeah.
And I mean I think we have a pretty good
system over here,
but it's obviously filled with
bureaucratic bullshit and too much
weight,
too much government.
There's so much,
there's way too many people doing stupid
jobs and getting paid too much or doing
them and I mean it's.
And,
and then the shit like,
you know,
trying to chase down medical marijuana
in 2017 trying to stop legal marijuana
and like why,
like what,
who's paying you to do this?
Like why,
why are you doing that?
That doesn't make any sense.
It's not what our tax dollars should be
going to.
You know,
it's funny when you go all the way back,
I think about it.
So we've talked about that process of
who's keeping them from doing this and
you have about the pharmaceuticals with,
with weed,
which I think is true.
You know what a funny one I think about
is john mccain and mixed martial arts,
who is sponsoring john mccain,
budweiser,
who was like the main advertise of her
boxing.
It's like you cannot make an argument
that boxing safer for them.
Mma,
you can't freaking do it.
So like it's impossible possible.
It's impossible.
But john mccain's over here getting paid
by budweiser and saying mma is awful,
let's ban it.
And the same time he's promoting boxing
essentially.
It's freaking mindblowing.
Well,
in his defense it was mma
from a long time ago and it was,
it wasn't really the same as them may
now.
And he's turned the corner and now he
supports.
Yeah.
But also you've got budweiser and bud
light or sponsors now of mna.
So it's like.
But that's a real problem with
politicians.
Thirty years.
There's so many dirty politicians.
I don't know what percentage is,
but it's high,
97.
It's probably,
it's probably a fucking high.
What crazy shIt that.
What crazy conspiracy do you believe in?
So the one that got me started really
like independently think myself as nine
slash 11,
which I think that was,
that was for a lot of people.
Yeah.
What,
what do you think about nine slash 11.
Oh,
I know,
I don't know all the answers,
but I know the given explanation.
I don't believe what given explanation.
Uh,
the one that came,
what's the damn report that they wrote?
Um,
the nist report?
No,
that wasn't what it was,
was it?
Yeah.
Well,
nist is the one who did the report on
tower seven collapsing
now.
What was the other report that came out
with right away?
Anyway,
so my buddies live right by the airport
and he played loose change for me.
And I said,
you were out of your ged mind,
like you are insane man.
Right.
and then I started thinking,
well that doesn't make,
maybe maybe I should think about it,
you know,
that it was an inside job.
I'm not totally,
I mean,
I,
so I think obviously the planes flew
into the buildings for sure.
No doubt about that.
But,
um,
that maybe the,
there was inklings inclinations that it
had that was going to happen and that
not enough was done to stop it.
I think
this is one.
This is another thing where you have a
gigantic tragedy and because of a
gigantic tragedy,
there's a lot of people that draw these
conclusions based on witness testimony
and things that are happening.
But I think you have to realize that
anytime there is some,
some thing that happens,
people start looking for all these
different correlating factors,
right?
You start saying,
well,
hey look,
you know,
there was a local tests that were being
done.
There was,
they were looking out for planes that
were potentially gonna fly into
building.
They knew this was going to happen in
advance.
But if you talk to anybody that is in
intelligence,
there's,
they're dealing with that shit every
day.
Just one day something happens.
There's always warnings about terrorist
attacks.
There's always warnings about things
happen.
And a lot of times they,
these warnings get toward like,
the fbi stopped that.
I'm
quick.
There was one,
there was one in san francisco,
right?
They had bombs and they stopped and we
through security,
wherever.
Yeah,
and this has happened many times now
when,
when it doesn't,
when they don't catch it and it goes
through,
then people start thinking,
oh,
there was some sort of a conspiracy.
They allow these planes to fly into
buildings.
The missile hit the pentagon and he
pulled up.
Look,
there was a video came out of that last
week,
but I might've been fake news.
The pentagon thing.
There was a video of the pentagon or
something handed the pentagon which
looked take a missile and not an
airplane,
but I don't believe it was know.
I was like,
this is interesting because I've never
seen this video before and obviously
there no video evidence of what hit the
pentagon.
There's a video of something.
I know there was one camera thing or a
security camera video that was released,
but what they did have is all sorts of
pizza pieces of aircraft all over the
fucking lawn in a blown up building and
a plane that's missing and all the
people dead.
Like,
I'm going to guess it was a plane.
You know,
I just,
I think people look for conspiracies and
everything because it's exciting,
stimulating about it.
There is,
but then obviously be.
I know that you don't believe that
everything we're told is the truth right
away,
right?
I mean if we go to something like a gulf
of tonkin incident,
right?
I mean perfect.
That's been proven to be false or the
fat,
like the banana republics,
right?
Where dole asked us to go take out one
of their dictators because they were
going to nationalize all the banana
plants in that country.
I mean those things have been now proven
to be totally factual that the United
States government went and did that
stuff.
So The fact that,
and you know,
in 19 sixties or seventies,
those things were reported the opposite,
right?
So we can't obviously take
everything that we've been reported as
truth.
Well,
there's definitely been conspiracies
that have been put together and executed
and these conspiracies have greatly
affected the american people.
the gulf of tonkin is a perfect example.
Another one that they were planning on
was operation northwoods operation.
Northwoods was one that they were
planning on blowing up a drone jet liner
and blaming it on the cubans that were
going to arm cuban friendlies and have
them attack,
wanted,
obey.
there would be sacrifice american troops
in american lives and they were going to
do this in order to get people to be
excited about a war with Cuba.
Yes.
Was.
ThIs is a real thing that was signed by
the joint chiefs of staff.
It was released by the freedom of
information act and it was vetoed by
kennedy,
so we know that there were people,
at least in 1962,
they were planning on shit like this.
Yeah.
So that's a real thing too.
And the idea that that just went away
and no one does that anymore.
It's crazy.
I dOn't,
I don't believe that.
I think there's,
there's most certainly evil people in
all fucking sectors of life.
Yes,
absolutely.
Yeah.
So it's good to have an open mind,
but there's also a lot of fucking
conspiracy loons that and they get
consumed that that's,
that's the issue they get consumed with.
nothing that I've been told is true,
which is obviously I said that one far
end of the spectrum that I didn't know
who that end is.
Crazy.
Also.
Yeah,
there's people out there that think to
satellites are fake and they think that
they were real and that the earth is
flat as that's once I just shake my head
like the moon landing one's my favorite.
I got balls deep in that for years.
I was completely.
You think they did not go to the moon?
No,
I don't.
I don't think that anymore,
but I.
You know what I think now I think I
don't know,
but I do think that it is one of the
more fascinating conspiracies that
between 1969 in 1972,
they had seven,
seven,
seven attempt.
Six of them successful when they went to
the apollo 13 was the one that they
didn't apparently make it and they had
to come back,
but that was the only time in history
that a human being has been more than
400 miles above the earth's surface.
All the space station missions,
all the space shuttle missions and all
that stuff is is within orbit.
That's low.
That's all very low.
They went 260,000
miles out and back into deep space,
but they had never even flown a chicken
out there and see if it comes alive.
Like we really,
really?
Yeah.
No,
I'm not into this space.
Travel.
And so.
And they did a couple of flybys went
around the moon early before they landed
on the moon.
Yeah.
But other than that,
I mean without unmanned drones,
like what we have on mars and things
like that.
We've never really sent a living thing
out through the magneto sphere,
through the van allen radiation belts
into deep space,
have it,
you know,
there's all these possibilities of solar
flares and anything that would have
killed him instantly and they just did
that and then we haven't been able to do
that since 1972.
That's the one way I.
I've never looked into the moon landing.
I think it's kind of goofy.
Right?
Well,
it's weird.
It's a weird one.
Why have we never gone back?
It's been fifth,
surely our technology is far superior to
what it was in 1969,
right.
The technology is far superior except
that they're not using that technology
for man space travel into deep space
like that and it's going to the moon,
so it's like our technology and all
these other areas is superior,
but they haven't really worked towards
that because they haven't been funded.
So the big issue is in many ways it's
money,
right?
It's how much money is there and going
to the moon and it's also very risky to
send humans out there.
Maybe we're talking about manned
missions to mars now,
which may or may not take place by 20,
30.
They're talking about doing that,
but it's way cheaper and safer to send
robots out there.
Like why risk human lives retro the
moon.
Right?
And if put robots on mars,
rovers,
rovers on mars or most,
that's the most interesting because
they're.
They're sending these really high
resolution photos of the surface of mars
and they're running tests and checking
for biological life.
It's really,
really interesting stuff,
but between 69 and 72 when they did all
this stuff,
I mean there's the technology back then
was nothing compared to what they have
now in terms of calculations and
computers and and it's also there was a.
There's unquestionably some stuff that,
whether it was images or video that was
faked and I think really like that never
looked into this at all.
Gemini 15 is the big one because there's
a photo of Michael Collins,
it shows him in deep space and they,
they use it as a press release saying
that he was on a space walk when it was
really an image of him from a test run
where there was all this stuff in the
background and he was on his harness and
they just blacked out the background and
tried to sell it.
As him being in space a find that my
Michael Collins,
I was looking at how much it costs to
send somebody to space,
so it's an insane 79,
70 million for ash,
a nasa astronaut to fly on a russian
shuttle.
Private guy's trying to sell tickets to
places that mean phase.
I was just trying to do at musc
obviously,
but that space,
that's just,
that's just low earth orbit.
That's,
that's still inside 400 miles.
None of them are trying to go anywhere.
No.
Well they might in the future.
Branson.
Well that's all same thing.
It's all the way through but,
but,
but they are talking about future visits
to the moon and to mars.
But a lot of times I feel like when they
say that,
you know,
George Bush senior said that they were
going to go to the moon,
back to the moon again in like fucking
one was that 1990 or whatever the hell
that was.
But People have always said we're going
to go back to the moon,
but we haven't been back since 1972.
Does that mean that we never went?
No,
but then it gets weird when you find out
that wernher von braun was a fucking
nazi.
Who?
Wernher von braun,
the guy who was the head of nasa.
He was the guy who organized the moon
landings and though he was the head
rocket guy,
he was he.
That guy was a legit nazi like he's
wanted by the simon wiesenthal center,
said that he was alive today.
They would prosecute him for crimes
against humanity.
They would hang the five slowest workers
every day in front of his berlin rocket
factory.
Oh yeah.
No,
100 percent.
I mean,
that's what they did.
What they did was they took this thing
was called operation paperclip,
where when we won world war two,
they took all the top nazi scientists
and they secretly brought them over to
America and they did it on the down low
so that no one would think like,
hey,
why do we have a guy named wernher von
braun running the american space program
was because the,
the nazi scientists or insanely
advanced.
So the question is like,
well,
were they really nazis or were they
scientists that were under the boot of
the nazi administration?
I mean,
well,
I don't know.
I mean,
I'm not around that,
but I do know that these are the people
that were the head engineers and the
people that designed it.
Wernher von braun's himself was saying
how impossible it was just years before
they did the moon landing and years
before operation paperclip,
that it was impossible to go to the moon
or how ridiculously impossible would be,
but technology advanced from then to
when 19,
69 happened to when they did it.
I stopped saying that we never went to
the moon because I really don't know
what the fuck I'm talking about and
that's.
That's a big part of understanding these
conspiracies is hard.
You have to.
Well,
you have to really know.
How much do I know about rocketry?
how much do I know about aerospace?
C?
Zero.
So if I'm running around saying,
I don't know,
I don't believe people went to the moon.
What is it based on?
It's based on mostly on ignorance,
speculation and the exciting,
the excited feeling that comes with
trying to uncover a conspiracy.
Sure.
But a,
and I think you do have to be a little
bit discerning on what you hear,
but it is frustrating and that's where a
lot of these conspiracy guys,
they think they know more than they do
because you have to come to the
realization that you're probably never
going to know the real answer with a lot
of these things.
Realize that.
I mean some of them come out many,
many,
many years later we're talking about the
gulf of tonkin writer or operation
northwoods.
Many years later it comes out,
but you know there's a good likelihood
that I'll never know the truth on stuff
I read a lot about.
I think with the moon landing,
it's way more likely that we went to the
moon,
But that some of the footage is fake and
I think they probably did that because
it's incredibly difficult to film things
on the moon and I think they filmed some
stuff in test runs and then tried to
pass that.
They didn't have it Back then.
They had these cameras that they had in
the center of their chest.
I think they have been taking a selfie
on the moon.
They have the snapchat snap chatting it.
You'd have to take your shirt off and
then you would die because they didn't
have a camera that you could put in
front of you.
Well,
maybe they have all those clicker
buttons they could have wIth their big
gloves on and they put the thing out and
then click it and then boom,
snapchat life on the moon.
Well,
that's what they said.
it was that they did it remotely.
That's how they captured the video of
the lunar module,
leaving the surface of the moon and
panned up and watched it go that they
did all that remotely.
It's all this some squirrely footage
ever.
See the video of them jumping around it
like they're on trampolines.
See that?
Like they're just bouncing straight up
in the air and you're like,
well,
what the fuck is that?
How come the physics are different in
different flights?
Like in some,
some of the flights like apollo 11,
they're barely getting off the ground
and one where they're like,
they're walking,
but they're going to do like that.
Well,
there's ones like that,
and then there's also ones where they
fall down.
It looks like the getting yanked up by
wires.
I think it's entirely possible that some
of that stuff was fake,
but I don't.
I think it's way more likely that they
actually went to the moon then they
didn't,
but it's way sexier to think that they
faked the whole thing.
It's fun.
It's fun to think they faked the whole
thing and everybody was quiet about it.
And you know,
neil armstrong gave this real cryptic
speech on the 25th anniversary of the
moon mission saying that,
you know,
there are hidden truths,
uh,
the,
that uh,
what,
uh,
what is the exact quote that he said?
Um,
some of the great truths that could be
real revealed,
removing some of truths,
hidden layers.
Like he was giving her away.
It was real cryptic.
It was like,
what do you see if you could find it?
Yeah.
Play the.
He might've been given it away.
Well,
it seems if you were conspiracy theory,
this would give you a rock hard boner
because less than listen to this,
neil armstrong made a rare public
appearance.
Next generation of tax payers.
No,
no,
no.
Just play the whole thing so you don't
confuse everybody.
In 1994,
neil armstrong mater rare public
appearance and held back tears as he
spoke these brief cryptic remarks before
the next generation of tax payers as
they toured the white house.
Today we have with this group of
students some on america's best to you.
We say we have only completed a
beginning.
We leave you much.
That is under.
There are great ideas.
Undiscovered breakthroughs are available
to those who can remove one of truett's
protective layers.
What the fuck does that mean?
I mean what you supposed to say?
Yo,
I went to the moon bitch.
That's supposed to say breakthroughs
away.
Truth,
protective layers like I don't
understand what that means.
The via the press conferences.
One of the more fascinating things,
if you watch the press conference again,
I was balls deep in this stuff for
years.
The press conference from 1969 when they
were returned from the moon is one of
the most cryptic weird things you'll
ever see.
these guys look like they just stole
something and they're being questioned.
It's,
it's.
I've never seen a video where people
look like they're more full of shit.
Then that video of the press conference
from 1969.
It's weird,
man.
It's weird.
They're like fidgety and looking nervous
lIke they're getting away with
something.
Then they might have done it.
They might have been forced to say some
things that they didn't want to say and
that could be part of it.
Absolutely know they could have done it,
but there's a lot of weirdness with the
moon landing.
It's,
it's.
If you wanted to have like a conspiracy
that to wrap your head around.
IT's exciting.
It's one of the best ones who benefit,
who benefits from it?
The United States government did because
it showed military superiority over the
russian,
so we were able to do that,
but also it was the nixon
administration.
People would just flat out full of shit.
Well,
yeah.
I mean they were just lying to people
left and right back the government
though.
Yeah,
but even more so then because It was
unchecked,
there was no media,
nothing that would expose them for this
and this stuff.
They would air it on tv once in 1969.
You never see it again unless you
watched it on failed.
There's no youtube.
We can go back and watch the astronauts
on trampolines video.
That's my favorite one.
You wAtch that.
You know what in the fuck is happening
there.
These guys are bouncing up in the air
like how are they doing that?
Like they never did.
If you watch apollo 11 when they were
moving around on the surface of the
moon,
it just like they're moving in slow
motion and then you go to whatever it
was like apollo 14 or 15 when they were
doing the trampoline thing.
They fucking flying through the air.
Have you seen it?
I have not.
I know I had never gotten to the moon
thing.
The flight watching this ridiculous.
This
and like their feet are hidden.
Look at this.
Watch these guys bounced up in the air.
It's like they're on some sort of
wireless being yanked up into the air.
Oh yeah,
like what the fuck are they doing?
And they're playing like falling down
and it's very weird,
but it could've been that they were
really on the moon and these guys were
fucking cowboys and yahoos and they
wanted to bounce around.
Oh,
you were pacing your posted those
videos,
post those videos back in the day.
Yeah.
I had a debate on penn jillette's radio
show with a guy who was an astronomer
and he wasn't willing to admit a lot of
stuff.
That was a fact,
like the fact that wernher von braun was
a nazi and the fly looks was still
there.
Well,
the flag had a wire first of all on the
top of it that stiffened it up to make
it,
but there there's videos of the flag
moving in a nonexistent breeze,
which is weird too,
and they try to make some logical
explanations for why the flAg could be
moving in a vacuum and some of it makes
sense,
but some of it doesn't like the wires.
One is weird if you watch them fall
down,
like go to that one right there.
Jamie.
You like if you watch sometimes they're
falling down and when they're falling
down it looks like they get yanked back
up,
but I think it might not have been real
footage.
What they might've done is use some test
footage like right there at jamie,
right there.
Let it go.
Like homeboy falls down and then it
looks like he is yanked back up.
Look at it.
Oh,
he did not want him standing up.
Yeah.
What is this that's standing up?
You can't stand up like that.
Right?
But you're on the moon.
Earth gravity.
But there was no.
There was nothing to make them go like
this.
Right.
You can't get
up without.
Exactly.
Now we go back to mma because that's
what these freaking folkstyle wrestling
is.
The next generation of mma you can turn
to your base to get up.
You can't look at it.
There's nothing on the ground.
How's he going to get them on?
Mexican yanked up.
He would have super abs.
He would have to be like a break dancer
because okay.
Maybe a break dancer,
a break dancer,
but you can't get up without putting a
base down.
Right?
Yeah.
That waS really weird.
I never saw a court.
watch it again.
Watch them get yanked up.
Yeah.
He's got no base.
That little pieces played in reverse.
Almost does.
It almost does.
Yeah.
That he couldn't stand up like that,
but the thing falls down right
afterwards.
So it wasn't a reverse.
Not.
I think it's entirely possible that some
of the footage was bullshit,
but it doesn't mean that they didn't go
to the moon.
It means that overzealous people in.
He only has one sweat on the ground
there too.
Right?
Yeah.
Well that's true.
Look at this watch.
So he stood up like,
that's ridiculous.
You can't do it.
Right.
Foot's down.
His left foot's up and he just goes
straight up there.
That's fake.
But I've never been in one six,
zero gravity and neither of you know
what that says.
We never went to the moon was fake.
No,
the video is real.
That's from television.
The video,
that guy standing up like that.
He got help somehow.
Well,
he can't stand up like that very well.
He could have been on wires.
It could have been that they were using
that to simulate what it would be like
because they definitely filled a lot of
simulations.
They get a lot of that because they
wanted to prepare the astronauts.
It's entirely possible that some of
those simulations gotten passed off as
being an actual video of them on the
moon.
Sure.
Yeah.
FaIr enough.
Or the fake.
The whole fucking thing.
I wasn't there,
so pretty used to it as a privilege.
I think folkstyle wrestling is the next.
That's the next genesis of mma,
right?
We go,
what's next?
like that guy standing up.
People don't realize if you watched the
lima roy fight,
it was,
it was incredibly frustrating to watch
for me,
uh,
because lima was literally just laying
on his back and guard,
you know,
and guard is almost nonexistent
effective in mma now.
What?
Unless you're Brian Ortega.
Okay.
There's a few guys,
tiny amount,
but I think those.
But those guys are like,
you,
like your wrestling is so highly
effective in mna.
Some people could say you can't get by
just with breslin.
Well,
hey,
I don't wrestle.
I'm a black belt in jujitsu.
You use a lot of wrestling.
Yeah,
primarily.
Yeah.
I mean It's not that Brian Ortega can
box too.
We could do a lot of other things.
Strike.
I mean he's a good solid striker,
but his guard is so dangerous.
It's just another level of dangerous as
opposed to most mma fighters,
including lehman.
yeah.
And so,
uh,
you know,
people actually going back to their
base,
right?
Which has been,
it's been a no,
no forever.
And it may,
you don't go back to your base because
you expose your back.
But then again,
you know,
what percentage of guys who are sitting
in guard actually get submissions from
the garden.
Now the numbers really small really
well.
So you're going to have to find out now.
Okay.
Like this is so,
so frustrating.
So the,
in the,
in the lima fight,
roy wins the first two rounds.
It's competitive,
but he wins pretty clearly.
But the leg kicks her state.
I'd never been kicked as hard by
anyone's douglas lema.
He kicked me one time in the leg.
I freaking it and walk right for a week.
really?
oh my god.
He kicks so hard.
He took so hard,
so hard.
And so I'm third round.
There's this accumulation of leg kicks
and all of a sudden roy's leg is really
up from getting kicked a handful of
times.
Right.
And you to doing that low caffeine.
Yes.
Will kick it.
I'm kind of all over.
The roy royster are starting to do this
one instead of checking it.
So lima starts taking control of the
fight.
I think he wins the third run in my
opinion.
Fourth route in the beginning.
He like kicks him once and roy falls
down and he hops into mountain starts
beating him up was like,
holy crap,
this fight might be over and then so
recovers.
But then the fifth round,
rory goes out and shoots like a single
leg.
Double leg,
like immediate.
We're talking first 10 seconds.
Right?
And going into that,
ryan,
you think shit,
he might get finished this round.
I mean,
he,
he can barely walk,
look at his leg and so they make us take
it down 10 seconds into the round,
he literally stayed in guard for four
minutes,
50 seconds and you're like,
at some point is he going to try to get
up because he has to get.
If he gets up and he lands were two more
kicks it out,
getting taken down to fights.
Likely over.
Wow.
You know.
But he refuses to turn to his base
because this is anti Jujitsu.
You shouldn't turn to your base in
jujitsu because you your budget and
choked.
Yeah.
Fuck it joe.
At that point you're losing,
right?
What else are you going to do?
Well,
he never tried to sweep them.
He never did try to submit them off my
back.
Butterfly sweeping a couple of times.
But.
So at this point,
I mean even if I thought it was two,
two rounds,
right,
right.
It was in the fifth round.
You've got to try to get up at some
point.
So that was the one that did it for
rory.
So he won.
He won 49,
46 on two scorecards in 48,
47 slash one.
So what?
It was three to one.
So then even more,
right?
Even more reason to get up,
right if you're losing by that much,
um,
but yet lima refused to get up.
So at that point I'm thinking,
well,
hey,
maybe lima thinks he won or something.
I dunno.
But yeah,
so a lot of jujitsu people are
struggling with this fact that in modern
day mma you're going to have to try to
get up because god is no longer that
effective and you just get punched in
the face over and over and over again.
And that's terrible.
What are your feelings on going to half
guard and like going for an underwriter?
Same side and yeah,
try it,
but it's not,
you know,
again,
like as me as a,
as a top guy,
I would rather be in half guard than
full guard.
I'm going to land a lot of damage from
half guard.
And then you're also,
if you're half guard here and me trying
to work and you're tired and you're very
unlikely to sweep me.
So I think half guard is better than
full guard,
but I think,
I think eventually where people are
going to have to get to is they're going
to have to actually get up.
You're gonna have to get up and putting
your feet on someone's hips and kicking
them is no longer a great solution.
It works every once in a while,
but it's not like you can do that every
single time.
It just gets.
It's pretty rare.
Pretty rare.
So he rarely.
Everybody's so aware of it.
Yeah.
So bottom bottom and top folk style
wrestling
I think is the next genesis and mma
where people are really going to have to
have a deep understanding because once
you do get taken down or once you get a
takedown,
um,
and there's some,
you know,
yoel romero was the perfect example.
He never did folks wrestling in America,
right?
He's a very,
very elite freestyle wrestler,
but he gets his takedowns and you can
always stay on top for like 15 seconds.
Right.
It's like you did all that work to get
the guy on the ground and they use let
him back up.
Like what was the point?
Right?
What was the point of it?
Well,
he's,
he smashes some guys on the ground like
machida when he got him down on the
ground and some of them you put them
away.
He's um,
he's a freak athlete too because it's
hard to say hey,
do what he does because like,
no one's built.
Like that guy.
That guy's the weird.
He has the weirdest body I've ever seen.
Really?
Why?
Because he looks like he's 230 pounds
and he weighs one 85 when he weighs in.
How the fuck is that one?
80 five.
I always look at him.
I'm like,
I don't even understand it.
Like where's the weight going?
And you would think he's.
Well as guys it's on pds but looking at
him.
But then when you look at him like he
won a world title and 98,
99,
somewhere in there.
He looks the same.
It was the same at age 18 or 19,
you know,
it's incredible because then you think
like,
well if he is a pdf that had to be prior
to age 18 because he looks the same.
Well what are your thoughts on like
corella and cause you know the curlies
yeah,
but they used to call him d experiment.
Yeah.
And his parents are tiny,
you know those parents are like five,
five,
seven,
and then he's six foot whatever the fuck
he is a guru of man.
Yeah.
And I always wondered like one day in
the future,
whether it's five years from now or 30
years from now,
they're going to be genetically
manipulated people.
Crazy,
right.
We watched icarus.
Sure.
Which is to,
oh yeah,
you had.
And that was fast thing and that pretty
much just,
I mean cemented the russian that
anti-doping program or they run every
single person,
state sponsored doping program for
everybody,
for everybody,
for everybody.
Which crazy.
And it's like you had the hint that they
were likely cheating,
you know,
but then as someone who competed against
them,
man,
that's a tough pill to swallow because
they wouldn't make you feel.
I mean,
now it's like,
well shit,
I guess I should have been one way or
the other,
but to know that you are a leg down and
like going into mma now I haven't met.
I do.
Everyone was cheating for sure.
Right.
So I'm going to fight them whether
they're cheating or not,
like to pride days.
it was essentially sanction that was
sanctioned.
Like tHey would tell them like,
hey,
you know,
when this contract that says you can do
steroids,
right.
How does one fc handle that?
Uh,
so they don't,
they don't do drug testing yet.
Well that's,
yeah,
I mean it should be fun.
I've been pushing them to do so,
uh,
you know,
in my time there.
and,
and their,
their thing is that,
um,
a lot of these countries,
it's not prevalent in Indonesia or
manila or wherever.
So what else?
Just to find out,
just get the fuck out of here with that.
That's my,
that's not my,
that's not me saying that.
That's there joe rogan saying that.
Get the fuck out of there,
but I know you've sought,
you've,
you've talked a couple of
times.
I've heard you bought their way in
program at one sts,
which I think is fantastic and I think
every,
every mma organization should do it at
the high level one.
Could you explain it?
Yeah.
so it's really simple.
You do hydration and you do wait on
scale,
same time.
So you can't cut water weight out.
Right?
Right.
So it depends,
hydrate,
get on the scale.
Literally moments later,
like you go in the bathroom,
you piss,
they test the specific gravity you go
get on the scale.
Right?
So essentially everyone moved up one way
class.
Every one of their champions bumped up a
weight class.
So like over there I fight one of the
five,
but you know,
it's essentially welter,
they,
they even call it welterweight because
it's the same thing because I can't cut
any waterway.
So they adjusted it.
So they adjusted,
they moved every day.
So I was the welterweight champion.
I was still the way to welterweight
champion,
they just move,
the weight class is different.
Um,
so there's the day of the fight today
before the fight for the fight.
If you make the two days before the
fight,
if you make both the weight and the
hydration,
you do not have to wait test or
hydration test in the last eight years,
you're clear.
So if you make it both those days
because you're not going to be,
there's not going to fluctuate and
funding for hours.
And listen,
if you can figure out how to cheat that,
I can't figure out how someone could
possibly cheat that test because now
when they first incident I said,
well,
how is someone going to cheat on this?
Or how could someone cheat?
You know what it's like they look at
their watch,
your piss,
you know,
you can't have like a withdrawn or
anything.
Uh,
so I don't,
I don't know how you achieve.
I don't think you can.
So yeah.
So it's fantastic because like fight
week then instead of making this.
And so what I would fight at one 70,
one 83 to one 85 to start my waterway,
cut out,
cut the waterway to one 70 or 71
depending on pedal or non title.
And then I would hydrate back up.
so now I don't have to do that.
The dehydration process,
I'm literally the exact same size I was
prior.
And uh,
you know,
media obligations during week are
obviously a lot easier because I'm not
worried about cutting my weight or I'm
not feeling miserable or whatever.
Um,
and it's a lot safer.
And then,
so if someone misses,
so,
mrs.
Obviously there find the same as in
America.
If you miss what you're find,
if you miss hydration,
uh,
so say joe,
you're wanting 85 and you weighed in
when a five,
but you're dehydrated,
you didn't really make it right.
You have to get hydrated and make
weight.
So if you miss,
if you miss it,
so it's the last day you haven't made
it.
You have to keep drinking until you piss
hydrated.
And then whatever you way there is what
you weigh.
What's the parameters when it comes to
hYdration?
Not hydration.
It's the.
It's the same skill they use for it.
So in America,
at the beginning of the college
wrestling season or high school,
you have to do specific every test.
I believe I might mess up a zero,
but I think it's one point.
Zero,
two five.
Okay.
Is this a specific group which I know is
the same they use for hydrated,
not hydrated In wrestling in America to
anything under that you're dehydrated.
No,
you're good.
So you want to be bullet.
So one point zero,
zero,
zero.
Zero is water.
Oh,
okay.
So you want to be close to that.
Right?
And so There is like you do have to,
you have to drink some water,
right?
If you drink a whole bunch of water,
you piss it out perfectly hydrated.
But if there have been a couple of
times.
So in the early days they did,
they did tests.
This is the first two days actually just
testing to see where you were at.
The third day was the one that counted,
you know.
And so like if you,
if you ate a bunch of meat or something,
you might show up as dehydrated even
though that's what you walk around and
every single day,
so you have to make sure you drink a lot
of water.
So it's coming out nice and clear.
That's an interesting way of doing it.
And I think that's a great idea because
I think that is one of the biggest
problems in mma to uriah hall.
And vito belfort get canceled last week.
Uriah hall was like literally having
seizures on his way to the way it's
crazy.
Right?
It's fucking insane.
And I think it's one of the worst parts
of mma because I think mma shouldn't be
about who's slickest in being able to
deceive the weight system.
I mean it should be your skill versus
your opponent's skill.
You're both the same.
Well the whole,
the whole point of it is the whole point
of the way the fight.
Similar,
same size.
That's the whole point of it.
Yes.
and so why people would fight back
against those system that one fc is
using is beyond me because listen,
the most miserable part of my weight
cut.
I'm fine dieting.
That's all good.
right?
But when you got to cut that last 12,
13,
14 pounds of water weight out,
it's miserable.
Everybody knows is miserable.
Right?
And it affects your performance the next
day.
Yeah,
I mean,
so my,
my thought process with affects them
more than it affects me.
Maybe that's just me being positive
about it.
Right.
why is that?
Because if you're a wrestling and pussy
and I'm not right or maybe it's just me,
my me psyching myself up.
So my thought process on everythIng is
anything that goes wrong will affect my
opponent more than it'll affect me.
Oh that's good.
But I am more stable.
I can deal with shit that goes wrong.
Most people affects them.
And so maybe that's just me telling
myself that,
but that makes me feel good about it.
People feel that way about wakening the
lightweight cutting because they think
that the other guy is not gonna be able
to handle it as well.
Make them go through some adversity and
then the next day he's gonna
troubled.
Sure,
exactly.
So,
but I think if you take that process
away,
I think it makes media obligations a lot
easier.
It makes people a lot healthier and
yeah,
I mean how many fights have,
just from a business standpoint,
how many fights have we had canceled
this year because of the weight thing.
I mean quite a few.
Did it change your performance?
How physically?
How do you,
how would you feel?
I think I felt,
you know,
honestly for me,
I know they said those studies that you
don't really fully hydrated.
I believe it was 36 to 48 hours after
man.
I've always felt fine.
And so I,
I,
so when I graduated college,
the way class in the United States for,
for the olympic stuff was one 63.
I would weigh roughly one slash 75 on a
day to day basis.
And then water cut down to one 63.
Um,
and then when I was fighting in one 70,
I will be say between one eight,
three,
one 85 and water cut down to one 70.
So my water weight cut was very,
very similar every single time.
And I was disciplined in that manner.
I want,
I didn't want to be fluctuating.
And so my goal is actually to get down
to my target weight six weeks prior to
competition,
right?
So I'm walking around one a three,
two,
one,
one five,
six weeks prior.
So I'm on the same exact person every
sIngle day.
Whereas I think the part that a lot of
these people f up and it's because
they're not disciplined enough,
is they try to descend while they're
training,
right.
You know,
maybe I get up to one 95,
which is a small bump.
Some of these guys are really
undisciplined.
They get way,
way,
way overweight,
right?
And so during that last six weeks or
even the last couple of weeks,
they're trying to bring that body weight
down.
Right?
And so in my mind,
there's two ways to lose weight.
You can diet and lose body weight,
fat mass,
whatever.
Um,
and then there's the waterweight where
we're sweating and we're taking that out
of us.
Right?
Those are the two ways.
And so I think a lot of guys and I,
you know,
I don't know if you've ever cut wait
show,
but I know so for me it was in college
and in the summers I'd get really fat
and then I'd bring my weight down in the
fall and you feel it when you're not,
when you're losing more calories than
you're taking in,
it's like this weird feeling in your
body and you feel like shit all the
time.
And so I think a lot of fighters are
doing that really close to when they're
fighting.
And so now the waterway cut makes you
feel terrible and now they're cutting
everything out.
Calorically alSo.
So that's like a double whammy.
That's what I think about it.
There's another thing that benefits
wrestlers in the wrestlers seem to take
pride in being able to push through
discomfort.
And the more miserable you are,
the more you just fucking bite down your
mouthpiece and deal with it.
We're [inaudible] you get used to doing
that all through camps all through
college and high school.
you're always dehydrated.
You're always losing weight.
Well,
I mean the college dressing that is not
that.
The way cutting is not that bad anymore.
So they have the system and people are
starting to change a 97.
I think couple people died and change
it,
but you know,
then they institute the same thing as
one fc.
That's sort of a portion.
So it's once you do it in the being a
season,
find your minimum weight.
But I think more than anything what
people are,
it's,
it's a one ron.
So you.
So if you're dual meet is at 1:00,
everybody weighs in at noon,
right?
So what people have found out,
you can't cut.
Wait,
you can't go wait.
You wrestled like shit.
So the problem with fighting,
doing that though,
his brain injuries.
Yeah.
So that's I think once you'd best.
But in college wrestling you're talking
about the discomfort thing.
Part of that is that,
you know when you go to a college
wrestling program,
again,
it's very structured.
You can't skip,
you have to be there every single day,
right on time.
And then it's like you have 40 black
belt,
right jujitsu,
black belts,
and not even just black belts like world
class 19 to 23 in their physical prime
ready to fight each other every single
day.
And so you get used to this grind
dealing with people battling people
discomfort every single day.
Um,
you know,
and a lot of it's also dealing with
injuries like,
you know,
in charleston and talks about it a lot
that hey and I was talking to my kids
was listening to national tournament for
the nca is March 15th through 17th and
you cannot guarantee me you're going to
be totally healthy on that date.
You cannot guarantee meet your and be a
not sick on that date.
You're going to have to compete March
15th through March 17th no matter what,
if you want to enroll a national title.
And so wrestlers get used to this grind
where you just don't see that in other
sports.
Yeah.
I think that that aspect of wrestling is
one of the biggest tools that they take
into the octagon.
The mental toughness and that ability
to.
I mean the grind,
it's again,
it's,
it's a badge of in wrestling
to be able to handle the grind.
It's not really in kickboxing or in moy,
tai or any other sport.
Well,
they're not really forced to.
I mean how many,
how many kickboxing or or jujitsu
schools,
cuny name,
where there's literally 40 black belts.
I mean it's,
it's been borne out through high school
wrestling.
You go to all these national
tournaments,
estate terms,
you find out who the best are,
the best of the best,
get recruited and they go to these
institutions to train with the other
best of the best of the best,
you know,
and then,
and then in addition to that,
the other,
the post-collegiate guys who were trying
to make the world teams and olympic
teams,
they're sticking around training.
So you have this melting pot of freaking
really great wrestlers.
They're trading with each other every
single day for five to plus five years
if you're going to world championships,
right?
Yeah.
There also seems to be like a much more
systematic approach to training people
and a lot more drilling,
you knoW,
and a lot of jujitsu schools like gosh,
the arm bar from the guard here.
We hooked the arm.
Okay.
I go onto here,
my legs,
I make my leg,
I lift up.
Okay.
Your practice,
everybody get together.
It drives me insane.
It drives a few times.
Like I'll go to jujitsu classes
sometimes and they'll literally go over
to techniques.
You drill it twice and then the last
rest of the class is just people
rolling.
Five minutes,
five,
five minute goes.
It drives me insane gel because I come
from this wrestling background and then
I also like sports.
Psych and
study of high performance is like that's
what I love.
I love.
I love studying people who are the best
in their field at whatever they do and
we know without a shadow of a doubt,
just saying go for five minutes is not
the most effective way to train someone
does not happen.
So the wrestling,
there's a whole bUnch of different you
could do.
Some days you might do matches,
some days you might do a 30 minute ago,
some days you might do groups of three
women.
That goes,
some days you might do situations.
I start on the single leg,
I started the high crotch,
I a friend doc,
right?
And so there's all these different
scenarios that we might try.
I mean,
if I'm coaching my academy right and
we're working on,
we drove front headlocks or we call
methods position,
we've got both armpits and bounce and go
for that.
We don't just say,
okay,
now go five minute goes because how
many,
how many tribes are they going to get it
going into the maths position that are
the front headlock,
maybe one,
maybe two,
but essentially most people have used
say go for five minutes.
They,
they,
they're not disciplined enough to make
themselves do new skills.
They revert to whatever they do best and
then just do it over and over and over
and over again.
Right?
And so if I want a kid to be good at a
headlock,
which if you'Re going to wrestle at a
high level,
you need a good for headlock,
period factual,
you have to have it.
I'm going to put him in there 50 times
in that practice.
He's going to get it over and over and
over and over and maybe the next day
it's single legs and the maybe next day
it's double legs,
right?
And then maybe some days you say,
hey,
go for 10 minutes,
go wrestle,
right?
Because you want to change it little
bit,
but saying go for five minutes.
Every single day is very much not the
most effective way to do it.
And it's so insanely frustrating for me
to have that haPpen.
and almost every jujitsu school on the
planet
bravo's talked about this a lot and one
of the things that he says that,
I'm jujitsu,
so fun to roll,
that people just want to get to the
rolling part real quick.
I don't care what they want.
He could like,
I don't freaking care,
joel.
I want to.
And my kids tell me all kinds of stuff.
I said,
I,
I'm running practice,
I went to the olympics,
I want to have trophies.
You're at my school because you want to
learn how to be the best diamond house
to be the best.
Yeah.
I don't care what yoU like.
I don't care what you like.
Some days,
every once In a while.
Hey,
you guys don't play games.
Let's play games every once in awhile
just to keep it fun.
Just to keep it fun.
Right?
Hey,
you want to do this?
Let's do that every,
every once in a while.
Okay.
I'll indulge you.
But most of the time your here and so,
you know,
we don't.
For our,
for our young,
we don't really push our young kids too
hard,
but like,
especially when we're talking about high
school guys,
you're telling me you want to be a state
champion,
you're telling me you wanna go to
college,
you're telling me all these things you
wanted to.
I know what it takes to get there.
I've been there myselF,
I've seen many other people achieve
those things and so you know,
and there's a lot of,
you know,
it's really funny because people choose
to in this,
even though mma we can go live,
people choose what they value.
Right?
And I'll juSt give you a simple example.
I'll get this.
I got this one kid who's probably
listening to this show right now because
I know he loves you.
Uh,
what's his name is.
ah,
well I can't give one of my kids a shout
out and that all of them,
so okay.
But he's probably,
he's gonna know who I'm talking about.
He goes freaking hard.
Just boom,
grind,
grind.
Just I couldn't eat.
I couldn't ask for a kid to work harder
joe.
But when I started teaching technique,
he tunes me out and then we go to a
national tournament and he places but he
gets,
he gets scored on a whole bunch by the
technique.
We were just drilling and then I say,
hey bud,
you just tune me out.
The last three weeks we were just
drilling that thing and you got your ass
kicked by it.
And so I love the fact that you want to
go hard,
but you need to also value the
technique,
right?
Yeah.
And then there's some people who valued
the technique too much and they all do.
I do the technique and then when it
comes to going hard,
they don't go hard enough.
Right?
Because in wrestling or in any,
in any venture you want to take in life,
there's not just one way to be
successful.
You need a bunch of different attributes
to be successful and so if you overvalue
one or another and you devalue other
things,
you're not going to be as successful as
you could.
You might still be successful,
but you're not going to reach the
pinnacle because you're not putting
yourself into the right situation.
It's funny because in a lot of ways it's
like what you were talking about
earlier,
the two sides of the coin of a fighter
being a wild person who doesn't care,
the cowboy and then the other guy who's
like super systematic,
everything's controlled.
Yeah.
You almost have to have everything and
the fighters that have those really
strong attributes just have to be aware
that those attributes are strengthened
even further by technique.
Yeah,
a hundred percent.
And again,
it's both sides that quantum,
he and another one would be,
uh,
you know,
suddenly called beginner's mind and then
know it all right.
When you come into,
when you come into practice,
you need to have a beginner's mind.
I mean,
I got to work out with three or four
time world champion olympic champion
pearl's last week and he was asking me
questions.
It's like this guy really cared about
learning from every possible source and
he's already,
he's already at the pinnacle and still
trying to learn.
Interesting thing to dominick cruz said
during the broadcast about steep meo
chick that steep when he went to
alliance,
mma was asking everybody,
you have to.
Yeah.
But then when you go into a competition,
you can't have the same mindset thinking
I don't know,
I need to ask.
Right?
And so like kids who,
kids who have just the beginner's mind,
theY'll,
they're great in practice,
but then they go into
like cultural,
which I do here,
what should I do?
Which I do.
It's like,
let's just go wrestle,
wrestle.
But then kids Are coming to practice
like I know it.
All right,
well that's a very unhealthy mindset
also because you.
And it's great when you compete.
It's great when you compete.
So you got it.
You got to balance both those things,
right?
Like you can't have just one because if
you're,
I know it all.
I'm a bad ass.
That's great for competition.
But you come into practice,
you're going to stop.
You're learning right now when you're
coaching kids,
how much time,
if any,
do you spend on mindset?
Um,
and so at every I added my facebook
every monday I do this mental monday and
then I usually repeat,
repeat it or something fairly similar to
the kids at practice.
but I also think it's a lot,
you know,
I think competition is where you get
your really,
really good teachable moments because
that's when kids care the most.
And so,
like the kid I was talking about when he
loses it,
because he didn't want to listen to me,
I,
because say,
well,
look it,
look at this.
This is a great example.
I did this,
I do private lessons with this fourth
and fifth grader.
They're brothers and uh,
and like five weeks in rome,
you're doing this wrong.
You're doing this wrong,
you're doing this wrong,
you're doing this wrong.
They don't want to listen,
right?
Then they do it.
They have a match.
Last week they do it wrong and it didn't
cost them the match,
but it almost costs in the match.
And,
and now I can say every single time I
say you're doing this wrong,
or I can say,
remember that time in that match when
you putting your back because you did it
wrong and you refuse to listen to me.
So I think that,
uh,
matches create great teachable moments.
You know,
like,
hey,
you remember when you wilted under the
pressure because you weren't tough
enough,
will you need to practice a little
harder?
So you get used to that pressure.
Remember when the referee made a bad
call and you flipped out because he made
a bad call and they didn't think about,
well,
I still have to wrestle addresses match,
right?
So there could be all these,
there's all these teachable moments
within competition where you can say
point to something very clearly and say,
well,
look at this and see how this affected
you and see how you would have been more
successful.
So I think for mental aspect it comes a
lot more on one,
on one basis and sometimes I'll use it
in front of the whole team.
I don't,
I don't like really picking on people,
uh,
every,
once in awhile I will.
Um,
but so I think that,
I think there's competition provides a
lot of teachable moments for athletes to
see,
well,
am I stronger here?
What do I need to work on?
Because again,
we can't,
you can't say one mental aspect makes it
guy successful.
It's this conglomeration of many,
many,
many mental aspects that will make
highly successful.
Now when you're coaching,
whether it's coaching wrestlers or mma
fighter coach anymore,
none.
Zero.
I have.
Okay.
I helped a couple of buddies,
but I don't consider it really just
helps you.
When you say,
just say when you're coaching,
do you,
do you concentrate it all on strength
and conditioning or,
or is it from the wrestling that you get
most of your strength conditioning?
So we only got them,
you know,
an hour and a half,
three or four times a week.
And so we don't do lasting conditioning.
I know I,
I right.
Especially with the older guard that
recommend they do some
on their own,
um,
you know,
for a college program,
for high school program where we're
getting them monday through saturday,
maybe twice a day possibly.
Obviously we're going to do that,
but you know,
we're an academy,
uh,
you know,
we're kind of on our own.
We give them three or four times a week,
so it just doesn't trump what we need to
do in that short time window.
How do you balance it out though?
Like how do you know how much strength
and conditioning to do versus how much
technique and skill work?
I mean at the college level?
Are we talking about our.
Because we do not,
we do know strength and conditioning and
I recommend kids.
You're on the road and you know,
and if I had 12 hours a week with them,
I would do that.
But we,
you know,
we don't,
we don't have the ability to,
um,
I mean I think,
I think it's important.
I think it's really important.
I don't think it truly is that I don't
think it trumps especially knowledge.
And then if kids wrestle really hard
against each other and kill had that one
saying like wrestling is the best train,
the condition,
I can't remember.
He said something.
If you wrestle really hard against each
other,
you're going to develop those things.
It's like,
I think like people when when I grabbed
people are squeezed,
people that are like,
oh my god,
I've never felt anything like it.
And I think that comes from that doesn't
come.
If you put me in a weight room,
I can do nothing abnormal.
I'm not abnormally strong in any
exercise.
I'm actually like on a college division
and coliseum.
I'm significantly less strong than most
people.
Right.
But then when they arrested me and
they're like,
holy shit,
I never felt anything like that.
And I think it's because a lot of those
things that I do are very,
very,
very wrestling specific and I developed
that strength because when I grabbed
like freaking grab as hard as I can,
when I squeeze them,
I squeeze him as hard as I can.
And so now from doing that,
thousands of times I've developed that
squeezer that strength.
Um,
and so I think strength condition is
important,
but I don't think it trumps doing other
stuff.
And if I had all the time in the world
and these kids didn't have to go to high
school or middle school,
I'd probably put them through some.
But,
you know,
we don't have that luxury.
What did you do when you were finding an
mma?
How much did you devote to strength to
get this thing
twice a week?
Kish and maybe three sometimes.
What kind of stuff?
So I had a personal trainer since I
moved to milwaukee.
I actually.
And then I actually helped them open up
a crossfit gym.
Um,
and it wouldn't be not specifically
crossfit workouts,
but kind of that type of work.
Nothing slow when I'm doing three sets
of 10 and two sets,
eight,
you know,
nothing slow like that potentially,
one,
one or two days.
We might do like a slower start and
then.
But you know,
I think fighting you need to be very
highly active.
You know,
you need to be in really good shape and
move a lot of things really fast.
So kinda cross it type stuff I think is
probably the right direction to go.
And now when I go back to college
programs besides light,
the heavyweights that in season stuff
for college programs is mostly higher
paced stuff which I think is very
relevant to both wrestling and fighting.
So did you do,
when you were saying like you were doing
like crossfit style workouts,
so are you doing like kettle bells box
jumps?
Like everything?
Just so when I said that I just meant
that,
you know,
we are moving at a high pace through a
lot of stuff,
you know?
And it would be like,
he would tell me,
hey diego,
do some.
No.
Do sled pushes,
do this,
do that,
do that.
But what about like your diet and
nutrition and supplements and things?
Those sites have never
been a that much into nutrition.
I,
I sold it.
I don't.
Okay.
I was fat when I was a little kid.
Right?
Clay.
Too much at age 11.
I said I don't wanna be fat anymore.
So I went from 130 pounds.
One hundred pounds in.
Damn.
He lost 30 pounds and 11 his sixth,
fifth grade.
Sixth grade.
And you're 100 pounds.
That's a lot of weight.
That's 30 percent of your body.
Well,
yeah,
it was fat.
I was fat as shit.
Are you eating everything and you were
wrestling into.
Yeah.
You know,
I was,
I was having some success because when
you're fat or there's not a million
people to compete against.
Right.
So anyway,
so I lost 30 pounds,
sixth grade.
So I,
I stopped drinking soda.
I had this whole whole list of stuff.
I just kind of discipline at 11.
Yeah,
I know.
And that's a,
that's a now when I look at kids,
I think,
I think the mental maturity is huge in
longterm success,
being able to make,
like,
see,
see the future and make decisions on
what you want to do at that young age.
So I lost 30 pounds and so now I've
slowly started like reintroducing lot of
stuff.
But it's like sodas,
gross.
I haven't drank a soda and forever,
uh,
you know,
they're growing fast food.
I cut off as food.
I don't,
I don't ever have any fast food in 20
years.
I mean it's just disgusting,
you know.
And so like I eat generally healthy.
My wife and I cook at home a lot.
We make really healthy food.
Um,
and so,
but I don't take any supplements.
Zero,
no multivitamin,
nothing,
nothing.
So you get all your nutrients from your
food?
Yeah.
And I just figured like,
I.
So I tried a couple of supplements in
college.
I never,
I never felt anything from them.
Like I didn't feel any different,
you know.
And so I'm like,
eh,
I didn't feel anything.
Why am I,
why am I going to take that?
I don't need to take it.
And then,
so then oBviously I became like this,
uh,
anti pd crusader it,
you know,
by chance.
And so then it's like,
well now I really can't take anything
because if I go take something and I pop
hot because these idiots or putting
something in the supplement that should
be there,
I'm almost like a total asshole.
So I literAlly,
I don't,
I didn't even take protein.
Nothing.
Wow,
that's crazy.
So did you make sure that you ate the
proper amount of vegetables?
Green leafy vegetables.
I just need some food and latin script,
you know,
like it's like healthy food.
We're eating salads and you know,
I'm not eating cake and ice cream and
pizza and that kind of stuff and we're
eating healthy food at my house,
you know,
but I'm not measuring the grams of thIs
are granted that are.
So I really think,
what am I and I,
this has been proven by science that you
only have a certain amount of time every
single day to have a high amount of
mental focus on stuff.
And so I think like,
my training is more important than
focusing on nutrition and stuff and so I
want to really like really zoning in
really high level focus when I'm trading
and stuff.
And so I think if I worry about all this
stuff,
they'll take my focus away from that
right or wrong.
That's kind of how I thought about it.
It was a smart way to approach it and it
never really affected me.
I mean,
uh,
like I said that,
you know,
even when I took the supplements in
college,
I never really felt them at all.
So like,
well,
if I don't feel it,
why would I do it?
You know,
it's kind of ironic though,
that you were an anti-drug crusader and
you went to the one place that doesn't
drug test I have now,
right?
It really hurt.
It hurt me.
But,
you know,
and it is,
if you look at,
so we talked about like Singapore being
so fantastic and having a really high
gdp.
A lot of the countries over there,
uh,
Indonesia,
manila,
Philippines,
um,
they don't have huge high gdps right?
I mean they're not super wealthy
countries and so when we think about,
you know,
how much it costs to buy a lot of the
steroids that are readily available in
America,
they're just not as available and so I
think they do have a point and if you
look at the athletes,
there's not a lot of athletes that look
like yoel romero now you'll notice
probably not using,
like I pointed out earlier while he's
tested clean except one once was tainted
supplement,
but they proved that it was a tainted
supplement.
So when you look at their athletes maybe
except a few of the russian ones,
they look pretty normal.
Like it's probably unlikely that they're
using from my for a few russian ones
from Russia.
They can't help it.
It's like part of the culture.
Yeah.
That one russian,
the one russian guy that I fought in
april of 16,
he was freaking enormous and you know,
the other thing that I think a lot of
mma people are using some type of a,
oh my gosh,
I'm blanking.
What gives you endurance,
epo,
that type of stuff.
Because if you want to call dress edge,
how tired people get seven minutes and
then we're fighting 25 minutes and
you're not going to get tired.
Like that's not normal.
well,
people definitely tested hot for that in
the ufc.
Who's the guy that fought mighty mouse
of Russia?
Yeah.
Crazy.
So,
but I think more people are using that
and I think if you,
you know,
I don't have any conclusive evidence,
but if you look at when you started and
then how somebody fell down a just
straight down their bodies look
different.
They look different.
They're competent.
I mean Johnny Hendricks would be one
that comes to mind.
I mean,
what's his freaking records since you
saw it ain't very good.
I'll tell you that much and all of a
sudden you can make weight and you know,
if you remember.
and I remember.
So obviously I watched johnny because he
was,
I couldn't stand johnny.
He beat me when we were 17 and then I
tried to wrestle in my students.
So we were different.
He was one 65,
I was one 74 and I was wrestling for the
all star classic and I called the people
who put it on and said I want to wrestle
him.
And uh,
they turned the match down so it's,
I've kind of like,
I wanted to get that one back and I
never got to get it back from when I was
17.
So I've been following pretty closely.
If you watched johnny like a constant
fight prior to that,
he gets so tired in like two rounds,
right.
Let me just fucking exhausted,
exhausted.
And then all of sudden he's gone these
five round fights and you're like,
hello,
how are you going to get tired?
And that exhausted in two rounds and now
you can vote for five rounds.
Johnny,
like,
what's going on here?
I mean,
in his defense to a team take down.
They implemented a pretty fantastic
program over there.
I mean they spent a lot of money on it.
That was the whole thing where they
were,
they were paying him.
Then they wanted 50 percent of his own.
I got the same offer right out of
college.
Did you know we were both graduates?
How does that work?
I felt like he was betting as myself.
They paid you a $100,000
a year for seven years.
They got 50 percent of your career
earnings and I said my thought was,
well if I ever make it really big I'm
going to make a million dollars a fight
and I'm going to pay him back in the one
fight.
You know,
like it's,
it would be like hedging your bet
against yourself and I don't ever bet
against myself.
Yeah.
But for them I get it too.
It's like they have to have some sort of
a reason to put out there and it's a big
bet whether or not you're going to be
able to be an absolutely.
But.
So if you think you suck,
it's good to take that bet.
If you've got an obama make it dog,
I'm okay with making it a little bit of
money.
Yeah.
Then it's a good bet.
It doesn't seem like the best strategy.
It doesn't seem.
It's interesting and I think,
I think there's probably somewhere in
there with,
you know,
I,
I know if you manage it,
it's where you go pick out,
it's pretty proven that high level
called justice are going to make really
damn good fighters.
That's pretty proven.
So go in and try to find a couple every
year spending some money on them and
then getting a percentage of their
earnings,
that's probably a pretty,
I don't want to say a safe bet for the
people putting out the money,
but it's,
you know,
take down,
take down had jake rush holt who was an
amazing wrestler and for whatever reason
he just didn't transition great to
fighting.
Right.
He was good but he wasn't great and it
was like for as good of a wrestlers he
was probably third is gonna be a little
better.
Yeah.
What do you think is the fact or like if
you had to look at it from a wrestler
because there's not a lot of outliers
like that,
like where you don't like and,
and so when we talk about how good jake,
right,
he still made the ufc,
he still won some fights,
so it's like he wasn't a bad fighter but
he's a three time ncaa champs.
So you expect him,
hey,
he'll probably go challenge for a ufc
title.
Right.
so,
you know,
in his case,
I don't know what the factor was.
Um,
but there's not a lot of outliers like
that where it's so there are really high
level wrestler and then they don't have
any success.
Mma that's really unique.
You don't see it a lot.
Yeah.
It's,
it's interesting like I've looked at it
from striking from if you see like
really high level kickboxers some have a
style that would readily translate to
mma and som are fantastic.
Kickboxers like maybe peter hertz is a
good example or a nesto who's where I
wouldn't really think that they would
translate that well to mma.
Whereas mirko cro,
cop,
who might've been like a slight notch
below them in kickboxing,
translates perfectly to mma because he's
so explosive and quail and I would
wonder.
Decent takedown defense too.
He kept it for awhile.
They developed it,
but the thing about mirko was
unbelievable power and speed and he
could just close the distance quickly
and blast.
Yeah,
and I think that is a difference between
that and a guy who's like,
I'm methodical,
set things those guys didn't do as well.
they didn't translate as well.
They get tooken taken down to a
hustling.
What?
What would you think would be like the
step mom?
It's a different guns you don't want.
The other things that I think benefits
us wrestlers is the fact that jujitsu
people are stuck on doing jujitsu the
jujitsu way,
right?
Strikers are stuck on striking.
When we come into mma,
we know we can't win a match just by
wrestling.
Right?
So we know.
We know.
I got to add striking.
I got,
I got to add.
You did,
and I'm open to that idea.
Right?
I'm open to those ideas that I have to
add those things into my arsenal.
Were jude,
some jujitsu guys are like,
well,
I'm just going to submit them and they
don't.
They don't develop their.
I mean there's,
you can literally not name me joe,
uh,
a jujitsu guy or striking guy.
Well maybe jose aldo who has developed
high level wrestling,
but you can name a lot of wrestlers
who've developed high level something
else,
right?
I mean when you see the crossover,
like jon jones was a wrestler,
he can strike with pretty much anyone on
the planet,
right?
It means steep meo chick wasn't a
wrestler.
He can pretty much strike when they
don't on the planet.
I mean,
so you had these wrestlers who are
becoming high level with these other
skills,
but you don't have a lot of other skills
becoming a high level at wrestling.
And I,
and for me,
I think it's the stubbornness of people
who come from those other backgrounds or
too stubborn to want to work a lot in
wrestling.
Whereas russell's like,
okay,
teach power strike.
Yeah.
I think it's a,
it's a recognition of what's important.
Like george st pierre is a perfect
example of a guard who started off with
a ql christian background,
didn't wrestle in college or high
school,
became a fantastic wrestling.
He's good.
Yeah,
and just figured it out and realized,
realized what a critical skill it is to.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So there's a handful of very small
handful,
jose aldo would be like if he wasn't an
offensive wrestler,
but who'd be like,
he was so ridiculously hard to take down
mean fantastic takedown defense.
And so there,
there's a handful but there's not a lot.
And then.
But then if you go to wrestlers,
going the opposite direction into
jujitsu or striking,
you know,
you,
you can name quite a few that were able
to do those things really well.
You know,
it's interesting when you see a guy like
khabib number grumet off and you see
fantastic.
Fuck yeah.
In his,
his mauling wrestling.
I mean,
you see what a massive factor it is.
Fights like the edson barboza fight.
Like that to me is one of the perfect
examples.
When I say look,
the ability to take the guy down and
control on the ground is the.
It'S the bottom of the pyramid.
It's the most important foundation
because he dictates where the fight
takes place.
Yeah.
You might catch him when he's coming in
and trying to get you.
You might,
but if he gets you.
He was like a fricking terminator
though.
He was just like,
I'm just going to come get you.
Yeah.
He just ate kicks and no hope.
Just the constant chasing him around
chasing them.
Right.
It was.
It was insane.
Yeah.
No,
he's fantastic.
Yeah,
but no,
I would totally agree that at the bottom
of the pyramid,
it's like the is the trump card.
If like if you're fighting a wrestler
and you can't stop but take down,
you're going to lose 90 percent of the
time.
Yeah.
You know,
and if,
if you're the wrestler and you can go
get a take down really easily,
you're going to win 90 percent of the
time.
The only wild card in that equation is a
guy like brian or tig fight so well off
his back,
but how many people get submissions from
garden?
How many of those?
Yeah.
Me even like any of the anthony pettis
who got a lot of submissions,
guard,
a lot of that was transitioned off of I
body kicked benson harrison.
I bought a kicked benson and benson.
Harrison hates getting body kicks,
so he dives in for a take down.
It gets armbar.
Gilbert melendez gets and get a teen
show because he got jacked a few times.
Right.
So there are,
there's a handful of those,
but just strictly like I'd take you
down.
You're in garden then I submit you
right?
Maybe for receIver doom every once in
awhile.
Maybe brian or tega,
but the numbers pretty damn small.
it is very small.
Yeah.
It's smaller now than I think ever
before because people understand that
takedown down or the guard defense.
Yeah.
Even like this guy that I.
So one of the things that frustrates you
the most more than anything else that
may bad strategy just like drives me up
the wall,
like the lima thing,
but this freaking knucklehead to fought
Michael Chandler on,
uh,
on saturday.
I just see it named gordy gordy.
Yeah.
Moved here.
I don't know his damn name is.
So the first round he pulls guard like
fast gets frikking hammered on for like
four minutes and then he ends up on
bottom in the second round,
third round he gets taken down and I
don't know,
15 seconds.
Did he try to get up one time?
Nah,
he just laid there and I was asked what
performance in 45 seconds.
Like everyone's while to try a camera.
Everyone's while to try to triangle,
but it's like,
dude,
you're getting your ass whipped.
You're down two rounds and nothing.
Try to get up.
Try to do something,
change your strategy.
If your strategy is not working,
you can't just stick with the same
bullshit and get your ass off for
another four minutes and 45 seconds I
give me a break.
What do you think's going to happen down
there?
Well,
I think some guys get locked into a
defensive position,
like they realize they're getting
overwhelmed and so they just try to
survive.
You think so?
Yeah.
Really?
You don't think that way because you're
a champ and champions don't think that
way.
But for some people there's a.
There's a acceptance of their,
their faith as well.
Pin this,
this is just getting their ass whipped
and so they just try to stay conscious.
They try this just to protect themselves
as much as they can.
Kinda like edson barboza.
But then you know,
instrument edson barboza you saw once he
realized he was going to survive.
Like when it was like two minutes left
and third round maybe ish side the first
round.
He's like,
I'm kidding.
I'm gonna get fucked up.
I'm just gonna.
I'm just going to survive.
Right?
but then when there was coming with us,
he's like,
no.
He was like,
okay,
I'm going to fight again.
I want to make it through this shit.
I might as well if I want to make it
through this,
I might as well just fight back.
Right.
And so he started fighting back really
hard,
like the last two minutes,
theft tried.
He certainly tried,
but there was a period in the middle
where he had resigned to just take it an
asshole open.
Well,
I think he was just.
Body was just not responding.
He was getting so fucked up and you
could see the pace that habib put on a
first round,
like halfway into the round barboza is
like,
jesus christ,
you see the look in his eyes,
got that thousand yard stare.
It's like,
whoa,
what I signed up for.
This guy's on another level.
I mean he reallY is on another level.
I'm fascinated by him fighting tony
ferguson and apparently they're going to
do that now.
It didn't happen.
April.
Yeah.
They don't know if it's going to be for
the interim title or the actual title
within.
They're going to strip connor.
They're in a weird way.
He beats up tony.
That's just my end and I've
underestimated tony before so I could be
wrong.
Again.
I just,
I think it's the again,
trump card.
I think tony's kind of of those guys
where he's pretty good everywhere is
pretty damn solid wrestling,
high level jujitsu,
but I
khabib wrestling being better than
tony's wrestling so it's going to end up
on the ground and I think tony is going
to think he can submit him because his
jujitsu is very high level,
but I think be one of the things where
it could be just good enough not to get
submitted and then he's going to land
damage and land damage,
inland damage,
inland damage and tony's going to get
close to a submission and close to a
submission,
close to a submission but not quite get
it.
And then all this damage is going to
just accumulate and accumulate and
accumulate that.
That's kinda how I see it going.
It's fascinating and I also think it's
fascinating now that could be but has
changed his training and has a real
nutritionist.
Had no problem making weight.
So all the factors that played into him
getting removed from the last time they
were supposed to fight pulled out of the
car.
And I thought that was kind of
overblown.
Healy,
ms dot wait one time.
he only missed one.
WaiT one time.
But his body shut down when he's making,
waiting for the Michael Johnson fight in
a similar way.
But he still did the Michael Johnson
fight.
Yeah.
But it was the same thing happened
during the way and it was a rough way
in.
But there's been other guys who ms dot
wait many times.
I mean if we go to a Johnny Hendricks,
johny hendricks,
melvin gallard guests and they missed it
by a long list.
So I thought the thing kind of
overplayed.
He may sway one time.
He had some injuries which sucked for
him.
Um,
but it was,
that was happening for a world title
fight,
you know,
fighting for the interim title.
He,
mrs.
Wait,
yeah.
I mean,
and so it was one of those where he
probably just like,
it was like,
okay for him to make it be difficult.
And he just got just a little bit too
big.
Actually.
Was it for an interim title when he was
supposed to time?
I think it was the original time.
Was Kevin Lee,
right?
That was for the world title or interim
title.
Job title.
Yeah.
The whole.
That whole division is kind of fucked up
with connor.
Not even knowing whether or not he's
fighting and they're going to strip him.
Right?
Yeah.
Mostly I think so.
I would imagine.
Unless connor says,
fuck it,
I'm in.
I think the best comeback.
Fuck it.
I want to keep me belt.
I know the best course of action strip
cotter let,
let could be even tony fight it out and
then it kinda wants to go back.
Get my title shot.
That's going to happen.
Whatever.
Well,
I think what would be the most lucrative
thing as connor versus shut up joe or
the fight gsp.
Oh,
you do?
The one thing I want to be number one,
I don't want to fight tyron because
we've been friends for 20 years.
Uh,
I to fight gsp.
That's what I want to fight.
You think that they would set that up?
They would try to set up gsp versus
tyron.
Right?
That would be the big super.
Gsp doesn't want to fight him.
Who can hit hard because he's worried
about the brain damage?
I think so,
yeah.
I don't hit that hard.
Interesting way of looking at it.
You're trained with gsp.
I've never changed,
so I've trained with almost every top
what the weight of this era except gsp.
Really?
Yeah.
Well marie,
but a shields,
fitch diaz a couple times.
Tyron obviously,
um,
you know,
go down the line of train with pretty
much everyone in this era.
What do you feel like if you do wind up
retiring,
what do you feel like you'll,
you'll wind up doing?
Just coaching.
Wrestling.
I love doing it really enjoyed a lot so
I could,
I,
I don't think I'd go back to the
collegiate level.
It's obviously
always an option.
It,
I went out for the four years,
I coached college wrestling.
I loved iT,
you know,
and then it was like,
hey,
I won the belt is making a lot of money.
I should probably try to be good at this
instead of just doing it halfway.
And so I did that and then,
you know,
we opened the wrestling schools and now
it's going really well and I really
enjoyed that a lot and you know,
there's positives and negatives.
Like I love coaching at the highest
level,
being able to talk about his level to
the college guys.
So I missed that part a little bit.
But then obviously if you go work for an
institution like that,
there's gonna be a lot of bureaucracy
and I worry about that.
I don't like that.
I love owning my own business,
a heavy amount of freedom and not having
to worry about what I tweet or what I
say or yeah,
having with telling me what to do or
where to be or where to dress or
whatever,
you know,
like I don't like.
So I love that freedom obviously.
Then running your own business has its
own challenges also.
So,
uh,
but I,
I think I will coat dress them for the
rest of my life,
whether I fight once more where they
don't find once more,
I'll probably call jonathan for the rest
of my life.
Oh,
awesome.
Yeah.
Well listen man,
I'm glad we finally got a chance to do
this.
It was fun.
Really,
really fun.
And um,
tell people about your podcast.
Uh,
so I have a wrestling podcast called the
tea room funky show that had said
another to what t dot rowe and funky
show,
hero and funky show.
How do you spell that?
T dash row funky.
So tire a tire.
And tommy rollins is to 10 minutes a
champ for Ohio state,
uh,
made a couple of world teams,
was really close to make an olympic team
and um,
you know,
we was on the phone one day and I said I
want to do a podcast.
I'm like,
ah,
I want to do a podcast too.
Let's just do it,
you know,
so it's not like a job for us.
We just do it for fun.
We enjoy it,
we love talking about wrestling and you
know,
for me it's really nice,
like a,
you know,
no one's on the same schedule as me now
that I can talk wrestling with.
So to be able to get on talk for an hour
a week about wrestling,
it's a blast.
Awesome.
So that's on itunes and soundcloud.
People want to find you a.
It's been asking on twitter or
instagram.
I like.
I'm on instagram,
but I don't really get into it.
I don't.
I don't know.
I Can't.
I can'T get an instagram is just
pictures like I get it.
There's no banter back and forth.
I struggle.
I post every once in a while.
But you like twitter of twitter fun,
ben asking.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thanks brother.
I appreciate it.
It was fun.
Yes sir.
My.