Okay,
here we go.
Four,
three,
two,
one,
boom.
And we'll live cat.
How are you?
I'm good.
Good to see you here.
Thanks for having me.
My pleasure.
I'm looking forward to talking to you
for awhile.
I know it's,
uh,
I feel like been a long time coming and
I don't even know how much time we have
affiliate.
There's a hell of a lot to catch up on.
Shit.
Yeah,
there's a lot to talk about.
Always.
You're a getting ready for Boise.
That's your,
uh,
your neck,
spine,
pleats fighting.
I'm Marianne.
We're now July 14th.
The end,
the century link arena.
Now you took,
you took a good stretch off,
right?
A couple of times.
Yeah,
a couple of times.
I,
um,
let's see.
After I fought Meesha,
I blew my knee and then,
well,
the world exploded.
And so I had I think 18 months off
between that and fighting,
uh,
Amanda.
And then after I fought Amanda,
I saw Amanda was like September 27,
something like that.
And I fought Ronda February 28th.
And then after Ronda,
uh,
took another big stretch off,
fought Juliana the following year,
uh,
July 9th,
and then this was another big stretch
off.
So yeah,
it's been a little bit scattered,
but doing what I can.
Yeah,
you are,
you are doing some crazy therapy to
write some,
some interesting stuff down in San
Diego.
Yeah.
So,
um,
there's,
there's been a few things I've been
working on,
like I'm not a huge fan of western
medicine,
you know,
like,
uh,
even,
I mean,
you can call it alternative medicine.
It's like original medicine.
I,
I appreciate looking at things like that
way more than you know,
big farm.
But I,
uh,
you know,
one thing that,
um,
you know,
fighting has gotten me and,
and stuff with,
you know,
I th I think it's more prevalent in
women,
although I'm thinking it's happening
with men too,
is like our endocrine systems are not
happy with these weight cuts and they're
not happy with us.
Like getting hit in the head a lot.
Go figure.
Right.
Yeah.
Go for it.
So,
um,
you know,
within all of that I've just,
had medical problems and things that
like I'm constantly working on and I
feel really good.
I'm,
I'm constantly improving.
But,
um,
one thing I was feeling a little bit
stuck on was a wine,
I like some of the endocrine problem
issues,
but,
um,
like I dunno,
I,
I had,
uh,
had I went to this facility in San Diego
is called,
um,
Dang,
why can't I remember?
Oh,
a mindset.
And actually the UFC sent me there
because I mean,
we have you sought,
oh,
we have all of these things.
Like,
um,
after fighting Amanda,
I got my head pounded for a good four
minutes there.
Um,
I had a Tbi afterwards,
so that was like,
uh,
immediately lowered my,
a estrogen,
lowered my da ta,
my testosterone and I'm hypo thyroid.
Like I will always be hyperthyroid now.
Like I have to that fight.
Yeah.
And um,
you know,
still toughed it out.
So it was trying to do what I could to
go and fight Ronda as soon as I did
afterwards.
And,
you know,
part of my game plan is don't get hit.
And which means like,
let's just dart out her and see what
happens.
You know?
So what,
that's what happens when you do that.
No,
Tbi is traumatic brain injury.
Just in case if someone is listening to
this,
doesn't understand what we're talking
about.
And then in the Rhonda fight,
if people don't know about that,
you just charged after and he got caught
in an arm bar and like,
what was it?
Very quick.
Okay.
14,
it was 14 sayings,
but I did hit her with a knee.
I did throw her ass,
but she practice a little Ninja move and
caught muddy alarm.
And it was,
it was over,
you know,
but I mean,
even,
even her coaches were like,
I mean,
that's the,
you did what you're supposed to do
there.
And She just got you.
You know?
So,
um,
that would be an awesome fight to be
able to revisit one day.
Uh,
she even said that we'd do it.
I mean,
who knows her career so open right now
I'm going to fight again.
She doesn't need to.
Yeah.
It really doesn't need it.
I don't think she wants to,
you know,
I think,
uh,
oh,
I mean,
who knows,
you'd have to ask her,
but there's a lot of lessons to be
learned.
And what happened to her in terms of
like all of the distractions and
Hollywood came calling and there was
scripts and talk about doing road house
and there was all this,
all this shit going on.
There was other than fighting.
Yeah.
You know,
and then it was also,
look,
the sport has evolved so rapidly in the
women's,
women's MMA has gotten so high level so
quickly and if he's,
I'm sure you saw a man does last fight
with Raquel Pennington.
I'm like,
Holy Shit.
I mean that was a fucking high level
performance from her.
And five rounds,
super high cardio,
just put a beating down on recal
painting.
It's one of the toughest girls in the
world for sure.
Right.
I do like,
I mean,
I'm curious.
I was saying the same thing as the
fights going.
Right.
And then I have,
uh,
some people in my ear next to me,
they're like,
well,
how long has it been since raquel?
Fuck,
cause she didn't look her right.
Her like beefiest straight.
She,
she looked a little tired.
She looked a little like not her typical
and then it was like,
she is a year and a half off herself.
Right.
Like right into a title fight,
which I have to say I'm a little bit
envious of because when I beat Misha,
I,
when,
uh,
I was supposed to coach ultimate
fighter,
but that was all ultimately going to end
up in a title shot with Rhonda.
And I blew my knee and my husband passed
away and there was like a long moment of
silence in there.
And then when I was able to come back,
they made me read,
earn my title shot,
you know?
And so it was like,
wait,
oh,
we're doing that now.
Or just like
penn done.
Like what,
what attractive contenders are
available.
Like what?
Yeah,
it looks good.
I agree.
Yeah.
I mean,
it was very young at that,
at that age or at that at the time.
Right.
And in Bantam weight right now there's
like there's no standout contender.
And Raquel had beaten some really good
fighters.
She looked like the next in line.
And did she blow her knee out as well?
She had some sort of surgery.
I like,
it could
be lion,
but I think she gotten like some
accident with a four wheeler,
like rolled over and broke her leg or
something.
I could like totally be making that up
though.
She could have just twisted it walking
down the street too.
So I don't know.
Yeah.
Now that you're saying that,
I do remember something like a Bro,
a broken leg,
it would,
you'll find out what it is.
Um,
but would you a,
were you surprised by that fight
between and Amanda?
Yeah,
I mean,
I didn't,
I didn't see where cal being the one to
beat her,
you know?
Um,
I do feel like Amanda's been working and
doing like,
you know,
improving,
I mean,
she changed her camps,
the coaches that she's working with.
I tried out for a while at at one point
too when I was trying to find my spot
and they're legit.
They're very good.
Um,
and American top team has a lot of high
level training partners,
both girls and guys,
you know what I mean?
She had a good,
a good decision made there.
So I,
I see how she's improved.
Um,
I think with the time off with Raquel,
I wasn't sure how it was going to go,
but also I just,
I just don't know.
I just don't see where Kelby and to be
being the one that beats her.
It's so hard to tell you no,
right.
I mean,
anybody on any given night at the
highest level of the game,
someone can,
when someone can be off,
someone can be a hard,
yeah,
there's no math to be done in this
sport.
There really isn't a,
math is ridiculous.
So I mean,
sometimes I hear like statistics on me
or definitions on me or labels on me and
I'm like,
wait,
I'm a,
I'm a known striker.
Like I'd never would've thought I'd be
known as a striker.
I mean,
I've been doing Jujitsu and wrestling my
whole life,
so me and I'll take it,
fuck yeah.
You know?
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
But even that is yes.
But I mean that,
that in itself was like,
I love to wrestle and what can I do once
I've closed that distance,
while it's those,
those short and goals strikes,
you know,
there's,
there's needs and there's elbows there
that those are the most destructive
things I could possibly do to someone
when,
when we're that close and to do all that
work to get that close.
But granted,
that's all influenced by my time,
what I got to learn from that
discipline.
So,
you know,
it's all relevant,
but,
um,
you know,
it's,
uh,
it's always just interesting to hear how
you're now being categorized.
Yeah.
It is weird.
Right.
But you are,
you are definitely a dangerous striker.
I mean,
you're dangerous.
I agree.
I mean,
I like it and,
and I'm,
I'm enjoying constantly learning and new
things like the,
the basics were always hard for me to
get,
cause I wanted to do the big girl stuff,
you know,
and uh,
found my way,
like right in the middle of all of that.
And in found a way to use how aggressive
I am and how just like dominique
domineering,
I can feel in there and all of that.
So it's like,
I don't know the,
I want the maximum amount of damage
without taking damage,
which is obviously the goal.
Right.
But like I want to put it into a dance,
so it's like a little,
I don't know.
Did you decide to go to San Diego?
So you're at alliance now moved from
Colorado to San Diego.
So a few things.
So one of them,
one of them was like,
Colorado is a complicated situation for
me.
I mean,
I had gyms that they're like,
a lot just happened up there.
Um,
and I love my team elevation.
Like I love ice.
I'm still close with everybody.
Like I go to Colorado for Christmas
holidays.
I get still home,
you know,
but a couple of things.
One with the head injury.
Um,
Colorado is amazing for training,
right?
It's amazing for building your,
your endurance and whatever.
But it is not good for healing.
Like you'll never see a doctor tell
someone with Alzheimer's or a Tbi or
heart problems or even like massive
allergies or um,
what's the,
uh,
arthritis arthritis,
those are not,
that's not a good place for people to
live with.
Any kind of inflammatory or like major
thing that needs to be healing because
your body's already working at such a
high level because yeah,
because the altitude,
I mean the thin air,
the,
the things like that,
it's just like I spent so much time and
so much money,
like figuring out what the hell was
wrong with me that,
you know,
I ended up at the Mayo clinic spending
weeks at a time going to all their like
specialized different,
uh,
doctors in situations like that for them
to tell me like,
you know,
if you want to heal,
you want to give yourself the best
opportunity to heal,
you're probably not going to do it up at
altitude.
Like we would prefer seeing you at sea
level.
And so combined like I kind of,
I needed to almost exiled myself from
Colorado cause I want to love it.
And I was starting to,
it was starting to get like less
colorful for me,
you know,
cause I felt like I had the best there
was as far as coaches and the best there
was as far as training partners and the
situations like everything was as good
as it was going to get.
Like it literally was as good as it was
going to get.
And it was like this can't be it.
Like I don't feel,
I don't feel right.
No.
And I was like,
that means I'm gonna have to take a
change,
you know?
And I was scared.
Like I have a little boy,
like I'm taking them away from
everything we know and we just packed a
u haul and we left and we,
we got to San Diego in San Diego I went,
I wish I had written down like all the
gyms I went to in showed up at like
anonymously to,
because I didn't want them to,
like,
I wanted to kind of catch them with
their pants down.
Like,
what are you guys like right now versus
if you're prepared,
I don't want to show up and have you
have people here watching me.
I don't want you to put on a show,
like I want to catch you how you are and
like,
have you decided what you think of me
too?
Because these needs,
this needs to be a fit.
I mean,
fighting and coaching and training is
very intimate and it needs to be
authentic and real.
The days I'm sitting there,
ugly white girl crying on the ground,
but I need,
I need you to tell me to keep,
stay on the erudite and you know what I
mean?
Like just let me cry,
you know,
that kind of thing.
And um,
it's,
uh,
so I went to all these places and like
I,
the best part about it is that I got to
learn and train with so many fighters in
so many coaches that I like.
I'm so excited about the relationships I
made and the people I know.
But,
um,
like all of them,
it was like,
this is awesome,
but it's not the place.
This is awesome,
I came up to La
and I was very close to going to
American top team.
They had an awesome deal set up for me
to go,
like helping me with my kid,
helping me with a good percentage for
training,
like how uh,
living situation was going to be,
they're going to accommodate me really
well.
Um,
but when it was time to like pack my car
and go like something was like that
wasn't it,
you know?
And so I'm like,
I mean sweaty all the time,
like right here and just making that
look hot.
There's a lot of cool people in Florida,
but there's just,
there's some subhumans down there.
Yeah.
I really appreciate it.
Like the Latin culture.
I mean,
I'm all about,
yeah,
it's Florida.
There's some fucking swamp people
though.
They're no joke.
No joke.
Um,
so,
uh,
then I looked west,
you know,
um,
I know ed stores out here,
he's my manager and,
and I had a few pockets of people I knew
that could maybe be a support to me and
my kids.
So,
um,
came to la.
If I was here,
I was going to go to the black house.
Uh,
I think,
uh,
Oh,
where's calvin?
[inaudible] I'm again 12 and gasoline.
You got to say his name wrong every
time.
But where is he coached the MEU ticket
kings.
Kings.
Kayla's going to king's black house.
And I was still trying to pick Jujitsu.
Like I wanted like a art of Jujitsu guy
or,
or uh,
you know,
just someone really good.
Yeah,
because I came from traditional
traditional Jujitsu and like I love MMA
and mixing it up,
but I need that.
So I felt you introduced to purple for
like ever like six years.
How come?
So long?
Because I'm being a Weirdo about who
promotes me.
Cause my husband,
my husband promoted me to purple belt
and like I really want what whoever
takes over to the lineage to be like
that.
Like I don't want it a different one
from 10 different people.
Like I want that like I want to pick and
it be right.
And so actually now I'm super excited
because I just started training at attos
and I have so much respect for Andre and
his wife and Angelica,
there's so many good fighters come out
of that gym to Great Jujitsu.
I,
I've been changing,
they're like four weeks now and I've,
I mean I've trained there before,
but like every day for weeks now,
and I've only had like one day where I
walked out feeling like a rock star.
The rest of the days they were whooping
my ass,
but it was good,
you know,
like I needed that and it tells me,
yeah.
And there it's just been so good.
And to see myself that way and to hold
people that way.
Like I was legit Jujitsu me and I was
like killing it on the circuit for a
long time and then Emma May comes in and
puts this pressure on,
like even those kinds of competitions,
even though they're not even the same
animal.
And I'm annoyed that I let that bother
me and keep me from competing in between
fights because I left the back.
You have a big name in mma?
You feel
weird about competing in Jujitsu
tournaments?
I think I did I or maybe I thought I'd
pick up bad habits or I would do
whatever,
but because maybe other people had that
experience,
but like for me,
I need to see it for myself.
Like if I go and I do a tournament and I
do great,
then hell yeah,
I'm going to have higher expectations of
myself in a fight.
If I go and I do shitty.
Okay,
well like now I get to learn like that
competing is where I get to learn
everything and spacing out these
competitions.
Especially at the time I've had to take
off in between fights.
Like,
like I'm not,
I don't believe necessarily in ring
rust,
but like when they say go,
I don't know what go means until a
little bit later than I'm expecting and,
and it's been the pattern in these last
two fights.
When the fight starts,
you still feel like,
is this really happening?
Kind of.
Well,
even this last night,
this last fight with Caitlin,
like we got in and I was like,
do I remember what to do here?
You know?
And I was like,
fuck it,
I'm just a throw bombs.
And the whole time I was just like,
and I'm not,
that's not me there,
you know?
It was just like chucking my hands at
her and hope and they land and if they
didn't like the fuck out,
you know,
you feel like out of composure.
Yeah,
until the,
until the third round.
And then the third round I was awake and
ready to go.
And I mean,
I felt warmed up.
I felt right.
And you know,
she was looking at the clock and backing
up and all of this and I was just like,
come here,
come here.
Like I'm ready to fight,
finally,
like,
come here.
And uh,
you know,
I don't know.
So there's something to be fixed about
that,
eh,
I don't think it's a secret,
but,
um,
I dunno.
I think maybe something with the warmup
I need to like fully like have like a
respiratory exhaustion before I go in so
I can simulate those first rounds being
the hell out of the way.
Even in wrestling,
I don't know.
You know,
there's,
there's a lot to it.
Like Gosh,
we're bouncing around all these
different things.
But I mean,
one thing with the,
with that treatment center that I went
to is like,
um,
doing different things,
like dealing with your psychology,
dealing with like the synchrony and your
brain,
you know,
having your brain function and in on the
same hurts at the same or different
areas of your brain.
So it's therapy.
So it's these magnets,
right?
Like the,
the main people in there.
I mean,
it's beautiful.
Not Beautiful but beautiful to see
sitting in the lobby waiting.
When you see people with Alzheimer's
come in,
like there's a man that wheels his wife
and every day and,
and you can't,
you can,
I think at the beginning of the week she
gets like an ivy,
so she's like a little bit more up and
chipper.
But by the end of the week,
you know,
she's a little bit more slow motion and
stories like his,
where he's talking about,
um,
you know,
before they started going in there,
she would just go to the bathroom all
over and every day this man takes care
of his wife,
puts her makeup on her,
like goes and gets her hair done even
though she doesn't even know,
you know,
and now she can at least tell him that
she needs to go to the bathroom.
Like just be like,
hey,
it's time,
you know,
and he can get her there and you know,
sort of,
kind of have like meaningful moments
that they haven't had in awhile for.
There's a ton of veterans in there and
active veterans to active military guys
that are,
you know,
they're doing these door breaches and
then they get their head rattled up too
many times and they're noticing they
have problems with some depression.
I mean,
and these are high level navy seals,
high level,
like,
like special forces that need,
um,
need.
They're expensive people.
They've,
there's millions of dollars poured into
these people and they're not ready to
let them go yet.
So they're like,
how can we fix them,
give them this like performance edge but
still get them like,
like healed enough.
But we need,
we need to throw them back in there and
they,
we need them,
you know?
And so I've had to sit in on
appointments with the Department of
Defense in talk about my experience with
it.
I had to,
uh,
I,
I don't,
there's some really famous people I
don't even think I get to say because
I'd be a dick and I'm to probably be in
trouble,
but,
um,
that I've sat in on and,
you know,
they've had their own issues with mental
health or ptsd or,
um,
uh,
they're like autism,
different things like family members of
theirs or whatever that I've sat in on
and kind of been helpful in talking
about because I went in there on two
different antidepressants,
um,
and these,
I was put on at the Mayo Clinic and
felt like post the Nunez.
Yeah,
this is how crazy am.
I mean math is right.
You lose to Rhonda in 14 seconds.
You Kao Amanda Nunez.
Amanda Nunez beats the shit out of
Rhonda and 48 seconds.
That's,
you might be like the perfect example.
Having a math,
you know and I mean crazy.
It's crazy.
I need you beaten down to UFC champion.
Well,
I mean I took,
it took two and a half rounds for me to,
for me to sub Pennington too.
You know,
like there's nothing,
you know,
but who is it?
Pennington goes toe to toe and round and
round with holly.
Holly Knox out.
Rhonda too.
Like it's just this division
to his fight with Ashley.
Evan Smith to this day that the ending,
when she got her in that bulldog choke.
Oh,
Robert and blood and finished her like
literally one second.
It was a violent,
crazy.
I,
I screamed so loud at the end of that.
It was just fucking chaos.
That was,
she's done.
She's had two fights that ended like
that with like one second ago.
She finishes the fight.
It's tough girl.
Anyway,
MMA math is ridiculous.
It doesn't work.
And you might be the best example of how
it doesn't work.
But,
so you go to this,
the,
the Mayo Clinic puts you on
antidepressants because you just feel
like shit.
He like
shit.
And because like of the different
endocrine problems that I had,
right.
So I can't have any of the medications
that'll help that.
So I have to be more conservative with
it.
And one way they thought to do it is
because my cortisol levels are really
high.
They're talking about,
um,
and I mean granted I have a lot of
stress,
especially like,
you know,
life hasn't been easy
was like,
mom,
your husband passes away.
You're in the toughest,
probably the toughest sport on the
planet.
I'm trying to be the best at it.
So yeah.
So your elite,
you're in the top 10 so you're,
you're in this weird position where you
never know when you're going to fire to
who you're going to find is a constant
amounts to.
And it's not like you're making millions
of dollars doing it either.
No.
Well and it's expediting healing for me
in,
and I also have a kid going through what
I'm going through,
so it's not like I get to like split and
cut corners and just,
you know,
it's like there's maintenance to be done
at all times with that.
So I go there,
they tell me,
you know,
we could probably lower your coders all
levels if we could load or lower your
stress levels.
So we'll try it.
Antidepressants,
what did that make you feel like?
Flat as fuck and like I didn't,
am I,
can I say fuck on this?
Okay.
I know,
I just didn't know if I have a quota.
How far I'm like a bad person.
Like did I get handed to like a doug?
It added to a certain level,
zero restrictions.
You can say whatever you want in the
shit out of it.
Okay.
So there's no one listening.
Got It.
Okay.
Um,
so yeah,
they,
they put me on,
they usually have flat flat,
which like all that training camp
getting ready for Juliana.
I'm just like,
I'm like,
okay,
I'll,
it'll,
it'll take off in the fight.
Like,
I feel good in the fight when they say
go and run the loon that no,
no ups,
no downs,
no,
no pissed off.
Like want to kill,
you know,
nothing,
and show,
not scared but not happy.
No.
And I was like,
why am I not nervous the way that I get
nervous?
Like,
like,
like I was okay.
Which usually like especially two weeks
out,
I have this like flesh of emotions,
you know,
where I'm like,
fetal position in the corner,
like what the fuck?
And then once it's over,
all I want to do is kill,
you know.
But,
uh,
again I didn't have that either.
What kind of made me nervous because my,
my other friend Barb pancheck,
we,
she,
she's a new 20 fiver.
Um,
we would always like call each other and
laugh at how dumb we are being at that
point.
Like,
look at me,
you know?
And uh,
but that was all gone with the,
yeah,
but what should,
did they put you on?
Um,
oh,
is this one?
Oh my gosh.
So off Paxil,
keep going.
Um,
PROZAC.
What do they have?
Uh,
do you know what I mean?
Jamie affects her fixer,
the fixer and was playing stupid over
the crazy pills twice a day.
Just tic tacs tries them out.
Um,
so,
so they put you on this stuff and did
they try different ones?
Uh,
no,
because uh,
not a lot of time there isn't,
you know,
and,
and they're looking,
I'm like,
I need the side,
this side effects matter.
Like these can be ones that made me gain
a bunch of weight.
Right.
They can't make me like,
like I need to still be able to sleep.
Like I have to be able to have like
enough highs,
lows to be able to
function and learn and,
and whatever.
And so this is like the best they,
they could have for me.
So anyway,
I,
I fight that fight with Juliana.
You know,
I,
I feel like the first round I came out
how I wanted,
you know,
and then halfway through the second
round,
like it was just awful.
Like she had my old coaches in her
corner.
You know what's weird about that fight
is I could hear you and I could like I,
this is where the flat came in is like I
wasn't,
I didn't feel like I was in the fight.
Like I could see herb Dean's feet and I
could hear you talking about us and I,
I saw like I could hear Juliana's
coaches and it was breaking my heart
that they were coaching against me
because they were my Colorado gym and
she went and trained with them and I
know she had trained with them
previously.
So I mean before she had taken the
fight.
But to me it was like fucked up to here,
you know?
And it hurt me in a way,
like it's,
I wish I could explain it better,
but it was like I heard them and I just
wanted to go home.
You know,
I look at the clock and I'm like,
kittenish just be over.
I don't want to go back to Colorado.
I want to move like in,
I literally on this side of the cage I
had my past in Colorado,
I had these coaches,
I had the drama with that,
with that Jim,
like how everything went and,
and then on this side it was like all
new problems like San Diego,
Eric and then we're good.
Like there was a lot of trading partners
there.
It was sunny,
it was similar to Colorado at different
but in the right ways,
you know?
And it's like I just want it out
fight.
You were in San Diego trainer for that
fight or no?
Yep.
I can't,
I just flew out for it for,
for the training camp.
And while you flew out there,
you were still taking the
antidepressants and did it,
did that fight convince you to stop
taking them?
Yeah.
Did that fight?
I went to a,
what did I do?
I think I went to the,
I was at the Pi,
I was working with Novinski and people
on like what to do about that.
I even talked to Gordon and Dr.
Gordon.
Mark Gordon.
Yeah.
To help me with all of that too.
Cause he thought there was a more
conservative way to help me with those
issues as well.
And so I knew I was talking with him,
I had him talk to them.
Uh,
they were all trying to figure out a
way,
but,
so there's like,
there's no ways to even just naturally
bring you up to think about retiring.
Yeah.
And that,
that's the thing is the center was
really the place that was,
is like,
okay,
I'm going to go here.
I've tried everything else.
I'm going to go here and if they can't
fix me then then I'm,
I'm going to have to be done.
How crazy is that man?
How fucking hard is Amanda Nunez hit?
It's nuts.
She does it like she,
I don't want to say she hits like a dude
cause that's kind of weird.
You know,
it was like a dude.
But uh,
yeah,
it's uh,
I remember being surprised.
I remember like having this open guard
on the ground and kind of like,
come here,
you know,
like I dare you.
And then she hit and I was like,
Oh,
oh,
oh you have those.
You
could see the look on people's face when
she hits him,
like where you saw it Rhonda like right
away,
right.
There's a part in that fight.
Cause I watched our fight after and like
you,
uh,
she hit me and it like did say I think
it's right when it had to be when I hurt
my head cause it like drop my arm and it
dropped my neck.
And I just remember like seeing like the
little twin eat tweety birds and I was
pumped because I was like,
that's where the cartoons get it from.
Somebody explained that shit.
That's exactly where they got it.
It's like whoo.
And uh,
and my arm,
like I couldn't get my arm back up and I
remember listening to you and you're
like,
cousin not intelligently defending
herself.
I'm like,
listen Joe,
that fucker won't work.
You know?
And then she screwed up because she
grabbed my knee and my knee was the one
that was like the catalyst to all my
problems over the last couple of years.
And it was just like,
don't fucking touch that.
And after that it was just like,
I just angry when she grabbed you in.
Yes.
Who's the wrong knee?
But I knew what she was trying to do.
Right.
Yeah.
So then it,
and then on top of that is like,
it's just,
I don't know,
the rest of it was just like punishing
her.
She was Kinda like Sassy before the
fight anyways.
Like in awkward ways,
like not even like cool hypey ways,
like just staring at me really weird in
a room where it was just like me and Tim
Kennedy sitting there eating like
watermelon and stuff after weigh ins and
I look over and she's just like,
like staring at me all weird.
I was like,
Damn.
Tim's like,
dude,
what do we do?
I'm like,
I can throw out a plate of watermelon
at.
I can throw a table.
I don't know.
I don't know what tone we're doing.
Wow.
When,
uh,
when you stopped her,
we've played the recording of you
screaming like maybe 10 times on this
podcast because to this day,
that is one of the Ross moments I've
ever seen inside the octagon.
Like when you,
when you jump,
like when they stopped that fight and
you screamed,
it was fucking bone chilling.
It was,
it's so,
I mean,
I'm sure you've heard it,
but that here it is right here.
Play it Jamie.
That's like from your genes.
That's like,
that's some cellular level shit.
Yeah,
that's intense.
It's relief.
It's like I didn't like,
like we lived,
you know,
they didn't,
we get to eat.
They don't,
and you know,
it's,
it's a relief.
It's,
Oh yeah,
yeah.
I mean you were,
like you said you lived,
cause that was,
I mean,
look,
it's just a fight.
There is a referee,
you're going to be saved.
But one of the things that George Saint
Pierre said last week when he was on the
podcast,
he said,
the mentality that you go in there,
the way you fight,
you are a warrior.
Like you,
you know that you're going to be
rescued,
but you are fighting for your life.
And when you're fighting a fucking
killer like Amanda and you get lit up,
like you didn't survive that first round
and then go back and stop her.
That's where that comes from.
I mean that was just fucking it.
Tense.
Well it's the,
it's the practicality to me,
right?
Like,
yes,
exactly.
We have a referee,
we have cage walls,
we have whatever,
you know,
fans,
it's entertaining people.
But like I need to know,
I need to know that like w that'd be a
nature,
you know,
that'd be doing whatever that be self
defense that be,
oh fuck us fighting over a territory or
food or whatever.
Like I need to know what would happen.
Like if we had like that's why I want
these finishes.
We only get 15 minutes to be able to
tell ourselves what would have happened
in that situation.
You know?
And,
and when it goes to a decision,
I'm pissed cause I don't know,
you know,
like you don't know,
especially these three round fights
where I'm waking up like these last
couple of fights,
like late in the fight them I'm pissed
because I'm like,
I don't know if that would have been
another 30 minutes or another two hours
that we're scrapping in the woods.
Like who gets the bone?
You know,
I want to know.
And,
and so that's us.
It's,
it's crazy and issue practicality and
it's sheer survival.
And this is the way I get to know
myself.
That's deep.
Who gets the bone?
Ooh.
Damn the way you just put it.
I don't think I've ever heard anybody
put it that way.
You need to know.
Yeah,
that's intense.
But I get it.
I get it.
That's where that's cream comes from.
You got the bone.
I don't know.
So you go down to San Diego.
What was your short list before,
by the way?
I'm a huge fan of,
uh,
Eric.
Uh,
alliance is just one of the best camps
for sure.
And I think Eric Delphia was like,
probably one of the most underrated.
And because he doesn't toot his own
horn.
Yeah.
He's like in the shadows,
laid back,
doesn't want any intention.
She's not trying to get any attention.
Like he's the last guy to like request
attention,
you know,
but super,
super knowledgeable and one of the best
guys in a corner too.
Like his advice is always excellent.
I never,
never heard him say the wrong thing in
the corner.
He's always like on point.
But what was your short list of places
to go to besides the wines?
Um,
I went to,
did you go to New Mexico by?
Yes,
but I feel like I'm not trying to walk
in on holly and like make sure it weird.
Then we're going to fight each other at
some point.
I know.
And that just,
you know,
I don't want to be that guy,
you know?
Although I know I'm welcoming.
I know that everyone,
there's always been nice.
I've gone and train there before and
it's been good.
Um,
but it's just not a cool move,
you know?
Um,
I went down to Arizona,
um,
with crouch.
Loved it there.
Great Guy.
Yeah.
Great.
I feel the same way about him.
Same.
Yeah.
Very,
very,
very humble.
Very good.
Yeah.
I'm super knowledgeable too.
Huh?
I'm up in La.
La was cool too,
but it was a lot of that
driving around in the traffic and
congestion and I couldn't sacrifice the
like the um,
yeah.
Is,
is so many people here.
Yeah.
And,
and coming from Colorado and coming from
like chill out doorsy you can drive 20
minutes and be somewhere no one's ever
stood before too,
like stuck in traffic,
breathing air.
You don't want to breathe like,
like everyone's a little pissed off,
but no one really knows why people,
Jamie's Jamie's been saying this
forever.
Yeah.
Where would you go?
Maybe Colorado.
So dope.
They're sailing.
Food culture could be better there.
I wish we could combine that food.
Culture of culture.
What do you went to?
I mean,
I'm in a health food.
I mean like ethnic food.
I like every,
I like,
I like trying new stuff all the time.
I'm not very like Food Cheney,
you know.
I'm in a fire and meat.
Yeah.
Are you,
are you so good lead over fire?
Yeah,
so I've decided I would go for the
steak.
First of all,
it's a great,
I love vegetables,
but you can get them anywhere.
I can get them in Colorado.
Not really.
I mean it's not exactly the produce
capital of the world,
but you can get them.
Yeah.
It's not the best.
Just get a greenhouse,
grow some tomatoes on my spare time.
So,
um,
did you try Montreal?
Did you think about five star?
I,
I did not.
Well,
I thought about it,
but um,
I don't,
I didn't get up to Canadia.
Aye.
I went to Thailand,
I went to Mexico.
I went to you think about going to
Thailand.
Yeah.
I mean when I'm there especially,
it's like such,
it's a Buddhist culture.
People are so happy.
I mean,
then you have your shit.
They're just like you have everywhere
else.
But at the same time,
like,
like the Moyie Thai training is good.
I know the places I would go to Jujitsu,
like the fair techs and Patios is,
is coming around in,
in pretty solid.
Like I've been considered that for this
camp just to kind of like make some
changes cause I really want to have that
influence in that like exposure to the
authentic when we tag.
And like when I looked back at my most
successful and most happy times after
these three fives,
I've lost three in a row.
Like that doesn't happen.
I'm not saying,
you know what?
I'm like,
no,
I'm better than this.
Like something's up.
And I know there's a lot that I need to
work on.
I mean like,
uh,
my,
my life in general and I'm doing it and
I'm happy to be doing it and I'm happy
to be getting the lessons even if this
is how I have to get him.
Like fuck it.
At least I know.
So,
um,
I tried to look back and analyze like,
what was I doing when I was my favorite
fighter,
when I was feeling the best and it was
like very traditional,
thick Moitai in very traditional,
thick Jujitsu.
So that this camp has been something
that I'm gonna also be outsourcing
because I want to be like that
element.
So I'm doing my,
I'm doing an actual Moitai with John Ex.
He's uh,
uh,
Jeremy Stevens Moitai coach I think too.
And then my Jujitsu with attos.
And then,
cause before it was like I would do
these separate disciplines,
put them together and drills and
sparring and then go mango people and
then like have fun with it.
Cause it's like these little goals I had
set,
like this little bucket list I would
take into a fight with me and tried to
pull those things off and then go learn
new stuff and then go try to do that.
That's why I was constantly evolving.
Every fight,
even in the fight with Amanda and I like
snapped her down and I had her by her
head and everyone's screaming news news
and like hold my beer.
And that's what I go on a throw her with
the,
you know,
the old,
they call it a ddt.
I,
it wasn't,
it was a freestyle headlock suplex but
it was like,
like I want,
I want every fight to be different and
fun,
like know what I have,
but see what else I got right thing and,
and that,
that I don't even get to play that right
now because I'm fucking up and I'm,
I'm not doing what I want in these
fights.
So I decided to take steps backwards.
And how do you dial in training and
training?
I,
I don't know it,
it's something's,
something's been missing and I'm
partially wondering if it's that,
you know,
so like every fight I'm looking to make
improvements and change.
Like I'm not going to ever sit here and
say I know everything and that it's
just,
I have no excuses.
Katelyn found a way to beat me,
you know what I mean?
Juliana found a way to beat me.
I kind of beat myself in that one too,
cause I let my head get into my,
you know,
and that sucked in again,
another thing for me to have put time in
and I'm happy I did,
but I mean that got me to move to San
Diego.
So I mean I'm,
I'm happy for that message.
It costs me a lot of money to get that
message,
but I'll take it,
you know.
Um,
and Caitlin,
yeah.
She found a way to beat me in,
into,
have been beaten by Jujitsu when I feel
very accomplished in Jujitsu that like
stung differently.
You know,
it's done way differently than just
someone else getting their hand raised.
Do you feel when you're in training that
you're the same as you were before,
when you were at your best?
Um,
when I was at my best,
no,
but it's something I'm working on like I
have,
I know I have like the hangups that I
have.
I know there's a ton of mental stuff,
you know,
one,
um,
just how life happened and,
and constantly having,
like,
I had this expedited adaptation to
training.
I had to get new coaches,
I had to find new gyms.
I had to do all of this while in grief
and being under like,
like this isn't the most forgiving
crowd,
you know,
like when,
when you're having a shit day,
definitely not the worst.
It's crazy.
It's crazy because it's such a,
like you're so exposed and you're so
vulnerable as a fighter and the fans
might be the meanest.
Well,
and yes,
there is so mean and,
but I feel like I have the best fans
too.
Like I have the ones like the ones that
are really old,
they're so ride or die and like I'm so
proud of him.
But um,
like I didn't even start doing my own
social media.
My,
my husband did my social media and so
all of a sudden I get thrown in to
social media and how social media works
when I'm at my most like low vulnerable
and all that shit.
I didn't know you're not supposed to,
I'm looking at it like investments,
right?
Like I'm like,
Oh,
here's the stock.
I'm going to put money into this stock
and let's just see how it turned out.
I was like,
ah.
And I think the first person that ever
told me not to do that was callin like
later.
He's like,
never read the comp,
which is,
what are you doing Brian?
Cal doesn't read.
She's,
I don't read the comments,
but I'm like,
well how will I know how I did?
He's like,
just fucking no in here.
Peers,
you're no,
you'll know from your coaches and you'll
know,
you'll know.
Well,
it's,
I mean it's sex when you know,
like six hours later you wrote some shit
that people are taking wrong or I mean,
it's like an opportunist situation.
They like wait for you to fuck up and
they're like,
oh,
right there,
right there.
I'm like,
you know,
I didn't mean to say that.
Or you know what?
That's not how I meant it or whatever.
But hard
because everybody's text looks the same.
The tax that you would get from a holly
Holm or someone you respect versus a
text he get from some fat slob sitting
there eating Cheetos,
farting into their hands.
The same person,
like it looks the same as on text,
but it's just you're going to get like
some people that just want to hurt your
feelings because they suck in their life
is terrible.
Like I've never met a hater that's doing
great.
Like there's no,
no,
haters are like,
man,
my fucking life is awesome.
But you know what I liked doing?
I go on Youtube and I just go make
comments.
Then it just trying to hurt someone's
feelings.
I just try to cut them to the bone,
just say fucked up shit about dead
relatives and what they did wrong.
Like those people were all just losers,
just fucking losers,
you know?
I mean there's just no way around it.
That's all they are.
It was so foreign to me cause I mean in
wrestling,
like I did wrestling,
I did soccer,
volleyball,
swimming.
Like I never ever heard anyone be
discouraging.
Like no one ever came to me and was
like,
fuck you.
You suck.
Yeah,
you wouldn't
get that in someone who was a fan or
someone.
Even if someone's from an opposing team
and like she ain't shit this.
They're just saying that because they
want to beat you.
But the haters that you're dealing with
online,
they just,
there's a lot.
Look,
life is fucking complicated.
It's hard to get right and as your
seeing with your very difficult career,
there's,
there's a lot of like decisions to be
made.
There's you,
you can fuck it up.
You got to build back up again.
Try.
Right?
And you're a smart person who's strong
and successful for losers.
Life is impossible.
It's impossible.
And so they go through life just angry
and depressed and sad and failing at
everything they do.
But they still have a phone or they
still have a laptop and like you fucking
con flooding loser.
And that's what you're getting.
That's where you're getting,
you're getting all that anger.
You don't even know this person.
Why are they angry at you?
Because they're angry at life because
life is fucked him in the ass.
That's they're angry.
They're angry at life because they got
dealt a shit existence.
Right?
They have bad genetics,
they have a bad family,
they have a bad job,
they live in a bad neighborhood,
they have bad people around them.
They feel bad,
everything's wrong and,
but they still get to talk.
They still get to talk shit and they
still get to type things,
type mean things out.
That's,
that's why he can't read comments cause
it's fucking hot.
The only thing you could do is inspire
with your work with you what you do and
you do that already,
you know,
and you're a human being.
You're going to make mistakes and you're
going to do things right and going to do
things wrong and you're going to have
these epic moments and you're going to
have these failures because that's just
a part of like doing things that are
complicated.
But you can't read the comments.
You definitely can't take them to heart.
Noted.
Yes,
no.
Did he got me good a couple of times I
get,
Oh fuck up your day.
I'm like,
yeah,
yeah.
What happened?
It's sad because those people that are
doing that,
they're in pain.
This is,
oh,
the only reason why they would lash out
at you like that and they go,
no,
I'm just telling the truth.
He just couldn't handle the truth.
Even if it was the truth.
The way in which people say it and the
reason why they're saying is because
they want to hurt your feelings.
They're not being kind.
You know,
there's a lot of that going on today.
I mean,
even then,
even in the media,
the way people tell stories and write
stories and write articles about people,
it's like they're not,
this is,
it's not just that they're trying to
tell the facts and explain what's
happening.
They're trying to cut people down and
hurt people and it's,
this is,
I wonder how much of it has to do with
the fact that our fucking president does
that because it seems more prevalent now
than ever before.
It seems like there's like a trend and I
think a lot of like,
one of the things about the president,
whoever the president is,
it's like there's some people that are
not going to listen to anything he says,
but there's a certain amount of people
that are going to take his actions and
use it as almost like a barometer.
Yeah.
An example of how they should behave and
how this country behaves.
It's like he's the top dog and when the
top dog is insulting people all the time
and saying shitty things and holds it
can be successful.
Yeah.
It's,
it lets people know there's,
or you want to get ahead.
I want to get ahead.
You gotta do like him and then they,
they go out and act like assholes too.
Yeah.
That's a bummer.
So anyway,
you go down to San Diego and what,
what are they doing for you that gets
you off of the antidepressants and gets
you feeling better?
Whoa.
Uh,
it's again,
like you get in there and I mean it's,
it's scary to go again,
like I said,
there's,
there's all these different people in
there.
I'm the man found the,
the research on it by treating his own
autistic kid.
And,
and you can see the before and after
videos of this kid and it's like,
damn.
Okay.
And then,
um,
I brought my son into,
cause he has adhd and he's off his
medication now as well.
So I'm going in there.
Uh,
they do an eeg first and then they can
tell which of your brain are firing it,
what hurts in seeing,
um,
the congruencies in like how all of that
is happening or not happening.
And um,
then they kind of prescribed these,
these different,
these machines like on your,
on your brain that make,
uh,
these like electric impulses,
but they're magnetic to,
um,
kind of speed up or slow down the
different parts of your brain.
So if the front of your brain is moving
slower than the back of your brain are
those or whatever.
So,
um,
they're noticing obviously patterns with
fighters,
hockey players,
football players,
like,
like people that are leading with their
heads basically.
Um,
having like,
uh,
and then with the veterans that are like
emotional things to where I mean,
and,
yeah.
And then like,
I mean,
having to compartmentalize as well,
like some of the shit they see should be
upsetting me know,
and,
you know,
but there's,
there's different ways that we can train
our brain to,
to drop things like that.
And then ptsd is when it's an
involuntary and it all comes in and,
and that,
so,
you know,
I,
I've been diagnosed with PTSD.
I had walked in there with medication
because of being depressed,
uh,
and the anxiety and all of that.
Like my symptoms were terrible.
And I know there are a combination of
things,
but even like my startle reflex,
like,
you know,
I could hear someone come walking around
the corner,
like,
clap,
clap here,
their shoes.
But the second I'd see them,
it would,
it would stop my heart for a second.
And that's like shit on your adrenal
glands,
you know,
and,
um,
all this stuff was,
you know,
an anxiety that,
um,
I don't know,
it was hard to fall asleep at night.
Uh,
you know,
my memory was crap and this is all,
different stuff happening in all these
other fighters that I know as well.
But I mean,
like I said,
I've been trying things so much,
so much over the past few years that I
get excited about and either it works or
it doesn't.
And um,
the,
the point is,
is,
is now I found this and I feel better
from this,
but I,
I was so excited about all these other
things.
Like I can't just start telling
everybody of the new thing that I've
found because I've said that and been
excited about like everything else with
this one,
this one's like the equal scope.
It's like,
uh,
it's uh,
um,
same thing.
It's kind of like a tens machine or stem
machine,
but like a super,
super low frequency and that's bad ass
to like it,
it helped on injuries.
Like,
you know,
if I rolled my ankle or hurt my toe,
like you could bring the swelling down
from this to,
to normal essentially in like an hour
and a half just working on with this
like tens unit on it.
And,
and I mean,
they originally used it for race horses
and,
and for,
you know,
super expensive million dollar horses,
like the equipment they brought over,
it was like 90 grand and like,
like these really specific like special
metals that were put into these plates
and you know,
they do stuff like that.
But that wasn't working on my head.
It was working injuries and it was
working on,
um,
I want to say it helped with like my,
like digestive system maybe or my,
um,
uh,
I don't remember some,
some other things it was helping with
too,
but what,
you know,
I,
I started doing that,
um,
or I was doing that when I walked into
mindset and started doing that
treatment.
And so what do they do it?
So you sit in a chair,
you know,
and they ha they put this prescription
in this machine and the machine has
kinda got like a,
like a arm that goes on in a specific
part of your brain and you,
you know,
you close your eyes and it sends us
these,
these magnetic pulses into your head.
And I mean,
you don't feel anything.
It's almost like you can hear what it
feels like,
but I don't know how to describe it.
It's,
it's a sense,
it's essential,
but it's not,
it's not exactly hearing and it's not
exactly feeling.
Um,
yeah.
And I mean you,
you,
you leave the place after your
treatment.
Like I go,
I would go twice a day.
It's 45 minutes away both ways.
So I am driving a lot everyday to go to
do this cause I want to give it a fair
shot to do it every day.
I do everyday,
I haven't gone these past couple of
weeks cause uh,
stuff with my kids.
Uh,
scheduled school's almost out and then
wanting to try out different things with
different coaches.
Uh,
as far as these new disciplines go.
So I haven't been there as much.
But um,
yeah,
for the last was August I believe is,
is when I was like really,
really getting into it and go on twice a
day,
45 minutes each way.
Twice a day.
Yeah.
So you would,
you would spend 45 minutes one way,
one way and then go back again.
Just fucking move closer to where the,
because the alliance was down there.
And so I would,
I would drop my kid off at school,
I would run,
and then I would go there.
I would do my treatment.
I go back to practice down in southern
San Diego,
then I'd get my son,
and then we'd go up there for the
afternoon session and then I'd come back
down and,
and we'd go to his sports.
And then I'd have my second two a day.
That does not leave a lot of free time
for cats and Ghana.
Oh Hell No.
Just that alone can be stressful.
But I was seeing the results.
That was the crazy thing is I was
feeling better.
Well,
the results when I just walked in like,
like God,
like I couldn't sleep.
I had just,
uh,
anxiety.
Like I had that,
that startle effect going like the,
um,
my memory was shit.
And these were all things that I went to
the UFC pie to talk to them about
because I'm like,
I don't know what to do.
Like I,
I want to fight.
They offered me to fight Chris Cyborg at
one 45 and I was like,
yeah.
And I was like,
well,
like hell yeah,
let's take that.
But like,
can you guys at least help me get this
shit figured out first please.
You know?
And they're like,
sure.
Um,
so Dunkin French,
he's at the,
the,
he's,
so he went to college and t and was
that,
oh no,
he was at Notre Dame using this
treatment with the doctor.
I'm Kevin Murphy that runs the mindset.
So,
uh,
he was like,
this guy is doing a lot of things with
people as far as brain health.
He's like,
go see them when you get back to San
Diego,
it's kind of far from you,
but like give it a shot,
Kat.
And I called the guy,
I'm on the phone,
super frustrated,
like super like emotional.
I'm like,
I'm,
I'm at my wit's end.
Like I've tried everything I can think
of like holistic views,
like chemical views,
this like everything.
I mean,
spending money out of my pocket trying
to figure this out because none of this
is covered by the UFC.
Especially because,
you know,
not something I claimed in a fight.
I mean,
I thought Amanda,
and if you don't claim that stuff within
the 30 days,
like you're on your own.
And of course my head her,
of course I'm dizzy.
Of course the lights are bright.
Of course,
I can't think.
Right.
I got in a fist fight,
you know,
and I wasn't doing good in it for
awhile,
so I,
I figured,
you know,
but then a month and a half,
two months out when I wasn't better.
It's like
sure.
Even though it clearly came from that
fight,
you still don't get covered.
[inaudible] what not one.
It's endocrine stuff too,
you know?
And it's like there's very,
there's like
how could they dispute that?
That's where it came from.
Now you go,
hey,
sit down.
I want you to watch something and just
play that first round.
Go,
what the fuck do you think happened?
I don't know.
But I mean if you play that video for
them,
if any,
anybody in the insurance business was
denying you coverage,
saying that didn't happen while you were
under the banner of the UFC.
Like you're out of your fucking mind.
Watch that video.
What do you think is happening while
this fucking assassin is throwing bombs
at your face?
I mean that's it.
That is crazy that that's not covered.
Yeah,
that makes me sick.
Oh,
it's frustrating cause bye bye.
Like literally you look at the papers
like it costs me more to fight then,
then it,
then I make
makes sense.
If it was dealing with a broken hand or
a torn ligament or something like that,
it might make sense.
And Mike,
it does not make any fucking sense if
you're talking about brain injuries
cause anybody who understands how brain
injuries work know that there's,
there's a considerable amount of time
after a fight where you still are
suffering from symptoms and you might
decide 30 days later,
60 days later,
90 days later you got to do something
about it.
Right.
Well I mean now I know how I come out of
a fight and I'm like,
my pinky hurts,
my elbow hurts,
my hair hurts,
my eyebrow hurt.
It's like when a claim all of this,
you know,
because before I was just being tough,
I'm fine with fuck it dude,
this is why it's so crazy and I didn't
like,
I didn't get it and I didn't know and
then,
but they should know if they're in the,
they're in the business of insuring
fighters.
They should have a larger window where
people can claim head injuries we talked
about
that's,
I mean it kind of goes together with
like any kind of,
any kind of mental,
anything.
Like any,
you talk about mental illness,
you talk about head injuries,
you talked about Tbi.
It all goes into that stigma of like you
can't see it,
so it must not be real.
You know what I mean?
Or,
or whatever.
So it's like,
but that's the head injury business
basically.
Yeah.
The point is to make them drop and be
done.
That's what everybody,
I mean it's not,
it's not the worst thing in the world.
The wind with a body kick or an arm bar.
But the reality is what people like is
to see head injuries were in the head
injury business.
You know?
Yeah.
So how long after you starting with this
treatment do you start to see results?
So the first,
I would say the first thing I noticed
was my motor skills in practice.
And so,
you know,
I would go,
so you think your motor skills were
impaired?
No,
I,
well I just feel like I had a block.
Like I said,
it's,
it was comical enemy.
You can even ask them at alliance.
And it was funny,
it was funny,
but not to have like we're in class,
you know,
we're learning,
I'm watching the coaches,
like they do a drill and they explain it
and they look up.
All right,
everybody ready?
Ready?
One,
two,
three go.
And we clap and I have no fucking idea
what we're doing.
You know,
like we walk off and I'm like,
like there was even a couple of times
where like they clap,
they,
they're like,
Kat,
what are we doing?
And I'm like,
um,
three kick.
And they're like,
no,
20 pushups.
And I'm like,
man,
I'm not even like,
I'm not just a bad kid like talking and
like,
no,
like I'm in trouble because I'm,
I don't hear you.
I can not lose eye contact the whole
time.
Like sit here and I'm like focused,
but no,
I'm not retaining it and less like if it
has to be the last thing that they do.
Like we can't talk about shit if,
if,
if it's the last thing I see I can go do
it or I could go do it.
But if they're like,
all right,
and then they explained some philosophy
about it or do some movement or
whatever,
like then I lose what we're doing.
Like my,
my mind would just go right to something
else.
Like I had a very hard time
concentrating and you know,
it's,
it's crazy because when I got to this
facility,
you know,
I didn't know,
I didn't necessarily know what I was
walking into,
but they have,
you do this questionnaire and like on
this questionnaire is like all of these
things.
I'm like,
that's part of something like me not
being able to focus as part of something
my sleep,
that's part of something.
This startle effect is part of something
like me having these like completely
like specific things that are all on
this was like damn okay.
Like I didn't even want to see the eeg
because I was,
I was scared.
You know,
I was like,
what if you can't fix me and now I know
all the shit that's wrong with me like
that.
That sucks.
But then you know,
they show you different egs and they
show you the,
they take it every single week and so
you actually get to see it and you get
to see the level that you were
functioning at,
especially the different parts of your
brain.
But then,
and the thing is that's awesome about
this is you get to keep the results.
Like unless you go do exactly what you
did and go fuck it up again,
you get to keep it.
It's not like this maintenance package,
which is,
you know,
a problem for these pharmaceutical
companies.
There's,
there's,
there's not a whole lot of retention on
it because once people get their brains
functioning,
as long as you're not sitting there
hitting your head against the wall,
like you get to keep feeling better.
Like these,
these veterans get to go back to,
to combat or whatever it is,
their job is like we fighters get to go
back,
football players get to go back.
Like I,
I sat in with the chargers,
uh,
medical staff and talked about our stuff
there as well.
I,
I don't even remember who else there was
people from all over the country coming
in asking about this,
you know,
and,
and needing to sit in and,
and they're looking at these is in
particular.
So what is it doing?
Like how was it fixing it?
So one,
um,
I think it,
you know,
there's something with what goes on in
your brain with,
with the thyroid stuff,
with the endocrine stuff is like getting
your damage to your hypothalamus.
Right?
And that's like,
that kind of directs all of the
information that goes to your thyroid,
your thyroid,
you know,
then sends out everything to your body
in there when there's like a disconnect
there.
Um,
no,
it was just screws everything up.
And then on top of it,
like now that we're cutting the same way
that we've always had to cut,
but we don't get ivs.
I mean,
I mean you,
you cannot 100% rehydrate your brain
within 45 or 48 hours.
Like you can get your body decently
hydrated,
I believe,
but your brain is just,
it's its own thing,
you know?
And so now we don't have ivs are
hydraulic system in our brain is down
and now we're rattling it even more like
dehydrated.
I mean,
we're just going to have,
you know,
bigger side effects,
uh,
tire brains being dehydrated that now,
um,
the damage that comes to the
hypothalamus to the pituitary,
to the,
um,
your thyroid,
all of that that goes on there like
that.
They're,
they're saying that you can,
you can get it firing back at a level
that it was before it got hurt.
Like,
as long as the cells are still alive in
it,
they can reenergize those cells.
Now if you have like just a dead party
or brain,
you know,
they're not bringing it back to life,
but they can um,
use these magnets to kind of fluff on
backup,
give them back their energy,
their,
their life and put in a,
put them back into a functional way that
was something similar to you at your
healthiest and,
and make it,
I mean not more or less durable just
back,
right?
Yeah.
When you,
when you were saying motor skills,
like what was wrong?
Cause that's one of the things that they
see in fighters that have taken too many
shots.
They start having the,
they analyze fighters,
gates and one of the things that happens
is your legs get closer together.
Um,
your,
your balance is off your,
your steps are shorter.
You don't have that sort of like dynamic
fluid motion to your body and you're
having a heart,
a harder time with balance and just
motor skill.
Totally.
So how I felt before going into there,
it was all I had was a gas pedal.
I was like,
just will,
you know,
and just fuck them.
You know,
just cause I,
I wasn't reading patterns of people
anymore.
Like if someone leans this way a little
bit,
I'm like,
oh,
okay,
I know what you're thinking.
Like if they set this way or that way
and,
and even meet juking them in like China,
like faint at them.
Like I,
I wasn't,
I couldn't even see the reaction I was
making them make,
like I knew what motions in my muscular
memory to make them do,
but it was like I wasn't getting the
feedback because it,
it just like wasn't,
so that was one of the first things I
noticed was,
you know,
going back into practice and,
and watching people's angles and beating
them to it and,
and,
and like remembering,
I'm like,
damn,
I don't just have to shoot to shoot.
Like I can wait and do it when it's at
the right time or I can even like,
like take advantage of,
of the fact that,
you know,
I'm making them step back or I can flash
fire and they're facing and jump on them
at their knee jerk reaction.
You know,
like these things of like being able to
manipulate the situation and make them
adjust to me.
Like I could see that again and I could
see.
Would you seen before?
Like when I just had go,
all I had was good
when you didn't see movement,
like say if someone was going to spin
and they're like reload it up their
hips.
You didn't see that?
No,
it's just hit hit him first.
What were you seeing?
I all,
I didn't,
all I saw was get their first,
all I saw was like closed the distance.
Don't get hit in the head.
Like make like get down and get low and
just be a linebacker,
you know?
And,
and hit him because I,
I knew I wasn't seeing that stuff and
the more I tried to see it,
the more I would just sit there and wear
it.
Cause I'm like any minute now.
I mean,
any minute now I'm going to,
I'm going to catch the pattern,
I'm going to catch the pattern.
But it wasn't,
then it wasn't popping up.
So then all I had,
you'd have,
you were just like super light sparring,
just moving around.
You didn't see it?
No.
No,
not really.
No.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's fucking terrified.
I was like,
yeah,
it was really scary.
And like even I even get to like a good
position in Jujitsu and I'd be like,
I know I know stuff here.
But she didn't know what to do.
What was it?
I know,
I know stuff,
you know?
But like it wasn't like,
especially with adrenaline firing,
like it wasn't just happening for me.
And so like three,
four weeks into that,
all of a sudden like that fog was
starting to go down a bit.
Right.
And like part of it was,
and then,
and then I'm also sleeping better
to goal before,
like during like the first week.
Oh yeah.
Cause every fucking person I went to
could fix me.
Right.
And you drive in 45 minutes,
like what the fuck?
Yeah.
Eh,
yeah,
it in a,
in a,
in a car I leased.
So all those miles that,
you know,
it's like damn.
And um,
it's uh,
it was super frustrating.
Yes,
everyone can fix me,
everyone can fix me.
And then they don't.
And then my heart's broken again and
then I go to the next one and then my
heart's broken again and then it,
and then the next one.
So this one I'm like,
I'm like,
I'm not even going to tell people about
this because I'm sick of fucking hitting
up and being excited about it and
telling them to come with me and then it
doesn't work.
And then I'm that guy again,
you know?
And so going into this and then watching
it work and then seeing all the other
people that was working for in there
that,
and they were never trying to push me to
promote it.
They were like,
just come in,
just get here.
You know?
And if you like it then till the,
cause the UFC was talking about getting
one of the machines at the Pi and
they're kind of going to have me be like
a Guinea pig for it.
Ian Mccall went in there too,
but it didn't like he,
he was doing his own kind of other stuff
that was making it so it wasn't working
for him,
but like I was all in,
you know,
was making it so it wasn't working.
I don't think he was coming in often.
So I think,
and the thing is is that it does stir
shit up,
right?
So like they,
they,
they mess with your,
the the levels because again,
they have to like the back of your
brain's running at four hertz and,
and okay,
eight is technically where like you're
sleeping,
you're at rest like year,
there's part of your brains that could
be under your resting hurts,
right?
While the front of your brain is running
at 12 so that's like high anxiety,
but like low energy and they can,
they can almost tell you how you've been
feeling lately,
which was like nuts to me.
Right.
And you could,
they can tell,
you know,
because of this and this,
that,
that you have some ocd tendencies versus
this person constantly feels like they
have no energy in their memory,
isn't working in their emotionally and
capable of like being in,
you know,
being a positive force in a relationship
right now.
Cause I don't have it so they could read
it.
You should.
It's scary though.
Cause I cute when you see that like
little like,
and they're like,
what's that?
It's for me.
It's,
that's a two hour drive.
Shit.
Yeah,
I know that there,
I don't know if they have anything up
here.
I know that they have a bunch all over.
It's called,
I couldn't,
the website's not coming up at this
personalized repetitive transcranial
magnetic stimulation,
a noninvasive therapeutic approach to
the treatment of Ptsd and other neuro
neurocognitive disorders.
Kevin,
Tim Murphy,
MD,
Vice Chair,
department of Radiation Medicine,
applied sciences,
Uc San Diego Director,
Pediatric Radiation Oncology Program.
Uh,
rady children's hospital,
San Diego.
Wow.
Yeah.
So that's where you're going.
And,
um,
I mean obviously during this whole thing
you have to be questioning what you do
for a living.
Oh yeah.
Well,
and it's like,
okay,
so they can fix this.
Say they fix it and then I go do it
again.
You know
Cyborg,
right.
I mean you were,
you were thinking about fixing it and
you,
you were going from one girl who hits
like a dude to another girl who might
hit like a bigger dude.
Yeah.
I mean cyborgs fucking terrified.
And it's like I know healthy at my
healthiest,
like no,
no problem.
I believe that like,
I believe in myself like that.
Like I can figure them out,
especially in find a way to not get hit
doing it.
Like I didn't get hit in my mma career,
significant a hit,
not one significant significant hit and
tell Amanda.
And then after that I was getting
fucking lit up.
Right.
And,
and not even,
not even Juliana,
like she kind of opened him bitch slap
me a little bit from the sides but I and
but like I can find a way to,
to like still control it enough to be
like,
like very effective without taking too
much damage.
But like that,
that slow of my,
my motor skills,
my mechanics,
it was,
it was really bothering me.
And that's not how you go fight someone
like Cyborg.
You don't go in there with that weight
in your pocket.
You know,
it's so important that you're talking
about this because this is a,
this is such a factor that we don't see
on the outside.
Other people,
you know,
other people.
Then the people that are really close to
the talk to about these things.
Like if we were seeing you fight and you
know,
when we see the decline of certain
fighters,
you know,
you see certain fighters,
they,
they're in a couple of really hard
fights and then you see a decline,
like a real obvious decline and their
skills and their abilities.
Very,
very rarely are they opening up about
what's going on,
about losing memory,
about not being able to see patterns and
people about not,
not having their motor skills in tune
anymore that things are off.
You know,
so you talking about this I think is,
it's so important and it's so important
for young fighters to recognize like,
Hey,
this is also on the table.
Like here's a great therapy for it.
But this is also a possibility of,
you know,
if you do fight a fucking killer like
Amanda Nunez,
this is one of the things that can
happen to you.
Well,
and it's partially because I have man,
I have teammates.
Yeah.
I have people that are 10 times worse
than me that are just like,
I mean the stuff I hear,
the stuff I see,
it's,
it's sad and it's scary and they have
kids and they're not going anywhere
soon.
You know what I mean?
And they're passing their Mris.
Right.
You know what I mean?
Like
their Mris.
Cause what does the MRI really see?
I don't know.
But if they went to this place and got
all their brain mapped out and find out
how everything is firing,
it might be a completely different
result.
Like we might be retiring people way
earlier,
at least forcing them into therapy way
earlier.
It's possible.
And I mean in that,
and that's the thing is it's like the
risk needs to be worth the reward and,
and you know,
like right now in this sport it's a
juvenile and it's not getting us like
this kind of like,
like I,
I can't afford to take another two years
off because I went and I fought cyborg
while I'm sick and something bad happens
to me.
You know what I mean?
Like I want to be sharp and if,
and if that means I have to take time,
take the time I took off off and get
healthy and do all of these different
therapies,
the conservative,
traditional and nontraditional,
like all of that.
And so I can feel the way I feel now and
the like,
I'm pumped and I'm excited.
But like that is something that I really
want to know that people know they can
go do.
And it's not vulnerable.
It's not saying you're weak,
it's not something wrong with you.
Like,
like it's your health and your longevity
and your future because that shit,
if you don't treat it,
it doesn't get better.
And like you don't understand the
depression,
you don't understand like,
and there's an identity that goes away
with the seeming like you failed or you
can't do it anymore or whatever.
Like that,
that mental health aspect that comes
with the physical health of your brain,
like that all that all needs to all
needs to be more educated as far as,
as these fighters go.
As far as all of it goes.
Like,
I'm happy to be the Guinea pig because
I'm damn,
I just want to see everybody.
Okay.
You know?
Well,
I'm happy that you're talking about it,
but it's,
um,
it's been something that,
you know,
I've talked about quite a bit and um,
the,
the real problems behind traumatic brain
injuries because I've had a bunch of
experts and I've talked to a bunch of
neurologists and I've talked to
neuroscientists and people that are
really studying this stuff and um,
I've been real vocal about it and it's,
it's a tricky situation because
obviously I'm a commentator,
but like when someone gets knocked out,
I'm very vocal about them taking a long
time off.
And it was one of the things that
happened after Rhonda got knocked out by
Holly.
Um,
they were talking about getting her back
within like,
it was like four or five months later
to,
to fight again.
And I was like,
they were going to have a rematch with
holly and I'm like,
you guys are fucking crazy.
Like,
you're crazy.
She shouldn't be doing anything.
She shouldn't be getting hit.
She shouldn't it be sparring.
She,
there's,
she shouldn't be getting her head
rattled and she definitely shouldn't be
fighting holly fucking home who just
kicked her into another dimension five
months later or whatever it was six
months later.
I'm like,
there's no way this is not,
should not be happening.
Like you don't even know what's going on
yet.
You don't even know what kind of damage.
I mean,
think of what happened with you and
Amanda did you stayed conscious at
least.
I mean,
Rhonda got fucking flat lined and then
got hammer fist.
It didn't the head while she was
flatlined.
It was,
uh,
one of the most brutal knockouts in
women's mma ever.
And you know,
and you saw when she came back and
fought Amanda and got hit like right
away,
that hesitation.
Oh,
she was just stiff and up and the fear.
And then also Amanda,
I felt even before the Holly Holm fight,
I felt like Amanda was the more
dangerous fight for her because of her
hands.
Because Rhonda is always in this
position where she's closing the gap.
She's getting close to you because she
wants to clinch up with you and throw
you and take you to the ground and arm
bar you and what have you.
But with Amanda,
you're dealing with a Brazilian Jiu
Jitsu black belt who knocks people
fucking dead with one punch,
like it's a terrible match up.
I felt,
and obviously that proved to be true,
but what drove me crazy was how
dismissive all these people behind the
scenes where all these agents and
Hollywood people and all these people
that just have no idea what business
they're in,
they really don't even this business,
the business,
it's basically the business,
like we said,
of head injuries and you're just like,
you're trying to sell this thing where
you're,
you're dealing with someone who had a
fucking significant head injury and now
you're pushing it back in.
There was someone who's really good at
delivering head injuries and is this,
is this really all been mapped out?
I mean,
what kind of training have has changed?
I mean what you,
she's still with the same coach.
Has she done anything differently?
Like what,
what do you think?
What,
what result is going to be different,
you know,
and the downplaying of the significance
of a fucking ruthless knock out like
that I just don't think can be
understated.
I think people should take a long time
off when they get knocked out like that
a long time.
Yeah.
Well,
and I mean especially some sort of like
invasive treatment like from out the
gates for something like that.
You studied and I mean,
I mean I know they put a flashlight in
your eyes and ask you if you okay send
you to the doctor,
do whatever.
But I mean like,
and,
and I think honestly that's what the UFC
is like effort was in,
in this,
in it and offering this information of
this treatment to me was to see like,
hey,
is this something that would,
would benefit fighters in,
in a situation like that?
It's at the Pie.
It's not at the Pii,
but what they were saying is it would be
at the Pi,
um,
still.
But the trick with it is that it is
something you need to,
you need to go to.
I need you to go to twice a day and have
that like schedule of it in that routine
of it.
But US says fighters like flying to only
vegas for it and paying our own room and
board are own flight,
potentially having to fly our coaches
and to have to,
you know,
keep us working and doing whatever while
we're working.
I mean it's just an,
I don't know.
I mean,
It's tricky business.
You know,
it's real tricky business.
And how old are you now?
35.
Do you wonder how much longer are you
going to do this?
I like,
I,
I feel like I got like a good couple of
years left.
Like I'm,
I'm still having fun,
you know,
and like the chest of it is still fun
and like the training is still fun and
I'm still learning and like enjoying it.
And um,
I dunno,
like getting through everything that I'm
getting through and learning everything
that I'm learning is like,
it's so inspiring to me.
Cause I,
I definitely don't feel done.
Like I still have so much fight in my
heart and like I really love putting my
hands on people in,
in always like advancing and improving
in,
in the day I stopped improving,
you know,
uh,
then I can look at that.
But right now,
like I don't care about plan B,
I don't care about what's next because
that's not what's happening.
So your passion for doing it,
it's still there.
Yeah.
And the purpose,
there's the passion is,
is huge.
I love the passion,
you know,
that to me is huge.
But the purpose,
like the bigger picture,
the,
the what I'm doing here,
what I was born to do,
what I was born to get through.
Like I have to get through this,
like I want to get through this and I'm
getting through this.
I'm,
I'm watching myself and that is like,
it's bad ass to me.
It's exciting to me.
It's,
it's,
um,
it's what I'm doing here,
you know,
and I am,
I'm all in like in and I can make,
I can just make things for myself that,
um,
I get to show myself every single day
that like no one could have ever told
me,
you know,
it's all stuff that I know firsthand
from my experience,
from my world,
from me trying things from me,
risking things like all of that and,
and um,
to understand myself and to know myself
like it's been the biggest reward out of
all of this.
Know yourself through the struggles and
know yourself through the fights.
Yeah,
all of it.
I mean,
and even how much you get to learn,
just even going into a fight,
right?
Like realizing so going into a fight,
being on antidepressants like,
okay,
I'll wake up,
but I don't know what this will do.
I feel flat.
I don't feel flat.
I'll be okay with these people there.
I'll be,
I won't be okay with this.
These people here,
like,
like all of that is very clear about
things that like,
this has my attention whether I know it
or not,
that that's something in my life that
needs,
needs to be looked at and needs to be
addressed.
Okay.
There's direction.
Like all I ever want is understanding
and direction.
Like I just want to know,
you know,
and so,
um,
I get to deal with that,
that that leads me to come to San Diego.
San Diego is,
is a new chapter in my life that I get
to name,
you know,
uh,
also for my kid and myself.
Like it's,
it's,
I,
I get a reveal so much to myself through
trying different things and to just kind
of like letting life take me down the
path that I'm supposed to without me
sitting here freaking out about control,
freaking out about things that I,
I can do nothing about.
You know,
I just want to walk away from all of
this like content and happy with how I
did.
Whether that means I never have my hand
raised again.
I don't think that's the case.
Like I beating these girls,
having the belt that is not a pipe
dream.
I already beat them.
You know?
It's not like I'm incapable of that and
I'm just wishing I got my fingers
crossed.
You know?
It's,
it's not that my whole journey of my
life in sports from being a kid was to
meet my highest,
best,
to be my highest good.
And,
and that is what's driven me the whole
time.
I look at these girls and I respect them
because they're here doing what I'm
doing.
We're all just out here trying to be the
best at it.
We're all trying to participate.
We're all trying to,
you know,
find ourselves in it and learn what we
can learn and go implement it,
you know?
And,
and so for that,
I have respect for every single one of
them.
Some of them I like less than others.
Some of them are like more than others,
you know,
but,
um,
really like we're building this stage
together,
we're doing this together,
you know,
and I'm,
I'm extremely proud to be part
of something like this and my position
in it and my purpose in it is to,
you know,
find my personal good,
my personal best.
And you know,
this has been extremely long road for
me.
Nothing has been easy and I respect
that.
Like I'm grateful for that.
Like all the things I know because of
the hard times,
like I feel fortunate to know,
you know,
and I would never have learned them any
other way.
And I get to handle them.
And not only do I get to handle them,
I get to like,
like relate and understand people and
see things differently because I get it,
you know,
maybe not exactly word for word pinpoint
per pinpoint.
Oh,
I'm not even gonna try to say that I was
going to make me fall over.
Right.
But you know,
it's,
it's all there and it all matters to me.
And how I get through this really,
really matters to me because I know it
matters to other people too,
you know?
And,
and how they do inspires me as well.
Do you know what you're going to do when
you stop?
I,
I just don't,
I mean,
I feel like there's this thing is
there's this awesome resume and
building,
right?
You know,
like I'm a UFC fighter,
I'm a national champion in wrestling.
Like I'm,
I'm,
um,
I don't know,
constantly advocating and working on
working on myself and trying to help get
other people working on themselves too.
Like I don't know what all that's going
to look like.
And the thing is,
is I don't even want to,
I don't want to look,
I don't want to care about all that yet.
Right.
Cause that's not where I'm at.
And like,
I want to be all in here.
I don't want to think about what's next
or plan B or,
or how all of like,
all of that because my heart is here.
Right.
You know,
it's like,
what are you going to do in your next
marriage?
Right,
right.
Yeah.
You know what I mean?
Like I,
I'm right now,
I'm,
I'm here,
right.
I'm doing what I'm doing.
I don't,
I,
I'm not looking towards what's next
because right now I'm here.
Yeah.
That's great.
Listen,
that's what you want to hear from
someone who's fighting.
I mean,
fighting should be all in that study is
the only way to approach it.
If you're a fighter and you're also a
neurosurgeon and a part time real estate
salesman,
good fucking luck.
You don't have 100% to give everything.
You got one,
100%.
Especially with something like fighting,
it's just such a crazy way to make
living.
You really have to be 100% committed to
it.
It has to be your life.
Yeah.
And I,
I appreciate the opportunity.
I like,
I like everything I'm doing right now,
you know?
And I feel like all of that will be part
of what's next.
But I like that that'll manifest that
it'll figure itself out.
I mean not to,
not the like hippy way of,
oh,
everything will be great.
I'm sure.
Like when it's time I'll look at that.
Right.
But right now this is what I'm looking
at.
So the,
the kind of drive and discipline and
work ethic that you showed to become a
top level MMA fighter and a national
champion in wrestling,
you could do anything with that and
whatever you set your mind to.
I really believe that.
I mean,
I think the biggest problem that
fighters have when they retire is
finding a thing to put their energy too.
And then their identity because their
identity is of a fighter and when that
is taken away from them,
there's that.
And also the thrill.
I mean there's,
you guys are experiencing a level of
excitement and intensity.
Like when you're talking about two weeks
out,
you're crying in the fetal position and
going,
what the fuck am I doing?
But that all builds up to these moments
like that crazy primal scream after you
stopped Amanda Nunez.
Like that's a experience that very few
people other than people fight to the
death are feeling.
There's,
there's something,
there's something that you guys are
experiencing that unless you're the
person in the woods fighting over that
bone,
you really don't know.
You don't know.
And then for you to go to regular life
after that,
it's going to be hard and it's going to
be hard for a lot of fighters.
It's,
it's very difficult for a lot of
fighters to find another thing that
excites them.
The way finding excites them because
it's such a crazy pursuit.
And then on top of that,
you're dealing with what you're dealing
with,
but you're dealing with it publicly.
You're talking about it,
which I think is a,
you're doing a great service to
everybody when you talking about your
problems and your issues because there's
so many fighters that you know that
you're experiencing this and that I know
that are experiencing this.
And you know everybody who,
anybody who's done any sort of martial
arts competition and been in gyms,
you're going to see people that have,
that have taken too many shots.
It's just part of the game.
And you,
you know,
it's what you're doing by talking about
it so openly.
While you're still a top level fighter
is I think,
very,
very important for everybody.
Huh.
Thanks.
I'm trying man.
It's been a lot of trying things,
but I do,
I do feel value in this,
you know,
and I mean exactly when people are done
like,
Eh,
there's some pride in,
in having to go get a nine to five or
whatever,
you know,
after being a,
a level of fighter at this level,
mind you should,
you not have the fucking brain cells to
be in life.
It's like,
like I got high functioning thing that
you can be proud of.
You know what I mean?
It's,
it can be really stressful to not live
up to the capability that,
you know,
you have what you're just not like
there's that wall or that fog or
whatever,
you know.
So I mean,
I just think people maintaining
themselves and doing everything they
can,
however vulnerable it feels like fuck
it.
Do it like
both that they could spread this therapy
across the country.
And how big are these?
Yeah,
they have,
I mean,
they look like they,
so they,
they have,
um,
like mobile units.
But again,
like it would need to be on,
I don't know if it's on some sort of
route or whatever that people would need
to be able to show up to or what.
But um,
they,
uh,
yeah,
I know they have one in Indiana know,
I know they're going to have one in
Colorado soon,
I think relative to the training center.
And when you say mobile units,
like how big are these mobile units and
are they as effective as the one that
you're going?
It's a,
it's a creeper van.
You know,
it was like a little dish of candy in
there.
Yeah.
It's like you get in and,
um,
it's the same exact chair,
you know,
and then they have their,
they're trained,
uh,
nurse nowhere to put it on you.
I don't,
and then even the Eeg,
I mean,
it's like a,
it's a wireless eeg,
so I know that every week they make you
do the eeg,
like same time,
a relatively the same time,
so they can keep good track of what your
brain is doing and how to prescribe the
levels to be at what on your head.
Um,
and I,
I think they have one in Arizona.
I know there's one in Texas.
Um,
I want to say there's 12 over the
country,
but I can't tell you where.
And the mobile one.
I mean,
how big is this?
is this something that uh,
Jim could get and how is it
prohibitively expensive?
Want to say again?
I might be full of Shit,
but I think they're like $100,000
for that machine.
But I do know that they're being,
um,
insurance will cover it because,
uh,
for the insurance will cover it for
Migraine,
uh,
ptsd and autism I think.
I think that insurance will cover it for
that.
But then,
um,
tricare's is also accepting them as an
insurance as well.
Wow.
And so when they're doing this to you,
and you know,
you said you got it in August,
you started doing it and you started
seeing improvements after he said four
weeks.
Yeah,
four weeks.
It was like the first time I saw
improvements and then the bigger
improvements where coming leader,
yeah.
Does it,
does it keep getting better?
I mean,
is it better now than it was last month?
Yeah,
I mean,
to the point where I can,
I'm,
I'm okay not going for three,
four weeks,
you know,
like,
like I said,
these last few weeks have been all about
me getting everything right to be in
training camp right now.
So you feel right now like you felt
before the noon hour?
Right.
In the way I'm changing.
Like I'm having fun with it again.
Like I'm,
I'm watching people,
I'm like fucking with them.
Like I'll get them to step that way and
then I'll step that way and then I'll be
very satisfied.
Oh my God.
Especially on for a while.
Yeah,
it was gone.
And,
and like that is the art to me is the
games and the playing and,
and the like getting you to do this so I
can do that.
And then,
you know,
like that was what was fun.
Yeah.
Good.
Getting in a fight is not fun.
Right.
But the chess,
that's what's fun.
The game like,
like making the oohs and the Ahs and the
crowd happen because you know some
gangster shit,
you know what I mean?
Like that's fun.
That part's fun.
Going in and getting cut up and bloody
and having headaches and like your ankle
hurts for a month and boil or she's not
fun.
No one wants to do that on purpose.
You know,
I want to go in and do what I can not
get touched and then have it go on a
highlight reel,
you know?
And that wasn't happening for awhile and
even on this last one,
and it's just like,
man,
I felt better.
I totally felt better and in,
but what I needed to change wasn't that,
that that was fine.
What I need to change.
This is other things that I'm changing
and I am,
and again,
like if that's how I have to learn it,
cool.
But like it's all part of the process,
you know?
I'm not no second in this entire thing.
Have I stopped believing in myself?
No second.
The only thing I worried about was like,
it was like,
all right,
am I going to be,
is my son changing my diapers here in a
few years if I keep doing this shit,
you know,
like,
I don't want that,
but I never stopped believing that this
is what I'm meant to do right here right
now.
And I have time and I have more fights
and I have everything it takes to go out
and be every single one of these girls.
Some of them again,
you know,
I do know now when you're in camp,
um,
how many days are you,
you doing two a days?
Yeah.
So some of them are,
it'll be like,
sometimes I'll have to add more cardio
in the morning.
So like if there's fasted cardio,
if I'm heavy,
you know,
depending on how that goes,
as it's like a science at about 45.
Like what do you walk around?
Yeah.
What do you walk around?
I can get all the way up to like,
I've,
I've been all the way up to 76,
but that was before.
I didn't know that was when,
uh,
I didn't,
I was,
I didn't know I was hyperthyroid.
Oh.
So I mean,
now I was eating like 600 calories a day
and doing fasted cardio and two workouts
in my weight wasn't changing.
My coaches were like,
what the Fuck's wrong with you?
I'm like,
I don't know.
I guess the women in my family get kind
of big,
so shit.
Maybe it's just that midwestern style
hitting me now,
you know?
But,
um,
no,
and then when I went and I got my panels
does that,
and like everything was all screwed up,
you know?
And then that
Nunez fine before the Nunez five.
What was the heaviest got before then?
I never broke a hundred.
150 552.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's crazy.
I walked around like one 40 I didn't
even have to cut cut for Misha.
I walked,
I woke up in the morning like two just
didn't eat breakfast.
Wow.
Yeah.
And then now I'm a big Mama.
Jamma like how I look at food and I get
fat.
It's in the solid.
No,
but I don't hate it on armour thyroid
or,
um,
uh,
leave.
Levothyroxin.
Yeah.
Okay.
I take it every morning and like 15
minutes before I can eat anything heavy.
You should look into armor thyroid.
It's a thyroid that's made from a pigsty
Roy.
And uh,
apparently it's a,
it's more bio available.
A lot of people have better results with
it.
I would,
I would try it.
I won't try.
I wouldn't try it now just cause I'm in
camp,
but maybe in between the next ones.
Yeah,
I'm hyperthyroid too.
Yeah.
Runs in my family.
My family too.
I didn't,
um,
I have a weight problem cause I was
working out a lot,
but I was getting headaches and uh,
I went to a doctor,
get a,
like at the end of the day,
like a say around like seven o'clock at
night.
Um,
uh,
after dinner I would be so tired that I
just like,
I couldn't talk.
I just had a lie down.
I couldn't hear it.
I couldn't log on,
talk,
boom.
And I'd go out and it was like,
God,
these headaches are weird.
Like this is,
it didn't seem,
it didn't seem normal,
like the,
the late,
I guess it was like after dinner
headaches,
like right before bed,
it was just,
it was,
it was not a normal exhaustion.
I started getting nervous about it and
then when I got it checked out,
it made sense and my mom has it.
My sister has it,
it runs in our family.
Yeah.
I don't know if it's that genetic for my
family,
but you think it's from the head and I,
yeah,
I mean it was right away.
Yeah,
it was onset.
And then,
um,
you know,
and then you do these Mris and you do
all of this other stuff and it's like,
all right,
well there's where your head hurts and
they're just what's wrong and you know,
so I mean,
it was just,
it's all too perfect,
you know,
puts together your camps,
like who decides what you're going to do
as far as like how much work you're
going to do,
what kind of training you're going to
do,
where they're going to do sparring,
or they're going to do
this training camp.
Um,
I,
I'm,
I'm outsourcing different things,
so I have like,
I,
I talked to Eric Delphia about it and
like I said,
I said I wanted to outsource the Jujitsu
and the Moy Tai and those are going to
in itself takes so much time.
Right.
And then,
um,
my strength and conditioning and I'm
doing with Chad missy is he's,
he's mad ass.
Uh,
so my strength and conditioning coach,
Lauren Landauer,
do you know who she was in Colorado?
So he's like family to me.
He's been there for everything.
Like I didn't even know when he got
there.
He,
but he was always there,
you know,
um,
he told me about Chad.
Uh,
and so I started doing strength and
conditioning with him.
I'm going to do that,
um,
three days a week.
And then,
um,
I know that I want to get working with
the more traditional Moitai again.
So I'm working with John next two days a
week,
um,
and I think he's going to arrange my
sparring as well.
And then,
uh,
Andre Galvao,
I'm going to try to work two or three
days a week.
And then,
um,
so I handed all of that information to
Lauren Landau and my other coach,
my nutrition issues,
Josh Ford.
Have you seen him before?
He's got like a tattoo goatee on his
face?
No,
he's been doing my nutrition and um,
I've,
he's known me since all I did was
Jujitsu,
you know,
so he's been around,
he knows my style.
He knows me as a crazy fighter and all
of that.
So between Lauren and Lauren,
Lando and Josh Ford there,
they're putting it together based off of
what they've seen out of me in the past.
But if you're going to Jujitsu and
you're doing a lot of Jujitsu training
and then you're going to Moitai doing
Muay Thai training,
when do you get together and do mma
training?
Okay.
That'll be the sparring days.
And then there'll be a light sparse,
like kinda drill day in the middle in
there too.
So are you sparring Moy,
Tai and sparring mma?
No,
I'm going to be swearing mme.
So that'll be where I mixed together the
and like,
that's kind of how I like it too.
Like I like doing the disciplines
separate.
And then and then me finding where to
put them in in a lot of times that's
where my freestyle wrestling just ties
it all together.
So you're more Thai training would
basically just be technique drills,
[inaudible] a Ninja moves,
all that and your moves.
And then Jujitsu.
Are you going gear?
No,
gay.
I didn't know beef or I did g for like
the past four weeks and yeah,
fuck man,
shit hurts your feelings.
But then uh,
obviously it's more practical to do the,
to do the Nogi and now they took the g
off of me and me.
I'm like a thousand miles an hour.
I'm so happy with myself.
Slippery.
Yeah.
Can I grab my shirt?
And what about wrestling?
Are you doing any rustling?
That part?
I,
I will.
I still got to figure out down in San
Diego I want a freestyle wrestler.
I'm not like,
I got a great shot,
I'm good at shots and whatever,
but I'm,
I'm way more about throws.
Like I like,
there's so much more efficient from,
yeah,
I got awesome hips for him and it's just
like,
man,
they're,
they're high risk,
high reward.
But it's my funky style.
Like I just get them done.
Right.
And it's so much less effort when you
taught someone over their head on the
ground and they don't know where they
are for a minute.
There's so much to capitalize on there
with the equilibrium just off and like
those are things I like,
like I count on,
so I need to find that freestyle
situation yet I have good freestyle
wrestling myself,
but obviously like,
like it's good to stay on top of those.
Like it's my strength,
but I need to keep my strength strong.
So I'm looking,
I'm going to make that happen.
So what do you walk around that?
Right now I'm like one 55 when 56 72 45
is a possibility.
Yeah,
I mean,
and I,
I've,
I've wanted to go there as well.
I mean,
like I said,
not having that fluid on our brains when
we fight kind of bugs me.
Like if I can walk down at one 45 and
eat breakfast,
like,
yeah,
I mean I won't,
I'm like eating clean eating right
everything perfect.
I'm one 55
yeah,
because I watched one of the,
uh,
they had a video of Cyborg cutting
weight to make one 40 member in the
winter,
which didn't make any sense.
There wasn't even a weight class for one
40.
Yeah.
I don't know what the fuck they were
doing with her or they were trying to
prime her for one 35 or seeing if she
could make one 35.
Yeah.
But she was like weeping and it looked
like she was dying and like what the
fuck man.
Yeah.
Did she do the water cut in that one?
Like the,
the bathtub?
Well she did a lot of shit but it was
just hard to watch and she gets big too.
Like they uh,
I'm friends with the way I'll be who?
Her boyfriend and he like hit me up when
I was supposed to fight Ronda,
they were hitting me up during my
training camp.
Like,
Hey,
cause I think they have,
obviously they have beef and I think
they wanted it to be like kind of
political,
but I'm just like not in to that.
But they were like,
hey,
how Chris you,
do you have
any girl training partners?
How about Chris come train with you to
get ready for Rhonda?
And I was like,
oh,
maybe.
I mean,
how big is she?
And they're like,
like,
oh,
one 82 and 83 and like,
what was the,
how does that help me?
Another big motherfucker on me.
Like,
Oh God.
I'm like,
um,
thanks.
But like I got Neil Magni right there.
Hey Dude,
over like those guys are one 82 yeah,
I'm not paying her hotel.
She so fucking big.
That's so crazy.
I mean,
she really,
she probably be fighting one 65 yeah.
And there there's a 55 you know,
common,
hopefully.
Yeah.
I mean,
I just don't know.
there's only so many 40 fives.
I mean,
she's obviously got the belt at 45 but I
think even 45 is a brutal struggle for
her.
And you know,
as you said,
you could only do that so many times.
It's taking a little bit of your life.
Every time you do that,
you know,
you're,
you're chipping away at Oregon.
Yeah.
And I just remember like I remember
coming into mma and like I used to cut
to one 25 like dying,
dying and that,
so I was,
I wanted to be ranked number one at one
25 that it was my goal before I moved up
in like I,
I did,
I was ranked number one,
their beat everybody I can be.
And then it was just kind of like the
last time I made one 25 I just,
I,
I fought a girl named to k Ohashi from
Japan and I remember it was like last
minute cause I suppose to fight a girl,
something happened to her and then they
replaced her with Tko and I just
remember being so happy that we were at
altitude because I was like,
I think I had a heat stroke at the,
the water cut,
like the bathtub cut because I was in
the water for like 20 minutes and I
remember at 10 minutes I was like,
something's wrong,
something's wrong.
And they're like,
you have to stay,
you have to stay.
And so the 20 minute line,
I like dove like a salmon,
like out of the water and I passed out
on my floor and they gave no shits that
my managers there and I'm naked and like
I don't,
I don't know,
I'm out to the point where they're doing
the knuckle rub on my sternum,
you know,
to try to get me up and then I'd rub on
your skin,
you know,
trying to wake you up.
That's how they wake you up.
Yeah.
It's like in your sternum.
Cause it's like something with the
nerves hero like hit your adrenaline
awake.
She was crisis so bad.
And so I'm up and I'm like,
you know your hands and arms are
tingling and everything cause you're
like waking up,
you know.
And I'm like,
I don't want to get back in that
bathtub.
Like put the sauna suit on me.
I don't like put it on me.
I don't,
you know,
so not that that like,
I mean health wise I was not okay,
but it was like I'm not getting back in
there.
So they put this on a suit on me and my
hands are like freaking out,
like doing this weird shaky like t rex
arm thing and cramping so bad in my feet
were doing the same thing.
But it was like,
like they had to cover me in the
blankets and put all of the stuff on me
to keep me hot cause I was not getting
back in that hot tub or the bathtub is
terrible.
And after that,
like I remember I felt it in the fight
and I was like,
I'm so glad we're at altitude cause I
feel horrible.
I can't do this again.
And then I went up to 35.
Jesus Christ.
Yeah.
It is the worst part of fighting.
It really is.
And it's so,
it's so unnecessary.
There's gotta be,
I mean,
what one FC is doing,
they've got some,
uh,
they're,
they're eliminating weight cuts by doing
hydration tests and,
and testing people several times during
the camp,
finding out what your way,
finding out what your actual weight is.
And Ben ask him,
went into uh,
the,
the way they're doing it in,
in detail when I did a podcast with him,
but that seems to be the way,
and they made everybody move up a weight
class essentially.
Jeez.
I mean,
and that's the thing is I,
okay,
like contract contracts can still exist,
but maybe you're just contracted as a
fighter and you have to fight certain
amounts of time a year or or whatever.
But to have people contracted to weight
classes is like,
it's hurting the sport and it's
obviously hurting fighters individually
as well.
But like
it's just unnecessary.
Yeah.
Well you should do is fuck,
I mean there are weight classes,
there should be more weight classes,
so there's more opportunities and you
should be fighting for what you are when
you're healthy.
It's hard enough.
Well,
and I think especially because the sport
is,
because I mean,
it's very blatantly clear that it's,
it's,
this is not a bracketed sport.
Like this is an entertainment sports now
it's clear like we're doing what puts
butts in the seats,
right?
We're doing what's best for the fans.
So at that point,
what are these divisions really matter?
It's about the matchup,
you know,
you can throw a belt on it,
any fight these days,
like,
so I think if we're going to evolve the
sport to,
to having entertaining fights or
entertainment type fights,
like we should just evolve the,
the contracts to that as well.
Like,
shit,
I mean,
it'll still save the entertainment
value.
Like,
look,
you can get,
uh,
or catch weights even.
Like,
what do you guys want to agree on?
You know?
Right.
Like who's down for what?
If you had an ideal weight,
what would it be
to find out?
Yes.
Uh,
probably 45,
45.
Yeah.
I feel like I'm skinny enough that I'm
like flying squirrel,
flexible stuff,
you know,
but,
uh,
but still a hell of a strong,
you know?
Um,
but when you're dealing with someone,
like Cyborg is coming down from one 80.
That's the thing though,
is me healthy.
Like it don't matter.
Like,
um,
I'm the water,
she's a rock,
you know?
And that,
that's something I remember thinking
when I was going into 20 fives.
It's like,
I'm going to be huge against all these
girls,
you know,
like they,
they may not be as dehydrated and fucked
up is me,
but I can hold them down.
Right.
You know,
and,
and I can do what I want and eventually
break them.
Right.
You know,
and I,
she's,
um,
she's got that in her back pocket too.
Yeah.
But like,
you know,
you get the,
the,
I I thought watching the Tonya Avenger
fight,
like there was a lot of things,
uh,
that I,
I saw in that fight against Chris and I
was like,
damn,
like that,
that right
there,
there's,
uh,
there's something I could do there just
fine to me seemed like Chris is being
very cautious and conservative and that
she was just picking her shots and,
and just trying to be very professional.
Like the way she was fighting was not
like this marauding rampaging destroy or
like we've seen in some of her other
fights.
She fought much more technical and just,
and Tanya evenger was throwing wild
fucking bar stool type shit.
She was just,
she,
her hands were down.
She's whinging big bombs.
She knew she had to go for broke and you
know,
Tonya,
every juror's tough as fuck just to take
that fight.
I mean the difference in size was so
apparent between the two of them when
you saw them inside the cage.
And you know,
tom is just,
just a really tough woman.
But her style,
she was just trying to be unpredictable
and wild,
you know?
And cyborg was just moving in.
Let's just real,
real professional and technical.
I felt like she was cautious.
I mean it was a big fight for her too,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
That was the first,
was that the first belt defense?
What was that?
No,
that was the first ballot because her
winning the belt for the belt.
Right.
That didn't happen again.
Yeah.
And it was like,
see Ya Germain de Randamie is like not
interested.
Yeah.
Wait,
does she go there?
She said,
oh she's still fighting.
Well she remember right after the fight,
I interviewed her after she won.
First of all,
that fight bothered me.
It bothered me a lot cause she hit holly
after the bell twice.
One hard and really rocked her.
And I watched that.
I was like,
fuck man,
that was a big shot.
And like you,
you could say you accidentally did it
once.
Maybe,
but she did it twice and one time hurt
her bad.
And even so when I watched the fight,
I'm like,
that's the,
the,
the times when she hurt holly was after
the bell,
but holly fucked her up twice in that
fight.
She hit her with that question.
Mark kick cracked her and rocked her and
then she hit her with a straight left
hand and dropped her too.
I felt like holly deserved the nod in
that fight and I definitely think she
deserved the nod if you take points
away,
which I definitely think she should have
taken.
She hadn't points taken away from her.
I just think I just didn't,
it didn't sit with me well,
and then after the fight she said she
needed,
when I asked her about Cyborg,
she's like,
yeah,
I'm getting surgery.
She was like,
I'm good.
I got something wrong with my thumb or
something.
So I was like,
okay,
she's going to get some surgery.
And then.
Then it became a ped issue.
She said the Cyborg is a lifetime ped
cheater,
that she's a performance enhancing drug
user and that everybody knows it and
she's not going to fight her.
So she basically just gave up her title
and went back down to 35 I think.
So she is fighting again.
I don't know if she went and got surgery
on whatever was going on with her hand,
but she is going to fight again,
but she hasn't since I don't believe.
I don't think so either.
See if you can find that.
Jermaine Duran to me.
See what she's,
who she's fighting next.
She hasn't tweeted since November about
a fight then.
Damn,
November.
Yeah,
that didn't happen.
See,
that's the person not investing in
social media.
Are you doing it right?
Are you doing it wrong?
Oh No.
She was like,
I'm just not interested in this.
Which is crazy because this is how
fucking tufts cyborg is Germane to
random.
He fought a dude and coyote them.
I mean there's a Moy Thai fight with her
fighting.
Yeah.
I remember when I first started fighting
and like getting pointed at looking at
like that,
like,
here's why you want to learn.
Moitai and I was watching her,
I was like,
that girl is,
she looked at me and do some wars and
she's like older too.
I mean,
I can't say older.
I'm like one of the older ones now,
but she is she older than me.
Yeah.
But she,
um,
she fucked up a dude.
She Kao to Dube is tray right hand?
Yeah.
I mean it's a,
I mean,
and then if she fought a guy like knew
it was a guy signed up to fight,
a guy fought on,
beat them and they're like Cyborg.
Yeah.
I'm not doing that.
That's how scared she is a Cyborg and I
get it.
I fucking get it.
Cyborg walking around 182 pounds.
I get it.
Kz around.
I need to have,
yeah.
I mean it's a really open division.
A one 45 right now and Megan Anderson,
it's about to fight.
Is that at 45 or 35 I believe that's it.
45 Megan innocence.
Big Girl.
Yeah,
that's what we're legit 40 fiber.
She's,
she's strong.
She's in her prime.
She's really tough.
She's good at everything,
you know?
And she's a legit girl and fighting
holly in her first fight in the UFC also
like shows how much they think of her.
But I mean,
how many fighters do they have at 45
he's like fucking three.
Let me know who the fuck is there.
You got holly who fought Cyborg and lost
and then you know,
w what else you got?
You got Megan Anderson who was over in
Invicta and most people other than the
hardcore fans don't know about her.
You know?
And she was trying to get her name out
there.
So what do we got here?
Is that the whole division?
Yes,
for sure.
That's a whole division.
Yeah.
Jesus Christ.
Oh,
y'all nose on there too?
Well,
Yana fought Cyborg.
She little isn't she?
She got nuked.
Yeah.
That was a,
I mean,
she did her best,
right?
She,
when did she fight Cyborg?
Same night.
I fought a UFC two,
two,
two mm.
The July or she looked good.
Cyborg got ahold of her.
It's just like one of those things where
when Cyborg starts landing on girls,
you see the look on their face and in
the fuck,
what am I doing in here?
I mean,
I was most impressed with Cyborg on her
kickboxing loss when she,
when she fought Zarina barge.
Did you ever see that fight?
She fought her and Moitai terina bars is
a fucking beast.
Demand.
I,
she doesn't need her from across the
room in the face bars knocked her down
with a front kick to the face and she
dropped her and time still cyborg was
still chasing after her for every
fucking round.
Yeah.
I was like,
that girl's lid.
I mean,
she's,
she's big and she's strong and she's,
but mentally she's tough too.
Like she's,
I mean to just a fight that girl at
during the bars had,
she had I think almost three years
without a fight where she couldn't get a
fight cause nobody wants to find her
because she's just a fucking bad ass Moy
Thai fighter real long and tall and just
classic Dutch style Moy Tai,
you know,
and um,
cyborg stepped up fodder in lion fight.
I mean,
when she was like the most feared mma
fighter in the world and said,
fuck it,
I'll take a Moitai fight.
And with like zero Moy Tai professional
fights fought like one of the best girls
ever.
It's really pretty admirable.
You know how bad ass she is in that
regard.
Oh that's cool.
But you know,
when you have a division that's that
small,
it's like what,
what do they do?
You know what I mean?
What are you going to grow the girls,
make them get bigger.
Like hey girls want some food.
Like Hey,
you know,
I mean this isn't,
this isn't the pride days where they can
just fill them up with,
um,
you know,
whatever the fuck Gabby Garcia is on,
and toss them out there.
They have to be legit,
you know,
I don't know.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
it's a,
it's a weird situation cause I,
I mean,
I don't,
I don't follow enough to,
to know what is out there to follow
invicta or do you pay attention to any
other organizations outside of the UFC?
No,
no,
I'm in,
honestly,
I don't watch the UFC that much either
cause I like,
I don't have cable.
Like don't know.
I have netflix and a DVD player.
We just in school.
Yeah,
we go crazy on 80s and nineties movies.
Wow.
Yeah.
Well look,
Netflix,
you kind of don't,
I mean you could watch good shit all day
long.
You don't really,
I mean,
so many people have severed their cable
now.
They just don't want to do it anymore.
Fuck a commercial.
I mean and how much is cable?
It's like a hundred bucks a month or
something like that.
It's Netflix 10 yeah.
I felt like that like get the fuck outta
here and it's not like you run out of
shit to watch.
Like you could watch Netflix all day for
the rest of your life and never run out
of shit to watch.
You know?
It's a weird time for those cable
companies.
It's like the only thing that really
keeps people buying cable I think or or
direct TV.
One of the big things is live sports.
Live sports is like one of those things
where you kind of have to have direct tv
or cable or something
generational too.
I mean,
there's a lot of people that just always
had it.
Yup.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
My generation,
these young kids,
they don't give a fuck about it.
Yeah.
John Young kids don't watch CBS and
like,
see what the fuck is that?
And if you,
the weird thing is if you watch regular
tv now it seems like you're watching a
machine,
like you're watching some,
some shit from like a bygone error,
like laugh tracks and then cut to
commercials.
They're like,
what is that
cliffhangers to be continued?
What is,
it's just weird.
So what do you do when you're not
training other than a watch dvds?
Um,
not really much.
Like I'm trying to get out in San Diego
and like,
like live,
you know,
in play by the like I'll get to the
beach when I can try to soak up the sun
and whatever.
Um,
really like I have a struggle because I
realized I came here to,
to work.
Like I came here,
I changed in my life to come out here
and be all in and be as successful at
this as possible.
So my day is about training,
about doing the like rehabilitation type
things that I need to do and then making
sure my kids' needs are met and you
know,
wash,
rinse,
repeat with that.
Like I recently went to,
like,
I've been to a couple of escape rooms
but was fun.
Yeah.
They're super fun.
Unless you're not getting out,
you sit there and they're like,
hey,
let's take your picture at the end.
I'm all pissed,
right.
I'm still here.
Yeah.
I didn't get out.
We didn't get out either.
We got out of one room,
but it led us into the second room.
It's hard.
I can be like,
there's a,
there's hard,
it was hard for me being an athlete
because I'm like,
there's harder.
We can do.
Like I can work harder at this,
but there no working harder at it.
Right.
It makes you smarter.
And it's also like weird shit to put
pieces together,
you know?
Yeah.
And then,
um,
let's see,
there's like a,
there's like a horse,
a rescue that I go down and I'll like
put time in down there and just kinda
like be with the animals and feed them
and like you can try to rehabilitate
them.
Some of them are scary man,
like,
but it's cool cause they're actually
like something really to be scared of
like half the shit we're afraid of is
just in our head anyway.
But there's this like gigantic animal
that doesn't know if it wants to kick
you.
I love you.
And it's like trying to be friendly so
you can help it and teach it.
Stuff like that.
That's taken some of my time.
It's been cool.
That is weird with horses,
right?
Like you could break them,
you can lasso them and they'll let you
ride them.
Like wild horses.
People go out and catch wild horses and
ride them around.
Like what other fucking animal can you
do that too?
That's so strange.
You know,
like that is really strange that you
could like get a horse.
He got them in the bar and the horse was
like,
fuck you.
Fuck you.
And you're like,
no,
fuck you.
You get a rope around them.
And they're like,
all right.
All right,
you got me.
You're riding me around now.
It's very strange.
I mean,
it would have weird relationship people
have with fucking horses.
It's very strange.
Oh.
Then my friend Whitney Cummings has a
horse and she's all in.
She's all in with this fucking horse.
She rides it bare back.
She's like,
you have to have a connection with the
animal.
It has to feel you like not a satellite.
Alright,
crazy.
I've seen
clint eastwood movies seems like he's
riding the horse pretty good with a
saddle on and she doesn't do that.
And she rescued this horse and she'd
like on her instagram,
she's always like riding around with
this fucking horse and hanging out with
it,
you know?
And she's like spending all this time
with it.
It's like,
it is,
I,
they call it equine therapy and like,
like I was trying to get this because my
brain was working in all these ways.
Like I got really excited about that
treatment center,
that,
um,
the mindset place.
And then again,
there's all those other people in there
that are in there in the veterans and
stuff.
I was like,
man,
if,
if I could get someone them down there
working with these horses,
one,
it gives them something to do cause the
ones that are disabled like their hate
in life and,
and that place,
like it's awesome because after a few
months of being there,
they all want to know how to help their
like,
like tell me what I can do around here,
you know.
And um,
even that,
with that on my man,
if I could even get them down,
they're like,
sometimes if all you do at this place
has shovel shit,
you know,
it's,
it's still like you're around these
horses and um,
this place in particular,
they're all rescues and they,
it's called Ferdinand's familiar and
they've all been mistreated at some
point or they were trained to be
something that they never graduated to
being.
And so there were trash and now they
need to turn these horses into like
rideable like horses or whatever.
Like that's the goal.
And then they have this,
um,
it's near imperial beach.
It's like on that land,
like right on Tiawana so you get,
the goal is to take them on this like
trail that goes all the way to the beach
and you can ride up and down the beach
like freely zero.
Can you ride the beach to Tiawana?
Is there a wall?
Oh yeah,
you can write it that both.
And it's like a see through wall and you
see them in through,
yeah,
I mean it's just like,
it's like panels and you can see right
through it.
Like I went down there and I could swim
around it.
Yeah.
I was thinking that the other day.
I'm like this,
you guys are almost too tempting.
Like I almost want to go over there.
Is it right here?
Yeah,
it's there.
That's exactly where we ride.
Fucking strange to me.
That is so God damn strange.
So which side is Tijuana?
This is tia one or the other side is the
United States.
Right.
And yeah,
that's exactly what it looks like.
They have their little umbrellas.
They're having their little barbecues,
chillin,
playing music,
having fun.
Meanwhile we're all over.
They're like,
Huh.
Like,
I almost want to try to swim over just
to see if anyone's going to stop you
because there is a little bit of like,
if you keep going up that fence,
they have like one car with one dude
who's watching,
who's watching the border patrol.
And it seems so easy to get here from
Mexico,
right?
All you have to.
Oh,
and how deep can that fence go?
Yeah.
How deep can it go?
Dig under that fucker.
Shitty coffee.
I mean he's put up here,
put up your umbrella and like a special
angle and you're good.
Just climb.
That doesn't seem like it's impossible
to come on.
I mean,
I'm not the best climber in the world by
fucking guarantee you.
I could make it over that fence.
100% look.
Yeah,
you just grab a whole
the APP,
some gloves on so you don't fuck you're
hands on.
You're going to have to do some soft
soft sand Shane and cause that sprint
afterwards.
Again,
burn your leg.
Yeah,
the sports world,
but unless they're on Dune buggies,
they're not going to catch you.
Those fat fucks.
I just,
I feel like swimming is the move.
Why climate?
You just swim a couple of hundred yards.
Okay.
Yeah.
Right.
It's like 200 yards.
Maybe.
Shit,
go left and then come back.
It's so weird that like bill dot wall
build that wall.
People are so crazy.
The whole thing is so strange.
I think one day we're going to look back
on countries like the human race one.
I think one of the things that's
happening to the human race for sure is
that we're getting closer to each other.
We're getting,
we can,
like I'll read tweets that someone will
post in Spanish or in Chinese or
whatever and you just press translate
and then you get to read it,
you know,
translate to English.
And I'm like,
wow,
there it is.
I could read this guy words.
And they have this thing called the
Google Pixel.
Uh,
it's a,
you know,
it's a phone and um,
they have these pixel buds,
these earbuds and these ear buds will
translate in real time.
Like you could say some shit to me in
Spanish and it'll translate it in
realtime to English.
Yeah.
And how long is it going to be before
that's way better and we're going to
realize that countries are stupid.
See,
but I think,
I mean I agree on that on the social
media side that I feel like social media
has made that connection for us on that,
like that I guess mental,
social side or whatever.
But as,
as humans individually like here and
now,
right next to each other,
like I feel a huge disconnect.
Like look at,
I mean a century ago,
more than less than like you knew who
the town butcher was,
right?
He knew who the blacksmith was.
You knew who the mayor was like you knew
like,
and everybody had their position.
Your kids were safe to run around like
everything.
Like everyone knew and there was value
to every single person for,
for what it is that they're,
their craft was or who they are and now
no one knows anyone.
And like,
people don't want to like,
like I almost feel weird sometimes at
like,
you know,
my kids,
my kid doesn't see all of the same
pictures that I see because I have
facebook and he doesn't or you know,
but I'm not ready like to have my kid
exposed to the library right there,
you know?
And it's a terrible thing for kids to be
exposed to.
Yeah.
And,
and I think that,
um,
you know,
so like shoulder to shoulder person a
person,
I feel like a bit of a disconnect,
you know?
But social media,
like we get to share information
sometimes not good information.
Sometimes you get information like the
fact that people are communicating I
think is important.
Um,
it's,
it's making people take stands on things
that they're all finding out.
Oh,
you believe that too.
Or I think that too,
like cool.
Like I can find my people,
you know?
But on the actual like oxytocin,
like social side,
people actually getting to know each
other like those like intimate
relationships.
Like I feel like that part is,
is suffering a little bit from it.
Yeah.
I think that's suffering a little bit in
real life.
Um,
because people were in cars,
they're in traffic,
isolated,
then they go to work and then a cubicle
all day,
and then they'd get home and they're in
their apartment or their house.
Yeah.
There's not a lot of like interaction
with people and it's just stinked.
This is just a,
a side effect of modern life.
Yeah.
You know,
and it's weird that there's so many,
like in La,
there's so many people next to each
other and almost nobody knows their
neighbor.
It's a very strange,
right.
But what I'm talking about is I think
countries are stupid,
like states.
I think countries like states,
like I think we should build a wall over
Florida before we should build a wall
for Mexico.
I mean,
Florida's a state,
right?
But Florida is just as alien as like say
Finland or something like that.
I mean,
it's just,
just the fact that you can move out of
Florida and like,
Fuck Florida,
man,
I'm going to,
I'm going to move to Atlanta.
And he'd go up there and like,
nobody stops you.
You just go.
But if you're in Tiawana like you,
like no dog,
there's a fence up here,
pitch like this.
No,
there's no crossing did to,
to me that seems like super fucking
strange and almost like guaranteeing
that those spots are fucked forever and
the only way those anythings ever going
to level out is if you let anybody
travel wherever they want.
And nobody's willing to do that because
it might fuck up the good spots.
Like la Jolla would be like,
no,
no.
You can't just like,
yeah,
we're not.
Yeah,
we're not,
you can't just come over from,
I mean you think about it,
La Jolla has some of the wealthiest real
estate in the world,
right.
And unbelievable.
Beautiful views.
And you could walk to Mexico from La
Jolla.
You could walk,
I mean,
what's the distance between Tijuana and
La Jolla?
Let's guess.
Let me guess.
I'm going to say it's 50 miles.
Is it 50
I'm going to say 50 no,
I it's not that many cause it's already
depending on,
oh yeah.
I would say it's a 30 minute drive.
Like,
like moderate.
Yeah.
Normal speed limit.
No traffic,
35 maybe.
So maybe it's 30 miles.
So it's like a marathon,
like a marathon run.
Which people do.
They run it all.
They've run marathons,
all Tom 20,
30 to 32 miles.
Nine 30.
So you're in fucking Tiawana.
You were in a third world country and
one of the worst neighborhoods of a
third world country and 32 miles away.
You have like these unbelievable
mansions on these bluffs overlooking the
ocean.
Look Nigga,
that shit.
That's crazy.
And Clara Natto it's very weird.
Yeah,
exactly.
It's very weird.
Yeah.
And,
and yeah,
that corn auto,
the island,
that's all super wealthy people,
right?
Yeah.
That's where Dick Cheney lives
apparently.
Yeah.
They,
they have the ability of shutting that
whole island down.
If there's like vandalism or like,
cause it's,
it's got its entry and it's out like,
um,
what is it called way?
So it's not exactly an island.
Like it does attach to the land.
What does that call the peninsula?
Yeah.
So,
but they have an ability,
uh,
both the peninsula edge and
the bridge to shut it down as a
community.
If Shit's going down on the island and
they don't want someone right
get off.
Wow.
Yeah.
That's how rich they are.
It's only one of the wealthiest places
in the world and another one.
There's a one off sawed off of Miami.
There's like some little tiny island
that's filled only with rich people.
Star island I think.
Is that what's called?
Yeah,
it's like one of the most wealthy places
on the planet.
It's one little spot off Miami.
Just fill with rich folks waiting for a
hurricane to fuck up their lives.
Is that it?
Star island is a tiny neighborhood of
massive houses in drama.
Oh,
there's drama.
see the big X on it?
Like fuck this place.
Okay.
It's not a drama.
Damn bad ass houses though.
But they have good brunch to,
yeah,
that's a little too,
so they have a little bridge and it's a
little tiny island.
All right.
Good luck people.
Weird people are weird cat.
That's not safe.
It doesn't feel safe.
Not in Miami.
Pirate.
A pirate.
Come wipe that whole crocodiles.
The place is filled with pirates.
That place is filled with weird shit.
It's just Florida's so straight.
I love it.
I'm joking around,
but I hate it.
But I love Miami.
I just,
it's so strange.
It's such a,
every time I go down there,
I'm like,
you should have to have a passport to
come here.
This is not America.
I don't give a fuck what anybody says.
It's great,
but it's,
it's chaos.
But then there's some s Florida spots
like we like,
okay.
Pensacola,
you could just go fuck yourself.
Would you say it's basically Alabama by
as wealthy?
It might as well.
We,
other than Roy Jones jr I mean he came
out of there.
You put pence coal on the map.
Hey.
Nope.
Do you do any boxing training?
I do.
So I,
um,
alliance has been like real helpful on
my hands.
Like I wouldn't say there's a ton of
improvement as far as that goes,
like,
and I never really focused on boxing
before.
Like I,
I worked Muay Thai and kickboxing and
between Dutch and tie sal,
you know,
and then to go there and have my hand
sharpened was,
it was pretty cool.
Uh,
I just never,
um,
it was hard for me to like to relate
boxing to any sport I'd ever done.
And like,
as a,
as a athlete growing up as a kid,
like if I don't,
if I can't understand something that I'm
learning,
I try to relate it back to some like
muscle memory of some motion I've done
before in some other sport,
like volleyball or swimming or like
what's the mechanics of how I've moved
in,
something that I can even dance,
like turn into getting like some kind of
value out of so I can learn this thing.
And like boxing was not like anything
that I'd ever done before.
Like I've never had a predominantly
hands on sport that I was good at.
So it's been the,
um,
the most,
uh,
what's the word?
I don't know.
There's the,
the most work in the less,
the least natural of all of the
disciplines.
That's a come into cause for this word,
but you've trained Moitai so much and
more tie his hands in it.
Right.
The
thing I'm excited about the most,
we ties the clenching and the cakes,
you know,
so to set up,
right,
right.
And just having the,
the hips and everything with that,
that came with wrestling and that came
with,
you know,
the footwork of,
of soccer,
of dance,
of all of that,
stuff like that,
that contributed I think easily and
translated easily over to that.
But boxing was,
um,
not so much,
you know,
but part of me also thinks like,
some of that had to come with,
with learning.
Like you,
you got to get hit to realize you don't
want to get hit.
I'm not ready.
I don't want to talk about that.
I don't want to get hit.
So
yeah.
Yeah.
And slip and roll was shit.
It hurts my feelings and get punched in
the face and I'm happy.
I'm the kind of person that it pisses
off,
you know,
like,
so it makes me,
it makes me fight harder,
you know?
But like,
it's stunning.
It's stunning.
Especially when you get one of those
good ones in the nose and now your eyes
are watering but you're not crying like
that.
Weird stinging sensation.
Yeah.
Learning all of that,
that,
that all was definitely within the last
few years and it's been,
it's been fun.
It's been not fun but fun.
When you see like the evolution,
no,
a lot of fighters are getting into yoga.
A lot of fighters are doing yoga.
A lot of fighters are finding that they
have like real benefits and protecting
their back and strengthening a lot of
their joints and their ligaments and
stuff like that.
It's supplemental towards like the
physiology of it or because it's
something as far as adding to the
combative side,
uh,
I think both.
I think for sure it's good for your
mental endurance because it's,
it's hard.
I mean it seems like something that
should be very easy.
You hear about Yoga,
like,
oh,
housewives do that shit.
But if you do it 100% in,
especially hot yoga,
you're stuck in that fucking box at 104
degrees for 90 minutes,
sweating your ass off,
pissed at about 60 minutes and that one.
Yeah.
So there's definitely some mental
toughness that goes into the night
you endure.
You endure a 90 minute hot yoga class.
But I think for your joints,
for your range of motion and
flexibility,
there's almost nothing better because
you're so hot and sweaty,
everything's loosened up and you can get
into like deep,
deep stretches and deep poses and,
and also like for your foot strength and
posture and balance,
all that stuff is amazing.
Amazing for your back,
strengthening your back,
your knees.
Um,
it's really good for Jujitsu fighters.
Mean Jujitsu.
People love it.
So one of the best things for Jujitsu,
because Jujitsu,
so static,
you know,
so much of it is like holding on and
trying to advance position in slowly.
And then there's these bursts of,
uh,
you know,
explosive movements.
But so much of it is just clenching and,
and yeah.
So much of it is that,
and I think you really benefit from
being able to,
you know,
in these yoga poses,
holding these poses for 30 seconds.
When you're,
your body's burning and you're,
you know,
you're,
you're having a difficult time to
standing up.
I think adding the heat component to it
too,
especially if you're a weight cutting
finder,
like getting to know your body and in
teaching it how to sweat,
right.
This last training camp was pretty
awesome with that because I got a sauna
for my,
when I got us on a while ago,
I was using a red light for healing and
I was using the sauna because I know
that you can naturally boost your,
a growth hormone if you're in that every
night and,
and help yourself before you go to
sleep.
So I was in that every night.
I tried to go in for like 45 minutes and
that was so helpful in going into the
fight week wait,
cut.
Because it was like,
I know what it feels like when it's time
to get the fuck out.
And I know what it feels like when it's
time that I'm like that sound like when
I'm dripping like crazy.
I still got another good 20 minutes of
me sitting here like this,
you know?
And,
and I think it's really hard on fighters
when they're not in a sauna or that hot
for their entire camp and then they just
expect that out of their body the day
before a fight.
Yeah.
I think you're right.
This is rolling real good benefits as
you said,
two for recovery or reducing
inflammation.
Yeah,
I thought it was hopeful.
I got a portable sauna to bring up my
fights with me.
Oh that's nice.
Is it one climb into and like just your
little head sticks out is uncomfortable
as hell cause you can't lean against
anything or it'll burn your ass in the
chair and the chair is like this little
half chair and by that point you're
like,
Oregon's are so depleted in and you're
like leaning all weird anyway.
So it was just hell.
But I mean,
it gets it off and you don't have to
leave your home.
Oh,
that's nice too.
Especially if you're doing something on
the road.
Like who was it that,
um,
somebody that somebody was fighting
somewhere and they didn't have hot water
and they couldn't make weight cause they
didn't have the,
the bathtub?
I think it was a fuck.
I'm trying to think of who it was.
Thomas have been stressful.
Yeah,
they were,
I think they were fighting in Brazil and
there was no hot water for some reason.
Like the hot water was down and they all
like,
what in the fuck?
And they couldn't,
they want.
And why not?
Not Making weight?
I don't remember who it was.
I wasn't there for that event.
But I remember thinking like,
that is one of the real problems with
doing these,
some of these gigs in the road,
you know,
you're traveling to these places and
there's no fucking hot water if there's
no sauna and no hot water.
How he's supposed to make weight.
Oh.
And it's awkward to be in a sauna with
your opponent to,
and why I fought Carina Damn.
Uh,
again,
as a 2,425,
like a few years ago,
there is Eric Anderson.
Oh,
Cheetah was very respectful.
Damn.
Yeah.
The is Brazilian.
He knows.
Yeah.
He was like,
yeah,
but we were in North Dakota and we had
to go in and the same song and it became
a competition there.
Oh my
God,
I'm not getting out.
And when she,
when she,
like there was a point,
like I'm sitting there with my coach and
I'm just like biting down here.
I don't even know how long we were in,
but it was like a hard,
it was rough.
And um,
it's Kinda,
yeah,
exactly.
Like who's going to break first?
Who's gonna go first?
And she ended up being like,
fuck it.
And she goes and she gets out and I was
like,
Oh,
you have quit in you.
And I already knew I wanted to fight.
I didn't knew I won the fight.
I was like,
I saw everything I needed to see.
We're good.
Crazy.
That's so true.
I mean,
look,
there's something to that.
I mean,
you definitely don't want to die in
there,
but there's,
there's moments when you're in the
sauna,
you know,
I have one here and there's this thing
that happens at like 30 minutes.
We were like,
what in the fuck am I doing?
Well,
you start fucking weird now you're like,
oh,
I gotta get Outta here.
It's like claustrophobia.
Like you're,
you know that if you just opened that
door,
this cold air and you're going to feel
great,
just want someone that domain just lost
someone that asks you,
okay
question.
Just hoping.
It just opens the door for a second.
Let's open a door.
Let me run out that door right there.
But that is what creates those heat
shock proteins is that your body
realizes that it's in this terrible
situation where your way overheated.
So your body starts creating these
anti-inflammatory proteins and that's
what's so good for your body.
They did a study,
I think it was in,
was it Norway?
A doctor,
Rhonda Patrick brought it up on the
podcast that they showed a 40% decrease
in mortality from all causes,
from use of daily Sauna,
40% decrease in heart attack,
stroke,
cancer,
everything across the board.
It's unbelievably good for you to use
the car.
Yeah.
It's because your body in reaction,
the the,
the response that your body has in
reaction to that extreme temperature is
just to create all these anti
inflammatory properties and that's just
so good for your body.
Inflammation is just the root of so many
different diseases and problems that we
have.
Yeah,
so do you,
what is like the temperature,
induration duration recommended for
that?
I think it's 170 degrees in,
I think 20 minutes is what they want.
They want 20 minutes at 107 degrees,
170 degrees for four,
I believe the test protocol was four
days a week.
Is that the same statistic for say like
a Red Light Sauna?
It's a good question.
They didn't use a red light's on or they
didn't use an infrared sauna.
Traditional say just use the traditional
sauna.
But the theory is that it doesn't matter
because what matters is your body
reacting to the temperature change and
that doesn't matter how it's getting to
you.
They used a regular,
like hot rock sauna.
That's what I have,
regular hot rock sauna.
But I don't think it matters.
I think what really matters is just
extreme temperature.
And there's a lot of people believe in
those infrared saunas.
I think they're better.
I don't know.
No,
I just know your body,
your body likes sauna.
Whenever I do that,
I just feel better.
Sleep all good.
She's better.
It just feels better for my brain to,
I just feel better about everything.
I just think it's just like getting your
body heat it up like that and then it
cools off.
It just chills everything out.
Just everything feels looser.
A quiet.
There's like a quiet afterwards.
Yeah.
But yeah,
it just,
everything feels like it works better,
you know?
And then when I do it on a regular
basis,
you know,
but I feel the same way about
cryotherapy when I do cryotherapy on a
regular basis to everything seems to
work better.
Yeah.
See I,
I only do cryo therapy a couple times
and it hurt my boobs like so much that
I,
and I'm,
I just,
I don't want to go all ice bath and I
mean the thing is I'll get an ice bath
and I'm really like,
I'll get in but I'm complaining the
whole way,
you know,
like not not saying one nice thing to
you or your Mama.
Like I'm getting in there and I'll do it
when I'm ready and oh man,
it's awful.
Awful.
And those cryotherapy,
things like I appreciate the speed.
I appreciate like the,
but like do you really feel that they
get through all of those layers of skin,
like down to the optimal level on your
tissue?
Well,
it's the same thing.
It's cold shock proteins.
What happens is,
I mean if they really got it through
your skin,
you'd be dead.
Okay.
They're really got through.
But the idea is that your body produces
these cold shock proteins in response to
anything that's over are under 150
degrees below zero.
That's the sweet spot.
Apparently when you hit that 150 degree
below zero,
your body produces all these massive in
antiinflammatory properties.
Cause again it thinks it's going to die.
So it's like freaking out and people
with arthritis and people with severe
autoimmune issues where they have a lot
of inflammation,
real,
real problems with their joints in their
hands.
They have huge results from cryotherapy.
And there's a bunch of people that go to
my place that um,
they say that it's really essentially
change their life.
They were just in pain all the time and
now they know all they have to do is go
there,
step in that thing for three minutes,
leave and they're going to feel better.
And they just feel looser and relaxed
and whatever their flare ups and instead
of their condition deteriorating,
they're conditioned,
improved and stabilized.
Dang.
So it's about your body in the chemical
value,
not the cold itself.
Exactly.
It's about your body freaking out.
Yeah.
Yag Go,
what does this bitch doing?
It's 150 degrees below zero.
Oh my God.
And then when you get out of there,
you feel so good.
That's what does it for me.
When I get out all my God,
I feel amazing.
It's like this rush of,
it's just the,
what's it called,
norepinephrine.
Yeah.
You're,
you have this rush of it in your brain.
It's like you just took an awesome drug.
He's feel fantastic.
I get out,
the sun feels great,
people look better.
Everything just feels better.
You know,
I do two sessions too.
I do three minutes and then I go out for
10 minutes and then I go back in for
another three minutes.
That's how many times a week.
I try to do,
depending on how many times I'd do the
sauna,
I want to do one or the other four times
a week.
So either I'm doing the sauna or I'm
doing cryo.
So you don't do both in the same day.
Some temperature manipulation.
Yeah,
four time,
four days a week.
And if I don't do that,
I do hot yoga,
which is another form of temperature
manipulation obviously cause you're 104
degrees and you know you're there for 90
minutes,
sweating it out and that it mean it's
not as hot in the room,
but your body absolutely has that same
feeling that it has inside the sauna
where you just let claustrophobic.
I gotta get the fuck out of here.
Yeah,
I'm going to try it.
I will try.
I will.
I'm gonna send you this Emoji.
Like that's how you'll know I'm there
for them.
One Sauna,
I'm good.
I sit in there and I just turn up the
jams.
Well if you look good,
the song and just stick with a sauna.
I mean I think they're both really good.
Yeah.
What if I get in the cold shower after
the sauna?
Is that count?
It was this thing.
I like doing that too.
Doing that after yoga,
especially in the winter when the water
gets real cold.
I like to get in that fucking cold
shower and just really large.
Yeah.
I feel the two of them and you know the
UFC has that set up to where they have
the Jacuzzi right next to the cold bath
that they got that cold plunge.
It's like set to below 50 degrees.
You hop in there,
freeze your ass off and then hop in the
sauna.
Apparently there's like really good
benefits to doing that back and forth
like that.
Yeah,
it was um,
the last fight out there is,
uh,
I was sitting in that hot tub and then,
cause I didn't have the sauna,
uh,
hooked up.
I just wanted to go in the hot tub and,
and then I laid on like the partition
and I had like one leg dangling in the
cold pool and one leg dangling and then
the water's really good looking,
I'm sure.
But when you're just starving and dying
and give no fucks anymore,
it's just like I'm laying there like
that Mackenzie dern was laying over
there look a little worse than me,
but it's like,
I guess,
I don't know.
What did you think?
Would she miss weight by seven pounds?
Dutch?
It's kind of crazy,
isn't it?
It's crazy because she,
like,
I was literally sitting in the locker
room with her,
like,
we're giggling at UFC two to 22 like,
because we're both like curvy,
right?
And we're sitting in the locker room
laughing about how much that shit ways,
you know,
and it's like,
well,
can you do about that?
And even if you could,
do you really want to like,
right.
I mean,
I don't hate it,
you know,
but sitting in there and I'm like
laughing about it and,
and that was what,
what was the date of that?
March 3rd and then to come down much
over,
like she got her fight right away,
announced right away,
you know,
that she was fighting me.
What was it?
[inaudible] 19th or something.
And it was just like that,
like when you have that data in mind,
I mean,
granted,
it's not me,
it's her,
it's,
I don't have her body.
I don't have her problems.
I don't have her life.
I don't,
it's,
you know,
not my,
not doesn't mean anything to me,
but to know you have a fight and it's
signed up and it's ready,
like at that point it's maintenance.
Yeah.
You know,
it's maintenance like that.
That's not even doing anything
different.
It's just maintenance.
But like these weight cuts are harder
and harder on us.
We get older.
I don't know what her body's doing.
I don't know.
Yeah.
She's,
I think she's 25.
She's young and I don't,
I don't know.
I don't know what that,
to make 115 pounds asks of her and,
and I don't know if she's on her period
or not.
I Dunno if that makes a difference to
her with me.
I always,
I always get mine the day of wayins I
have other,
I have like three other girls for other
girls that I know that it's the exact
same thing,
like the morning of made way about to go
downstairs and there's that fucker
looking at you right then.
Just like there's,
there's why I couldn't lose it last two
pounds sweet.
The John Crouch about what happened?
Cause uh,
he asked her to leave the lab.
Oh,
that was where she was at when you
asked,
did she ever say why?
She didn't say why.
He didn't say why either.
They're both playing it professional.
I don't know what happened,
but she was
long time too though,
wasn't she?
Well like,
cause when I went to go train down
there,
she,
she was already,
she was there one in the days.
Yeah.
I don't know.
I'm not sure.
But I know her dad.
He's doesn't he teach in Arizona?
Magnetite I think so.
Yeah.
I'm hurt.
Jiu Jitsu is fucking nasty though,
isn't it?
So gnarly.
Woo.
Yeah,
she's good.
We competed against each other.
Yeah.
I was beating her ass.
Well yeah.
Well it was rough.
It was rough because I,
I it was worlds,
we were both purple belts.
I think it was the open division.
So I was like,
I was heavier than her by the next
weight class.
And um,
I went to take her down.
I double leg dural big and then like
where we landed.
So if this is like the square,
we landed like right here.
And so they called it out and so they
reset us in the middle.
So no points.
Oh,
so we get in the middle because she's
Mckenzie,
Darren,
because I'm not resilient enough,
so I would,
they start us again.
I'm like,
okay,
no,
did,
I can't,
don't go near that line.
Right.
So I go and I shoot another double
picker up.
Go take her down again.
Same thing,
but like,
it's out of bounds again because it was
too close because my double is like a
tackle,
you know?
Right.
And then,
um,
so we go back in the middle and we shake
hands and we go.
So this time I go shoot,
I pick her up and I look at the ref
like,
like here.
Good.
Is this good?
Put it down here.
Yeah.
So put her down,
go to pass her guard.
And I passed.
And then,
um,
I think she had,
I sat back for a straight ankle lock and
they're like,
and they disqualified me.
What?
And they're like,
you can't have an ankle.
you can't do that as I can't do what?
And they're like,
you can't do that.
And it's in the rule books.
I'm like,
okay,
if I'm going to look in the real rule
books,
what am I looking up?
What can't I do?
Thank you.
Can't you can't do that.
You need to go,
you're disqualified.
I'm like,
tell me what I did.
And they said that I reaped the knee but
I like,
I didn't like,
I don't,
I really don't think I did.
You know?
So you think they were just juke in the
system to try to get her to win?
She's Brazilian.
I don't know.
I Dunno.
It,
it happens.
It does happen some tournaments.
Yeah.
And I mean they,
they,
they sent,
the thing is,
is like I love ib Jj of tournaments and
I want to compete in them for the rest
of my life.
Like I,
you know,
so,
but,
but yeah,
there is,
there is some themes that go on there.
Like,
there's definitely birthrights that gets
you places that like that I would really
like to have,
but at the same time,
really no,
I don't want to have been born into,
I want to make the statement of like
happier birthright.
Like I got this,
you know,
I made it to some pretty bad ass
tournaments in,
in,
you know,
just like fighting the way I fight and
trying not to give a shit about all of
that.
And like I continued to do that.
I want to do the same,
you know?
Um,
but uh,
that was,
that was a rough one for me.
Like,
I was excited about that tournament.
I trained hard for that tournament and I
think we were each other's like,
I don't remember what match into the
tournament.
It was what to be disqualified.
And I was like,
but
so what did they call specifically
reaping the need?
Don't you have to go against the joint?
I don't know.
Like,
I wish I could draw you a picture.
Show you a finger bent.
Weird.
Come up with an excuse.
We'll be,
I mean,
the first two takedowns like we weren't,
okay.
Maybe your first one,
maybe the first one we were on the line
out fine.
The second one,
like we hit the ground and then we get
it a little so,
but we were in,
you know,
and then the third one I'm being a Dick,
you know?
And I'm just like,
yeah,
here good.
You know?
And so they're like,
they gave me the points and then I pass
and they give me the points and then I
sit back for that and now I'm
disqualified.
Sounds like it is.
And I like her,
you know what I mean?
Like I like her,
her dad was at my gym teaching a seminar
at my gym in Colorado like months
earlier.
And so when the match is over and we go
and we're like standing next to them,
they're like,
sorry.
You know,
like,
did you see that so many men on
instagram of her after one day in
Liverpool?
No.
Do you know people make fun of her
accent but it's not real?
Oh,
Brazilian Jujitsu just told me that
recently.
She apparently,
I don't know.
I mean people accents or weird to begin
with.
Like why do people talk the way they
talk in the first place?
Cause the sound with the people around
them.
Geographical.
Yeah.
I mean it's,
it's weird,
but there's a video that somebody made
of Mckinsey during,
after one day in Liverpool and it's
basically her talking,
but Darren tills voice instead.
It's rough.
I'm not playing that.
Don't play a JV.
Don't even pull it up.
I will not do that to her.
But it's pretty funny.
Yeah,
because I was super confused when I
interviewed her.
Um,
when she won in the UFC,
they wanted a translator and I was like,
what are you talking about?
Like she speaks perfect English.
Like this is really bizarre.
So George Greer Gel came in with me and
uh,
he's like,
just in case she gets messed up anymore,
it's,
and like,
I didn't even question it.
I was like,
okay,
I was confused.
I'm like,
wait a minute.
I know she speaks perfect English.
Like this is ridiculous.
Raised in Arizona right now,
but she fucking speaks perfect English.
So I don't know if they were selling it,
you know?
I don't know whose idea it was.
I don't know.
I don't get it.
But the fucking Internet.
Got It.
Okay.
Maybe
crazy.
Everybody was like,
what in the fuck is happening?
I didn't question it.
I'm like,
look,
I'm just here to interviewer.
I just want her to,
I mean,
she wants to speak in Portuguese.
She wants to speak in English.
I don't give a fuck.
But I was like,
why do you need a translator?
Like that's,
that's insane.
I don't know all of that.
I don't know all that either.
You know?
She definitely speaks English really
well though.
Does it?
Is there a benefit to Brazilian?
Well,
yeah.
I mean obviously that's a huge
demographic.
And his sport huge.
Primarily the biggest other than an
American American.
Yeah.
But I'm curious if there's like a
benefit or a marketing.
Like I said,
there's or something to that would,
that would make that more,
well,
Brazilians have immense national pride,
you know,
and her being a Brazilian and the
daughter of a Brazilian Jujitsu legend
and you know,
and speaking perfect Portuguese and
English and I'm just,
I guess maybe that's the idea behind it.
I don't know.
She's
killing it though.
Like technically and with her style and
I mean like everything that she brings
to the table is,
is already good.
You know?
It's like don't fuck that up.
Don't effect of with some,
yeah.
Who knows?
Yeah.
I don't know.
You know what?
Sometimes when I get around people,
like I feel bad because like I try to be
like really empathetic and,
and when I'm around like foreigners and
like I will totally slow down my
speaking so they will get it to the
point where sometimes I think I look
condescending.
Right.
You know,
where I'm like,
I just want this conversation.
Who is easy as possible for you because
I'm already awkward and like let me help
you out.
You know?
That's a different thing,
but it's like you remember when Madonna
had a fake English accent and everybody
was like,
pitch,
you're from Brooklyn or wherever the
fuck you're from,
not from England,
and you can't do that.
Yeah.
I mean,
depending on who she's around,
I guess.
I don't know.
Fuck.
That's the thing,
like if you're around people that have
that accent,
you'll,
you will pick it up.
Yeah.
When I was a kid,
I definitely had a Boston accent,
but I heard myself talk on tv once when
I was 19 it was a Boston guy.
No,
I've got to get rid of that.
Like,
how did I pick that up so quick and my
family's all Minnesota rural,
you know?
And so when I go home,
I get that and it will stick around for
a few weeks for sure.
Especially if you drink.
Right?
Yeah.
For sure.
I'm real tired.
Yeah.
Or You have your round.
All those people.
It's like comforting
has her fucking strange,
you know,
they're,
they really are strange that the like
specific to regions,
it just shows you how people are,
you know,
southern accents and even like England,
like you have like,
like very,
very different like British accents,
which I'm sure to them sounds exactly
like,
you know,
Texas versus versus need work.
You know,
just the different twain.
Yeah.
My friend's wife is from Liverpool and
she was trying to explain scouse to me,
like the way they talk and Liverpool
versus the way they would talk and like
say London and let y'all sounded English
to me.
You might as well be Australia.
I don't get it.
I get the,
you sound different than me.
I don't get what's happening though.
I don't,
I don't get the accent until like
somebody like clue.
Like Darren tills clearly has like that
Liverpool accent.
It's so clear,
but I don't,
I still don't get it.
I don't know what it is.
You know,
you can say he's from London.
I'm like,
oh,
okay,
cool English because English is it like
that.
Or like whoever was a ringing there had
like a list,
right?
Yes.
And so then that ended up being the
people picked up as like,
was it a compliment or just how it
happened because that's how things were
like pronounced when they were being
explained.
Like,
I don't know,
maybe there's some kind of like speech
impediment that went along with every
different dialect.
And I mean that is what it is.
I mean with,
with Spain,
the,
the way they pronounce certain words is
because like some fucking king somewhere
along the line had a lisp.
Strange,
strange shit.
Did you know that a place in Brazil that
has a list also?
I forget.
Really?
Oh,
I'm not,
I'm sure there must be like different
axes in Brazil.
Right?
Brazil is fucking huge.
I mean definitely different singsong eat
type of tones,
tones.
I would say more.
Yeah.
Did you ever,
uh,
train down there?
Yeah,
I've been down there I think three
times,
four times to train to chain in the
visit.
I did.
Uh,
uh,
I wanted big old Jujitsu tournament down
there before.
Yeah.
I think it was like Brazilian nationals,
something like that.
So we,
I would go down like get fully ready to
train,
get there the day before and cut because
once you're there and then compete the
second day I was there.
So the rest of it's vacation cause it's
like once you're there,
all the food,
all of the like beach and like lazy,
like there's nothing in me that wants to
work hard as I could do.
All I want to do is just enjoy the music
and the sounds and the people in the
know how to cook down there.
Those two.
Haas Korea's holy shit is brilliant.
Brilliant.
Well you guys have them in San Diego.
They have them everywhere now.
Thank God.
But a style of cooking is the best.
Those skewers oversight over fire.
That's what I'm talking about.
Meat over fire.
That's it.
And then the little sauces,
like the creations,
just oil and lime and,
and seasonings.
So good.
Talking to more,
you won't make,
wait.
Oh my God.
I'll always make,
wait,
I'm just a little bit more dead than
others.
Why is cap cut off her leg?
We just did two and a half hours.
Crazy time just flew by.
Right.
So,
um,
good luck.
Good luck in.
I'm in Boise.
I'm looking forward to seeing you fight.
Very excited and I'm glad we finally got
a chance to do this.
And,
uh,
it's,
is it causing gatto w MMA on twitter?
What is your,
do you know it?
She's got to check her phone.
I know how to send stuff out,
but I don't know how a lot of what it
is.
Uh,
it is Alpha Katz and Co.
Yep.
At Cat Zingano.
And then on my instagram,
it's Alpha Cat Zingano and then
facebook.
It's cat Zingano,
MMA fighter.
Cason Ghana.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
I'm glad we finally did this.
Yeah.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
Bye everybody.