Okay.
And we live John,
Donna her.
Thank you very much sir.
Very nice to see you.
It's my pleasure.
Joe.
Thank you for having me here.
It's nice to be with a fellow fanny pack
proponent as well and a now you have one
of the beautiful higher primate leather
bags like that.
Huh?
Joe Rogan has just given me one of the
most beautiful fanny pics than I've ever
seen in my life.
Um,
I wear a very cheap fanny pack and this,
this is a thing of beauty.
I was just telling Joe About my student
Gordon Ryan was recently given a Gucci
Fanny Pack.
It's literally the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen in my life.
When he wears it around me,
I get insanely jealous and which you buy
one of those.
It's like an $800 just on the principal.
Just on principle.
I can't buy an $800 fanny pack,
but I could definitely step Gordon Ryan
in the back with a knife and steal it
from and blamed it on Nicky Ryan.
I could do that.
Easily blame on his brother.
Absolutely.
Great TV series.
The fanny pack is making a comeback.
It's a slow comeback that a lot of
people are reluctant to join there.
They're scared.
They,
they worry about their position in the
sexual food chain and with good reason,
by the way,
I don't know why.
I feel like anybody that won't fuck you
because you have a fanny pack.
You don't want to fuck them.
They're too much work.
Strong point.
Essentially.
It's always a battle of a appearance
versus function.
Yeah.
Um,
fanny,
pex cold,
very,
very low on a parents,
but very high on function.
I feel like that one bucks,
the trend.
I think you're right between this and
the Gucci,
we've got something going on yet.
There's a video that I put up the other
day of my,
uh,
archery game is techno hunt thing,
which is this big crazy elaborate thing.
I got more comments on the fact that I
was wearing a fanny pack in the video
than anything.
Were they positive or negative comments?
Negative.
Yeah,
but that's my experience.
But that's just the internet.
The Internet is,
the Internet is extremely angry.
That's the first thing you learned about
the Internet.
They you can,
you could literally save a baby's life,
eh,
from and the 80% of the Internet we'll
call you an asshole for doing so.
It's a,
it doesn't matter what you do at the
Internet is very angry.
Well,
what the Internet is is it shows what
people are like when there's no social
cues.
When they're not in front of you,
they don't have to deal with like
looking you in the eye and what little
weird little hidden demons of jealousy
and anger and resentment and it's a
pretty sad stories in it if that's what
we're really like.
It's a,
it's not looking good for the human
rights.
The kind of people that comment in
general and what it shows you is that
99% of what we call human goodness and
politeness really comes out of fear of
consequences.
There's a lot of that for sure because
there's no consequences when you talk on
the line,
but I think it's the quality of the
people that are making those kinds of
comments.
Like I would say like if you look at
Youtube comments like Michael Jordan is
not leaving
youtube comments.
The people that leave Youtube Commons
and bitch and complain about things,
usually everything's not going so
fantastic in their own life.
But they have this forum now when they
feel like,
you know,
if there's a video that has 3 million
downloads,
they also are on that video.
They are at the,
they're there in the comments section.
You go to them,
they're a part of that unqualified.
No one asked him to be there.
Literally all you have to do is make an
account.
No one has to know anything about your
education,
the way your mind works,
what you've done with your life,
what mistakes you've made doesn't
matter.
You are old.
Fuck 66 and that's your name and you can
say whatever you want and you'll,
your,
your comments are right there with
everything else.
It's fascinating to watch.
It's very gal tarian but in a lot of
ways it's also,
it's like,
boy,
um,
I don't know if that's the best way
to get your information.
Yeah,
I think there's a lot of truth to that.
Yeah.
So John,
um,
you are
one of the most fascinating characters
in the world of Jujitsu and the world of
martial arts.
And for people who are not aware of your
background,
you started out,
correct me if I'm wrong,
um,
a philosophy student that's great days
and you were working as a bouncer and
you were jacked,
right?
You're a power lifter at the time.
Yes.
And you wanted to figure out a way to
defend yourself.
Um,
it wasn't really a question of wanting
to figure out.
It was,
it was,
um,
uh,
a pretty simple design that I had when I
grew up in New Zealand.
Martial arts was almost entirely based
around,
uh,
striking pro is,
you'll back me up on this joke.
Um,
we're similar age.
Uh,
when we grew up,
uh,
the,
it's no exaggeration to say that the
study of martial arts in English
speaking countries,
North America,
western Europe,
et Cetera,
was absolutely dominated by the striking
odds.
And,
um,
if you ask the average person who was
the best fighter in the world,
they would typically say whoever was the
best boxer in the world.
So in the 1980s,
Mike Tyson wasn't just the best boxer in
the world.
He was the best fighter in the world.
People always equated prowess and
fighting with the ability to strike.
Um,
I grew up in that time period.
And so,
um,
I grew up doing a study setting,
kickboxing as a,
as a teenager in New Zealand.
I came to United States and for the
first time,
there's no wrestling culture in my
country.
New Zealand has no wrestling culture.
It's one of the few countries that has
no indigenous raceland culture.
There's,
there were,
but it was kind of lost in the sands of
time.
Um,
when I grew up,
wrestling was something I saw once every
four years at the Olympics on TV.
And,
um,
I didn't even associate it with
fighting,
to be honest with you.
I disorders these strange sport with two
guys tackled each other.
And,
um,
so I came to the United States and I was
working as a bouncer.
Um,
America has much,
much more of a wrestling culture in it.
In,
in New Zealand,
when I grew up,
when you fought,
you were expected to fight with fists.
And if it went to the ground,
the two guys stood up and there was in
fighting.
You stood up and he fought like a man.
That was the idea.
And,
um,
uh,
in the United States when I was
bouncing,
I was absolutely shocked and impressed
by the prowess of judo players and
wrestlers in street fighting,
working as a bounce.
I worked alongside them and I was
massively impressed.
What year was this?
This is in the early 1990s.
I ride the United States in 1991.
Um,
so I started working late night,
a late 1991,
um,
in New York City.
Um,
New York is a very,
very,
very different city back then.
It's,
it's like,
uh,
um,
it's almost like two different cities
from what it is to be amazing how much
it's checked.
There's a transformation is night and
day.
It's become like a giant Tgi Fridays now
is,
that's pretty much what I did.
To give you an example.
Uh,
I used to live on West End Avenue on the
upper west side.
When I would come home from working in
nightclubs at five 30 in the morning to
go to sleep,
there would be large numbers of street
walking prostitutes on my block,
my avenue,
if that,
if you saw even a single street walking
prostitute,
and that area today would be front page
news of the New York Times,
it would be so shocking,
so completely out of people's mouth.
And it would literally just people's
minds score is the best example.
I'm square is an extreme example because
times square used to be all CD peep
shows,
nothing but cd peep shows.
Now it's like Guy Fieri restaurants.
It's all television.
So the transformation is huge.
So that was the New York that I went
into and uh,
it was a,
it was a violent New York.
Uh,
1991 I believe was the year with the
highest murder rate in recorded history
of New York City.
So,
um,
it was a very,
very different New York City.
It's not what you see today.
So I came into this environment,
I saw all these people were incredibly
adept and,
and they were using grant,
linkedin,
nick to do to.
So this impressed me a lot.
Um,
at,
uh,
shortly after that time,
was always working.
Um,
I started to hear,
talk about this show,
this ultimate fighting show.
And there was this Brazilian guy who had
beaten everyone.
He was wrestling people and strangling
them and locking their arms,
things like desk,
things that I'd never heard of.
So I,
I,
I'd heard this and um,
uh,
one day I was teaching at Columbia
University in a close friend of mine who
was also in the phd program,
came into my office.
It was office hours and he said,
John,
you know,
I know you work as a balance them and I
know,
uh,
you look at night and,
um,
I started doing this,
this martial art,
it's called Brazilian Jujitsu and uh,
it's mostly fall on the ground.
I remember you said most of the flights
you get into people who put down on the
ground and they wrestle.
And,
uh,
I was wondering if you would be
interested in doing it.
And I was like Brazilian Jiu Jitsu and
yet I never associated marshawn's with
Brazil for me,
martial arts,
you know,
Japan,
Korea,
Brazil,
like what do they got capital wearing,
you know?
Right.
Who is this guy?
So I'm like Brazilian Jujitsu.
It isn't you to see like Japanese,
like what does it,
isn't it like a contradiction of terms
like Brazil,
Jujitsu?
Um,
so this,
at the time I was around 230 pounds and
this guy was,
couldn't be more than 140 and he'd only
been training two weeks.
So,
um,
he goes to me,
you know,
we go in the ground and,
and we wrestle on the ground and I was
like,
okay,
let me put you in a headlock and let's
see what you can do.
So I shut the door of the office,
I cleared out the furniture,
chat support,
get on the ground.
Now.
Um,
I had the only thing I knew how to do on
the ground in those,
this was headlock be run.
And I,
you know,
I was a strong guy.
It pretty nicely.
Headlock and I'm,
so I grabbed my poor little friend and,
and throttle them with,
uh,
basically,
kids get time,
may type headlock.
And um,
uh,
to my shock and horror,
he started slipping around behind me and
started holding hotter and hotter.
And then about two minutes when guy,
and I really had no real control over
him and he was starting to get around
behind me.
Now I didn't know back attacks where I
had complete naive at the,
on the ground,
but I could feel something bad was
happening.
Someone getting behind you.
It never a good thing in a fight.
And,
uh,
I was getting tired,
my arms were getting tired,
I had no control of the guy.
And finally he slept at night to stand
up and run away.
And I said,
are you kidding me?
I'm twice your size.
You've been training to goddamn weeks.
And,
and if this was a real fight,
he would have got away from it.
And I'm tired.
That's not good.
And I was just saying,
if he did this in two weeks,
what could you do?
Some training?
So I was fascinated.
I went down,
um,
got completely destroyed on my first
day.
Um,
or it was hilarious.
Who was there on this first thing?
Matt Serra was the most,
uh,
he was a blue belt at the time.
Um,
so even on that first day you met people
that would become very important in your
life later on.
And I vowed to the moon and the stars
that I would at least become competent
and the game I couldn't live with the
idea that I was incompetent at an
important element of fighting.
I didn't want to be a world champ.
I didn't worry.
I just want to be competent and um,
uh,
I believe that would make my bouncing
work significantly easier.
That was absolutely true.
Um,
within a very,
very short period of time,
balancing got massively easier for me.
Um,
I've bought,
you know,
you always get this cliched Jujitsu
saves.
Judas was saved my life.
How many people need to hear people say
that all the time?
Well,
I can think of without any question.
There are four times in my life that
Jujitsu actually did save my life
balance.
I can say that with complete honesty.
Um,
uh,
it's a cliche for most people.
It for me,
it's,
it did happen.
Um,
so it made a massive difference,
but I still saw it as it was interesting
and something I just wanted to gain
competence in that fundamentally
changed.
This is really,
at that point I wanted to finish my phd
and become a professor.
That's what was my original goal when I
came to United States.
Um,
but things started to change when,
uh,
the three senior students at the hands
of Gracie Academy,
he caught all made a met Sarah and hold
Rio.
Gracie all went their separate ways.
They had to go out and start their own
schools and Hindou was busy fighting
professionally,
Japan,
so he couldn't be at the academy all the
time.
And he came to and he said,
John,
you're going to have to be a teacher.
Like there's no one else.
And how long have you been Tryna,
uh,
I believe if I go to the,
it was around four years.
I believe I was a purple belt when I
first started teaching at hands.
Those,
um,
don't quote me on that,
but I'll have to go back and check.
But I believe that's,
and why did he come to you?
Um,
probably because he felt sorry for me.
I don't know.
Um,
uh,
I was there a lot and,
um,
I think maybe he saw some enthusiasm
while you are obsessed.
Right?
And like you were there daily.
Yeah.
That became much more so when I become a
teacher because I saw that,
okay,
I'm filling big shoes here.
You must remember all three of those
names that I just mentioned.
All three were world champions.
Okay.
These were good,
good people.
And for that time they were,
they would kill us.
And here I am a phd student.
Now I've got to fill in these shoes.
So I was like,
I've got to get serious about this.
So I made a commitment to,
um,
to becoming the best possible teacher I
could.
Now you must remember I went in as a
teacher.
That was my first assignment.
And,
um,
so I decided my primary focus in Jujitsu
would be upon teaching.
And uh,
uh,
fortunate I came from an academic
background.
I had many brilliant,
brilliant professors coming through the
philosophy programs,
both in New Zealand and the United
States.
Um,
Columbia University had a fantastic PhD
program.
Uh,
so I was very,
uh,
experience and the art of teaching,
but in an academic context.
And I thought maybe this has given me,
faith has given me this angle where I
can use an academic approach to teaching
in a sports environment.
And that has really become one of the
patterns of my approach to teaching a
Jujitsu.
So this is,
uh,
in the 90s and you are a purple belt at
the time.
When did you develop this leg lock
system that has become so legendary?
So for people,
for the uninitiated that have never
heard of you or understand what we're
talking about here,
for the longest time,
Jujitsu was primarily attacks on the
arms and the neck.
That was pretty much it.
And there were known attacks on the
legs,
but they were frowned upon.
Yes.
Uh,
something happened you,
you got to see some of those techniques
in mma,
you got to see some heel,
occasionally foot locks.
There's a few guys are lawsky pulled off
a a foot lock in the UFC against Tim.
Sylvia has a few guys that were pulling
these off.
This is pre,
some are Paul Harris,
but you all of a sudden came along with
this very effective system that there
was rumblings many years ago about this
where a lot of people were talking about
it and a lot of people were saying that,
you know,
John Danaher has this insane leg lock
system and then you started developing
all these chat for people don't know the
top grapplers in the ward.
There's a,
there's a lot of top grapplers in the
world.
Jujitsu is incredibly competitive,
but you're recognized as being one of
the premiere coaches of the most
promising young people like Gordon Ryan,
who you're talking about before,
who is in Abu Dhabi champion,
Garry Tonin,
Nikki Ryan,
Eddie Cummings.
You have an incredible crew of world
class strangle artists who are also
known to be some of the very best leg
lockers in the world.
So what happened?
How did that,
how did that all take place?
Um,
let's go through,
uh,
we should talk about the history of,
Yep.
Let,
let,
let Habu you've actually asked about six
different questions.
Sorry.
It's good,
but we can answer them in turn.
So let's go,
let's the first question.
Your first question was a historical
question.
How,
how did it happen?
Yeah.
Um,
first off,
um,
there was nothing in my early,
uh,
learnings,
of,
of Jujitsu,
which suggested leg logs.
Nothing.
Okay.
Um,
hinder would teach.
By the way,
I should say my,
my,
my sensei throughout my entire career
has been hindered.
Gracie,
um,
I never left.
He ends up,
he taught me from white belt to black
belt and I never left as academy.
I'm the only one of his students who
stayed with them from white belt to
black belt and never left.
Um,
uh,
so hence it would teach leg,
lungs,
but it was taught in always the same
fashion that everyone else that here's a
move has a fig of auto.
Here's a heel hook,
isn't achilles lock.
Um,
so the,
the moves themselves when no one.
Okay.
They,
they were there.
They were in existence.
It wasn't like I invented he hawks or
something like that.
That's the idea.
Um,
but they weren't emphasized.
uh,
very,
very uh,
talented and um,
uh,
influential figure in my life was a guy
that I only knew for three days.
Now that sounds,
that sounds crazy,
right?
How can you learn something from someone
in three days?
Well,
actually the influence he had occurred
in three minutes.
I'm a big believer in the idea that
someone can come into your life for a
very short period of time and have a
massive influence.
I truly believe that in my case it was a
great American graphical dean list.
Dean lister was invited by Matt Serra to
come to the Hansa Gracie Academy,
I believe,
don't quote me on this,
but I believe dean was a brown butter at
the time.
I'm pretty sure matt was a brown,
but at the time too.
And um,
I bought him in for around three days
and he trained mostly with Matt Serra
and preparation for a grappling
tournament.
If I,
if I remember correctly now,
Dean was one,
mostly in those days for his Achilles
lock.
It later on he would become a heel hook
specialists.
But in those days it was mostly an
Achilles lock.
And he came to the academy role with
some people and he did a,
he was doing a logs and getting some
success.
Um,
you know,
went both ways.
I mean,
but um,
uh,
he,
he couldn't really get his stuff to work
on Matt Serra.
Matt Serra could get his stuff to work
on him,
but um,
uh,
he was doing something which was
unusual.
And so I talked with them just briefly
after clients and I said,
you know,
it's interesting what you're doing with
these achilles lungs cause I don't
really do that at all.
It's not something I do.
And he said one sentence,
which completely changed my outlook.
He cause why would you ignore 50% of the
human body?
One sentence,
why would you ignore 50% of the human
body?
And I looked and I was like,
I don't know why,
why would you?
It makes no sense and we never talked
again.
And then he went back to California.
We don't want to become too,
too time adcc champion mostly with Laila
lungs.
Um,
but what Dean gave me was not technique,
didn't show me a single technique,
but he gave me at point of view as you
give a man a point of view,
you can change them.
Okay,
you can,
we can work from there.
That was the influence.
And uh,
my Sensei Henzel Gracie was an
extremely,
uh,
liberal minded professor of Jujitsu.
He would let us do whatever we wanted.
Okay.
He wasn't one of those guys,
you know,
no one in my academy studying lake
walks.
He was never like that.
He was,
he would allow students to go in any
direction they wanted,
provided they could prove it was
effective.
Um,
so I started studying leg locks and
that's where I'm going to come to the
second question,
which you asked,
which is why did lake walls have such a
bad reputation?
And you'd,
it says curious,
right?
We don't think about this way about our
mugs.
I'm going to run through the main
criticisms and your,
you'll be my witness on this jury.
I'm sure you've heard the same criticism
a thousand times.
You would always hear people refer to
leg locks in the following way first.
The first criticism level too dangerous.
Okay.
If you,
if you allow people to do leg walks,
everyone would be entered in a week and
units would be impossible.
So that was the first quarter than we
would always hear.
The second great criticism is they
didn't work.
Okay.
Um,
you might be to tap out a white belt
with a heel hook,
but if you are a world championship
level,
you never got to tap anybody that didn't
work at high levels.
That by itself,
those two criticisms seemed to go in
opposite directions.
If they're,
if they're really that dangerous but
they don't work,
how does that,
how do those through Gel,
they are either incredibly dangerous to
the point where they can't be practice
or they don't work that they did.
The two arguments contradict each other.
Then you hear other arguments that they
were positionally unsound that if you
were in top position
and you went for a leg lock,
you would lose position and that was his
Austin.
Okay.
That's a criticism with no merit because
it that Chris St criticism applies to
guillotines on bonds,
et cetera.
You can be mounted on someone,
go for an arm lock in the loose position
ended up on bottom,
but no one criticizes ambos.
Um,
so as I went through the reasons why
people criticized leg logging,
none of them really made sense.
So I started asking myself,
well,
often the reasons people give as opposed
to what the real reasons are a very
different.
And the more I thought about it,
the more I thought the real reason
people donate leg,
lungs runs much deeper than that.
Let's understand Jujitsu for what it is.
Jujitsu is a systems based approach to
fighting.
Okay?
What is the system of Brazilian Jiu
Jitsu?
While it can be described in a few
different ways,
I'm going to give you one rendition
which is pretty simple and will resonate
with most of your listeners.
Jujitsu is a system based around four
distinct steps.
You can add steps,
you can subtract steps,
but the,
the rendition I'm going to give you now
is probably probably the most widely
known.
Okay.
Let's say a friend of yours asked for
advice on fighting.
He knows you're a Brazilian Jiu Jitsu
expert.
You're a black belt in Brazilian
Jujitsu.
And he said to me,
Joe Rogan,
tell me I didn't know anything.
I want to fight someone else using your
procedures.
What are the steps?
It was only just said,
what's the system that,
uh,
what is a system that had a spouses?
You're going to see always that step
number one is take your opponent to the
ground.
Okay?
Why was he,
why do you think the ground is so
special?
Why did rezone Cios who choose the
ground as step number one of its system,
why do you think,
well,
it all came out of judo,
right?
So Brazilian Jujitsu took the effective
submission techniques of judo and then
just refine them.
That's these dog.
The reason,
what's the,
what's the mechanical physical reason?
Because you can control someone on the
ground far better,
right?
You can control people.
Loma Chenko control suite from the
standing position with angle and
distance is different ways to control
people.
Yes.
In boxing,
if you only are boxing,
but why the ground?
Why did they choose the ground?
What's the mechanical reason?
What happens when you take a human being
to the ground while there's a whole
barrier behind them that you can press
them against?
What about if you're in bottom position?
While you could use that barrier as
leverage?
True,
but there's something that occurs when
someone goes down to the ground.
It's something big that you may be
missing here.
What am I missing?
What's the most explosive event and the
Olympic Games?
The the event that probably requires
more transfer of energy and development
of kinetic energy than any other.
There's a bunch you name,
but one of them for me is always going
to be the javelin throw.
The javelin throw involves a full
powered sprint,
a jump,
a massive explosive tuning of both hips
and shoulders and a throw.
All the quintessential explosive
elements of the human body are involved
in the javelin throw probably to a
greater degree than any other Olympic
event and as a result,
people can throw a javelin 80 90 meters.
What would happen if you took those same
javelin throwers and made them perform
the same event on the knees?
Wouldn't be so good.
They probably couldn't throw it more
than 10 meters.
Okay,
and what's changed?
The closer they get to the ground,
the less they can employ explosive
force.
What's the first thing cowboys do when
they go to brand is steer.
Take it down.
Yeah.
They lock up into lakes and they put it
down on the ground.
Nobody tries to brand as standing.
Still,
you're going to get killed because it
can employ explosive dynamic movement to
hurt you.
You put them on the ground.
Dynamic explosive movement is massively
curtailed.
It takes away the single riskiest
element of fighting,
which is quick dynamic movement that can
generate kinetic energy.
So step number one,
it was going to do it so it was get it
to the ground.
It's inherently safer.
Less things can go catastrophic.
Lee,
wrong on the ground and in the standing
position.
What step number two?
Secure.
Dominant position control.
Control.
Too vague.
There's many ways to control people.
There's a definite step.
You've just taken the guy down.
What's your first thing and was on
units?
Yeah.
Well,
the first thing I would try to do is get
to a dominant position.
What do you mean by that?
Be My pass to side control.
Try to match it.
You just sounds it.
It right.
Then get past his legs,
his legs.
Why legs are strong.
I carry you around.
You could hold a person in position.
They,
they're very good defensively.
They dangerous.
Too dangerous.
Okay.
If I end up inside your legs,
if you're a skilled,
juicy play can unlock me.
Can Lake Logan,
we can strangle me.
Even if you were an untrained,
funny,
you could up kick me.
Right.
Mania man has been knocked out by an
upkick.
Even an untutored guy conforming up.
Get sure lakes are dangerous.
So step number two is get pasta.
Those dangerous lakes.
What state number three?
Go for submission.
No,
he must be a 10th planet backbone.
So I hate to throw that in some rigid
step number three.
Joe,
you're failing on pass.
Okay,
I pass the legs.
Well.
Um,
I'm going to try to control.
I'm going to try to either a mount or
like I said,
side control.
You're on the right track trying to work
your way through a hierarchy of
positions.
Yes.
You got to go to neon belly.
You're going to go so I can draw.
You're going to transition to mount.
You going to transition to ray?
Depending upon
my game.
Yeah.
This is sequence of pins.
Once you get past your opponent's legs
and Jujitsu encourages you to go through
those various pins.
If you look at the sport of Jiu Jitsu,
the pins score different amounts of
points.
Neon belly scores,
a certain amount.
Mount position.
School is more ray mountain school is
more.
Why you have a wonder about then why do
we score the pins of Jujitsu
differently?
Well,
there's more available from rear mount.
Of course you have a,
you can of course,
you can tack the neck.
You can also attack the arms.
You,
you have a positional advantage where
you can't be attacked your,
you're behind them,
so it's one of the most superior
positions to achieve.
Very good.
What about the Mount Mount?
When the striking involves phenomenal.
Um,
when you just put your finger on it
right there,
Joe,
every one of the pins,
if you did soon,
the value of it is measured by your
potential to strike your opponent on the
ground.
Okay?
That's why their school more your own
belly scores more.
It's I control because from distance of
neon belly you can strike with more
power.
It's inherently unstable,
however,
so at scores less than mount,
which is inherently more stable and
office the same punching platform.
Step number three of Judas who was to
work your way through a hierarchy of
pins with a pins,
a graded in value according to your
ability to strike with a fixed on the
ground.
So far,
so far we've got three elements in the
system of Jujitsu.
Step number one,
get to fight down to the ground were
explosive.
Kinetic energy is less likely to do the
valid by a dangerous opponent.
Step number two,
get past this dangerous legs.
Step number three,
work your way through this hierarchy of
pins with the pins are understood in
terms of the potential to harm your
opponent with strikes on the floor.
What step number four?
Step number four is try to secure a
position where you can submit them.
You've already got the position.
So what's that number four attack with a
submission.
Correct.
So we've just described a zoned unit.
So it's a four step system.
It's beautiful,
it's elegant and it's deadly effective.
Step number one,
take the fight to the ground.
Take away the danger of explosive
kinetic energy.
Step number two,
get past as dangerous lakes.
Step number three,
work your way through a hierarchy of
pins.
Each one graded upon your ability to
harm your opponent with strikes on the
ground and set up step number four
submissions.
And now the question that needs to be
asked with a lake lungs fit into that
system
and where do they fit in?
They don't allow,
they don't.
They don't.
Traditionally leg walks fit into the
system in only one way.
When the system has failed,
when the system's not working and you
can't take your opponent down,
you can't pass his God.
You can't maintain a dominant position
and you can't get the regular
submissions to work.
Fuck it.
Try a leg lock.
Okay.
Yeah.
That's what we're seeing.
Lake logs was seen for generations as a
signal of failure.
When you couldn't get the system to
work,
you had to resort to leg logs.
It meant you were a bad,
you did sue player.
He couldn't impose the fundamental
system of Jujitsu and so you chicken
down and you went to lake lungs.
That's why they were despised.
Mm.
That was the real reason why for
generations,
lake logs were dismissed.
You don't think it was because so many
people were injured by them that they
were absolutely not.
People get injured.
The worst injuries in Jiu Jitsu don't
come from submission holds the worst
injuries,
Jujitsu come from falling bodyweight.
Yeah,
and people jumped.
God,
when people accidentally poorly
performed takedowns.
That's where you see catastrophic
injuries send units is we sued career
ending injuries,
the joint locks of missions.
You're out for a week,
two weeks,
you know,
catastrophic injuries.
Um,
as I see it go on Youtube and put in
God,
Paul gone wrong.
You'll see catastrophic injuries.
You see career ending injuries there.
You're not going to see from Aamaz he'll
hoax,
et cetera.
You'll see people getting hurt,
but it's a contact sport you expect
then.
Okay.
Um,
no,
there's a,
a very simple elegant system.
Brazilian Jiu Jitsu.
We just saw one rendition of it,
the four step approach and you clearly
see leg locks don't fit comfortably into
that system.
What I did is I tried to find an avenue
with,
I could come in and the results were
surprising.
The first thing is al forced it.
Rendition of you did.
Sue looked at Jujitsu from top position
where we took our opponent down to the
ground and we were on top of them.
But my study,
if you did,
so he didn't start from top position
started from bottom position.
If you look at my students in
competition,
you will notice that around 80% of the
entries into lake logs come from bottom
position or with their opponent behind
them.
In other words from water,
supposedly inferior positions.
So for me it was never a question of
losing position when I went for the logs
because I was already underneath my
opponent.
I started underneath how can I end up on
born by going fairly,
I'm already on board them.
So most of my early work in Lagos was
how to get into leg and disadvantageous
positions from underneath or when
someone is behind me.
So I never have felt this problem.
Okay,
I'm,
I'm going to lose position if I go for
like long.
So I could still play a conventional
Jujitsu game and have a very,
very strong leg or can you,
that was the first avenue of leg
locking,
but things became more interesting when
I got further into the leg lock game and
I started to realize that as you add
lake logs into the game,
you change the very nature of the sport.
If you look at Jujitsu as it's
ordinarily practiced,
it's a single direction game.
If someone is in front of me and I'm
standing over them,
Jujitsu is all about movement from the
legs towards the head.
I'm supposed to pass the guard,
worked my way up to chase the chase
contact and get my head next to their
head,
either in front of them or behind them,
either mounted or remounted.
So did you,
did so always goes in one direction.
If you were to get stopped or you lose
position,
you just start the process over again.
It's a monodirectional sport.
It always goes from the legs to the
head.
Once you start adding leg walks into the
game,
Jujitsu becomes a two directional sport
where you can go from the head down to
the legs.
You can go in both directions.
So if I'm passing someone's guard and I
simply can't do it,
I can fall back and go back into the
legs.
If I'm site control on someone and they
start to recompose the god,
I can fall back into the legs.
I'm going from the upper body down to
the lower body.
Traditional chiefs who always goes from
the lower body directionally up to the
upper body.
So ended up head to head with your
opponent.
But once you start adding league logs,
did you just see for the first time
becomes a two directional score instead
of a one directional sport.
And you can play your opponent's
reactions between the threat of lower
body and upper body in ways it opens up
submissions so much more easily than the
traditional game.
So if I take you back to the moment
where Dean Lester says to you,
why would you ignore 50% of the human
body?
You go back and think about this and
what is your next step?
Do you just start looking at students
and looking at what you're teaching and
analyzing positions and you're,
you're still rolling at the time.
Correct.
Um,
the first thing that I started to look
at it as,
okay,
who out there is doing a good job of leg
walking and the owner starts or was
everyone went,
a lot of people,
what you would see is random success
with leg,
lungs.
You'd see a guy wins a match.
Here we got wins a match there.
Um,
uh,
most of the imminent leg lock is of that
generation are actually coming out of
Japan.
You'd have people like Romina Sato had a
decent,
he'll hook for that time.
I'm an Ra,
I'm an Ra.
That was a little bit preliminary.
The mnr came slightly after solder.
They,
they,
they fought each other and grappling
matches.
A couple of,
one was younger than the other.
Um,
uh,
but,
you know,
they had some success,
I believe even soccer finished newton
with a knee bar.
So the knowledge was there.
Um,
but there was nothing systematic about
it.
There was,
there wasn't,
there weren't people who were coming out
and just systematically finishing people
with one move.
Okay.
Um,
uh,
so there wasn't much in terms of people
to study.
So the first thing I started to ask is,
well,
what is the,
what is the nature of leg lock in what,
um,
if it's,
uh,
it seems to have some problems
associated with it.
It's not as controlling as the
traditional methods of Jujitsu.
That was the,
really the keyword there.
Control on Cam.
Why do people favor things that rain
naked,
strangled so much?
Because it's such a controlling position
where amount as an incredibly
controlling position.
Why do people favor things like cardiac?
Tommy,
the they,
um,
triangle because this too is a very
inherently controlling position.
All the most high percentage,
uh,
finishing holes in injured,
it's who all have control as their
dominant feature.
Okay?
It's hot.
People were going to,
as a result,
one person can continue to use the same
move that illogically of success,
um,
uh,
over time against the wide array of
opponents.
So everything I,
every question I asked ultimately always
came back to control.
And the one thing you would see with
regards to the use of lake logs in the
late 1990s and early two thousands was a
lack of control.
So all of my studies and immediately
went to the notion of control.
Now there are many forms of leg lock,
but the ones that interest me the most
always come out of what the Japanese
call mushy go.
Rami,
Asha groms had generic term.
It just means tangled legs.
Okay?
There are many different forms of ashy
growing ashy.
Grameen is a mechanism by which I can
use to have my legs to control my
opponents legs and hips.
Oops.
When I started to do was make a deep
study of this notion of ashy grammy.
How am I going to use my legs to control
the real estate between my opponent's
knee and his hips?
Preferably on both sides?
Probably the single biggest cliche that
you'll hear about Jujitsu is it its
position before submission.
At the time I was primary interest in
the idea of control before submission
control is a much deeper and wider
concept.
Then the basic points,
structure based positional position for
submission model a of Jujitsu.
It is many ways to control.
People have very little to do with with
position.
For example,
ashy rom itself scores nothing and
Jujitsu but done well.
It can control an opponent just as well
as rare mount can.
So I started to see that there are many
forms of control that went outside of
the traditional basic positional
hierarchy of resigned you to sue Washi.
He was one of them.
Probably the single greatest key in the
development of my leg lock system.
Again came from a simple realization
that the greatest mistake that people
had made in lake log work prior to the
arrival of the squad was it.
They made no distinction between the
mechanism of breaking and the mechanism
of control she go,
Rami was the mechanism of control.
The lock itself,
whether it be a heel hook and Achilles
lock,
a figure for a toe hold.
That was the mechanism of braking.
If you watch 99% of the people out there
who claim to be experts in leg locking,
they don't distinguish between the two.
They see,
for example,
he'll hooking as a single skill.
There's the lock on the legs,
the ashy grammy or whatever term they
use for it,
and the lock itself.
They're not distinguished.
That taught is a single skill.
You can't differentiate the ashy grammy
and the lock and you'll see people
teaching in this manner.
What I did was to destroy,
only distinguished between the two so
that my students could all hold an ashy
grammy position and switched from one
now grommet to another and hope people
for extended periods of time and inhibit
movement.
If I can inhibit movement for long
periods of time,
I can break you at will.
I can take my time when I come to break
you because the control is there.
The control is prime.
To break a second,
the most people is just trolling the
ashy grameen immediately go for the law.
They don't even have so much.
The ashy grammy is described as part of
the heel hook.
They don't distinguish between the two.
Once I made that realization in the
early two thousands,
that's when the ball started rolling.
That's when,
um,
uh,
a significant amount of progress was
made.
Um,
I would say that you'll question was an
interesting one.
Okay.
You had the inside list.
They gave you the insight.
What was the,
what started you going for it was the
making first a critical distinction
between control and submission and the
case of leg logging between the
mechanism of control or Shiga Rami and
the mechanism a breaking,
which is the lock itself.
In my case,
the hug.
Oh really good example of this is how
effective it's been implemented by your
students against real world class
presents Jiu and competitors who don't
use these methods like a good one is
Gordon Ryan versus Cyborg Cyborg who is
a fucking beast of a man and just a
physical specimen.
A real freak and is known for his
Tornado Guard is,
you know,
is no stranger to leg locks,
is no stranger to any of the positions
of Nogi or gay Jujitsu.
But when I watched Gordon wrap him up
and control him and before he got the
submission,
you could see Cyborg look befuddled.
Yeah.
He loses the match was over roughly 30
seconds before the submission was
applied.
Yeah,
he was just trying to figure out a way
out of it and just was no way to go.
Is it terrifying position to be in for a
real world class Brazilian jujitsu black
belt,
like Cyborg when you watch that,
that match.
I was like,
this is stunning because Gordon is what,
21 years,
which is amazing and Cyborgs in his
thirties.
Right?
I think Cyborg has been a blight belt
many,
many years longer than Gordon is even
being doing Jujitsu.
He's one of the best guys in the world.
And when you,
you look at how well Gordon Dismantle
Tim on the ground using the strategy
that you just described it,
just see if we could find that.
Actually see if he can find Gordon Ryan
versus uh,
his,
his actual name is,
I believe you pronounce it a brew.
How do you do it's the carto approved.
He caught,
oh,
Cybil.
Abreu.
Yeah,
just a lot of cyborgs in the Jiu Jitsu
world.
There's a male Cyborg and MMA.
There's a female Cyborg,
I think Cyborg and pitfalls.
So we're watching it here now and you
see Cyborg who's this fucking tank of a
man and Gordon Ryan who's quite a
physical specimen himself,
but much younger guy.
It hasn't.
How long has John Gordon Been Doing
Jujitsu?
I believe it's between six and a half
and seven years total now.
That's fucking crazy.
And,
and immediately he dives under,
gets low
using butterfly guard.
And so his,
what he's trying to do,
um,
Gordon is trying to do what with cyborgs
legs.
Uh,
the first thing that Gordon Ryan needs
to do is establish inside position with
his feet.
If you,
uh,
probably the single biggest uh,
starting point for any kind of ashy
grammy based game.
If you want to remember anything about
this,
Joe,
remember this,
whenever you go into lake lungs,
the person whose feet dominate the
inside position will always dominate the
ashy grammy game.
That's the heuristic that I teach all of
my students called.
And Ryan has just established inside
position.
Well,
it's just pulled him in,
which is interesting.
Cyborg literally pulled him in with his
feet inside.
You have a Gordon,
his feet were positioned in a way where
they could own the end up in,
in the inside position.
So that's the first thing he's got to
establish inside position with the feet.
He knows damn well if his feet occupied
the inside position,
wherever they go,
he's going to get to the,
uh,
the ashy grammy and his opponent.
What about a stop now?
Can we freeze it there?
Pass.
Okay.
Actually,
can you go back a little bit with,
uh,
with overshot to sell at all?
Okay.
Right about here again,
initially there's a battle going on here
for inside foot position.
Cyborg is an extremely well trained and
upon it,
and he's doing a good job of trying to
backstage it with his left leg.
He knows that if he keeps both of us
feet on the lefthand side of Gordon
Ryan's body,
he will be able to prevent his opponent
getting inside position.
So he's doing the right thing.
He is doing a good job.
He had cyborgs,
not naive.
He's,
as you said before,
he's a multi time world champion.
He's very,
very good.
He's not lake locking someone who
doesn't understand what's going on.
He knows what Gordon Ryan wants.
Uh,
there's a battle here for inside foot
position.
Cyborg is doing the right thing.
He's going into a back step.
He's going to post his right hand on the
floor and try backstep out.
Let's go just a little further forward
into the video.
Got Freeze.
I go back just a fraction.
Just a little more.
Okay.
What is Gordon's right,
right foot have uh,
his,
his right foot.
It looks like it's hard to see here,
but it looks like he's got,
he's got inside position with one foot.
He's got inside position with one foot.
The whole question is what's going to
happen with cyborgs left leg.
Now we've got a battle between Gordon
Ryans,
left leg and cyborgs.
Left leg.
Okay.
How the battle goes from here.
We'll come down to one thing.
Who Wins that battle?
Okay,
go forward.
Just a little more hook.
Slump right away.
Okay.
Colen Ryan just won the battle.
Essentially at this point,
the fight is over.
The only question is how long is it
going to take?
Why am I so confident?
Am I,
am I an asshole?
Am I saying this because I'm an asshole?
No,
I'm saying cause I know what's
happening.
I gave you one of the keynotes of the
leg walking game already.
I'll say it again because it's so
important.
The man whose feet dominate the inside
position will always dominate the ashy
go rami game.
Now the second,
whenever you go to a tech,
someone's leg,
90% of the resistance on the leg you're
attacking comes from the other leg.
It's so important.
I'm going to say it to you again.
Whenever I go to a tech,
my opponent's right leg,
90% of the resistance is going to come
from his left leg.
We talked about control.
The foundational principle of control
and leg logging in.
As a principal I refer to as double
trouble.
Double trouble is a simple idea that if
I control both of my opponent's legs,
he no longer has the opportunity.
Use a second leg to defend the first,
so the amount of trouble that you've put
them in is literally doubled in a matter
of seconds.
Gordon Ryan has a hold of Cyborgs,
right leg with his left arm and he has a
hold of cyborgs left leg with his legs.
Why was I so confident that the match is
over at this point?
Because of cyborgs.
Legs are now controlled by Golden Ryan.
He is just attained double trouble.
Now let's slowly advance the video.
Do you see how cyborgs legs are in a
straight line?
He's having a very,
very hard time holding his base.
Is the con stop.
Uh,
can you go back just a fraction
right about here.
Freeze.
Okay.
Al Whole approach to Jiu is based around
the idea of putting wages around our
opponent's body so that we can inhibit
movement.
A wage functions just as,
um,
at doorstopper stops the door from
moving in a breeze on Cam.
The only thing better than a wage is a
reinforced wage.
That's where the wage is locked in place
by another part of your body.
Golden Ryan currently has inside
position with the right leg.
He has control of sidewalks,
other leg with his arm.
So both legs have some degree of
control,
but he's about to massively reinforced
that control by locking a triangle or a
Sankaku around his opponent's leg.
In order for that to happen,
he's going to have to lift his hips
slightly off the floor so that he can
elevate over cyborgs.
Left knee.
Watch the video.
There's the elevation,
there's the lock.
Freeze,
freeze.
Now he's got cyborgs.
Two legs in a straight line.
That means cyborgs.
Only mechanism of posting or saving his
balances,
his left arm,
that's all he's got left at this point.
The fight is done.
Cyborgs right leg is controlled by
Golden Ryan's left arm.
Cyborgs.
Left leg is controlled by a reinforced
wage to strength of both Gordon riots.
Uh,
legs locked up in a triangle.
Cyborgs actually a weight division
heavier,
I believe then Gordon,
but it doesn't matter at this point.
Both hips a controlled.
This is a full state of double trouble.
Both legs controlled and a breaking
mechanism in place is an asha grammy on
the leg.
You can break someone from their cyborg
knows his only method of not being
finished is to keep his hips over.
Gordon Ryan's hips.
So the next battle is how has Gordon
Ryan going to put sidewalks,
hips on the ground?
What saving Cyborg is his left hand.
Let's see how the battle goes.
The battle just got lost.
The hips went down.
Why was it so easy?
Stop.
I don't know.
Tell me.
Do you see that right knee?
Yes.
That's what pushed him over.
The right knee went into the pocket of
cyborgs.
Left hip.
That made a directionality of force,
was slightly away from the one base of
support that Cyborg had left,
which was his left hand.
So he got sat on his hips.
Now go forward.
Just a little
and freeze.
What do you see Joe?
In what way?
What do you,
what do you want me to look out?
What do you see?
Both legs are wrapped up but be more
precise?
Uh,
well he has incredible control with his
right leg.
Um,
the way he's got his right leg and his
left leg triangled he's got the cyborgs
right foot talk deep under his arm and
he also has the left foot there as well.
So he's completely wrapped up with his
legs and his arms.
Very good.
Okay,
let's bring in a few points here.
First,
if you want to immobilize a human being
and preventing it from moving,
and what are the best things you can
ever do is lock their legs together.
You get a dangerous prisoner with the
fish.
Can you do handcuff his feet together
and handcuff him?
Saying hands together and he's no longer
dangerous.
Okay.
He has.
Cyborg is one of the most dangerous
Judas who plays in the world,
but with the two of his feet slunk
together,
he's,
he's effectively neutralized oncom
pants.
Most importantly,
we've got a very interesting distinction
here between what we call a primary and
a secondary leg.
Which leg is the Asha Rami locked up on?
Well,
he's got the left leg is was triangle.
You to sound it.
That's the,
yes,
you Rami Lake,
we called it the primary leg.
The ashy go Rami has locked on cyborgs.
Left leg.
That's the primary leg.
The other leg,
remember our principal of [inaudible],
90% of all resistance comes from the
second leg.
The arm controls to secondary leg and
the legs control the primary leg.
So the resistance from the secondary leg
is pushing off and trying to separate
the lock.
This numerous things he could Paul mold
with foot.
He could put his foot on the floor and
turn.
You could invert his body.
There's a thousand things you could do,
but he's not doing any of them.
If you control that leg.
Betsy,
important theme.
So Golden Bar,
Gordon,
Ryan's up the body.
His left arm controls the secondary leg
and his lower body,
the ashy grammy controls the primary
leg.
As a result.
What do you think of cyborgs?
Ability to move is fucked.
He's completely nullified.
Yeah.
Okay,
let's go a little further.
Freeze.
Now cyborg is doing.
All he can do.
Movement has been taken away from him,
so his only option is to fight the
hands.
Gordon Ryan understands that he has
control of the secondary leg,
but he needs to make a transition to the
primary leg.
In order to break Cyborg,
he's going to have to release the
secondary league.
Now that's a,
that's a scary thing.
If you release a secondary leg,
then your opponent cosat defended
himself again.
So he's got a measure how he releases
the secondary leg.
So it is a battle for angle here.
Cyborg is battling for the hands,
but Gordon Ryan hasn't even started the
hand fight yet.
He still in the control.
Fine.
His only interest is in holding the
position.
Go a little further.
Freeze.
Why did golden switch his right hand to
the knee?
Well,
that's the leg that can control,
or a secondary list.
Secondary Leg,
which can defend.
Um,
I would imagine he's distracting him.
Why his Golden Ryan's head leaning to
the right hand side.
I don't know why.
Because that society needs to take
Cybil.
If cyborg turns his head to the other
side.
When Gordon Ryan releases the secondary
leg,
he's going to be a problem.
There's a battle for angle now that no
one sees Gordon Ryan's head tells the
whole story here.
Let's go a little further.
Freeze and Ryan is already beginning to
transition to the primary leg.
It's a way he's got it locked up.
It's just so horrific to yes,
the two of them crossed over each other.
Now at some point he's got uncross the
legs to get to the primary leg.
Let's go a little further.
Cyborg still engage in the hand fight.
Now Gordon is about to make his
transition to the hand fight.
Yeah.
Freeze Gordon Ryan's made the critical
release of the secondary leg.
This is where things start to get
interesting.
Cyborg has perhaps tragically sat on his
right hip,
which means he has no ability to use his
secondary leg to escape,
and because he's holding Gordon Ryan's
arm,
he has no ability now to one his body
and go into a attorney and escape.
Now Gordon reinders needs to release the
right arm.
Let's go further.
Freeze.
Go back just to here.
Okay.
Gordon Ryan is about to release a
secondary leg freeze right there.
Now,
very slowly.
Take it forward.
Watch Gordon Ryan's left elbow freeze.
Why did he put the elbow there?
No,
no,
no.
It's a wage.
It's a mobilizing the leg he really
wants to attack.
He switched his arm position from
controlling the secondary leg,
which he hasn't yet fully,
but he's put his elbow in front of the
toes of the primary leg to keep that
primary life from extending.
Correct,
and to be able to transition if it
honestly and to the Loc or he needs now
is to release the right arm.
Cyborg knows if he loses the right arm,
the fight is lost.
Continuing Gordon goes back to our
position.
Freeze.
Go back just to here.
Why did Gordon Ryan,
when the hand five battle freeze go.
Cyborg is one of the strongest people in
Jujitsu.
He's got two hands on a guy in a weight
division lower than him.
Why can't he hold,
why did he lose the arm?
Why Watch Gordon Ryan's right elbow?
What did you say?
Sent,
let me say that again.
He's just lifting it up and pulling it
away.
What is he doing?
He changed the angle through the elbow.
There's a grip over and a grip under.
If you just pull,
you'll never release the arm.
Right?
He changed the elbow position so that
one grip was lost and then a push poll
with the elbow and a slip once continued
forward.
Now he's got the left arm set.
As soon as the hands touch and sidebar
just taps before he even gets a chance
to extend it because he knows the games
lost.
Uh,
he knew the game was last long before
then.
That's pretty God damn impressive.
Mm.
Yes.
And yet you'll see this with almost all
of my students.
I have seen that was almost all your
students.
Which is so bizarre now how many people
are recognizing the system and trying to
mimic it or trying to find out some sort
of a counter attack to it?
Um,
that's an interesting question.
I'm a,
I'm told is actually kind of like an
industry of people who tried to break
what we do down and mimic it.
Um,
I know there's people putting out
numerous instructionals they've,
they've watched what uh,
the squad does and tries to,
to,
to break it down.
Um,
that's,
that's good.
And it's natural.
I,
I'd be doing the same thing if someone
else was coming out and we're making
people with a given me a lot studying
what they're doing to.
Um,
so yeah,
there,
there does seem to be an industry of
that.
Um,
the question is how successful I think.
Do you see any other groups of people
coming out and just exclusively
clinician people with the same moves?
Time and time again,
years at a time,
at
all levels of competition?
No.
You're,
you're seeing more 10th planet guys do
that now.
10th Planet guys have,
um,
and given you all the credit in the
world by the way that they've,
um,
started transitioning to a lot more leg
lock attacks,
leg lock,
fence
trading on that.
Yeah,
it's um,
uh,
what we find is most people definitely
struggle with defending it and,
um,
uh,
you know,
this has been around for quite a while
now.
It's been five years since the school
really started pushing this publicly
and,
um,
uh,
it seems that there's still going to be
some,
eventually people will figure things
out.
It's just the way progress works.
But,
um,
uh,
I think at this point it's pretty clear
that people have changed their minds
about leg walks.
People I think are recognizing that
there's something different going on
here,
that this is a control based approach to
leg locks rather than a,
you know,
a speed and power boast,
a approach to leg logs and,
um,
uh,
the evidence for its success really
comes from the nature of the squad
itself.
If you look at the three founding
members of the squat,
Eddie Cummins,
Gordon,
Ryan and Gary Taunton,
all three have very,
very different body types.
All three have very,
very different personalities and yet all
three use a very similar game.
Um,
two of those three athletes came from
nowhere.
They had no competition record before
they started training.
Uh,
with me at the hands of Gracie Academy.
One of them had a competition record.
He was a,
I believe Gary [inaudible] was a brown
belt,
a competitor in the g and,
but he had no legal game.
He was a guy who was essentially no one
for scrambling from bottom half guard
and using randek naked strangles and out
of scrambles,
um,
strangles out of scrambles.
My God.
Then we have such a tongue twister.
Um,
uh,
so gary,
Tom was a particularly interesting case
because he came to me is an already
developed athlete.
He's trained under a very good friend of
mine,
Tom to blast,
um,
and completely changed his game.
So that showed something very
interesting that showed that someone
could already have a developed game and
then take on this and change the game.
So that was a particularly interesting
case with the case of Eddie Cummings and
Gordon Ryan.
They came to me early in their
development.
So they,
they,
um,
they took it on wholesale as it were.
I think this style and approach and one
of the things that's so fascinating
about it is it really requires someone
like you to systematically break it down
the way you have described it.
Um,
I've done Jujitsu for 20 years,
but I'd never stopped and thought of all
the positions in the system,
all the steps in the system,
take the fight to the ground,
get past the dangerous legs,
you know,
uh,
achieve some sort of a dominant position
and go for the submission.
I didn't do that.
I knew,
I knew.
What I find with most utis supplies is
they know what they're doing on an
unconscious level.
Yes.
My job
as a coach is to make it conscious.
Okay.
Um,
now for me,
the most interesting thing when I,
when I first had to think about Jujitsu
is a system.
Okay.
I did that when I wrote a book for my,
for my Sensei Henzel Gracie.
Um,
he asked me to write a book and I
started thinking deeply about,
you know,
what is this thing that I study?
I spend all day on a man's,
what am I doing exactly.
And um,
when you start consciously thinking
about it,
okay,
breaking it down to steps you see
presented gets was a step by step
system.
My question was,
can I go further than that?
If you did sue as a simple single
system,
what about if he divided Jujitsu up into
niche areas and instead of having one
overall system,
you had an overall system with many
subsystems within it.
So he had a lake system,
a bag system,
the front headlock system,
a Kimora system.
My approach that you did,
sue,
is it,
I had recognized it much of the success
of early procedures who came from it's
systematic nature of the fact that it
was a systems based approach to Jujitsu.
And I took
various niche areas and created systems
within systems.
Then things start to get interesting
when I started integrating the system so
that one subsystem failed.
You could transfer to another.
That meant that my students could put
opponents who were trained much,
much longer than they head into a niche
area,
which my students had so much knowledge
of.
So much training in that isolated niche
domain.
To take a take,
someone who had trained three,
four times longs in themselves and have
more knowledge in that one domain,
then they're much more experienced
opponent did.
And so what you saw with the squad was
incredibly speedy progress.
Whether we're getting wins against
people who are trained to three to four
times longer than they had,
and this idea of what I call integrated
subsystems instead of having to,
so it was just one simple single system.
You keep the overall system of Jujitsu,
but you have subsistence within it.
Each one integrated with the other,
so that one's one system fails,
you can pass off to another and it goes
back and forth until you get the wind.
That was my approach.
Do Jujitsu.
That's one I want to do as him.
If I can innovate.
You did.
So in any given direction,
that's probably the one I would push
them angst.
Now throughout this time your dealing
with some pretty significant injuries
and physical limitations that you've
had.
Um,
tell me about those,
what those were and what and how those
hindered you.
Yeah.
Um,
uh,
when I was in my early teens,
I was involved in a,
um,
a rugby injury where my,
my knee was massively injured.
Um,
over the next uh,
six years.
Uh,
I would dislocate my knee ligaments
appeared to be,
um,
uh,
severely compromised every six months or
so I get a fresh,
which would be
severe and not be on crutches.
I spent a significant amount of my
teenage years on crutches,
um,
around the age of 19.
I had one last injury and uh,
my knee just seem to have no power and
it seems like,
uh,
I walk with a limp and um,
you must remember this is in the 1980s
in New Zealand and this is pre Mris,
um,
pre orthoscopic surgery.
The doctors said,
well,
we can do an operation where we
shortened the ligaments so there's less
looseness in there and hopefully your
knee will be strong again.
I'm an operation was performed and uh,
unfortunately the ligaments were cut too
short.
And as a result,
my,
my leg never straightened again.
Um,
I developed a severe case of
arthrofibrosis where my knee actually
became deformed and doesn't straighten.
Um,
simple actions like walking,
kneeling are extremely painful for me
and have been my whole life.
I'm just walking around,
just walking is painful neediness,
extremely painful.
And um,
you know,
it's not easy to do Jiu Jitsu.
We did,
there's a lot of kneeling and also there
were other kind of structural problems
as they got older because I walk with a
limp and one leg significantly bent and
one straight.
Uh,
I tend to be completely out of balance,
out of sync with my body.
So I as soon developed a considerable
hip and back pain.
Um,
so this was something I carried with me
my whole life.
And,
um,
uh,
when I started unit two at the age of
28,
uh,
there was,
there was a concern,
you know,
am I going to have to do this?
Well,
fortunately,
ground grappling as a rule is generally
easier on your body.
Then standing martial arts,
it is a,
I don't think,
for example,
with my leg,
I could even become moderately effective
at more title taekwondo.
It was something we had to get a jump
and land.
I just couldn't do it.
Um,
whereas a Jujitsu,
because it's on the ground,
you can,
you can become pretty good.
Um,
so I battled through that and uh,
I'm,
I developed a,
a satisfactory degree of competence.
Uh,
uh,
I got a blight belt from Henzel gracie
and I became one of his main teachers.
So you train with such a compromised
knee,
uh,
you just figure out a way around it.
You just,
you know,
what are you going to do sit down?
You,
you never thought,
well boy,
I fucked my knee up.
I don't want to fuck my other knee up
to,
you know,
I think at that point you,
you just got to go forward and um,
you've got a choice.
You got to sit down and feel sorry for
yourself,
where you're going to do the best you
can with what you've gone.
And how limited was your game because
your knee,
I mean,
were you able to,
standing position was difficult for me,
but will you ever do triangles and all
sorts of different,
I mean,
I had,
you know,
every week or so I would tweak it and
I'd be in pain for a day.
I developed,
um,
a strong for Ibuprofen throughout my
life.
Um,
and uh,
other problems started to emerge.
You switched to the lower back?
Lower back is a big issue and gave me
problems.
My whole animal.
Listo now I have a machine I have to
show you.
Okay.
That's a called the reverse hyper.
Have you ever heard of it?
Oh yes.
Um,
I believe they were used by a guy called
Louis Simmons.
Tom?
Yes.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
I can't use one now because they have a
hip replacement.
And when you go up,
it puts extreme shearing force on a hip
replacement.
So I can do it with body weight,
but I can't do it with a weight.
So,
um,
uh,
I'm aware of what they are.
They,
I know many people speak very highly of
them,
but I'm so yeah,
I had this problem and,
uh,
things didn't really become critical
until my mid to early forties.
When,
as a result of walking my whole life
with a limp,
my left hip started to become completely
bone on bone.
So then the problem's doubled because
now I had a completely screwed up knee
and a hip,
but I couldn't get any kind of
operations because George St Pierre was
fighting.
Chris Weidman was fighting.
They both had great goals.
And I,
I,
so I delayed the,
uh,
the hip operation as long as they could
until George had his first retirement
and Chris Weidman,
we became a world champion and then
moved further away to long island.
It wasn't training with me so much.
Um,
at that time I,
uh,
I started training the squad and,
um,
uh,
my first,
active competitive grappling student was
80 cummings and,
um,
uh,
I was able to work effectively with him
as best I could with my hip problems.
Uh,
and of course the original lake problem.
Um,
and then at some point I,
it got to a point where I literally,
if I walked down in New York City block,
I would have to stop several times and
just stand on the side of the road and
wait for my hip to stop hurting so I
could walk in.
It just became impossible to work with.
And I ended up getting a,
a,
a full hip replacement and that's when
they shear off the top of your head.
Yeah,
the screw bolt down in there with a new
hip and that's correct.
And how does it feel now?
It's pain free,
which is a wonderful thing for me.
Um,
like any,
uh,
fake Hep is never going to be as strong
as your real hip.
There's limitations on what I can do
there.
The only problem was that shortly after
the hip replacement wind and then my
knee finally collapsed after 30 years of
of problems.
And so I'm going to have to get a knee
replacement on the same leg.
Yeah.
Who and how do they do that?
One?
A knee replacements a little bit tricky
because you don't have as much bone mass
to work with.
And um,
general generally the longevity of knee
replacements is not as,
uh,
cause there's much more movement and the
need.
And there there was in the hip there's
much greater range of motion,
um,
and this less bone to a fixed two.
They generally don't have the longevity
of a,
a hip replacement.
Um,
so,
uh,
I'm,
I'm 50 years old,
so ideally you would want a replacement
that outlived you,
but I would probably have to get a
second knee replacement when I get older
to replace the first,
which is not ideal,
but I probably gonna have to do it.
Well,
who knows what kind of crazy technology
they'll have down the line.
I hope so.
I have to give me some kind of superhero
leg that turns things around for me.
Yeah.
Well you never know.
I mean it's just the,
the nature of the hip replacement,
the,
so it's so brutally invasive,
uh,
the sheering off the top of the hip and
then the rod that's inserted deep into
the bone of the hip and then all that
jazz.
Yeah,
it's a lot.
It's a lot going on there.
So,
um,
to,
to answer your question,
uh,
in the early days it was a,
it was an impediment that I worked
around.
Um,
but as I got older,
um,
I had to,
uh,
do a first operation and now a second,
believe it or not,
Joe,
I was actually scheduled to get my knee
replacement tomorrow.
Um,
but I,
I didn't do it because Gary Toner and is
going to be fighting his first MMA fight
and much 26 no.
Is He fighting for one FC One FC?
So I,
if I got the knee replacement now,
I would not be able to help them get
ready for us to first MMA fight,
which I thought would be,
um,
uh,
there's not fear on my part in it,
you know.
And,
uh,
so I delayed it until,
after that fight.
Why did he decide on one MC?
That's interesting question.
You'd have to ask.
Gary told him to be certain.
Um,
uh,
but he,
I think one of his main fears was that
if he went through the amateur route and
then worked his way towards the UFC,
there would be problems because he's
already an established name in
grappling.
And I think he was concerned that it
would be difficult for him to get people
to fight amateur,
um,
and uh,
and then eventually make its way to the
UFC.
Whereas one FC is a fairly well known
organization and they were pretty open.
They,
he did a grappling match for them and
they loved it and were like,
you know,
are you interested in mma?
And so he could,
uh,
as it were,
um,
go into a fairly high level of mma right
from the start as opposed to do a long
circuitous amateur route and then battle
his way into the UFC.
I believe,
don't quote me on this,
but I leave.
That was the logic
behind it.
Now are you a book?
So when you're demonstrating techniques,
so you're demonstrating them verbally.
Um,
after the hip replacement,
I could only do it verbally and I had to
trust and,
uh,
my,
my students,
80 cummings,
Gary,
Tom and Gordon,
Ryan and others.
Brian Glick isn't,
no one knows him,
but he's one of my,
uh,
great students.
Um,
I would,
uh,
point with a stick and,
they would do the most for me.
Um,
since then I've gotten a little better
and I like to demonstrate as best can
these days when I,
I can barely walk.
And,
uh,
on those days I'll have the students go
through.
Sometimes there's certain standard
techniques that I had a little risky for
me to do and I'll have students
demonstrate those.
But,
um,
uh,
I,
I do what I can on the days that I
teach.
It is quite fascinating that a guy who
was catastrophic injuries of his leg is
one who is known for being an innovator
and crushing people's lives.
There.
There is something kind of a strange
about that.
Yeah.
You were joking around about it being
revenge.
Yeah.
This is missing my revenge against the
world.
If God took away my leg,
I'm taking away everybody else's.
Um,
and so,
um,
yeah,
there,
there was something ironic about them.
Now,
when your teaching this system and um,
you,
you're,
uh,
showing all the guys in the squad,
the Donna,
her death squad,
do you have,
um,
like do you have it worked out to the
point where it's like you have a
curriculum?
Like do you have like,
even like the word curriculum because
that kind of implies that it's all
worked out and yeah.
Violence and you know,
it's done step by step.
Um,
I come in on any given day and I'm,
I'm there seven days a week.
I watch all of my athletes every single
day.
They didn't do anything without me
watching them do it.
So I know at the end of every day what
they need to work on tomorrow because
I'm there.
So it's not like a set curriculum early.
You know,
I know that on April 13 I'm going to do
this.
And it's not like that.
It's like I saw you train yesterday.
I saw where you fucked up and I saw
where you were good.
So tomorrow we're working this.
What an amazing resource for those guys
to have someone like you standing over
them,
watching them and analyzing their
positions and techniques and progress.
That's um,
that's generous of you to say.
Um,
but I always feel that my students are
more of a resource to me than I am to
them.
I've been blessed through my entire
coaching career to have some truly
remarkable students,
some of whom are famous and known to you
and many others who aren't.
And,
um,
uh,
whatever debt they owe to me,
I feel I owe at least as much to them.
Um,
my students literally give me
everything.
I'm,
I'm a notoriously difficult person to
get along with them,
demanding I'm,
I'm a perfectionist.
I can be downright unpleasant when my
body's in pain,
I'm short tempered.
Um,
and yet they're like angels.
They based stick in there and they tough
it out and they,
they give so much time,
so much effort,
so much thought.
And as I said,
whatever resource I am to them,
they,
they give it right back.
There are a resource to me.
Well that that attitude is why you're
such a fantastic coach in the first
place.
Um,
I remember one of the first times I've
started talking to you is when you were
working with George.
Now what's interesting is you had a very
interesting approach and even the way
you describe things you would talk about
shoot boxing.
Hmm.
Describe that because you,
you didn't talk when like I remember,
uh,
I think one of our first long
conversations with at some weird denny's
or something somewhere and one of those
weird roadshows,
like will it just sat down where you are
absolutely.
Right.
That was the first time we met.
We had a long conversation and um,
you were talking about the principles of
shoot boxing.
Please explain.
Um,
one of the strange things about the
sport of mixed martial arts is so young.
There's still so much to be done.
Okay.
Even the way people understand mixed
martial arts to me is interesting.
99% of people who look at mixed martial
arts see mixed martial arts as an
eclectic sport.
In other words,
it's a conglomeration of different
martial arts kind of banded together and
then you've got mixed martial arts.
It's a mix of martial arts and there you
have it.
You get two guys in a cage.
And what mixed martial arts,
I never saw mixed martial arts as an
eclectic sport.
I see it as a transcendent sport.
What I mean by that is there were four
distinct skill areas of mixed martial
arts.
Any one of those skill areas always goes
beyond the component martial arts that
make it up.
In other words,
the skill area transcends the various
martial arts that make it up and create
something bigger and different from the
core components that originally built
it.
When you look at the sport of mixed
martial arts,
you see there were four dominant skill
areas.
The first occurs when they first come
out and the two athletes who have no
connection with each other and they're
dancing around the cage.
This is the so called shoot boxing
phase,
which involves skills drawn from western
boxing,
Muay Thai karate,
a freestyle wrestling,
and various other martial arts with the
two athletes are jockeying for position
and typically they're trying to
determine the direction of the fight.
Would it go down or would it stay up?
That's one skill area.
The second skill area as a skill area of
the clinch with the two athletes are
both still standing,
but now they've got a hold on each
other.
They no longer moving around will this
has its key components come and drill
them from Moitai,
Greco,
Roman wrestling,
freestyle wrestling,
judo,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Then there's a third key skill area.
The area of fence fighting fence.
Boxing with a two athletes are in a
clinch,
but they're locked on the fence,
which dramatically changes the skills
required for success than if you're in
the open.
And then you have a fourth skill area,
which is the ground.
And of course that's divided into top
and bottom position.
So there were four skill areas of mixed
martial arts.
You could add more or less.
Uh,
for example,
you could add in the idea of the
geography of the cage can add a new
areas,
but let's stick with that fundamental
four for now.
If you show me any one of those skill
areas,
yes you can derive skills from those
component martial arts,
from Moitai,
from Judah,
whatever you choose.
But that skill here is going to have
other elements that are not part of
those original martial arts that has
something different,
something unique and something above the
various component martial arts that made
it up
when you're fighting on the ground,
a lot of what you do is the ride from
Brazilian Jujitsu and modern mixed
martial arts.
Most of the athletes come from a to two
background.
When they work ground skills they they
work on in a kind of a Jujitsu
framework,
but many of the things going on down,
there are a mix of things that are far
outside of your daily training and
designed units.
You can bring in things from Moitai,
you're throwing Moitai al was on the
ground,
but on the ground the,
I always have a very different feel from
the standing position.
They've,
a mechanics behind them is significantly
different.
You're throwing hooks on the ground,
but the mechanics of and hooks on the
ground have very,
very different from the mechanics of
throwing hooks in the standing position.
So yeah,
you're,
you're bringing skills in from box,
but you're adapting them to God.
So the way to look at the sport of mixed
martial arts is not just like,
okay,
I'm going to rope together some race
lanes and boxing and see what happens.
Rather you're developing skills in four
distinct areas,
a minimum of four,
and the skills you ultimately develop go
beyond.
And I'd significantly different from the
core components that you started with.
And so ultimately the skills of a mixed
martial artist at the highest levels
transcend the various corps martial arts
that made the sport up.
You're going to something,
you're going further when you fight in a
mixed martial arts fighter in your
Jujitsu fighter,
huge in a lot more than just you did sir
and the various other boxing styles,
et Cetera,
et cetera that you used.
In the case of shute box and and George
St Pierre,
everyone always talks about George's
wrestling.
Now George is a very good wrestler.
He's wrestler a long time with very good
people,
but 90% of the success of his ability to
take people down goes far beyond
wrestling and has to do with the
precursors to the shot.
What wrestling teachers,
he drew a mixed martial arts is how to a
shot.
It gives you the body mechanics to
finish the shot,
but the sit ups completely different
from wrestling.
I can show you endless examples of good
liz who went into mixed martial arts
competition with no background in mixed
martial arts and couldn't take anybody
down.
That distance is different.
The standards,
different emotion is different.
The set ups are completely different.
The context is different.
You've been punched sort of grappling.
Okay.
George,
in my opinion,
throughout his career had a level of
skill and technical insight and the,
the art of boxing kickboxing into take
downs that no one else has even come
close to.
Much of what he did in that area came
from himself.
Did he have good wrestling coaches?
Absolutely.
Did he have good boxing coaches?
Great.
Moitai coaches 100%.
Okay.
But the skills he was exhibiting went
beyond any one of those teachers or even
them as a whole.
The act of tying together all of those
disparate skills came from him.
The integration of skills.
And so you have someone who had a
wrestling background,
had a boxing background,
had a Moitai background,
but ultimately what he was doing with
something bigger than all of those put
together,
there's a sign of just to get fit here
with,
uh,
the,
the sum was,
was somehow greater than the components
that,
uh,
individually made it up.
And that's what I mean when I talk about
a trans in and support.
Um,
George St Pierre was largely responsible
through individual experimentation
starting in his late teens and going
through his entire career in the
development of shoot box.
Now when you work as a coach for George,
you weren't just working as a Jujitsu
coach,
you were working in almost like a
mastermind sort of a position you,
I mean I saw some conversations that you
had with him where you discussed various
things and in fact one of the things you
came to me about was you asked me if I
knew anyone who was proficient at the
spinning back kick and that's how I got
to working with George.
Your,
your,
your coaching with him was not just
simply like the,
these are the principles of Jiu Jitsu.
This is what I want you to work on.
When the fight goes to the ground,
you were working on a lot of different
aspects.
Like you are a guy,
they'd sort of put it together.
Now when you don't have a background in
striking and you know,
you,
you were looking at all of these various
disciplines and trying to formulate a
strategy for a guy who just such a
supreme athlete like George,
how did you,
how did you formulate that?
Did you do it based on the individual
and based on their physical strengths
and limitations and sort of formulate
what you think would be the best
approach?
Did you work it out with him in
conjunction?
Um,
the,
when,
when George comes to train with me this,
there's a bunch of considerations.
First of all,
George lives in Montreal.
I live in New York.
So time is always an issue.
Well,
he does go down there because then they
quite often,
but um,
uh,
but it's not like a squat.
The squat like seven days a week,
three times a day.
George was never liked that.
Um,
uh,
so in the time available we'll work on,
on,
on what we can,
so everything's always done with
Georgia.
Okay.
How much time is available and what is
the scenario that's coming up for
George?
Almost always.
That was,
um,
uh,
an upcoming mixed martial arts fight.
Okay.
Um,
so a lot of people often ask me to say,
well,
you know,
how can we didn't teach,
teach George Saint Pierre Lake logs,
why wasn't he leg lock and everyone in
mma?
Um,
well it's,
it's a good question.
Uh,
first off,
um,
leg locking as you saw from the Gordon
Ryan Clip requires if it's not done
well,
leg log in is one of those things where
if it's done well,
it's amazing,
but if it's done badly,
it's the worst looking thing in the
world and said disaster.
Um,
so,
uh,
secondly,
Georgia's game because his down to so
strong as almost always done from top
position on the ground.
Is it rare for George to be in bottomed
session on the ground?
Um,
and in a fight situation,
if you're already on top of someone and
you've got the striking prowess of
George St Pierre,
I was happy to,
to coach him more and what we call a
grapple boxing.
Just the skill of,
of grappling to punching on the ground
that just made more sense for him.
Um,
he's competent and leg logging,
but he's not like Gary Thompson and
Eddie Cummings or Gordon Ryan.
It could,
he finished most black belts.
He absolutely.
But why would you stake a fight where
literally millions of dollars?
I mean 40 is a legacy on the line.
Why would you take that risk when you
could just stay on time to punch him
out?
Peggy did was say John Fetch for
example,
you know,
um,
so it didn't really make sense that push
that hard on George.
Um,
your question though was,
okay,
well what about these other skills?
What about standing position?
Well,
um,
I'm,
I'm fascinated not just by judges who
are my martial arts in general.
And I've always believed all the various
sport martial arts in the world have
areas where they are particularly
strong.
For example,
I've always people make fun of
taekwondo,
you know,
that are,
dude,
don't want to just talk with him and him
and me,
you'll back me up on this joke.
There are some taekwondo players out
there at Olympic level who can kick with
a skill level that most people can't
even imagine.
Um,
uh,
I've seen people like heard Perez
kicking demonstrations where you're
looking at it as,
this is one of the most impressive
things I've ever seen in my life and
this is as the guy who,
if he hits you,
it's going to take your head off.
It's impressive to borrowers.
There wouldn't hurt.
Pres was in his prime.
I watched him.
Oh,
quite a few people.
I watched him Kao uh,
one of the u s national champions with
an ax care,
some of the worst Kaos have ever seen in
my life came from taekwondo.
Like they tend to involve a jump
spinning kicks with is just huge amounts
of,
of kinetic energy being developed.
You see the same thing can point
fighting crises and terrible knock outs
and point finding because people make
fun of these sports.
Acting on their own is the issue.
That's the issue.
That's the issue on their own.
They got problems.
But if you can integrate that into the
door,
well developed,
complete skillset,
they could be incredibly effective.
And I always saw tremendous potential
for Tae Kwon dos jumps,
spinning back kick.
No one does spinning back x better than
taekwondo.
Yeah.
That's one of the main things.
And they do it incredibly well.
The set ups are fantastic that the
application and mechanics,
everything's super impressive.
So I always thought that would be a,
you know,
George had a good spinning back kick,
but I thought that would be a nice
addition.
You always want to be building new
skills into upon or you don't,
you don't want to be that predictable
guide where everyone knows what you're
doing.
And um,
uh,
and I know you came from taekwondo
backgrounds and uh,
so I thought that would be an
interesting thing for you to work on
with him.
Well,
it was a funny conversation because that
was my specialty.
Yes.
And so when you brought in,
I always wanted to talk to you.
I was fuck found your fascinating guy.
So when he came up to me and you said,
do you know anyone,
it's almost like a trick question.
It was a trick question.
You know,
anyone besides your aunt,
what I sat,
I was like,
I was hesitant.
okay,
you're not going to believe this.
But the truth is,
I knew you had a good jump spinning back
kick.
I was trying to subtly,
did you?
Yeah.
How did you know word gets around.
I thought you were just fucking with me.
I mean I,
but I,
I felt like when I was telling you I was
like man I don't even want to,
I wish I knew someone who did it with
two ls.
You should have just been like yeah I've
got the best jump spinning back kick in
the fucking world.
I did jump spinning back kick quite a
bit but I prefer a regular spinning
back.
I want my foot on the ground cause I'm
just going off of that foot.
Yeah,
there's a significant amount of force in
the left leg forcing,
pushing off that back.
Interestingly you've seen some some guys
out there now having good success and
even maybe staying back.
Cause I remember seeing Michael Page had
a beautiful one.
He's got everything that guy can very
impressive.
He's another guy who came from that
point fighting background.
You know,
you see Raymond Daniels and him and a
lot of these guys from that background
that are defendant.
Daniel's worked with George for his last
two fights.
Very,
very impressive guy.
Phenomenal.
Yeah.
And,
and again,
it's,
he had just the point fighting skills
and now he's developing real boxing
skills and he's,
you know,
you've seen him in Beltour kickbox,
and you see,
you see the integration of the two.
It's phenomenal.
I mean,
he could just do things physically that
most kickboxer just really don't know
what he's doing.
He'll,
he'll jump up and do what's called like
a touch spinning back kick.
Like he'll jump up and touch you with
the front leg.
I saw that,
hit it in a glorified I believe.
And um,
yeah,
he's phenomenal.
He's phenomenal.
But the,
again,
when you see that it's like those things
by themselves,
you're just going to get taken to the
ground and smashed.
And most people,
unless you land one of those
catastrophic spinning back kicks right
away,
the the odds are you,
you,
you need all those other things as well
in order to be particularly effective,
which is why George was such a thing.
Yeah.
But that was a,
that was a fun moment.
It was an interesting because like I've
always wanted to like show somebody
this.
It's cause it's a weird little thing
that I know how to do.
Um,
going back to your original question,
the idea of Georgian and shoot box,
you will see that Georgia's entire
methodology in a standing position is
built around the concept of a dilemma
that the Lemur is always between his jet
and his takedown.
People always talk about proactive and
reactive takedowns.
Okay.
This guy's are reactive to discuss a
proactive takedown guy.
The thing about George is he would use
his jab proactively,
but he would use his takedowns
reactively.
Now that's interesting because George
would literally provoke people.
You're saying,
take down,
oh,
I just want to point this out past
tense.
You're saying this like,
you know something.
I don't know.
No,
no,
no.
It's George just won the middleweight
title,
relinquished the title,
and then the great speculation is will
George fight again?
Yeah.
The truth is no one knows because it
comes down some medical problems.
George has,
uh,
he's got a problem on his stomach and
colitis.
Is that what it is and what,
what is that exactly?
It's,
uh,
I'm not going to claim to be a medical
expert,
but it's one of the most frustrating
things that George has had to deal with
where there are certain parts of the
human body to just out of your control
and the stomach is one of them.
Just things happening in your stomach,
you can't control it.
Things like stress seem to make it
worse.
Um,
and uh,
uh,
the truth is that no one really knows at
this point.
So,
um,
wherever this doubt,
my
instinct is to think,
well,
you really want to come back,
George,
you've done all this and what a great
way to cap off a career too.
It was amazing.
It was in person.
I got to tell you,
when he came back,
this is what was really interesting
about that fight.
George had said,
I'm better,
I'm a better martial artists than I was
before.
And he looked better.
I mean,
he definitely looked like he was a
little out of competition.
Like there was a moment he should,
how many fighters do you know came back
up to a four year layoff.
Very few.
But skill wise he looked phenomenal.
I mean his striking looked incredibly
smooth and I think you could see it in
bisping's face like pretty early on.
Like this guy is,
this is not a rusty George Saint Pierre
is not a small welterweight who's,
you know,
making his way in the,
where he looked huge.
He looked phenomenal.
His,
his technique,
the way he was landing leg kicks and his
Sharp Jab.
And then ultimately that left hand that
he used to stun bisbing and get him on
the ground.
I mean,
he looks sensational.
Yes.
Um,
uh,
you were there the night George went
into his first retirement and you'll
recall the whole retirement thing was
kind of,
the speech was vague.
It wasn't,
it was confusing.
And because he did,
in truth,
he didn't know if he wanted to retire.
Um,
the whole thing was actually contrived
in the octagon right there in front of
you.
I would be in a hard fight.
Uh,
training camp hadn't been the best camp
though.
The fight for Hendricks was,
uh,
George was unclear if he wanted to fight
it all.
There were,
there's all kinds of controversies
involved in the fight.
And um,
then when the fight was over,
it was,
it was a very close fight.
Um,
and uh,
uh,
he wasn't sure what he wanted to do.
There was some language miscommunication
and ultimately he essentially,
he walked away from the game and he
walked away for four years.
That's a long time to be out of a sport
that as young as him or main,
which is evolving all the time every
year,
the sport changes.
And,
uh,
the belts tend to change hands very,
very quickly.
Um,
so when George started talking to me
about the idea of,
okay,
I want to come back,
I think I've still got conveyed.
I want to come back.
This a desire,
passion.
My point to him was,
first off you show you really want to do
this.
Like,
you know the last two fight camps,
it's tough.
You didn't seem to have the same kind of
drives.
He used to have you show you want to do
this.
Is this like a middle aged fantasy he
going through here and he said none of
that.
I feel this,
I want to come back.
So my question to him was if you're
going to come back,
I just going to do the same thing.
You just going to come back to
welterweight and do what you always did,
which has come out and beat the base
well to weights and just hold a title.
It's used to going to be doing the same
thing.
I thought if he gonna come back,
let's do something significant.
Something you haven't done before.
And so the way I put it to him was what
are the three most persistent criticisms
you always hear about George Saint
Pierre?
Number one,
you never fought up a weight class,
never went up.
Number two,
you fought.
So tactically sound was such an emphasis
on a strategy and techniques or what
have you.
That matches could become dull.
That the average fan was like,
well,
yeah,
he's,
he's winning easily.
It's dominant,
but it doesn't do it for,
it's not excited.
No drama in the funds on gun.
Um,
so he had this idea that,
uh,
on the one hand,
he was very technically sound
strategically deep,
but the fights weren't as exciting as
they ought to be.
Um,
the idea that he'd never gone up,
uh,
a weight category and the third most
persistent Chris and we didn't finish
fights.
Okay.
He at,
he was a very skilled fighter.
It wasn't finishing fights.
So my point is,
okay,
if you're going to come back,
let's do it in a way where you address
those three things.
Okay.
George is always concerned about his
legacy as a fighter.
And if there were three persistent
criticisms of George NPS legacy,
it was those three things.
You're not finishing fights.
You never went up a weight class and
you're too tactical.
Okay?
You're not providing the drama that a
fight should.
So I said,
let's change things.
We've got in that four years.
Previous to that,
whenever I was training George,
I was training him for a fight.
He was not with fire fighting.
Nick Diaz is finding cars,
condos,
finding,
you know,
whoever.
And it was always getting him ready for
a fight.
You Find Matt Hughes in two months,
let's get ready now you're a tired,
I'm not going to train you to find some
dude going to train you in Jujitsu.
Freddie Roach.
It's going to train you in boxing
in this sense we could,
we hit the time now to start working on
finishing skills.
A significant change occurred where my
primary emphasis in training George in
that four year layoff was in
submissions.
Now happily that happened at what time?
The time the school,
it was coming out.
So I had a group of some of the best
submission peoples in the world for
George to work with.
So it was submission started getting
better.
Suddenly George Saint Pierre,
he got on your back is a problem.
He's submitting people in the gym.
I could run off some names.
I won't do it because it's not the thing
to do.
But I could run off some names of
people.
He submitted an agenda would shock you,
like well known Judah to people.
And for the first time he's our primary
versus wasn't on grapple walks in.
It was submission.
Freddie Roach was working on what was on
the mechanics of punching.
George always had good in out movement.
Who was head like that karate movement.
The um,
the ability,
he always had a strong jab,
but now he's teaching them how to sit on
a punch.
70 George had a left hook.
Okay.
And you're a guy who can integrate left,
uh,
left hand chip between jab and lift or
gets a dangerous man.
Um,
everyone was worried,
you know,
there's so much overreaction to George's
jab is suddenly left talk.
Opportunities are opening up and now he
was sitting on that left hook and people
getting hurt.
So now for the first time you got a guy
who's got submissions and he's hitting
with genuine power.
As he came back,
it was a question of who's going to be
the opponent?
And the next thing I say it is,
well,
you know,
went up a weight division,
go up to 85 now.
Now
was any consideration about going up to
85 because the fact that bisping was the
champion,
no.
George has trained with business and the
decision was made before piston was the
champion.
Real?
Yeah.
How far in advance was the decision
made?
Because bisbing had defended against
Henderson won against four
year project.
Okay.
I didn't know initially.
Initially I couldn't make that decision
because then another student of mine,
Chris Weidman was the one 85 pound
champion and Chris and Georgia never
fight each other.
But once that was no longer an issue,
then it was like,
hey,
this,
this could work.
This could be interesting.
So d during the entire four years he was
talking about eventually becoming,
not the entire four years.
No.
Okay.
But he was training the whole time and I
was pushing him a kid,
you don't fight anymore.
Let's do some submission grappling.
Right.
Okay.
Um,
he stuck with Freddie Roach.
She loves working with Freddie Roach.
And,
um,
uh,
so the training was,
was going in different directions.
It was this Moitai coach.
Um,
mostly he works at Ferrazzi Hobby and,
and tries to that,
but that's more a integrated for us as a
black belt of mine.
So he,
um,
often,
uh,
does Jujitsu with fluoroscopy,
had I teach for us in frost,
that does a good job there.
Um,
but for us,
uh,
ties things together,
let's his principal function and I know
he trained with Phil nurse for awhile.
Then he trained with a lot of guys who
came out of,
uh,
Thailand itself from Tiger Moy,
Tai,
um,
uh,
yard.
That's a shortening of his actual name.
They will have very long names,
but a yard was one of his trainers.
They trained him prior to condit and
Diaz,
um,
uh,
did a fine job.
So there's never been a shortage of
coaches in his life,
but,
uh,
there were certain things that seem to
gel with them more than others.
Interestingly,
during that four year period,
George had a strong rebirth into karate
and worked with a lot of specialized
created people,
including Raymond Daniels and others.
Uh,
they came from the,
mostly from the European point fighting
karate a circuit and he was working with
them a lot.
And so somewhere or eh,
the cross has certain poor a period of
time where you're dealing with a
different athlete.
Now this is the guy who's had four years
off and the train had gone in different
directions.
It's finishing skills in both fisticuffs
and grappling had gotten considerably
better.
Um,
he was toying with the idea of going up
to 85 and experimented with diet and et
Cetera to get his body weight up.
That's never an easy thing to do.
And tactically he was working more on
the idea of being an exciting fighter
through movement and pushing harder for
the finish.
And,
uh,
and I thought those were three very,
very healthy directions to go and,
and um,
uh,
this would,
as it were,
if he did come back,
this would be offer a genuine
opportunity to address the three most
persistent criticism of his career.
Initially,
there was a lot of resistance from the
UFC.
I don't think they were fond of the idea
at all.
They wanted him to go to one 70 and,
and do what he had done.
And uh,
but George pushed hard for the,
uh,
for the fight at 85 and ultimately it
happened in a rather strange way.
Tyrone Woodley had a fight at one 70.
What?
Shum uh,
wasn't the most crowd pleasing fight and
uh,
George St Pierre was supposed to fight
tyrone woodley and in UFC,
you know what fibers mean,
it's on.
So they,
we chose the Madison Square Garden.
That's one of the great fight capitols
of the world.
And it's how it happened.
So there was consideration in fighting
one 70.
Yes.
And so this was the ufc his idea,
but what about your python for I,
I thought first of all,
I'm,
I'm not the matchmaker.
I'm not the main policy making under,
I don't want to say that I was the guy,
I was the guy that suggested those
ideas.
And George seems to like the idea,
he said,
if I'm going to come back,
if we're going to take the risk of a
four year layoff and come back,
it's a big risk,
you know?
Yeah.
I mean,
Muhammad Ali came back after three years
and had to warm up fights and still lost
his title phone.
But Muhammad Ali wehrly wasn't working
out.
That was,
that was when the Vietnam war thing,
it happens mostly doing tours of college
game.
It wasn't really working out the whole
time and improving.
You can see the difference in Muhammad
Ali,
his body when he came back,
it's still,
there's many other examples that you,
sugar ray Leonard came back after
layoffs.
He had one successful and one very
unsuccessful come back and he was
working hard the whole time.
So coming back,
cause it's a hard,
tricky thing on many levels too.
Not just physical but also
psychological.
So now this collitus thing is thrown a
monkey wrench into the gears.
If actually it threw a monkey wrench
during the camp.
Really?
I could tell you some stories about
that.
That camp was uh,
as,
as good as the four years was.
The camp itself,
I,
I can say it now because it's over,
was a disaster.
It was probably the worst camp I've ever
been involved in.
A really,
I was coaching of course the scored for
ADCC.
So,
uh,
adcc I believe was around six weeks,
before George is fine.
So I was in Finland and communicating
with George and he's like,
feeling good.
Let's get the moment I get back,
I'm just going to get on a plane from
Finland to Montreal and start the camp.
Uh,
George sent me out.
I've got stomach issues and I was like,
what do you mean stomach issues?
What does that even mean now?
Um,
uh,
about two weeks into the camp,
the issues got so bad that George
literally could not,
now this is a six week fight camp.
It's a very short camp.
Back in the day we used to do eight to
12 weeks,
but George thought a shorter camp would
be better.
He,
as he's getting older,
he wanted to short at camp.
First two weeks were okayed,
but I was in,
uh,
the aftermath of the Finland expedition
and um,
uh,
when I first went up,
George said,
I've got to cancel.
Okay.
I,
uh,
I can't train my fights four weeks away.
And George took two weeks off.
It was a critical moment on a Friday
evening where I say it to for Rasa
Hobby,
this is the second time I've had to say
this to for our salary.
The other was the Carlos condit camp.
I say George isn't training by Monday we
can to pull the plug,
there's no other way.
And we were talking about a four year
layoff and this camp is lost.
It's dead in the water.
So four weeks out he takes two weeks
off.
Uh,
I believe it might've been five.
I'll check the dates later,
but I'm very close to it.
There was a critical two week period
where during that two weeks,
what is he able to do?
Essentially?
Nothing.
Yeah.
Just no train light drilling some
movement.
And uh,
he,
he was,
it,
it occurred the worst possible time.
It,
it wasn't at the start of the,
was in the middle of the camp so that
the first two weeks were lost because
then,
uh,
we had two weeks of inactivity.
Then there's two weeks left.
And I remember the first time I went up,
I bought Jake Shields,
Gary Turner and Gordon Ryan with me.
And we came up and we went through some
drills on the ground and I was happy,
you know,
Joseph Del k on the ground.
He did fine against the score guys.
And um,
uh,
we worked on some specialized grabbing
stuff and then the next day he went to
do a shoot box workout.
Now I could sit here all day until you
adventures of George St Pierre Doing
shoe box training with people.
I've seen him spot everybody.
Okay.
I'm not gonna mention names,
but I've seen George Saint Pierre
takedown effortlessly.
Some of the biggest names in mixed
martial arts in weight divisions,
far above his own so many times per
round.
You just lose count.
Nigga.
I,
I'm,
I'm afraid to even tell you the stories
because people wouldn't believe me.
Um,
I'm used to seeing George Saint Pierre
has shoot boxing,
bap,
Bang down.
Right.
Okay.
Um,
I've seen that since the thought of his
career,
I watched Joe Saint Pierre to a shoe box
workout where he couldn't score a take
down.
This is a fights two weeks away.
I'm just looking,
going like,
holy heck,
what is this?
He's getting hit,
he's getting frustrated,
he's getting tired.
And I said to Varanasi,
us,
you know,
this is,
this is a crisis.
This is one of the biggest uscs of the
year.
It's Madison Square Garden.
He's the headline.
The USC had to pull some big things to
get this fight to happen.
They didn't originally didn't want it.
If we pull out now,
it's going to look like a disaster.
It's going to be George let the UFC
down.
Um,
and to his everlasting credit,
George said,
I'll be back on Monday and I'll be
better.
We went up and,
uh,
he,
he is,
he dug in deep.
What can I tell you?
He's a trooper.
He,
um,
he trained every day,
those last two weeks and as each day
went by,
there was significant improvement.
And I remember there was a distinct
moment,
about five days before the end of the
camp,
I swung to a shoot box,
work out,
and he looked like the old George and I
was,
okay,
I believe in this care again.
You can do it.
Jamie,
will you please google?
Collitus I don't know enough.
I believe he should.
What the goals?
Ulcerative colitis.
Yeah.
I don't know.
It's so it,
it's something to do with stomach
ulcers.
Um,
I'm not going to claim to be an expert,
but uh,
yeah,
I can tell you what the symptoms were.
I was extreme stomach pain and inability
to eat at,
screwed up his entire diet.
And when did it start?
Uh,
it's not an early in the camp and got
progressively worse and then hit for the
camp.
There was no issues.
Uh,
here,
all sort of colitis is usually only,
uh,
in innermost lining of the large
intestine,
colon and rectum forms range from mild
to severe.
Having all sort of colitis puts a
patient at increased risk of developing
colon cancer symptoms including rectal
bleeding,
bloody diarrhea,
abdominal cramps and pain.
And it sounds like a party.
Yeah.
If you read the,
can you bring it back,
read the first four treatment,
can help with this condition,
cannot be cured,
requires a medical diagnosis,
lab tests or imaging.
Always required chronic can last for
years or be lifelong.
It's incredibly frustrating for him to
deal with.
And it says treatments,
including medications and surgery.
Yeah.
So it's a forgery,
but,
uh,
it appeared to back off a little bit in
the last two weeks.
He came back and he,
um,
this is the kind of person,
George Saint Pierre.
It's the morning of the fight.
Saturday morning we're in New York City
in the hotel room,
uh,
for us,
hobbies,
Freddie Roach and myself,
or at the breakfast table,
George comes down for breakfast and he's
weighed in,
he looks at his breakfast is originally
the plan because it was a fight at one
85 was to have george come in at a,
at a higher body weight.
But he ended up weighing 191 pounds,
which is exactly the same as he used to
fight at welterweight,
the same body weight.
So that was kind of a disappointment,
you know.
Um,
and uh,
he quietly excuse himself and went to
the bathroom.
Everyone else went away to do their
things.
And I sat there and I realized he's in
the bathroom for an hour.
He came out and I would say,
George,
you okay?
And he looked at me,
he said,
I'm fine,
but I knew he wasn't.
And then he went out,
fought.
Um,
and then afterwards he told me I was in
so much pain and he was afraid to tell
me because he would worry that if I
cornered him and I thought he was
compromised,
I wouldn't call him the way I normally
would,
that I would doubt him.
So he kept it all inside,
didn't say a word.
And uh,
he's a good kid.
You know,
you can't help but to it like that.
Wow.
Well that's what makes them a champion.
Yeah.
That's one of the things,
it's,
it's less than perfect conditions.
He could still rise to the occasion less
than perfect.
It was a very far from perfect.
Now you said that during the Johnny
Hendricks fight during the camp for that
fight,
when he decided to impromptu retire
inside the octagon yeah.
That there was talk during the camp that
he didn't want to fight.
Yeah.
What was that about?
Uh,
really centered around two things.
One,
I can just,
I can not discuss because it involves a
personal life.
Joe Saint Pa,
there was some things going on in his
personal life that,
um,
uh,
deeply affected him and he was deeply
unhappy with some circumstances in his
personal life and I'm,
it's not appropriate for me to talk
about those.
Um,
and the second was the whole idea that
it become an obsession with George at
that time,
which is the use of anabolic steroids in
mixed martial arts.
And um,
he was deeply unhappy with what he
perceived as the prevalence of the use
of anabolic steroids in mixed martial
arts as a whole and among his opponents
in particular.
And um,
uh,
he wanted a testing program to be bought
in for that fight.
There was talk about it but nothing came
of it.
And,
uh,
it became like this psychological
obsession during the camp and uh,
uh,
between those two issues,
there was a lot of unhappiness.
He came in,
he did a strain,
you know,
he's,
he's a professional athlete.
It's not like he missed workouts or
anything crazy like there wasn't a going
out at night or anything foolish,
but there was a degree of unhappiness
where I'm looking and thinking how much
longer in this go on
now there was some talk about the tyron
Woodley fight and then tyron had this
bad performance,
but if George did get healthy and was
confident enough in his health that he
could get through,
get through an actual training camp,
would he be interested in considering a
fight with Tyron Woodley?
Absolutely.
I think Tyron,
what is a great champion?
I know he gets a lot of steak,
a lot of flag.
That kid is talented,
very talented,
very good,
and he doesn't think George wants to
fight him.
He was on the podcast the other day.
People say that for reasons so that they
can motivate someone defined,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
There's a political aspect to it and I
think that both athletes have a deep
respect for each other.
Um,
targeted wound.
He's a very,
very difficult opponent to beat.
These people criticize his style,
but people don't understand difference
between regular fighting and
championship fighting.
Championship fighting is about winning
and losing and you got to do what you
gotta do to win.
That's the first consideration.
It's nice to impress the crowd.
It's nice to do this or that,
but ultimately it's about what are you
going to do to win?
What do you,
what are you going to do to beat the
second best guy in the world?
That's a difficult,
difficult thing.
It has to be done correctly.
This idea of fighting to entertain this
is a very complex thing and you talked
about it with,
uh,
George addressing that are attempted to
address that in his comeback and trying
to finish and be more energetic and
aggressive.
But the reality is that's not always the
best way to engage.
There's is a right way to fight a person
with a particular skillset.
And especially in the Woodley,
uh,
versus,
Stephen Wonderboy Thompson fights.
Yeah.
I was like,
this is the only way to find that guy.
You cannot,
I mean,
unless you are what he is,
which is a very skillful traditional
martial artist that has this very unique
ability to bend at the waist,
like a snake and slide in with
techniques and it does a lot off the
front leg.
Dangerous stuff off the front leg.
Unless you can do that too.
You really shouldn't be on the outside
striking with him.
It's just,
it's just too weird that styles too
weird.
So he kind of had the lay back and if
you and I that again,
if you look at the results of the fight,
the times in the fight where someone was
hurt,
it was tyron woodley putting the hurt on
wonderboy Thompson.
Yes.
Those are the only times in the fight
where it was really exciting.
Other than that,
it was sort of wonderboy kind of trying
to pick out them from the outside and
um,
it's a very difficult fight to look good
at.
Um,
you know,
the whole idea of mixed martial arts
fans,
there's always three kinds of people
that watch mixed martial arts.
There's fans of drama is fans of
violence and his fans of strategy.
And technique.
Guys like us,
when we watch mma,
we fall into the technique and strategy.
That's the guy to me.
I can watch Woodley flight one,
the boy,
and I'm fascinated by that.
To me that's just like,
wow.
I said magic.
How can watch it all day?
Um,
many of the fans want to see violence.
That's what they're tracking too.
And it's a significant portion.
Um,
others like the idea of drama and
athletes in a sense have to brand
themselves according to one of those
three choices.
George always branded himself as the
technique and strategy guy.
Tyron Woodley struggling with that now
himself,
he's doing the same thing.
Um,
Kale Sona and is the quintessential
drama fighter.
He didn't really have an exciting
fighting style and he was never really a
technique and strategy guy.
So he went with drama.
Some of he'd done vocally,
um,
you know,
get like a violence based.
Find someone who's a mop.
How jaros that's his appeal.
You know the Johnson,
yeah.
Rumble Johnson.
It's a violence.
Okay.
He's not into drama,
is not going to talk anything.
He's not gonna.
He's not,
no one is stuck as strategy and t neat
guy,
he's going to come out and do the same
thing every fight and it's going to be a
violent finish.
Um,
so every fighter has to,
as it were,
identify what's his ear,
what's he gonna do,
what's going to be his appeal and work
within that.
And um,
you know,
tyron is learning.
It's not an easy thing to do.
You get criticism from certain,
uh,
as we said,
the other two elements of the,
of,
of the mixed martial arts audience,
that seems like the big fight.
It's certainly the big fight for Tyron,
but it seems like the big five for
Georgia as well.
Yeah.
It might only,
um,
reservation.
Uh,
when
you,
when you say,
is this the big fight,
is it essentially,
it's the same fight that George did for
a decade.
It's George against another very,
very tough welterweight.
What you did for 10 years was life.
Yeah.
But tyron is so,
he's especially dangerous.
I mean,
he's a more,
I think he's more dangerous than
Hendricks.
I think he's more dangerous than those
guys.
I think his ability to put you away with
one shot is,
but you could say top of the food chain
tricks was putting people away with one
shelf and one years.
Yeah,
he was Hendrix's fascinating case.
And we should probably talk about that
once the camera stops.
Um,
he's a,
he was a fascinating case and I can
understand why he was so successful,
but you know,
there's a lot to maintaining that.
There's a lot too is one thing to get to
a position where you are a world class
fighter.
It's like how long can you keep that up
to her?
And one of the most impressive aspects
of George's career was the fact that
George was able to keep that up for so
long.
People don't understand this.
They say,
um,
it's incredibly tough to become a UFC
champion,
but however tough net is,
it's 10 times tougher to stay there.
Um,
and on so many different levels too.
It's not just a physical thing.
The moment you become champion,
you become the most studied fighter in
the world.
Yeah.
Everyone knows every little weakness.
They see every little strength and they
can negate it.
And um,
psychologically it's tough to,
you know,
every time the other guy fights,
it's the biggest fight of his life where
he's,
every time you find it was just another
fun.
Is He a 10th title defense?
Fios is another flight.
The other guy across the ring,
this is the biggest moment of his life.
He's coming at you with everything.
He's gone.
This is his moment of glory.
This is literally gonna change his life
and keep them.
So Ufc champion feel is his the next
fight.
That's the question is like is it
possible for a champion to maintain a
challenges intensity through a 10 title
fight defect or do you just have to
accept the fact that you're dealing with
a completely different mind space?
I think ultimately you have to drop the
whole pretense that it's about intensity
because no,
I don't believe anyone can hold the same
amount of intensity of a teen years of
preparation.
You have to start thinking in terms of,
I'm going to defend my title with
technique and strategy,
because if you go with intensity,
you can only hold intensity so long it's
going to diminish and time as you get
paid more,
as you get tired,
as you get injured,
as years go by,
the intensity drops.
Now when you analyze various fighters of
today,
who stands out to you?
Who they lot.
There's some very,
very impressive people.
A guy who impresses me enormously is
Demetrius Johnson.
Yeah.
I extremely impressed by this.
I think he's the
greatest of all time.
Um,
oh,
it's hard to,
graceful time is such a tough thing to
say.
It's um,
uh,
with Demetrius that the open question is
always going to be what was the level of
competition.
Right?
But that's not his fault.
He can only fight the guys that give you
what's like Roy Jones Jr when Roy was in
his prime.
Yeah.
Same sort of situation.
He was so much better than everybody
else.
It's like how good were these guys?
I mean they were worldclass guys,
but against him,
they just looked like they didn't belong
in there.
What you typically find is that when you
come to a cs who's the greatest of all
time,
it's always going to come down to
criteria.
And um,
each guy,
his his strong point,
his claim to fame,
as far as,
you know,
I was the bass guy of all time.
Um,
let's stick with just UFC champions.
Otherwise we could have a discussion
where we too great if we go into pride
and you know,
sure he's getting,
it's going to get out of control.
Um,
but Demetrius Johnson's,
uh,
his,
his claim to fame is,
is the completeness with which he's
winning fights.
He's using everything beautifully.
He's knocking,
you know,
he's hitting people.
He's,
he's clenching people.
he's hitting clinched knockouts.
You know,
you don't see those often in the USC.
Um,
he's incredibly good on the ground.
A few times he gets in trouble.
He seems to navigate his way out without
a problem.
Um,
this a completeness in his skillset,
which is incredibly impressive.
Okay?
He's integrating wrestling and striking
and ways that just deeply,
deeply impressive.
Um,
you'll get someone like Jose Aldo who's
right up there in terms of,
you know,
as he wanted the grace of all time.
Um,
a sad thing about USC is that,
uh,
UFC fans I should say is that,
um,
people have very short memories.
You a guy loses a couple of fights and
suddenly he sucks.
And it's like,
dude,
Jose Aldo was a killer and you kill it
for 10 years.
Um,
and uh,
obviously very,
very skilled.
He had that and um,
and he fought,
you know,
many tough opponents.
And uh,
do you feel like when you see a guy,
like,
although you were just seeing the miles,
the miles pile up,
or do you think that Max Holloway,
he's not that old,
it's nothing,
all of that.
All 32.
Yeah.
So I'm reluctant to say it's the miles
and also wholesale to it didn't really
take a lot of damage and it's crazy.
And he's,
he's not like a guy that got knocked out
five times and you know,
it came back.
So in terms of like the damage he took
in his age,
I don't think it's a question of miles
and his,
do you think as a team it's a question
of the game just passing them by,
um,
new levels of the game?
I that's,
that's a great question.
Well,
I feel like Max Holloway's style,
it was almost like the perfect.
Yeah.
A lot of it comes out to styles and um,
and you're right,
uh,
Holloway's awkward distancing and things
like very good distance but also
phenomenal endurance,
unbelievable mental toughness,
extreme confidence in himself.
And he has the ability to break guys
just puts a piece on them.
Very Nick Diaz like in that regard.
Yeah.
It just puts that pace on him.
And you saw it with Aldo.
You see all those start to wilt cause it
almost thought as strongly in both
cases,
yes.
It starts very strong.
Well that's his thing though.
He's so explosive and he sprints
essentially.
But you really can't do that.
I mean,
his style is highlighted by incredibly
explosive,
fast movement and Max is not.
Maxxis is about avoiding and then
accumulation of bombs,
a of techniques keep it on you keep and
also his well-roundedness,
his ability to submit you ability to
absorb shots,
maintain composure when being fired upon
all those things.
Incredible strengths of his but
particularly,
uh,
matched up against Aldo.
His strengths really shine.
Yes.
Yeah.
But that's a,
Eh,
a whole mark of that if you're going to
call someone of the greatest of all time
is they have to be able to take on a
wide array of opponents and still be
successful.
Yeah.
Which is why Demetrius gets my vote.
I just feel like when you look at
Benevidez,
when you look at,
uh,
many different people that he fought,
showed him a bunch of different looks,
bunch of different styles,
and he was able to overwhelm the mall.
Wilson,
Hey,
what's your assessment of his fight
against Dominick Cruz?
Apple Weight Division?
See,
I look at that as a learning experience.
A different era,
a different guy.
He had a full time job back then.
It wasn't the same fighter happens if he
finds dominick Cruz is second time of
fascinated by that.
I want to see him fight Tj dillashaw
yeah,
I think that's the big fight because Tj
is willing to go down to 125.
So instead of fighting dominick at one
35,
Tj is like,
I can make one 25 and Tj feels like
he'll be the guy to break the legacy.
He'll be far bigger,
stronger.
It feels like he could match him speed
for speed and he thinks he can make the
weight comfortably.
I'm really fascinated by that.
Fine.
Because also I think Tj is one of the
few guys that's trained,
uh,
by,
I think Matt Hume is one of the great
unsung heroes of MMA.
I agree with it.
He's a master,
fascinating,
fascinating guy.
Incredibly intelligent,
deep,
deep knowledge of the sport.
Both stand up and on the ground and,
and integrating those two things
together.
He's one of the few guys you can
genuinely say his,
um,
uh,
expertise across all areas of mixed
martial arts and played a pivotal role
in taking someone from being an unknown
to a legitimate greg,
we'll champion,
um,
all the time.
I see people who,
people often don't make a distinction
between recruiters and coaches.
Okay.
This,
there's many fight camps out there that
are very good at recruiting people that
were already good and helping them to
manage them,
et Cetera,
and make them slightly better.
The world's full of recruiters,
but there's not many coaches out there.
Matt Hume took a kid who'd known,
had heard of and took him from obscurity
to arguably one of the best of all time.
Okay.
Um,
and he,
he did it in a way with that,
that kid went from being essentially a
wrestler to a genuinely well-rounded
mixed martial artist with a complete set
of skills.
Uh,
that's an impressive accomplishment.
Yeah.
Um,
and it's also his,
the way he does it,
the way he fights,
how little damage she takes.
Yes.
It's his movement,
his,
uh,
ability to control,
like a good example.
Dodson who fought John Dodson,
who's unbelievably explosive and fast
and dangerous and just overwhelmed him.
If Demetrius Johnson didn't exist,
Dolson would've been a very good
champion.
Oh yeah.
Highly regarded champion.
Yeah.
That people don't realize how good some
of these opponents adion and they say,
oh,
well,
I see the level of a ponant that
goodwill Dalton's it
very good at Dodson was especially a few
years ago.
It's extremely dangerous.
He seems to be in a bit of a Rut down,
whether it's a psychological rod or a
physical Rut.
It not quite the same guy that he used
to be,
but you know,
it's hard when a guy best you,
the way that mighty mouse best too,
because it seems like the level of
talent is so far above where you're at,
that you,
it's like you're left with a dilemma.
Like,
how do I catch this guy,
Ken?
Is it even possible for me to catch him?
Because they had two fights and the
second fight,
mighty mouse won handily.
He,
the first fight was closer.
The first fight was more dangerous.
He got hit a few times,
but in the second fight,
mighty mouse just showed leaps and
bounds and it was just a route he just
ran him over.
Um,
the other arguments are Anderson
Anderson in his prime is one of the,
uh,
it's a great argument for the greatest
of all time,
you know,
uh,
outside of the UFC,
it's fader.
I think those are really the only
arguments for the greatest of all times.
And George George's in there,
especially coming back and beating
bisping,
that puts him,
you know,
right back into the mix.
And in terms of a argument of one of the
greatest of all time.
Yeah,
I think it was an important step for him
because as I said,
there were three persistent criticisms
and he answered all three in one night.
So,
um,
that definitely helps his case.
What's your thought on could be abnormal
to madoff?
Extremely
embraced.
His kid is a deeply,
deeply impressive.
I've um,
uh,
he's coming to the academy a couple of
times before fights.
I've never actually seen him train.
Um,
he,
uh,
after his fight in Madison Square
Garden,
he bought himself and a group of his
friends,
his training partners came into the
academy and trained in my Monday
afternoon class.
It could be,
didn't train.
He just sat on the bench cause he'd just
support on Saturday nights.
Of course he's not going to train,
but his,
um,
his,
uh,
his training partners came in and
trained with a squad and that was a fun
afternoon.
They rolled with,
um,
I think mostly Nikki Ryan and um,
uh,
it's hard for them of course,
because it's submission grappling.
That's not really what they do.
They do more the interface of,
of um,
grappling to bind with striking.
So they had a hard time of it.
But,
uh,
he struck me as a very,
very nice person.
He shockingly big for his weight
division,
shockingly,
shockingly.
So,
um,
like all the people coming out of the
Caucasus regions of Russia has wrestling
is extremely good and they have probably
the base wrestling program in the world.
That whole area stretching from,
uh,
asitia through Dagestan's or Chechnya
all the way down to Iran at that areas
is the hotbed of wrestling in the world.
And it shows all find fighters.
They're all strong and wrestling and he
named is add to that,
the various skills.
And you've got a tough,
tough group
people.
Yeah,
I was extremely,
I bet I've been impressed with every
single performance he's had in the
octagon.
I mean,
he's a undefeated,
which is incredibly rare in and of
itself,
but in the hundred and 55 pound
division,
even more impressive.
But the way he mauled Barboza Jesus
Christ and you can see the fight was
essentially over halfway through round
one.
Yes.
Yeah.
You could see it in Barboza his face.
He was drained.
Yeah.
That was an incredibly impressive
performance.
Um,
I,
uh,
obviously there's still,
you can't put them yet and the grace of
all time category,
but he hasn't won a title,
hasn't even challenge for it yet.
But you definitely get the sense that
if,
if he had had a title fight by now,
he probably would have been a champion
by now hem versus Connor,
Jesus Christ.
That's what I want to say.
Him versus connor and Russia or him
versus Tony,
Tony Ferguson.
And then would be a very interesting
fight.
Well,
what's interesting about those two
fights as you have basically polar
opposites can be to him and we get all
of us a control based fighter whereas,
uh,
Tony Focus in is a scramble based fight
them.
And just that clash in styles is going
to be fascinating with regards conor
mcgregor and could be minimum get off.
The feeling one gets is that if they did
fight,
it would be a complete shutout in one of
two directions.
It's either like a man beating up a
child on the ground or it's just a flush
knock out a guy unable to cover distance
properly and walking into a left hand
and just being catastrophic k Ote.
And you feel like there's potential for
it to go in both directions.
Uh,
and
that's a fight I don't think goes to the
distance.
It's,
uh,
it's one way or the other.
Yeah,
I agree.
Um,
I feel like what connor presents,
it's interesting in terms of danger is
speed and one shot knockout power with
his hands and could be,
has been heard coming in by Michael
Johnson.
It's really the only adversity ever
suffered inside the occupant and he
dealt with it.
Well,
yes,
that's a good sign for debate.
It's a sliver of hope that every
opponent clings to.
They watched that one moment where
Michael Johnson clipped him and be like,
look,
he's human.
Yeah.
It can be hurt.
It's like the terminator if it bleeds.
Okay.
I believe that this predator.
Oh yeah.
What'd I say?
Terminator?
Yeah,
you just fucked up your reference.
Sorry,
I'm sweaty.
Ah,
yeah,
I did fuck it up.
Um,
but I think that connor has been
overwhelmed on the ground though and
he's been overwhelmed by Nadya's.
Yeah.
And he's been controlled in the ground
by Chad.
One gets the feeling that whatever
amount of controlled they were able to
impose on them would be nothing compared
with what could be,
could impose more of a,
could be busy.
Um,
it's a much more dangerous form of
control.
Could be.
Yes.
It could be,
has a program of hitting people on the
ground,
which is substantially better than
either of the two athletes you just
mentioned.
Yes.
Um,
and big differences when it could be,
gets you on the ground.
You're not getting up.
No,
you're getting mauled and it's almost
like a spider.
Like he's injecting venom into you and
slowly but surely like we can in your
body,
like you,
you see after the first round when
Barboza gets up,
it's like okay.
You mean he's,
he's alive still.
But this is a different person now and
going into the second round,
I mean the Barboza gave an admirable
count of himself.
I mean showed himself to be a true
warrior.
He did try a couple of spinning back
kicks in.
Yeah.
Some of them were relatively close.
Barboza is kicking.
Heavy strategy though is very different
than connors connors kicks or just the
opposite.
His kicks are just probes.
He sort of poking at you,
poking at you and it putting things out
in front of you and he's just tried to
just trying to drop that hard left hand
on you.
It's a fascinating guy.
It was fascinating.
I always undervalued him.
When he first came in the UFC,
I said,
oh,
it's high but typing.
But the more I started with we'll
wrestle.
He's saying he's very,
very skilled.
While he's also,
he mind fucks people.
He mind fucks people in a way that,
um,
but I don't think he's mind fucking
could be anything that works on could
be.
I don't think that's going to happen.
I just think there's,
we do dealing with a totally different
kind of human being.
Those people from Dagestan are just so
hard.
It's just a hard part of the world.
They're just,
they're made of hardier stuff.
You know what I mean?
It's just like they have to deal with
way more.
Not that people in Ireland are soft.
They're fucking hard people too.
I just think that with,
I've always said the most important,
if you have a pyramid of technique,
when it comes to mixed martial arts,
the base of the pyramid,
the most important thing is the ability
to control the grappling,
the ability to take a guy down.
If you can take a guy down and control
him,
you have a significant advantage.
You can choose where the fight takes
place and if you are competent in the
standup,
which could be was definitely competent
in the standup.
So you are adequate in the standup but
overwhelming when it gets to the ground.
You can present problems with a guy
standing up and which,
which case his problems.
The guy has to deal with the striking
aspects which opened up the takedowns.
Um,
I wholeheartedly agree with you,
but I'll go a little further.
Whenever someone asks me what are the,
what are the programs?
Well,
what do you look for when you see a guy
dominating fights?
What,
what,
what makes someone go in the right
directions with a training and,
and the fighting itself.
I always say this three things.
If you show me a fighter who can,
one,
dominate the setups to dominate the pace
of the fight.
And three,
how can I phrase this?
Dominate the simple direction of the
fight.
Three things.
Dominate the setups,
dominate the pace,
dominate the direction.
You show me a fighter who can do those
three things and I'll show you a fighter
who can win 95% of the fights he gets
into
dominate the setups,
dominate the pace,
dominantly direction.
Thinking about someone that could be,
or anyone who comes from a,
a,
a strong wrestling or judo,
Jujitsu with takedowns baseline is they
always kind of at a dominated direction.
They determine whether it goes down to
the ground over there where it say
standing to be always dominates the pace
of the fight.
Once you're on the ground,
you're on top.
The other guys is reacting to what
you're doing,
trying to get back up to his feet,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
You're dominating pace.
If there's one weakness that could be
pairs is,
is not as strong.
It dominating the setups to get to those
areas where he can dominate pace and uh,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
If he's going to lose a fight,
it's going to be in their area and
corner more than anything else.
As a guy who dominates the setups you
set up before the kicks,
a probe,
they're not kicks.
It's not trying to hurt you with the
kicks.
He's probing.
He hurts you with this.
Okay.
So connor skill is,
he's a master of dominating setups,
especially in a standing position,
but to beavs mastery.
Out of those three critical areas for
domination and all forms of fighting is
he's a dominant,
uh,
he's incredibly dominant in determining
the direction of the fight and the pace
of the fight.
That's why he never gets tired and it's
white.
It's got a very high work rate,
but he never gets tired.
He never see him just completely
shattered despite the [inaudible]
working
hard the whole time and the fight,
despite the fact that he's significantly
weakens themselves,
make 155 pounds,
which apparently he's done far better
now.
He had a real nutritionist heading into
this camp and it was much easier for him
to cut the weight.
I'd be fascinated to see him fight at
one 70 and,
well that's a plan.
Apparently that was a plan.
I'm woodley was joking around about it
saying he,
he'll send them nutritionists.
So Sal,
keep his psycho ass down at one 55 was
his exact,
that's fine.
Yeah.
With regards to your point before saying
this,
this core combat skill,
the most important one that you as a
commentator look for when you look at
finance,
you know,
um,
can you determine,
uh,
you,
you put grappling
skill,
is that number one same way.
There'll be wrestling with every samba
at the beach you get.
So what have you,
um,
I,
I would go through them and say,
yeah,
there's three things that I look for.
Who dominates the setups,
who dominates the pace,
who dominates the direction.
Now what are your thoughts about
strength and conditioning for mixed
martial arts fighters?
That's a,
that's a huge question.
But the question is like,
what takes precedent?
The skill training take precedent.
Like there's several schools of thought
and um,
one of them would be one of the more
interesting ones is nick curse on and
Marvin Marinovich that camp.
They believe that you already know how
to fight and that what the camp really
should be about is just radical strength
and conditioning to the point where,
let's,
uh,
that's a mixed question then.
Are you talking about a fight camp or
he's talking about fight training over
the year?
It's very difficult.
Let's,
let's talk about a fight camp and
specific.
Okay.
Average fight camp is around,
uh,
six to eight weeks and has the lungs,
you have a,
it's like a 10 to 12 weeks.
That's a,
that's a very,
very long fight camp.
Um,
how much physiological change can you
affect in the body and six to eight
weeks
she can,
you could tighten everything up.
You can,
you can certainly increase your
endurance,
your threshold,
your ability to work.
How much could you increase your vo two
Max and six weeks is a good question.
A few percentage points,
I believe.
Uh,
I think considerably less than that.
Really?
Yeah.
Hmm.
I don't know how much could you increase
your vertical jump in six weeks?
Not much.
Not much at all.
I'm not a big believer in the idea that
you're going to create big,
significant fight changing physiological
changes in six to eight weeks.
It's not really my experience.
Um,
but I can show someone a single
technique which can have a direct impact
on a fight.
I can show them that in five minutes.
Okay.
Um,
I'm not gonna claim to be a medical
expert who has a deep understanding of
these things about my experience in
coaching is that physiological changes
take time and you're not going to get it
done in a fight camp.
Yes.
You can make physiological changes over
a year,
two years.
Absolutely.
George went up a weight division.
Okay.
But it took quite a bit of preparation
to do.
So it didn't happen in six weeks.
What kind of strength training was he
doing to do that?
I know he's very involved in gymnastics.
George George has primary physical
training outside.
It has gymnastics.
He loves it.
Um,
uh,
he also for a time did Olympic
weightlifting.
Less so now than before.
But,
uh,
there was a time that was a big part of
it.
Um,
recently he started taking on a training
in water with various fins,
et Cetera,
to increase resistance.
And he's quite a fan of that.
But the truth is,
George go through,
goes through cycles and,
uh,
you know,
boredom is a factor.
He get bored at a certain
kind of physical activity and you want
to try something new.
Right?
And so he's gone through various cycles.
I can tell you this,
Georgia's strength has not significantly
changed despite the various changes in
physiological training.
Like when he did Olympic lifting,
he wasn't massively stronger than when
he did regular weight lifting or when he
did swim training,
I did.
I didn't feel like,
okay.
One made him stronger than the other.
Okay.
Um,
there's so many interesting questions
and the one you just asked it.
Okay.
Do I believe that strength is important?
Absolutely.
Okay.
And anyone who says that strengths
doesn't make a difference in a fight is
just straight up ignoring the obvious
facts is a reason why men don't find
women because there's massive strength
differences.
There's a reason why this weight
categories because there's big strength.
There was been heavyweight and
lightweight.
Okay.
Um,
strength makes a difference.
The proof of that is simple,
easy to observe.
Why do people take anabolic steroids?
Because they know that strength makes a
difference.
Okay.
And is there a reason why they are
illegal?
Because they do change the outcome of
fights.
So yeah,
strength is extremely important.
The question is how are you going to
build it and then are you going to do it
in camp?
Is your fight camp can be based around
strings?
That's a risky strategy.
Can you ready to get that much stronger
in six weeks?
Um,
I've always believed that the whole idea
of fight camp is to prepare an already
well trained athlete to get around the
problem of one individual.
It's programming one individual to solve
the complex problem that another
individual presents.
It's kind of like preparation for an
exam,
so to speak.
And um,
for me,
the whole,
the whole thing,
every flight campus motivated by two
very simple questions.
How are you going to win this fight and
how you not going to lose this fight.
The entire structure of the campus based
around that and almost all of it has to
do with tactics and techniques rather
than changes in the physical body.
Now when George is in off camp,
when,
when we say out of camp is that when he
would,
that's a period of skill acquisition,
trying to acquire new skills.
So that's when he would t I know he's
notorious for taking trips to like to
Brazil,
experimentation,
you know,
you bring in different perspectives at
different person,
hey this is interesting,
this has potential,
this doesn't really have much.
But then you start changing things up.
Now do you have that same approach with
all the fighters that you've worked
with?
It depends on the context.
How they mixed martial artists.
Did they train with me full time part
timers?
It would depend on the context.
I can answer with regards to the school.
Yeah.
Well I mean I'm,
what I'm,
what I was going to bring up is Weidman
Weidman's approach.
Um,
uh,
you know,
coming from that elite wrestling
background.
And then developing a lot of,
uh,
significant,
mixed martial arts skills.
He,
uh,
is in,
an unusual situation right now.
Right?
Where,
where does he stand in terms of like
future opponents?
Like where's he at right now?
That's,
uh,
that's a tough question to us to answer.
Um,
uh,
Chris I think had probably one of the
most meteoric rises into will change
chip level.
He literally beat twice in a row.
The guy that at that time was considered
by most people to be the greatest of all
time.
His run up to that was incredible.
I'm sure you've commentated many of
those funds until this kid who an
animal,
that the timeframe with which she went
from obscurity to world championship
level is incredibly,
should undefeated,
is insane what he was doing.
Um,
so there was this incredible meteoric
rise.
And then there was a,
a short period after that where he
appeared to be crushing great former
champions and the outer machito Vito
Belfort.
It wasn't just beating them,
he says smashing it.
And that makes it an incredibly
impressive.
Um,
and,
uh,
and then I think people were shocked by
what appeared to be an unbeaten record.
And then suddenly three losses in a row
and catastrophic iasis that we're
getting smashed by Luke rockhold getting
kod by a flying knee from Yoel Merrill
and getting dominated by gay guard
saucy.
And then all the controversy that it led
to that stoppage.
So it was,
it was three in a row that on a guy who
never even experienced defeat.
And so you go from no defeats to three
catastrophic defeats in a row that
that's,
that throws everything off.
Um,
but then he rebounded with even gas
finished one of the toughest guys in the
division and he's not an easy know.
You saw what guested on went on to do
with yes.
Bisbing bisbing and uh,
so yeah,
he's,
that was,
that was a great one.
That was a nice come back.
And,
but the question is,
where does it go from here?
Um,
uh,
and I don't have an answer for you.
I'm so sorry.
How often do you work with them on,
not often,
Chris.
Um,
Chris came to me as a student.
He was a student of met Sarah,
who's,
um,
one of my great friends and a,
a training partners from the Henzel
Gracie Academy.
And Matt was having some medical issues
and he said,
John,
you know,
can you take over this student of mine,
Chris Weidman,
this guy is incredibly talented.
I'd heard of Chris because you know,
we're linked schools,
uh,
fairly close by and people were telling
me about this amazing wrestlers,
you know,
uh,
incredibly talented picks techniques up
and you know,
I always take these things with a grain
of salt because people exaggerate and
stuff like,
so Chris started coming in and it was
all true.
This kid,
you can show him a teeny on Monday and
by Tuesday is doing a better than you
are.
And uh,
he has a gift for physical movement that
you don't see very often and guys that
big,
he's big,
agile,
highly intelligent and uh,
and had at that time a level of self
confidence that was deeply impressive.
I would show Chris a guillotine
variation and then five minutes later he
would be using it in the gym and then a
month later to be using it in an MMA
fight.
I guess he,
he literally would see opportunities and
immediately act upon them.
What I worry about with Chris is that in
those three losses,
W I'm not saying this has happened,
but what I worry will happen is it
fighters who are typically very dominant
and what confidence fighters when they
experienced a feet lose confidence and a
big pot of croesus success was that
ability to see opportunity and have the
confidence to immediately act upon it.
Um,
so my concern if I,
uh,
if I,
if I look at Chris's,
will that still be there when he still
had the same conference,
which was such a big part of his rise to
the top,
will it be drastically altered by three
losses?
And I'm,
I'm very pleased to say that it didn't
appear to be so in the fight with
guests,
Willem,
he,
uh,
he actually took a heavy hit at the end
of the first round in that fight and
came back at eat.
It looked like he had,
he'd gone through those,
those,
um,
those three losses and come back,
come back strong and everything was
fine.
So I'm pretty confident.
Uh,
Chris,
we'll go on to great success again at
one,
knowing how good Chris is on the ground.
How shocked were you about the Luke
rockhold fight?
Uh,
it was a hard one for me to watch.
Um,
uh,
Chris stopped working with me after this
second Anderson Silva fight.
We did most of that came together and
then,
uh,
he stopped working,
um,
uh,
with me move further out onto long
island.
He opened up a gym with Ray Longo and,
uh,
went back to train with Matt Serra and,
they,
those guys were incredible training
camp.
They did a fine job getting them through
the machine to fights,
et Cetera,
et cetera.
Um,
I went,
um,
uh,
I,
I was at that UFC,
uh,
it was in Las Vegas.
Conor mcgregor was the main event and
Chris was the,
uh,
Co main event.
And,
um,
uh,
the fight had interesting beginning.
Um,
Chris was doing well with the take
downs,
but,
um,
uh,
luke rockhold was doing a great job of
controlling Chris's head with like fake
guillotines to prevent any kind of
damage on the ground and doing a good
job of standing back up to the feet.
So there was no really significant
damage.
Um,
then they got into an interesting
kickboxing battle where,
um,
uh,
it,
it seems to go in one direction,
then switched directions and increased
seem to be getting the better of it and
things look good.
And then there was just one episode
where everything just came unstuck in a
second.
And I remember watching and it's like,
uh,
like watching a bad dream,
you know,
and um,
uh,
yeah,
it was shocking.
Yeah.
Chris,
through an ill advised wheel keck.
Yeah.
Which is slow and telegraph and rockhold
took him to the ground.
And what I was most shocked with
was,
and I've seen it time and time again,
I saw it in the David Branch fight and
sought in Leo Machida fight is rockhold
top game.
It's be fucking terrifying.
Pretty impressive,
very impressive.
Unbelievable.
I attribute that,
not just his skill,
which I think is considerable,
but also to training on a regular basis
with Daniel Carmia and Cain Velasquez is
just his wrestling,
his grappling,
it severely underrated.
Maybe not so now,
but his ability to control guys on the
ground.
It's just terrifying.
Generate an amazing job,
I hope.
Got very strong submission skills.
Yes.
People I didn't think talk about those
at all.
And uh,
he submitted a good people and he's hit
summit at Biscayne without one arm.
Good team.
Suddenly some of his finishes like
highlight reel finishes.
Beautiful.
Um,
you know,
he's got tremendous skills.
Um,
he's big for the division.
Uh,
he's uh,
you talk about a guy who,
uh,
Dominique's that pace and dominates the
direction he's,
no one can hold them down for any period
of time,
is great at getting makeup to his feet.
He wrestles the fence very,
very well.
Like all the Aka guys,
they're good on the fence.
Um,
he's a,
he's a very,
very impressive fighter.
I'm impressed with him and a lot of
ways,
but his ability to control top level
guys,
I just thought,
my thought was when he got Chris down
like,
okay,
Chris is a worldclass grappler.
He's going to be able to get out of this
situation.
That'd be scrambles to,
it's a lot happening,
but there was none of that.
It was just total control and ground and
pound for a considerable period of time.
Yeah,
it was rough.
It was rough to watch because it was one
of those where you could easily make the
argument for it had been stopped sooner.
Yeah,
I think so too.
it was a rough one.
Um,
and now rockwell is going to face Yoel
Romero,
which is very,
he's the freaking ball freaks.
That's like that guy was made in a lab.
Yeah.
Isn't Yoel Romero with fighting dated
Brunch?
No.
Did this happen recently?
Yes.
Uh,
I've been at Robert Whitaker,
got injured.
What happened?
The knee again,
most likely if I had a gas,
I don't think they released it,
but there's been an injury.
Maybe it's a different entry,
but um,
when did this happen?
A couple days ago.
Wow.
I've just flown to California and using
the Internet.
So yeah.
So rock.
Good for you.
It was only two days.
Joe should all say that.
Um,
but a rockhold and you'll,
well now we're going to fight for the
interim belt.
That's a huge development.
Yeah.
Big Development.
Wow.
Yeah.
Um,
that's uh,
I mean Yoel Romero.
That's um,
it's,
that's a different vibe.
Yoel Romero is probably the most
uncontrollable man in the universe is a
difficult,
difficult posting to control in any
aspect of the fight.
He's a fight is some parts of what he
does make no sense.
Like he's one of the greatest grace
lists of his generation and many people
take them down.
Yeah.
It gets taken down all the time,
but they kind of control and he just
springs back up.
He's not worried about being taken down.
I think that's part of it.
Yeah.
Cause he comes so hard with the upper
body leaves the lower body open and um,
and you're right,
there's no consequence to it.
He can just get up whenever he feels
like it.
Um,
he,
he has a greater propensity to change
direction at speed than anyone else who
would have seen in my life.
Yeah.
People always talk about speed.
They're all,
you know,
this guy's font.
So that guy's spas to me,
the only kind of,
there's two kinds of speed,
they don't impress me in fighting.
One is the speed of decision making.
Okay.
If you can make decisions,
good decisions faster than your
opponent,
you gotta win a lot of fights.
And the other is your ability not to go
and straight lines at speed.
But to change direction.
Speed of directional change is the most
important kind of physical speed.
And fighting I'll get is plenty of
people that weren't really that fast,
but they can change direction quickly.
And that's the kind of speed that counts
and fighting.
So the two kinds of speed that you
needed to be to be a fighter was speed
of decision making.
And a speed of directional change.
And you see lots of fast people that
there's a Hussein bolt is fast,
but he's not fast and directional
change.
It's not his thing.
But I think that Yoel Romero is,
there's this certain twitchiness to his
movement where it's so hard to read
where he's going,
where he's going to be in the next half
second.
That's,
it's just a handful to deal with that.
That is a very good assessment of what,
what's shocking about him,
his ability to go from zero to 60 insist
freakish shin.
This is him at 40.
Yeah.
What was he like when he was 25?
He just doesn't look like a 40 year old
man and just everything is wrong.
Yeah.
It doesn't look like a normal person.
Like if you look at his body,
his proportions,
everything looks like something from a
movie.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
And that flying knee that he hit Chris
with was like,
she,
she's Christ and now he could feel it.
And the audience,
it was,
uh,
it was terrible.
It's just the,
the amount of force that he can generate
is just stunning.
But he's also a guy that's carrying
around a tremendous amount of muscle and
I wonder what kind of pace he can keep
up.
You know?
And we saw that in the whitaker fight,
you faded a bit and that fight,
one of losing that fight,
and we've seen it in several,
was fights.
The Tim Kennedy fight,
you faded in that fight and eventually
came back to win.
But he's got so much to feed.
There's so much tissue,
you know?
Yeah,
yeah.
No,
he's a fascinating character and
fascinating.
And again,
boy wouldn't you have loved to seen him
in the UFC at 26 yeah,
I mean when he was just dominating
everyone,
the wrestling scene and he says he's as
good as I get in Raceland metaled into
every single world class competition he
ever answered.
Not only that,
but the best wrestlers in his weight
division of that time.
He beat all of them like crazy.
It's as good as he did it.
The hard to imagine.
Yeah.
All right John,
I think we've covered
basically enough or it's a,
we're three hours in here,
man.
Oh my God,
this is awesome.
This is longer than one of my instagram
posts.
Your instagram posts are amazing,
by the way.
I'm a huge fan.
You're,
you're one of the few.
That's not true.
I have a lot of friends share them.
They didn't send them to me in text
messages.
Occasionally you are breakdowns of
technique and strategy and what is
actually happening.
I think they're critical.
I think your voice and what you're
doing,
like with the squad and what you're
doing for,
for Jujitsu as a whole and the way
you're able to articulate that and break
these things down,
it's,
it's really,
really critical.
I think it's awesome.
Thank you.
Very [inaudible].
Say thank you and I'm really glad we
finally got a chance to do this.
It's better than a meeting at Denny's.
Yes.
Denny's for meeting.
It was fun to,
um,
what is your twitter for people?
Is it just John,
Donna her on instagram rather?
You don't have a twitter?
I believe it's Danaher.
John Danaher.
John.
Yeah.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Thank you brother.
Cute.
Okay.