This episode of Your Mom's house is
brought to you by Saatva luxury mattress.
The only online mattress company that
provides free delivery set up and mattress
removal.
Well, no, well no.
Christina.
Hey, what's up everybody? I'm Tom Segura.
I'm looking for a ride or die chick.
She's Christina piece.
She's a government informant.
Let's get on with the show.
I'm very happy and excited to announce
that I haven't added a fourth show.
Holy God at the Merriam
Theater in Philadelphia,
Aka fill her up.
Delphia Pennsylvania.
This one is going to
make sure I get it right.
Is going to be Friday. Uh, what month?
October. No, November. Friday,
November 16 the 10:30 PM show.
All the other shows are sold out.
So if you waited your now the clock
is ticking. Get your tickets. Friday,
November 16th,
10:30 PM.
There will not be any more shows added in.
Fill her up.
Delphia very, very excited about that. Um,
only thing else left with
tickets is Fresno Fart know,
uh,
Bakersfield has a few tickets left and
there is also tickets at Fort Myers,
Florida.
Um,
there might be also some at that
Wednesday show in Montclair.
Mom, Claire, New Jersey.
That's a the week of the Philadelphia
shows. So that would probably be the 14th.
The 15th is sold out. So
that's it. Thompson, right.com.
Click on the tour page. And as I
mentioned before, if you didn't do it yet,
a lot of you did. Thank you
very much. Sign up for the, uh,
email lists that I have.
There's a big email,
email announcement that will only
be via email coming in a week or so.
Um, that's what I got a
snitch. What do you got?
Huh? Hey, excuse me. Tom Bundy.
Tom Wayne.
Gacy.
What'd he got there before
you tell your FBI agent?
What do you tell me what you got?
Uh, so I've added this show
and man, Diego, California,
the seven o'clock is sold out.
So I edit a 10 o'clock show at the House
of Blues and then December 7th and fill
her up Dell at Phia, at the punchline. Um,
it looks like that shows about to sell to,
so we're going to add a
show there December 8th.
Out of the 10 30 show at the Gramercy
theater in Ju Dork teddies and those
tickets are flying to, so if
you're thinking about, uh, going,
you should definitely get
your tickets because, uh,
I'm not staying longer in judo.
Arcadis AI got babies and stuff one
night guys. That's how I roll. That's it.
That's it. It's going to be
online. Yeah, that's right.
What are you doing besides murdering?
I'm doing shows in a murder.
People after the shows,
you put together the case against
me by just seeing where I tour.
Are you going to follow people? That's
how they got that. Uh, uh, Vince,
what was his name? Komodo. No, the, the
rape. The Co, the comic rapists. They,
they were like, oh, there's
a show in Gainesville.
And then there was a show in Starkville
and then there was a rape and each city
and it's cool. Well, just lines up
with your touring schedule, man. Yeah,
that's just like you.
Perfect cover.
Let's get on with the show.
Are you ready to get started? My
dearest ball hog. You ready to go?
Okay, here we go, boy. Oh
boy. Oh boy. Oh Shit. Blanca.
Oh, good. Quiet, nice and quiet.
What's happening today? Right?
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome everybody from [inaudible] USA,
California. And uh, I am a, with
a very, very interesting, uh,
Eh, Eh, El name is Mr
[inaudible] Hawaii. Oh,
I miss this. Go Away. You have a lot
of business. A lot of interesting.
Yes. Eh, but eh, we cheese, uh,
your main characteristic,
you're hit your main characteristic.
Well,
my main characteristic, my
specialty is, uh, face farting.
Randy,
loving to live well.
Well, no, go to your mom's house.
Oh man, I can't believe you're not tattle
telling on me for something right now.
Hey,
it's good to be back.
Always love doing the podcast Hashtag
turned him in its movement on Twitter.
Now hashtag she's a snitch letter go.
That's the other movement.
That's the only other psychos would
endorse your side on these things.
I'm just saying a lot of people
wait in last week. A lot like crazy.
If he missed it.
Um,
it really took off also on social media
about whether or not I have a ride or
die chick. And I gotta tell
you I do math. And, um, look,
it's just, you know, it's your choice.
You let me know who you are. Is it, is it,
is it,
I chose to protect our children.
You're not protecting your children
and protecting our children.
If you suddenly start going on a murder
spree because the Barista at Starbucks
got coffee order wrong.
You don't think that I have a right to
protect our kids and turn your ass in.
First of all,
I just got upset with somebody else.
They ain't going to sit with my family.
So I don't see how the two are connected.
Okay. Because it's something and I
need your help and you're like, no,
I'm going to leave you behind.
Yeah, you're right. Gosh,
I am just a terrible life. Well,
that's the consensus for sure.
I told you I would help you bury
the body in cases of manslaughter.
Involuntary, right? Yeah,
but not premeditated.
Only if it's to protect
our family and if you,
if we're hurting like a child molester
or a rapist and I take joy helping the
listeners a reality.
Okay. They don't have,
they don't have to children
to protect the listeners.
A lot of comments and messages,
but we also got a bunch of emails.
I'll read some of them right now.
Please let me get this kind of be, look,
here's the first email. Tom's wrong. If
someone harms family, I'm all for events,
otherwise runaway and called the cops.
Also,
sulfuric acid is used in pool maintenance.
Uh,
is that what, okay. Just this coincidental
that they mentioned that. Huh? Sidebar.
This is what they mentioned. Hello.
Tommy jeans and Mommy, Christine,
my wife and I were listening to last
week's episode and the question of loyalty
was brought up between your marriage.
Would you wrap me out if I killed someone?
I expected my wife to carry the same piece
of shit feelings as Christine but was
done when she said that
Tommy is 100% right.
Sounds like Christine's genes can only
become a certain amount of high and tight
before she's the one that, that uh,
the very valid she promised. Uh,
it looks to me that Tommy
is not only the water champ,
but the marriage champ as well. Way To
really fucked that one up. Christine.
Todd is the psycho champ is what
he is. More messages. Hey Man,
Richard Kuklinski Aka the ice man.
Earns a well deserved reputation
as a cold blooded killer,
but manages to keep his
violent professionals secret
from his wife and children
for years. Hey Chris, niches. That's
your nickname. What the fuck? Okay.
These are weighted towards
you in case you haven't.
All I needed to slow one for sin is me
and my girlfriend down to ride to the
bloody end. Just me and my girlfriend.
That's Tupac. Um, Christina,
I cannot believe how you would
turn in. Tom. Fuck you rock.
That's my favorite email
that's ever convert.
These are all slightly weighted
towards your, when you read the emails,
they're all in supportive view.
Let's just put it that way. I just,
I put this together and I just see what
kind of wife and mother would I be if I
didn't protect our children from a
psychotic believe the term is half assed.
Wow. Wow. Wow.
Hi, I'm, I'm ride or die.
Up until that premeditated,
I'm a snapped because some guy cut
me off in traffic. I told you that.
Okay. Who's going to be your
second spouse? Let's talk dummy.
Who's not going to fucking push back and
get me shit. You're Dalmatian wise. Yeah.
She's definitely not going
to say anything. Dalmatian.
My wives don't say anything. No.
Yeah. Yeah. They're pretty good. Uh,
whatever. Look, this is
such a ridiculous topic.
You're clearly about to
snap anyways. Yeah. Right.
You watching Ozark now you're 10 episodes
ahead of me. I'm the only one. No,
I like that show too.
By the way.
If you face farted on people,
he would kill them. Think so.
That was a bad one last.
That's what I was going to go.
That's where I was going on.
Let's get back to her. Thanks
for doing that. Oh wait.
Oh, burp to now. Come on. If
you're going to fart like that,
at least have the matches nearby. I know.
I didn't know what was in there though.
Yeah. Face farting. Well, um,
why don't I show you
what the,
what the moment is.
He's like book. I love this. A setup.
This is part of that, you know,
this is part of the, his arousal is
pretending to not know what it is.
Andrea did pray for her as a show
called her. I Dunno, but mistress.
Why she looks very cute. Um, she's
dressing like me. She's wearing jeans.
I like her. She's not my same. I wonder
if she can part like you. I bet you
nobody can find like me.
This guy's like do not know
if face farts. And she was like, I'll
show you. And He, and he goes like,
I don't know.
What is it? Can you, can you explain
to the people that watch? What is it?
Eh,
what is baseball?
Oh Wow.
Cool.
Mariachi modality.
Hey Pete Souza.
I'll show you nothing.
Are you ever to go down? Yeah. Dip Shit.
That's the best way. If you want
to know what I do in my specialty,
you should try it.
And Italians,
they'll fucking do anything.
She animals maybe not in
front of the Jack in the box.
She not one on deck. She's
always ready. Schoolwide.
Wow. She is fully smarter than
them. So she's got a big ass too.
Oh, she just fired on that guy's face.
He's smiling. He fucking loves it.
And he goes, oh my gosh. I did not know
what you meant when you said if face,
no, I see. So it's that. You
actually fart in my face.
Could you imagine having this job?
This guy's job?
Yeah.
You're going to be a reporter.
We're going to send you out to the Jack
in the box and you're going to let this
chick fart in your face
in the parking lot.
This has gotta be just a joke set up for,
for the new facility.
Oh, you're right. This is
like one of those porno. Yeah.
Set up all this stuff better than
me. He's a real journalist. Oh,
I thought he was visiting America.
I met a nice lady and she's like,
I faced [inaudible]. He's like,
what is this all about? It's how far
and the far comes in. The next thing.
He's like, you said it's
harder here. Monday legs.
She's like, yeah, show
me. It's a little gooey.
Stuff comes out.
Do you think
she does? Oh my gosh. Oh my gosh.
He is. Huh? He's very,
he's very dangerous.
These because they see that we are in war.
Huh?
Oh my gosh. Eh. Deletions 40 aura.
Your characteristic or your beauty
this because you are a very,
very beautiful girl.
Butter
man. Do you think her dad, hey, here's
a scenario what your dad's looking,
I should try it.
Your Dad's looking to jerk one day and
he's searching for the porn he likes.
Yeah. And you know how all the other
subjects come up. All the other types.
Yeah.
Is Your Dad and then like come to
Christ and it's his little girl.
How many times do you think that
happens? Happens all the time. Yeah,
but if you're, if you're the dad of,
of the metro mistress at [inaudible],
you're like, yeah, she's
dropping farts. I mean it's, I,
it's probably a different feeling than
if you see your daughter in a blow. Bang.
Do you think that's the worst thing to
see your daughter do and porn? Let's,
let's, no, probably it's double or triple
anal is probably the worst. That's what,
no, but blow bang. Maybe Blow Bang, wait,
what's a blow? Bang again? Like blow jobs.
Yeah.
But like it's,
it's when there's like eight guys
standing around her and she's like,
like looking up. She then the shows I
[inaudible] she loves it. I love it.
I love it. How much do you think, how
much do you get paid for the Blow Bang?
Because the agents got to call her and
be like, all right, I got you a gay.
Normally here's the thing,
I'm going to hook you up normally.
You know how you get like 500
bucks for a blowjob? Yeah.
Well I got you 800 bucks for 10
blowjobs actually for more it's less.
Right.
But if you stay long a dollar and you
blow everybody there, yeah. You get $400.
Yeah. Okay. Cause we're
paying for your travel. Yeah.
Free lunch. Free lunch and yeah,
whatever. Whatever you want to eat after.
I can't,
I can't imagine.
I'm trying to think of what I would
personally consider a way worser.
Is it the blow bang, wait, wait, is it,
what is worse to see your
child doing? Hi. Yay. Ooh.
Fufu cause see something about like
five dicks over the face and just on the
face seems really kind of
degrading. Right? Seams, seams.
I'm talking pure optics.
So,
uh, but then again, if you know, if
there's two dicks in her ass, you're like,
I fucked up. I didn't do anything.
I did, I did things wrong. Right.
So you're saying to me what you're asking
essentially is what's worst parenting?
What's the result of worst parenting,
multiple decks in your mouth or multiple
dicks in your butthole and virgin?
I think, I think I'm going to
go with the double penetration.
I do think there's nothing worse.
I imagine that seeing it then,
I think it's the most challenging of
the things to doing something away from
your face.
For some reason it feels like these guys,
they did something to your body,
but there's almost like a,
they did it to you and it's not,
it's not on you,
but the blowjob is a voluntary act.
You can just lay there and take,
I'd be like,
it was terrible.
But if you're like and she and she's
going from one to the next around the
circle, you know, oof.
And then every guys are hold on and then
she has to like let it go on and then
then do the big smile.
That's the worst part is that
she's got to act like she's like,
how was today?
It's so much fun.
I was awesome. I was really the top,
she has to pretend like it was a little,
oh my God,
you guys are so disgusting.
Her life was as second all those guys off.
Okay, so here's the thing now speaking
of, I would rather do the fart face.
I would do face farts all day over
any of the other stuff in porn.
If I had to pick a lane.
I don't understand. He knows
what it is. Definitely.
I am very excited about,
he ain't too dumb for face farts now
speaking of too dumb to come a lot.
That's also been very popular.
Big,
big issue on our show
and we got this message.
I think I found the right photo for
the not too dumb to come shirts. Cool.
Hope you find this useful,
your ride or die, Chris rude.
There it is. And there's forest
and he's got his eyes closed.
It looks like he's choosing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. There you go.
He's playing ping pong. Good job forest.
Yeah. He's even got a dumb haircut.
You know, I was just thinking that
dumb, that hairpin persons cut.
There's a certain look. What kind of
luck? Well done. People have a certain
look sometimes, I'm sure.
Sure, sure, sure, sure, sure.
Talk strictly hair if gt kind of an honor.
No,
I got some bad submissions for FTT RTD.
Yeah.
People were like doing things like, oh,
it's FTD RGT. I'm like, Dude, look at,
look at the letters first
before you submit. Um,
so, oh, where's that one? I
wanted to pull up this to you.
God, I hate it for kids
to porn, but for Simon,
it's just as bad if your son does it.
Then if you're a little girl as it, right.
So do you remember our, doesn't
even answer me. Sorry. Say it again.
What's the way worser? What? Your son
doing porn or your girl doing porn? Well,
everybody always assumes that
it means that you go, oh,
it's worse than my daughter is doing porn,
but I don't think,
I think it's kind of jokey to be like,
I'm really thrilled that
my son's doing foreign.
I don't think that really happened.
I don't think a parent of a of
a guy is stuffy. Like, dude,
it's great.
Like my kid fucks a lot.
Like I don't think that
conversation really happened.
There are more of a commodity in this
business because they're so rare. Yeah.
Guy That can do that on command
is, it's a talent. It's a talent,
but I still don't think the parents
are like, it's really great.
Where is our kid fell into that he didn't
know how he can get hard all the time
and now he gets to show
Pete come on command.
That's a bigger towns a lot and
he comes down and eat them too.
And just bigger town than that guy
that's claps and slaps is actually,
it is a bigger town. Kind of
should be a little more celebrated,
but I think it makes for a lot of
probably conversations that, you know,
I think there's a lot of parents in that,
in that position that probably go like,
ah, he's a, he paints,
he's taking pictures,
performance artist in La. Yeah, no, he's
done some acting, but he really, he,
he actually had making furniture and he
loves it. They're doing stuff like that.
Yeah. They're not like, he's rock
hard when you need them to be. Yeah.
I wonder if Rocco's a Friday's parents,
were they proud of him? Um, well,
didn't his dad die?
His mother died when he was younger.
I know his dad died when he was younger
and the mother was alive and then when
his mom died,
he went over to his mom's best friend's
house and put his dick in her mouth and
came immediately and ran away in shame.
Yeah. Yeah. Just what anybody does when
they're grieving grieves differently.
When his mom saw him
masturbating when he was a child,
she winked at him and smiled. Oh Wow. That
kind of, and he was like, this is great.
This is a good thing on
the right path here. Yeah.
Is that what your mom did
when she found you? Nope. No,
my parents really were so
fucking weird about sex.
They kind of aren't they? Yes. I
think looking back you go, you know,
when you try to like analyze your parents,
you realize they're just people.
You know,
there's just people out there and in
most cases people are doing the best they
can in most cases. I don't
know. I mean, you know,
most people's parents are
doing the best they can be.
People are neglectful and shitty. I'm
trying to say that's the best thing. Yeah.
But I'm saying like in my parents' guys,
they're not neglectful and shitty.
We're doing the best they can. But
I think that there was, you know,
they were so uncomfortable with just,
I think my dad would have been a little
different about it if he hadn't been
with my mom who was much
more so an old school,
Catholic Catholicism. And it sets
South American breed of it where it's,
it's a, it's kind of heightened. I mean
she did boarding school with the nuns,
you know, it's like, I'll tell you
and listen, I wasn't raised religious.
My parents were communists.
They weren't coming for their
raised in Communist countries. Yeah.
So when we came to the states
were Catholic by tradition,
but not by practice.
I didn't get weird about sex until
I went to Catholic high school.
Middle of the Catholics
will do elementary school.
I don't think I stopped feeling guilty
about it until I got married. I mean,
and that's like not even from my home,
not just from school,
like stuff that I picked up,
dude. My parents were like,
if my mom saw like a woman
in a bikini and she's like,
are you watching pornography?
Seriously? So I'll be like, oh my God.
Like I thought just a woman's body. You
shouldn't be, but it shouldn't be like,
that's nice. You know, it's changed.
It's changed in ladder. Like, you know,
like as we become adults, it's not as
weird. But when we were kids, oh my God.
But no gotta feed. Everything's
poor. No, like a woman's legs,
Porno. I remember asking my
dad, I mean, think about it now.
It's also just a change in culture, like
the way people talk to their kids now,
you know,
but I asked him if he masturbated
when I was a a kid cause I was sorry,
I'm not sure. And he goes, no,
I go, did you ever masturbate?
He goes one time, like a one time,
cause you had when I was 16 and I go,
what happened is like that's it. So I
just went in my room like, fuck yeah,
you're the Weirdo.
You feel like a real weirdo now.
That's the kind of stuff I'm
talking about where you were like,
what the fuck man, it's not
good. It's not good for kids.
And then I tried to bring it up again.
I told you that right where I came out
of the shower and I didn't know how to
talk. I was like 10, like, uh,
um, uh, so can I talk to you?
He was like, yeah. And you know,
you could tell it when it's
hard for a kid to say something.
I was taking a shower.
I remember this like it was yesterday.
I was taking a shower and
um, I was washing, you know,
my privates and um,
uh,
all this stuff came out and then he goes,
next time, don't wash there so long.
I was like, all right. That was it.
And that was, that was the conference.
I was like, I'm trying to talk to you
about this and not feel weird about it.
And he was like, yeah, you don't want
to do that. Just watch what's on TV.
Let's watch the football game.
But that's the hangup about sex.
And I have to say after having two babies,
you really realize that it's just a
part of the bigger picture of human
reproduction. It's
really not, you know, my,
my boobs are food for somebody right
now. My badge was a portal of, for some,
for two people to come into this planet
like you, the, you know what I mean?
It's not, it's no mystery and your sex
and sexuality, it's like, what the fuck?
I would have a whole different psyche
about this. If I was raised differently,
I probably wouldn't find sex stuff
is funny as I, because it's so taboo,
so taboo deep like it's in
my brain's DNA that has,
you know, well, cause I had the opposite.
My parents were oversexed and it was so
open all the time. We talked about sex,
you know,
my mother wanted to teach me and I was
reading books about it when I was like in
third grade and she would show me her
edible underwear and her discussing sex
toys and stuff.
Like it was almost too much for me.
It was over stimulation to our ninth. Now
I'm totally not, I don't care. I'm like,
oh well that's a body they fuck.
Yeah.
But I wonder where we both got
our love of poop stuff from.
That's a difference to, well, my dad
champion that. That's true. Yeah.
My Dad's a big pen. I can't tell you like
I didn't think it was, I wasn't like,
this is awesome. But I did
react. I loved more upset my mom.
Yeah, that's, that was the, that was more
the draw of it to me was that he was,
he would be like, take a
shit. He'd be like, yeah,
he'd get all excited and I'd be like,
yeah, I took it. I wouldn't be like,
as excited as he was, but then
she will be so upset. I was like,
this is pretty good stuff cause it makes
mom mad. Makes my med. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
That makes my man I wanted to do talked
about shitting a lot in my house.
It was just constant.
Every you just want to take a shit.
You talked about it after. Yeah. No, he,
he 100% every day. Yeah. It's still how's,
you can take a shit that was good shit.
Yeah. I got to tell you, tell you
ahead. Kind of, kind of sloppy,
sloppy Joe every day.
My mother liked poop stuff and it was
actually my mom. That's hilarious. Yeah,
she loved it. She's always, she,
my mother had kind of what you would
consider a low brow sense of humor and
surprise. And she liked like they call it
like a [inaudible] tumor and Hungarian,
like a farmer. And I think that's totally
where I get it from. And my dad too,
like Cheech and Chong and
Eddie Murphy and you know,
we're not highfalutin folks
over at the budget skis were no,
definitely fucking dirt dogs. Speaking
of this topic, do you want to,
we actually had our question answered
about queef versus fart debate.
There's no I've answered
no, no. The debate,
the debate was answered by a
doctor for us. Oh, it's your life.
So a doctor or the cock doc reiterate.
What's the question again?
If,
um,
the question was, I think you
pose the question, you said,
is it a Queef if it comes from
your ass or is it definitely from,
but sex? Yeah. So we're like,
is it if there's, if there's,
if there's air pushed in during
anal sex when it escapes,
is that a farm x scapes,
x scapes? Is that a fart?
And I thought it was not, and I think
you said, well look, it's a butthole.
So when anything, any air
comes out, it's a fart is says,
well or it's definitely not a queef.
Queef comes from the machine.
I get what you're saying. So let's do
what the doctor says. Another category.
This is a practicing urologist.
I can't believe,
I can't believe doctors listen to this
show. And this guy has messaged me and,
and uh, and I've, I've messaged,
we've sent messages to each
other and he's a real doctor. Um,
allow me to settle your queef
versus fart debate definitively.
This comes down to definition though.
You might be right Jane. Okay.
Queef is a vaginal expulsion of air your
email or was raising the question of
whether or not it matters what the
origin of source of said air is.
But the answer is that it doesn't matter.
And here's why.
Sex is not the only source of queefs.
And not all queefs are expulsions
of air that has been forced inside.
For examples.
There are diseases that can result in
the formulation in the formation of a
Fistula, which is an abnormal
connection between two hollow organs.
A Colo vaginal fistula is an abnormal
connection between the colon and the
vagina. This can result in gas from the
colon being expelled through the vagina.
That's crazy. Even though the gas
is a byproduct of regular digestion,
since it's expelled via the vagina,
it's technically a queef air
coming out of the vagina.
Likewise,
air forced into the rectum during anal
intercourse that subsequently expelled is
a fart because farting is the expulsion
of air through the anus regardless of
its source of origin. Sorry, Tom.
Christina is right by the way.
Huge congrats to Christina for
creeping out that baby. Also,
please add some tampon Florida dates so
we can come out and see you guys. Uh,
this is the, keep those jeans high
and tight. Dr Pecker checkers, MD. Um,
he really is, I swear to some guy in
Florida, I promise you. I promise you.
Um, while we're on the subject, your
farts and either way in two parts,
do farts pushed the shit out or
do Brown's push the farts out?
The answer is that it's both.
There's only so much space and split test.
Everything has propelled all
together by the muscle action.
It's possible that Eric and
filter around the browns,
but the browns and farts are both
pushed along a by what? Paris.
Dallas and those traveled together.
Teamwork makes the dream work. People,
this guy sent me photos from his practice
of stuff that would just make your
eyes water. Shall we see them? Can
we see that? We could see them?
I don't know if I should. I mean
you can't. I'm sure you can't bro.
I guess we could under the like, hey,
we're studying medicine here, but okay.
I mean, we're talking like disease
Dick. Dick. Really? Yeah. Okay.
Well let me set it up. Maybe I'll
set it up for when our, sure.
Maybe we could show our guests. Um, what
a neat idea. I can't believe it so far.
It's the shit out. Oh, this is
felony shit poses a farts out too.
You're not even going to marvel at this
revelation. It's absolutely fantastic.
Thank you doctor Cock Doc.
I'm just saying that from my whole life.
I thought farts push the shit out.
And then doctor drew came by and he said
it was, what'd he say? Neither? Yeah.
He was like, oh fun. I know
they happen there, Eric,
irrespective of one another and
now this guy saying it's both.
So it's like blowing my mind.
It's like when you find out that
light is both wave and particle,
you know what I'm saying? Yeah,
no, I know what you're saying.
Pretty exciting stuff.
Well,
I guess I did think that she has
pushed the farts out. You know,
I thought the farts push the shit out.
My thought,
my mom was right about that because she
would always love for those who don't
know, my mother would say whenever
I, whenever I'd Fart and I'd be like,
Oh guy for it.
And she'd be like,
be grateful for the farts because farts
Bush this shit out without the force.
There is no shit. Wow. Yeah.
In a way. And she's right.
Um, our guest is here. Should
we go get them? Yeah. Yeah.
And there's some really important stuff
I want to get to. I mean, I'm serious.
Really important. No, this is good
stuff. Like really important. Yeah. Okay.
All right. All right. We'll
be right back Jean or back.
We're doing a little mic
tracking. Okay. Yeah.
Where he sound different
there Tom. That's, thank you.
That's the guy that can't stop coming.
That's,
he comes at his dad's funeral a
hundred times back in the news. No,
you would not believe the
sophos that was prepping today.
And what happened was our producer
thought we were recording tomorrow. Yeah.
So usually sends me a folder of
all these files of things to play.
So he messaged me, he's
like, I fucked up. I'm sorry.
So I'm like pulling stuff on my own
and it's not the same cause it's like,
you know, it's usually organized and
I just hit a button and it plays.
So I'm going through emails and
I see this thing about this.
This is probably like the episode
that I would say at least early on,
best to find our shows them. Yes.
We did a huge segment on this guy.
When you're on your knees at your
father's funeral, at his casket,
you were saying goodbye to him.
And then we have nine orgasms right
there by your whole family is standing
behind. You never want to have
another orgasm as long as you live.
Why not
just keep on com.
And it was like a documentary like
thing they did on this guy who has this
condition where he just comes all day,
every day and it's ruined his life.
But he orgasm, he did. He doesn't come.
Doesn't come right every time. No,
but it's the ability,
he's like,
can't go to like my kid's
soccer games on the side,
but you know like I'm like go.
And then he's like,
you just orgasm and he's got erections
all the time and he feels it was horrible
cause he's like,
I feel bad being around my kids cause
I'll just start orgasmic as I'm looking at
my kids and, and he's
like, you know, I can't,
I can't, I feel like an
asshole if I'm ordering dinner.
And I come and like I'm just nothing.
But what's the name of
the condition? Oh man, it's
probably in this thing,
multiple orgasms syndrome or something
that's too clean. That's gotta be,
it's gotta be a funnier one for
persistent genital arousal disorder.
That's right. Oh, pst.
Yeah. I just remember that.
I talked about it in my last person.
Persistent genital arousal disorder. Yeah.
Yeah. So there are, they're a wealth of
people like this on the amount of wealth,
but there are certainly, I mean there's
definitely more than one. It's, it's, um,
and they've had, you know, there was
one last year, it was in the news,
this woman was hospitalized and she was
like, she just keeps like, you know what,
this guys,
he was so sad,
which made it so funny cause you could
tell offering was at his father's
funeral. It's just coming. It's just
like, that's what dad would have wanted.
That's what dad would've wanted.
I just had nine rather powerful
orgasmic sensations to my entire body.
So names row, he would have
shit like your parents' funeral.
So you want to hear the big news?
Could I imagine? I'm planning on it.
Here's the big news. Okay.
This guy was profiled on our,
we were obsessed with this guy.
This is a few,
I mean a number of years
ago haven't really,
I had to go back through
these drops to find them.
It's like it's in the first like 100
audio things we pulled, you know,
so it's like, it's back in the day.
Okay. Here's why he's back in the news.
Oh, he tran. Oh, nice. No,
it's like he's following our show.
Wow. Yup. Well what that is is he wants
to feel what it's like to come as a woman.
This guy coming is only so fun now.
She only climax is eight times daily,
so I guess that knocked it down a notch.
Maybe that's,
I don't know if that's part of the reason.
Maybe it is. How could it not Scott?
He was like, I'm tired of common
transition. He looks tired.
He looks like he's just drained.
I got to say when he was a man,
that's a bad haircut,
but can I tell you I love that guys. Hair
cut. I think that's such a fun guy. Yeah.
The bangs are always bad. We were just
talking about dumb haircuts. Like it just,
you look dumb. It's the
same hair over there for us.
Better as a woman. I've definitely fucked
that chick. Yeah, I fucked that chick.
Yeah. Many years ago in a bar or
someone, a dark bar somewhere,
but then not having the testosterone
not down the orgasm number to only 8%.
Only eight a day. You know, how much,
how much coming that is so come so
much company doesn't come anymore.
Like just, I mean maybe, let's
see. I need more information.
The transgender mother of
two hit headlines. Having
the hunter orgasms a day. Uh,
here, look, look, I nailed it. Persistent
general arousal system. Okay. Uh,
Christine Decker, two rivers,
Wisconsin ultra rare condition. Um,
an accident triggered the illness. What's
her name now? Christine. Christine.
Christine Rivers. If you're out in
Albion, Madison, Wisconsin. Come on up.
Comedy on stage. Oh, it's a great club. It
is a great, have you been there? Yeah. Oh,
it's the fucking best. I've just got, I'm
going there and two ways. First of all.
Got, that's probably good. I just keep it,
keep it, just keep it straight. Fantastic.
Andrew San Te. Hello. Hi. Thanks
for having me. I am such a fan of
him coming here.
Such a great actor,
known you for years and I'm so happy for
all your success and I'm so glad you're
here. Thank you. That's him
right there. That's him collapse.
So wait, when he walks, if he comes,
he has to like brace himself. Well,
sometimes it just, it just, it
just floors. By the way, you know,
said that I've never had an orgasm.
That good outcomes are just fine.
Everything's fine.
Yeah. All right. And they're unprompted.
Like when you're, you wear a diaper,
how does he see, he's got to say,
you can't just rip through underwear.
That's just tear through
like he's out of come.
You know what I mean? Like he
has all gone, all gone. Yeah.
There's no more come every time.
No, but he gets, he gets the,
he gets the feeling. Every time
I hear this, this is actually,
this is the audio from this moment.
Oh God.
Yeah, I remember that.
Oh, how old is this?
Does this, uh, how old is she now? Oh,
it says 30 oh two Racine remains
married to are devoted wife.
April 36 no, that's Chris. Christine.
Christine's 40 I think it said so already.
Her wife stuck it out was a real g g we
watched an entire series on this called
lost in transition about people that
have been married for like 15 years,
have children. And then the
husband is like, guess what?
I'm a lady. What is don't.
It's really hard to stay together,
but the women try. Yeah, the woman,
the woman here is sort of a ride or
die chick. I would say. I think women,
I think women in general assumably try
harder if that's the other way around.
Dudes are like late later within seconds,
look at how forgiving,
a lot of times our women are to
a man's physical traits. Totally.
You've seen these super like
these fat piece of Shit. Guys.
I've known guys who were like no fat
chicks and they're the fattest guys have
epic, no teeth demanding.
Demanding. Yeah. He's like,
he's like, I mean, I don't
fuck with chicks like over
one 20 and you're like, okay,
dude.
And like the dude just looks like a
fucking candle melted and then stopped
halfway through it. I'm like, just pick
guys. And you're like, Jesus Christ,
and here's the thing that can, I will
score chicks all the time. Totally.
It's an unbelievable that
the woman goes like, yeah,
he's confident as it goes with them.
It's one car.
They take one characteristic to roll
with. Women are like, oh, he's, you know,
he's a smart or he's sweet.
Yeah. Yeah. And for this guy,
he's gotta be a tide bud.
Not going to fuck a pig.
I know a girl who just told me,
talk to you about her boyfriend. She
goes, well, he's nice to me. I'm like,
I fucking hope. So. Yeah. Like that
was the thing. She was impressed.
He's nice to me.
There was a guy last night with a really
good looking chick at rite aid trying
ice cream. You know how they have
the right of the ice cream? Yeah.
He's trying all the ice cream.
He massive, massive, popular,
skinny little tiny girl right next
to him. He's just like, uh, give no,
give me rocky road. Do you know? He's
like trying all of them. And I was like,
how does this, how does she get trapped?
How does she end up in that situation?
It's just low self esteem.
Yeah.
Coupled with maybe he's got something
else off or you don't know what is hog
looks like or what his bank account
looks like. Yeah. But there's,
everyone's got a penis.
It's gotta be money because the girl,
you can always go get another penis.
I'm telling you.
But just someone that sometimes
those broken, broken wings
out there, those girls,
if you're just nice to them. I mean that
just got to find the damaged one guys.
Yeah. Yeah. Tip for the
dudes. Get the damage.
Those are the ones you can
manipulate. Yeah. You can own them.
These are healthy girls broken.
Yeah.
You don't want them if they got
their shit together. Right? Yeah.
If they're educated and they're
really got a good family,
that's what a waste of time. Yeah. Look
for tiers. That's who you want to. Yeah.
Someone that looks like they
always were just crying. Yeah.
That's what you want just on white.
Right. And they're like, I'm all right.
And you're like, hey, then swoop in.
But those are the girls that settle for
the pigs eating ice cream in the writing.
That's exactly right. Those are
your double anal checks. DVD, A's.
Let's talk. Let's ask Andrew
by the way. Fantastic comedian,
actor Anderson Tino about ride or die.
So last week we pose this question
and it got a lot of feedback. Okay.
Listen carefully. Okay.
You're married. Yeah. Um,
so I guess should I pose the question
as to you or what do you think your wife
would do? I'll ask you what you
think your wife would do. Okay.
So let's say your wife's out and
she comes home and she's like,
hey baby. And you're like, ah,
I got to tell you something.
And she was like, what?
And you're like, Hey, you know, uh, you
know that a FedEx guy. And he always like,
he'll just kind of like pull the truck
up and his is a mirror, like slap the,
the mailbox. She's like, oh, that guy's
an asshole. Yeah. Yeah. So anyway,
today I was across town,
I was getting one of my juices and then
I saw him in the parking lot and I,
I dunno, pissed me, I killed him.
But anyways, uh, no one saw it and a,
I got the body in the trunk. So,
uh, just want to let you know.
Do you think she turns you in?
No. No Way. Because she's your wife. She's
my wife. Yeah. She wouldn't turn me in.
She would, she would have, she would
first, cause it's me. She'd go, well,
you're fucking around.
And I go, no dead series.
I'd show her the body and then she'd
go, well, you've got a plan. Right.
And then that's what she would want.
Yeah.
She wanted to know if I've got
some kind of a plan. No, let me,
let me be clear here. The
motivation for the murder. Yeah.
It was just that the guys w w uh,
side view mirror dinged our mailbox.
Like, can I tell you something at him off?
Stop hitting my fucking mailbox. Yeah.
Here. Talked to him about it and see,
and we've already gone over this.
Stop hitting the male parent and,
and you saw you kill him and then your
wife, your children. No, no kids. Okay.
But Christina, right there she is. She,
that's her. That's her immediate response.
Herniate.
Ricky's been snitching.
She's the fact that he would
just willy nilly kill people.
Kill me and on our children. That's why
you have to put no, no, no. That's right.
No, no, no. If I'm that
kind of ans listen, wait,
if I'm that kind of unstable guy that
kills someone, went over nothing,
then you better do the right thing and
help me out because I will fucking kill
you. That's what I'm saying.
I'm saying if my wife was like,
we need to tell someone, I'd be
like, that's it. You're dead.
You're fucking dead to you and Fedex
guy will be buried together. Si. Si, Si.
This thing that I think is
nonsense. Right? How pissed
I am at the Barista. Yeah.
Yeah. It might be. I might
be a hot head about it,
but that's why I'm pissed that she's like,
well,
how do I know you're not gonna
turn around and kill our children?
But Andrew just said, if she doesn't
help me, I'm going to kill her if you,
if you go against me. Yeah. That's my
constant fear is me going, Jill's in.
Why would you go against me?
Why would you then I have to walk on
eggshells for the rest of our marriage.
So after this,
are you joining the US marshals or
what's your I've got to protect our kids.
Tom, you're psycho. Well that's,
but no, that's it though.
I would, I would go fund,
first of all, I'd have to find a backup
wife. Then if you started questioning me,
I find a backup life.
Who's your second wife of choice?
What am I looking for
that might not a Dalmatian.
What does your dumb dumb. A total
bozo. You just like a 21 year old.
Barely there. Yeah. And you're more on
him back. I'll see you y'all next week.
That kind of thing. Give her, give
her like a YSL person. She's like,
you're the best and you're like, sit
in this room for a while. I'll do that.
Just give her some snacks or something.
Give her a little cash.
I'm going to give her, give
her a buyer a, not an iPhone,
but like the iPod that looks like the
iPhone, but just tell her it's an iPhone,
you know, just, she's like, it doesn't get
it. The service will get connected soon.
Don't worry about it. Okay, I see that.
I love that girl Labia. I love you too.
She's got some really young
name that they don't, you know,
I'm writing a book about river
jobs and how you can blow jobs,
but that's what that girl does. She
does their time. Not Hands Watch Daddy.
Oh my God. Totally. Yeah. They
call you and they call you daddy.
They have to. That's just a rule.
That's automation wife. She's just, uh,
she's barely, they're being
called Daddy's pass. No thanks.
Hard task poppy.
And I've had it,
I've had it done once before
telling them out from him.
What do you think for me for fucking
three HD graduate from a total fucking
gutter slot. But poppies, poppies hot.
If it's coming from a Latino woman. Yeah,
but was it a Latino pig?
Who Was it?
Just some fucking Maria
Jody sludge chaser Jodie. So
pig course. Anyway, but
it's okay if it's from,
if it's a white girl that calls me Papi,
that's what are we doing?
What are you doing? Yeah. So
you're saying that, okay, so you,
you think your wife should be
ride or die with you at the core?
She's gotta be first degree. Okay.
Let me tell you, let's flip it.
If my wife is like,
Hey,
you know that bitch from the office that
I fight with for the last fucking three
years, I'd have to ask you what your
answer is. I slit her throat. I'm like,
gangster, where are we burying this
bitch? You'd be like, yeah, dude,
you want to drain it? And then I'm
thinking about camping. I'm like,
where can we put it? How far away
can we get and where am I going?
I gotta get the temperpedic. Yeah,
you came home and you're like,
I murdered someone. I'd be like, what
are we doing? How are we going to do
God?
I would take so much pride in coming up
with a cover story on me in the least
bit concerned about my [inaudible].
You had a reason even at the time,
if it doesn't make sense now,
it made sense then. Now we've
got to, you got to support.
Female killers are way fewer and
far between. True man killer.
So I'd probably be pretty crazy.
I mean,
if you start looking at me real
psychotic, okay, it's a little different,
but I fucking kill you.
Then I just want you to down afraid
of me stabbing you in your sleep.
Not unless you're taking it
to a thing where you're like,
like rocking back and forth, you know,
licking knives. I'd be like, all right,
something's rough with her, but if
you just told me a story, you're like,
I got real pissed off. I did
this crazy thing. Yeah, I
would totally be like, yeah,
I'm with you.
How do you know it's a onetime thing?
That's my problem with you and I know you.
You're very impulsive and,
and once you get a taste for killing,
it's not going to stop. Okay.
But you crossed that line. We're
not talking about brownies, right?
We're talking about, but once you
cross that light, that's the one line.
You're not supposed to Christ
once you do and it feels so good.
I know you're going to
like, it feels so good.
I know you,
you're going to like the three probably
does feel really good to take somebody's
life. I also think it's probably,
I think it's also like, well,
I'm the kind of guy who so like meticulous
about everything that the cleanup and
all that shit. Yeah. That would
probably deter me from doing it again.
It's just so laborious.
So you're like, oh my God,
I don't want to fucking bloodhounds
paperwork all the shit out now.
It's like buying a house. I know. They
keep sending you emails. You're like,
what is this? What am I signing? I
don't want to do this anymore. I don't,
I never will cash. I'm giving
you cash here and I just
take it. Well, the cleanup.
Yeah, it has to be. It's to be a thrill
to have someone tied up, I imagine.
You know what I mean? Like in a
base and just the control over them.
I kind of get that.
Oh my God.
It is kind of,
and it's kind of cool and it's kind of
cool where you walking in the and you
just shut the door. Just walk in
and stare at him. Don't do anything.
And I closed the door again.
Just give them little glimpses of you.
Help your wife listens to this Andrea.
She's going to,
she better stay in her
cage where she belongs.
Great guys. Okay. Moving right along.
I just want to see if come daddy
has any more fun. Oh Yeah, look. Oh,
she's dating somebody. They're
cute. They're cute together.
Full body shot by the way.
I'm surprised.
I thought that was going to cut off here,
but it's got the golf pants and everything
and I will say it doesn't usually
work out. It's worked out for her
quite nicely. I think she looks great,
but that shot right there of debt,
frankly arm that looks like literally me.
If I put tennis balls,
has as tits dead friendly.
Armed with that little bit of red hair,
that's me. That's me in a tank top.
This condition was prompted for
Christine when she was a man, uh,
and had a back injury. Uh Oh yeah.
Way makes sense to the hospital.
In the ambulance. She started
having orgasms and the next day,
according to this article,
she had 236 orgasms. Yeah.
The constant spasm is leaving her
pelvis and agony. It'd be on my knees.
All these people would be staring at
him. He was humiliating. Jeez man.
I've been lying to myself for so long.
I knew I was meant to be a woman. Oh,
I'm glad all these people are switching.
By the way,
if all these people that have wanted to
switch for so long and now that society
is like, do it, I'm like, go for it, man.
Whatever. Yeah. I think it's good to,
people want to switch, go for
it. Whatever you gotta do,
there's got gotta be
nothing worse than feeling.
Then honestly feeling like
you're born in the wrong body.
That's gotta be the weirdest
feeling in the world.
Terror feeling in the world is being you
feeling like you're in the wrong way.
Like a guy that's such a guy. Yeah. You
transition is just always gonna look bad.
You know what I'm saying? She always
tells me that if I were to transition,
I'd be the ugliest, ugliest, but you
wouldn't be a babe. Yeah, yeah, you'd be,
you'd be a solid. Uh, he'd be a
big Husky Midwest girl, you know,
cause you have broad shoulders,
you know? Yeah. So much hair.
But you see some of those,
some of those guys say they got
to be like a seven in Omaha. Yeah.
You'd be a babe in Nebraska.
Just cutting trees and shit.
I'd think I'd be an okay chick. I'd
be, I'd be a sluts. I'd be wild.
So just fuck Ricky redhead girl.
I'd be a freaking red headed
girl running around. I also have,
my legs are kind of skinny
enough where I can send them out.
I could send them out and do hot chick
legs. You know, here's the thing,
by the way, all these guys, big
guys, when they start to transit,
we were watching that show and this
guy who trains it was transitioning.
It was like everyone thinks I'm
a man and he just decided and,
and he was big dude. It's like, dude, why
aren't you running every morning? Yeah.
I gotta lose the weight. Right. You can't,
I mean going to commit, you gotta commit.
If you're going to chop off the Wang are
you got to commit it dude. She's like,
people say things like, I looked like a
man. Like you're two 25 yeah, it's a big,
big, big broad. Yeah. Stop.
Stop benching dude. Come on.
Stop lifting at some point.
That's why I might switch just
so I can stop going to the gym.
I might just send out. You work out
a lot. I do. Really? Yeah, I do.
I've changed working out what I
work out now. I just try to swim.
I used to just be like, run,
lift weights, run, lift weights.
Now we just do different things to,
cause I just, it's so monotonous, boring.
And the people there are so boring.
That's true.
It's just the whole idea
of it is just kind of grow.
It grosses me out sometimes
when you see people like,
you know when you go to a gym, I don't
have, I don't go to gym anymore. We,
I have one at home,
which is great,
but when I used to go to a gym and I
see the same guy over and over doing the
same things and you're like, oh yeah,
this is like very like machines,
like creepy. Like he's doing the exact
same guy. What's up that guy and like, ah,
fuck.
That's especially weird when you see that
guy over the course of time not making
any progress. No progress. Yeah. Same Guy.
And sometimes you'll hear that same guy
complained like I just can't. He's like,
you're not doing anything right. Yeah.
That's why you're not making any progress.
That's even more sad,
stuck,
really sad is when people post
it on Instagram, their workouts,
I think there's nothing more fucking
boring. I don't want to call out anybody,
but there's someone I know that post
gym stuff all the time and I'm like, oh,
and I really like you,
but it bothers me so fucking much.
Does it bother you as much as people
retweet and compliments or, yeah,
that's Fred pretty parallel.
It actually bothers me when someone
I know comments on the gym photo in a
positive reinforcement.
Fucking snake. That's so self.
So after it dog. Yeah, go get
it brother Luke and Greg, Bro.
Shut the fuck you phony. That's such
a phony. Also the the gym people,
the few gym people that I know,
that dude that fucking shame,
like that's the hardest part
is they're not that good at,
they're not even that good of shape.
That's what bothers me.
It's not like jazz when you're
like, Whoa, the rack. Yeah,
he does his big, big fucking
grin, but it's the cocaine's Ma.
Oh yeah. Is that how positive
that guy really feels? No Way.
Cause his smile and he's like, hey,
he's like, feel good in my anchor.
I'm lifting this morning, shot eight
movies yesterday. Shut up fucking films.
That's for, I'm almost done with
my first workout of the day.
And you just see the smile just never
fade. And he's like, all right guys,
get after it. And you're
like, he's 6 million views.
There was an article that came out
that he suffers from depression that he
admitted he has severe
depression and you're like, ah,
I feel like a jerk. No, no,
no, no, no. Because if you spend all this
time working this and not your brain,
something's wrong. I'm not making
fun, but you're Gunna get depressed.
Like you're naturally, if all you
focused on was one thing all the time,
it's like, I know what I think is
depressing too. I've thought about this.
I think it's naturally depressing.
Those guys that get to number one,
number one. Totally.
I think it's gotta be,
it's so much attention and there's so
much pressure and I don't think it's a
coincidence that all the number one's
workout like lunatics. I think it's like,
I think it's actually kind of
depressing to get to get to that level.
Do you think number one's always self
sabotage or do you think that's just a
pattern of it? No, I don't
think they all self sabotage.
I think there's just so much pressure
to maintain it and there's a natural ebb
and flow.
Like you look at someone like Tom Cruise,
he was the number one of
number ones for a huge stretch.
Then like obviously it's weird, personal
stuff happens. It's all public, right?
It's like these Scientology theoretical,
crazy jumping. I love this woman, all
that shit. He puts it back together and,
but he also is known for having like,
I mean there's no kind of an odd point
of view personality and it's all tied to
staying in that top slot I think.
Right.
I get obsessed with being up
top posts and I won't say who,
but
people I follow, they're like
number one, just grinding.
That's all I know how to do grinding
work and it's like, dude, what's you,
what's your life about? That's
it. That's all you're going to do.
You are readily a multimillionaire
and just take a break.
I like reading that one. I'm
not doing anything that day.
That's my favorite shit.
And you're like, I'm winning today.
I didn't do shit. I feel fantastic.
I don't know who said that.
I think norm was talking about that.
That's on something when he was like,
yeah,
sometimes my day is so consumed with
getting a meal and a concern for the next
meal than my whole day is just
going to get food, having it,
doing it than going to get new food and
the day is over. And I did a whole day.
I was like, as like I've
had those days. Yeah.
And then when I see people doing
the thing bragging and I'm like,
I feel good that I didn't do shit.
I also think
that some of the, the grinding
braggers, they're really, they,
they're doing that for themselves. Oh,
totally. Not just as a, um, as a show off.
I think they need it.
They need to do it to keep going because
without the act of documenting it and
showing and getting the reinforcement
something, they lose something.
So they need to go check out how hard
I'm working and tell me how proud you are
of me for how hard I'm working.
Well,
I think there's two kinds of people though
that like some people like when they
get accolades, they have to tell
you. Yeah, and some people are,
I'm embarrassed of telling you.
Do you know what I mean?
Some people are so scared to let you
know that sometimes when you find out
something about a friend and you're like,
I didn't know you.
I didn't know you did that.
And they're like, oh yeah.
And they're kind of embarrassed about it.
But then I have so many of the other
friends, I have someone that will call me.
I wish I could say his fucking name. He
will call me and tell me of great thing.
That's just that he's just acquired or
achieved or whatever. We all know, Bert,
what am I going to say?
What am I like?
I don't know what you expect the
response to be awesome, right?
I think I like to brag online only like
I like the online bragging is because
it's there. If you want to
see it gone gray. No. Uh,
but you know what I just realized it
makes me so annoyed about the workout
braggers is that you're
supposed to work out diff shit.
I took a shower today. Hey, I'm
fucking shower to brush my teeth.
I took a shit like, no, dude,
you're supposed to do that
stuff to maintain your life.
There's no reason to brag
about or we're also all first.
The grind always supposed to be,
we should be grinding.
They're acting like they work hard
to maintain their life.
You work hard, but that's,
you know what the irony is the people
that are like grinding the hardest.
Like imagine the rock band, like on the
grind. Just had my personal chef cook,
my personal breakfast and my personal
gym with meanwhile a dude is like,
I'm on the grind, I'm on my fourth
job today. I'm tired. I have six kids.
I make 40 grand a year and the rocks,
like I can't tell you how
much that respect you.
Big Ass smile is so true,
Andrew.
It's like the guy that delivers my
Amazon package. He's fucking grinding.
By the way. If that is bragging on the
Granby and like fucking on the guide,
I'd be like respect dude.
For sure.
We need more of those grinders and
those guys don't want, they don't,
this is what they're going to ditch.
Phoenix 115 shovel in the air
grinder grinding. That's the real,
that's for sure.
Those people won't brag.
That's because they're the false
narrative of cool guys. Uh,
do what the rock does.
Then they feel like I got to get up
to that to do the and watch an insane
document.
Viceland put out a piece about these
people in Miami who rent exotic cars.
I started walking.
I got like halfway through.
I don't want to spoil it for the fucking
creepy cause I saw the text on screen.
That was like quarter of the way in
where they go. Sure, sure. I'm sorry.
I was just drinking water.
I'm a champion.
They're already saying,
they're like, we could,
we were not able to verify any of the
claims, get this guy. And I'm like,
that's not a normal thing
to put up on screen.
Like they're obviously prompting
you to pay attention to this. Yes.
And then they show him like
doing coke and like, yeah,
his friends where he's grinding.
He said yes to doing coke on camera,
like an ro one.
I am about to hit this town and then
I didn't get through it. I mean not,
I want to see the rest of it.
The basis of it is it to tie into what
we're saying is like, it's this fake,
like we're all winning,
we're all rich.
And he basically is saying how sad
it makes him that he's got to keep up
appearances because he can't,
he literally can't.
And he's like doing everything he can to
do anything he can to lie, cheat, steal,
do whatever he can look just to
look like it's just a fake it.
That's what's even more, do
you know, do they cover this?
I was trying to figure this out. So
this, this piece is all about how,
especially in Miami,
the exotic car rental business is.
I am. No, without a doubt. I mean
they're going to peak a Kansas.
Even the guy who's like, he's like, if
you come and you don't run a hot car,
your piece of shit drive that
narrative. So everyone's like, okay,
and it's all crazy expensive card.
We're talking like entry level 250
grand for these cars, Rambo all the way,
most Ferrari's Rolls Royce, you
know, Nutley's nothing, nothing.
Just regular luxury Uber,
same luxury car,
like a s five 50 Mercedes. They like
get the fuck out of here with that shit.
But anyways, I'm seeing this and
watching and you're like, okay,
people will rent these cars,
do those businesses acquire all that?
That'd be way too much capital,
right to be with buying.
So it doesn't talk about it on there. But
of course our brains, right. In the same,
I started doing research cause I was like,
there's no way have enough capital
to buy 15 Lambros right, right.
And so there I found a few other articles
so you can look it up about people
that get these,
um,
the subsidies from major high if they're
reputable from high end companies to
like Lee lease and sublease from them.
And that's how they do. That's how they,
but they pay it,
but they pay a super premium on the,
on the leisure to be able to supply
rented one as a prank on Bert like a year
ago where I, you know, and
he was like, you bought this.
And I was talking to the people that
rented it to me about this. I was like,
cause they were cool and they were
like, oh they, they follow like comedy.
And they were like, you know, he's had in
the car. I go, so you buy all these cars?
And they were like, ah, yeah, like kind of
like dodging around it. I'm just curious,
I'm not trying to get into the
business with you. I'm just asking you.
And they were like, yeah,
these are all our cars.
Like it wasn't like they
didn't were forthcoming with
how they actually are able
to do. I think there's a million little
sneaky holes. Like there's one on sunset.
Um, there's one like right
on sunset next to a bar.
And one time I talked to the guy cause
there's like three cars in the showroom.
I was like, coming to you have, he's
like as many as we need. I was like, no,
that means you don't have shit,
but you're able to find them somehow.
I think they go find real owners or find,
you know,
companies that collect or whatever and
they pay them a premium over what they're
going to lease it for. It's just, it's
got to make sure it's a shady business.
It's a crazy business. Tom,
when you rented the Lambo,
did you put your car insurance or
did they go to jail for that? I take,
there's what? I rent cars on the
road. I'm like, my insurance is great.
What did it cost to rent the Lambo?
A G I, it was like a thousand,
something like that. It was for a day.
You know, it's expensive, but I go,
you're not doing enough business to,
you know,
to pay off these kinds of car and make
a profit. There's no way, man. No.
They'd have to be literally conflict
the second you bring it back.
Every someone's,
they're waiting and they have,
they're busy moments and everything
here in la too, you know, people,
you always see those high end cars,
Beverly hills and sometimes
it's an owner of a car,
but lot of times it's these exotic sunset
strip stuff. You know, it's all rentals,
rentals, people from out
of town. Although I was,
I met this guy who was a liaison,
you know these guys in La that
don't do real jobs that you're like,
but they get paid good money and you're
like, well how did you get there?
He's a liaison to this rich family
from Dubai and he basically is there
everything, go get it, go
do it. You know what I mean?
Like the, the ultimate gopher,
he does literally everything for
them. And he's like, oh yeah,
they constantly rent cars. They
won't just buy a car. He's like,
so they'll rent a Bentley for like two
months and then give it back and then
they'll rent,
you know,
Ferrari for a month and then give it
back in a Rolls Royce. I was like, what?
That's, they just don't feel
like buying. He's like, no,
they just don't want to have anything
acquired. They just want to like get it,
give it back. Like everything is
at least everything is to rent.
There's people like that that I think
come to la that spend absurd amounts of
money on shit like that, and those
companies must make a ton of them,
but they don't care because
there's so much. They're like, no,
I just want to give it back. My
cousin came here to hear that. Well,
they wouldn't you like,
oh yeah, if I was that.
Well there is that kind of money in
La. You see, you see it, you're like,
there's not,
there's really rich people living in
that area that you were talking about.
Yeah. Well, no, I'm Beverly. It
was at the Beverly Hilton. We were,
some cab driver was telling us that
these girls come during the summertime at
the Beverly Wilshire in Beverly,
Wilshire as Arab and like, you know,
like Middle Eastern coming and it's like,
before I forget what time of year
for Ramadan maybe? Or is it, yeah,
I think so. Don't respect.
Don't disrespect. Ron was
a dare. Don't you? Dare,
don't you dare.
These girls come with like
their chaperones and then
their fathers and brothers
are back home and the other gold country.
And then they spend all this money on
like Chanel clothes and all these labels
where, um, and then leave them
behind and you can't work.
Oh whoa. It's a back into the
country. That's crazy. Where did they,
where does it go? Does
someone like, they're like, I
don't know, throw the trash.
You see some, some homeless dude wearing
a Chanel dress that's, he looks good.
The thing is that the hotel was,
we were there to have lunch with someone
and we were like, oh, that's right.
We were, here we go, uh, what is going
on? Because it was so like so busy,
but it didn't feel like a normal
day. And they're like, oh,
I don't remember if he was robbing him.
It was some time of the year.
They're like, oh, it's blah, blah
blah. And uh, this always happens.
We'll get like thousand, you know,
princes and whatever here and there,
like armed security people and they're
like, they're just nothing but lambos,
Ferraris,
Rolls Royce.
And then you saw hundreds of shopping
bags from all the rodeo drive cause they
can't wear them back home cause they have
to wear traditional gear or whatever.
I don't know what that's called. Yeah.
They said like, oh it's just fun.
Like they'll buy it and wear it out
to dinner. And then there's, there's,
there's uh, he dropped the
[inaudible] job. Is it?
That sounds really nice. But you
say with that face, I don't know if
there was,
I watched,
I watched one of these youtube warm
holes where people go about them.
Don't talk shit.
Talk Shit.
So if you want to talk some
shit cause that wine box video,
oh my God. Yes. That's so one of
the best. I love that one. Um,
oh I watched this video about people
that go rent cars in the m and a,
what does it in Dubai,
in the Emirates or whatever.
And they leave them at the airport.
Like there's, you can look it up.
There's this video,
there's like thousands of cars that are
like really nice cars because if you
don't pay your, um, if you
skip payments, it's a prison.
Double offense in Dubai.
Oh dear. So they'll,
what they'll do is they'll drive them to
the airport and they'll catch a flight
out of the country and, and
ghost. Wow. You look, look,
look, look it up. It's insane.
There's like Ferrari,
Ferrari, beemer, Mercedes,
because they just didn't
make their payment on yeah.
Were they just leave the cars?
It's like a,
it's like a car graveyard at the airport.
When my cousin from Peru came here to
study English few years ago, he was with,
it was all foreign people from all over
the world, his class. And he goes, oh, uh,
he's like, oh, there's
this kid in my class
from the UAE. And I go,
yeah. He goes, do you know,
they just gave him money to come here.
And then they just bought him a place
and he takes out the whole class,
like in, he'll rent limos and
like a sprinter vans and is like,
let's just go out tonight, pay
for everybody. And they're like,
what the fuck's going on? You guys
the best? And he's like, he's like,
I don't worry about it. Like,
uh, my government just pays
for it. All my government.
Yeah. He's like, they just
gave you and he's like,
he would bring out just like what could,
wait, what school is this? This is a,
he was studying and they were studying
English at USC. Oh, in college.
But it was like at a, you know, an adult
study. Sure. Do you mean the government?
Is this the ual you a,
he,
he said that this is my cousin told me
that if you're a citizen you can go to
the government and be like, I want some,
I want some shit. And they're like,
all right, and then give you money
and uh, I want to buy a house.
Here's the money for the house.
If you go,
I want to study anything at any part of
the world. It's on them because they go,
you're going to bring it back here.
So it go study that thing.
It's a pretty flat, pretty black
system. I want this. Okay. I like it.
I love it. We should move the fuck
are we doing here? They'd be like,
give us the money. We want to
leave. We, these could live there.
Not me as a little after we murder
that Fedex do, we might have to move.
That guy keeps hitting the fucking
mailbox. What do you want us to do? Yeah.
Damn you to the first
conversation is really nice. Hey
Man, you missed the, you, um,
you hit my mailbox. Notice that
I've seen it. You hear that,
that smack and then he and then his,
but he does this to you and this pisses
you off. He goes, I don't think I hit it.
Aww, I saw. Yeah. Well, okay. Yeah,
I'm pretty, I know, man. I didn't,
I didn't hit it, but sorry about that
many of them. Yeah. All right. Okay.
Second day hits it and then you
go, hey dude, you were yesterday.
You remember how we just, you know, I saw
the truck hit a 10. Now. I did see it.
I saw it too loud. I think you
heard it. And then he says,
and sticks out a little too
far. If I'm being honest in
mirror. No, no, the mailbox,
it sticks out too far, so, okay,
well maybe you go around it.
I can't sit tight turned from the corner.
All right.
I gotta go do some other deliveries now
you start, now you're cooking day three,
day three.
Now he really gets it.
Now Tom's waiting for the guy you're
waiting outside for me as they say.
And then I say it to you. I
go, hey man, smoked it today.
Sorry about that. I, I
clipped it bad. I clipped.
Took that turn fast and
I'm a little hung over.
I'm also one of your packages that you
were supposed to get. It was a big one.
Something important. I don't know. Um,
it broke at the warehouse so, well,
you know. Okay. You figure
it out with them. Okay. Yeah.
All right. All right man.
Have a good day. I'll see you
there now. You too. That's it.
It's brewing underneath
three days of this. He said,
then I see him at the juice bar. Yeah.
Here I am at the juice bar. I know,
and I'm at the juice bar.
I know the guy that works there.
He's been waiting in line for
quite a while. I Walk Right
in. I go, Mikey, what up?
Boom. He, he's got my juice ready. Yeah.
I don't have to pay for it or nothing.
He gets up there,
wants his juice.
I got the last of whatever the juice
that he needed it. Oh fuck is what now?
I go see a, now I go out the
stairs to the back parking lot.
It's really like not even a parking lot.
It's like trash cans and stuff.
Dumpsters and I see Fedex fucking frank.
Right?
And he's just like, he's, he's
like, God damn, this is good.
He's like making a scene of it. He's
bragging about it. God. It's like,
fuck you get the best mango here.
Best mango here. Why this shit in?
And that's when I go like,
Oh hey man,
I noticed you fucking parked without
hitting anything here, you know?
And he's like, yeah, yeah. Oh, did you
want this? These are good. He's like, ah,
I use throws him, check
it out. He goes like this.
Oh Shit.
Hey look,
any hits Tom in the head with the
empty one. What do you think happened?
Yeah, yeah man. How do
you kill him? I mean,
I think there's probably like a,
a piece of juicing equipment that
broke that's in the parking lot. Yeah,
there's a grinder type of blade.
They kind of half, half broke.
I luck out and that when I pick it up
if feels like it's actually a handle for
yeah. Like it's been made almost.
It's made for this and I just,
he's just like eat a dick man. Try ups or
something like that. And as he does it,
I just right behind them.
Oh yeah. Cause it's a lot
of Blah, a lot of black.
It's too much to be honest with
you. I probably panic, you know,
a good bit at first and then it just hits
me that like the parking lot is not a
parking lot. Like I, we're both in an
area where there's no cars, you know,
so I'm like, oh, there's no one's seeing.
I look around, there's no cameras.
I'm like, Oh man, I just, all right,
I gotta I gotta get Outta here.
Clothes are covered in
blood. Yeah, I dunno.
I feel like the way
that he hit the ground,
most of the blood is like that there
is forward and it's going into a drain.
You slit the throat from behind. Yeah,
but, but look at like this. If you,
if someone came like this oof. And
his arms here, it went out that way.
So he slipped and push,
push slit
or the main thing I got to figure out
is yeah. So I, I backed my car up,
I pick him up, I throw
them in the trunk. Yup.
And then I looked at his truck and I'm
like, ah, just leave it here, I guess.
You know, I don't think he came here
and it's illegally parked. I bet. Yup.
What about the tickets?
There was a lady with a dog
walking by. You're not going
to, you saw me do it. Of course.
This is a new development. She goes,
oh, is it that comedian from Netflix?
Todd Todd. Yeah. I'm
Todd. I love you. Yeah.
Big Fan. Big Fan. You know what though?
You know you got to do with her.
Yeah. Her throat. Now he just got to
hit her with your car. Oh, an accident.
Oh no,
that is true.
You got to hit her with your car
and then if she says my name. Yeah,
hundred percent yeah. Yeah. She knows. If
she knows you, it's just, oh, but the dog,
you don't want to kill the dog.
You don't want
to call it.
The dogs are cool,
but you definitely got to hit her
and you've got to hit her hard.
You gotta get her nice and hard.
Now you got blood on the grill of the
car and then you've got a body in the
trunk. Yeah, but you're
going to burn all that shit.
Are you gonna burn the holes or the
whole car or the truck? I'll be, I think,
I mean at the truck, first of
all. I mean that thing. Yeah,
5,600 pounds or something. I mean, it's
come on 40 miles an hour. Even that,
it's like, sure. It's over. Yeah, sure.
Yeah. I just try to clip her, you know,
if anything she lives, there's definitely
memory loss. She's probably, you know,
talking with her eyes, looking at letters
where the computer sure. Hey, yes,
one of those.
So it was Todd Sikora that hit me.
It takes me like 25 minutes to
get it out. Um, but I don't know.
I then I just bring it home. I, I
tell you what's up and I'm like,
what are we gonna do with
this thing, right? No, now,
now that you present the scenario
that way, like real talk, I,
I might have to help. See, I know.
Really. There you go. Here's the thing.
Cause like I would actually love you again
panic. It'd be like, fuck dude. Like I,
what am I,
what are we going to do?
I can't have you going away
to prison because you know,
think about it that you got a tour in
2019 you all these dates coming out it,
you're selling out all these shows.
Bail on that dude.
Yeah. Well that's what I, the people
are waiting for you to show up. I mean,
think about all this. That's what I
up the pepper. Pepper. Pepper. Yeah.
Think about the sex would be so hot.
He tells you this conversation he'd read,
does it reads the story and you're
like, I gotta fuck this guy. It's true.
Dead Body or not, this is
hot man. Or I tell you during
sex. Yeah. Yeah. You're like,
wait, what happened? Was that
the juice bar? You're like yeah.
And then right before I come I go,
I killed that.
Bought Him Guy Black Guy.
Oh God.
Yeah. It's funny guys. By the way,
this was sent to us so many times and uh,
I'm sure it would have been in the
folder if blue band had prepped it,
but I found it just,
you may have seen it also.
This was sent to us up fucking
200 times this week. Okay. Yeah,
I see that guy on Twitter.
You this Andrew.
This guy is such a fucking
psycho. I love it. Whereas he, oh,
I don't hear him. We need to hear him.
Oh, it's muted. God dammit. This is why
yo yo yo yo Yo yo west grafting
west cracker with mother
fucker. Quick Black Guy.
Oh,
we say
black, white, Brown, yellow. All right.
Pink, Asian, Asian. Hey Shai.
I'm looking for a thick booty,
bitch.
Hey man, you don't really hear that.
Can't you pattern hit me the fuck up.
Don't come dry. Obama. Bring
your jug. Bring a blank.
Let's get wet.
Let's
remember this low. Stay wet. Oh Wow.
Big booty pictures. I love you. Yes.
See this is a perfect example of
what we were talking about earlier.
The guy with no teeth making demands.
I got to tell you, I like this guy.
Here's the thing. I think it's authentic.
I think this guy really gets high with
women 40 years younger than him and it's
probably cool. Like has like a decent
place where it's like it's not bad. Yeah.
He's like, you got your,
brought it blonde. I brought
all these drinks. You know,
he's like, come Yas. And
they're like, all right. Yeah.
I just think like he probably, he's
probably super chill about everything.
You know what I mean?
Like he seems like he's,
he's woke enough that if a girl came
over and was like, I don't want to fuck,
and he'd be like, that's chill.
Let's just get high as fuck.
He doesn't seem like a foresee,
weird, creepy guy. Where
does he live? What do you,
what kind of digs does he have? He's
in, he's just up by Bob Hope Airport.
Just by Burbank airport. Yeah.
Yeah, like an apartment complex.
It's one of those old dude. It's a, it
used to be a house now it's a duplex,
you know? Yeah. And he's
got a, he's actually got the
dominant side of the yard,
so like the other side's
concrete for the driveway,
but he's got like a nice little patio
with those little string lights that he's
got. It's pretty chill if I'm not
going to lie. It's kind of cool.
He's gotten a cute, cute,
tiny little fucking fluffy
dog. Absolutely. Super Cute.
Yeah.
He's not that bad of a dude.
I feel like he's getting a weird rap
guy who's had a pretty decent job for 40
years. He's always got cash on him.
He's got like, he has a cleaning lady.
It was places. Nice Pacer.
Well treats her well. No teeth.
He did not have,
I think he just had a lack of teeth.
I don't think he had no teeth.
I think he was, he was, I
think it was, you know, two,
three deficient. He's not new to the
drug game. I don't know if you know like
getting wet and rolling blunts like,
yeah.
Well it could be double
p when you dip a blunt
in, in, it's formaldehyde.
It's embalming fluid. We've been in
the game in the game for a long time.
Kill people. We've hid
bodies to go way back. Yeah.
We've been getting wet for years. I
was fucking with me. No, that's real.
Getting wet means dipping a blunt in,
in embalming fluid for
Formaldehyde or PCP.
He makes you feel good. Feel really
fucking cool dude. We got some nice,
good, good. Yeah, so he's had a
couple of runs. In fact he used to,
before he got this desk job, he was
working, he was working at a funeral home.
That's how I discovered doing
like getting wet regularly.
It helps him not thinking about his
first wife and those kids that he hasn't
seen in a long time.
So you do you do you get high like that?
You know what's so sad? Must
Traction. She, Santa Clarita
is not that far. It's not,
and he should go up there more often,
but he's working on himself
a little bit right now.
He can't go see those kids
in this condition now.
And on that child support that
he's had to pay over the years.
He can't afford dental work.
No Way.
It's pay the wife and the
kids are fixed my teeth.
Well at this point a lot of his
kids are thinking, you know,
do I introduced him to my grandkids? Yeah,
he's great. He's great. And they're like,
I don't know. I don't think it's
ready. You know? But they're,
that's the irony of the whole thing is
he has a nice little Honda civic that he
pumpkin and car to drive up there.
But since he's ecofriendly he walks to
work because it's only three and a half
guys eco friendly yet? No, he, yes,
it's three and a half miles
from his house to his office.
So he doesn't drive enough. So they
booted his car. So it's like, you know,
one thing he does do Rago I can
tell you that it does do wrong.
He uses too many of those cars smell.
Oh my God. It seems was
like 15 of those like, um,
it's like a evergreen
wintergreen, wintergreen. Yeah.
It goes overboard. Too many.
Yes. He not only hangs the
trees from the rear view,
but also on his turning
signal. Oh God, man.
He puts the clips in the air
vents and under the seat.
Do you think when you ask him how
his day's going that he elaborates?
Like when he's at the checkout,
at the group pens. If you're cute,
there's a lot of woman.
If you're a woman, yes.
If you're a big booty girl that's looking
to get wet, then definitely. Yeah. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Got About his day. But if you're
a guy, he's quick to brush you off. Yeah.
If you're like, hey man, how's it going?
He's like, everything's fine. Yeah.
He doesn't know if you're a snitch or a
po or what's your, you know what I mean?
Yeah. He doesn't know your deal, dude.
He doesn't know. He's just, you know,
who would snitch right
away? Prison. Chris Nicha.
Although how you presented that scenario
to me, you guys and I felt the panic,
but you see how that might
help them to say panic,
but you see how that works because
when you empathize with us,
you understood where that pain came from.
Do you think this has a
similar vibe to you? This guy
just break my heart. Certainly.
I agree. Good man. Merk hard.
Good bye.
Yup. No teeth, no teeth. No,
that's, that's genuinely no teeth.
But hey guys, at least he
likes, he's educated. He's
watching Anderson Cooper. Yeah.
Yeah. He's up on current events
and I am a fan of full volume.
While you're making a video,
the camera,
this is out there. Yeah. Framing wise.
It definitely. Can I tell you something?
It hasn't,
has no idea.
Anderson Cooper's gay and would turn
that off if you found out. Oh probably.
You know what I mean? He would be
in such shock and called him. What?
What? What do you mean gay?
Like goofy. Like a weird guy.
You meet a foo foo stuff.
Totally is. No, no idea. I feel like
I feel like that, you know how many,
how many people like
Kevin Spacey coming out,
coming out to the world at
a very inappropriate time
when he also got accused of
touching boys. Yeah. So many people in
middle America where like he's not gay,
gay, no worse. Where are you from
originally? Chicago. Oh, okay. Okay.
But I know like funny,
the epicenter of the Midwest is a city
that's like such a diverse create like
you don't have any. Yeah.
But then like, you know,
an hour west or south or two hours south,
you're like, oh man, this is different.
This is different words.
Same in California though.
Same thing. Yeah, same thing.
Yeah, but, but,
but the population of southern
people in Southern Illinois,
I remember as a kid going down there,
they have southern accents. Oh, that's so
weird. And you're like, wow, no one, no,
we don't, not in Illinois.
We don't have that.
But people will have kind of like a 20
minute down South Korea and you're like,
what did I know? But they say it like
it's the deep south that's, you can,
you can run into that in a lot of states.
Yeah.
They just have southern rural
sense. Yeah. It's so weird.
It's like you can run into it and
like, uh, mid central California. Yeah.
That is so strange to me.
I don't know how that ended up over there.
Really weird to really weird places
with creepy names. Like Visalia. Yeah.
My style. Yeah. Yeah. The way to San
Francisco, right? Yeah. Bakersfield.
Oh, Christ. This guy.
Straight up sex or play foreplay.
Look at his eyebrows. Foreplay.
No, it good. Damn man. You know.
Agree Dude. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Making
more demands. Anything wrong though.
He's clean now. This
guy's living situation is
significantly different. Yeah.
What do you see? This guy's
pretty unfortunate actually.
He's, he has a house. Um,
it's a, not really a house
anymore, but it's like a,
it used to be a nice little piece of
property had in Tarzana and when his wife
left him,
everything left him the need to clean
and take care of it and it's overgrown.
It's, it's really, really sad.
His neighbors have called
multiple times to Hoa about him.
Do you think he has animals? Multiple.
Any cat piss everywhere and he doesn't,
he lets them roam past tense.
He had animals snip,
but then they just die. You know? I
think he drops on you when you come over.
If he gets you to come over, you have
to all do you take in all this shit.
He's like, mom, my mom is in the back.
Your mom is that. She's real sick.
You don't, you don't make
much noise. She's real sick.
You're like, all right. Yeah.
And you're like, what's that noise that
by no later. Yes. That kind of thing.
And he's like, Shit, don't make
you, don't make a fuss. She smoked.
So will be here in the morning to change
it. Don't, she's in the iron lung,
you know,
like she'll say she'll be fine here.
That his lips are also a kind
of a shade of purple. Yeah.
To me could indicate the tobacco
use or he's close to dying.
Could be good. Could be inching
his way towards death is about,
he's just about a heroine. Wait
a minute. Do you mean to tell me?
Hold on, hold on. You don't
think this guy lives a very,
very healthy lifestyle? I
feel like I don't, let me see
him one more time. Nowhere.
Bam.
Teeth or in his mouth.
I am an on here.
You know they get shit.
God don't look great. No.
Stay with you longer. Yeah.
Cheat on. You worked another one. Okay.
And won't cheat on you with another guy.
Now did he put in the top and the bottom?
I'm only spirit. Bottom. Just the bottom.
I feel like just the bottoms, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Marking guy. He can have anybody
he wants. Yeah, that's true. Thank you.
Really want you, we want you
for that. I got on my arm.
What's he watching today?
This is a game. I think it was actual
high, low game. Full volume. Loud.
You can pick up what's
going on in the game.
It'd be so great if he
shot this behind the TV,
like just sitting right behind
the TV hadn't been even funnier.
It's going to say that halfway in the DV,
one of my biggest pet peeves is talking
to somebody on the phone and like,
let's say they don't get
within the first few seconds.
If you hear the background like
that, you're like, hey man,
are we going to talk a hang up? Yeah.
I mean my dad's still, I'll be like,
what's that noise? I'll try to
like, yeah. He's like, Oh yeah,
I got turned TV and stands up.
I gotta find the remote.
Turns it off. Hold on, hold on. You
know what's interesting, so loud.
This fake wooden paneling and
the background and these beams.
These are like old San Fernando Valley
type household. Definitely an old ass.
You're right about that. Yeah. Did.
We didn't actually show Andrew how
we were introduced to this guy.
This is actually how he's known
to us. It's from this video. Oh,
last lady,
10 15 times.
I even went Beaumont's wow.
Yeah. That's really good. Yup. Do you
guys think he's lying? I don't know.
I always think it's cool,
like when guys brag about how good
they are about on sex, I'm like,
this is a cool guy. I think
he needs us most got, yeah,
I feel like I know how to
flop. You're like, oh no.
Probably guys knowing how to fuck
really. Well yeah. If you're like,
I think he's got like some form of are
you super strong too? Oh, that's good too.
Tough guys. Strong mark.
When they brag being smart.
I don't know. I think I gotta
be honest. I think he's right.
I think that sounds true.
He'll make you gum. Yeah.
Do you think that's his pitch
when he meets a girl? Yes.
That's like he's calm 10 15 times.
How much time you got? Like, um,
I guess I got time to come. I would
love to come 15 times. Okay. Well,
but Tom and I were talking about
this is that, that's not the, um,
the lore for women. No, like make
it, you don't want to come 15 times.
I don't know.
I feel like you're Josh in us.
Like that's how a dude would
entice another dude. Yeah.
That's in the gay community
that is letters the same pitch.
I'll make you come 10 15 times.
Guys are like, heck yeah,
let's go to your house right now.
What are we doing at this bar? God,
it must be amazing. It must be so good.
How much fun? How much fun? My neighbor,
my old neighbor and the old building, he,
he was a pump king. He was the pump king.
That's what I called him cause
he would fuck all the time.
Always Awesome Fun Party.
Common common new people coming by.
Just in, I'd sit there on my window,
just stay Erin wave and sometimes it's
some of the new visitors, you know,
some of them up like, yeah, fucking good
rid. What'd you do tonight? I did a spot.
Yeah,
I did one spot and I jerked off my,
my wife was sleeping in the
bedroom and I'm ate some cereal,
but I watched you three guys
tonight. Yeah, I saw crazy.
Yeah. Sometimes he would.
Sometimes he would fuck on
the living room and I had a,
he'd leave the blinds open a little bit.
I wouldn't watch from for long.
Maybe two or three nuts.
We got an email from somebody said last
night my wife and I decided to partake
in marital love.
I had finished my part of the oral
exchange and it was time to receive.
Everything was going great until out of
nowhere she starts laughing hysterically,
which is never a good sign.
I tried to stay in the game,
but I wanted to know what's up.
Through her laughter.
She managed to cobble together a,
I'm sorry,
I was just remembering when Christina
said that Tom's asshole is hot and gave me
so thanks for that Brian from Toronto.
You're welcome. That's nice. Yeah. Nice.
Your wife.
I don't want to give it to me.
Does she touch your be whole? Is she
a fanning or be home? No. You know,
she's kind of, she's, she's, I think
she gave it a whirl once and I,
I panicked a little bit.
Sure. Yeah. And I just,
it's like my no fly zone for some reason.
I don't know why.
For some reason the shit comes
out of there. Yeah. But I mean, I,
I'll tell you the hell out of her.
I love fucking looking ass.
I'm a big ass liquor, big ass liquor.
So it's just, you know, that's,
that's for when she doesn't have to
reciprocate and eat your scrum. No,
I don't know. I don't really want
her to, you know what I mean?
I'd appreciate a little bit more gagging
on the old Knob, but uh, yeah, you could,
uh, he could slob on it a little bit more,
but no, the butthole is just kinda like,
eh. Let it be, you know, you guys
are so amazing. Yes. Listening.
My has a couple of more,
couple of,
more of those and now the butthole
is just kind of like, um, yeah,
we gave it a whirl. We can't,
we know. We tried it. Yeah.
We ate at that restaurant and if it wasn't
that good, you know, so it's like, Nah,
we're not going to come back.
Maybe I want,
I've already tried to get you to just
like take a little test drive, you know?
Yeah. Just to try to like your scrap.
Yeah. But it's too hot. It's like,
this is why I said it's hot and
gaming where it's not as Gamey.
You could make up for some, maybe
like some a ball Chokan like some ball
but like really, but through
the, through the pop,
that's not even real.
Life is real. It's real.
It's very real.
I'm a Baja Baja Baja.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Yeah. That's all I want you to do. Little
Huff, you know, I mean just stop being so,
so reserved about it. You know, just get
in there. Are you a low hanging fruit?
Got Low hanging fruit? No, I think
they're pretty, I think that is fantastic.
They're high and tight. Yeah, they're
good now. He's got great balls.
I've always complimented you on your
balls are getting lower and I getting
worried about it. Really. They're
starting to swing. They're starting to,
they're starting to swing.
Swing a little there are we like,
I won't say that this happens with any
regularity but if it's July and it says
it's the right or wrong toilet.
Yeah, it will get some splash.
It's a couple of swingers I get and I
thought I got a little weird out back
cause I asked another buddy and I was
like, can I see are nuts. Like how,
how tighten are nuts.
He was like, for sure.
And he showed me his nuts and I was like,
oh no. Like I think you're really there.
Do anything like my dads,
if that's all future. Okay.
That's what I'm scared about
because my dad's nuts are the,
he puts him there on his knees and they're
insane and that looks like a pig from
like a pig's ball so bad.
I was scared of that.
He's never shy around me and I go, Oh
God. I saw him from behind. I was like,
Jesus Christ. He bent over
to put on underwear. I was
like, are those your ball?
He's like, get outta here. And
I was like, dude, crazy. Yeah,
like grocery bags.
So slumping philosophy on the cruise.
When he lame,
he laid on the bed with in boxer shorts
and each ball swung his legs over and I
caught a glimpse and then he
called, he was like, come on man.
They're just my nuts son,
your daughter.
So she's seen that sound like your mother.
I was like, I have seen a lot. I know,
but I was like, do you think she wants
to see your balls dude? And he was like,
all right. I was like, all right man.
A part of a part of him was so cool.
Oh sorry. No, go ahead. No, go. Does
it hurt when they get hang here?
Like does it hurt cause my tits.
Yeah,
but that's so the weight differential.
This is so light. Think about how heavy.
That's heavy. That's like that's
how these, no, this doesn't hurt.
It only hurts when I'm only
hurts sometimes in bed.
Like if I'm in an awkward
position sleeping and if I
roll over a weird way and
I'm like Ah,
and I got him caught up a little bit.
Or you can sit like especially
wear jeans a little. Yeah, that,
that line we'll kind of, you'll be
like, oh shit. Yeah, that hurts.
Cuts your nuts and probably going to
increase more as you get older for,
she should make jeans for your nuts.
Like the two little nut that comes
through your genes. Huggers, not hug,
none huggers.
That's what the genes will be called.
Or even like a stretchy panel for that
area of the crotch? Well, they make,
they make, um, they make night pants like
that. I really liked like, uh, you know,
like nighttime jammies,
they make really like big cups for your
nuts and your balls. I really love that.
Yeah. It's really nice. Yeah.
And where are these nighttime pants
sometimes and my cock sits in this little
just in this little bowl,
like a little cock and buffalo.
It's like someone holding it up just
gently and it's nice and soft and it feels
like this sometimes. I love it.
That's nice. Yeah, it's really nice.
You do. Are you a fan of
ball play? Do you like ball,
golf? Everything. Do it, go
for it. Give it, give it to me.
The only thing I never over the years are,
the only thing I learned is one,
it takes me way too long
to come from a blow job.
That's just an honest fact
and unfortunate truth.
I remember being like getting my
first one and I was like, wow,
I'm never going to come. This
is bad. Yeah, it scared me.
And then I think it fucked with my head.
Then for years I would swerve women from
giving me a blow job really well cause
I was like, can we just have
sex? And like yeah, okay.
Like if it was for play it was like let's
just fuck cause I was so scared that
they were going to be like,
why can't he come from
heard about multiple comics
doing that as a like to like
to Dalmatians on the road. They'd
be like, you want to know something?
I can't come from a blowjob
and I just got to stick it in.
And then the girls be like, ah.
And he's like, it's never happened.
And they're like, you haven't had one
for me. And it was just to solicit. Yeah,
that's smart. Yeah. No
mine's more pathetic.
Mine's like I just am in my head
and I just can't, he can't. Yeah,
I just don't come that fast. And
then I get conscious. I'm like,
she's been sucking my cock for way too
long. This is bad. I feel like a mean guy,
you know,
cause then they kind of look at you like
you're going to come and you're like,
I don't know. I don't think so. I don't
know. I'm sorry. And they're like,
am I bad at this? And you're
like, yeah, you're pretty bad.
That's the best is when you get into
their confidence and they're like,
what should I do? You're
like, try harder than
that. And I don't like, I don't like, I
don't like super aggro. I like ball play,
but I don't like them when people like
some people like hard,
weird shit.
I've seen those videos that's fun raise.
He like to get some like smacked
and like even this, that hurts,
that hurts on your balls.
You'll see people full on slapping.
The pulling one is weird when they,
you know,
they wrote the bag and they pull
it down is that one moves to watch,
watch a Brazilian video.
It was a,
it was a Argent time and it was a,
they love shit like that.
The guy in the office, it was, the
setup was, um, he's in the office,
like waiting for an interview,
you know,
and he's like waiting for the job
that she comes in. She's like six,
two and heels like,
like it looks like a real office
worker and I'm here for jobs. Yeah.
And so she right away it's like how
bad do you want the job? And he's like,
and then dude takes his pants off and
he has the underwear on for a while and
sometimes with the underwear on you go,
ah,
this is probably a pad in
there or something. Yeah.
Then then the word comes off.
She starts kicking this guy in the balls.
So God,
it makes me like inside makes me curl up.
She pulls holes,
suffer,
suffered,
his legs would shake.
So then used to ask me to play,
that made me laugh so much.
Your lab is there.
And then like what the fuck is this?
I want to see blood,
I want to see blood and they'd
have that bad. Am I dick? No Lady.
Don't make me laugh the most.
He'd asked for more.
I don't know how you can cause
honestly the pain of much,
much less than that makes me collapse.
Oh yeah.
Like I'm at my dad's funeral fucking like,
I won't be able to move one tap one.
So how does this guy take this? It's,
I think at some point it's
mental that they're just like,
they're so fucking deranged that the
pain is so intense. It's like satisfying.
You know when people do that, he's like
pain fucking Mongols that are like the,
the harder it is,
the more that the less they
feel in a weird way because
it's like so intense. It,
oh, it takes over. I can't
know. Too sensitive. No,
I don't like being hurt last week. Oh,
go ahead. Go ahead. I was going to say,
you made me think of like the funniest
porn scenario to me that I see that I
watched the video, but it doesn't turn
me on is you've been steel. You see,
I caught you stealing. You ever seen that
one? No. Oh my God. It's like, it's so,
oh wait. Yeah, yeah, yeah. It's
like the employee that's like,
you're my new employee and she's like,
I'm your new employee. And he's like,
did you steal something? She's like,
I don't think I took anything. How?
How would I have taken something?
And he strips them down and of course
they have something like insane,
like insane. It's like a laptop that
she stole in her. Like in her, you know,
and like her jeans. Yeah. He's like,
I saw you still stole this. He's like,
I'm going to have to punish you. I'll
do anything. And you're like this,
it's such a poor, poorly written
scenario. Cause scenarios.
Now we're getting like they're either
insanely good and they turned me on or
they're just so bad and so
shitty and creepy. Like the
brother sister shit. Yeah,
that shit. People love it. It's
fucking everywhere. It was popular.
I think it all incest things are
super popular. Oh, I opened up,
I opened up porn hub.
Any of those right away.
Stepbrother fucks step stepsister and they
liked it. They always say it. I'm like,
who the role is there? Like
sis. She was like, yeah Bro.
Like you would talk like that,
but it's to establish like gives me sister
mom said you were going to make lunch,
which was like, oh I got lunch for
you brother. And he's like, Whoa,
fucking suck my Dick.
Then then that's like the start
to the scene and she's like, fine,
if you'll shut up about it.
Yeah. God about making lodge.
I haven't come to any of those
videos today. Maybe it's because,
I mean I don't know. I'm just thinking
about therapy thing. Like are,
do you have to repress looking at your,
I don't know. I don't have siblings.
Like do you have to repress that shit so
deeply? No, it's not a, I think it's a,
just an people love naughty.
I think super taboo. Taboo.
It's not even the idea that would never
fuck their sister ever gross. Disgusting.
But then they see that and they're like,
it's so wrong.
Like it's wrong to the wrong.
It's also cause they're watching two
strangers do it. Like your actual,
like if a family member was even in your
sexual zeitgeists then you really have
an issue.
But I think it's cause they're like,
I don't know these fucking people right
here just to Weirdos and I'm watching do
weird shit is really fucking her brother.
That's nuts.
I definitely got to come to us.
And what don't you think of your own
relationship with your brother? No,
we were sent this last week.
Apparently I didn't know this,
but I gotta show this to Andrew.
I got to see it. Um, this,
this has been around for a couple of
years. I thought this was new to us,
but this video has been around
for a couple of years. Um,
I don't know if you've seen this,
but this is what's been around. Uh,
we played it last week.
Oh God.
And Julia made Joe just wanted to say hi.
Wish you a great day.
Tell you that meeting you yesterday and
getting a look at you was probably one
of the greatest moments of my life.
You was so beautiful.
You don't know how beautiful you
are to me. So just, you're gorgeous.
You're precious.
The met her at a club and got her
number and then she woke up to this,
this nice guy. Inbox. Sweet
guy. Sweet. So far. Yeah,
you're gorgeous.
He's got a good goatee.
He combed his hair and he's got the fan
running. I like this. He's almost too,
it's a great goatee. It's in the, in
the, in the world of goatees. Got It.
That's the one. He's got a cute
little bunch and underneath there.
So the more hairs growing in the crevasse,
but it's been sitting in my
mind when you said to me,
you want to go back with
your ex boyfriend, please
erase him from your memory.
Please don't ever go back in the past.
I know because I've been there and I
understand when you know you're trying to
find somebody and you'd go on dates and
not the compares to your Eurex but hold
on. He was religious by the way. You
didn't see the cross in the hallway.
You know what kind of guy he is? Yeah,
he's a good guy. He's a good guy. He, um,
he also will let her know that if she
were to knock it back to your ex and go
with him,
that she would forget about her.
I love you like you've never been loved
before. I believe it. I will cherish you.
I'll make you just fans. Still a woman.
I believe me. After you experienced me,
you won't even know who your ex
boyfriend is. Almost like that.
I make you come guy threat.
Similar proposal. Yup. Yeah.
And then let's take you
guys on this podcast today.
The creepy guy up a heart
open to making your arms both.
Let's go full throttle.
Oh yeah.
I could see me falling in love
with you just so I don't know.
I just looked into your eyes and I just
melt. Wow. This guy's a fucking bromantic.
Yeah.
I'm liking this kind of loud.
I like everything he's got at this
guy up with a sister. Come on.
Yeah. Let's see what else
he's got to say. I mean,
I'm so interested in this guy's
rhetoric. Do you when you, for me,
when I see something like this
feeling is like my new best friend,
my new best friend who I am so
humiliated for it. But I also go like,
cause we were talking about last week
that this is what happens in my mind is I
start thinking about embarrassing
things that you've done. Yes.
And I get washed over with that
shame. I get, I've got videos,
I've got videos are pretty similar
to this. So yeah, pretty close.
Pretty close. 34 when the
first one can now, um,
probably uh, probably put
out a little, um, God,
I was probably on the cusp of the
first round of Dick Pics and uh,
sent a, uh, sent a Haffey
I thought that was fun.
Like just not a fully, just like a half
the half Chubb, you know, like, yeah.
I've never gotten one because he and
I hooked up on the time of Friendster.
Oh yeah. Never even, I've never
sent my wife a dick pic. No chance.
I got half little Haffey
yeah. As a text. What was no,
I think it was an email to be
honest with Ya. An email? Yeah.
I think it was an email. A
picky emails. Both spots. Um,
no and that probably is the nail in the
coffin. You meet this girl and like,
what's the shit? It was like
friend of a friend type of shit.
Don't really know her that well. A lot
of flirting. Um, I thought real horny.
I'm going to send you this penis.
Pick A, I got no response and got uh,
nothing ever again. I think it was
indication of my, my lack of skill.
Really. Yeah. Was there? Um,
but it wasn't like, you weren't
just like, oh, I met you,
here's a dick pic.
There was like a lot of,
there's a lot of communication
and then she saw it. Ghost. Yeah.
Not a cool penis by not a cool penis
by, that's my name of my bio. Yes.
Send me the pictures and it's a, it's
just half. It's half. That's, yeah,
but here's what I'm thinking. Like, Hey,
I'm getting excited. I bet you it was.
It's better than you think it is. I think
it got sent around to friends. Yeah,
that hurts. And I was like, Ooh,
I show it to all my friends here.
People. I painted a little
face on it. On the top. No.
Do you hear people call your city
Chicago? CHICAGO? Yeah, for sure.
I don't like shy town either. That bothers
me so much. Really? We don't say that.
Right. It's like someone being
like the big apple. You're like,
no one's ever said that about New York.
Who the fuck puts this out there?
I was born and raised here
in the big gamble. Uh,
what about Illinois with the
hardest? Yeah. What are you
doing? Yeah, Illinois. Nope,
it's not, yeah. Chicago. Yeah. Shy town.
That stuff is city. Nope. No,
I never really picked up on the R in
Chicago, Chicago. And it would be,
she would always joke if we,
especially if we were announcing dates and
we're like, oh, we'll be, and she'll go,
we'll be in Chicago. And I would laugh.
And then in Chicago, it's terrible.
I don't like the one week I go,
oh,
I was flying in the United way and he
was going to Denver and the lady on the,
on the,
you know the PA system and that wing here
at Lex is like flight 26 28 to Chicago
is boring now. And I was
like, no fucking way.
And it's like I had never paid attention
to it. Where does the art come from?
They'd throw it in. Why? I don't know.
I think cause Chicago sounds so Duh.
I don't know. People's, a Chicago.
So it sounds like the this
in the city. No. Yeah,
but in Chicago it's such like a thick,
like Chicago is such a
thick accent that the A's,
depending on what part you're from, say
Chicago, ah, to emphasis all in the APP.
But when people say Chicago, it sounds
like all, all there and our cargo,
that's where it comes from.
Chicago, Chicago, Chicago. Yeah.
But people in the city. Chicago,
Yeah. Yeah. It's like the most,
it's the worst.
It's almost as bad as like hearing a
woman with a Boston accent. That's the,
that's the most unattractive I
was, I did my, when I did my,
um, half hour for comedy
central in Boston, and when
I left some girls like, uh,
some girls like, Hey, I'm trying
to do a Boston. She's like,
my friend thinks you all cute. And
it's like, yeah. And she goes, yeah,
my friend wants to fuck you. And
I'm not, I'm not making this up.
I had a slew of people around
me. I go, thank you very much.
So my girlfriend's right there, you
know, 10 feet away. Another girl goes,
I'm a friend. I'm thinking, I want
to fuck you. Like right there.
She's talking for her friend right there.
I was like,
this is the most sexy trashy. My friend
[inaudible] she wants to fuck you.
I'm a friend.
I want to fuck you.
It's like Boston has this like
just brashness to it. The,
that Baltimore accidents. No
good either. No. Or we'll Philly.
It's like hails home. It's the same.
It's like mid Atlantic. Yeah. Uses sexy.
Oh, it's on, it's on. I'll suck your
dick gets on Chicago. For some reason.
Girls that are have hardcore Chicago
accents. Yeah. Especially if they're like,
you know, Chicago girls, you
like it? They said, no, it's
terrible. No, it's terrible.
Yeah, because I thought you'd be
like, oh, go Scott. Dislike, dislike.
It's just sounds so dumb. Like you guys
want to go out and fuck around and party.
It's like this weird. It sounds you
sound dumb. It sounds dumb. It's not.
It's not hot.
I don't think there is.
I don't even the southern
accents not good for me either.
I don't know what chick broadcasting.
You're cutting out most accents. I can't.
I don't like accents. Yeah. What are you
into then? Just people. Just regular,
regular old girl's. Where's your a wife
from Denver. Okay. They talk like us,
like people just like regular ass old
people. Yeah. She used to tell me though,
she's like, Oh, you know you
have a big accident. I was like,
I have a nondescript accent.
No, no. When we started dating,
he bet Christina, you had that Carolina.
That's a good over here, Christina. Yeah,
I get over here. Yeah. See? That's exactly
right. Yeah. That's what Mites Mites.
My Dad's from North Carolina and that's
so, but that's fun. Those are fun accents.
Yeah, come on. Come on boy.
Of course. Dana, is he from?
He's from Carolina. Yeah.
He's from this small town called Valdese.
Oh yeah. It's about, it's like this big.
Everybody older boy.
Andrew Andrew while I was Hollywood boy.
Shout out to Randolph County
is good. I'll there. Huh?
Also up in Hollywood girl swimming pool.
You're doing drugs. You don't do drugs?
No. I don't know if that was really how
he talks. That's how the family toughest.
Yeah. Yeah, he does. And he's lived
in Chicago for so long. He does it.
But everybody else up there. Hollywood
too. Fancy boy. I'll see you when a rich,
oh, that's big. A big on that. I get
that from friends from the south.
My foreign cousins have less
references to show business. Ah,
so they go, eh. How is a
Hollywood Mr as Steven Spielberg?
I'm not a director and
they're like, you always be at
Victoria. Spielberg. Me? Yeah.
Where are these people from?
Peru. Oh Wow. That's beautiful.
I tell everyone that my cousin
is he Steven Spielberg. Okay.
You are kind of, you look
a lot alike. Yeah. We have
beards. Little tiny Jewish guy.
Yeah. Same thing. I like
the southern accent that,
I mean the one thing I don't like is the
valley. I grew up in the valley. Yeah.
That's like, but I really
don't like as, I don't hate,
I hate vocal fry and up speak and I feel
like a lot of girls now are doing that.
That's the one that we all agree that
that's the worst of all the ones, but,
but that's,
but that's not even like a regional thing.
That's like a cultural made up thing.
Yeah. It's not even from a place.
It's just kind of like people
have just made up. Yeah.
Megan and I have been together
for nearly three years.
She's a beautiful girl who I'm very much
in love with and I have a lot in common
with shit when you get
home and in the pool.
Cool man. Yeah. Cool. That's a man.
That's a man who could kill us.
I mean,
I guess I could shit on every
accent like San Diego tough.
I can't like do Debbie.
Great special.
If you did a special shitting on
shit on every, every single accent,
you just like, you don't have to think.
You start with one that everyone's like,
yeah, that accent sucks and you
just keep every one of them.
You just do every accident. Fucking
Brits. San Diego's fucking like a,
we were down there [inaudible]
we were fucking ribbon did and
how can you be a professional with that?
So basically your w nine is
faking and totally filled out it.
It's spot on.
I can't be a pro with that.
What about this sexy accent?
Anyhow, I'm heading off to work.
You see behind me everything.
Every square wrench from crown mold
into chair rail to floors, to lighting,
to plumbing. She says doors, windows.
It didn't go, but not the roof.
I don't fuck with roots.
He said he did the electric and
plumbing too. He's a sweet guy.
He's also like that. If that guy's
your friend. He is. He's like,
you want a ride to the airport?
Oh my God. It. He's like, dude,
I'll drop you off at the airport then
I'll wait for you to fly back. It's true.
And he would if like if you said that
something broke. Yeah, he picked Ohio.
Somebody what you know, do it, you
know, come by. I'll pay for the party.
I'm an Spi.
It's any get you to parts.
So this is the type of guy you got.
I'm a very guy handy.
I'd love to build you whatever you want.
What do you want a vanity
sweetheart addressing?
I hope this video doesn't scare
you. It does. That's how I shoot.
I just want you to know that.
Know that and I look forward.
I'm going out to dinner
with you any way you want.
You order what you want to go to
the appetizers. Ciao baby. Trey be,
you want to get one of
them espressos afterwards?
I'll pay for that bothers me
so much. Library. We're like,
we hate all that library.
Xpress ambulance, ambulance,
amber lamps supposedly.
Supposedly it's tough. Yeah.
Or or uh, uh, x specially, specially,
especially all intensive
purposes last year,
regardless is used all the time. All
intensive purposes. I got to admit,
I thought that was until I was about 36
intensive. I also thought until I was,
I think a few years into dating her,
I thought the expression was ahead
of the curb. Yeah. Well, okay.
How about this one? I didn't think I was
like, yeah, I didn't. I was like, well,
the curve, you want to park park?
Is it kitty corner? A catty corner.
Oh, right. See I say kitty corner,
but it is catty corner. I
it is. It is, but for years,
I know a bunch of people
that say kitty corner.
Maybe it was accident three off dumb
fucking execute corners or category
wholesome over they are category quoted.
You saying kitty cat a corner.
I thought it was combatative. Remember
I did think that calls for combatitive.
Yes, and she called me out. Yeah. When I
was like, it was this combative situation.
He's like, I'm sorry, what did you
call it? I'm like, did he correct word?
She's like, it's combative. It's
comp about additive. Yeah. I have to.
I had to look it up. Hello? Yeah.
That's not your fault. Yeah.
They spoke English wrong. English isn't
their first language. Yeah. Yeah man.
Come on. No, I learn English
from the television was hurt.
I had one foreign parent
and it definitely,
you just hear wrong shit all your
whole life. All you hear from him,
you know there's so many.
We don't have the other.
If I didn't have them to balance it out,
I don't know what I would be saying right
now. No Way. I would talk for a living,
but TV fixes all that. It
does help. I learn. Yeah, for
sure. That's fucking wild.
And also your friends
coming over and being like,
your mom says the dumbest fucking shit.
That too.
That helped that ls quicken it out.
Parent. Your friends are always like,
why did she say like, it's just out there
later. Don't worry about it. Ignore.
I like,
I used to love going over to friends'
houses and the parents would yell at them
in a foreign language. I loved
that. I thought that was so fun.
It was so personal in
their own little thing.
You've got to heard that plenty
in our, yeah, I like that though.
That made me an hour cause then you
don't know how much trouble they're in.
You're like, Oh shit, what did she say
to him? We always sounded more intense.
Oh fuck yeah. Like, like
my, when my mom would yell,
she's not like a huge yellow or all that,
but when she would yell it sounded like,
Oh, you're definitely, you're grounded,
right? Yeah, you're fucked.
And I'd be like, no, she just
told me to finish dinner.
Clean up the plates. It stop
fucking around. Okay. I had it.
This is a crazy situation. I have to
tell you, this happened two days ago.
I'm walking home back,
uh, in the neighborhood.
A water balloon almost hits my
wife in the face, not like an inch.
You're walking in your neighborhood
walking in the neighborhood.
Water boon almost said,
and you know those big mcmansions that
are all around West Hollywood. Okay.
So there's like three in a
row on my street. And uh,
I mean I'm talking like literally
just breeze past her. And I was like,
what the fuck? I look up, lights are
off, lights are off in this other home.
And I'm like, it came from,
you can just tell, you know,
you know where it came from? Yeah.
I go to the first house, you know,
I'm bring the doorbell, you know, she's
like, come on, let's go. And I'm like, no,
fuck that. Fuck. Like I'm on one. I'm
like, no, this guy comes down and like,
you got kids that live here, man. He goes
like, what? No. He barely speaks English.
No, I go, kids, do you have
kids? No, no, no. Go to the
next house. Ring, ring, ring.
I see lights going on and off and I'm
like, they're there. I know they're there.
Finally ring again. Guy Gets on the
intercom. Uh, W can I help you? I said,
you got teenagers that live here,
man. He goes, yeah, why? I go,
my wife almost got hit in the fucking
face with a water balloon. He goes, what?
Hold the fuck on. I'm not kidding.
I fell in love with this guy.
Instantly he comes outside,
comes to the gate, and he goes,
are you fucking serious? And I go, yeah.
She almost hit her in the face. Man.
That's fucked up. I mean, that could
have really fucked her up. I mean,
just from a two story roof. And he goes,
you want to scare the shit out of my kid?
Am I go, yeah, sure. Okay. He goes,
hold on, hold on. He goes upstairs,
brings down this little skinny little
15 year old kid. I mean, you know,
like skin and bones and his little tiny
Asian friend who's probably just never
ever been in trouble in his entire life.
And he comes downstairs and he's got,
he's pushing him towards me and he goes,
tell them what you did,
tell them what you did. And the kids
like, oh, we went through and I go,
you dread throw water balloons at my
wife. He goes, yeah, yeah, I did. I did.
And I go apologize to her face right
now. He said, I'm so sorry. Like, I mean,
I mean you could tell he's like breaking
down. And then, and then his dad goes,
you know what I told him
and kids icon and he goes,
I told him he could hit you once. I
didn't know he was gonna throw that at me.
And so I'm Kinda like, even as a standup,
I was like, Oh shit, that's funny. Yeah,
it's very, and I go, I go, yeah, he did
it. He said that to me. And he goes, yeah,
I told him he could hit you one
time and the kid is low. I mean,
he's genuinely like,
cause his dad did not look like he's dad
would be like a fucking tough piece of
shit too. Like his dad was a punk
motherfucker who's like, yeah, I told him,
he hits you in the face, both of you.
And he's like, no, but, but we're sorry,
you mean in it? And then he's like kind of
hiding behind his dad. Like, no, no, no.
And I go, come out here, come outside,
come outside the gate. And he goes, do it,
do it. What the fucking man
says. And at some point I'm like,
I have to stop doing it.
My wife has given me like the fucking
insane pushes us on towards the edge of
the gate. And I go, I go, give me your
hand. And he's like, give me your hand.
And he gives me his hand.
And I shook his hand, I go,
don't throw shit at people anymore. He was
like, oh, I watched his whole body like,
oh my God. He thought I was going
to like pull his fucking arm,
do some fucked up to that
is a real one though.
Dude sends a kid every
sends the kid inside.
I give him a big handshake and you know,
we're talking about, you know, and I was,
I, he goes, thanks for doing [inaudible]
that helps me sometimes. How did I,
you know,
he's like,
I don't know if these fucking kids
to control these fucking assholes. I,
I was like, dude, I was a
punk piece of shit when I was
a kid. Yeah. But he's like,
he's like, yeah, but if I
don't do stuff like this,
they just do whatever the fuck they want.
I usually take him belt until them,
I'd beat to shit. Oh. And I was hoping he,
I was waiting for him to be like, yeah,
no, I'll crack them in a
fucking high when you leave.
But he kept saying it the
way he said it to him,
cause I told him he could punch you in.
I told him he could hit you once.
It's almost like he said that before and
now it's finally going to happen. Right,
right, right. Cause I'll let somebody
hit. Yeah, that's fucking brilliant dad.
It was awesome dude. You really
shouldn't be fucking thrown, you know,
throw those balloons off.
No, I mean you could, he, I,
you watched him go through
the waves of like panic,
like genuine fear, like actually
feelings like scared, like hurt,
like gonna cry type of Shit that you
watch him go through all those as a
teenager. Like cause your footing,
you're doing dumb shit as he,
you don't think about anything. You're
like, oh we're just fucking around.
And you'd get away with one level,
then you go to the next one. Yeah.
Like I remember, you know, it starts
with like egging something. Oh yeah.
You're going to steal some shit from
place. Next you're going to vandalize.
Same with drugs or hooking. You know,
you give out a hand job or a job,
you start hooking wants start eating.
Guy's ass is on the street,
then I'm planting up, you know,
planning, doing crazy shit and wet,
wet angel. I remember until I got
caught doing stuff, he just keeps,
it keeps escalating because that's normal.
You're testing boundaries.
What can I get away with? How
much shit can I fuck up? Oh Man,
I was such a punk fucking kid. We used
to garage hop. You know what that is?
That's such a Midwest.
When people leave their group,
people in the Midwest League, their
garage is open, you know, like you know,
cause they've drove their car home and
they're doing something in her outside
and coming and going. They
just leave it up. Yeah.
We would go in there and steal
whatever they had in that. Oh Shit.
Beer mostly is what you're hunting for.
Cause in the Midwest most people
have fridges in their garages. Yeah.
You just hunt for beer. And then also
if there's some other shit, take it off.
Just take everything you can. Goes got
nine iron. I'm just going to take this.
Yeah. Fuck. I like golf. Take it. You
know, we were just pieces of shit.
We've tried to break in,
steal and do whatever we could
use. Test the boundaries.
Then you get hit by dad and,
and you know that. That's great.
Cause I think about our two boys.
You're going to have to regulate dude,
you got a God. If you got to let
them get punched by a stranger. Yeah,
you do have to let them be, you
know, get checked. You don't do that.
It's got to check them, but you have
to let them get checked publicly.
That's cool. I don't know why he
trusted me because I don't, I don't.
I look like I have it together.
But for some reason like what would
a bad move if he was like, go ahead,
hit my kid. I'm like, fuck yeah,
you told me to hit him Bro.
I thought you fucking had some
sense to you. No, no. Right.
Get the fuck Outta here.
And he's like, sorry kid. Did he
know you were a decent human being?
And that's pretty crazy because the
conversation we had beforehand was pretty,
pretty obvious. I said, yeah, he
almost hit my wife in the face.
He knew I was going to punch a kid with a
woman with me, but if I was alone, yeah,
you can almost hit me with a balloon. He'd
be like, oh, okay, fuck off. He's like,
get these brass knuckles,
put these on.
Really hit my kid for knock his teeth
out his fucking job. Where can people,
are you, are you wrote in it or you road
dogging it in and out a little bit. Um,
um, in Chicago, right here on the
top on Chicago, I go back to Chicago.
Where are you gonna go?
I'm gonna be at the beat kitchen playing
two shows on Friday night doing my own
thing because I played venues there
and it's home for me. So I was like,
I'm just going to do my own little thing.
Yeah. So I'm doing that, uh, Friday, uh,
Friday the 21st, that's this week. And
then the next, the following weekend,
the 26 in September, I'll be Madison,
Wisconsin, comedy on state. Amazing.
Favorite fucking club. Andrew is one
of the best comics working today.
You got to go see him do
stand. Absolutely. I've seen
you multiple times. So fun.
You have a special ed that people can
watch. Yeah, it's on showtime. Yeah,
you can watch it on showtime
if you don't have showtime.
I've ripped it on my Twitter.
Go to my Twitter. Go. Yeah,
because showtime has this weird,
you know, they don't let whatever,
what's it called? Home field advantage.
Shot it in Chicago. But yeah,
go go rip it off my Twitter if you
don't have showtime. I don't give,
I was like fuck. Cause I asked them, I
was like, can I have permission dude?
You guys hide this stuff.
Yeah. People need to see it.
If it's not on Netflix it's like
I don't think they know that Lord.
It's hard to find. So they were like, no,
we can't give you clips
or anything like that.
So I ripped it myself and
I was like, go ahead. Fine.
Actually it's not on my account.
Somebody else's youtube so,
and I'll just keep putting it up if they
keep taking it down. There you go. Yeah,
man. Home field advantage. Santiago gum
and for tickets. Is it interesting to,
you know, dot com [inaudible] dot com
yeah. All right. You were fantastic.
I appreciate it. I'm going to stay
here. All right. Okay, great. Next week.
This is an old one here.
This is what Allie, uh,
Zinzer what does, what's it
called? Double Pipe classic. Okay.
All right. Bye guys. Thank you.
Uh,
he's fine.
He's fine.
He's fine. He's fine. He's fine.
Okay.
I shall do
mine.
Okay.
She's
fine.
She's fine.