This episode of Your Mom's house is
brought to you by Saatva luxury mattress,
the only online mattress company that
provides free delivery setup and mattress
removal.
Wow.
Christina.
Judge a judge was a judge.
One of the things I think we
haven't even mentioned gene,
these episodes are happening,
um,
at a pace that is different than
normal because of this movie schedule.
So like right now when you're hearing
this episode, I'm shooting my dps,
my boy girls, my boy, girl, boy girl
scene. This is like call my scenes.
We record, we recorded this probably
three weeks or so before you heard it.
I know.
We usually do it in real time.
Like we do it right before two days
before it comes out a day. Just say fresh.
Cause we're kind of a current event show.
We like to be up on what's
happening in the world. That's
right gene. And um, yeah.
So it is one of the things it's
sort of a pain about right now,
but all we're doing it, we're doing
it, we're trying, we're trying,
we're trying to make it work.
We want to keep doing our show.
Can we please talk about, so we get
obsessed with, let's play the show,
fighting it, and we're doing that.
Let's to the show open as we go,
as we always do, and then we'll,
we'll get right into it. Here we go.
New episode of Your Mom's house.
Go ahead. Fuck your mom.
Okay Glen. Fuck your mom.
Fuck your mom. Your mom to
shut the fuck up. Okay. Yeah.
She gave birth to the wrong baby.
Okay, Mama, she gave birth to you.
You was a mistake.
Okay.
No,
we'll go to your mom's house.
No. Are you saying fart mix? You
want to book with my money? Oh,
that does kind of say yeah. Yeah. She's,
she got real upset. She's very feisty.
You know what? Uh, what's that? Is that
like a game thing? Yeah, she was on a,
was it twitch and I'm streaming
thing and people can come and check.
What really jumped it off was this,
was this
shut up CX. Okay. You don't want to
say that I look and salary Todd. Okay.
We taught is, is you okay from
seeing other people are retarded.
Okay.
Well,
you see other people are retarded.
It means that your mom actually give
birth to the wrong baby because you don't
ever have to rise to judge people when
your Dick is not even as this thing.
You can't even,
you can't even like have a proper Dick
and you say that I look like a retard.
I don't know. I don't think she looks
that way at all. I don't know what's,
and I don't know if it doesn't look that,
I don't even know what the insult is
that she's saying about the Dick. No,
I want her to know,
fuck your mom. Okay. Go ahead and
fuck your mom when you fuck your mom,
mom to shut the fuck up, okay. Because
she gave birth to the wrong baby. Okay.
From the moment she gave birth to
you. Okay. You was a mistake. Okay.
I had a girl, I like
it. I liked, by the way,
I don't think I've ever heard go fuck
your mom and when you fuck your mom,
tell her shut up.
So it's actually double
a pretty great insult.
It's saying go fuck your mom and when
whatever noise she's making you told her
to shut the fuck up and take it.
She's ruthless man.
She's great.
Yeah.
I really like your rights to say I'm
retired because your mom didn't give birth
to have shit hole like
you acid. Oh yeah, girl.
Good for you. She's fired up. I liked
the heat. Yeah. I like her fire.
She was very fired.
If we trained women to be more like her,
I feel like the world
would be a better place.
Like to stand up for yourself
and not take any shit. Be a lot.
I think that's good. It'd
be so retarded. Yeah. A lot.
A lot less Harvey Weinstein
action happening in the
world. You know what I mean?
Striking back. You think you
think he could take advantage
of her? I think she's,
um, she's, she's calling the
shots today. She really is.
She's a fucking animal. I like her. Yeah.
You get a sense her rage
if he's really upset.
I felt like that's what the Internet's
for a lot of people at functions as a
place to just let your rage out.
Yeah.
I have a feeling she's been called that
a few times though because the r word.
Yeah. Whew. I don't even want
to say it, but the r word, uh,
you think she's been called? I don't think
she seems that way, but you know, hey,
yeah. Potato Patato very
hurtful word, you know,
and do I have a giant?
It is so you shouldn't say it.
Yup.
Yeah. Goodness. I mean, you know, she's,
she's maybe not as sensitive to the word
as we are because she's of a different
culture. So we're going to be
a little forgiving here. Yeah,
you can let her say what she said.
That's her opinion. But yeah,
it's uh, here in the
United States, sensitive.
I don't know where she's from, but here
in the United States, um, you can't,
you can't talk like,
do you want to fuck with my mind?
Similar. Yeah. Similar.
Sorry. Similar. Similar.
I think she's might be tie.
You think so ty? What? No, no,
like that, that a little, I hear that.
Okay. Well you're the master of accents.
You tell us. I Dunno. Actually. I
know where she's from, Cambodia.
So I need to polish up on
some of my Asian dialects.
Can we please talk about our show now? Uh,
yeah, we can talk about our show now. Um,
a lot of good stuff happening. Where
is it? I had it here for right.
Oh yeah.
Ah,
oh yeah. Oh yeah. Oh,
um,
so that's our,
a reality show Stinger that we
hadn't been a long time ago,
but we haven't dove into delved into a
reality show in a while and we've been
watching more scripted stuff, which is,
you know, good quality. Tell you why.
I'm a huge fan of the reality genre.
I love it.
I feel as though you've got me into shows.
I used to never watch a lot of those,
but if they're not making
them as real as they used to,
there's so fabricated now,
but this one's a hundred.
It's a documentary type style. Well,
yeah, it's a series. I mean it has a run.
It's on,
it's on Netflix here in the u s uh,
I say that because we have
a worldwide audience. Uh,
oh boy. Uh, anyways, the
show his age gap love, right.
They just got glove and we talked
about it last week, but my goodness,
I thought it was a one off cause
that's kind of how it was presented.
This is just tackling one subject and
then I hit more episodes and there's a
whole season.
I'm so obsessed.
I know I haven't seen you this joyful
since you got into your narcos a
Telanovela. I think the reason
that I'm so obsessed is this.
The show is permission for me to
bring up my worst personality traits.
My most critical mean,
mean spirited,
but funny and fun
personality traits because I,
the whole time I just shake my head,
I'm like, Ugh, this is disgusting.
They're so gross.
All the old people are gross.
Makeup's all fucked up on the teeth
are all young people are gross.
The whole thing is just gross.
And I have so much fun just
hating them the whole time. Oh,
I think that's going to be a
guest. One second. All right. Um,
our guest is here. He is,
uh, fueling up with caffeine.
Said he refused to come on unless he
had coffee. I was like, all right. Yeah.
It was very, very demanding. So we uh,
you know, we, we cater to our guests,
so, but yeah, so age gap. Um,
yeah. I love, I don't know.
I you're right. I haven't had, cause
sometimes when a reality show, uh,
we get into,
you know,
it's usually like kind of background
music if you don't have to focus on the
grounds of sunset. It's kind of the, what
did that below deck, the yacht thing.
It's like I can miss an episode and I'm
like, oh that's, yeah, that's the guy.
That's cool. It's, yeah, it's like candy,
you just kind of cat. But this one,
I am so into studying and I also love
making a list as it goes on of WHO's
grocer? Like who like to fuck less. See.
And the thing is with us as a couple,
everyone's like,
you guys love each other so much. There's
so much love. And, and I'm like, you know,
a lot of our relationship, we're
United by stuff we hate. Yeah.
It's actually our ability to sit down
and watch a show like that and criticized
the shit out of people.
We don't even know they were really
bonds us ruthlessly do it. And uh,
with no heart and just, it's really,
if someone were listening be like,
you're a real asshole man because
we're doing, it's such a mean way,
but it's, it's, it's just you and I
like no one's really getting hurt.
I would like to do,
if we could through licensed,
I don't know how that would work is due
like alive streaming of us know how we
could do it or watching the
shots or we could do it.
We just say this podcast is going
to accompany episode two of age.
Got Love.
And then you press play on it here and
we have a different feed and then you
just talk as you do it. Yeah.
Can we do it in bed though?
I want to be able to lay it. Just bring
a zoom recorder up there. What I was,
I mean, well my favorite was so
the new champion of gross next,
cause every episode you introduce
new older people who were like,
that person is disgusting.
So there's a guy now who is like the
champ of gross and which one you feel it
cause we had no, he had the really
long white hair and he's got,
he used to be a minister. He's so
nasty. And his, his uh, so age,
they're, this age gap is
40 plus years or something.
And she's like pretty nice looking.
Gow Normal. Yeah. And she's like, yeah,
they start talking about the
makeover that he's, you go, oh,
she's going to give him a
makeover. And he's like, no,
no, no. This is him. Postmates.
So he's got his long, white people
had it. And you're like, what?
And she starts talking about when I met
him, his breath was really sour or what,
and she goes,
his teeth.
I asked him when the last time he went
to the dentist and he said 20 some years.
And she goes, so she goes, you could
really smell his breath strongly.
And she goes, now, you know he's had his
teeth white and you're like whitened.
Those motherfuckers are grains. They
went from green to yellow and she's like,
and his breath is like passable
now and you're like, oh my God.
I mean so, so gnarly.
And this poor girl is,
she's like fucking 30 or something and
they have five kids running around the
house. I just loved, you know what it is.
I think it's why everybody
likes those shows.
You just end up feeling better about
yourself and the decisions you've made and
where you're at or you get to look
into somebody else's home. Well,
I was wondering,
the breath alone is such a deterrent
for me and somebody's mouth being that
jacked up. Like what? What did
she like about him? I'm not sure.
I don't know. That's the problem with
these. I think it was just, you know what?
I think it was because they met in church,
I think it was,
there was some type of power dynamic.
She saw that he was the minister,
so she sees him in front of the church.
He's the, he's not, he's a father figure.
Literally two people, not, you
know, in life. In other words,
he's giving them guidance and advice.
Yes.
She was attracted to that paternal
energy and he told, you know,
he would give the sermon every
week and this and that. And then,
but then she's like, but physically he
was repulsive. And you're like, what?
How are you banging this guy? I Dunno.
It's, it's astounding. It's really crazy.
Jesus. My, my least favorite actually
is the Florida,
the acting couple or the guys like 60
and she's 22 and she was homeschooled and
she grew up in a religious upbringing.
So she's totally socially are worded.
Yeah.
One might say
and he's like not, he's not bad looking
objectively for an older gentleman,
but he's such a, that I look
and saw we had, okay. Yeah.
He, he's such a Boner, a dad Boehner,
like his jokes are like loves and the
size of a small child. And I, I'm like,
Oh my God, your personality so
unbearable. You are right. Okay.
About this.
This is my,
one of my favorite people in the thing
is that that guy I thought was less
physically gross,
but he is creepier.
Creep factor is a creep factor
because there's something,
he's disguising it with that.
Aw shucks.
Yes. It's phony. Yeah.
And it's a, it's yes.
Because you know, you know,
he's preying upon this.
She is now 22 they met when
she was like fucking 18 yeah.
And you know, and he's like, Aww
shucks, there's some bullshit there.
So that's scarier for that guy. He's
really taken advantage of her naivete.
Definitely. Yeah. It's not fair. They,
you know what it is too. I almost,
I have more respect for the trophy wife
and the older gentlemen couple. Yeah.
Just because there's an even exchange
of power. There's an even exchange.
It's right. Good looks and getting laid
for money. Yeah. Older guy, younger woman.
But she's hot. He's the got the money. So
there's an exchange, there's a contract.
But when the balance is totally not fair,
where it's like she's,
you know, 17 when we met
homeschool, totally naive. You know,
you know the world, Bro. You
know what, you're fucking
dealing. Right, right, right,
right. Any aid that wealthy,
you know what I'm saying?
Like she's doing her own dishes
and shit. Yeah, they gon,
they're gonna fucking Chili's for dinner.
I would like that camera to,
they were rolling that house.
Ooh.
I know that one's the one for a couple
of years. When she finally wise up,
she'll wise up at some point.
Yeah, it's, it's unequal.
What about the older lady who her 28
year old booboo is doing her toenails
filing her nails and her
feet and they're rotten.
They're rotten and crusted
there likes to give me a panic.
She's a, they're American, right?
She's,
she is a troll.
She's hideous and something's really
fucked up with that guy. Yeah.
He's weird too. He's on some type of
spectrum because he doesn't, it's not,
the eyes are not registering regular
emotions and he's looking at,
I saw her and we kissed and we kissed
and she keeps me, she's like, oh, she,
she's dude.
He's touched too,
so she's taken advantage of
some nice looking touched guy.
You know what I'm saying? He's touched.
He's really tough. Definitely our word it.
Yeah. And she's taking
advantage of this headache.
Hearing those horrendous fucking on hurt.
It's just gross.
What are you going to give me a pedicure?
If they looked on shut up,
I wouldn't let go near anything like that.
I can't even reach my toes anymore. When
are you going to start doing it? I mean,
I would do that for you, but
you don't. But here's the truth.
You don't look like that. And that's
why I would do that for you. Thank you.
If you look like her, I just filed
papers, so just serve you. Hey,
so disgusting.
She is disgusting.
It is fucked up too as a spouse where
you just let yourself go. It's not fair.
It's not fair to do to some
money. [inaudible] all.
Alright, let's get our guests.
Okay. Keep you one second. Let me bring
our guest in and a very excited. Oh,
all right. We're back.
We're back. Um, yeah.
We were talking about our
son's name, Ellis. Uh,
it is true that we saw the movie month
after Doc Ellis.
We both have immigrant.
I know. It's a good one. We both
have immigrant parents as you do.
So then people were like, oh, Ellis
island. That's where we're like, yeah,
that's the last thing I would
have thought. So I'm like, Eh,
but actually that's the one I have
to bring up. Whenever somebody goes,
what's his name all I have to go like,
you know, like Ellis Island. They're like,
yeah. I'm like, okay,
that's just like the island.
That's a great name.
He's a great kid.
Well with us is at the fantastic Tom
Rowe international comedic superstar.
Tom Rhodes,
who's not a stranger to your mom's house.
It's been a long time in
Redondo. We has a long time, man.
We had such a good time. I thought, wow,
I'm going to be a regular on this show.
We stopped doing guest guest
for two years. Okay. No guess.
And we did the Culligan Man.
He goes, I got Lincoln man
cause I had fans.
Have you got the part of your podcasts
that came to my shows and said, hey,
can we get rid of silly?
But you tour where you were like a world
renowned comedian. You're at, like,
you really do your road dog to the
Max. Like people are like, Oh yeah,
I'd do the road. I'm like, you don't
do the rogue like Tom Rhodes the road.
You really, you've done it. You've done
it. Comedy fucking everywhere, man. Yeah.
Well I, you know, I, um,
I've been doing the international
circuits for 20 years and you know,
I had,
uh,
I had that Sitcom many years ago in
NBC and when the Shit come finished,
I had a lot of money and I had played
everywhere in the United States and I
looked at my money is like
kind of my NBC artist grant.
And I started taking trips to
London and invested in myself,
slept on a friend's couch and uh,
actually the movie phantom thread.
Yeah. Everything I liked the best about
that movie is it takes place on Fitzroy
Square. And I, my friend rich hall, um,
he lived on Fitzroy Square and he
gave me a key to his apartment.
So that's where I would stay
when I would go to London.
And it's like a short walk
to the London comedy store.
And so there's some thread, so
you know, people know that's PT,
Anderson's new movie, Pt
Anderson, Paul Thomas Anderson.
I love Paul Thomas Jenner's. Oh my God,
he's so amazing. I haven't seen it,
but he's such an amazing,
I bombed in front of him like a month ago,
so I really cool guy. It's you
and it's a, it's a great film,
but I love the fact that it takes place
on Fitzroy Square, but you've also,
you've done, I mean London, but you've
done all over the South Pacific.
But what I was going to say was London
was the key to the international circuits
for me.
I got him with London and then that
led to gigs around Europe and Asia and
Australia because I want to know if
this happens to you when you step into a
whole other country. In other words,
whether it's a European country, Asia,
I'm going to do you have
first show anxiety of like,
is this going to work for me? That's
kind of the drug, that's the fuel.
Is this,
this fear of Oh shit,
this might not work well
and what is going to work?
And then the fact that you have to
think so quickly on your feet, like, um,
people don't read those references
and going to work. Yeah.
You know how like when you're locked and
loaded in your brain and you're telling
a story and you're like, how
you say brain is thinking, okay,
I'm going to go into this little section.
Yeah, I'm going to talk about this next.
And then you get this little
panic fear of, oh my God, is that,
that's what you're addicted to. In a
way. It is actually so funny. Yeah.
Like it's really cool. Like
when I'll do, uh, you know,
I didn't live anywhere for 10 years. I
put everything into storage and like, uh,
the last time I did your show, I wasn't
living anywhere. No, that's right. And,
and it was really cool.
So I would do three or four months a year
in Europe and then a month in Asia and
Australia, six months
all over the states. Um,
but like when you got like a week in
Ireland booked and a week in England and
then a week in Holland, it's like,
it's different. See like, oh,
okay, wow, Ireland was great and you know,
I really got the hang of it by the end
of the week and Irish audiences are the
best. And then you go to England and
you're like, it's completely different.
Really. Yeah. I would try to use this. I
was just down for it. Irish audiences, uh,
Irish, you can tell it, you can
see it in their comedians. It,
there's a storytelling tradition. Yeah.
Yeah. So they really love stories. Yeah.
And then you go to England and they,
they like self deprecation. Right? Uh,
you know, you don't see, I've never
see like a real arrogant Jimmy Carr,
but you never see like jacked
up arrogant English committee.
They're always a blessing on themselves.
Seen as like an American quality. The,
yeah,
the bravado and the like.
And then I saved the day is an American
thing and like the British sentiment
would be like, and then I fucked up the
day for everybody. Yeah, yeah, exactly.
I remember I did the Edinburgh
Festival in 2014 and this,
this wrote this review of me and she said,
don't we all wish we could be
as confident as the Americans?
And it's like, it's so stupid. Like, um,
I've had up ups and downs in
my life, you know, and uh, I,
you guys know me
personally and my, my, My,
my dad and my sister died and I,
I went into the emotionally
I was in the toilet,
I was heartbroken over losing
these people that I loved.
And it took me a while to build back my
confidence and then here's this woman
going, oh, it's this
American quality. No, it's,
we're each individually fighting
our own fight in life and you know,
things happen and you've got to
constantly be coming back from the brink.
Whatever you are,
you are
do not like about the
festivals and the overseas, um,
comedy scene. Like the one thing I do not
like the idea of reviews all the time.
I really don't because you don't have
any exposure to it when you're kind of us
based. Like you do shows everywhere.
No one ever does a fucking like,
you know what I mean?
Once in a blue moon,
maybe some city beat blog will be like,
I went to their show and they kind of do.
But like when you start doing some of
these festivals and you see all out,
um, I think it's just such a
departure from what I'm used to.
I was never a fan of that. Even if it's
like a nice review, you still like,
I don't know, it just feels like
you shouldn't be doing a writeup.
Yeah. Who are they qualified? What is
your qualification? Just some funding,
you know, it's gotten even
worse because like in Edinburgh,
the newspapers in England used to pay
for these reviewers to go up there and
most all of those newspapers
cut there. Oh sure. Budgets.
So they ended up your guide to budget
with a website viewing things and you're
like, Nah, I like, there's
like college kids writing.
It was like what are, yeah. Who are
you? I've seen some of those by the way,
that are absurd for a cause.
The one place you do see the review here?
State side is colleges.
I've done colleges and the reviews,
it's not even that they're,
they're critical.
It's so bad.
Just such a terrible writing because
it's just like a freshman, uh, you know,
journalists. It'll be like, I
went to see Tom Segura at our, uh,
student performing arts center.
He opened with a joke
about how cold it was here.
The joke went like this.
I thought it was very funny.
He next tackled these topics, some
of them like, and it's very just,
you know, stating a fact, stating a
fact, stating the line, stating review.
And it's like you're putting that out
into the Internet, uh, memory bank.
It's just, it's, it's
terrible. Gave away your joke.
Of course you gave away the joke
and he would do like, quote,
like long things and you're like, yeah,
just, uh, yeah, there's, uh, English. Uh,
I hate
to bring it up. This website
is it comedy website? Uh,
and they wrote some thing
about a joke that I did about,
not a joke. It's a story that
happened to me. And, uh, it's, uh,
it's a joke on my new album. And, uh,
my wife Ashton and I were talking about
the, the me too movement. We did a,
uh, an episode for my podcast
and talking about experiences,
and I talked about this comedian who,
uh,
had tricked me into going back to his
apartment when I was very young man.
And a,
and then this comedy website in
England wrote this salacious story.
I mean, they wasn't, wasn't salacious.
The headline was Tom Rhodes accuses such
and such comedian of sexual assault.
And then they quoted my joke and they
quoted us talking about it on the podcast.
And one of the things that bothered
me the most, well, I mean, you know,
they're trying to get clickbait. Yeah. I
didn't accuse the guy of sexual assault.
I tell the story of the creepy
older famous man yeah. Who,
you know,
tried to trick me and got me back
to his apartment and manhandled me.
Yeah. But he didn't punch me. He
didn't penetrate me. Yeah. Uh,
it wasn't,
you know,
and I think that sexual assault
is such a serious issue in the,
in the world right now.
Yeah. How dare this,
this site is kind of trying to
get yeah. Trivializing the, the,
the movements. Yeah. And uh,
and then also they gave
away my story punch like,
oh Geez, that's the worst though.
It was rolling on many levels.
Qualifies anybody to be a critic.
I mean,
even if you look at a Cisco and,
and fuck bird or what are their names?
Yeah, he's dead. They're
dead. They're both, yeah.
Apparently they both hated each other too.
So these are two men
who were full of hate,
I'm assuming to either a failed artist
or whatever. And one of them made like,
it's one of those celebrated awful
movies Ebird like a rotten tomato,
like valley of the dolls to or something.
So like,
so you're a field filmmaker yourself and
that qualifies you to criticize other
people. How I know like
it's just, I don't know.
I hate people that criticize already.
Like what are you talking about?
That's why I roll my eyes
at every top 10 list. Ah,
like as if anyone in your life,
everybody can write a top 10 list and
technically everyone's right because it's
your fucking top 10 list.
But the idea that we would make one
person's top 10 lists as credible,
whether it's movies, music,
books, comedy, it's like, why?
Why is your top 10 lists of value?
You're just, you don't even do it.
You don't do the thing that you're
saying you have the authority on.
Like you're not a musician, right?
Don't write music. If Bill Burr,
what a print out like,
hey, top 10 specials,
I'd be like, all right,
that's fucking bill Burke.
Let's listen to that guy's opinion on,
you know, comedy. It's absurd. But uh huh.
I know it's silly.
Fucking listen to these Jack Offs.
There's a lot of good movies that they
got terrible scores on you and I want,
we don't, we totally discredit when you're
going through the iTunes or something.
Like I don't even listen to that
guy. Let's see if it's good. I mean,
the only ones that are pretty much
they're spot on is if it has single digit
approval. If it's like 8% of
people liked this movie here,
like it might be dog shit.
If it's 35% it could be a decent
movie. Some people, you know,
just didn't resonate with
that and their sensibilities.
Or you look at the Oscars and you're like,
is America really watching these movies
that the academy has a big heart on
fire.
They made this big push now,
but now every category
has like 10 nominees.
It's a too many nominees. Madness.
You've got too many people up for,
I watch shape of water last night.
How was it?
You know what I can see,
I think that's the,
I mean,
I really want to get out to win,
but I can see why shape of water did,
did win because, and I, at the
very end of the movie, I go, ah,
I get it. It was a love story. I mean,
it's a woman in a fish and they're fun.
You remember splash,
we all loved splash, right? You
know, it's, uh, and so I thought,
yeah, well get out was a horror
movie and horror movies never win.
My wife loves three billboards,
which is about hate and people dealing
with hate, which really speaks to,
you know,
where the world is today.
There's so much hate and all
these lovely it out. Dude.
It's such, I, I, I'm,
I don't know I could,
I could step into a class about that.
I think so too.
I think I saw a fascination of one
because the guy invented his own genre,
which hasn't been done since Quintin
Tarantino in 1992 with reservoir dogs.
That was like such a, Oh wow. It's kind
of, it's mine. He'd wanted his own genre.
So for that alone, hearing him
talk about like, I love Jordan,
Bill Peele saying that he started and
stopped writing this movie like 20 times
and thinking that people wouldn't
like this, maybe never get made.
And Amsterdam, uh,
Jordan Peele was in boom,
Chicago, this, um,
Improv theater in Amsterdam.
And uh,
I had a late night talk show on the Dutch
television and I would stop by there.
Uh,
there was a bar out front,
it was in my neighborhood and he
was the guy that I would talk to.
I would pop in there and, uh, he
was a sweetheart of a guy. And,
uh, I, I, you know, I very
lovable, wonderful guy.
And, uh, it's funny, like when
you know somebody and they,
they knock it out of the park, you
know, like guy watched your special,
I've felt the same way. Oh,
thanks man. Yeah. Um, it's,
it's like a good feeling when you see
people totally knock it out of the park.
You didn't mention him. I did love jury
special as well, but what was the I, it's,
um, was that a year ago? Oh my God.
I haven't had one in many years
this October. Was it October?
It's a while ago now.
It's October 27 incidents.
It was a really, okay,
go ahead. Go ahead. No, but here's
the thing. I'll say this before. Uh,
that thing about, that's fine. It's fine.
The thing about that,
your specialty is great.
Now I'm going to feel bad
about me over this time.
The mom or something? It's a
cold. Oh my God, you guys, uh,
her special now it's called mother and it,
which is the best title mother.
I'm just kidding.
But one thing I love,
the thing I love about,
I'm so disappointed in so
many movies, you know, I mean,
you go into movie, you want,
you want it to be surprised.
Do you want to have things happen
that really you didn't expect?
And so many movies when you press play,
it's a blueprint that they're following.
You go like,
this is this scene.
I know what the next thing does that
sets up that this is that relationship.
Here's the conflict, here's
the resolution. Yeah, I saw
the movie the whole time.
The thing I love about get out is just,
just so many layers and so many
elements of surprise. Like you're,
you're constantly like, Holy Shit,
this means that and this, you know,
like you're the fact that,
that you could watch a movie and be
surprised so many times captivated by the
story. That's what to me was like
the most amazing thing about that.
Totally. Like when the woman's hitting
the tea cup and he's fallen down the hole
metaphor of the sunken place and you know,
institutional race.
It's just an incredible, if you haven't
seen get out at this point, uh, it's,
you know,
it's really,
it's an amazing movie that people so
sorry to people have emailed that a few
weeks ago.
They were blown away by your chicken
noises that you do a really good chicken
noise.
Um,
I guess you did one on the show and I'm
so used to your checking calling that it
didn't really stand out,
but hey, your chicken.
Well, I mean it's in my
special time and you know,
I am not going to watch any more movies
until I go watch your special I guess.
Got It. I'm going to write the most loving
review where it is ever been written.
It's the craziest, most unique, odd,
I mean I like your hat people do things
here that you don't ever see any place
else.
One competition that people flock to
for locals really needs no introduction.
Wow. Because it's not hard to hear. This
is the national cluck off where people
from all over the United States come and
sweet to see if we can mimic a chicken
the best. Um, that's great. You know,
uh, I'm from Oviedo, Florida and then, oh,
veto is famous for,
uh,
the Oviedo chickens really walk
around on the little downtown area.
Where is, oh, veto. It's uh, the panhandle
area. No, no, no, no, no. It's um,
east of Orlando About,
oh,
I mean it was a charming go beach
kind of towards cocoa. Okay.
Uh, it was a charming little citrus
village when I grew up there.
And now they built a circular highway
around Orlando and it is a highway exit.
Now there's a chili's and
a target and all that,
but there's still a little downtown area
and there's a Popeye's fried chicken,
which is funny because these chickens
walk around in the parking lot. Oh God.
And that's the one thing my
little town was known for was the,
as the chickens. Chickens. Wow.
Two, um, tied us all together.
I mean, people are asking, can we make,
are in for it? They want to, they can.
Christina. No, I can't do
the call. The rooster call,
but that's a specific time.
But you do,
you have done some impressive animal
noises. I think you did. He'd goat.
Is it sheep goat? Yeah. Let, we'll start
with the chicken. Okay. That's all right.
Yeah. Yeah. The pressure's on now,
but this is when the winter step up.
I listen to my face. I can't
laugh though. I can't laugh.
Well,
that was great. Really Great. Yeah. Hey,
hey.
That was really good.
Yeah. Thanks guys. That was, what
do I win? You could kind of have,
you could compete. Really
great checking. I don't think.
What kind of animal sounds can you guys
do? I don't know. That was really good
per day.
That is is not you. That was me.
I just did it. Ah, I come on.
What animal sounds like he's stuck
at your Chin like that too. I'm not,
I don't do the a master of accents,
but I'm asked from animals. Yeah.
They weren't know if
you can beat this guy.
One man entered the cluck the gun and
didn't lay in it because he took home his
12th. That's right. 12
national cluck off title. Oh, it's like
music. We say you have an ear for it.
I have an ear for animal sounds. Any
barnyard animal I can pretty much mimic.
Wow. Where was that? I don't know.
I wish it were in la. Yeah. The craziest,
most unique chicken show. God, I mean,
I don't know where that this is.
It's been an old age question.
What came first? The chicken or
the egg? Kind of boring intro.
I mean drawing here my goat.
I do. Okay. Ready? There's
also a visual way, right? Yeah.
Ah,
I was really good.
That was really good. So you do have
a skill for this. People were right.
They spotted it correctly. You're
really good. Terrible reality shows.
And I can make animal noises.
That's all I got. That's what I got.
What's your talent? What's
your odd talent? Oh Wow.
Can you wiggle your ears?
Double jointed.
Can you flip your eyelids?
I wow.
I haven't.
You pick your nose with your tongue.
When you travel. You traveled Europe
so much. Did you ever meet this guy?
There's nipples are
disturbing
this video. That's Europe.
You've traveled to Europe a lot
in Europe. That's how they are,
right, Jeremy? I don't know.
You spent more time there than
me. Those are so thick. Right?
That is so bizarre.
Yeah.
What about the offer from that gentleman
in his apartment? Should we play that?
Should we have roads? Necess
which offer though? I'll try.
Oh. Oh yeah. You want to
go all classic on them.
It's like it's been a while since
you've been in your mom's house.
You should know what we're
talking about. Okay. Yeah.
I don't know if you're down with this or
if you want. Oh yeah, cause you always,
you said that.
Well now you have a place to live,
but if you ever travel again
and you need a place to live
black, God's love to fuck and fuck
good. Yes. You're a hot black guy.
You want to fuck me at 2195 if you
want to move in, you can move in,
but you got to fuck the, I have
any, I need to be fucked a lot, man.
You can rent free food, free rent and
everything else, man. He has a GL man.
Men from jail, homeless or
um, your thug median income.
Then Franklin boot cheer, man. If
Vicky would have at least you got up,
it's a bad angle to be
lying down when you're like,
when you're looking for like a sexual made
partner, there's a whole lot of wrong.
Right. You don't want, you
don't want that dumper in angle.
You're the first guy to
mention his position.
You should be setting up definitely a
little more lighting. Better lighting.
Cover up those under eye circles.
Yup.
Foundation a little something.
But anyways,
free rent if you're ever in, I
don't know, I forget what city,
but I'll find out the great thing about,
I'm not living anywhere for 10 years
and then get everything out of storage.
Um, my apartment looks like a
national geographic gift shop. Oh,
does it? Really? Yeah. And then I, uh,
I, you know, I was blown away to fight.
I didn't know your mother was
from Peru and if you come to my,
my apartment, I've got Peruvian
blankets that you love. Peru.
Peru is my favorite place I have ever
been in my life and my all time favorite
souvenir.
I ever bought anywhere in the world and
I've been doing a joke about it is, um,
my handcrafted Peruvian
chess set and it is, uh,
the Incas versus the Spanish
conquistadores. Yeah. Well
we know who won that one.
Well, and I suck at chess whenever I play,
I'm the INCAS. When I get slaughtered,
it's historically accurate.
Hilarious. Uh, but uh, but yeah, I,
when I lived in Amsterdam,
I had a late night talk show for
two years and then the same network,
let me be a presenter on a travel show
for a year and I got to film a highlight
on Peru.
So I didn't go to the Amazon north part,
but I went almost everywhere else.
I travel what was there for
like almost two weeks. And, uh,
it was one of the greatest experiences of
my life. Did you do eyeliner? I did not.
Uh, you know, when you're
filming a television show,
they don't encourage this or
Anthony Bordain or something,
then it would be all about,
I've never taken my wife there.
And you let this man and pregnant you
were not taking you to the motherland.
I gotcha. There. I,
she's nervous about it. She read something
about Shining Path. I'm like, damn,
that's gone. Let's expand. That's
the terrorist organization.
I was there when they were
setting off bombs like living in,
I was spending my summers in
Peru and you would hear like,
oh my law and see like buildings shake.
Wow.
Windows shatter. And the next morning
I would call my parents, you know,
in the u s and I'd be
like, yeah, they, you know,
shiny path set off a 2000 pound bomb
let yesterday. And they're like, yeah,
so, uh, everything else good buddy. I'm
like, Jesus, you're not nervous at all.
They're like, no, we're not.
We went to Machu Picchu when we left
the road outside of Machu Picchu,
some like kind of country road people.
They had a,
there was some protest of some kind
going on and they had rolled massive
boulders off of the
mountains into the road.
They would block the,
that was apparently
way of protesting and
Peru have not know though.
That's some like really rural
shit though. Yeah. Yeah.
We've got no other way
to voice our displeasure.
Of course somebody get up there with
a, now they got, I mean that, that,
that organization's long gone
man. I know, I know. I do.
My Elk Guzman as the leader of the
Shining Path. He's in prison for life.
He's there on an island prison,
like their Alcatraz, uh,
I want to go back and spend more
time in Cusco. Gray was the, uh,
was the Rome of the Inca empire
and there's this famous Cusco.
Can I ramble about this? Yeah.
There's this famous 12 sided stone.
The ink is, did not use mortar. There's,
and this stone is like 10 tons and
it's as 12 sided stone and it's in this
foundation, uh, a wall. And uh, the,
the metaphor is that no stone is too
irregular not to fit in place somewhere.
That was the way that they, that's
the way that they did their masonry.
I love that. That when you're in much
appease, when you see these, you know,
15 foot,
5,000 pound stones and they're laying
flush with another stone and all they can
do is hypothesize about like,
there is there, like they're like,
we would today in 2018 we would use
tractors and bulldozers and you know,
equipment. And they're
like, we have just theories.
We don't know how the fuck
they built this and how things,
it's crazy he moved in late like that.
And some people think aliens might have
that. Maybe they just don't know. It's,
it's, it's really, it's so impossible.
And they're like, you know,
they had thousands of people,
but we still don't know how they
would make it look. And I mean,
they made buildings out of rocks.
It's crazy. [inaudible] PG, uh,
the way the did like home
dwellings or are laid out that, uh,
there's still running water that
runs through them, which is amazing.
And they took you to the
sacrificial Chandler.
They used to just slaughter people.
Cool. Everything is positioned so that,
you know,
you could worship the sun because
they're fucking stupid primitive place.
We got to bring this stuff back
then, man. But my favorite thing, uh,
the train from Cusco to Puno that you can,
the last car,
the Inca classes,
the first class in the last two cars on
the train have leather arm chairs. Yeah.
So the regular train ticket is like $14.
And then that's from Cusco,
Machu Picchu, Cusco to Puno. Oh,
to put in seven hours through the Andes.
Puno is the biggest city on
Lake Titicaca. Okay. And Yeah.
Um,
yeah,
you don't even know what's on the shores
of Lake Titicaca has a statue of Beavis
and butthead laughing.
So one of my favorite things
I've ever done in my life, uh,
so the last two cars is the first
class and it's only like 27 bucks.
He got leather arm chairs in the caboose
is a bar car and the ass end of the
caboose is an out open air Bannister.
So you can get a cocktail at the bar
and then you're like leaning against the
banister as you're
going through the Andes.
And then there's like birds of Lama.
It's just absolutely amazing.
It's awesome. You should go
sometime. Yeah, we'll see.
I got other shit going on. Yeah. You know,
so funny you said that your parents would
send you to Pei-ru and my parents, uh,
let my friends, my best friend
Shauna and I go in the summer of 94,
we were 17 years old,
not yet 18.
My Dad like just let us go to Hungary
and this is right after communism fell.
This isn't only two years after the
Iron Curtain. So Budapest was still,
it's like pretty much corrupt,
still run by the Russian mafia.
The apartment that we stayed
at didn't have a phone.
We had to use a phone,
see later bitch and uh,
on the corner of where our apartment was
in Hungary was a place called the black
roof. It was a strip club. So there was
like terrible elements and we would just,
you know,
we were 17,
so we were out at night like boozing
cause you could drink in Hungary.
No one gives a shit.
I was 17 with my best friend,
like running these streets.
I would never let my kid go at 17.
But they thought Hungary was the
way it was when they were, you know,
when they were living there during
communism, when it was safe.
But like not at all.
Here's what we're going to
panic the morning after this
one particularly notable
bomb was set off because it was so
powerful that, you know, we were,
we were let's say 15 minutes outside
of downtown Lima and, uh, in the house,
uh, that I was staying in with my
uncle and my cousins and aunt lived.
They had this a window that
was like an old school.
It was a like 150 pound try Amazon think.
So.
No. So it was like 150 pound
window that you had to,
you used to crank, right. And
then it would let go, Ooh.
It was open by a crank,
really heavy and enormous.
And in the middle of the night,
the bomb that went off was so big downtown
that that window blew open and then
just shattered everything. And it wasn't,
it was national news, international news.
Cause you know, the, the,
the Shining Path movement was growing
and I thought they were going to be like,
you're getting on a plane today, right.
It barely registers to my parents.
I was like, could you see it on
CNN? They're like, yeah, well,
you know how it goes. You're going to,
so, uh, you guys going to go do this?
You're going to go to the still going to
school today? I'm like, yeah, like, yeah,
worried about this shit at
all. And they're like, hey.
And my uncle was in media,
so they're like,
your uncle is a target because the,
the shiny path would target people with
influence, you know? So they were like,
he had body guards and I'm like,
wow, you're not worried about this
family didn't have any influence.
Yeah. Scumbags. Just Hungarian.
Totally everyday. What the fuck man?
Um, what's wrong with their parents?
So did you know that, uh, one of our guys,
this guy here who was a
also legendary on our show
before you have sex,
if you want to be haunted for two
or three hours, like you never been
in your life, you have access
to marijuana too. Good.
We'd listened to me.
True. We'd alone can get you
really hornier than normal,
but it's been an Andrew
will take about 10,
12 Benham girl before you want to have
your sexual fun with your partner or
whatever you do or masturbate.
So what do you think? First of all, about
10 or 12 minutes after looking at it,
that guy,
I never would have sex everywhere.
That guy was really disturbing. Yeah. Um,
so he's been featured on the
program a few times and he's back.
This is a, and we've an
update. Well he has a, uh,
I guess this is just a commentary that
he has on a topic that is important to
us. I've gone way up,
let's say for what reason?
It's Kinda nice now. See what, see
if you agree with what he says.
Are you sure it makes sense
for now?
What the Dennis Dennis questioning Dennis.
Okay.
For now,
what the dentist do you really wish that
all of us would have no more troubles
with their gums or teeth?
Because if you do,
then you don't make any money and you
don't have a life anymore and you wasted
your life. So if Christ comes
right now and says, well,
I'm going to heal everyone on this
planet, Amount Hill, their teeth,
then where does that
leave you man? Wow. Right.
I have more a serious
issues with my dentist.
Yeah, I mean that's
ridiculous. I mean, wait,
you're saying that he has a ridiculous
beef with something irrational?
It's irrational beat for, first of
all, if you're going to make a video,
put on a shirt, put on a
shirt, opposite philosophy.
He's never had shirts.
It,
it did look like he had some kind
of hair gel in his hair though.
But my dentist displays vacation photos
in the waiting area and I think that
just breeds resentment. Um, you know,
you're sitting there and like there's
pictures of him like on a boat in the
Caribbean or wherever and it's like,
he's like, you're about to pay for that.
How many calories?
You didn't have a cavity,
but I just got the bill
on this fucking Bahamas.
My kids want to go paragliding.
God, Jesus Christ. Yeah.
Well this guy has got beef with everybody.
I love about find this guy.
People just cousins. He
sent them in. I Dunno. Yeah.
I think that my favorite thing though
is that he really thinks he cracked the
case with this. Where
he's like, he's like, Nah,
if you don't have cavities anymore,
where are you going to make your money?
And he really feels like he
solved the case. Totally.
My crop that he's like,
where's that?
And where does that leave you man?
Yeah, he's talked some shit.
He really ties and nailed you
figured out your whole scale. Yeah. He
just like a, like a homicide detective.
He's just a really solved
the case detective shall
Lacey's on it. So if you, uh,
how has it been by the way?
We haven't seen you in a while,
but how do you feel
being housed now as you,
for you went 10 years without a
permanent address? I love it. Ah,
yeah.
Cause Oschner loves to cook and it's
interesting the little things in life,
like having a sock drawer and
underwear drawer a really thrills us.
And the fact that,
uh,
we can buy family size shampoos and
everything was traveling, travel,
see everything was travel size forever.
And then we opened the fridge and
we're like, we own this mustard,
our third man. Uh, and it's,
it's nice to I,
this is my third time living in Los
Angeles and I used to not like Los Angeles
and now I love it because I'm
older now I'm married and uh,
now I can appreciate the,
uh,
fine fruits and vegetables that
are available in the mortgage. Um,
you know, I lived here 20 years
ago when I had the Sitcom.
I lived on top of the Hollywood
hills in this rockstar apartment,
all glass walls.
I view of all the lights of Los Angeles.
I was swimming in cash and then 20
years ago I lived in, I'm sorry,
10 years ago I lived in Korea
town and I was broke. And um,
now it's like the three bears
porridge is just right. Awesome.
Not broke. I'm not rich.
Just kind of uh, you know,
life enjoyable but seems like you're very
content and a good, a very good place.
Like, yeah. That's awesome.
Got to feel so displacing.
I that one thing I didn't like about
being on the road was that the constant
living out of the suitcase, like my Tom
and I were really hardcore road dogs.
There's a few years there where,
you know, you go out Wednesday,
you come home Monday and then you reset.
It was just living out of it.
We had to take Austin,
uh,
my wife traveled with me for eight of
the 10 years did I didn't live anywhere.
And I told her when we got together,
when she's from Holland and when we,
you know, the first year was a long
distance relationship and then I said,
if you want to be with me,
you have to reduce your life.
To one checked bag and to
carry owns and for a woman,
for a woman to reduce her life to like
four pairs of shoes. Very admirable.
She rolled with it and we had a
great adventure. Um, you know,
when we had time off, depending
where we were, we would go like,
and especially now with like airbnb
and Uber and you know, you can,
you can basically live anywhere
and have a nice life, you know,
four years in a row we went to Rome and
rented an apartment for a week or two
after I did like a couple months,
once of gigs in Europe,
did a month in Asia than we went
to Bali for a couple of weeks. Um,
when I was still drinking in the states.
When we had time off,
we would go to New Orleans. We loved
New Orleans, um, San Francisco,
depending where we were when we had time
off because we didn't live anywhere we
could live wherever we want it.
It's great cause I want to know
with all this traveling with,
I mean she was with you. How often did
she go to the show? A Lot, actually.
Yeah. Uh, I mean, that's probably why
I married her. Yeah. Uh, but yeah,
no, she, and she, that's
one of the things that I,
I love the most about her is she loved
not coming from the comedy world. Yeah.
Uh,
she instantly loved comedy and
loved hanging out with comedians.
It's so funny when you start hanging,
hanging out with comics,
it's more fun than watching them
do that. Totally. So like did that,
that was the best thing.
And then, you know,
doing festivals around the world and then,
uh,
having comedian friends and all these
different countries go to Australia and
then there's this group of
comedian friends to hang out with,
go to whatever country, and then
there's, you know, or go to Chicago,
good in New York and there's that new
group of friends every week to hang out
with. And, um,
I also liked the fact that she
was a heavy drinker. Did she,
cause she could hold her
liquor and, uh, and you know,
I was a heavy drinker forever.
And, uh, and yeah, you gotta
have a partner in crime,
right? You don't want her to be.
Yeah. So it was fun. We were,
we were partying and hanging
out with comedians and, uh,
when I busted my head open and
stopped drinking four years ago, she,
she dialed it back enormously. That's
great. You guys are a perfect match man.
Yeah. And it's funny because Tom and I
are the complete opposite of you guys.
Like when, if I would go on the
road with him like years ago,
I would never go to his show
and like pretty much vice first.
I don't think he ever
really now because we're so over it.
Well like I get anxiety being
in the room of a show period.
It doesn't even matter.
It's really actually so I don't like it.
I don't like being in the showroom know,
like when I'm not up there,
you guys would have like us that um,
you know,
when your partner sees you so often,
you gotta make your show lively
for them. Oh God, now no,
I'm the opposite in the room.
It's my Kryptonite
and he's watching.
There were years,
I would not let him watch me cause I,
it was like,
it gave me so much anxiety because I,
you know,
me as a human and then to see that
that would happen now would be is like,
you know,
because we know each other so well.
It's been so long and it's such like,
you know,
a deep rooted relationship
is if, uh, if we're in like a work
mode where another word, she goes, um,
I'm work shopping this thing, let me
know what you think. She might say like,
so watch this specifically or vice versa.
It'd be like, I'm doing this thing,
do you think this is this or that?
But then it's like we put
on like workbrain it's not,
and I don't feel like I'm watching my
wife feel like I'm watching. Disassociate.
Yeah. Disassociating on. And then
we're like, we're talking about a bit,
but just for like the joy of watching
it, I can't do it. I don't like,
I don't like watching, like if I
have a spot at the store tonight,
if I go there and they're like, I'll
find out, when am I up? Oh, you're up in,
you know, 20 minutes. Someone's
on stage right now. I'll pop in,
I'll start to watch them and after
a couple minutes I'm just like,
I got to get out of the room
so I have to leave the room.
I, I, it's funny, I, I uh, I like
standing there watching it. I,
I still eyes love watching comedy.
I like sometimes I'll,
I'll get there early when I'm at the
comedy store and I like when like somebody
is destroying the room before where
you can say something and then it's uh,
I'll give you an example.
Like the, at the,
I go to New York once or twice a year
just to do sets at the comedy cellar.
I love it.
And last summer I went to New York and um,
I had to go on after Amy Schumer.
And so Amy Schumer,
I had to follow her like three times that
week. And you know, she's from New York,
she's just hometown hero.
Everyone loves her. She's,
she's destroying the place.
And she told the story about her father.
She said he kind of an asshole,
he's got ms or whatever.
But she's just for her father and she
loves him and she's been paying somebody
to come and Jack him off.
Oh God.
And so this was her
closer and uh, and, and,
and, and she absolutely destroyed the
place. So like you got the, you know,
there's the normal anxiety,
nervousness as comedian when you're
about to go on stage and you're,
you're in your mind about
what you want to talk about.
And then when somebody is on before you
and they're absolutely ripping the place
to shreds and they're being adored,
and then that adds even an extra
layer of intensity to your, yeah.
Anxiety.
And so I guess for me it just
came to me the first night,
I'm like,
oh my God,
she's absolutely just can't believe she's
talking about her dad like this. Yeah.
It just came to me like moments
before I walked on stage.
I walked out there and I just
acted very kind of shy and,
and sheepish. Hi everybody. Um,
please forgive me. I'm a little nervous
tonight. This, this isn't my normal job.
My normal job as I jack off,
Amy Schumer's fine.
I'm not used to working under
these bright lights. And, uh,
normally I worked to candle
light with some soft Sinatra,
the backgrounds and like, it
just, it's like, it's, yeah,
it's like surfing, you know, you jumping
on someone else's wave. Totally. Um,
no, but you know why you,
you do that though, because
you're a better comedian. Ah,
actually that's the only
time I'll tell you this,
the only time I do feel inclined
to like, Oh, pay attention,
pay attention is if someone is ripping
the room, perform. Yeah, that is,
that will make me, but I'm doing
that not for my own curiosity.
I'm doing that to be able to be effective
and know what's going on. You know,
watched the person before me
just so like, Oh, if they, oh,
they do this topic or
this topic or you know,
if you ever thought about with all the
touring and all the years you've been
doing it,
do you ever,
have you ever thought about how many hours
you've probably written or no? Uh, no.
Uh, well, I mean I've put out a,
I just came out with a new album,
all hail laughter and
that's my fourth album. Um,
how much unreleased stuff?
Yeah, I have no idea.
I mean I videos and videos of
things from the past. I don't know,
it's just amazing to me how long
I've been doing comedy and uh,
it's, I that I can't sell more
tickets in certain places.
I got to a, I'm in Sacramento
next week. I be doing that.
The punchlines is such a great room.
Great Room. I love Sacramento and,
and Lady Bird was one of my
favorite movies of the year.
I thought Greta Gerwig should've
won the, the, the best act.
And I loved the fact that the
film took place in Sacramento.
It's this girl coming of age story.
Anyway,
I get this a email yesterday.
I'm just saying that a minimal
tickets have been sold and it's like,
when does this anxiety leave
you as a performer? Yeah.
How much do you have to do in your life
and career? Get where it's like, you know,
I shouldn't have to worry about, I
know a room like that. So what though?
But the weird thing is they're really,
everybody will have a theory and that
nobody is 100% right because there is no
formula. If we all knew the formula for
sure and everyone would just be like, oh,
just do this. But that's the thing. It's
like you just don't know. I mean some,
I mean sometimes it's a something online,
like people started selling tickets off
of viral videos now, you know. Oh yeah.
I mean you can just do something
that just blows up online.
All of a sudden that sells tickets.
Sometimes it's more traditional, it's TV,
it's movie or it's a special that
really resonates with an audience.
But even that you just don't
know it. There's no formula.
That's the most, I dunno,
frustrating part. But that's the part
that if there was an answer, you know,
it's like trying to, how do you
make a a movie be a blockbuster hit?
And they like, well, you know,
it's like, I dunno. It's,
I guess you'd think about things
the way you are in your life.
Like my eye,
there are certain comedians I
love and like I will go see them.
Uh, I'm fans of certain
people. I love Van Morrison.
Van Morrison played at
the Wiltern last week.
I W I saw him once before in New
York years ago. And he's older. Yeah.
And, uh, you know, I went
and I, and I'm a fan. I,
it's like I can appreciate just being
in the same room with the guy because I
love him so much, but only because
I'm a huge fan of Van Morrison.
I could pick out the
five songs that I knew.
I think anyone else who went to that
show would have thought, oh my God,
I can't believe he didn't do,
have I told you lately, or x,
y I wish she'd done more hits
or whatever, you know? Um, I,
it's, I don't know. It's,
I guess people who knows what I'm
trying to, no, I dunno. I mean,
I know what you're trying to say. If you
love somebody, you would support them.
Sure. Yeah. Yeah. That's true.
Guests. No, it's true. It's true.
It comes from having a devotion to
being real. That's what a fan.
But I mean, there's like, there's,
there's some cities like San
Francisco and Chicago and Atlanta.
What's your best city?
Ah, I love San Francisco.
The punchline. I like Minneapolis.
Acme. That's great. Uh,
the Atlanta punchline had
been playing for years. Um,
Chicago xannies you know,
there's, there's, there's,
there's a lot of them
that I love. Yeah. Uh,
the Sydney comedy store in Australia is
one of my favorites and they're good to
you.
I was there last year and it had been
a few years since I had been there.
But yeah,
I've played there a lot through the years.
One of my favorite rooms in the world.
If you played there. Uh, I did. Uh,
I did a guest set there when I was,
I was in town for
festival a few years back and I
got to do like a guest sat there,
which was really fun. That
was it. That's the most,
I love Australian audiences and Sydney's
one of my favorite cities in the world.
I just had to cancel for
someone's going to do
ne next month and then let you cancel
because I booked that, that movie.
So it's like a good reason
to have the cancel. Yeah.
But it's fucking my second cancellation
or a, well, maybe when you go
back you'll do the Enmore theater.
That's what I was booked to the more,
it was amazing. I was booked to do it.
We were, we were in that part
of town. New Town is like the,
it's the cool gay, artsy
area. Like if you were a,
an artist or a musician,
I'm just bomb because here's what
now I want to do.
I want to rebook Australia,
but I cannot book something
again and cancel. Right.
But I don't know what like, so I want
to book something without a lot of,
uh, a heads up. In other
words, I want to be like,
hey man, can we try to book Australia
for like eight weeks from now?
So that I know that I can definitely
do it right. But I don't know if
they'll go for that. It's pretty,
I Melbourne of course, uh,
is amazing. Awesome. Yeah.
Brisbane Perth. Yeah. Love these poets
supposed to do. I got to New Zealand,
the New Zealand comedy
festival haven't been, um,
that's god that was one of the best
months. Yeah. I refuse to go. Really?
No, I actually asked to go and, uh,
the promoters were like, ah,
we don't think you should
add a New Zealand to this.
And I was like, why? And they're like,
because it's not that big of a market
and you're not that big of a name.
And I was like, all right. I just
thought it'd be really, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So I was like, okay, so I'll
just leave it as it. I mean,
there was there talking about it like,
I, after all you've done, they were like,
oh yeah. They said, no, I know
when I tried to add new field,
what does the performer have to do?
It's a funny, Tom and I talk about that.
Like in our business, you're never
ever enough on the food chain,
no matter how successful you are, you're
always a piece of shit. We're saying.
We were saying that like, Bill start
saying things to you, like they'll go, uh,
and then,
uh,
this is the offer you're going to get
and somebody in your position should be
pretty happy with that
off. Wow. Wow. Oh yeah.
That was what we were talking
about when you were going,
I got a message about my,
my ticket sales for next
week and Sacramento.
Fuck, do I have to worry? Yeah. And
by the way, what point in your life,
and it's not, it's not
only that, the real,
the real job of a real
club is that they are,
suppose you're supposed to deliver the
thing on stage and like you do what you
can and your, your podcast or you
post that you're coming somewhere,
but they are your promoter.
That's the job they,
and a lot of clubs don't
look at it like that. Now.
It's not your job you're doing is
like extra as far as promoting,
but they're supposed to promote your show
and they're supposed to be creative in
ways to get people to come to that show,
you know? And so when they're like, yeah,
you didn't sell tickets, I feel I'd be
like, now you didn't sell tickets, right,
because you were supposed to let p,
what did you do?
You send out an email once or something,
right?
Why don't you be a little more proactive
about it and then they tell you, oh,
we got to back out this amount from your
pay because it costs me like five grand
and advertising. And you're like,
what did you know that you can ask?
I have five grand.
I didn't see any bus posters.
You can legally ask for receipts on that.
I would like to,
whenever whenever you do a build Burgo,
if they do like deductions, they'll
say, you know, advertising this,
you could be like,
I need to see the receipt receipt or,
or the ubiquitous radio spots
where they're like, oh, we
spent thousands on radio.
You're like, okay, that's really
hard to trace. Like she'd be like,
why would you do that? You know
who's listening? Yeah. Yeah. Well,
my favorite
is always, oh, you, you just
missed your bonus by 11 people.
Yeah. You sell a hundred tickets,
you're going to get the bonus.
And we only sold 89 fucking counting.
And I had one
say more. I did a weekend a few
years ago at a club that held, um,
I think the club,
the club,
let's say three 50 and I had a bonus
that would kick in regardless if it were
free or paid tickets.
And I had paid tickets,
bonus would kick in at 300 capacity.
So if as long as we're throwing people
in the room, I would get the bonus.
And I had like between two 85 and
two 95 at every show, but paid. Oh,
that's great. And they
didn't give me wow. Anyhow.
And then I called, that's the business.
What kind of fucking deal is that?
I sold tickets, hard
tickets. Right. And then,
but I didn't hit that magic number and
they're like, we'll get them next time.
Next time. Yeah, no, I do the other
club next time as well. How about
exactly? I love it. He's like,
like some of these club owners driving
a brand new Mercedes Benz every year and
it's like, wow. Yeah.
Just missed the bonus.
There was a place in town here where
the guy would, they don't pay for,
they don't pay you for spots and he would
pull up people like we can't pay for a
spot to pull up in like a
new Lexus. Yeah, you can't,
you can't dish everybody
15 bucks for the set.
And he was my favorite story in the
world. Chad Daniels, who's Hilarious,
who your friends are. You guys
did that documentary together. Uh,
I need you to kill. So he did some
club, I won't say where. And the guy,
the owner of the club pays you a different
rate contingent upon what time of
year you do the clubs.
So in the summer,
let's say he'll pay you 1500
but in the winter it's $2,000.
And so Chad goes in the summertime and
he's working out new material and the
club owner is like upset with that
because you know, Chad's working it out.
So it's not like kill, kill,
kill, kill, kill. And he
knows a child's capable of it.
He's a really funny comedian. And so the
owner is like, hey man, what the hell?
Like you came and you did all this
new stuff, like you're not killing.
You know what the fuck?
And he goes, well, he goes,
I'm doing my Somerset to go.
He summary,
he stuck with doing this
new set that wasn't killing.
That's just just to tell that
guy I'm doing my Somerset.
I don't know him, but now I
love it. That's fantastic.
Yeah. Somerset, I'm still,
the guy's like, dude, what the
fuck? He's like, well, you know,
I'm giving you what you pay
for in Somerset. I mean,
have you ever heard of that?
I didn't know that. The club, I
never, I know. Yeah, I know that like,
I know clubs, especially old
mark. Is that a room in Texas?
No, I'll tell you. I'll tell you
after the shades in North America,
cold market clubs especially,
you know your mom and pop
clubs midway will, they're
always packed in the winter because
people sure pack up, fill it up. Yeah.
And then clubs in like Texas and
Florida in the summer because of the air
conditioning. Yeah. Therefore too. It's
interesting. Yeah. So, but like those,
those cold places in the, if you sell
tickets there in the summer, they're like,
all right,
you're legit.
But they expect to have more empty seats
in the summer and that the idea that
they'd be like, and that means we're
not going to pay you as much is yeah,
it's the business where
it's the shittiest man. Um,
do you think this lady is touched or no?
Seven oh 4:30 PM.
I'm just wondering what the
heck is then our water supply.
What the heck is going on?
Why? I've done the Metallica.
I thought that create a
rainbow effect in a sprinkler.
She thinks there's a government,
Huh?
Get out of our ground.
That allowed rule type of effect to
happen like prisons done and our moon
anymore.
Everywhere we look,
the visible that crumb is rainbow.
That cannot be natural.
It wasn't.
Well, you know when you're offended by
your beauty, you know, because I agree.
Baby checkout. So I agree. You know,
she lives in a good neighborhood.
When you can hear the sirens
in the background and the
bullet holes in the fence,
that's a nice touch.
But now it happened and now we
have the naked have got there.
What the Hell is going on?
What is oozing out of our,
we as a nation need to appreciate a
rainbow baby on a small level. Well,
for people who aren't watching the show,
so it's a sprinkler and it's
created a natural rainbow. Yeah.
And she's convinced that the government
has poisoned her water supply. Water,
the light colors. Yeah. She really,
she really broke through
that conspiracy though.
Can, does that leave you man? Huh?
I think to,
to quote Dr drew when he came on our show,
there is a huge problem with
it. Right? Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
I really are fucked.
That's pretty bad.
I feel like a fifth grader knows
that, you know, light through water.
Of course. Yeah. They teach
you that stuff. Clouds,
rain rainbows. Um, Tom,
they uh, do you have dates listed
on your site? I do, yeah, of course.
Um, let's, uh, let's go through
because this, we are doing, um,
well that's hardcore pornography.
We have, uh, not on my site.
No, no, no. Sometime around
so you can see her car. I, um,
I have, uh, he loves us. Porn. Thanks. Or
plugging my, uh, dates I'm going to be on,
this is not happening. March 16th.
Oh, a fun. That's great. Yeah.
This, this episode will drop in a few
weeks, so that's what I'm kind of, Oh,
so you might have just missed
Thomas Thomas Sacramento or
has this is not happening?
Malaria. You might see him. Well,
no, but it's just a, you know,
it's true.
Um,
when's your Sacramento?
It's march 15 through 17. He's at
the punchline. Maybe we can wait.
We can swap in episode. Do this, trade out
the other one. It doesn't matter. Right.
Try it. Try it out. Uh, then
he's going to, Holy Shit.
He's going to be in Thailand,
Vietnam, the Philippines. Jesus
Hong Kong, uh, later in Austin,
uh, at in Vegas at Brad. Garret's
like Tahoe. He's doing, uh, oh,
the Great Tacoma Club. We've both done
that and enjoyed that. It's a great room.
Spokane. Yep. I haven't done spoken. I've
done that. It's great. I've done lol.
Looks like you're doing an lol and
San Antonio, the La Jolla store.
Xannies in Chicago. You're doing
poly, you're going to go to
Paris. What's that? Have you
done that before? Actually,
I was in Paris in January at this. I,
I've, I've, I've played in Paris a lot.
Uh, but there's this theater
that I played in January and uh,
theater la over. Ah, oh.
And I'm booked back there October 15th
and I am going to fill my next hour
special
on October 15th.
So if there's any listeners who is
looking for a reason to go to Paris,
that you should come to my,
my,
our special dude. Now we're going
to be awesome. When you do Paris,
is it mostly ex pats? I mean it's
obviously, no, actually this,
when I was there in January,
it was,
it was mostly French
people watch spoke English.
So for my hour special,
I need to, uh, I need,
I need to get some more
English speaking people there,
but, and it's a phenomenal room.
I have a long history with Paris.
My first love of my adult life.
Uh,
I lived with a Parisian woman in
San Francisco for seven years,
not to Lee. We're still good friends. And
the very first time I went to Paris, uh,
some guys tried to rob me
and I was maced and really,
ah,
I've got some great stories.
I almost drowned in Thailand
on this French resort region.
Audiences get all the nuances of your,
like if they also like stories and they,
they really love theater. So
you'll like, you'll never,
you would never get a heckler
in pay in France, right.
Because the audience is just
conditioned to watch the show,
respect the performer on
stage. But uh, yeah. But uh,
you know, so I've got my, you know,
best stories traveling the world.
I haven't done a special in like
five years. Think so do this is,
it's all my anxiety. I cannot
believe you're going to do
it in Paris. Yeah. Wild.
What size venue is the,
is this theater?
It's holds three 50. Perfect.
Wonderful. When I was there in January,
I sold 240 tickets.
It's amazing.
I can sell more tickets in Paris than I
can in some clubs in the United States,
international comedian. Like you're
kind of a trailblazer that way.
So this is fantastic. It's great. And I,
thanks Christina. And I, uh,
you know, I, I love Paris.
I got great stories and
observations and a pair earth.
It's magic and eat a lot while
you're there, man. There's this,
I this last summer when I was there,
I discovered this a Archna googled best
patisserie is there's this place called
storer, s, t, O, h, r,
e, r. And uh, I followed them
on Instagram. It's the rate,
it's the number one rated patisserie in,
in Paris.
It's on this street
called roof mount to Goya.
And this street is,
it's got bread shops and
cheese shops and it's,
it's such an amazing food street,
but this patisserie places the
number one rated patisserie.
And when I go to Paris now I'll
take the metro straight there.
And like they, they, there's these
custard tarts with like raspberries and,
Oh man, I'm trying to be carpet on
top of it. Well that's the thing,
like when I was there, it's,
you know, I'm trying to be,
I left breadcrumbs all
over the city. The, these,
these baguettes are only like a
dollar 20 and these, you know,
you just just walk around nibbling
on bread and then you like,
I got my little patisserie pastries in
a box for done for whenever I'm ready to
sit down,
easily old me out out.
I would look like, uh,
what's that guy that Burt looks
like Gerard dip? I'll do, I'll,
there's a, there's a fee as a
is a food channel show. Yeah.
Where it's, I saw it when I was in
Europe, so I don't know if it's, if it's,
I thought it was the food channel,
but it's,
he's basically eating his way through
Europe. Dude, he's been, he no badness.
You see like a couple of years ago
there was a big story where he was on a
flight and he pissed in the,
I'm in the aisle aisle of the plane
and they're like, what the fuck man?
He's like, he's like, he's well over
three bills now. And they're like,
you know what kind of
behaviors? And he's like, well,
I drink several bottles of wine every day.
So that's a contributes to him gaining
that much weight. And also he's just like,
so of my behaviors,
just kind of erratic because I'm drunk
apparently in the aisle I'm drinking
constantly.
He like he out with like
a, with lock cores. He's,
he's got a, I heard about,
he's got a regiment of
drinking but he's the on this,
he's on this food show and this friend
who he travels with like explains to him
and he's just like stuffing his face with
everything and like everything is like
fried in duck fat course.
It's a so good,
he knows what's up dude.
But in moderation,
I mean they don't have to eat the whole
God damn a bowl at duck fat and you just
rally even a dog Turd with tastes
good Friday duck [inaudible] Gerard.
Oh Wow. When you go, that guy
doesn't want to pay his taxes.
When you pull it up over the belly button,
that's when you're committed to
the lifestyle. You know, you don't,
you don't sit below the gut
lining. Yeah. You're like, this is,
that's like when you're a kid and
you're drawing pictures of people. Yeah.
That's what that is. Andy Cigarette. Wow.
Interesting. Tom. I think we can
trace Burdis fat to that time.
We put dried [inaudible] picture up naked.
And then one of us was,
I don't remember,
but he, um, yeah, he's a where's the,
what was that movie James in a film
and it was nude in a film and we were
watching it and then we brought it up on
the show and we were like, God, that guy,
look at that belly. It looks like
Burt's belly. I think that's how this,
you're right. It kind of started
rolling like burping. It's this one.
So he's totally naked here,
but it's, it's the shit,
this is that movie where he's playing.
Um,
it's basically takes the story of the
whatever the head of the International
Monetary Fund was member of the, Oh
yeah. What was that guy's name? K.
They had some Strauss.
Kahn,
French dicks. Dominique Strauss
Kahn. Yeah. Oh Shit. Oh.
And he played him in a movie. Well,
he played a character that was like,
like him, but they mimic the
story, you know, and um, yeah,
that, that guy, that was god,
man, that is drink booze, man.
It's just hard, hard booth.
Um, Shit. Tom Rhodes.
Dot Net and that's r h o d e s.
Dot net slash tour.
Try it out and um, you know, have
all that information about, uh,
my pair of special on the website.
Great. Next few months. So exotic,
top be awesome and exotic.
I love it.
It's so cool. Let me just check
here. The future of Comedians,
that's what eventually we're all going
to be world tours. You know what?
I can do it now and there's, there's
great comedy fans all over the world.
You know, I could, I'm
just lazy and you know,
I'm gonna have two small people
to look after. Maybe I don't.
Maybe in a few years. Oh, you'll
be able to bring them with you.
Oh,
says the person
without a toddler. Right. Some people
do. They're very brave. But Tom and I,
it's just not in our constitution.
Like we've traveled with Ellis
twice now on an airplane.
I think I had more anxiety,
you know, and it's, it's just,
it's makes me so anxious and
talk to you having a home base,
having just leave him home for now.
Maybe when I had asked
you that I have a child,
maybe way maybe my world travels will.
Um,
well no, you can, you can tour with your
child. Definitely like, uh, Ali Wong,
our good friend brought her
daughter with her, you know,
the first couple of years of her life.
So I think it's a really up to the parent,
you know, it's like what you're
comfortable with. And I was trained them.
Allie loves it.
She know she has helped that she brings
like her mom I think or whenever.
But anyway, uh, yeah, you can just
start doing it early. The, the,
the mom with the young child
crying and everybody, you know,
looking when they look,
they look, they look, uh,
but if you do it early,
like you fly,
like when that kid's like
two or three months old,
I feel like that's the way to do that.
But we did not do that. No, no we did not.
We are chicken shits. All right.
We got your chicken one more time
please.
Thank you. That was really good.
Really good. Thank you for coming.
[inaudible] was really fun and
that's it. We'll see you guys. Uh,
sweet. I think fuck boy is one
of my favorite. Like, fuck boy,
you're fuck,
fuck boy.
It's the PC version of faggot.
I like, fuck boy. If I can't say Faggot,
I'm going to say, fuck boy. Fuck, fuck.
Sounds like you're already doing it.
Fuck boy, boy, faggot.
Fuck boy,
boy,
boy.
Boy.
Sounds like you're already doing it.
You're already doing like,
you're already doing it.
Good.