This episode of Your Mom's house is
brought to you by Saatva luxury mattress.
The only online mattress company that
provides free delivery set up and mattress
removal.
Well,
go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's too
gross.
Are you?
Check it out.
Try it out.
Draw La.
I got an added show. A new show. 'Em It's
a second show being added in new genes,
Oregon. Nah, I don't want your
gene, Oregon. The Mcdonald Theater.
October 4th the nine
30 show has been added.
It is on presale Wednesday,
June 27th beginning at
10:00 AM Pacific presale.
The password if you want to get
it is try it out. All one word,
all one word,
try it out and then if the on sale,
the general on sale will be Friday six
29 June 29th getting at 10:00 AM Pacific.
If you want to get those presale
tickets, use that code word. Try it out.
All one word in addition to
those stinky little jeans.
That's who is this by the way.
This is instrumental to by
BG Jovi, blah, blah, blah.
A few tickets left. There's a sold
out show and brass balls beach.
A couple of tickets left for
a brayer Thursday show. Um,
it's the Friday and brass balls,
beach,
Florida that had west Palm beach
that has tickets. Uh, let's see.
About 50 tickets left in Boise,
sat ball, Sacramento, Fresno,
Bakersfield, those are all on sale.
Fort Myers, Florida in November.
Good one Jack me off hill, Florida.
His second show was added in horror.
Lando. They, the first
one is sold out Augusta,
Montclair and fill her up.
Delphia for people have been
asking about other cities.
They will all be announced soon
as part of a huge nationwide,
perhaps some international dates.
Um,
those will all happen in 2019 but that's
going to be probably pretty close to it
for me for the year. Oh, I'm
sorry. Pachanga Temecula.
That's also November 30th and
that went on sale. Jean, sorry.
Great.
Uh,
I to have a presale to a now fill her up.
Delphia I am coming to you.
December 7th.
Presale tickets go on sale. June
27th, 10:00 AM standard time.
When are you going? It's a December 7th.
It's the day before I do judo or kitties.
So the Promo code for that
Presale is going to be mushy.
M U. S. H. Y. Uh, so
by the time this drops,
you guys can get your presale
tickets, you pre sale. Oh.
And then I added a second show and Jus
Dork titties a 10 30 show mercy at the
Gramercy theater.
Those did have presale this week,
but the general on sale is going on now.
That's for December 8th,
the very next night.
So get those tickets at
Christina p online also.
1124.
It's November 24th
Thanksgiving weekend. Yep. Uh,
if you're sick,
your family,
if you like your family and wanted to
bring them to the best time to go out to a
show, I think it is. It's a Saturday.
You guys are sick and tired of being
in the house. Come see me, man. Diego,
San Diego,
California at the House
of bleach and that's it.
And I chew, we'll be announcing some kind
of thing in 2019 some type of a tour.
We're working it out now. Right?
And that's it for now guys.
Then do the,
uh,
I did a set at the Grammercy one time
with a Dave Chappelle and Chris Rock. Oh,
well, no big deal. So who, I don't,
I've never heard of these small time
comedians. All right, Jean Jean Jean,
Jeez.
Much fun. We have a couple of
great guests joining us today.
That'll be be here in a little
while. We have a lot to go over. Um,
you ready to get down with this? Right?
Try it out, man. Let's try it out.
Here's a deal, man. Deal, man. Oh, we got
to get another development with that Gal.
I can't wait to talk to
you about hitting me.
I swear it's how can I give any more?
No, it's just one of those things, man.
Here we go.
Yeah.
Benny long naked.
When another Munoz and Anita Lane in it.
Lotion one neck like this.
Yeah.
Don't bring it in one above it.
Well,
go to your mom's house.
Oh my goodness. I don't know what the
fuck's going on with this guy. Um,
real quick just to,
before I forget the, um,
twitch,
just in case you that you're interested,
we're doing this show two hours before.
Uh,
it drops on Youtube,
so youtube the show drops 11:00
PM Pacific Tuesday evenings.
That's when it comes out on Youtube,
on twitch is coming out at
9:00 PM and as an added bonus,
blue band is there. Jean,
you were there last week.
I'm going to try to jump on next week. I
did. I got to talk to mommy for a minute.
What's your, uh, handle? I think
it's queen jeans. Queen genes one.
I'm Dj Dad Mouth One. So I'll be there
in a week. I'm surprised nobody took
that. It's twitch.tv/your mom's
house podcast. It's cool. I, I,
you know what, I'm very not cool. Yeah.
And I went on there and I'm like, oh,
what a great way for fans of the show
to kind of chat it up, chat and, and,
and go along with what's happening live.
It's kind of weird,
but I don't know what this kid, this
kid does have a really long neck. Danny,
long neck and Anita Lane in a lotion.
One neck like this.
Yeah.
Now do you see, I do think it's
really long or that it's an angle.
It's really long.
I was going to ask,
do you think that the length has anything
to do with his voice being Danny Lung,
neck in, in, in, in their vocal
cord stretched out? Yeah. He's got,
is he not? He's not American,
right? What is it? He's
definitely American. Oh really?
I thought he sounded like New Zealand,
New Zealand. Oh No, no, no, no.
Maybe in US mom's truck. Oh my God. The
baby just kicked right. You have a baby.
Oh my God. I was so painful. Shit, man.
There's a person there and forget.
So ladies,
if you're known to newness, they
knew this comment, comment and uh,
you know, I know when it is, am I
in marks around what is happening?
Long neck one lions, Dram
your lists. You know what,
I can't help but think when
this happens. I mean, obviously,
you know he's an odd bird.
Yeah, it's an ostrich.
But what's great about the Internet is
that he's putting out a call out there
for someone to rub lotion on
his long ass neck. Yeah. It's a,
it's an odd thing to do. He sounds
weird. He looks different. Um,
someone's going to do it.
Someone's going to be like,
I'd love to rub lotion on your neck.
Is it about us being all connected?
It's someone is watching this being like,
I want to rub lotion on their kids.
That's the one unifying
element to the internet.
The rest is divisive and hate
and you know, horrible comments.
And then there's times like this where
some freak can get somebody to rub lotion.
That's true. Yeah. Do you think the
vocal fry is a result of the length?
I don't know.
I don't know if he is,
I'm making it so that it sounds
like that or if it's really,
um, just something that's,
you know what I mean?
I don't know if it's a big forced
thing. It's forced. That's an aspect.
This vocal fry shit. I know,
but guys don't usually do this.
Is it usually a a girl, a teenage girl
thing or a younger girl? Yeah. Yeah.
Dad. No, I don't know.
Megan and I have been together
for nearly three years.
She's a beautiful go who I'm very much
in love with and I have a lot in common
with. I can't wait to get
home and jump in the pool.
It sounds like he's laying
down when he speaks, right? No,
it does nick down.
Notice the dual desk.
He have vocal fry
and also again an accent and affect the
dual dis as he's talking like gangster.
If y'all got a Laney no
new on the side of my neck,
you know, tell him to hit me up. Got Up,
got it on nick. Manage. But it,
now this does have the elements
of a great, your mom's house.
I'll tell you what's,
what's striking me though,
I think I know what you're going to say,
but I do think what I'm really enjoying
about a damn long neck or Danny long
neck, whatever his name is,
Danny long there that um,
he's at least feigning some
sort of confidence. You know,
it's very easy to be down about
yourself if you have a 26 inch neck.
Yeah. But he's like, you
know what? I'm owning it.
I'm going to go with the nickname always.
You know,
you always have to accentuate your flaws.
Yeah.
Rather than try to hide them because
everyone sees it and that's really success
level when they call me big pop,
you know what I mean?
It's like saying mushy perps you know,
my tits aren't getting any smaller. Yup.
But we just got to address the fact that
they're getting more and more enormous
everyday. Big Daddy Stag Dick. Okay.
Put it out there.
It's one of your sad traits.
Really bummed about having
a big old stinky deck. Yeah.
Everyone used to point at
it and laugh like fun of me.
Yeah. I get caught on things and people
are like, oh, you got a big Dick.
And I was like, no, I talk about it.
Was that hard for you to
change after football practice?
Everybody hated changing after football.
I went to a,
a weird school with regard to that.
What do you mean? Well, I remember,
I mean it's weird because you should
be a little more comfortable with it,
but when I went to school, I'm an
underclass. I'm a freshman high school.
The upperclassmen were changing what
towels around their waist and and like
wearing boxers into the showers,
not Jesus.
So you don't want to break the mold of
what the upperclassmen are doing because
then you're like being extra
weird, you know, queer.
But it was weird that they
were doing that. It is weird,
especially because they're upperclassmen,
they're more developed.
I think a big part of it was
that it was a very small school.
I think if it were a normal size, high
school go, you know, or a big high school,
I don't think that ever
would have happened.
I've always felt that showering at school
was just so cruel and I know it's hard
on a teenager and adolescent.
Your body is just for Octa and then they
want you to get naked in the middle of
the day and then when I have practice
at the end of the day and then just go
home dirty, can't you do that like in
a jam or something? Yeah, I don't know.
Football you get really funky. It's
tight stuff. You know a helmet,
you're sweating and it's Florida.
What time of day were you practicing?
I was going to say rehearsing three
30 to five 30 and just fucking go home
and shower. Why do you have to
shower your disaster after football?
Just such a mess.
Amelie.
When one kid walked around flaunting
his deck and he had a big old,
yeah, he's black and he
had a big Dick and he also,
you know what he's looking for the dudes.
Oh, he was looking for the dude's. Yeah,
he was looking for Dee Dee found any
dudes in high school in high school,
but I think outside of high school he
definitely met some dudes. It's so crazy.
Yeah. Guys are such animal.
He liked showing it, you know.
But I feel like I would too if
I had a big old begging me too.
I didn't have a deck like that.
Oh who does vary?
My Dick would hide and especially
when I was active. Yeah.
Brought it would like invert, it
would like grow into me, but that's,
I think it's not like natural cause
you're, your body's protecting your,
you're tweaking berries natural.
If you have a little Dick.
I never showered after, well first of
all I didn't really do PE as a kid.
I would like fake run the I do,
I do like a 15 minute mile.
So I would never really break a sweat
because I was golf and then that meant
that my makeup will get all messed up.
So I was just kind of fake ticket sizes.
So traumatic for boys mean he's still
thinking about those decks, Huh? No,
I'm thinking about like the what,
how traumatic. It's like titty size,
but tiddy size is traumatic for us
girls. Yeah, that's true. I can see that.
I almost feel like Dick size and periods
are traumatic, different, you know,
but then you get your period and like
you want to hide that kind of from the
other girls who maybe they
don't have. There's really,
yeah, I didn't like it. Yeah.
Cause then it's,
that's embarrassing.
You could bleed all over your
shorts or something at school,
like the first time you get it.
That was my big fear is that I get my
period at school and like I just bleed
everywhere. I mean it didn't, didn't go
down that way, thankfully. God. But um,
yeah, but you guys are always
into your big Dick Sizes.
I feel like it's a big deal with
guys deal. It's a big deal. Can they,
I mean they have the science yet to
make people's Dick's bigger. They do,
but it's not, um, it's not
like breast implants. Yeah,
you figure it.
See that's the thing is that usually do,
and here's the thing about a
breast implant that doesn't,
let's say isn't perfect. You're like,
ah, it's still a tit or whatever,
a dick implant, or like, you know,
a fake Dick that makes you make it bigger,
could affect bodily functions.
It could affect definitely performance.
It could affect sensation.
Like it's totally not worth it to do that.
I feel like they could just put like
a mold dick over your tiny deck.
Like you've got a small like can we
just put like an implant deck over your
regular Dick?
I don't think they do it like that.
Like I would never sign up for
any type of surgery on my Dick.
That wasn't the mandatory,
well of course. I mean, yeah,
I mean like I have a normal sized Dick,
but I'm saying if it were,
even if it were like micro penis,
I still would be like, no, no, no.
I agree.
That's so,
but here's the thing is that men have
invented like vaginal rejuvenation and
boob jobs and cellulite sucking out.
You'd think that the guys would start
inventing penile growth stuff. Like,
I don't know if they can do bro. I
know they do employee, they do peanut,
well they do male, female to
male surgeries. They do. Yeah,
they do an enlargement surgery. It
exists. Right, right. But not like a big,
it's not good. I don't think it's, I mean
I've seen some shows on it. It's like,
I dunno, it doesn't seem like it's, if
it were a really effective and well done,
you'd hear guys be doing it well.
Cause I've seen those penises that like a,
when a woman transition, they basically
grow the clit out through stop point.
So you just have an enlarged and enlarged
clitoris or whatever and it's not,
it doesn't look like a big all
painter. I don't know. Dude.
So crazy between your legs.
That's basically what I would, I would
totally get badge rejuvenation now.
Snatch tighter just cause
it gets blasted with kids.
Like I'm gonna have my second baby and
this kid's already big. They're like,
it's going to be at least eight pounds.
I think the doctor takes it fucking
blast my badge for a test drive.
That's how they know if it's done right,
I'm going to have to have intercourse
with you right now. Check your oil
and you wake up. You're like, what
happened? He's like, feels good.
And it was a great time. Are you in the
room too? And he's like, this is great.
You're gonna love it as a
field. Oh really? Nice. Cool.
But I have to because it's all
blasted. It's all fucked up. Yeah.
No. What disaster down
there. And I don't think so.
Can be even bigger disaster after the
second boy. You think so, dude? Yes.
It's all, it's all trashed.
This vessel is trashed.
I need to get my eight tits done.
I could get my badge. Don, come on.
My tits are all fucked
up now they're below my
got big nat Geo titties. When I take
my bra off, they just hang to my belly.
I look like I'm ever seen
like those gorillas and the
zoo that I've given birth.
You're, you're kind of going
overboard now. Naked, pregnant.
I'm saying I take my bra and it
looks like Coco the gorilla. I mean,
she's just, it's been alive forever. I'm
surprised she lived this long, long time.
But anyway,
I have gorilla tits and then this belly,
it's fucking disastrous. Yeah.
Cocoa knew sign language.
How Rad was that?
Raised a bunch of kittens.
Coco is a little kid.
We saw a fucking hummingbird getting fit.
Maybe humming birds nest right
outside our kitchen window.
It's the most exciting fucking thing
in the world. Another 10 years.
I would weep at that site.
I think.
I know. I feel like it's really
special, isn't it? It is.
It's hard to be cynical
about baby hummingbirds being
fed by their mommy. I know.
It's so fucking cute. I got my little
feet are out there so little the baby.
I know.
Tiny little farm.
I get so excited when I have a customer
at my hummingbird feeder. I just love it.
I can't believe they're using it.
You know,
here you are here. Speaking of Moms, check
this out. So this girl set up her mom.
Okay. By just having an aggressive
conversation on the phone, like God,
like the mom is sitting there and she
set up a camera and then she's talking
like someone's talking shit to
her, you know, so that's the Mama.
Hello.
Do you could pull up,
I got you to address already.
Oh, I seen this. She's like,
what is the grandma says [inaudible]
has comedy that Sousa Trump
you can put up right now.
I'm here.
That's such a mom move. Right?
That's, that's your uh, yeah.
Your inner baby bird.
I know. Check this out.
Yeah,
she got her good.
I mean that mom went from zero to 60 fast.
Somebody calls our boy and says they want
to talk some shit. We talked some shit.
Yeah, call me. Call me
right now, mother fucker.
Gary and consulate yesterday.
I have some affairs in Hungary. Still a
little bit cause my mother's death, blah,
blah blah. And you have to call
to make an appointment, right?
They don't just take fucking walkups.
Of course, I called a week ago and,
uh, the Hungarian person
answers and goes, ah,
VR eating lunch, call back later,
click and doesn't even say goodbye.
It's so crazy basic.
Not really.
Cause that's how shitty my tribe is.
And I have the phone and to Tommy,
I go this fucking bitch. I mean,
why did you answer the phone then?
If you're not going to take my
call, let it go to voicemail, Bro.
You're eating your lunch. I respect
that. But then to just be like,
we already think, launch a call
back later, he can hang up.
That's going to hear what you have
to say. No, not nothing, 100%.
Exactly how I imagined the
Hungarian consulate to behave.
You have the unfriendly,
it's my culture and I listen. Uh, we
have many wonderful things about Hungary.
We were once a great empire,
culturally, a lot of cool shit.
But you know, my shrink is trying to
convince me. She's like, you know, not,
not everybody. And not every
Hungarian is like this. I go, yeah,
but as a culture were pretty rough.
It's a rough,
I would say it's accurate and there's,
there are nice people. That's true there.
I mean I have wonderful people
that I then, by the way,
you thought that that tracksuit girl was
one of your native cause like we were.
We were. And so we find it. So anyway, the
point is two months they're booked out.
She has one appointment I can have
in two months, which was yesterday.
Tommy and I rolled down there and I'm
sitting there and as blonde chick roles in
wearing track pants and the track zip
up and I was like, that's what's up.
That's my girl right there.
She's totally one of my tribe.
I of course do, you know, rude
is shit like not very helpful.
Sit Down with Uva and it's kind of
not.
And we'll have a video that
plays the passport photos. Yeah.
That shows you how to go about entering
to get your passport information.
So fucking weird family enter.
And in the video the family sits show,
they show you the family entering,
sitting across from the
Hungarian consulate,
we employee and video and then uh,
getting their photos taken. And
then fingerprints, you know,
they show a guy in a cast,
like his arm's in a sling
and the cast hang walks in.
He never even semis smiles.
He walked with a measurable kind of face
children looks like look like they fear
him like they stand back from him and
then when they're like take a photo and it
shows him going just
a grimace on his face.
That's what it would be
like when you come to there.
It's an off video.
Yeah,
just misery thing.
Optimistic. How's that now?
Most people would like even with
just show a family walk in, hey whoa,
it's so weird that they would cast a
guy with an arm cast and then two of his
fingers and a miserable look on his face.
Miserable. Yet. It's so funny. Very weird.
But it makes me dread even like I was
fucking dreading having to go there and
deal with this shit. Cause you know
the Hungarian government is like not,
they're not. It's not actually what
government is easy. That's true.
Having to do us stuff sucks.
But man, you can't even smile.
Like they can't even feign being
human. You know what I'm saying? Yeah.
So I'm glad that shit over with.
This is like the last thing I have
to deal with from my mother's death.
Nobody tells you when somebody dies.
It's just paperwork for fucking
two or three years, man.
It's just a legal nightmare.
So if you can get your affairs
in order and get a will in place,
a living trust before you died and make
it easier on your kids and your family
do do it because it is a such a
bomber if you don't have any of that.
Um, so anyways, you got a new show.
Well here's the thing,
I talked about it last week and I've done
a lot of messages. People are into it.
So this is a spoiler alert.
Spoiler alert,
the staircase,
spoiler alert,
it's 13 episodes,
so you might be behind and if
you don't want to hear this,
I'm giving you fair warning.
Scroll ahead a few minutes.
So that being said, here we go. I
have been obsessed with this thing.
Um, they recently added three new
episodes. So I guess this thing came out.
I missed it when it came out.
Originally it is an old ass show.
Well it's a documentary series.
How long ago did,
they probably originally aired it, I
don't know, at least a few years ago.
And then they updated it with
three new episodes, but it was,
the whole thing was new to me.
So I'm,
I've been tracking through 13 hours and
I even enjoy it when I wake up and I was
waiting for the twist, the
turn, you know, and uh, again,
if you haven't seen it yet or you want
to see it or you're halfway through it,
I'm going to give it to you right now.
Um, but if you're not, I'll tell you this.
The,
the fucking show gives you,
I would say eight episodes or more
where you're like, dude, this is,
where's this going to?
How is this going to turn in any way?
And then it's the biggest fucking turn
that you don't expect because there was
corrupt officials within the system,
um,
who withheld in perjured themselves
on the stand banana people in the SBI,
which is like the State
Bureau of Investigation.
I didn't even know there was an SBI.
I've never,
I don't know if every state has it,
but they have it in North
Carolina and you know,
it was a big, big murder case
there. So they send in the,
their officials and their experts to,
you know,
test everything and
uh, you know, uh, they,
they didn't do a DNA analysis.
They had a guy go on the stand and make
claims that they turned out that other
experts said you could never make.
And this dude just blatantly lied.
He just lied on the stand to
convict the guy who, you know,
the whole time you're watching
this thing and you're like,
there's no way this guy
has not done this crime,
but they end up placing if,
if he's getting a fair trial,
you could argue that there would be
reasonable doubt in some way and therefore
that's what you're, you're,
that's what you're going for
as a defense. You want to,
is there a reasonable doubt? Well,
they didn't give him a fair shot at it.
And what ends up happening is because
of the corrupt government people,
this guy actually a gets a new trial and
then has to decide whether to go for a
plea or take it to trial,
some terrible decision.
It's a horrible choice to have
to make. And actually, you know,
things became more favorable
to him, um, for the new trial,
like and looked like even more evidence
would be withheld because of some of
these circumstances and the time
had gone by and I'm like, baby,
this search warrant wasn't valid.
Maybe they shouldn't allow that.
So all these things would have actually
led to a more favorable case for him.
But then he's like, you know,
at this point he's like 71
and he's like, you know,
I've already been to prison for eight
years. It's been great. It takes on you.
And he has one kid who was like, go
to trial, fucking vindicate yourself.
The other kids like, are you out of your
fucking mind? Like this is too crazy.
Take the plea. You don't go back to
prison. Yeah, it's on your record.
But you know, you only have this much
time left and it's been horrible.
Let's just end it. So he ends up
taking a plea and he does take place.
So I woke up,
I wake up to eat snacks occasionally and
watch a minute of your show and he was
at home with his family, uh, drinking
champagne and celebrating and listen that.
And they're all just like, yeah, Daddy, we
know you're not guilty daddy. It's like,
how do you,
how do you believe your
parent who's clearly guilty?
I don't want to believe it. I mean,
look at, you can believe that he didn't,
I know there's people obviously that
believed that he didn't cause people would
think, oh, Jeren isn't, it's,
I know. It's so crazy. Yes.
So many similar behaviors to him,
especially in the early days.
See this, they actually,
what's incredible is the,
the actual just accomplishment
of filming this documentary,
they filmed it for 16 years.
That's amazing. Um, so it's,
it's an amazing thing to,
you know,
a product to even come up with like
what a project this is. But you know,
you see him in those early
days when she's, you know,
freshly dead and he's
smoking his pipe. Look. Yup.
But I loved her so much. I
miss her. And you're like,
there's just little things that
are quirks. What I learned also,
or what I came to think over time is
that it is a bit unfair in a way too,
man. He goes sympathizing with
the murderers. We'll know.
It's like you try to be objective.
You try to watch these things and go like,
it's a little unfair in a way to to judge
people's behavior under stress and be
like, that's the only indicator.
I mean I feel that way,
but I'm saying if you're somebody
you go, oh, he's acting like this.
You shouldn't act like that.
That's not a hundred percent accurate.
People process stress different. Yeah. No,
it's true. People have odd
reactions to death. They do. You,
you're in shock for a long time
when somebody dies and who knows.
But I will say that the words I've many
times I've watched her show when he's
talking and it's a lot of horse
shit he does. He does. Spin yarns.
He is full of Shit. And you know what he
never fucking says, right? I never did it.
I would never kill my life.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Well,
every time I'm eating a sandwich and
watching watch like eight minutes of it,
13 hour documentary. But if, if, if
someone had accused me of killing you,
there's only one fucking thing to say. I
love my husband. He's my pride and joy.
I would fucking kill my husband.
It's still saying that you guys
were even saying, I'm gonna kill me.
I love my husband. What would you say?
You'd be like, I'm glad she's gone.
Time to get dead. Time to date.
Can we look at your Netflix queue
and I want to make it,
I just think that it's,
to me that nine one one call reads so
false. I think this is my interpreter.
That's a, that is a totally,
it's like bad acting.
You could tell when you try to
act with someone and you're like,
you're not good at pretending to do this.
And it reads,
it reads like her.
I didn't hear it when I was laying
trying to sleep the other night.
And you played that and then I won.
I had panic in my heart for him.
You didn't can't tell, but I don't
listen to enough. Nine one one.
Oh, I thought it was horrifically
bad acting. I'm not an expert.
The other thing or the crime
scene photos and you're like,
I'm really supposed to think that
this is a fall. Like from the stairs.
I Dunno.
Is it possible they have experts testify
that it's possible that they see it as
how much blood is that? There's an
incredible amount of slough fall,
fall down the stairs.
I fall down the stairs.
I mean it's like lacerations to the head,
blood everywhere and she fell.
Oh,
can we please just pull up your Netflix
queue so the audience can see what I see
when I open Netflix and I have to click
on to my profile and thank God we have
separate profiles. I used to annoy me
about Netflix, but I'm like, look at this.
Fucking sociopathic. Here it
is. It's all psycho. Okay.
Staircase, Vietnam war inside
the mind of a serial killer.
Irish mob. American vandal.
Very funny. Uh, seven. Okay.
You're just rewatching that for fun.
I'm assuming. I haven't seen that.
Another fun rewatch. These are
continuing. Well that's cause I a burger.
Of course. Hitler circle
of evil. Another fun alley.
Of course Dexter,
uh,
making a murderer.
Okay.
They're American crime.
The traffickers.
El Chapo outlaw bikers, queen of
the south. It was either drugs,
war or murder.
These are yours.
This is survivor's
guide to prison. I mean,
okay. The conspiracy, the
seven five, that's also
go psycho killer. That's a good movie
and a lot of murder there. Okay.
Now let's pull up Christina's profiles.
It's not gay.
It's just called what normal people
like this is a healthier spread.
The Ventress I would say,
cause you're strictly in one cat,
like three categories.
Murder, war and drug lord,
Shit and Mafia.
That's all you fucking
psycho shit. Yeah, it's
definitely, yeah, that's different.
Okay. Here we go. Here's yours.
Cooking shows. Let's see. Here we go.
Good place.
Interior design. Yeah, like that.
Set it up. Queer eye cooking.
Here's wasn't staircase telling you to
watch it. I was at telling me here's your,
continue watching, watching popular.
I know Rita. I love that show.
It's think of life. Love it. Great.
But it's baking show 40 year
old virgin friends. Yeah,
so light trending. This is trending
though. Within your algorithm.
That's how trending works based on
the shit you like. Just trending.
It's trending within your preferences.
That's so funny. I did not know.
So you have parts of known
the ranch lust stories. Okay.
New Girl. Ibiza parks and rec.
Okay, so let's see what it was.
All dark and then it's suggesting
British TV shows where you critically
acclaimed irreverent TV shows
the office we'd the stuff,
normal people, notional TVC mines is
crime TV shows. You're says emotional TV.
Sensate Riverdale, Grey's anatomy.
Mad Men. I like international.
I'm into the Korean soap operas.
Yours has a bunch of Korean stuff and
I watched a few Spanish things and it
gives me all Spanish
suggestions all the time.
You make the mistake of clicking on
one foreign thing and then it's like,
do you like all foreign shit? It's like
want to see a bunch of Mexican stand up?
And I'm like, no. That's the thing.
If you make the mistake of
clicking on like one dumb show,
the Netflix forever is like,
do you like this other dumb
shit I saw that you liked?
It gives you this category.
Quirky TV shows featuring a
strong female lead look at that.
But I don't like any, I wouldn't watch
any of these. I'm not interested in,
you know, it's just interesting that
they have it broken down to that door.
They do working with a strong female lead.
Oh they do.
And I watched the 40 year old virgin
again. That's, I like that great movie.
We're into this Billy Bob Thornton
show Goliath. That's great. Amazon,
is it Amazon prime? Who's this here?
John David Letterman's new show.
Howard stern was on there, so I
watched that. I, Jerry Seinfeld did it.
Obama.
Tina Fey docu series.
I'm just trying to let you know that
like I have kind of a wider array of
interests. No, your shit's gay. I
get it and know what you're saying.
That's what you're saying.
Shit's all gay fucked up and shit.
My Shit's gay. I'm saying that I have
other than three primary interest.
Here's more my speed. Okay.
Speed. Yeah. We know what your
speed is. Psycho speed. No,
it's not psycho speed.
A little more respect for me.
[inaudible]
try it out metal. I love it. Um,
try it out metal by Julian. Julian.
Yup. Good name. There you go.
Not a lot of d bags named
Julian in the world.
Okay.
To sell his rate.
The never ending battle of what
our dear friend the try it out.
Guy is saying. Okay. Oh Man, no man,
no, we never know. He's going to
say homie out homie on out. Oh,
I bring to you
the home here now homie out.
So we'll down homie on out.
Halloumi out hold me out version of
a shirt where this is real inside.
It's, it's amazingly
sketched by Chris. Gosh.
Um, and he, he sent me his
version, which I have no love.
Give you his um, this is such,
um, I love the shirt so much.
It's disturbing. It's definitely,
it's definitely, you know,
Christopher and his Instagram.
See M c.
A. G. L. E. E. S. E. M. A. C. H. Lee.
Thank you Christopher. Uh,
love the sketch. Love the
shirt. It's on. Presale now.
Flipped it to black because people just
like Blackmore. I like black shirts. Yeah,
but it's absolutely hilarious concept. I
came aware of white shirt. I feel like,
excuse me, I get the armpits yellowed, but
within like a week, all me, I know. Yeah,
I know. I don't. And then like
the kids spill some shit on me,
so things look better on white too.
But people just don't like white shirts
as much. Fucking nerds, ma'am. Okay.
White shirts are for fucking nerds
and Europeans. Eastern Europeans.
Um, Yup. And Oh, tomorrow
the don't forget it's,
I'm on hot ones. Um, that
should be fun. Sean Evans.
Fantastic. Thank you sir. Um, how
hot was it? Be Honest. I know.
Everyone wants to ask you that. How
hot we're the wings. They got hot,
they got hot. So how does it start?
It starts like super, like, oh yeah.
Like where you're like,
that's not spicy flavor. Yeah,
yeah. You go, that's nothing.
And then it goes a little bit more
and you're like, oh, maybe this is,
it's your fear of it that's going to be,
and then I think,
I think actually they get the
hottest one is like number eight.
They say it's 10 but it's really
like you get to 10 I did all of them.
Oh yeah. I cried at one
point. Did you drink milk?
Yeah, we got, we got chocolate,
soy milk or chocolate.
I don't like regular milk is disgusting
and terrible that drink milk are
disgusting. People discuss.
If you're not a baby,
there's no point drinking if you're
an adult and drinking whole milk. Yes,
you're a total fucking pedophile
without question. You're disgusting.
You're a bad person.
Absolutely.
Don't you have a friend that's
drinking cups of whole milk? Oh my God.
Ordering it in restaurants.
Does it come warm to having this?
And he's like, he's like, oh,
and do me a solid Darlin go ahead and
bring me a glass of milk. And she's like,
I'm sorry, what gross does your
parole officer know you're here? Yeah,
I'll give him a heads up when she's like,
okay.
And so she brings it nice and warm.
Temp to room temperature. Right.
So it's all fucking warm. Like it just
came out of the cows tits. I Dunno.
It just seems drank a glass of
milk. It's like, ah, it's just flat.
Did you do that in private?
Do it in private or don't do it at all.
It just looks like it's a glass of mucus.
It's just fucking disgusting.
It's gross. I mean there's no reason
for you to be drinking that as an adult.
You're a grown adult. You're not a baby.
You don't need milk anymore. I agree.
Can I use to hate it as a kid?
Even like give it to you as your lunch.
It was like part of the lunch
program or whatever and he'd be like,
it smells because it would come in like,
you know,
a plastic container with all the little
milk cartons and it would just smell
because it had been sitting around
and the, and the spare milky deal.
Rose fucking nasty.
Let's put on something nice.
Okay.
Hi.
Oh Shit.
Yeah.
Do that also reminds me of somewhere?
Yes.
Yeah.
Oh yeah.
They had the same dentist. I didn't
really have this same kind of, well,
she's got equipment. You see she's
got the Janet Jackson headphones.
Do you see that shit? Well, she, yeah,
I mean she's obviously a little more
advanced. How did she get that art?
She's like, I have it lubricated
my instrument. I don't know.
I wish the guy would have
had a huge coffee at the end.
You'll see like black tar come
up. Yeah. You don't have no cough.
He knows what he's doing. Practicing
that long shift for days. Ah,
man is the rectum I've done night.
Not How do you get that crazy?
Like what happens where you just
don't give a fuck anymore, Tom,
how do I get there? That's
what I'm saying. I don't know.
Alcohol and then you'd just booze.
Yeah.
You really got to go hard daily. You
never fuck around. You never skip days.
Always drinking. Never. Not
Drinking. Now we got this message.
I haven't even read it yet, but it
says, um, dear mommy is an epidemic,
has been brought to my attention. Started
a few months ago when I was showing up.
Buddy. Tom's special
disgraceful. This buddy
of mine had the subtitles
on early into the special.
I suggested to turn them off. He said, no.
He watches everything with subtitles
on which is true and that was that 10
minutes or so go by.
I began to notice that he was laughing
at punch lines before they were being
said no. I paused a special on
laid down the law. He didn't.
He didn't and still doesn't agree with
me that subtitles spoiled, joke's ruined.
The element of surprise and timing and
overall just distract from the actor
performance.
We don't watch specials together anymore
and it's my mission to find out what
kind of person people are and
quizzed them on this. Get this.
A lot of people watch specials with
subtitles on. It drives me nuts.
I like these clowns are
just being pretentious.
They are ruining the experience
for themselves and also
watering down your guys'
comedy. My best denial analogy is it would
be like reading the last sentence of a
chapter before the last page
of the chapter as Comedians,
I would like your input on this matter.
Am I overreacting or these people?
Monsters,
grass casino on your machines within.
Thanks for booking Boise. Tom.
Look forward to seeing you perform.
Notice you two haven't had any
play on words for Boise yet.
Thanks for all the laughs Trevor.
Good point. Trevor Boise,
why is he Poissy noisy,
noisy,
noisy.
I Dunno. Boys, boys,
boys, boys and holes. Ease
boys inside me. Yes. I'm like that
kind of work on this, right? Well sir,
I think here's, here's the problem titles.
If you don't have a hearing problem.
Well here's the problem with the subtitles
is that they're not always accurate.
They're not always accurate.
But he's also right that with,
with regard to especially jokes,
right?
Words will appear before their
set of course. And so that,
and also you're missing out on comedic
timing, facial expressions. Uh,
maybe cause we work on these
punchlines, right? For instance, uh,
you just do a gesture to go with a
word and now the laugh is even bigger.
So you are fucking with what we do.
Maybe the people that are doing this
that don't need to have the subtitles.
Maybe it's a little bit of anxiety.
Interesting.
They don't like the element of surprise.
They they want, like he said, you know,
I want to read the,
the end of the thing first because I know
some types of anxiety about it. Well,
because people have tons of
anxiety. Well yeah, the yellow,
the key to good comedies, the element
of surprise. So either you're right,
maybe it's a control freak thing and this
guy doesn't want to have a good time.
In which case I would say give your
friend a drink, have a fucking beer.
Like chill the fuck out.
I don't know why.
I want to know why he wants to come
on if he's not having trouble hearing.
That's true. I don't understand
it personally. He wants that.
But it takes the fun out of the sand up.
Maybe he feels like it's a little
more insight or something, you know,
he's like a little more ahead. He's a
little ahead of it. But I'm telling you,
because I've seen how they
subtitle things. It's not
always accurate. The words,
uh, and the wording is so crucial to a
joke. Why don't you say Tom? Yeah. We,
we think about words. And how many words
and word placement. It's very crucial.
So I don't, I don't see why anybody
would want to spoil the fun.
I agree. I, you know, I'm watching
that show Rita, and it's in Denmark.
Well, language they speak. Is it Danish?
I think so. It's not American. So anyway,
uh, and I know they're fucking
subtitling it incorrectly. It bothers me.
I wish I knew about subtitling from
another language they fucking fuck up.
But even in this, in our own
language, they fuck it up. I'm sure
one thing that's so true,
it's like so inappropriate now,
but in the Narcos,
which is filmed or it takes place at
the previous seasons where Columbia,
I think they're going to
Mexico for the new season.
Those guys are constantly,
constantly saying, Maricka always.
Yeah. Mighty guys like a short,
shortened version of it. Um,
so it might've Gone Liz,
the full word,
mighty guys like fag and they say it all
the time and it's in this uptight all
the time. This show, it feels
like if it was an English,
that's just not acceptable to say.
Now Tom has honor percent.
It's 100% how everybody that I've ever
grown up with in South America speaks.
They're constantly calling you.
I mean,
more so than I ever experienced
growing up in English. They're much,
much,
much worse at that.
Well, this whole Social Justice
Warrior Horse Shit, you know,
it's a very wonderful American thing
that we're doing culturally now.
Policing everybody for every little
fucking thing they say that's remotely
offensive to them.
Listen, same in Hungarian.
Do you think they've stopped saying faggot
or whatever because a five people are
upset by it or whatever. I mean,
come on, you're going to stop.
You know what I mean?
It's just, it's silly.
You're not going to police the world
into making the perfect world exist to
everyone gets their needs
and their feelings or was
going to be nice knowledge.
Yeah, guys, this is a safe space.
That's my favorite. It's a safe space.
There's no fucking such
thing as a safe space. Okay?
You're always under threat of
being your feelings misunderstood.
Are you not communicating clearly?
This fucking generation is,
fuck you guys are all fucked and you're
creating this puritanical dog shit place
is. You never going to
sterilize the world guys.
It's never going to fucking
work out for you so well.
The world is a fucked up
place. I know that. Everyone's
nice. No one did. I don't.
You want to prepare your kids for that
inevitability that there are fucking
dickheads out there. Either fucks
racist people. Avoid that guy.
Don't talk to someone like that.
You walk away from them.
The best thing the preschool teacher
ever said to us was that he, she says,
your son is a great kid. Nice kid,
doesn't play with everybody. And I said,
that's right. That's how I fucking
raised him. He's an elitist when you did,
but I did say to play, but he plays with
some people he doesn't play with good.
Why should he play with everybody?
Kids he doesn't play with or just Tan.
They're not what you think.
Have a little bit of fun,
more Melanin in their skin.
No, she did not say that.
He's just blondes lump ones in their
eyes. Make sure the light, I don't know.
It's just, do you teach them
that? That's not what we do,
but,
but I am proud of him.
He's discerning because why shouldn't
she be discerning with your friends?
It is great.
You wanna hear another prank call.
I loved hearing other prey called another
one from, I think from Fort Simpson.
So he calls a tattoo shop.
This guy's got talent with the uh,
God. It's so funny what he does.
The,
the Sissy.
A Fremont Street. Remember that? How can
I forget? He's like, Hey, I'm a sissy.
Gemini. How can I
forget? Oh, he's a sissy.
Gemini.
He's such a fucking freak.
I'm a Gemini too.
Did you know that I'm a sissy?
Geminis this guy, just in case
you're a, Oh, we can't forget
cause I like white. We'll
see like our son. Right.
You know?
Thank you.
Yeah. Okay, so that's that
fucking guy. All right. No,
the great.
Tony made a,
a prank call using him to get a
tattoo. He wants to get a tattoo. Okay,
so he sets it up.
My Dad was looking to get a tattoo.
Can't really figure out what exactly
he needed. If it's all right,
if you have a sec, do you mind if I put
them on real quick and you can rx. Okay.
Like a sailor. Jerry was kind of
style traditional. That's awesome.
Come on down here and check it out.
And so like that. Make an appointment,
bitch.
All right. That
too.
On what?
Gemini?
Yeah.
Special white slept.
Um,
which is,
I love of the Tattoo Guy. Laps and laps.
I also think it was great that, um,
that's so funny. Tony did a, he
goes, he's like, come on, dad.
Plays against, so like the Tattoo
guy. What's going on? It's brilliant.
It's this guy got a real talent.
Yeah. This guy is a real talent.
The fact that he's trying to temper dad
is just fantastic. Another great call.
Thank you so much.
Let's stop here for a
moment and we'll regroup.
We'll be back with guests very soon.
Okay.
We're back here with Comedians,
writers,
actors, producers, Jews,
wrappers, wrappers, shoes. Yes. Yes.
It's both Jews. No, come on. No. Are
you kidding me? Here's the thing.
You fucking converted. Oh wait, whoa,
whoa, whoa. I don't love the vibe of that.
I was, I was saying like, you haven't
converted. That would be nice. Oh yeah.
There's a, how do I say it? It was more
like a, Oh, I didn't mean that like that.
Let me rephrase it.
Did
you convert it?
People needed those facial expressions? I
think so. I think they do a lot. Ah, yeah.
Why not? I was Catholic. That
was humiliating. What are
you were Catholics? Oh yeah.
Yeah. You guys, do you guys come on over?
Hard to mass on Sunday every week?
No.
But see in Judaism you can still
have a Shabbat, which is today,
and we'll light some candles and sing a
song. And you're still part of, you know,
deep tradition. What's that? Oh, first
of all, was it it? Was it a demand? Oh,
it wasn't a demand. It was a, it was
an ultimatum. Was it really? It was a,
how do you bring it?
Was it like an expected ultimatum or was
it wasn't an ultimatum. I would never.
Right, but you were like, I
would prefer this. Well, you
know, the problem would be,
hmm, no, I mean obviously there's
a subtext of every Jew that's like,
I would prefer this.
Yeah.
It's like the obnoxiousness and chauvinism
to say like, and now you can join.
My culture is, I would never
have explicitly said that
she, Natasha volunteered.
Really? Wow. And you knew, but you know
it would be meaningful to him though.
I mean is that I went, well, yeah.
But also I went to Catholic school and
I was not connected with Catholicism at
all and she has,
she had an entertainment lawyer,
so she was familiar with the culture.
He been in Showbiz for another year and
I really did like fall in love with the
traditions.
I could see how that gets done.
Think it's all about like there's a
holiday where you just eat outside for a
week under a tent under palm fronds
and told me that this is a blue band.
Yeah, he's our producer. He told
me about it wrestling. Right.
There's the red band expanded universe.
I know about this. When we left,
when we left red ban,
we hired Bluebay. Well,
we also have a producer for our podcast,
but it's a Jewish podcast,
so it's gold band.
That's great.
Great name for our are real name is
and the Dov. Oh, he's okay. He's cold.
Ben Himself. He's from the old country.
Yeah. So, um, yeah, no, we're big fans.
I just think the Jews are great.
So great.
I feel very welcome now. Yeah,
kind of did that yourself.
You don't even have a producer
here. Yeah, that's right.
I just pushed the button all by myself.
That would be bad if that was
one of your saved like drops.
I approved.
The sound effects are actually totally
negating the double lightening bolt flag
that you have in front of your house.
But now I'm kind of going, okay, I'm,
I'm more comfortable.
There's a bunch of save
stuff for every Jew.
Well, that one says I
approve Jews. Jews are great.
Jews are funny.
Whose voice?
That's it from an interview
that Yoshi, you know, Yoshi,
Yoshi did an interview once where he
talked about a lot of crazy things.
Those were some of the things.
That's Yoshi.
He also says this in the same interview.
Fuck the girl with no arms and one leg
necessarily.
Have you say something good like,
yeah, so I mean I, you know,
if I have somebody coming to the show
and I go like this might be funny to drop
with them, I'll prep it, I'll get
it ready. So Natasha converted.
It's so fascinating. I really
do. I mean I was raised pretty,
I wouldn't say like intensely,
but like pretty Catholic grade school
and a
Catholic,
all girls Catholic school for high school,
I was the first challenge.
The Jews were more rational because
I grew up in the San Fernando Valley.
It just made a little more sense,
a little more intuitive.
I mean the two main tenants are
24 hour period ideally where you turn off
your phone to Saturday sundown and you
like candles and have a dinner party
and then the next day, Saturday,
what does it mean
is converting you right,
don't fucking call me no cell phones,
but you know about that.
It used to be Saturday.
They literally, I'm not
kidding. They literally, they
shifted the day by one day.
I mean, the whole thing
about Christianity was that
it was self conscious about its
connection to Judaism for a long time.
So they did a lot of weird
like adjustments to say
we still have a sabbath,
but it's no longer on Saturday even
though it's pretty obvious that it's,
that it's all good test to mentors. I
mean I'm not even a, well there are three,
Natasha didn't say it right. So there
are three main tenants of Judaism.
Procreate,
keep Shabbat.
And then you remember the beginning
of ducktails where scrooge McDuck is
swimming in the pool.
Right?
Cool. Why don't you, yeah,
that's the third major.
Third Nights of tenant points.
I love swim and background,
but we invented that. You invented,
that was a gift that we gave to you.
And the reason why I know the tenants
is because I had to take 19 four hour
classes in order to,
you're good at it.
The other thing I love before a trio of
rabbis told me that if I went to Paris
with my baby, they, you know, if it
was Jewish it might get like, you know,
hurt. And was I okay with that? Oh
Wow. And did you, when you menstruate,
do you have to go sit in, in
the every time? Yeah. Yeah.
I don't touch her for the full week.
Do you know about that though?
That's not a joke. No,
that's Orthodox Jew.
Jews don't touch you. Not only for
the week that you're menstruating,
which obviously every normal person
doesn't touch their white while they're
meant straight up.
Of course,
the week after also it's two full weeks
until ambulation and then we fuck when
you're fertile. Right. I
mean the, the argument,
it's pretty barbaric and cave manage,
but the argument is kind of like, well,
if you don't touch wife for two weeks,
then you're like so horny
for your wife all the time.
There's something about that,
which I haven't felt horny
for my wife and I would,
I would say seven years and we've been
together for six. No, you're right.
I love to hit that cooked. You also
totally love the fact that, I mean,
other cultures do this,
but like in Jewish culture,
it really like Jewish people will
support each other, you know, like, yeah,
that's definitely true. Knowing like in
businesses I'm serious. Like, you know,
I don't like where you're going with this.
I'm serious.
But they w people will support each other.
It lifts up a community.
Like you don't see that in every culture.
Well,
I think that any culture that has been a
subjugated to weird forms of oppression
become black, tight, tighter, and more
and more connected and more supportive.
I was thinking about this, about
gay people recently, like, uh,
how it's like homophobia so awful.
But it also creates this like
interesting culture of like, you know,
this fiber community. And if homophobia
literally went away then, I mean,
imagine what gate the gay
community wouldn't exist.
It wouldn't be a gay
community parades or nothing.
That would just be like people in the
suburbs fucking each other, right?
Yes, it would be good. I'm not saying
it'd be bad, but there'd be something,
there's something vital that's created
from oppression, which is why I'm
Oh, ardent homophobe not
cause I don't like gay people.
I like to push the culture forward.
Mother fucker.
You appreciate that.
That makes me feel like a member
of a community. There you go.
Is that also what that guy
said? That's Joe Pesci touch it.
Did you get any kind of emblem or necklace
or what do you get when she got her
clitoral? When they removed it and put
it on kind of the value. You get a name?
Yeah. Oh yeah. You're allowed to
say it or you got a special like it.
It's not like a transcendental mantra
or you're not allowed to tell him.
Can you share your TM mantra?
It's Natasha, Coco Diaz.
Tell him your name. What's your
Jewish name? Oh, that's good. Dot.
Oof. The guttural are, isn't really
flowing off the back of your throat, but,
but which means tree and I don't remember
what that light of light because of
Ligero. No, but yeah, that's why you went
with Ora. Yeah. Okay. I gotta tell you,
I know I'm really into the fact
that you're not like, yeah,
I did this thing to fucking, I don't
know, pray with him and sacrifice kids,
whatever. Jews, dude, you're like,
I'm really on board with it. Yeah.
Well, I mean I can't say that I'm
fully, oh, actually we got to run. Okay,
thanks. But most of his brothers
a rabbi, so, and he's moving here,
so he'll also help us, you know, continue
to celebrate the big holidays. You know,
it's nice.
They're all at night,
the holidays and you're already
drinking and eating. You know,
you're on a good team.
You know the, you know the old,
there's an old Jewish joke,
which is that every holiday has the
same theme is a, they tried to kill us.
We won. Let's eat well because
that's a classic to Joe.
Nice. I like a celebration.
Then like Easter Sunday,
it's a bomber I fucking hallway.
Bummer.
But Easter is also based on a
Jewish holiday. What are the,
is it the crucifixion of JC? And then
he rises from the dead to the station.
Fucking cross. Chuck bomb
was a Bummer, but Easter is
Passover, right? So the last,
the last supper was passed. So it
was a Passover Seder. Straight up.
Yeah. Where are you like
have to get blasted drunk?
Yeah. Well, no, you, oh, that's
four cups of wine. That's true.
But there is actually one holiday in
Judaism where you're literally supposed to
get drunk. Oh, right. That's
a different one. It's called
Purim. Oh, Pam. About that.
It's like, it's Ju Ju Halloween and you
are literally commanded to get so drunk.
There's a character in the, in the story
called Haman who was like the bad guy.
He tried to kill us. We won.
Let's eat. And uh, but this
is, they tried to kill us.
We want low. Let's get
back. Let's get fucked up.
You guys are really
putting on an appealing,
do you tell your choice? They're
Catholic. Not yet. I mean,
he's only two and a half, but we're also
not, yeah, we're not really, I mean,
maybe you could argue where culturally
Catholic, but it's also at a man.
I mean it's like there's lights.
Did you, how'd you baptize them?
Remember we did at the
urging though at the,
almost almost ultimatum of, of
my parents. Oh yeah, yeah. Oh No.
I didn't want our child to
go to hell either, but I
wasn't going to, I mean like,
I don't remember you saying it. I
remember getting multiple calls. Okay.
Do you want to hear what was it
in July? And I was like, ah, yeah,
setting it up right now. All right. Are
you having a girl? No. As a boy. Oh,
nevermind that. Wait, what was it? Well,
it was just one of the other great
things is instead of a baptism,
the girls comes out of your coach,
a naming ceremony,
give birth out of their vaginas. But
no, isn't it? Um, if your mother,
you don't have to get their
debt cut. Oh yeah. That too.
Automatically you're in the club,
you were in the club or you get jumped
in or fucked in. That's the other,
it's like, it's like [inaudible] basically
you'd have to do 19 four hour classes.
Uh, welcome everybody to the
orientation for ms 13. Um, but,
but that would be a good clip.
That would be great.
I would love for you to use it.
Yeah.
Unless people think it's racist
and it goes viral on that level,
then I would like you to not use it.
So there you go.
What's called Coulis. That's my
favorite line in that. Um, okay.
Judaism where we got it. Yeah,
we got it in 1994 our costs.
I'll tell you what's funny about
the conversion classes. It was like,
it was a couple of couples like
Natasha in me. First of all, it's all,
it's all I didn't have to,
but I did because it was nice.
It's a nice husband
and there are no, no men. By the way.
There were some like people like me,
but there were no men converting because
the men have to get circumcised to like
God be adults. They have to get
their, did they do for real though?
Yeah, they got a little ritual Dick.
For Real. That's why historically
Mr Teen Orientation, I'll take
out our dicks for the ritual.
Yeah,
they cut it right here.
The head I, I don't know. I think it's a
great question. I actually think it's, Oh,
definitely. It would be on the
head of the Dick. This is like
a blood spiritual, you know, making
your day is like gang shit man.
Yeah. For Real. Yeah. But that's,
that's why historically men have been
much less likely to convert to Judaism
than women because even if you're 40,
you still have to get the circumcision.
You got to do it well. You raised a
orthodox or, yeah, I was raised, well,
I was raised in Oakland with my mom
who's like an atheist Hippie, but my dad,
when my mom and dad split became,
uh, he got a, became very religious.
He joined up with a group of Hasidic
Jews known as the sophomore who are
literally the most religious of all the
Hasidic Jewish groups are like the most
extreme of all the acidic juice.
It was pretty, pretty crazy.
They don't like my dad and mom,
my stepmom and my dad didn't sleep in
the same bed together because of the,
because of the monthly, it's
really intense. Yeah. Yeah.
You wouldn't want to accidentally
wake up with like, you know,
menstrual blood on your,
on your pajamas,
like the Godfather when the horse head
is in there. You know what I mean?
They didn't share a bedroom. They
shared a bed room, but not a bet.
They had two single beds.
Exactly. Like Lucy and Ricky.
I think that would, my dad would
say, you know, Lucy, I'm home.
And he would walk over to the other bed.
He would smash,
he would probably pump for a while
until it got like really close.
And then he probably, he slowed
down a bit. He caressed her bed,
then he started pounding again and
then it'd be like, Daddy's coming.
And that's what I remember.
Yeah.
Fuck through a hole in the sheet or no,
that's a truce. The Handmaid's tale.
That's a true rumor.
Uh,
a false rumor that that is so pervasive
in Judaism that Jews believe it about
themselves because the,
the, the, the air, uh,
refined air of Jew Jewish
observance that my dad was at.
90% of American Jews that you've met
have no exposure to that in real life.
But I do, I mean, I have,
I have cousins who spoke,
speak Yiddish as a first language and
speak English with an Eastern European
accent raised here, raised in America,
third generation Americans. But they have,
they like if you met them, they'd
be like, Hello Tom, how are you?
Love or whatever it needs to do.
They sound like Cardi B talks.
Yeah,
dude,
I have family honestly that I wouldn't
be sure that they knew who are raised in
New York. I'm not sure. They
wouldn't know who the Yankees were.
Not Positive that I'm not, I'm
not, I'm not joking for sure.
They wouldn't know who Cardi
B is. There's no, there's no,
there's absolutely no question. They
would know who Cardi B is. Awesome.
I know some Dominicans that,
uh, okay, I'm listening.
Were born and raised in Washington who
don't know who the, the square Rebbie is.
Definitely know the Yankees are, but they,
uh, have, uh, accents and you're like,
you're born here. Well, yeah,
yeah, definitely. And heavy
accent. You're like, oh,
you came when you were 12? And like, no,
no, I was born here, but this is it. Yeah,
totally. You know, they have
a heavy, and they sound yet
they have like a Danish. I had, I
had a cousin one time when I was,
we were in the hospital when my dad was
sick and uh, and my dad died eventually.
Anyway, I just wanted to tell
that story. But no, he goes, he,
there's a wheel at the
story of him fucking right.
Well he fucked my step mom and a death.
And that was,
I mean he told his dad he would put the
jacket. Well, he actually ejaculate.
It's so hard. He turned inside
out and that's how he died. Yeah.
He just kept coming and coming
until he wasn't there anymore.
But I still have that jar of common.
So every, when I need advice,
I got it in the talk to it, like
raises into a figurine, you know,
turning brown. He pops up out of the,
out of the thing and just like, what,
how can I help you? Nobody.
But my cousins come jar.
My cousin goes, I, uh,
cause he knew I wasn't religious and he
didn't have much exposure to people that
weren't religious.
You know,
and there's this thing that
happens when someone's sick.
Do you have to kind of guard
their deathbed kind of,
sort of has to be like a religious
person there to make sure that all the
rituals are done correctly,
whatever.
So it was very odd because it'll be like
me who's next to his dad and then like
a kind of tertiary family member who's
not really that close to the family,
but it's just there to
like be a ritual guy.
So he turns to me like in the
middle of the night and he goes, hi,
I have a secret I have to tell you.
And I was like, what? He's like,
cause you're not religious. I feel
like I can tell you. And I go, okay.
And he's like, I've always wanted
to. And I go out to be gay, be gay.
You willing be gay, you're gay, it's
okay for gay. I'm thinking to myself.
And he goes, he looked,
he goes to be a lawyer.
Oh that was really big, deep,
dark secret is dig deep.
That's how religious they are to be a
lawyer. It would be like so secular.
They only,
they only to be rabies is that it there?
What are they supposed to do there
to work in some, uh, you know,
business that the family owns
and to study their whole lives.
It's like to be a lawyer as to like have
aspirations to connect to the outside
world. And there's just that.
There's nothing there. Okay.
Fucking through a sheet though.
Fucking through. So you know,
the Jews have the prayer, uh, like
the, the, the thing that they wear.
Have you ever seen it? They Dang, they
have the dangling like little fringes.
So that's a garment Poncho.
Yeah, it's exactly like a Poncho.
That's a garment that's a square with a
hole in the middle that they put on in
the morning.
Every Jew,
every or the docs who wears though
sometimes if they're less religious,
they tuck them in. So you don't
know that they're wearing them.
And if they're more religious,
they put them out so that the world knows.
So historically those garments would
be hanging on a laundry line in the old
village or whatever,
in the Shtetl.
And Non Jews would walk by
unaware of what the thing was.
They would look and I go, why is there
a big sheet with a hole in the middle?
Somebody said, oh, they must,
you know, the most logical, yeah,
those logical things that they
must have walked through that hole
and then everybody starts to believe it.
So much so that like,
I would say honestly most Jews, you know
that think that think that about them.
Their own
doesn't party. You though, when
you hear like in any religion,
like let's talk about, you
know, Christianity or Islam,
when you think about someone's level of
devotion being that high, you're like,
man, that is just too much. Oh,
give your life to this. I
mean, I just go like, but I,
I mean I respect someone's
dedication to it. I'm like,
you're making your whole life about right.
I really under beliefs, I really
understand it though. Yeah.
I really get it because my, I think
what it's about is that like the world,
if you're not religious,
if you're paying attention to the world,
it's so obvious that the world is,
that life is chaos. It's terror.
It's fear, it's people killing each
other. It's like meaninglessness.
It's careening towards death.
It's like it's empty and alone.
And religion is this thing that goes, no,
no, no, no, no. It's totally meaningful.
It's completely,
it's completely enclosed.
There are answers to all of the questions
you think are unanswerable and you
don't have to worry.
Just join this totality of a religious
system and like there isn't any becomes
comfort. It's total comfort
completely. Of course.
I, cause I know it's my mom's
pretty pretty religious, you know,
not like dedicated in the type
of way that your father was,
that your child would have a
bad life if it wasn't baptized.
Love it guys.
Yeah,
I thought Catholics had a waiting
room for that type of situation.
But like we're saying like, you know,
like my mom prays the Rosary if the,
if a car rides longer than 10
minutes. Oh, you a religious,
she carries a Bible with her. She doesn't
carry a Bible with her. But I mean,
you know, she wears a necklace with a
bit of a Virgin Mary or something on it.
So your mom's house is a church.
It's the house of the Lord
is the House of the Lord.
One thing about her is that like
when she does get stressed out,
she's a very overwhelmed,
it's very
anxious.
But the only thing that kind of like
brings that anxiety down a lot of time is
prayer or the thought that like
it'll be taken care of. Oh, it works.
It's not up for debate whether or not
prayer and being religious meditation or
whatever the fuck.
So these two Jews have a uh,
hey, hassle out. It's fantastic.
It's the honeymoon standup special.
You have to look great.
I did a gorgeous, I was eight months
pregnant here though. That's fine.
Well yeah. Great. Yeah,
but you're not that great.
I just did it thing eight months
and I look a lot bigger. No, no, no.
Um,
I love how you guys,
you both your sets and then you had the
Q and a thing that's kind of fun and
couples grows.
Did talks, does a half hour of
stand up than I do have are set up.
Daniel Tosh it. Yeah, I dunno.
It was weird because he, you know, he's
got his own thing. I guess to be honest,
I wasn't familiar with
his work right then.
We just knew it'd be a funny play on
words. And we, I'm a Texas by the way.
You did it in Austin. Yeah. Yeah. Uh,
and yeah, so Natasha did a half hour,
I do a half hour and then we do the,
this is what we're doing on
the road to the last hour,
half hour is us bringing couples up
and kind of like troubleshooting their
relationship and just basically roasting
them. Yeah. It's really fun. Thank you.
So you toured with that, with this show
though for a while, right? Yeah, we uh,
we went on a tour and a, it was really
fun, as you guys know, do to her together.
No, no, he won't. He won't even
get a couple's massage with me.
That's true.
Why will you get a couple of,
but have you seen his Netflix queue
by the way? That'll explain it. Well,
it's the Netflix Queue.
It was just mostly things about murder
and drugs and shooting and you won't get
a massage to a couple's massage.
Couple's massage. What? What?
Why does it remind you of his murderous
now? Because he's a psychopath.
This is just part of the ones
that have to do with Netflix.
Queue is like that but
he likes couples miss.
Not a psychopath want a couple's massage.
He'll pretend like he does but this one
is so in tune with that side of himself
that he is going to close up the wound.
What's the issue though? I'm the,
I don't like, I don't like that. Okay.
When you go into like a treatment room
and you're there, it's like it's all you,
you, you, you pull apart,
you want to fart and stuff.
I mean I do want to force
someone to breathe loud.
I want to grown and I don't like any
other distractions. I don't like,
you don't want to hear like,
so Christina was [inaudible] that shit
irritates me and I don't want to hurt her.
I hear you want to be able
to like with impunity,
slowly move your legs apart and push
her to wars and just to do an a silent
negotiation to you do it. You
have to put your, I don't know,
what are you talking about?
I figured your legs
cause he knows that even
talking about massage,
how do you ask that?
It must be or you want to talk about that?
I mean it is it your legs up
and scoot your butt down. Okay.
I've heard from other people. Yeah, I
did not know you did that. I didn't,
I but I've heard from other people. Sure.
That part of it is like they're doing,
they're giving you the massage
and then there's like a very,
there's this period of silent negotiation
where the person will be like rubbing
and then they're like sorta errantly
like sort of flinger your balls,
you know like sorta
flick finger like this.
Just a light grace and if you close
your legs then the person massage,
oh this dude likes bodywork. Okay, he's
here. He's a legitimate human beings.
A little swipe.
Then you slightly just a little
bit open and then open a little,
just a little less because if
you turn around and flop out,
they're probably going to be like, this
is uh, like a cop or I don't know what.
Right. So yeah, it's a, there's
like a, there's a dance.
You don't want to have
your legs straight forward.
What will the Cummins in the balls or
actually it's in a jar filled with my
father's ashes.
A good drop.
What'd you say? How many times have
you done this? I've never done it,
but I watch a lot of documentaries
on Netflix about this. There is,
there are a lot of Daca. Yeah,
there are. You learn about, anyway,
the point is I like traveling
with Mosha cause I'll be about,
I'll go get a massage,
I'll come back a lot more like sort of
reasonable and in my, in my, in my mind,
I honestly don't know how
we'd do it with the child
on his birthday.
When is it?
July six to Seattle and gets available
cash or.com we sold out the first show.
So there's only shows available for
the late show, but it'll be fun.
Columbia city theater in Seattle.
We're going on a big RV trip with
the baby and we're terrified.
We're terrified that you bought one.
I have one. Yes. Yes. This is awesome.
My plan is to just try to
not cry, not cry. Hello.
This alarm is going to be hard.
We're driving from here to Seattle
because I have a wedding in a,
I'm actually marrying another
woman, uh, after my birthday.
It's a birthday present
for me. Judaism. No for,
we're going to drive all the way up the
coast like all the way to sat up on the
coast. That's a long ass dress. A long.
How long? How long is this going to take?
We have like 11 days.
We'll be good to only drive
three hours a day with the baby.
Going to be that going
to bring a helping hand
and he's coming in the RV.
I sense you have contempt for this trip.
Well,
if you can believe it.
I'm really into camping and for s and if
you can believe this and Natasha's not
as into camping.
That's hard to believe.
It's hard to believe she's a rugged Kinda,
you know wild.
I've always noticed that about her.
She loves hiking, Birkenstocks,
her
Hilton Garden Inn.
We had a severe anxiety
flying with our son.
I don't want to you bring
the car seat. Uh, yeah.
You bring everything. You fucking
bring everything. You do it alone.
Because I was planning on doing that
personally. I, there's some women who for,
it's like not a big deal. Yeah, the
baby's fine. He sleeps on the floor.
Not with my kid. He's a boy. He's active.
It would give me so much diarrhea,
anxiety to do it alone.
I can't even imagine if you were the
one that shit your pants. I promise.
I actually do have so much anxiety
when we phone a couple times with them.
We've,
we've sworn it off now until he's like
10 what's the weirdest thing that's ever
happened to you guys on an airplane?
So weirdest thing. A memory.
It was always something horrible.
There's so many weird things
that have happened on airplanes.
Don't have a great story,
but I do have a story.
There was a time when I got on a plane,
I start flirting with
this girl pretty hard,
like I didn't know where she
was just sitting next to me,
and this is actually
a very pathetic story,
but what ended up happening was we ended
up holding hands up to New York and
that was
the end of the stuff.
That should give you a massage after a no.
I adjusted my legs open slightly and
she didn't respond to that at all on the
way to Africa.
That's true.
That was a long flight and I ate
tacos in the Atlanta airport.
Bad idea before like a 19 hour flight.
Oh,
they don't have bathrooms
on the African polite
pair of panties with me and my
carry on. When were you there? Yeah,
we flew to Africa together.
It seemed like the kind of couple who
goes to the bathroom in front of other
in front of me.
Did you give
each other but no brown,
Brown, brown a lot.
I
was a woman.
I can't even begin to entertain this,
but like as a guy, when you have to Fart,
you always had to deal with this problem.
I leave the room,
you know?
I don't think so.
This is a central issue.
Our listeners care about the topic
they want to know about, so hold on.
So you're watching a movie,
Natasha? I don't know if
I, if that's true for me,
I'll either hold it.
Wow.
I mean it's like why do I want to
breach that? At this point you're,
how many years in six years have you
been holding it that long then fart in
front of each other? Like
friends? Yeah, definitely.
Do you fart in front of your guy
friends when you're out of the house?
I put the girls, don't I do, I
don't know. We got to hang out more.
I'll get you to start farting.
Tell him after an afternoon
that closer to the friend. Definitely
the more, I mean if it's a really,
really close friend, I'll sit on them
and fart in his lap or something.
If it's a really close friend,
I'll slide my dig into him and I was,
it's really about farting,
but it is that I'm gay and I had
a secret that I have that I'm,
I'm trying to reveal on this podcast
and my wife Natasha. So you never want,
even when you're pregnant,
you never had to Fart or what do you
do when you have to farm it? I didn't,
I didn't. Uh, I mean I just, I don't ever
have to, you don't ever have to Fart.
No. I mean, this is a lot
about number two is, well,
what do you do when you
have to remember too?
Mine are white and I don't do that
either. Hers or Velvet Velvet, Hawaii,
reality. Believe this. Tasha is on brand.
It's exactly what you imagined the topic.
I know they're white. I never heard that
before. But that is because I'm anal sex.
That is why they're so white. Yeah, that's
a lot. Do you guys think this is funny?
Just be honest. I had to do with shit. No,
not yet. No, not definitely do it. Shit.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
Those guy climbing a tree,
he's going to look like
you just got to treat food.
What's he trying to do? He's trimming
a tree. A tree trimmer. Okay.
It looks unprofessional. It was like
a little buddy has some boring shirt.
No shirt. He's got the straps in
the robe. I don't know. Whatever.
You should have like a machine to do that
I think. I think you're probably right.
I mean that just,
Oh my God. Oh my God. Oh my God.
Moshe thinks that's funny. I don't,
I don't think it's funny either.
We're kind of the same now and Natasha,
why don't you create a real funny,
let's talk and I'm over 14 right?
Also,
I love trees and I know how they should
be trimmed, so right away I'm like,
so I know there's a man at the bottom
of that three screaming and agonist.
He's like just saying it was a giveaway,
like I knew what was going to happen
and you'll surprise I got you. It was,
I was surprised. That's a very surprised
if that wasn't going to end well.
That was a long drop. And the Adelaide,
the agony at the, I didn't like the fall,
but the screaming at the bottom, that
was pretty funny. One more thing.
That tree doesn't need to be trimmed.
That's
what bothers Natasha doesn't need
it. See, I'm a big proponent of like,
the screams can be funny.
Oh yeah. The shout. Oh, you
know, can I hear that again?
Sure. It did seem kind of good. Yeah,
just the end. Good. Alright. That scream.
Let's see where is, he sounded
painful if I remember. I mean,
that guy might not be alive. Yeah. And
that makes it even funnier, right? Yeah.
Oh my God. Hold on.
Hold on. What happened?
What happened?
Go ahead.
I don't want to get,
he broke a bone that he's
hurting. He's in pain. Yeah.
He might've popped the liver. I mean,
and it's hilarious to my husband.
That's what I'm going to have
a very refined sense of humor.
This is obviously funny. I
mean, it is cut this part,
maybe my husband, ear to ear. This
is the happiest he's looked Tommy.
We're having a baby. No smile.
Definitely out of a tree. Yeah.
So you're going to have two boys. That
sounds really hard. You got him to,
it's all digital. This
is why, but this is why.
This is why she's not farting and you're
not fighting cause you have girls.
Two female dogs,
little Pablo are the only male forces.
That's why I'm out numbered by dicks and
balls and Fart. You got more clips, Tom?
I've got all kinds, all kinds of
shit. Trying to see some clips.
Watch his videos like this all the time.
I've got my home pages or are
CNN Kook Slam meal on Instagram
likes
Dr Phil like molestation videos.
Why that? Why that is what used to
referring to what she's referring to.
That's way better
not the mothers are like,
I don't,
I just want your my son because exactly
what my reaction was funny was that he
was so close to the ground
and hurt himself so badly,
so badly and the parachutes open like
it didn't know what went wrong. I Dunno.
It's like he didn't have it fully open.
I don't know what's going on with it.
Okay. Would you guys marry your mom?
Wait, what? You're asking me if I would
Mary, my mother? No. No.
Why? Because she's my mom. That's,
I find that kind of off putting,
get around to calling my mom.
I mean,
let's say, why would you marry your mom?
I don't know. I just putting it out there.
Are you queuing up a clip right now?
Tell her mom and you're my son and
I fall in love with him. He said,
yes I am. He said, you know what, I was
scared to let you know too. I am too.
We're both consenting adults.
If, if it comes down to it,
it's just like the gays there,
you know,
as long as they're over 18
everything's fine. Yeah.
You know what I'm really glad for is
that this is subtitled cause they're so
stupid that I'm saying,
it's like why are they talking to cameras?
Like marry your mom.
But that's,
we thought on this is like just don't
tell people that you married your mom.
That's why I watch those racism
videos on Worldstar with,
it's like the old white lady got like,
go back to your fucker.
It's like the minute be racist,
by all means.
The moment the person you're being to
poles, the camera, it's like walk away,
you're going to lose your job,
you're not going to work at quickie mart.
More enraged.
And they are also so used to phones
that they don't realize they're being
recorded. But he definitely know
he's a, he's at an interview.
Let me say this about this couple.
You know how Wise Cup,
teardrop,
apple,
it's kind of full circle to your ms
13 no, you know, here's the thing.
You know how like when you have,
when you were single and you
would have sex with somebody,
you shouldn't be having sex was,
it was like a little hotter, right?
This is probably so hot. Like when
you get to tell mom fucking, I mean,
it's probably so hot, right? You know,
if you're down because you know it's,
it's literally the ultra, the,
the, Oh gee taboo. That's true.
And it's gotta be kind of awesome.
Also led to my favorite
listener made songs
of all time here. My son, I'm your mom.
You're my son.
I'm,
your mom told me you're asking when
you ask them when you see your mom.
Oh yes, I would hear my son. I'm your mom.
It's just like the gates.
Just like the gates
fell in love too before they had
sex, it sounds like. That's right.
What was cool about it?
Because they had a relationship from their
previous relationship of just being a
mother and son.
They're able to really communicate openly
their desire before they consummated
friends for.
That's actually,
we were so fascinated by this. We found
out that there is a common thing amongst,
uh, parents, even siblings that
are separated for a long time.
A lot of times when they're reunited,
the feelings are so overwhelming.
It can be confusing that they'll
shift sometimes into sexual feelings.
Oh man, that's so intense.
It's very intense.
So would you,
would you like hook up with your mom?
I would rather just to kill
myself at this moment right now.
Even that have entertained
this conversation. Yeah. Even
as a bit, yes. Great. Okay.
I accept that, but yeah. Oh man,
that would be, see you afraid, you
know, base it damn these afraid.
Do you play this video for every podcast?
Not Very podcast a while. Here's one.
Hi Melanie. I'm Scotty with
ecstatic hearts, Tantra,
which just want to share that
there are many ways to orgasm.
She's acting like he's going
to John Waters movie sucks.
You can't put that style
acting. Yeah, like a over,
I just played it cause you're a
couple ice. Any sex right now?
They're this ever going to Oregon.
He just came on on came hug.
That's so funny too because not rubbing.
Well,
I mean it's like in the touch and I had
been having sex for years and you've
never ever had an orgasm. It's
like they're, they're just hugging.
That's funny.
Oh Man.
He like yelling. This just came
in. I haven't seen this one.
It's this therapy to yelling.
It was the primal scream in the burning
man I've seen. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
This doesn't appeal to me because it
seems like it would hurt my voice,
but I think most of us should do this.
Why?
Because I think you have
more rage than I do.
Rage. I don't have any rage.
Do you have more than me?
Like when you get mad where people
park. Oh, that's true. Really? Well,
we live across the street
for an elementary school
and people are always coming
to pick their kids up and
parking in my driveway. Oh
No, no, no. They don't
park in his driveway.
They parked like two inches out and
I kind of plot out a little bit.
Blobby he could still get
out and I was a school,
are y'all done? I go, that's a driveway,
and then she's like, this lady was like,
well, it's too big. I'm like, I
didn't pour the fucking concrete.
I didn't establish this property. I
bought it and he's yelling this, throw a,
and then she goes, she goes, well,
I'm just going to go and I go, well,
I'm going to call the police. And
she was like, go ahead and go.
I'm going to key your car. She got
back in her car and drove away. No, no.
She's picking up her kid from school.
What am I going to say? Really respected.
[inaudible] name's Maggie or car.
One of the great things of greatest
minds ever had was I was in in Berkeley.
I was going to park and
someone cut me off and,
and pulled into the spot and the lady
was just like walking away and I just go,
I said it exactly like this.
I go, I'm a key. That car,
have a nice time in the bank. I'm a
key that car. And I just drove away.
Of course I didn't key the car. I went
to bed about my day, but I do yell.
I'm a key that car,
really the street. I just,
I loved the idea that there's no
possibility she would be in the bank,
not freaking out, not enjoying
her time. Yeah. And I and I,
and that was the price of entry for that.
Yeah.
That is also the opposite of,
you know, spreading love and joy.
That's right. It's like
spreading that key, that car.
That is what I miss about Christianity.
I liked that you did it. Yeah. That car,
it's good because it's you
that car threat, it's menacing,
but it's like you just as an empty
threat and then you're not going to be,
you are fucking her day
up, which I like. I loved
that. I was just like, okay,
now I'm going to go on my day.
And at least she got punished
for taking that spot.
You'd almost be a bitch more pleased with
having done that and not even getting
the park like I could. Oh No. Yeah
I think so. Just feel good about,
I would never do that dude. We
had a, we had a funny situation.
Speaking of conflict cause I
sometimes am prone to conflict and uh,
we were driving back
from the air from lax.
We got picked up by an Uber
and we just watched, um,
we just watched drugstore cowboy wait
at midnight, midnight cowboy cowboy.
So we were kind of thinking about that.
And um, the car, the guy and the Uber,
he looked like kind of a professor and
he rolled his eyes a moment. He saw.
So I should have like known
something was up, but I didn't quite,
why wouldn't you roll your eyes?
I mean just cause what we look like
snobs or whatever. I don't know what,
what his process was.
Whatever we get in the car,
I might've been wearing two
hats. That's true. Possible.
So we're in the back of the car, we're
talking about the plot to midnight cowboy.
We're like, you know, what
was that? Were they gay?
Was that a gay love that situation?
What kind of analyzing the film and he's
Kinda like heroin thing a little bit.
Just the littlest bit. And then,
uh, it's like an hour ride.
We get back to my house and we're kind
of, we're kind of going like, okay,
Natasha goes, you turn left here
because our entrance is not where the,
where the address has a, he kind of snaps
at her after he goes, like, he goes,
I'm a turn left because the thing says
to turn left. And I go, all right,
stop the car. We're getting out right now.
And uh, he's like, I can't stop the car.
And I like open. I had already opened the
door and uh, and he's like, I, I do that.
I pulling over. So he pulls over into
our driveway and I, and I'm like,
at this point, like, I think
I did, he starts screaming,
so I pull out your phone.
So I pulled out my phone. It was just
like click, you know, and I was like,
say goodbye to your job at
Uber, you know, whatever.
And we get out and he's like, cause he,
oh, that's right. He called me a jackass.
He's, he swore he took it to
the swearer zone and I'm like,
that's when I started recording. I
was like, what'd you just say, be it?
I didn't say bitch. Uh, and
he's like, he's like nothing.
I didn't say anything and he wouldn't
give me my luggage. Right. He's like,
she's eight months pregnant.
At that point,
I think it was actually on the way
back from the special actually,
and he wouldn't give me
my luggage and I'm like,
give me my fucking luggage to get the
fuck outta here. And he's like, nope, no,
I'm calling the police don't know
why he's calling the police. He goes,
you go in the house, I'll give your
luggage to your wife. I'm like,
I'm not leaving my pregnant wife out of
the way. It's because I was being cool.
Yeah. Yeah. Super Cool. You know,
often people would say being cool
would be supporting your husband,
not an Uber driver,
but uh,
just knew what to do to get him to leave,
I guess as opposed to like starting to
film him and activating him and making
him really mad in our drive.
Well, he walks out and he's pacing
back and forth, calling nine one one.
And I'm like, give me my fucking luggage.
So I go distract them to Natasha.
She's like, what? I leap into
the car and pull the trunk open.
Now I go to grab my bags. He freaks
out, runs over slams the car shot. Yeah.
First you told me eight months pregnant
to go pop has a trunk. Okay. To be honest,
we're all in the front seat.
All right. Well we do.
And where to be honest,
I'm not really in a good mental zone at
this point. Yeah. And I popped the trunk.
I go to grab the thing,
he slams it shut.
Finally we negotiate a settlement where
he does take the bags out and I'm like,
all right, now get the fuck out of my,
off my property. And, and he's like,
I know way I'm waiting for the cops.
I'm like the carbs for what dude?
Like what are you going to tell
the fucking cops? And he's like,
I'm going to tell him that you were, you
know you were obnoxious. I go, okay. And,
and he's like, know? And I
started walking away and goes,
and I'm going to tell him that you didn't
understand the plot to midnight cowboy.
That's really funny.
Absolutely. He Won. I will.
No question is a consumer knows
where we live. That's true.
There's no question at that
point in the interaction.
I was kind of like as a comedian,
like you're like, this one's not,
this one's yours.
You take the w one whites
on that.
That's fucking I,
it's almost unbelievable that he
could come up with that. I know. Yeah.
He looked like a retired history teacher.
He's clearly a set,
like he was like 65 70 they so funny.
It's almost like if I saw that in a movie,
I'd be like,
that guy would not be able to put that
together. Was funny. It was very much,
obviously it was driving the car.
As we analyze this film that he
clearly thinks he understands more,
that he's just going like,
oh my God, these insufferable
hipster scar in the back.
Think they understand this. Just like
driving angrily. Maybe he was like a, um,
like a film critic or like
I bet he taught at La Community College.
I did threaten to shoot him.
You did? Yeah. As I was walking in, I
was like, you better get out of here.
I was like, I don't have a gun. I
think like, you know, or you know,
I'm gonna go get my gun or something.
I don't have a gun.
There is no group said that to him.
I think so.
Would you put up with this type of
behavior in your yard and my yard,
like right in your driver for it not to
be on your property so that guy fucking
knows where you live. I'd be afraid he's
going to come back and Jack me later.
I did feel that
we got into a fight because I just felt
like he was escalating it in a way that
my issue is that she
should be like on my side.
Stranger swears at you and tells you
and it's like not giving your luggage.
Wouldn't you be fired up
when he said when the guy was like,
I know when to turn left
and then I would have just
been quiet about it. Exactly.
I wouldn't have been like,
let me out of the car and open up the door
or what pissed you off about
that is what I'm saying.
Was it like being disrespected but
he disrespected her wife cares.
It didn't affect me attitude.
Anyway, let's roll the clip
me shape pig
mediation, dehumanization. Who?
Those bottom teeth are just taken away.
Um, this is kind of bothering me.
Well, first of all, I like a lot about,
this is a Bobby Lee character
TV and I'm very proud of it.
He did say,
ah, that's a shit turnover
over here. Well, wait,
what's bothering you? Uh,
first of all I liked, I don't
want to, it's very close up,
close up. About my, like
my, my submission fantasies.
I'm not going to shave fully.
I'm going to have an
extremely shiny face and not,
not trim my nose hair framing and the
bottom teeth are just so proud cause he's
in this like wait,
he's looks like he's on the toilet
because he can see his shampoo bottles.
He is definitely in the bathroom.
The cool thing is is that if
you need to go to the bathroom,
he's okay with that walking
on the street shout hey shit.
Big stuff. I love that.
He goes into a bit of a
piece, he goes into a pit of
a bit of a character. It goes,
if you see me walking on this
street, stop me. Go Hey shit. Big.
Like it sounded very New York.
It did like who watches a lot of movies?
Uh,
and then I'll come to you.
I have latrines.
Your pace is just shit and your,
your verbal mediation PSL from me.
You can shit off of me.
It didn't show up.
Well it's very expensive to have
people come to your house and do that.
So he's probably trying to get is
extended for free. Cost effective.
I like how you,
I do wonder if how true this is.
Like if I did see dude on the
street and I was like, hey shit pig.
And then I just shit in his mouth. If he
would hit this guy, he's down. He's down.
Yeah. Wow. Yeah, I think so.
Definitely like $300 to have a woman come
over and do that. Yeah. At least. Yeah.
Well I don't think there's a lot of
women doing the shit pig videos. Yeah.
Dominic. No. To come over and shit on you.
Oh saying he's doing it to try to get
free people to shit on him. Right.
But I think he's gay and I think our men,
I think it's free in that convenient,
but he tells you if you want to meet
him, you meet him at the bus station. No,
he has a a desert area. Let's
not listen to it again. Yeah,
he did say that you can meet him at the
bus station. What site is this from? A,
I don't know. The site that it was
pulled from. Please don't tell him. No,
I'm just curious what he's in Norway. Oh,
so he's not sort of directly available.
No, he's not. Okay.
We were looking at the by
there, it's even not dirty. Boy.
He's a bit of an outlier there.
Dude. I was in Norway once,
uh, and I went to the,
they have a comedy show in Bergen and the
local comedians found out I was Jewish
and we're like really kind of titillated
by that. And they're like, oh,
come with us, you'll
love this. Look, look.
And they brought us downstairs behind
the comedy club into this basement.
And they go, this was the room
where they tortured the Jews.
I swear.
And I'm like,
why would you think this is a tourist
destination that I'd be like, Yay.
And then they pointed up and there
were swastikas on the ladder. Ooh.
In the balcony across the
street. And they're like, yeah,
the Nazis were here and they,
this room,
they would interrogate the
Jews and torture them. Like,
Ooh, thank you. You like it?
Yeah. You are shipping big,
right? Yeah, that's a, yeah.
It's really intuitive over those guys
to show you that? Well, you know,
comedians really get human instinct
and human and the humanity.
So they really knew that that
was a thing I would like. Weird.
So weird. We were looking at this kid.
Oh by the way, have you noticed that?
Do you know that some people watch
comedy specials with subtitles on?
They do sometimes, yes. Okay.
Wait, because his mom is deaf,
so sometimes we have settings. So that's
different. That's totally different.
Sometimes our subtitles or
just on. Oh, okay. Right.
But you're saying something different.
I'm saying that we got emails about,
this guy was like, I was
watching a special with my
friend is subtitles were on.
He's sitting there laughing at things
before they're said, cause he's reading.
Right. And, and then he's like, you know,
I've noticed that a lot of
people are doing it and people
who are not hearing impaired.
Why was like an odd thing to do?
You mean specifically comedy
specials or just stuff?
Specifically comedy especially. Why?
I don't know why they're doing it,
but I am of the thought that it's
gotta be kind of ruining it a bit.
It's like stair step ahead. I'm very
used to that because I grew up with it.
Something my parents being
deaf, but uh, I wonder,
I would like to watch my own special with,
I mean I can't ever watch one of
my own specialist. Definitely.
But I talk so quickly that I wonder
if the subs had a person, actually
I'm telling you there's no way
they can get it right. No, no,
that dear ms, ms, whatever.
They're missing a beat. I
mean, they're misquoting,
they throw it up. Wait before you
say it or, or, or, or it's late.
It's not matching up. Kind of fucks it
up. Especially if you are, if you are,
if you can hear the reason why, why would
you do that to yourself? I don't know.
I that's bizarre. What's the
reasoning? Maybe it's a comedians.
You sometimes miss punchlines and
so they want to watch it. I guess I,
my theory on it was at this guy's
doing it because like maybe he goes,
he's just like a little
anxious and doesn't want the
mystery of where does this
going to stay like a second ahead. So
it's like true. Almost comforts him.
It's bizarre. It's bizarre. Hey,
maybe we could have them weigh
in on our Yani debate. Yani,
there's nothing to talk about. We know.
What's the other word? The Yani. Yeah,
the Piss on me beat me guy.
Uh,
he's saying I got you. Just a good
point. Okay. We'll just wrap up on that.
All right, that makes sense.
Okay. Um, so this guy,
no, we would do it. That's okay.
Do you think this is terrible? Um,
so this guy is the biggest celebrity
that this show is ever created.
Okay.
He's legendary.
He's amazing and he's contributed so much,
but there's a mystery as to what he's
saying in one part of this video. Okay.
Okay. You can give me your
version of what you think he say.
So I'll just start it off.
Black. God's love the fuck. Fuck good.
Look if you're a hot black guy and you
want to fuck me at 2195 if you want to
move in,
you can move in.
But you got to fuck the how many
I need to be fucked a lot, man.
You can't rent free food, free rent and
everything else, man. He has a GL man.
Men from jail, homeless
or um, you're thug.
Want to come move in if
Franklin you too man. Free Rent.
You could at least in a k fuck me
piss. Somebody beat me a home, Ya know?
And there it is. Wait a minute. Oh yeah,
it's clear what he said. What does he say?
A whole minnow. Oh No, no,
but that's what I understand that there's
a controversy about what he's saying.
Right. The last part, the last thing I
hear it again. Of course you can hear it.
Many times
he rented Elisa in the k fuck me piss.
Somebody beat me at home, Ya know?
See what saying? What do you think he's
saying? I'll tell you my version of,
and it's,
it's,
I don't want to taint their opinions and
tell me what you hear first because I
feel like, well here's
the audio, just the audio,
all them, Ya know, piss on
me. Beat me home. Ya know,
I,
I ain't got nothing really whole meadow,
the right lane.
See what I think he's saying is that's
been submitted I think cause he,
he tells you about what he wants,
literally gives his address out.
He says, Piss on me.
Beat me home here now.
And he's in such a frantic excitement
that it comes out of here now. Yeah,
I'm home here now. I'm home
here now. Okay, let me so
piss somebody beat me at home,
Ya know?
No. Oh No, no homie. Now some
people are saying, he's saying,
whoa man out hollow man out. Oh Man, hold
on, hold on. Hold on guys guys. I mean,
I know he does. He has an
affinity for black guys, but like,
he's not really street. It'd be crazy to
pivot at the barrier and be like, Hey,
hold this man now. Right now. Right.
People have said,
that's my argument to it doesn't,
it's not consistent with
the rest of the speech.
Now that's so cool if can
be this restaurant. Yeah.
By the way,
Trejos Tacos.
There's so many different
versions that people are, I mean,
people have said he's saying
a homie on out, hold me down.
Hollow me out. Um, uh,
in and out, like you said. Okay,
so this is a clip you found.
This isn't actually a
person. Oh yeah. People,
we found this and it's been talked to him.
We don't know that you have his address.
Write him a letter and no,
but it's really, I write him
a certified letter. He's not,
there's no way he remembers
what he fucking said. That
Watson, I'm telling you.
Crazy true dude.
I tell you what,
I challenge your mom's house to
write a certified letter with half.
You rip a hundred days in.
I Dunno.
He says it's a drug rip a
hundred dollar bill in half.
And tell him if he could tell
you the accurate answer to this,
you will send him the
other half of the hundred.
There's no way that dude doesn't want the
other half of the hundred or actually,
if you want to save your money, say
that you are a black guy, a black top,
but loves the fuck, but one thing he
does when he's going to respond to it,
I don't think cash is the
incentive here for this.
Find a big black guy home
drive to his house and be
like, Oh, I'm here to top you.
But first,
you know what I love most about him
is there's an unwrapped gifts, right?
There's the red bow.
Oh,
there's another light present he has left.
Oh and looks like there's another
president. It's like his birth.
You know what's inside of that present,
right? Oh, this was one present.
That's the boat of the presence.
So he's not that popular,
but you know what's inside of it, right?
A whole me now. Oh man, that whole minnow.
There's so many people that are trying
to figure it out. We do it one more time.
Just a quick reminder that the,
what's he saying? Oh, I'm here now,
homie on out hold here down all the
different groups of been a tee shirt.
Does he know this is the third tee shirt?
Yeah. Wait, I'm saying how
could you possibly probably
not send this guy a letter you have?
Well I like pull me out.
We have,
there's,
there's other people that we've featured
on this show that we've actually
contacted and offered goes, well
we'll offer it some substantial money.
Much more than a hundred dollars. No they
won't. They won't even answer us. Yeah.
Sometimes they want to answer sometimes.
Uh, what getting like, what's going on?
Wait, how many know we've had, we've
respond how much and and he was like,
go fuck yourself. No, he was
like, uh, he basically goes,
I dedicated a video to you.
Like he dedicated a video to us and
that was his response and he got
overwhelming like contact
from our listeners. Wait,
how much did you offer her, this person
and for what? What's subsist to interview?
Just in it. Just to make fun
of him on your podcast. I know.
We just wanted to interview him.
This guy on it will be a probably a
very respectful, like absolute dateline,
you know? Wait, so, uh, what did,
what did you offer that person? What's
substantial money like? Well, yeah,
like for over we're over $500 to 500.
I mean,
I'm just going to offer him
$500,000. Half a million. No,
but I mean I also was like,
or just get back to me with what you
want or can I hear it one more time?
I'm going to weigh in and finally my
final way. The final, your final version.
Okay,
here we go.
Fuck me. Piss. Somebody beat me at
home, Ya know, come see me when I come.
Come home here now.
Don't hold me on out homie on now it
sounds like it's today and try it out and
try out and wanna fuck a pitch.
Let me try it out.
She has to apply it only as fuck,
man.
I'm looking at the hardcore guys and
meaning wanting to do it and I want to
deliver it. I'm a hot swap.
My trash come down. Let's fuck
screens over here.
I don't think it's,
I'm home here now because it doesn't
fit with the theme of what he's saying.
Fuck me. Piss on me. Shit. It's like
he's like, you want to come over?
Do you want to come over? You want to
come over drugs and forgot what I forgot.
Like he's just talking gibberish. That's
a very good, that's a very good point.
I think you're right and I think you are
reluctantly being the lead detective.
Well she's got the right jacket
for it. Wait, so it's like, oh.
So he's going like fuck me, piss on
me. Like he almost is doing that.
I almost see saying hold me down. But he's
saying hold me now or whatever. Right.
It's too fucked up mess.
Right, right. Yeah.
Just got like a bottle of Tequila.
He doesn't drink
liquor bottle behind it and pull me
on y'all. Come on with me on the,
y'all holding me on the
call. Palm, Ya Know Harlem.
It's Stephen Hawking
the horn.
It's a good point.
I feel like it's hollow man out.
But you're right.
It's inconsistent with their own neonics
before calling me on that street. He's
not a street. No. I want to
tell him Natasha, before I
forget. Oh, I'm so bummed for,
I was going to do the thing for her,
but that you play drunk so well.
You're such a great actress and
every time I see you do drunk,
you think I'm really drunk. No. Yes,
yes. Like you. You see you do this in,
it's brilliant.
Where are you?
Don't overdo it like you do it the way
drug people really do it or they're
trying to hold their shit together,
which is so funny and so good.
I just wanted to tell you that I've
been to a lot of practice. Her Pr,
her drunk is amazing. So funny, Huh?
Pants less drunk on burning love is
truly one of the funniest things up.
We laugh out loud. Funniest
things I've ever seen. Right.
She's kind of like street a little
bit too. Yeah. Well she's trash.
She what she is.
She's calling me on now.
Yeah. That's so funny. And your
trash boys. Well thank you.
Tasha would make funnier ear relatives.
I love that too. I like Tata.
Thank you. My family. I'm part of,
I think what a family is here for
is to make fun of them. Yeah. Yeah.
Moshe said I could make fun. It does.
Does he care if you make fun of him? Tom,
to make fun of Tommy? I do all the
time on stage. He doesn't care.
Is there anything that's off limits?
Uh,
not yet. You got to make fun of
her. Yeah, he does all the time.
Talks about my loose
Vatche my big floppy tits.
Oh yeah. You're loose badge
and big floppy disk. It is.
Tom Tells me first. It's not like,
it's like we have a quarterly.
What's so what's your, what's your
off limits? We got no lines. No, they,
when it comes to the stage,
there's no lines for sure.
Right? Yeah, exactly. Well,
I'd like to have,
I,
I'd like him to not say negative things
about me and I'd like to say negative
things about him.
I'm sure vice versa.
But I mean what in interpersonal
communication at home
I'm brittle and I have a
hair trigger. But if she gets on
stage and makes fun of my deaf mom,
it's all good to trades or
no, no. I will say though,
the way Moshe acts with people,
with their cars and with Uber people,
he doesn't do that to me. No, that's
good. Yeah you will say that. Huh?
You will say that. Cause that's what I
coached you to say on the drive over here.
But it's what,
I don't want people to think that he
carries that into our relationship.
I know how unstable it seems.
I am.
I just have a thing about
being disrespected and it's
not good and I don't like
it that I disrespect you sometimes,
but you don't act like that. Yeah,
but it's not people that I know
disrespecting me. It's like strangers.
It's different. It's way
different. I'm getting better.
I'm a lot better than I used to be.
I believe it's called righteous anger.
That could be
right. But this is a dude
thing. Let me tell you though,
cause I know that you had fucking choke
a man out for snapping at me like that
too. I think, uh, it's just, it's like,
dude, it's testosterone. I did Tasha.
I know you're right.
And I also didn't look at it like he was
protecting me because it seemed like he
was endangering our family
because of your volume.
She was letting people know where we live.
The guy might have a gun,
like why go there?
I did analyze and uh,
I decided he did not have a gun.
I mean they were probably correct.
We're no,
remember he had like a weird pace maker,
a wire coming from his neck. I was like,
I could just grab that and
Yank, you know. And he's just,
you just unplug them.
Yeah, like commander data.
But it's also the testosterone that sent
Moshe into a rage where he thought it
was a good idea for me to climb pregnant.
Eight months pregnant into his,
the guy's front seat without
his permission. And when
Moses did it, the guy goes,
are you fucking car? But like, he was
so pissed. So it's like I almost did.
Right, but if you had done it, I
would've been back at the trunk.
I would have grabbed the whole main
out and gotten the fuck out of there.
He said, are you my fucking car
when you went to pop the trunk?
Joe, she'll get into, his
friend was all he wanted me to.
He told me eight months pregnant to,
to,
to slither my way into the guy's car.
Cause the guy was saying was holding
our luggage hostage in his trunk.
Yeah.
I love this story.
I liked the design. Are you
on? Well, here's the thing.
I definitely understand
both sides of it from him.
I definitely get as a father though,
what would you have done without a
father at this point? Yeah, that's true.
I understand you feeling like,
I feel like it's almost like a very,
very defined male female storyline
because you're, you're being,
you're being composed, you're
being rational. You're,
you're thinking ahead. Yeah.
Trying to make it go
faster. Well, annually.
Do you use our intelligence to get out
of potentially physical on the island?
Just use my brute strength,
right. Sort of gorilla,
I'm out of my driveway.
But it should be because men size each
other up right when you get into it.
Right.
Did size up this handicap 70 year old
with like an old suit on with a, you know,
elbow what he did, he really did. He did.
It was like, I could probably win this. I,
you probably wouldn't have done
that with like a guy who was like,
look like he could kick your ass.
That's the great hypocrisy of like,
I just can't stand to be disrespected
because if the motherfucker was like a
thugged out like six foot eight body
filler, I would have been like, all right,
listen man, um, uh, I'm
sorry. And anything I can do,
I don't understand the plot to
midnight cowboy. I'll tell you,
just say that the woman he yelled
at who had his car, their car,
it was like a,
I'd say 65 year old white woman would,
he told the woman you were
like, Oh, my key, your car.
Oh, you weren't there. I will.
She was. And so I felt like I could take
her, but see, that's, yeah, but that's,
we almost the only people who don't think
about who they're saying things like
that too are literally crazy people.
Right. That's why they're crazy, right?
Because they're like, yeah, I'll say
that to the fucking six, five, you know,
300 pounds. Like, yeah, dog barks like
dogs that are way bigger than you.
They don't know what they're doing. Yeah.
Yeah. So I mean, it's how you stay alive.
That's ape shit. Like literally that's
ape shit. That's what monkeys do.
So ultimately we'll get out of my little
jungle area. He helped out because,
you know, he felt threatened, uh,
disrespected and I totally agree.
I understand that you understand that.
But ultimately in this court
side, are you on, well, Hey, I,
I'm on her side as a survivor of
the feminine instinct is to be like,
let's not start some crazy shit.
Let's just go get inside. I mean,
when I'm vulnerable. Yeah. Yeah. I mean,
I,
but the thing is like,
I identify with what he thinks
because done it depends on it.
He might've done it. It
depends. It depends. I mean
I think the older I get now,
like you said, being a parent, I do think
about things like that. Like my behavior.
Um, you know, my incidents or have
gone way down, way down. I mean, right.
You got admit that you
buy people suing me.
Taking my money. Yeah, totally.
Therapy. This is therapy for us.
I love it. Oh yeah, I've been a oh
yeah. I mean I'm not like an angry dude.
I have a weird thing about strangers
disrespected. It was like a child thug
reverts back to like, I've got
a little on the streets, right?
I've got a little part of, of my
from Oakland. Where are you from?
I'm just kidding.
It's a fun area for me.
I don't mean to say you were from
the town. I'm from the town and I,
and every kid in Oakland thinks
that they're like a thug. Obviously.
I'm not an idiot.
I know what I look like.
It's not like I think I actually
strike fear, look like [inaudible].
I don't even know who he is.
A rapper too short. Anyway,
but there is a little part of me,
Natasha calls it old motion.
That's what that's her name for that
get that character. It's still there.
It's still just a little, and it doesn't
comport to who I am. I'm obviously,
I mean I get that I'm a little hipster
fob but uh, but it just comes out anyway.
And I said to Natasha and me and my
friend Jacob joke around about this,
anytime I mentioned the fact
that I grew up in Oakland,
I'm in a very bad psychic
zone and I need to like,
if I'm in conflict with a stranger
and I say, oh, I grew up in Oak,
I'm from Oakland, I got to go
like, yeah, I'm in trouble.
That's the trigger where that's how,
you know what,
I've reverted deeply into
my old persona recently.
I won't go into the whole thing.
It was too long.
But recently I was disrespected by
somebody and I had homicidal fantasies.
I was sitting there and I,
I imagined myself beating him so badly
with his head exploding against the
cement. It was very satisfying to go
there after the feeling all the rage.
But I just left. I left the situation.
I fantasize about people dying.
I don't care how they die. I just
want them out of my life. By the way,
I, the last time I got no fear, let
me go into a physical fight. Like A,
I don't know. I can't remember last
time I got in a physical fight, uh,
probably 10 years ago. That's kind of
a recent two recent two recent. Um,
but, uh, I was really ashamed of myself.
Yeah, probably. I have a whole
bit about it in my first special.
Were you working like, or like,
you know, on the road I was at,
I was at a comedy show.
It's a whole thing.
I don't want to do bits because
there's so many bits in it,
but it's a whole thing.
How it literally couldn't have been
funny or was that a Hanukkah show?
I had a drill in my hand,
like I disrespected me.
I literally threw the Dreidel at his head.
That's how the conflict began.
The traditional Jewish way to start a
fight. And we like went outside and I,
I won the fight. Uh, but, uh, you
are being hired by a comedy club.
I don't love the incredulity and
your voice. No, I always had a,
it was at a show at the Edinburgh
Castle in San Francisco. Uh,
it was like a bar show before
you were like a touring comedian.
It might've been just before I,
yeah.
It might've been just before
I was a touring comedian.
That would've gotten
back to your agent then.
Maybe it was more than 10 years ago. Maybe
it was too. Yeah, it was probably 11,
11 years ago. Yeah. Something like that.
But, uh, you guys swung on each other.
Yeah. So fun. It was a
whole thing. Where you,
so you never watched my special? No. Ouch.
Uh, there was a whole thing where like,
he was in a show who's disrespecting the
performers that used to really make me
mad when there'd be somebody disrespecting
another performer while they were on
stage.
And so he laughed and I started to
applaud when he finally left the room.
He's like being loud and obnoxious.
And then he said some shit to me through
the dre Latam classic and then he's
like, come outside. So I ran outside. I
didn't know what I was doing, but he uh,
everything, it was kind of weird actually
because he had a third friend and um,
and he, he is, it was me, the guy
and the third friend and then,
and then Brent wine, Bach top kid. Yeah,
the last person you need to lock
up your back. Let's talk some shit.
Yeah. Talks to see. Exactly. Uh,
so it was kind of weird actually because
we were going back and forth, you know,
yelling at each other and then
things are calming down a bit.
Like I got control of my
senses. I was like, look,
I'm not trying to start a conflict.
You were just being super
disrespectful in there.
Everything was kind of calming down.
And the third guy who was like playing
the mediator was like, it's all good.
Let's just calm down. All of a
sudden at the end of the whole thing,
as things were about to like be over
snatches my hat off of my head and he's
like, that's a cool hat. I mean, as
I used to say in the, in the bay,
this was a line I dropped.
I go, look, I'm not black,
but I'm black enough that if you grab my
hat off my head, we're going to fight.
And uh,
so we did,
we like ran outside and the
dude I had been training,
like doing boxing training
for like a year at that point.
And it kind of interesting. I never threw
a punch at the guy like, which has come,
I think of that as like,
maybe that's good. Like maybe
if I punched the guy, like,
I don't know, something could,
a bad could have happened.
But what ends up happening,
we started wrestling around and I like,
like kind of when a headline,
I've got him in a headlock and I like
choked him out. I literally like,
he literally tapped like, oh, and uh, and,
and at the end of it, you know, and he
goes, I go, are you done? Are you done?
And this is from the bay. I go, are
you done? Are you done? And he goes,
I'll never be done.
It's like I'm fighting a night.
I'm fighting at night from the roundtable
end. He finally, everything calmed down,
everything conflict over end of thing.
There's a whole thing where he had cut
me and also bled on me. So it was like,
I was like, and he looked in that moment
as I looked at his body, I'm like, Oh wow,
you're like,
you are a gay heroin user.
Like everything about the moment there
was blood. I was thinking to myself like,
oh my, this dude is like, was he around
the same age as you? He probably was,
but smaller. Like I hate that fucking
disrespect to the other performance man.
Almost got in a fight at the
three clubs. Yeah, totally. Yeah.
This lady was sitting in
the front and it was the,
there was two shows back back to back
shows and she was like, yeah, and like
talking over people. And I was like,
and so I was, I wasn't on that show.
So when that show ends,
people leave.
She stayed and then I went to host the
second show and she started to do it.
But because I was so worked up from
watching her, I immediately was like,
shut the fuck up. And somebody was
like, don't talk to her. Like, ah,
you're the asshole. Like,
Hey asshole, I've been here.
And she said something anyways, I call
her a cunt. [inaudible] people were like,
whoa.
And I'm definitely like,
just super, what is the
occasion? Is it, it's a showcase.
Is it a Montreal showcase?
A showcase that I'm,
I'm not showcasing,
I'm posting for them for the other
comments and I'm so mad that she's ruining
this for them. It's funny though, is
that the guy who was going on first,
I was mad at you. Like
why is he ruined it? Yeah,
I know they weren't, but then
somebody was like, some woman goes,
don't say that to her. That's my
friend. I go, that's your friend.
Then you're a cunt too.
And then people got up and left.
Then the show kind of actually
started to kind of go together.
Well the friends, the friend
who was like, that's my friend.
Her son walks in with a backpack.
Anybody who goes out with it
backpack,
that's bad news right there.
And he was like, just staring. He was
like, cut, talk to you for a second.
I was like, all right. And
I go outside. He's like,
you called my mom crying and I go,
who's your mom?
Yeah,
any points to like the friend. I go,
I didn't really, I didn't call her.
And he's like, yes you did. You
said Blah Blah Blah. He's like,
I want you to apologize to my mom.
And her mom's mom was like looking all
like up at me. Like, you know me can,
she was like, what happened?
Why were you so angry? I go,
cause your fucking friend is tea.
They're like,
well she's been drinking and this and
I go, exactly like get her outta here.
And it was, we have this whole thing
and I go, all right, I'm calling now.
I'll say this. Sorry, I said that
to your mother. I'm not sorry.
I said it to her though. [inaudible]
and they were like, okay,
fair enough. They shook on it. Yeah. And
the kid you could see like he was like,
he was so fired up that I had said that.
And then he just kind of like,
it's so funny too, cause it's
like conflict. It's so ridiculous.
It's like the guys like mad, like you said
the word to my mom. Like what? In what?
Who Cares? Really get your car
and drive away and you're right.
I have no defense other than this.
At the end of that fight,
I was like so ashamed of myself.
Like I was as I like,
the whole point of that bid is that you
can't really win a fight as an adult
because even if you win, you still feel
like a loser. You know, you're not,
you don't get that triumphant
like playground feeling anymore.
That's not available after 30.
Uh, but my friend Jessie, who,
who I grew up with,
a kid I probably got into a lot of fights
with when we were in middle school. Um,
it's like the,
at the end of the day,
like we're all a society and humanity
is real but it's also an illusion and a
mythological,
like a fake thing that we're living in.
In reality we're all like monkeys were,
were,
were Simeon with testosterone
and we're just like,
it's amazing that we don't come at like
sometimes there's just so many people
around each other that it's inevitable
and in Vr that conflict will occur
between two males and you just have
to hope that your developed enough and
enlightened enough to avoid that,
that you don't like die. Yeah. Yeah.
Just hates your mommy and Daddy.
That's probably where the rage comes
from. Do you think so? I that I don't,
I think at a certain, at a
certain point, at a certain point,
like avoiding conflict as a skill and
an unnecessary one and one that I'm
working on in a much better
at than I used to be.
But at a certain point like there is just
a, there is a, there is a testosterone,
a chemical reality that when two
males are in the same zone and they're
challenging each other, like
it's difficult for there
not to be conflict there.
It's possible to not be physical
conflict. And that's not about like, no,
that's not about your mommy and Daddy,
but your wiring,
that shit when you were
growing up and you're like,
people used to fucking get on me, dude.
Like that's like your primal, that's your,
your blueprint for the rest of your life.
That's always going to be a trigger.
You know what's really fucked up about
being good at avoiding conflict is you
don't feel like a winner.
It's not like when you walk away all peace
and love like brother, it's all good.
Like you owe your lifestyle. I'm a bitch.
I just, Oh, and if you, so if you fight,
you're an animal. If you
lose your, if you acquiesce,
you're a bit as hard to be happy.
I get that.
But I also think you can feel like the
enlightened smarter one who avoids things.
You can and you still feel embarrassed
or I still feel it. Even when I'm in La.
I recently had a conflict with it,
with a person very recently. Uh,
this isn't like a stranger person.
This is a person who was like trying
to get my goat and talking shit and I,
and he was at such a low kind of area in
his life that I could have like really
kicked a man while he
was down. Yeah. I mean,
it's very easy for Comedians to do that.
And instead via Natasha and some
other people searching, I was like,
you know what,
I'm just going to like walk away from
this and just like check out of this
interaction. And in the end I
felt like, damn man, you know,
I had all these good comebacks. So it's
like, it's hard to even feel like you win.
It's gotta be hard cause you're
close with Brent [inaudible].
They're low frequency and they're drunks
at your show. Like it's fucking drunk.
Pops off dude. I get, I see red. Like I
want to fucking kill you. Relish children.
I want to fucking kill you. Let's
say you have to remind yourself like,
this person's life is so shitty that they
started drinking at whatever time they
came to the show. They're,
you know, they're sabotaging.
That's something to remember about the
Internet too is like the people that are
in common with me on the Internet, just
everybody's upset. What does the jeans,
I know what it is. So what's
wrong mommy? No nothing.
Let's remind people that,
uh, the specialist on
Netflix, if you haven't seen,
it's fantastic.
Honeyman's standup special.
I do half hour,
most doesn't half hour and then
together we do a live couples roast.
Thank you for saying it
was good. Uh, absolutely.
And you can see them live
after an 11 day RV trip. Yeah.
Seattle, a second show has
been highlighted. Six last
six. Columbia City theater,
Moshe kasher.com. Thank you guys for
coming over today. Dude. Thank you guys.
Uh, we'll leave you with this, uh,
original mouse mom's house scat by Matt.
See. Thank you guys. We'll see you next.
[inaudible]
sweet little scanner to
do this thing called scat.
You love scattering and do this thing.
It looks scan you little scatting
and do this thing called SCAPP.
I'm scared of them.
Oh,
Scotty.
No.
Okay.
Please,
please
leave your mouth.
Your mouth.
It's terrible. Oh, wow.
That one was, that was my,
that was actually the best one yet.
That was the best one.