Well. Well, well go to your mom's house.
Christina,
can you spell that for me?
Yeah.
F F,
F.
Yeah,
like passing gas,
passing gas,
passing gas fart.
Cincinnati,
heart, heart, heart, heart, heart, heart,
heart, heart, heart, heart.
I see
the Cincinnati Fart.
Hey Jay Orlando airport sent that in.
Unbelievable.
That was so amazing.
So amazing.
And we'll have a lot more to talk
about with this and Fart. I know.
More developments. Late
breaking wind. Oh Wow.
You nailed that one. Set it up and
you just knocked it out of the park.
Geez. I know you have some special
dates. I'm so excited. Finally it's here.
I've been doing a bunch of one nighters.
You have links? I have links. Oh,
that's the best thing. I have
links@thousandranch.com. Here we go guys.
I'm coming to Seattle,
September 27th Seattle at the
Tacoma Comedy Club to come on.
Yeah, come on. Your County Club.
September 28th I am in Portland at the
Hartland Hartland at helium comedy club.
October 4th Dallas.
Tay Hos
eat my ass, my ass. Chaos at hyenas.
Comedy Club.
October 5th,
Benjamin Houston used to Euston.
Tay House at the secret groups.
Juice and honor a blue band.
Tickets are up.
The links are up now.
A thousand ranch.com gay or tickets.
Now I'm doing only one night guys.
That's it.
I got a baby I can't fuck around
for six shows. Also locally,
June 19th and it flappers
comedy club and Sperm Bank.
The five o'clock show.
I know it's weird.
June 22nd at the Improv hearing
Hollywood and oh well allowed sal later.
That's [inaudible] dot com for tickets.
Please get that shit now.
Big News jeans,
big news the first time.
She's a really hitting the road since
pushing the baby out since I'm a
person came out of my snapchat. No.
And I like this way. One night
is the way to go. I think it's,
and it's going to be all mommies. You know
how that goes. It's going to be chaos.
So much fun.
So please come out,
come out Tommy jeans this weekend.
I'm in sperm vine, California
at the Irvine Spectrum, uh,
outdoor mall.
The beautiful
Molly comedy club in sperm by California
next week,
June 16th 17th and 18th
Gasfield Tennessee,
Zany comedy club.
I will be there Asheville
throwing it around and let's see.
I got a sandy guy blow.
That's good. Yeah. That's for a while.
You can get it. San Diego, right?
That's in July 15 and 16 what
else do I have before that?
I have a west nut sack.
New York.
Is that the first time you called it that?
I don't think so.
I was the first time I've really
registered how good that is as good.
That's June 23rd 24th 25th with a
full charge will be there for that.
Nice, and then what? What? What was set
for this? I've got to get this right.
Somebody sent in.
She is inside me for Cincinnati.
Close enough.
July seven eight and nine
that's the new liberty township.
Funny Bone and then limited townships.
What else do I have? I got, oh,
Saint Louis tits is coming in
August.
That's really good. I believe that's
August, right? Yeah, the 20 no,
sorry.
July 21st 22nd 23rd St Louis tits
and then later, uh, come
fart bus Ohio. Okay. Yeah.
August 11, 12, 13. All right.
I like a Jew pork. Teddy's,
that's my one.
Caroline's
eight, nine 10 of September. And then
the Trocadero theatre in fill her up.
Delphia Pennsylvania November 18th has
been added because November 19th sold
out.
So thank you very much for this.
And when we,
when we have a question
that we need answered, is there
a way you can answer yeah, yeah,
that's blue band.
Wow.
On Mike for the moments and the many
times that we need him fucking deal.
So everything good blue band.
Yeah. Everything's great.
You feeling better now?
I am. How's your nest? Uh, healthier.
It's a or their worms there now.
Yeah.
Yeah. All right. Hey, there he goes.
There he is. Blue Band. All right. Um,
shut him off. Wow. That's how it works,
man. How was it? That's how it works.
Let me get this ready for you. Uh, all
right. Here. Let's start the show. James,
you ready? Oh, of course. Let's do it.
Yeah. Hello. Hey. Hey. Any Joss vote?
If it's what in a tunnel.
Go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Nice.
What a jerk.
That was really fucked
up. Thanks guys. Um, yeah,
that was horrible thought.
Now we have an explanation of why.
Tell what happened to, I'm not
stupid. Fool. Fool me once.
I got to do it again. Okay. It's over
now. It's over. It's over. No, no, no.
It's over. She's going to explain what
happened now. No, I promise you though.
It really is. It's over
it now. She'll tell you,
tell me if you think this is
accurate. I promise. I swear to God.
I swear on our baby's eyes and it's over.
Okay.
Just come on. Come back. Okay.
Thank you.
Alice goes blind.
Just relax.
You relax. This is terrible. What was
terrible? Whew. Okay.
Yes. Tables had, yeah.
Most of Alta Loma sock.
No hard man.
Why did she take a fucking aboriginal
Blaine to people listening?
What's going on?
This lady looks like she's on one of
those Lotto Collin local segments and
flourishing and burn. And it sounds
like Norway. As she was talking,
she, uh, she vomited, stepped off
screen for a second, just came back.
And the, uh, translation on the page,
the closed captioning says that,
that she's saying I have very
painful menstruation. Right.
And that's why she can take a painkiller
for that. You don't need to feel it.
Does it ever, is it ever painful? So
painful. Yeah. You feel like vomiting?
Absolutely. Hammy. Wow. Wow.
Yeah. Childbirth to man.
Same Shit. Different toilet.
Different toilet. Yeah. Terrible. Oh
wait, let's start over again. Sorry.
I'm skipping it. Look, I
skipped it for you. God.
I'm the best LMS show to piggy back.
Good.
Yes.
Tables had my sock.
No hard Manson
or extending, they'll count.
Voles. Smells handout.
Sharon, can you got guys
working off? It was odd to me.
So
they provide the right hit the town.
She's a pro though, isn't it? Yeah.
I mean she came back like, hey,
back at it. There was so much vomit to,
yeah, I didn't even like see how much.
Thank you. Hmm. I don't know why you
didn't watch. You haven't done that shit.
Like on the road,
the gripe had a fever of like 102 and
performed or like violent diarrhea and
then they call your name no sick.
One time I went to,
um, my doctor, our doctor, Doctor Dick,
who people know from my stand up. Yeah,
I was so sick. And he, he,
he looks, you know, doctors,
when you go with a cold, the check out
your notes, check out your ears, he goes,
woof, you got an ear infection
bad and your left ear when I go,
so what do I, what can I do? I have a Gig.
I still remember I was playing in
Indianapolis to Planar sometimes cause you
can't, you can't go. And I go, I gotta go.
Cause I used to have the mentality that
like, yeah, your health doesn't matter.
Yeah, you go right. Your show is number
one. And he's like, well I want, he goes,
I'm putting in the file that I told
you not to travel. And I go, okay,
I'm going. I go, is there anything
I can do? He goes, well, yeah.
Um,
so in your left ear,
so if you get a left window seat,
um,
when your eardrum ruptures,
it'll go all over the window.
You could do that. I got it. Thanks.
[inaudible] you asked me
what you could do. Yeah.
And then he gave me a steroid
shot, you know, it helped. It was,
now he put that in my head,
the rupturing and that whole flight,
it felt like it was building
right to the end of, yeah,
I could feel the pressure growing.
And I was like, ah, ah, ah. You know,
and then I mean I performed that week.
I couldn't hear, I couldn't hear myself.
I couldn't hear it through
the monitors and the speakers.
I remember I did radio and
when I left radio I got up.
Somebody else sat there for a segment and
he goes, uh, hey, is your hearing okay?
And I go, why? He goes, these headphones
are so fucking loud. And I go,
I can't hear shit right now.
It was
the word. Remember that weekend
I remember telling you not to go.
But that was also the,
that was also the time
where I thought if I don't,
not only why like not work again,
but I also need this money. You know,
it didn't need it bad enough.
Right.
But it was like it would
have made a difference.
Yeah. That's a time in your career. You
don't realize you can just cancel it.
Staff if you have to. You have
your second, you're dying.
I actually had to cancel one thing.
I did have a legitimate illness.
Remember a booker doubted my how
sick you were and I was like, Bro,
trust me. You don't, you don't
light heartedly cancel a week. Like
there was that flight. I puked
on the whole, the whole flight.
And then I spent the night there puking
and then flew back and then they gave me
like,
so what
going on, right? Yeah. Do you think,
yeah. Like look at my track record.
Do you think that the kind of
person that I just go like,
well that's why we're so reluctant to
cancel because these assholes do go like,
yeah, oh, come on man. Are
you really bleeding out of
your ass or what's happening?
I don't think so. You can still perform.
Come on. Monkey dance. And you're like,
no bro. Yeah, I know. Hey,
I remember the guy was like,
you cancel on me last second. I
got, I'm throwing up and shitting.
I'm on both ends. Yeah.
Puked that. Sure. Flight.
I've gotten sick in a Boca Raton. I did
the New York City Comedy Club. It used,
it's no longer there. Uh, it was a
front for something else, I'm sure.
And I had a fever of 102 and a flu and
I was like shaking and performing for a
bunch of blue hairs and I was so horrible.
What I do it like I
should've just stayed home.
I don't even know if I got there
and I was sick or what, but oh,
that's the worst man. You
can't even remember. You don't,
I'll never do that again.
So now, um, we have a blue band on Mike.
Just a little, uh, introduction
to some people listening.
Uh, I was always fascinated by the Jewish
people. They seem to be everywhere.
They have a lot of power
and influence in this world.
Although lighter skin shoes like to claim
to be white when it's convenient for
them. Jews and whites are
in fact very different.
Would it be known that blue band put
this file in our folder for this show?
This is the, this is the girl who
got kicked off of Youtube. Yeah.
For Making Hitler wasn't that bad.
Yeah. So this guy re uploaded
on it. Something from
somebody else. Yeah. Oh good.
Well let's learn more about it.
109 countries throughout history,
so they have picked up on all kinds
of various genes. In this video,
I'm going to teach you guys how to
properly identify who is of Jewish descent
because Jews particularly are so mixed.
It can be very difficult to
identify who exactly is a Jew.
I like the little girl
she is. That makes it extra
sweet the way she does it.
Do you think Ari Shaffir ears?
Aries is so fucking on point with Gigi.
I know all of these guys look like Ari.
Here's how saying here's how
Jewish looking Ari is. Yeah.
I could tell somebody, hey, meet
me at the staple center. Right.
Um,
but first meet,
I want you to get Ari and bring them
down to our seat. Right. You know,
they're like, who's that? I'd be like,
he looks real Jewish and they'd be like,
come on. And then they would walk up the
Ra and be like, I found them the course.
He's an exemplary ju. Yeah.
Not under the radar at all.
So it's just so exciting because now this
opens up Jew jokes in a whole new way
for us. Yeah, sure. I feel like we
couldn't really go far now. Yeah.
Yeah. This is a well, can we see how a
new identified you? I'm sorry. Sorry. Um,
she, uh, so anyways, this girl
has been kicked off of tragically,
tragically kicked out. Hmm. Let's see.
More Jewish. Glad somebody has, the
easier it is to spot them to successfully,
you have to examine all
of their facial features.
You have to look at their facial shape,
eyes, mouth, and listen to their voice.
People with Jewish glad always
have more than one Jewish feature.
I personally look for three
or more features to the
side. If somebody is Jewish,
three or
more. Um, one thing Jews. Oh,
nearly all Jews have naturally
curly and coarse hair.
This is due to being in a mixed with
negroid blood. No boy, more Jewish jeans.
The darker there. Harris Jewish men
tend to have chorus beards. You know,
we're about to find out.
We both have a,
what I call Ju Ju rumors.
Tumors in our family.
Yes.
We may have a Jewish blood.
So we did the DNA testing 23 and me,
it takes like six to eight weeks and
we're gonna find out 40 parties. Yes.
We both have juniors in our, do you
really have a tumor? Yeah, absolutely.
From the code of the Spanish descent
that there's, um, no Spanish too. Yes.
All right. God Sephardic, sorry guys.
I know my juice. Hello? Whatever. Um,
there's the other type
of Joe Has Siddiq nope.
Tom Ashkin. Ari. Oh,
she figured that would be your fucking
line right there. Yeah. That is a shift.
Or you're a Jew. Yeah. Um, my
mother thought she was a Jew,
so we'll see. Okay. Um, this is uh,
quite the video.
Yeah,
I think I'm pretty, yeah,
pretty full on it actually.
She has, she, she's like, I
personally like to go with three. Wow.
Oh really hate the Jews. It's so weird.
Yeah. There's a few that aren't too fun.
I never understood this one.
Uh, me too man. The other races,
it's so easy to process. Oops. But the,
what are the Jews? The don't do anything
except to be successful in proximately.
All Jews have naturally
curly and coarse hair.
She's going to read now what I just read.
I mean every other group that you spot,
you spot the hair. Yeah.
Oh my God. A classic ways.
Looking at the nose. This is so racist.
It's really that and look at her.
I liked the drawings and that
drawing looks like Ari. Yes.
One thing that kind of sweaty and
greasy cause like ori eyebrows arch.
This is not happening.
We got a lot of stories.
That's really good.
Wow. Thank you. Thank you. Blue van, Betty
free. Dan, I didn't know she was a here.
So jeans, a lot to cover
today. Two genes. Genes.
What do you have for me? You have
something, there's a lot in our world.
Where do we begin?
I mean do you want to start off with,
let's just do some
personal news first of all.
So the other day you and I,
well this was actually last night,
I was in the bathroom.
You were in the baby's room and we
both burped at the same time. Yeah.
That was really weird.
And different rooms and profit
and it just kept together. Yeah.
And I, and I asked you, I go,
what time, what does that call,
cause you famously named the double
pipe classic. Yeah, that's true.
And I know people give you credit
for that. I appreciate you.
I appreciate you for
saying that. Yeah. When,
so lovebirds burp or fart in different
rooms without seeing each other.
It's called synergy
synergy.
I feel like that is what we have.
I mean mine,
I was just walking out
of that room and then I
write yours at the same time and
we fired it at the same time too.
Unprovoked.
That's cause you have to be really
connected to somebody for that to happen.
It's like when you pick up the phone to
call someone and they're on the line,
you're like, what are you doing?
And they're like, I just fired it.
I thought about you. Yeah.
So synergy now synergy.
Neat wine is interesting too.
It led to yesterday. You,
I've never, I could, I thought
this was a magic trick.
You smelled my beard and you
nailed what I had for lunch.
But I mean to a t,
right?
So we both have our talents,
Tom. Yeah, but my beard,
so my beard normally just
smells like farts. Right?
Like whenever I eat something that
smells like garbage parts but,
but so garbage and fire,
it says accurate. Yeah, I came home.
But right now it's a little more trim
when the, the bigger it gets, the more,
obviously it's, it's really, uh,
traps, the traps things. Yeah.
So I think you go to kiss me or
something and you go, you hold my face.
You're like, you had at
first I go, that's a guest.
And you start listing the details.
You got, yeah, you had garlic chicken,
you had onions, you had
rice, black beans. I'm like,
what? And then you go and you had
planned tans. What? You nailed it.
I know. I mean that's the exact meal
ahead. I know. We went to Versailles.
A Cuban place. Yeah. And you named
everything that I ate. Thank you.
The thing is is that I, you know, I don't
know if I can do a blind smell. Yeah.
But if you give me an area, cuisine,
I can tell you which items you ate.
Uh, just off the smells.
It's unbelievable. Yeah.
The smells. Usually this,
the strongest ones are
right around your mouth.
You tend not to wipe that clean enough.
No,
I'm serious and I can really smell
what you ate. What do you mean?
I tend not to wipe out really clean.
You're not like a hygienic. What?
The person that's so wrong and misleading.
You're a liar.
I'm not hygienic. Not really. What
your beard always smells. That's life.
My beard smells like life.
It doesn't smell. I like,
I am hygenic that smells like go ma.
Meaning that he would say that it's
not true anyways. They're not anyways.
I am hygienic. Not really. Like, what
do you mean always in your beard?
Is there a product we could buy
that would get the food smells?
I think I can take a shit on your
fucking face while you're sleeping.
I think it's called soap. If you used soap
on that beard, you're such a liar. Oh,
by the way, I'd like to thank
you. I didn't get a chance
to, but thank you so much.
Uh,
you left a like a poop smear as a
bottom of the ball this morning.
Yeah.
And it was a nice surprise when I went
to go pee to look down and there was like
a layer of fresh shit.
Do you think that was,
what was that from,
do you think?
I think it's from your turn and
you didn't flush. You just left.
You left like the poop cart drove
through and left streak. Yeah.
Well that happens a lot.
It was heavy. That happens.
Okay.
Yeah. Hey, this is another clip.
I'll say different things to different
cause a different clip board. If it's,
that was not the same clip.
Uh,
that was fun.
That was fun. I enjoyed that. Very,
you know what made me laugh hard this
weekend is when you came in the room.
Yeah, you're right. I think
it's time to admit it.
You Go,
I have IBS.
Do you really? Yeah, it's been 10 years.
I've been telling you that something's
wrong, something's wrong. And you're like,
it's an, everyone has diarrhea
all day, every day. I'm
like, no, something's wrong.
It's in your act. It's in your fucking
act about how you shit. And I'm like,
do you need to go to the hospital?
That's real. Right. So what,
what's the tipping point
for you that you find
somebody else talking about it and they
were like, yeah, you know, if I eat that,
you know,
I'm going to just shit.
It's going to be pretty immediate.
And you know, I have IBS.
That's how I think every day. If I eat
that, I'm going to shit everywhere.
So magic three, three
syllables, three letters.
Yeah, I'm, so then I started to do some
research and I was like, I got this.
And then I started to Google treatments
and we started to read the things you
should eliminate and you go,
you eat all those things.
It was like chocolate, caffeine,
artificial sweeteners, carbonated drinks,
fried food, like everything that
was on there, I'd be like, yeah,
that's an Asus rotate.
Every day you wake up,
the first thing you do is throw some
sweetener and some coffee and then it's
sugar parade and then it's crap.
And then it's so does [inaudible]
all day long. Yup. Yup, Yup, Yup.
Any other buddy?
So are you going to go to Doctor Dick?
Doctor Dick? Yeah. Maybe I'm going to,
I'm going to go to this
food specialist that he,
food allergists person
that he recommended.
You're going to start,
they're going to start this.
I read somewhere that there's two blood
tests you can take that will determine
if you have IBS and then
we can medicate you.
Or maybe you could just not eat sugar
and caffeine all day every day, you know?
And there's that option.
Yeah, I mean the thing about
me is I always, I'm alert.
I would say I'm a quick learner
and something happens to me.
Not at all.
6,000 Times I'll pick up on
that, you know, and I'll be like,
I'm going to do something about
that. So that's, I finally,
I figured it out way
faster than most people.
Yeah, you're not, you know, you're
not big on cause and effect.
So now we know I'm not big on
hygiene and not big cause and effect.
It takes a while. Got It, got it.
So that was kind of neat that you finally
admitted to having a stool problem.
Yeah. Now when you, you said that
there's red in the bowl too, right?
Is there a red,
there's red.
How often? How often is there red? There
should be no red. Sometimes there's red,
like a not looking again
for me once fool me once.
Shame. Oh, not everybody for
me twice. I'm not doing it yet.
Okay. So No, I'm not, I'm not
even going to look over there.
I'm going to look at the people at home.
Watching people at home was,
there we go. Um, I'm not looking.
I know what you fucking frozen.
I didn't freeze it on anything.
Yes you did.
I can see in my peripheral vision
cause I've perfect peripheral vision is
probably on her barfing and I know that
it's not. Yes it is. No, it isn't lying.
I know you're lying because
you're laughing. You're
like blind person right now.
They're like
play the piano.
Okay. Can you please come back
to the show? I am on the show.
You can take away the still of her
barfing and then I'll return to the shell.
Not Looking. All right. Do you see how I
got you? I got it. Yeah. Are we done? Yes.
Yes.
May I bring up another item?
Another one of your
movements is,
um,
I like these notes that
I keep on our lives.
So I think we should play a game where
I smell your beard and guess what you've
eaten today. That should be a segment
on the show. I was thinking about that.
Maybe he's pretty good and you can try
to trick me. We took a shower again,
so we resumed our marital
shower takings together.
So horrible.
And you had boogers
hygienic,
everything that day.
Anyways,
we were in the shower briefly this time.
I don't make the same mistake of
showering with you the whole time.
So I was getting out and you came in
just as I was about to leave and I am
standing there and I smell what smells
like somebody just dumped an entire
container of coffee in the shower like
somebody took, I don't know what that is.
Correct.
And just it's so pungent,
like black coffee and I looked
down and your p is like Brown.
It's so thick.
Like do you think you could
drink water today, dad?
I mean you complain about dog,
but it smelled so strong.
You said that. First of all, I've
always been a big water drinker.
Oh Book Shit I have. I've always your
water now it's right behind you. Shit.
That's my one or liar.
I've always been a big water
drinker for from the day we met.
I've been somebody that has a bottle
of water on them all the time.
And since that day I thought about it
and I've been balancing water to coffee
more. You really need to. I
have been. That's my point.
Smelled exactly like fresh brewed coffee.
We should measure who drinks more
water in a day. I, I do in a second.
I think it's me more than two
to one. No, absolutely not.
I hydrate so much more.
Okay.
That doesn't mean anything
because I'm prepared for the show.
I knew I got it just means you have one
right now. Hour and a half of water.
I dehydrated and I hydrate. Same. Oh
my things, Lee, Bro. That's what I do.
Wow. That's what I do. You're going
to lie like that. That's the truth.
That's not the truth is the truth.
I drink more water than you and then I
got a backup water that I keep here just
in case the primary is not there.
Don't even drink water.
You don't even drink water.
Get your life compared to me.
You better get your life liar. You
don't drink water. Seriously. Wow.
That's how little you drank.
Okay. All right. We'll see.
Why don't we do a water
challenge? I'll fucking challenge
you right now, Bro. Okay?
Okay. Let's do this. You'll see how
much of your water hell to the, no,
seriously. Why don't you
love her? You want to,
why don't you get your own Goddamn fucking
bring one. So drink my old ass water.
He may get their fresh fresh one. Know
your why. Smells are all over. I like,
I've even wash your beard since yesterday.
Since you ate Versailles, please God,
give me the old one.
I don't trustee you steal it from me
now I have more.
You're the worst.
Stop it.
You're the baby.
No. What am I going to do for the
whole show? Have plenty of water.
You got water in your hands.
Me. That's not enough shit head.
You're the worst.
Hope your IBS gets even
crazier shit in your own beard.
So great.
I had a really interesting
question I wanted to ask too.
I never know what it is
with you. Go ahead. Okay.
I remember a long time ago,
first of all,
we haven't even played the song to let
people know that we're talking about
Brown. It's kind of, it's
a little late for that. Why
don't we save that one? Okay.
But I have a really important question I
needed to pay attention to me right now.
Really important.
So remember when I asked a long time ago,
where's this going?
How is it?
How come?
Sometimes you make yellow and then you
make brown and then there's more yellow
like yellow road.
Yeah,
I remember, but okay.
And then remember, okay,
then why is it like you can be full, like
your stomach feels full. It give either
you take your shit, right? Like
let's say you take like a hardy shit,
like a hot hardy one and
then you're hungry again.
Like how does that, that's
the question. How does this,
because what's in the condos?
There were some like,
do you think they come out faster?
No. Lynn, how are you hungry again?
Probably because if you take that
big hardy shit that you talked about,
right? One that meant that your
intestines were removing, right? Right.
So if you take that big shit,
maybe they get a little more activated.
Juices start flowing,
which kind of sends a signal to your
body that the digestive track is going.
Therefore, maybe what's in your stomach
is starting to move down and then, hey,
since this is moving, let's get
some more food in here. Okay,
so you're saying that the biggest
digestive signals to your, to your brain,
maybe your body's like you just lost
a lot of food or eat more now. Yeah,
maybe that's an interesting
theory, Dr Oz. Yeah,
but it was a really scientific questions.
Yeah.
You know how you make Brown and the yellow
and then there's more yellow and then
you know how when you take a stinky
hardy shit, then you got to eat.
But doesn't that happen to you a
lot or you eat and then, I mean,
I mean I do feel like sometimes I'm about
to eat and like I got to shit and then
I go shit. And then eating as much
more satisfying. It's the same thing.
It's not the same thing.
What I'm saying is sometimes you'll feel
like full and then I'll take a shit and
then I'll be like, dude, how did I just
get hungry again? Like I just ate? Yeah.
You know, that's one of
life's great mysteries. I,
the good thing is you put it
out there too, a lot of people,
so I'm sure we'll get some
really interesting answers. Okay.
The good thing is someone's job here
to go through those emails. Now, um,
you have an email or excuse me, a
voicemail that we should, oh my God,
this came in as we were preparing to do
this show is breaking news late breaking,
uh, [inaudible] a
friend, the Persian lady.
We call her guys please or
have, uh, our Farsi listeners.
If you could really pay
attention to this one for us,
it is the most aggressively
worried, one in 30 voicemails. Um,
here's what sound the Ma
is listening to right now.
I just tell on my main blog at Denny's,
mother fucker duals hardcore
stake course scares the bars.
Oh my God. Oh my God. What a one
month. I mean, you're from Sherry,
very up to know in Malaysia
who was Doulas Doula,
mother,
father of [inaudible] and want
to give it to you so you can,
you know, there's so
many attorneys, India,
[inaudible] acid,
[inaudible] gonna invite
kids skating side this year,
this image via.
So cons of this somewhere.
Got It.
I think there was a,
there's a lawsuit because of a bad
breakfast at Denny's or like you said,
like take like a grand slam didn't
come out yet. I'm supposed to.
Yeah I heard that too. Cause she goes,
if I can, Danny's mother fucker right
on my main blog at Denny's mud.
No, no, no. She said I got a blow job.
Yeah I do. Oh, a hanger steak.
I didn't tell him my in blog and Dennis
right course of bars. Oh my God. Am I
taking the balls? Oh my God. On my mind.
I mean
the wall,
dude.
That's it.
And this way to go back and forth on that,
the plot thickens and I mean I'm kind of
glad that day we didn't get to talk to
her and it just went to Miami
on the outer voicemail. Yeah.
Cause we can't put a stop to this.
Unreal man. This is crazy. It's getting,
the stakes are getting even higher.
Okay.
Someone needs to translate
that immediately.
We find out what [inaudible] is doing.
Yeah.
Oh Wow. Awesome. Interesting.
In my cell phone news.
I got another, um, you
know, sexting offer.
It says hi. How are you?
I just got back in town,
just looking to hang smiley face.
This is from Nate.
I remember a while back. Yeah. It
was like, Hey, what are you doing?
So let's see. I mean, I haven't answered
him and he's still persistent. Nate.
I never took up on his offer last time.
Hey. Um, you know that a bird is so
fat stuff really took off. You know,
I know he's been just getting bombarded
hammers and then I got some audio.
Uh, he's his shows back. It's coming
back. Bird the conqueror. Yeah.
So He's been doing
radio, um, and you know,
just call in and like promoting the show.
And it's a great show.
So it makes sure you record,
it's on travel channel
called a birth the conqueror.
And he does like adventurous stuff.
Guys. This who were fat guy. Shit.
So here's him on a,
I think radio maybe today.
Bert,
what's up? What's up
with you? Oh, I'm fat.
That's what you had to ask you.
Bird. Chrysler. Why are you so far?
Dude, I'm getting fat. Shamed beyond
belief. Why? What did you ever do?
You know what you guys know? She
does know Tom's a girl, right? Yes.
And Tom just as a joke said to somebody,
uh,
they was doing one of those morning
TV shows and he was like, Hey,
do me a favor in the middle.
Ask why Burt Chrysler's fat.
And the woman messed up my name and said,
why is bird Chrysler so fat?
And Tom just said some answer, but it
just went viral. And literally, I mean,
I get a hundred tweets a day. Same Burt,
why are you so fat? No, really Burt,
I have a lot of questions. Why
are you so bad? And it's so,
this is what the problem with fat shaming
is, is that when it's true, it hurts.
I mean, you should see
my Wikipedia page. He is,
he has taken it upon himself to just I,
and he find,
he called me up the other day and
he's just giggling. He's like,
have you seen what they did?
Their Wikipedia page? It
is, it is literally a page.
It says, I died. She says,
I'm allergic to giraffes,
that I enjoyed digging holes
that I'm uh, related to, uh,
the Lee Iacocca Chrysler people. And then
I changed my name because I was so fat.
It's got to stop.
And so now we have to start thinking of
something to come up with four Secura.
See the problem is that that's like,
that's like threatening to burn the devil.
He doesn't care. He loves
it. He loves it. He loves it.
He enjoys it so much. He kept laughing.
He goes here, but it isn't real. I go,
the problem was all of it is he
is 10 times fatter than I am.
He is borderline obese.
Like not even joking.
If you saw both of us naked, you wouldn't
for a second say, oh, it's a tie.
You'd be like, well Tom Ziglar has
got them by, by at least 40 pounds.
Does he have,
does he like his beard?
Like is he proud of his
beard and said this shit?
Well,
let me tell you something.
He didn't have a beard until
he saw me and I had a beard.
You got the beard idea for me to do.
You look so fat. I was like, dude,
you cover it up. If you don't have a
beard, it looks like your Chin as balls.
You've got to grow a
beard and cover that up.
Birds such a liar.
He had a beard before birth horse,
way fatter than you buy them. And
he's, the fat is comic working today
by the way. It didn't just go
viral. It went mommy. Yeah. Yeah.
I think he was BTW it went up.
They went m o m m
hello Bernd Chrysler,
the Wikipedia thing.
That is just hilarious.
I don't know who got it
into them to do that,
but it is so fucking
outrageous. Um, and find it.
He thought that, that we, I go,
we didn't ask people to do that.
People just did that. No, we don't. We
don't really encourage that either. Uh,
changing somebodies Wikipedia page.
No, no, no, no. Not at all. I mean,
we'll see if it's still, it's still
right now. Okay. It says he was born in
[inaudible] 78 in Cheyenne,
Wyoming,
and then he died today
in the coastal waters.
Off of France,
possibly from AIDS.
Okay.
He was born in Wyoming. As a kid, he
would dig out, dig for hours, each tray,
each day, the trial, the other side of the
world. Sometimes you only food. He would,
he would eat for the day.
We'll be worms from the ground.
He eventually gave up after a water spout,
the,
that dug up knock crusher out briefly.
Uh,
he has an addiction as a kid of biting
hair off his uncle's beer with his teeth
for hours,
which was cured when his uncle punch
Burton the job for two hours straight. Uh,
she wanted his crisis.
His mother wanted bird to create
clothes for Jurassic and adult.
But vert was allergic to your ass.
I don't fuck it is so fucking silly.
Um, it's, oh yeah.
And then it says that on this
podcast that we talked about him, um,
about how the Chrysler Company,
uh, you know. Gotcha. Okay.
It's really, really funny.
Well, I'm glad that it's hit.
It's hit the mainstream media now.
It's a,
it's a real thing and it's
all because of my eyes.
Yeah, it really is. You guys really,
really, really got him. Uh, wait.
Actually it surprised me. I remember we
made the thing of the plea, we're like,
hit them up with a bunch of tweets today,
but it went so much further with
the Instagram, the Facebook,
and he said that on his Facebook page,
people will be like first fucking year.
Why are you so fat? And that people that
know him will be like, hey, that's rude.
And then they'll be like, hey, fuck you.
I just want to know why he's so fast.
Oh my God. Anyways, it is
probably the best entertainer,
sportsmen fat or the new since
the beginning for years. Years.
Brian Speer much fatter. Uh,
it's because of his belly.
It's very distended and bloated.
Like an alcoholic or somebody
pointed out he looks like,
like an African child like that.
Who else looks like that?
I remember from the boyfriend
on trailer park boys. Oh yeah.
Lay, lay. Lay. He's Randy.
Yeah. Late by my friend.
It's like if six Randy's
were tied together. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah, absolutely.
Right. He's, he's a little fatter than
Randy, but yeah. That, that type of fat,
that's a booze. Fats, the
hard booze belly. Yeah. Right.
That's going to be harder for him to lose.
Right, right. Cause it's hardened. Yeah.
Visceral fat, visceral. That's the
heart attack fat, right? Yeah. Yeah.
It's what they call it. Fat. It's going
to get that anyway. No Fun. Bert. Um,
can we pause for women and I
need to go to the restroom. Okay.
You're going to shit or a p no,
I gotta fix my makeup because I cried.
You got a few announcements.
Oh, I bet. Yeah. Um,
that was really funny about
bird, by the way. When do you,
do you think he'll ever
actually lose weight? You'd
have to stop drinking, right?
Yeah. Yeah. That's not
going to happen. Um,
I want to make an announcement before
I forget the movie. I narrated.
Can we take a joke? Okay. Documentary.
The trailer is on iTunes today.
Uh, I just retweeted it
at Christina P on Twitter,
iTunes trailer.
It comes out a limited
release in movie theaters.
July 29th and then August 2nd it'll
be on iTunes for digital download.
You guys can see it then. I'm so excited.
It's such a great documentary. Yeah.
I can't wait for you guys.
See it.
Did you think you have the
right not to be offended?
Either change your
parameters would offend you,
were raw or just realize you're wrong.
I've always refused to
apologize for a joke.
There's a lot of people out there whose
job it is to be offended for other
people.
It's almost like people have gotten soft.
Yes.
Duty of a comedian to find out where
the line is drawn and deliberately cross
over.
Bye
Bye Dad.
Stage
no yard.
Easily offended.
Please don't come to a comedy show when
they start going through the comedians.
Everyone else needs to sweat.
This play was specifically designed
to offend everyone and then the I'm
offenders changes into
you're going to die.
They were calling me black Hitler
because it's the Jews weren't safe.
The blacks weren't safe.
Yeah.
Lenny Bruce, he was arrested for
what he said. I can't imagine that
there is that cool to have your show
with the cops or the side of the stage
beat that.
Anybody ever
free speech greenway important
because me being a Jew,
I don't want to have to pay for speakers
anyway. I narrated it.
Ted Balaguer directed it.
It's going to be out soon to go watch
it. That's awesome. I'm so excited.
It's such a timeline. I'm,
I'm excited to see it.
There's so much bullshit going on.
Comedians or apologizing for jokes.
It's so horrible. So
horrible. Yeah. It's um, oh,
we should, uh, by the way,
we should plug the fact that
on our youtube page every
Thursday we have classic
jeans going. Oh, right. How
exciting. They're saying, oh yeah,
we should set the set up.
The fact that Dave don't
find art on the podcast.
It's so unprofessional.
We've traveled together.
Sweeney everybody. I apologize. Listeners,
apologize. That's the first part. Did
we record this in a submarine? Why is,
this just shows you how far the shows
come. This is what is a red band.
Oh, Mommy's in Burbank.
This is not his couch.
This is before we even moved it into
red bands studio on the back of,
he says is that first one,
right? Yeah. Oh my gosh. Yeah.
So you fired on the very first episode
of Wyoming? Yeah, episode one. Wow.
How neat that do you see how
that part is the main ones?
I like you porn and stuff have made it so
that, that they work now on the iPhone.
Yeah. And stuff like that. Just
started a jerk it last week too much.
My iPhone stuff. I know and don't look, I
know people are like, oh is she going to,
this is so like tame for our
level of discourse with each other
post quite all. And he'll be
like, I gotta take a shit.
And then that's the first one. Very first
episode. You, isn't that interesting?
It's, it's same shit. Different
toilet, you know. So we're at,
we're doing is with classic jeans
were going through the catalog. Yeah.
Every Thursday a new one comes up
cause they're all the originals.
I kinda know I want to see it,
but I don't because I'm embarrassed.
And then when it got, when it hits
episode 41, it'll be audio only,
but it will be up there,
you know.
So there's gotta be some episodes
with up to $40. I have missing videos.
You have missing video?
Yeah. To make you didn't do it. So. Wow.
Did we burp on that first one? I don't
know. I don't think so. I don't know.
We'll have to watch it just,
just far. Yeah. That is special.
That is pretty special
man. Um, oh wow. Wow.
Good to see where you kept it real,
Huh? From the very, from the jump.
No, I haven't seen this, but um,
it says there's queen ass
rapper. Who's that? Yeah.
That's not her legit name. But uh, shed.
I just did audio because the video we
probably shouldn't be playing. Okay.
You just found someone submitted it,
someone submitted as like,
I think I found queen ass rapper. So
she makes, these are like self made. Um,
someone records it for her.
There's a weird porn guy that's
like prompt her and stuff.
Really interesting. Let's see what,
what was the, let's take a listen,
but I kind of,
yeah,
thank you for, it's all day.
They be coming out of my big old,
oh my gosh. More big,
hard boiled eggs today.
Oh, that'll do it. Yeah.
Yeah. Maybe that's a,
that's that's the lady for the king,
you know,
could be,
I don't think he wants to be set up.
I feel like he's just happy
living in him and his farts.
You have any cell in his food and
his Manet's yeah. This guy is,
you know,
he's not,
oh,
there's so gassy. Yeah. Yeah.
She seems like so much sweeter than him.
So much sweeter. And he's not like, Ooh,
he's, whoa. You know what I want though?
And I know it exists. I need a woman.
Cause this sounds a little fetishy
like, oh, I can't believe. Yeah,
like phony. Like I want those stinky
farts I've been doing all day long.
Give me the girl that just does
it for the love of the game,
the way the ass rapper does. See, I think
I should stop eating eggs for breakfast.
Like, no, no, no. I want someone that's
in it for the love of the FARC. Yeah,
that's good.
But better work is good little booty.
Yeah. You know when it's good. It's good.
Yeah, that's true. She's doing good work,
man. If we could see her, we could
at least identify if she was a Jew,
but let's move on to now we have
something alarming to talk about.
You're what? We're doing it. I just
had my, yeah, my stomach lurch.
Like I have something in the pit
of my stomach. It's nerve wracking.
So upset about it already.
So last week it was
obviously a huge episode.
Speaking of farts where somebody brought
into question the authenticity of this
isn't any part,
we ended up calling the hotel.
We went through this
whole ordeal with them.
Then we made an addendum that
we tacked onto the episode.
There's a video of it where we discuss
it and we break down in that moment that
we figured it out,
that we were in fact in eight oh eight
and we're so embarrassed are considered
not even doing what we're
about to do right now.
But we have to be honest with the Mommy's.
We can't, can't lie to them live a lie.
I know, I know. It is not about
lies. Talked about. We were like,
should we just let it go? And then
we decided no important Tom Board.
And we have too much respect for
you to make you believe that it's,
you know, okay to do this and it's
not. So we're going to tell you
right now, cancel your
reservations for Roommate Oh eight,
because the Cincinnati fart
happened in room six 18.
Oh my God,
I'm so ashamed. I'm so
ashamed. I'm embarrassed. Look,
this is the water gate of your mom's
house. This is a massive scandal.
But Tom and I want to come clean
with you guys because we respect you.
We respect those of you who are
making pilgrimage, uh, to your Maca,
which is the redness. It's
stolen. The Renaissance Hotel,
the Cincinnati farts still happen.
Here's, here's how we just,
the room number I'm afraid we should
have done was detective work. Obviously.
Sorry it in the moment, but here's
how we figured it out. Okay. Yeah.
Okay,
so I do see a reservation that we did
have for you in room 18 and your arrival
date was August 19th
six 15 1618 six 18
girl there though with the same name.
I just want to make sure I'm not,
because my dad also stayed
there under the name
Tom Segura. So do you
see a second? Second,
a different date of arrival?
August 21st
okay. Here's how we figured this
out. Let's walk through this.
Let's walk through this.
Okay.
The reason that the eight away wasn't
making sense to me because of the arrival
date of August 21st so I looked in
the phone August 21st was Friday,
the day of the wedding, and
I go, well, nobody came in
town the day of the wedding.
How do I know this?
Because everybody,
US and my father were at the rehearsal
dinner the day before August 20th your
honor. Right? So August 20th
that's rehearsal dinner day.
Everyone's there for that. And
I remembered that. So I go, no,
he was in town for the rehearsal dinner,
couldn't be him.
And then it hit me the wedding day,
August 21st my dad would
have checked into the hotel.
Why?
Because the days before he stayed at my
cousin's parents home with my mother in
Cincinnati, in Cincinnati, went to
the rehearsal dinner, went back,
but the wedding was closer to the hotel.
So the day of the hotel,
instead of driving back
out to the suburbs,
he checked in on August 21st stayed in
room eight Oh eight the Cincinnati fart
had to have happened in room six 18 and
I know this is mind blowing to a lot of
people. I'd honestly upset us quite a bit.
I mean we considered, I'm embarrassed,
I'm embarrassed. I know that people
have been writing reviews and,
and you know,
saying that they crawled on her hands
and knees to the room and just smelled
under the door.
But listen,
eight oh eight is not now in the,
in Diff,
in defense of room eight Oh
eight Topdog did stay there.
Yes. And here's why I made
that association with eight
Oh eight state the band.
Cause I, here's how I, anyway,
in far breaks and here's how I know I
remembered the night of the wedding.
I went home early with top dog.
And your mom, you stayed behind.
Okay. They drove me home and then
we went into the hotel in the lobby.
We went up in the elevator, they
dropped me off, walked me to my door.
That would be on the sixth floor.
And then they went back,
took the elevator the remaining way up.
So now I remember that's correct.
They were in room eight oh eight not us.
And we were in six one eight which is
my birthday. So that, the problem is,
those are two numbers that had,
and the mistake was in the early episodes,
people saying 1618 that's why it said
it's not [inaudible] it's 6.8 I mean this
is just, I'm sorry. I know
it's, it's beyond upsetting us,
but we had to tell the truth,
but did you want to keep this alive?
I can't live a live with these with our,
with our audience, with the Mommy's this,
it's too important to us.
Draw a line through it.
Six one eight draw a heart around it and
that's where it happened and that's for
sure. Now we're, we're
priests are sticking to six
one eight this is the Diane,
if you already made your reservations,
I'm sure you can cancel eight oh eight
and get transferred over to six 18 there
was sure they'll accommodate.
There was a guy that recorded
him making the reservation,
really was a good trails off at the end
of the day and then he explained to them
why he wants to stay there. No. Okay,
so Cincinnati fart and they're
like, okay, well let's amend it.
It's not 808-SIX-ONE-8618 that's a
final, final answer. Finally answer,
look, we had to come clean. Would you?
You know what? You want to live a lie? No.
Did the listeners want to live a lie?
When you go make your pilgrimage,
when you plan your summer note,
it's upsetting.
It's upsetting to a lot of you right now.
I know your summer plans just got ruined,
but I think it's better to just tell the
truth. You know? And now you know that.
Now you know what, what really
happened? It really happened. Ashamed.
I'm embarrassed.
I feel like Nixon
Watergate scandal,
the newspapers Thursday
all going to be like you thought
it was eight Oh eight wrong.
The mommies are wrong late
breaking me late. Breaking news.
That's happening now and I know it's
fine to this news is find a devastate the
mommy community,
but I feel like we can heal.
I don't even know what to do.
We're getting g all we're going to,
we're going to move on.
And I still believe we all
sell the way we believe.
Guys Hashtag we believe
Hashtag burn it's man man.
Unreal.
We're not perfect,
but we know what's important and it's
important to be honest with you. Um,
hold on. I do have one more piece
of interesting news before I forget.
We had a celebrity,
a double pipe class.
Like now a lot of you have been tweeting
us that you've had your first double
pipe class constitutes
a double five classic.
There's a lot of chatter on the Internet
about, you know, when, what, how, why.
Uh, but we got a celebrity
tweeting that, uh, the,
the singer of panic at the
disco. Yeah. Brandon a Uri.
And is that how you say his last name?
He tweeted that he had a double pipe
classic. Pretty crazy. There was a lot.
It's a famous one and there was
a lot of attention around it.
I mean, he got, wow,
I think over 5,000 likes and
a thousand retweets people.
Most of the first 50 comments or just what
his followers were. All cute girls
going like, what's that bread?
I love the socks. But then some of
them looked it up and they were like,
it's a bourbon. A fart at the same time
in case you're wondering. Yeah. Brent,
Brendan, Uri, Uri. Yeah. What
did you say? I don't know.
I'm just making sure I get the guy's name
right. [inaudible]. It's Brendon Urie
panic at the disco exclamation
mark because he's really,
he's a cute boy.
Yeah,
he's really handsome and girls will
just watch this guy chips on periscope,
the girl, some girls, not all,
not some 40 year old
married ladies with babies,
but he's really cute and that took a
lot of courage for him to come through.
It was very brave and say that's the
main thing we want to get out there.
You know, it's like coming
out as nonbinary coming out as
a double pipe. Classic
Person. Somebody else you've,
I'm going to keep mocking the
gender spectrum. The answer. Yes,
yes. Well, because that
spectrum is a little blurry.
There's a lot of dog shit bullshit blurry
because I don't know where I fucking
land on it
and I'm crazy obsessed about my rap.
I love rats more than I
love people. I do. I do
think crazy girl.
I can't live without them.
Sean top piece and breeds rabbits.
This is huffing.
Arat smells good. It smells like,
looks like you liked those too.
So you get a lot of your
two favorite things. Jesus.
I'd be terrified to be in her home.
I'm not going to lie. I don't like,
I mean I think the pet rats a little
more sterile than the oh definitely.
Definitely.
I'm not into it.
Sometimes I suffer from
G Gmr I to get more rats.
G G L N get less nauseous.
You're right though. A beard
would greatly hide. Yeah.
Oh it looks like a Louie
Anderson Right now. Baskets.
That's why he's so amazing in
that role because he's so fat.
He looks just like a, like a nice
fat lady. Like a nice older fat lady.
So good as a woman was fucking so good.
Cause it looks like bird.
If he shaved right bird
without a beard right here,
man. The Rad thing is no good
though. That's no good. You're,
you're going to definitely die alone.
Why can't tell one or two is acceptable?
I think a house fall is probably not wise.
Tall has nine 1972 bedroom.
Any animals
or children?
Each of the Ras have
different personalities.
He doesn't like the exercise.
Janice and lily is my jumper.
Sweet.
He's like our dog breeds
bothers me the most.
Janice, I'm not a fan of Janis. You have
big, this whole tale is how big that is
right away.
Like for children.
Each of the rats have different
personalities. Burger likes to eat.
Do you ever get so scared your eyes?
Water.
That's what just happened to me right now.
Can I tell you though?
I used to be afraid of them too.
And then my cousin had a pet rat
for a while and when they're,
when they're your pets,
there are a lot cleaner and
it's just like having a rabbit.
I would be in her home and just with a
golf club and just beating these rest
today in front of
her crying.
You're not jumping anymore.
That doesn't bother me as much
as the, the, uh, the terrain,
Angela people really, I, that makes
me, Matt makes my asshole pucker.
That's not as filled. And I've had
them pretty much ever since then,
I'll never be without them. And we know
both of my siblings and they were rats.
We get to know one each other.
Oh boy. Yeah. Yeah. He's
like, I like rats to, I don't,
but my fucking mom made me live with rat.
That's one of mom's crazy things. Could
you imagine having to live with that?
About bringing girls home
and tried to finger him,
whether it's fucking rats crawling all
over the place on the couch, you know,
he's like, yeah, I was
watching movie. No Lily,
don't worry about having like a Boa
constrictor or a python as a pet.
You know those people and
then they're like, whoops, the
snake God out. Yeah, no, no,
that's not it. No. Why? Why
are you doing this? Stop. Just,
there's, there's rescue centers for
a reason. Animal Wildlife Center,
and then you hear those idiots in Florida.
They get pet crocodiles in their
bathtubs and then they grow up, you know,
they caught on video that we're in that's
been in a golf course for 19 years.
Easily 500 pounds.
Man will tell you they need,
you need to take that, that gator and
put it somewhere else. It's not, okay.
Not Okay to have that.
And it's terrifying.
What do you think the deal
is with the 19 rats? I mean,
I do think people get the exotic
pet for like it's an attention.
She's the same thing as this
is filling an emotional need.
This is like a hoarder. 19 of 19
of any animals. Something wrong.
19 of a rat. Like when you get an
out of the norm pet that many times.
Yeah. You could tell someone's
got a lot of emotional.
It's like eating diapers and stuff.
It's like eating diverse. Yeah.
Do that. That's it's one of the, yeah,
eating the diaper. The eat the diaper.
Dirty diaper. Yeah. It's a
strange addiction episode. I
haven't heard that one yet.
Eat the mattress. The
mattress phone line. Yeah.
Nail Polish and then they go
what's really going on there?
Like I was abused and like, okay,
can we talk about that? Yeah.
That's what you're feeling. The whole
molest. I never dealt with it bad.
It's bad. It's bad. Yeah. I saw I was,
I think two dogs is even eccentric,
you know? It's enough. Pretty cool. Now
I'm saying came in, you want to see it?
It's been awhile. What's popping with
you? Yo You more, you more low key,
you more low key. But Yo, I
listened to your mix tapes.
You know what I'm saying? We just
out here. You know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying? God Shit
working on, you know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying?
That we can move his dirty fucking legs.
So this nice guy can have his, his
interview is nice moment. Yeah.
Stupid fucking weed socks. What
are those guys? That's a Tyler,
the creator and a what do they
golf? They go by golf though, right?
Like that's the crew would
golf Ma. Yeah. Patriot,
patriot. And by the way popping off.
Thanks everybody that signed up.
There was a bonus episode up. What does
the next one when this episode go up?
The other one we did whenever we want.
Oh really? So there'll be another one.
Let's do it next week. Cool. Next episode
comes up. Next week, bonus content.
Sign up and you get extra
your mom's house. Just extras.
It's not going to affect what we do here.
Here's a really intense,
and I mean in tents, vocal fry. How?
Boy from a man,
usually vocal fry is
more prominent in women,
young women and the car dash in effect
and Steven Seagal and Steve and C guy.
Honest,
honest.
So I got this guy,
this guy does it so intensely and for
so long, you know what I'm saying?
Hi,
I'm rob was xy car today I'd like to
introduce you to or latest humidification
device, the humor fan, the human fan.
He is our humidor air circulator.
So your first question might be,
what do I need a humidor air circulator?
And the reason for that is that humidity
actually rises and it's lighter than
air. So inside of your humidors,
especially if it's a lump,
you're wondering what's, uh,
what's so crazy about that?
It's because you might not realize it
at the time, but it's a deliberate,
it's a deliberate choice to make do that.
Your voice doesn't do that on its own.
You have to make it happen and you can
do it so much that it becomes second
nature that's actually really
harsh on your vocal cords. Yeah.
But that sounds like he's just being lazy.
Like,
maybe he doesn't want to a
nonce. Yeah. But he's actually,
yeah, it's a lazy way. This
is that because of the APP and
it wasn't,
I develop this thing and I'm proud of it.
You know,
you'd think that they would also,
humidity actually rises and it's lighter
there. Throw inside of your humidor,
especially if it's a larger humidor,
might have to have a
higher humidity level.
Uh, a more inspiring guy to
do the video for the product.
Probably insisted on doing it. He
goes, I have the best global fry.
I want to do it. Um,
what's this thing? Oh yes,
I have it queued up.
So I bought a new mic and we tested it.
Yeah.
And it's so great that
we're buying a second one.
It was too good to put on the show
today because it would have been, yeah,
it would've been one mic and then only
you sound like you're in a tin can and I
sound amazing.
So what I did was kept it that way.
I did radio a couple of
weeks ago and I remember,
and the guy was saying, oh, what do you,
what do you use for your podcast? For the,
for mic. So I told him these, sure as
I'm sevens and he goes, he goes, well,
the best ones are these Evy, uh,
Ari 20s. And I didn't really,
uh, remember entirely, I remember that
somewhere in the number was r e or,
or you know,
20.
So I just pull up the company and
they have an ar [inaudible] and an
[inaudible]. And I go, well,
which one should I get? Oh,
and then I realize I could
probably just Google, you know,
a comparison. And then I realized I
could, and then this is what I got.
It's really,
I think it's really interesting
here. I have the capsules from each,
the Ari 20 and the [inaudible],
as you can see,
they're quite different.
The Ori Three 20 uses the same capsule
designers in the already 27. Oh,
no, no, no, no, no, no.
I already 20s or external tubes and the
Ori Three twenties are integrated into
the capital structure.
I meant for a microphone comparison.
This guy says a lot of stuff that a lot
of people maybe don't understand about
Mick
cre,
20 users of standard gas magnet to
create a synergy and [inaudible] uses a
neodymium magnet to create is voltage.
So the Ori Three 20 I'm like,
well which Mike should I get?
We'll have a brighter and higher output.
The Ori 20 sensitivity is 1.5 millivolts
for Pascal and the Ori Three 20 says
2.5 millivolts and they both have
humbugging coils to eliminate emi.
Oh the already 20s is an enclosed Bob
and wire directly below the element and
the Ori three twenties isn't exposed coil
wire on the outside of the capsule and
do achieve it's brighter top in
the Ra three extra resonator dome,
which it excites me.
Shop around nine k,
just shoot me in the and what
makes the ori three towns capsule,
new diaphragm.
It's geometry and low mass,
high velocity mylar wherein
exceptionally fast I go,
I think I want to get the Ari 20 but
then transient response and vivid detail.
So those are the differences
in the capsules. Okay,
but what else does she have a close
look at? The switching differences.
This is what I wanted to,
if you already,
20 contains a dual position switch for
filtering in the left hand position.
The mic is flat from 80 Hertz up to six
k with a broad two and a half db rise
between 16 and 18 K and it's balanced
out with a minus three DB slow
80 coach down to 45
the right hand position engages a base
till curve throwing four and a half db of
attenuations see 100 hertz down to
100 so then I thought the Ori three 20
switching effectively creates two
different mics with completely different
personalities. Stop it and
presence. There's a form. Okay,
I'm going to die. That goes
on to compare on paper. Well,
I'll show you how they compare
and sound. That's what I, okay,
I've got the mic set up
and ready for comparison.
Great leg.
You think you would do this earlier?
Like we're three minutes.
I know I did actually. The guy does
a very informative video obviously,
but Jesus, when he takes that thing
apart and starts talking about it,
check a wise
and canisters and tell me
which one to buy, asshole,
asshole.
You know what I mean?
Which one's a good one to mention that
because the ori three twenties output is
hotter than the Ari 20s. I've
got the microphone preamps
balanced on the console.
So did the game. Is he talking about
he like, he's doing a good job buddy.
Good job. Yeah, it was a lot.
All right. Um, so now you know,
it was seven minutes to just tell me
which ones, you know, how are we hit? We,
we played Joey Diaz. I'm talking
about shitting in a bathtub. Yeah.
He said that the reason that he
stopped was because of his wife.
I knew it and this is,
I'm so happy to hear that.
Do that no more. That's when I was an
animal. I've done was way before the baby,
way before I got married. Yeah,
you don't Shit in the shower.
My wife caught me one time.
She caught me tossing this shit
and she goes, what was that?
It was a bit as she's quiet like,
Oh shit,
this thing flying off and it
was rolling in the air with
the scanner and it just bless it goes.
What was that like? Why that accent?
You have an accent no more. You're too
old for that shit. And that was it.
My wife gets it.
That's it. Wow. He threw a log. Yeah,
I heard it from the shower and a toilet.
Yeah,
he did you imagine me walking
in on now and just imagine what,
let like how much of a barbarian that
guy is where a regular practice for him
with this pick it up.
Woo. Yeah. Wow. Yeah.
I don't even think I can understand
that. It's a lot to understand. It is.
It is a lot to understand.
Oh man,
there's not, there's not a lot
traumatized. I know. No, no.
Um, thanks for sharing that.
I'm glad you brought that back.
I just forgotten about it. You know,
I got something else for you. Okay.
What'd you got
ladies and gentlemen?
Tom Segura master.
Wow. Challenges every week come
in. Can you do this accident?
Can you do that accent? And of
course the answer is always yes. Um,
but I wanted to see what you thought
of some of the people being pitched to
imitate. Okay. Yeah.
Diane, what is the real key
of the problem into you guys?
It means a player because I ended
up doing with the last two years
is that the guy from the blues traveler.
Remember that guy?
Know that guy?
Why did you put me into,
does it mean the party?
Because I ended up doing with the
last two years, about two years.
You have to do the laugh.
The craziest then that's fine.
But what I'm really good just sit in is
getting is for you to get to know Joe
here in the middle. Yeah. Joe was coming
up. I knew it was going to go here.
Joe Is quite the guy.
I mean I,
I was really excited
when I saw him come up.
What? What does the New York,
you have to call me too.
What it means we left
because we keep up to what
it means a lot. It was
like four teeth. He does.
I always wonder when a
guy like this did the,
when the teeth fallout,
does he just go fuck it?
Like does you think they're in the way?
Like does he think thank God, you
know, that fell off like a scab.
You're like,
Oh God damn.
But waiting for that scab to fall off
for a week because now he's got his
drinking that he's got his frequent mouth.
We're ready to go.
Yeah. Yeah. Wait, my favorite
is you do look in a mirror.
Like you know that that's hair growing
out of no's and you're a little bit about
the end of this notice it's
quite red, but Koski. Yeah.
So intense. We have a friend that has
a similar knows. He's also pretty fat.
Ooh. One to two fees. No. Three. Yeah.
Oh my God. Uh, but it's perfect.
The Straw can fit rec. Yup. Let's see.
Let's see if I can nail his accent
meet too. Let it be there.
We left because we keep up.
We really kill him with things
that we have got dealing with
cheaper then the,
then
it means that I came to the scene.
We are literally killing.
Wouldn't think
that we have got dealing with building.
Why did they cut to the sheep?
What they know English there though.
Kid exert. How are you not listening
to what he's saying? There's too much.
Listen to him. Listen in the
dirt and the sheep are running.
Listen to Joe.
No doubt.
Some
tango
tangles,
Tang buys and goes Tang,
Ambrose tangos and cranberries.
Blacks,
black fat.
Oh is he was raped or give
me a little back to him.
Yeah.
Oh No. This is going to be a hard
one. Even for the master to mimic.
Uh Oh is he the [inaudible] back to this.
Well Eileen.
Okay.
All right. Gimme gimme one way and
I'll get it. I'll get it. Yeah.
Yeah. Oh is he the rate to give me a
little back to him that this [inaudible]
[inaudible] back to, to do it. Is that it?
That was perfect. God so fucked up. Uh,
I always begin linking that back to God.
Uh Oh is he the rate
[inaudible] back to him.
This lateral Eileen.
Hi.
No, Ah, I wish we could drink cause
he backed in the womb. Now. He goes,
at least we were raped though
back then. Not, no. He said,
I wish we could drink cause it go back to
the car, drink and go back to the farm.
I waited to get drink
and go back a positive.
Oh is he was raped or give
me a little back to him.
Shaq was raped though. No, he said wow.
I squire squire back to the pose.
But he said let me translate.
Huh?
Oh is he the rate [inaudible]
I wish we could drink and it goes
back to the school. I don't know.
I wish I was raped though to
go back to the squall line.
That is not what you're
saying. Uh, I was drinking.
Drinking goes back to this.
What? I told her to shine.
Oh is he the rate or give me a little
back to him that this letter, Wiley.
This is unbelievable. What language
is this? This is what is this?
This is Gaelic or something
that was annoying.
Did you miss the Public
Mr [inaudible]?
We do because
we can and we can spin it.
Jesus.
How did you miss the Public Front on you,
Mr Pub when it burnt down? Yeah. Have
you missed the boat when it burned down?
Mr [inaudible] Campbell.
Ah.
Something tells me that when the pub
burnt down, Joe didn't not drink.
Yeah. It wasn't that no pub
equaled no drinks for Joe.
Joe was still able to find the right,
like he's pouring something.
We have to, we'll have some video of
an outlet in the lead up to speed.
Yeah. Habits everyday. Is that good?
That's perfect.
Mr [inaudible] when we have to,
we'll have some video of an outlet
because we get there. We will.
Yeah.
I mean I didn't seem that bad
to, there will
be a challenge. We can, we can spend it
and we, we got to spend
it. We got to spend it.
We got spinned it.
We got Splenda.
Maybe he's like my dad
sweetener is Splenda.
We can,
we can speed.
We got cats with SPLENDA.
Just the biggest
challenge we can spin this
been dick. All right. Why
nail down a really good,
nailed it again.
I'm like waiting for a real challenge
to kind of scare scarecrow hats.
Terrifying Tale, Huh? Ooh, God.
Imagine that guy. Just, yeah.
Now what would you rate?
I know where you're going.
Which one of those three guys?
What'd you blow? No. Have those disgusting
Irishman? No. What'd you blow it?
Him or the microphone guy.
Oh, good microphone guy. Why?
Because he's not a bloated
alcoholic piece. That might be fun.
I can't understand a word he's saying.
Is it all in the gym?
What to watch it later to off
from using people we used
to call it. I'm coming here
to have the newest depressed.
The turban.
Well, he's beer names. I can hear him.
I can not understand like American.
What is he saying? I'll tell you here.
Let's start. Let's start from here.
More fucking sheep.
Let a nightmare whether this is,
when are one,
when we told to call this,
I'm coming here.
We'll have the newsletter.
You're the worst. Every time I'm trying
to fucking do audio. You're like,
look at this. Look at this.
You're distracting. It's too
distracting. It's too good.
There's too much in this. Okay, here,
let me, let me make this easier. Okay.
But now I wanted to see the drug guys
face when he's staring at that guy talk.
It was great.
Worst.
Kim, what? What's it like to
have the pub? Did you think
it's boring?
Tell you that everybody,
the tournament in Japan won't just calm,
can move to county.
Can I please see my boyfriend again?
Yes. I miss him. I miss his drunk stairs.
That's what I'm to blame him.
Hate daggers at the guy.
I like his beard. I like
everything. I liked it. I'd be
here like that. What's that?
The traps? Yeah, those are good. Yeah.
What did you have to to live out in the
wild on the bottle and just talk to be
back.
He said it's great to be back. I
don't understand man. Oh, okay.
I never understood why they
let drunk people play darts.
That has to be the dumbest thing in the
world to put in a pub with these guys.
He was standing.
Wow.
[inaudible] see.
Got It.
There's no way.
Do you think Irish people listen
to our show and they're like,
what are these fucking American saying?
No, they think we talk like retards core.
They understand it. Yeah. Yeah.
This is like unbelievable.
Look at Joe.
Put Your eyes. I called
Joe Burton. Five years.
Five. That's, that's generous
Burton at too. Yeah. Yeah.
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. He's
going to die. Oh Man. Hmm.
What else do I have for you? I got
something else. Okay. It's the bar thing,
isn't it? No. What else do I have? No,
that's it. We got a couple of
other real quick things to do. Um,
we have a fill her up,
seal her shut coming
up and we had to do it.
Big shout out to Mike Johnson.
Mike who is actually a sh a shrimper.
He,
he works off the coast of Louisiana.
I thought you meant he likes women's toes.
He does that too.
It says that he loves women's toes and
it's because he's always around stripped
and the shrimp reminds him of the toes.
So he always is.
I'm eating shrimp and toes.
Um,
and he prefers just lemon juice and
not cocktail sauce. He says. Wow.
He's a, a, a member of the Patriot and
family. So big shout out to Mike Johnson.
The toe and shrimp eat are very,
very nice to have you on board. Um,
genes. Are you ready to play? Fill her up.
See like, yeah, let's go
shot.
Shot.
Okay.
Yeah,
I like that. Real good. So
this is a filler up, um,
that was submitted by d Joseph Mccann.
Uh, okay. Have you done a
mom? Australian filler up?
I'm pretty certain we
have a long time ago,
but he said there's such good options.
So she's everybody's favorite anti-semite.
Mel Gibson. Yup. Um,
who I thought to be clear that he was
born in the u s moved to mom's Straya live
there for a few years in his youth move
back. That's what I understand. No,
don't know. There is this super advanced
Chicco watt machine in front of me,
so I'm actually going to
look that up real quick. Um,
he doesn't represent mom's Trillia that
he was born in Peekskill New York. Oh,
okay. Then they, his folks
moved. Yeah, that's, that's what
I understood. Um, let's see.
Lucky mom's Julia is nice. Yeah. Nice
place to like, exactly what happened.
Move with his parents to Sydney
when he was 12 years old, said Nay.
The mom's trail? Yeah.
Yeah. Do you do Australia?
And that's again Bomba Mobay
so his paternal grandmother was
born in Australia to Irish parents.
Paternal grandfather was from us,
so yeah. Okay. So he went there for a
while. Let's see, when did he come back?
Oh, and then his dad basically wanted him
to go there to avoid the draft. Smart.
Good.
Yeah.
Since his net worth is $425 what the fuck?
Wow. Maltesers is that
mom's Joleon, right?
Is that your favorite actor? Mal tasers?
Lubin is they your favorite actor?
Mel Gibson? Yeah. No. Oh,
is he your second favorite actor? Nah,
I don't think he's on the top five.
Six? Yeah. Yeah. Wow. That's
your six favorite actress?
My six favorite. You
know what if that, um,
that this girl who did these,
these videos,
it's just narrow. It's just Mel
Gibson and they just put a pitch on
how to spot as you could be like, I
want to do this, how to spot at you.
And they're like, everyone is fascinated
by the Jewish people and you just,
although lighter skin smell,
Mel Gibson going when I just get Jews
are flagging guys. I said pitch it up.
All right. Get the kid to do it. This
must be somebody's a daughter, right?
I'm assuming.
Probably there's no like little kids
raging antisemetic seven year old girl,
the greatest singer songwriter
actor of all time. Russell Crowe,
but fucker Xtrordinair Hugh Jackman.
And of course,
does that mean Chris
Hemsworth? Uh, Hugh Jackman,
I guess. I don't know. Do people assume
he's in the bud fucking, he's not.
He's straight. People are
always like, yeah, big,
but because he doesn't musicals
and all that stuff. Yeah.
You can throw in Steve Erwin, Paul
Hogan, nausea wine member hand. Okay,
so let's talk about what
you do is we want to,
I think we've probably done Russell
Crowe and maybe he hasn't aged.
Well let's take your mail out of it.
He's just a port,
so I think we go Chris Hemsworth.
He's really contemporary.
You know that. His jeans? No.
Betsey's licking Fifo as Peter
Right now. That's cool. Dog Porn.
I love that stuff. Oh yeah. You're going
to want some of this right here. For sure.
Cute. I like him. He looks like
a vampire when he's long hair.
I like that.
Um, some of that hems. Wes,
how about him?
He has a brother.
He has a brother Tom Cigarettes.
Yeah, they're both accurate. Oh,
that's his brother. Okay, well
let's pull up both then. Oh,
Liam,
that's crazy that there's two pieces of
Dick like this in a family, you know.
So lackey. Yeah. Okay,
well, here you go. Um,
so let Liam looks like he
did he date Miley Cyrus?
Oh yes he did. So let's, uh,
let's look at what Liam's
done so people know.
So Liam is Australian actor played
the role of Josh Taylor. Uh,
oh, he was, he started as Gail Hawthorne
in the Hunger Games film series. Oh, okay.
Let me think. Oh yeah, yeah. Okay.
Yeah, I got it. Cute. Cute. Yeah. Okay,
so real cute. You cute dog. Um,
and then homeboy, what's the, what's
the other guy's named Chris? Chris.
Chris. It looks like they have
another brother. Really? Yeah,
but Chris that this guy's got fucking
just, just pouring out of his eyeballs.
Look at him. I know
that guy, the Avengers,
he played Thor,
a perfect getaway cabin in the woods.
Snow White and the husband Red
Dawn, right? Dawn. Yeah. Red,
red bleeding dog. Cause you get so much
pussy. You don't know what the do. Yeah,
that's him here. That's, that's this guy.
He's got a bloody dog. That's stress.
These guys both have bloody dungs now.
But I feel like a lot of people who
are into the hunger games, that's a,
that's a tough one to
shake. Right? Cause that's,
that's a really popular movie. Oh
He's got a man Bun and no blame. Yeah,
not a fan.
Well what are you feeling?
I mean they look the same. They
don't look the same. Similar.
I'm going to vote for that panic at the
disco guy. Is, is he didn't play what?
He's not on the list. He's not
Australian. Same. Okay. I see.
So this one's like Cla,
little cuter. You're cuter.
A little more Fay and
the other one's rugged.
Yeah.
That one's a little more rugged but like
rugged because he just bought fuck you
so hard that he built up a sweat.
This guy's definitely making you eat
his ass and you're never ever sang.
I don't think so.
It's always clean enough to get in there.
Now the other boy is a little more emo
and he might have to talk about feelings
with you, like write in his journal
and I dunno if want all that
come on. I like to go rugged. I'm more of
the Alpha. Personally. You are the alpha.
I mean I like an Alpha Guy Chris,
right? Yeah, yeah, yeah. He's,
he's not, you're right. He's not
going to take no for an answer.
The other one is just, he's going to talk
too much about feelings. It'll make him
all my questions. They go out the window
because he's got all the answers. Right.
I like that. Yeah. I don't have
to be like, what do I do now?
He's just going to take me by the back
of the head like 50 shades of grey.
That's Chris. He's that guy and he's
going to put you in his fuck done, Jen,
and you have to sign a contract where
you exercise. It's going to turn a week.
I just don't care.
Right Chris,
you know Luke is going to be like you
sure your eye with those and I'll be like,
dude, fucking wrap it
up. You know, let's go.
So I'm definitely going,
I guess.
I think these might be the three
brothers right here is if I end.
There's always one brother.
That's the really odd ball.
He won like two brothers got the good
looks and then that third brother,
not so much. Didn't really sucks
for him. Dribble all the way down.
I'm going Chris. Right? I'm going
Chris. Maybe we could do it three way.
Let's ask him. That'd be great. Let
us know. Fill her up. Sealers shot.
If you go to our Facebook page,
facebook.com/your mom's house podcast,
there's always a pole that links to
the filler up. Sealer shuts.
Now it's time for the ladies.
A lawsuit tale. There is,
there's Nicole Kidman.
We know that. Kate Blanchette.
Oh, I love Q love. Cate Blanchett.
Naomi watts loved Naomi Watts.
Rose Byrne. Don't know who that is.
Rebel Wilson of Wilson
Phillips of Wilson Phillips.
Here, let's show you
who's who. Who's that.
A lot of guys, honestly, and I mean a
lot like big girls too. Oh, that girl.
She's really funny. Very funny girl.
That's rebel. That's her name. Rebel.
Yeah. She was in the pitch.
Perfect movies. Bunch of movies.
She's, she works a lot. Really funny.
Let's see what Rose Byrne looks.
She's a pig. Yeah. Gross. Oh, I love her.
She's
talking about my asshole.
Yeah, she's great. She's actually
my favorite and she's been in the
neighbor's movies.
She plays Seth Rogan's wife and the
neighbors and the neighbors sequel.
She actually has really good comedic
timing. Excellent. She's really funny.
Here's some movies she's been in.
First Class, the internship I saw.
She was getting the punch. What got him
to the Greek. Yeah. Get him to the Greek.
I love that movie. That's the
kind of such an underrated comedy.
I think it was so funny. Um, and
let's see, hold on and so forth.
Is She married to spell? Oh,
she's with Bobby kind of volley. The Guy
who's, this guy is such a good actor.
You know this guy.
I did tell you my answer already.
You know this Guy
Oh yeah. Duties in a, he was in a
Jackie nurse, Jackie. Yeah, exactly.
And he's on a vinyl right now,
that HBO series. Oh, he's great.
He's a great, great. Yeah. Uh,
well here's the thing. So that,
that girl, the, the fat ones
married to him. No, that's
Jackie Queue. Right. Gotcha.
Yeah. So that's, yeah, that's her. Listen,
I can tell you straight up
now for a lesbian affair,
I can't do the big girls cause
the sweat and the smells.
But you do big boys. It's
different. Vaginas are
different. You get it, you know?
Yeah. What if she just cleans it up?
I don't know. You have to really,
really be on top of it.
Okay. I know my choice, but go ahead.
I'm Jackie who I love her. I'll
explain a little bit. Well,
I'm still a huge fan of her work and
we could talk and her coach, you know,
won't be a sweaty. That's
what I'm thinking about. If
I got it down there, sweat,
smells, things like that. See, I'm
kind of into that and I think, oh boy,
I'm going rebel all the way. A couple
of reasons though. First of all,
I really like rose. I like her work.
Yeah. But I feel like with Bobby,
see he's dropping the hammer so regularly
that her standards are real high.
You know?
I'm going to have to have like my best
day to equal maybe his worst day. Right.
You know,
and like he's really,
I think he's probably just a
savage fucking Italian pig.
So I just feel like there's
a lot to live up to rebel.
She's happy if you go like, Hey, I dropped
this on the ground. Do you want it?
But I know what you're saying. And I think
in normal world terms, that's correct.
Yeah. But she's famous. Doesn't matter.
She's just really getting a lot of
d thrown at her. Yeah, absolutely.
Famous people get way more love
thrown at them though. It's different.
It's different with women and different
with women that are overweight.
It's chick hat. Yeah. But you have to
understand there's someone for everyone.
And now with the Internet,
she can find whoever is
into her styles and types.
Listen, it's just, there's
something you don't understand. Um,
I know what's what here and I
want to pig out on her. Right.
And,
and she'll be,
she'll reciprocate so much
more because she'll be like,
oh, you're a fucking, like
a awesome looking guy.
And like you just ate my box so much.
Right. Then I didn't even pay the day,
but you don't care. And, and then
she's Australian. She's so cool.
She's going to have the best
personality. I know. She is. Yeah.
But I just feel like then I'll be like,
you know, you reminded me of this, uh,
one of these big trees and I like to
get every week that it's like this puffy
kind of pastry,
but then inside there's so much custard
and that's what I'm going to you up with
right now is all this custard and
then she'll be like, is that it?
And then we'll go for like round two
and then I'll just keep
just telling her up. Yep.
But you're saying she's custard flavor?
She was like an eclair. Yeah. Vlan.
And Yeah. Yeah. And I think I'm going
to just really, she has hardened her.
Okay. Um, anyways, I just wanted
you to know that. All right.
I just feel like you should
appreciate it a little more.
Can I have a threesome with a Jackie
Q and her husband though? God,
you're such a liar. I like him
too. I like them both, you know,
huge fan of her.
You trying to his fine.
You,
there you go. Um, yeah,
that's, that is. What else? Is
there anything else to cover?
We have, we went through and find a
shirt a lot. It was a really fun episode.
Let's see. Before we close this out, we
have to do, we have to do a shout out?
This is so ridiculous,
man.
We have to do a shout out because we
have a closing song and call it young
Patrion. Oh good. Oh my God.
Want a shout out? A few more patriotic
people. Liz Small. John Gillette,
Chris Lobb Shyer. Keno trigger. That's
what the person went by. All right. Okay.
And Jamie from Vancouver.
Thank you all very much for signing up for
Patria by Adriana.
Put that down.
So that's that fun episode.
Thank you guys for listening.
Um, blue band. Thanks for sharing
your voice with our audience.
And now here is a young Patrion,
uh,
featuring Dj dad mouth by blackout
produced by blackout or blacks out.
Remember he says this. I would like
that. Something like that. All right.
Anything else? Jeans? No
thanks for watching and
listening. Bye guys. Hey Mommy.
Linkedin is helpful.
Going to shit as big tap sent out
to everybody and stuff like that.
Bikes,
the Coney island case around
wanting to your mom's house.
Graduated from loving
to Dando running trick.
Go around the city.
Most of was a phase me
because I was 24, seven, three. Damien,
I know you're coming back with
Lance Armstrong on Monday.
I'm black. Saturday job. I stopped
trying to pass me. Get married. Fuck
fucking bodies.
Give me the ride.
Every God damn
gender being an astronaut out of space.
You never seen her fell better so fast.
You know that we
ice? No, I'm talking about, I'm saying
the
killer
Mike Braff in the drip it down top dog
or the patents in the bathroom. Now
pass the prize.
It's the chairman has does that
mother fucker Taiwan
pikes?
Thanks.