Do you need to wipe down
what's with the jeans?
Capers 32 episode nine this weekend
decided to write a song from my favorite
podcast out there called your mom's
house with Thomson Segura. Christina.
Christina are both standup comedians
and they're married and they're fucking
hilarious. So go check out their shit.
I'm at your mom's house. This shit is big.
So much. Your mom's house bringing him
at your mom's house. Don't bring anyone.
How much your moms fucking Sam at
your mom's house to your mom's house.
Where you in Argentina? Are you willing?
Dany Ag, Mike Thomas, Christina Ellison.
Fifi [inaudible] stupid like a
porn star turned to do Dj Dad.
Now rocks are crap.
Muckross to the gun up to me now.
I've been rocking with mom and he's like,
give me,
give them her and I would never
treat jeans like king asked.
Ruben Diego made as big as you where
they live in a dream to get a full up.
He's lining up to give them the sugar
cream and I just got an apartment on
Thursday late. Someone yelled, but I
heard my name. I got to thank him. Aim.
Let's be real.
I have her suck and like a succulent
Chinese meter and Christina's pot. Yes.
Unique show with her. Tom made
the baby. She's the best deep bro.
I'm at your mom's house. Your
mom's house. Who is ringing?
I'm at your mom's house. Don't bring
any one's mother. How much your moms,
your mom in a bucket. I'm at your mom's
house. Welcome. Come to your mom's house.
Take her
we'd and iced coffee.
I'm like Ted Williams
cause I got a high bun,
radio voice pleasant kind of a and part
of the muscle chart might have one.
I heard this,
my book and I was seen was above.
You get some going to fill a rubber
seal. A shot. What's the Joe Rogan ask?
What's the machine? Let's get your wife
high and tight. You know what I mean?
You know what I'm saying?
I'm so behind vocal fry.
I had a masters and sent him an x place
to make a public by Jimmy Johnson.
Sex tape was sponsored by
Squarespace to make generic problem.
A couple Twitter at cable was there.
And when does your mom's house
for more than an hour make brown,
don't wipe and go right in to shit.
Come on.
That was amazing. Amazing.
Wow. Capers. I said,
did he really has to go? Yeah.
Yeah, he totally played. Wow.
He was loud. You talk silly.
You're, yeah, that was really good.
Cavers 32,
episode nine,
you can go to wow.
Caper loose sero on Youtube.
Well done man. Really cool. Feel
honored. I do too. We really great. Yeah.
He got so many of the references.
Like
nailed it. Yeah. That was the ultimate
mommy song. Um, and he's a good rapper.
He knows how to, he has his raps. Yeah.
Uh, no. He uh, he's talented for sure. Um,
look, we're a, we're doing
this again. We'll get into
that after the break. Fuck. Uh,
I got a big announcement to
make and that is, I am coming.
Uh,
I am coming all over your
mother's fate now. I am promoting,
come on guys.
Let's grow up.
I know she is coming to Philadelphia.
Philly, fill her up, fill
her up. Delphia fart.
Ladell for Pharrell. Adele. I think
Bartlett over Adelphia was pretty good.
I'm coming on uh,
November. The what? I have the link right
here. I could just click it. Oh my God.
I'm coming. November 19th,
Saturday, November 19th,
the Trocadero theatre and Philadelphia.
It's a big deal.
Tickets are on sale today.
And the reason that the promoters put
the tickets on sale today is because it's
jeans day. Yeah. Wednesday.
They absolutely, they,
they hit me up before and they said,
we'll make the tickets go live the day
your podcast comes out. So perfect.
I think that's pretty cool.
It shows respect for the show.
Um, it's on sale now.
So if you're listening,
doors are at seven shows a seven
30, the Trocadero, uh, overnight.
Go to Thomson [inaudible] Dot Com.
A couple of other things.
If you are listening and you're in
Tacoma, no added to, come on. Yeah,
we added a late show Thursday because
all the other shows are sold out.
Oh my gosh,
that's crazy.
So we have one more show that has
tickets available. Those are going. Um,
so thank you very much. And of course
I'm coming to Seattle. People ask me,
are you going to go just to Tacoma?
No, Seattle. We'll definitely,
you only do the secondary cities? Yeah. I
don't do the big city. No major markets.
The only site
of course I'm doing it. Um,
next week. No, November,
march 17 through 19 Sacramento.
Sac Ball,
Sacramento with a big urn.
Alright.
Andy Erickson will be there. Um,
and then the end of the month,
Cleveland Steamer Hilarides
March 31st to April 2nd,
the full charge will be with me
and then sperm can Washington.
Um, that is march or April 21st
to 23rd, also Jacksonville,
Florida and Syracuse. New York. Wait a
minute. What's the one? So Jacksonville's,
yeah.
Jackerd Jackson Jackson's
Dick Jacket offs.
Annville there you go.
Yeah.
And then um, yeah, so
those are all on sale.
Tom Skerritt dotcom jeans. Well, I'm
doing a lot of stuff in la.
Um,
come see me at the comedy store on
the ninth. That's a, that's tonight,
right? As this drops. Yeah. The
ninth, 8:00 PM show comedy store.
I'm with Mary Lynn Rice Cub. Joseph
Rogan. Greg Fitzsimmons. Yeah.
Oh,
it's a fundraiser for a school.
And then on the 10th of March,
8:00 PM show ice house.
I'll be that show.
That's the 10th APM.
And then the 13th I do a 5:00 PM show
at flappers full payers comedy club.
That's a Sunday show. It
is not kid friendly, even
though it's early like that.
Don't bring your kids. And then
on the 15th I met the Brat Improv.
So come on and see me.
Eight o'clock show at the Bray Improv.
Come out and support your jeans.
She needs your help.
Come and do it and that's it.
So get your life jeans. Oh,
listen to that Steve
Bro. Um, yeah. Do that.
That's go to that. Let me doing an
episode. Check this episode out.
I put a call out to people that live off
the grid, which is kind of weird to do.
I know on a Pi Cap, but I've found people
who like live in crazy parts of Alaska.
Yes. I like to find out what that's
like. I'm very curious about that. Yeah,
right. Do you want to sit in on it? I'm
very curious about, yeah. It's so cool.
It's such a fantasy of mine.
That's it. It's, I think everybody to
a degree has that fantasy. Even not,
they don't do have it all the time,
but there's some parts of
you at some point that go,
let me get away from all of this.
And what's that like to dip it? Also,
it's really philosophical as far
as far as esophageal heartless.
Offical what's the point of being
so involved with this madness?
The Society's consumer? Yeah.
It's all consumerism and
America. It's all nonsense.
Donald Trump is going to be the president.
It's all going downhill.
I want to thank, does the
diesel for the instrumental, uh,
that he calls Spaceballs.
So thank you for submitting that.
We love your instrumentals.
We love your songs.
We're going to get into some songs,
submissions here in a little bit. Um,
these are really moving along.
Um,
can ready shit. Oh
good. Oh, what the fuck?
You got to turn that shit off.
Fuck shit
possible.
Um,
here we go.
I'm ready guys.
If you don't know which you may be
not knowing until you right now,
when I tell you,
this is our first episode with video of
what we're listening to on display for
both Christina and you, the listener.
So if you go to our youtube page,
it's youtube.com/your mom's house podcast.
Uh,
you can actually see the videos as we
play them on the show. So I thought
that's amazing.
This is a huge deal for us.
What is amazing is that you're
going to see in the moment,
but we're listening.
You love the ball by
stepping up the Yim h game.
This is a whole brand new studio,
brand new stuff,
doing this episode of second time. It's
we like to do, but the second time better,
you're going to like it.
You can practice your retard
stuff. God Damn it. Okay, well
let's open the show. Hold retired.
Hey Ty.
Okay.
Oh,
oh,
okay.
Don't bring in one love to this.
Well,
go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Oh my God.
That's really out of line.
When did you do that? When you're off?
What's that? That's an that guy's video.
You were like, no, I think it was.
It was a different thing. So really,
um, so we're back for a second time.
We should address that now. Um, people
probably don't know what that means.
What that means is we actually did this
podcast yesterday front to back over 90.
We always wipe front to back. Oh,
it's front to back over 90 minutes.
The first time ever with the Monitor.
First Time in the studio.
And one of the things we did
when we set up the studios,
we've got new microphone.
Yup.
And did I do a microphone
test? A microphone one? Yes.
That I do a microphone test. I'm
microphone to know. And what happened.
I wonder why that is.
Microphone too was, but
it's interesting now if you would ask
a psychologist why you didn't test my
microphone
July.
That's what I would say.
You didn't want me to have a
voice and that's ridiculous.
I definitely wanted you to have a voice.
It just,
it was the absolute biggest bummer.
I mean,
the worst thing is to
do work for no fucking
yes. I've done it on that Steve, Bro,
like three times where I've recorded the
entire episode and then gone back and
found that either sound studio had
fucked me. The mikes weren't working.
I've screwed up at least three or
four episodes, so I totally get it.
And we're right.
Yeah,
no,
I mean horrible.
Yeah. You know what I'm saying? Anyways,
we're back. It's going to be better.
We're getting so much better now.
That's like about our file better.
Um,
as we discussed yesterday,
one of the things that I really like
about this opening clip is that it brings
me back to childhood.
This is clearly sibling on sibling fart.
Um, it takes me back to memories
of farting on my sister. Right.
Sometimes they got me with their farts,
you know, but I don't believe that.
I don't think either of them had the same
kind of heat they had. I mean, there's,
you know, they were healthier, rancid,
but sometimes real healthy
eaters of real nasty farts too.
They definitely farted.
They forward it to mean game.
I think Maria would have worst ones.
He for sure files flat files.
She, yeah, she definitely,
oh my God, you guys are so disgusting.
Definitely drop some cars. Oh my God.
Oh my God. Seriously. Um,
so god, Oh my God. This girl though,
it's perfect. I mean, yeah, she sets,
I just respect it so much.
She says the trap,
she Bates him where she just goes,
hey ty. And he's like, what's up?
Yeah. And she rips a real, a real
daddy farther [inaudible] yeah.
And the smell. So it's hard to
get the sound down. The smell.
You understand that it had two lives,
right?
There was the initial part and then
there was that kind of backdraft. Yeah.
If you will like a fire. I mean, listen to
this whole fart. It's pretty crazy. Sure.
Really.
It really is something they tie.
I'll get his face as
he said the time.
No.
Yeah.
Okay.
They're so cute. They're cute. Uh, this,
this really went viral, this video.
Of course. It's perfect.
It's perfect. Perfect.
When I first saw this video is
probably a little over a week ago. Um,
I I saw with a few thousand views,
it was sent to us and I was like, oh,
that's cool.
It's a fart video and it's got,
well it's almost got 4 million views now.
Amaze, I mean just shows you that we're,
we're onto something with this first time
around the sun thing. Yeah, of course.
Your mom's house has always been on the
cutting edge and people are like, oh,
you know, you guys are shows
just about farts and no, no.
God who found Thursday lane? Yeah.
Your mom's house. Chaos river. Yeah.
Your mom's house. Yup. Peter
Kane. Your mom's house. Yup.
We break major stars on
their show. Yup. Okay.
You think it's America's got talent? No,
it's your mom's house. Your mom's house.
Linkedin is helpful.
Yeah.
Linkedin is helpful. Breakdown is
helpful or no? Ghana's helpful.
Nobody really uses linkedin. I don't
need the hell. I don't know. So,
um, wait, seriously. Cause I get,
I get invitations every day like so and
so wants to add you to linkedin. Yeah.
The fuck is he using it though?
Complete maniacs and assholes.
Linkedin is for nerds, man. You fuck, it's
helpful. Breakdown is helpful
and what's not? It's not.
Um, it's not, it's just not all fall off.
Um,
yeah,
and I love that it's a girl farting that's
always the breast and it's not sexual.
It's just like sexual,
you know what I'm saying?
It's not like fart on me.
Right.
It's not in the context of fetish. It's
just like a girl farting. It's still,
as much as I respect,
everybody's different,
you know, turn ons. Right.
It is crazy that that far, it's
really get people going. Sure.
Is. You know, it really is.
It really is. I know. It's just,
it's just cause it's not your lane.
It's hard to fathom. And I get it.
I mean, people don't get it. No.
I mean I get that people, that reality
that you're laying is your lane.
If something's not you and you're like,
that's fucking crazy.
But so people like fart.
It's good for it's,
man,
that's a lot of people's lanes.
It's enough people's lanes that there's
a lot of categories on the Internet.
So many. Uh, well, why? I mean a lot
of, there's whole studio's videos,
dedicated hire sites to farts.
Red Bands sent me a link of a site
that is a tube site just for farts.
He said that to you? Yes. He's like,
I know. I know. You'd appreciate,
they just like check out this park site.
Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. Of course.
Red Band knows what's up. Yeah.
We should check in by the way, a
little bit later on. I'm kicking ass.
We're bribing. Even look pretty
stuff lately. I get notified.
I don't know if you subscribe
to him on Youtube. I do.
So I get notified of any new,
Oh, I didn't know if you did.
I'm probably one of his sub
five subscribers. Sub Five.
What's that first five
subscribers? Dumb. Is that real?
I don't know.
I just said it.
He just made that up.
He made a chess to get a channel up and
I was like subscribed. Yeah. Speaking.
I have subscribed guys,
you should be subscribing to our
youtube channel right now. If you don't,
if you enjoy these videos, strive.
You know why we do behind the scenes.
We do extras.
We do unaired stuff.
Talking to my dad off the air,
but my shit didn't bother him many times.
He's told me that if you
watch that video on our,
on our page at least a thousand times,
he's told me,
never bothered me when you shit.
I'm like,
why do you keep saying he's letting you
know that he loves you? I know Ellis.
This shit doesn't bother
me. It makes me laugh. No,
this smells still is an impact though.
It's impact. It's horrendous. Yeah. Wow.
Quite smelly. Yeah. Okay. Well, yeah. Um,
speaking of it, so like my dad's ripper,
I haven't noticed any a new ones,
but let's, let's do check in.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely. I mean,
yeah, it's, let's not let that fall by
the wayside. You know what I'm saying?
Okay.
I don't want to overdo this theme,
but do you want to make your
special announcement or,
oh look,
don't you think it's time for,
you should notify people
though with an olive board,
Brown dog,
Brown drawn from coming off
for people who are like, I listen to
this show on speakers in my cubicle.
God dammit. Yeah, there's porno and
shit. Talk. Give you a little warning.
All it's kind of a late warning.
It's already started. Yeah. Um,
all right.
So this is something that
really happened and it's so,
um,
substantial,
the age substance to substantive that uh,
you know,
we're stopping the show
essentially. Yeah. All right guys.
Here goes March 3rd at 7:22 PM I,
Christina Biedrzycki had a double pipe.
Classic
[inaudible].
It's pretty amazing.
It is amazing.
You were sitting there. Describe it. Yeah.
I described the moment for
me because I was living in,
I didn't really want to say, feel it. You
know, you were holding our child. Yeah.
What a really special, more special
moment that I even recognized.
You weren't holding our child and I
was sitting only a few feet from you.
I was distracted and you said Tom and I
was like, hold on. I think it was reading,
man. I go, what? And you go,
I just had a double pipe
classic and I dropped my phone,
I dropped my phone on the
ground and I said what? I said,
what time is it? What could you
write down the time you did mark it,
you wrote the time down. I mean,
what was it like? You know,
people ask because we've had people email
about them and yeah, tweet, you know,
a guy even came up to me at a show has
girlfriend and he was like a double pipe
class, I guess week. And his girlfriend
was like, it's so disgusting.
I go, I said, that's really special
car. Yeah, it's the Halley's
comet. A body functions.
You don't cause me to have somebody who's
obviously well respected in the body
function game, you know? I mean
they happen literally once,
maybe every five years maybe. Really
they're not, they're not a common,
yeah, no. Cause you have to,
everything has to go just
right for a little bit to go
up in a little bit. Right.
Picks a path like 99% of the
time. Well, yeah, you're right.
And the reason that I happen doesn't it,
sorry to interrupt shirts and go burped,
fart or four simultaneous,
which is the hard part. Now,
luckily my anus has loosened as
I've discussed, due to childbirth.
And I think what happened was the burp
happened and usually I have more farc
control, but because I've lost
FARC control, Bam. And it happened.
And you know when you're in
the moment you're in the game,
you don't realize it until a second
later. Maybe. What I don't maybe,
I don't know. Will this be
a more common thing? Oh,
because of the pregnancy.
In which case does it count as much?
Of course it counts.
Maybe you know they're not as
genuine. That's not true. Tom,
don't you rob me of this gift.
Look, childbirth ravaged my body.
Pregnancy ravaged my body.
The one gift nature gave me
was the gift of farts. Now,
uncontrollable bowel movements
that are uncontrollable.
I'm going to enjoy this wonderful gift.
Okay. Okay. Well, you know, I'm just,
I'm just thinking out loud.
You know,
how dare you try to take the validity
of my double pipe classic from me?
Well you just brought to my
attention that things have changed.
Don't shake your head. I just feel
like dare you robbed me of my joy.
I think that it's fair to bring
it up to discuss it. That's all.
It's sort of like fuck you.
Okay. You heard what I said.
It's sorta like you kids
face is just amazing.
Maybe you could use a little
bit of a lesson. Idexx,
FedEx, Fedex. I can't,
you know it's weird.
My earphones or I can't hear that.
Is there sound in this? There is
sound. I don't hear anything Tom.
I can't hear anything in the
decks. Fedex, Fedex is what I hear.
You don't hear that you're making that up.
Only a retarded person would be like
Fedex and a retarded person saying Fedex
would make a lot more money on tour.
You know, trying to make me retarded.
It's so new.
One tour as retarded.
Tom and one is normal time and just see
what the difference in ticket sales are.
Well you know I have new agents.
That's the time to bring them new ideas.
So
sounds like you like to do a
retarded theater tour, guys.
Here's the thing.
I know you're thinking of booking
me out as this not retarded.
Stand up.
What I'm saying is let's,
let's revisit the game. Maybe I am
retarded. You know what I'm saying?
And see if a retarded comic,
you know what I'm saying?
Could bring in more ticket sales. You
feel me? You know what I'm talking about.
You know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm talking about me coming
and what do you think they would say?
They'd be like, absolutely
Mr Segura. Absolutely.
They want to commission and you're going
to make so much money as Thompson were
retarded comedian,
but you're going to make so many,
like what I'll need to do then
is establish that I'm retarded.
Like people that are coming to the
shows now know me as a not retarded guy,
so I don't want to get a new persona.
I mean, I knew name, right? No,
I think it's just the evolution.
You know? I have a solution.
It's like I'm retarded. Yeah. Lino
like Lucy Kay. His children got older.
He talked about that. He got a
divorce. He talked about that. Right?
This is just your evolution as a comedian.
How did I become retarded though?
Those natural, it's not natural.
You woke up one day retarded,
so just walk out on stage.
It's fine.
People just let Twitter. Let the
people on Twitter tell you. Oh good.
That's where I like to take my cues.
Let the Twitter people telling you how
to do it. We'll see. Let's see guys,
do you want to hear Tom Sager
retarded comedian? Just tweet at him.
Let him know that's harm cigarette.
Thanks baby.
Oh Jan was in you.
You say you go forward.
I had to show a challenge.
He's throwing down the gauntlet.
I feel like that sounds kind of retarded.
What if I walked out on stage?
Yeah,
as wrong.
He's retarded.
You know with Dany Jakks
what's her name? Danny. Danny.
That was the first obviously mentally ill
person that we've kind of poked fun at.
That's a bit of a stretch of a comment,
but, but that's what I'm saying.
I don't think
like,
I think they've all been a little and
hey, hey, hey. No Hitler.
Just wanted to tell you
that. I really do. Let me a,
yeah.
I also want to tell you that the place
where I'm actually going to poop in your
mouth is actually in your mouth.
Oh,
not actually outside of it.
Um,
and I probably might
smear it on your nose and
but see, yeah, she just said I'm going to
do it in your mouth, not outside of it.
And now she's married on your nose.
I mean like where are you pooping?
You know what I mean? It's interesting
cause they must've had a, the,
the preceding conversation where he
was like, wait a minute, do I need,
you're going to poop in my mouth
in my mouth or around my mouth?
And she's clarifying. No,
no, no. It's in your mouth.
You know what I think actually happened?
She probably told her plans of pooping.
Hmm,
I'm going to poop on his mouth to Hitler.
Oh, hello. I was like, wait a minute.
That's a main labs. Are you doing
in the mouth or on those? Very,
very important distinction.
Those are two different kinds.
He said you should make
a video where you can see
clearly where you're going to the
pope. And then she goes, thanks Hitler.
And then I made this video.
You should make a video clearly stating
you're pooping intentions. Yeah.
Why are you going to Scott the tiny
tiny acts need to know now. Ah,
for cause that is a big thing in Germany.
Yeah.
The Germans are love shine,
shine, shine, shine some pot.
So Hitler told her to do
this is what you're saying.
Yeah. He's like, he was like,
Donnie, do you want to want to
suck on these me ups of mine
on your chest, you know, stuff like this.
And since I actually love
you a lot, you know, uh,
I just want to tell you that I really
do miss you and I really do love you.
And Yeah.
Um,
hopefully if you ever need to,
uh,
I'll uh, be making more
videos. Okay. All right.
Bye.
Cheerio Darling.
You know,
it's really creepy.
Is that she only blinked once all
of the open stare the whole time.
That's hard to do. That is hard
to do. There's one, oh sorry.
I guess I caught her on.
Huh?
Your mouth?
Not Actually,
but there was a while about,
and I probably
it's way off. Sorry. Towards the end
I was like, she hasn't blinked in wow.
And you know on your face
on your chest and you know,
stuff like that.
So since I actually love you a lot and
I like that she thought of the um,
the poop as a gift. Sure. Yeah.
Right. Most people, women. Yeah.
I did want to give me a gift. Does
that what you're saying? Well,
it makes me kind of
reevaluate what gifts are.
Maybe I could give you
a poopy gift sometime.
I think you already to be kisses you
Dale. It's at your farts are, yeah,
that's kind of sweet.
But it just kind of sweet.
I like that you said this is probably
the first person with something wrong
mentally that we were making.
I just never occurred to me that a lot
of them probably something's going on.
Yeah, yeah, I think, I think so.
Um, this will be clearly, well,
somebody sent me a video to check
out this dude. His name is crazy.
Lokes mm. And uh, he's putting
it down like a beast and Walmart,
you got to check this guy out.
What's up?
How crazy lopes right here.
How many no saying yeah.
Pharrell's
God is good homie. Shit. Crazy
low Scott to Keith. Thanks.
Fruition.
How army you don't say for real style?
No. Yeah. I don't know if you
think he has mental problems. Um,
I'd say yeah. Right off the
bat you say. Yeah. Yeah.
He seems excited to be at
Walmart making a video.
So he's set up his camera on obviously
a merchandise shelf and is kind of
swaying back and forth touching his
ponytail. Yeah. Um, and he said, you know,
God is real.
You know what I'm saying?
And you can tell that he's ramping up to
something. You know, it's, it's beginning.
The wheels are just starting to turn.
I wonder why the theme of Walmart Wyant
why necessarily putting it down like a
beast and wall.
What's the Walmart connection?
There's other customers are walking by
that notice the crazy lugs is putting it
down
from now and say the n sound homie.
No salary for reals.
No.
How many shall goes out to every body
doing the buying and stuff like that.
So he shouts out,
everybody doing their
thing and stuff like that.
Literally a shout out to everybody
in humanity. The hotels. Yeah,
that's a nice shout out.
Okay.
No, straight up. No shoo. Shoo.
Let me look.
Let me give y'all a little bit of
shadow boxing for crazy loves. Whoa. No.
Say for reals though.
Okay.
Putting on a clinic. I mean, he's
giving you upper hands giving you hugs.
Jack, he's giving you this. Oh Shit.
They hit an upper cup too. Damn.
Tend to tolerate his. Tip
it down. Moving all around.
Now you'll notice he has kind of a,
a paraplegic guys gripped.
Yes. It's not normal. It's not.
It's not a normal fist. I mean, I don't
know what you know about what, not a lot,
but I do know that when you
make a fist and you punch,
it should be like right straight.
They probably not like this.
You had never hold your thumb and
not, no. Yeah. Yeah. It's very,
it's a peculiar way,
right? Oh, for sure. Yeah.
He's really, he's definitely
put it down. We go,
yes. I mean, wow.
It's intense side Walmart begging.
Well,
I'm just glad I'm not at that Walmart.
Oh yeah,
I'd get rid of May where the shoulder
row. Oh, go to the side like that.
No deal.
I would say he's not very technically
sound. No, but he has ideas.
Spa Spark
for him to win. I guess.
Mayweather's on May 2nd.
Yeah.
Boop, boop, boop, boop.
He just literally like this.
He did a straight up press,
a straight press over his head as one
of his punches. No Punch that exists.
Like it's almost like he's like a king
of Improv when it comes to punches.
I was going to say is I've never seen
a punch like that. Has He trained?
It's a good question.
I mean
it looks like the statements together.
School of Kiki punching.
Here's what amazed me.
How do you learn the sound
I was going to give y'all
no more videos but crazy.
Laos just live in like a beast.
Oh God.
Yeah,
buddy
shall goes out to everybody doing
their thing, stuff like that.
And his gang and the gang keep
every thank pushing your now,
but reels down from the
training to the rat been,
oh,
you're now,
do you sense mental illness are
not on this one? It's not right.
So one thing I noticed was
how bad his punching was.
And then this motherfucker isn't a
proper gym. He looks great. He's a,
is he a fighter? No, there's no
legitimate. No. Well then why does he,
he looks official. He now,
okay, now watch a box.
No.
Oh Geez.
Even I know that's not good for him and
I'm not a profession. I feel like what?
I don't know is this guy,
like the guy that walks a retarded
kid at the bus stop. No, God, no.
I'm saying like, is this guy being nice to
him? I think it's a mercy. You think so?
Because he's kind of, he's got the
head gear on. He's like, Oh yeah, no,
I mean look, this is, this is some
bullshit right here. Bam. It was, yeah.
I mean, what? What? You know, he's,
he's touched,
he's not touched crazy lug spars
with smooth hands coming in angles.
What,
what so bizarre.
Well,
okay, there's a lot of him fighting.
Yeah. He likes to fight Vinay.
The name of this video is crazy. Lokes
sparring with homie with a lot of heart,
which made clergy lokes hold back.
So he's saying like,
because this guy had heart, I'm not giving
him the full business right now. Crazy.
Loucks but like, this is, you know,
it's technically horrific, right? What was
he just doing right there? We see skip,
skip, skip, skipping. He's still,
but he's still, he's still more
active than Steven Seagal.
This is more than he does.
He's definitely more than he does.
Hey, definitely more than I do.
And I want to say this though.
I want to challenge crazy lokes
why I want to challenge crazy,
crazy lows. You know what I'm saying? If
we're putting it down right now, you know,
shout out to you and everybody all wow.
And stuff like that.
If you want to go into the ring with me,
I don't train. I'm not
a trained fighter. Wow.
I would love to challenge
you to a fight for charity.
We can donate it worked though.
Look at that footwork.
That's going to fuck with that for
work or that I will challenge you.
I will donate.
We can donate the money to charity
and I bet I will knock your ass out.
So it's up to you homeboy.
You just tell me where you want to meet.
Uh, what ring to go to
and what does that mean?
This is all advanced shit,
shoulder rolls and stuff.
Man. I would love for you. It's
either challenges guy or trains did.
Now I know like two or
maybe he could train you.
I will light your ass up and
I'm challenging you right now.
Just tell me when you want to do it.
Like I said, we can sell tickets,
we can give the money to charity because
I have you probably gracious dude like
that and um, you know, crazy legs. I mean
I want to, I want you to put it down.
Maybe we can do it at a Walmart.
Maybe that would be like, oh, oh shit.
Here's you at Mickey D's.
What are you doing here?
Pushing in the game and stuff like that.
We call maintain and stuff for like,
yeah, yeah, yeah. No, I'm saying yes.
Real stuff sprayed up though. Shoot.
Praise loads. Just sheer then.
Yeah, no, come speak from
our fans and stuff like that.
Do it for them cause Yabby you know,
say they look giving me to
love and I love speaking fee.
Y'All just for them,
maybe he's one of those deceptive fighters
and deceptively towns. Right, right.
You put it on a video, goes today,
shit. And then you show up at game time.
He just like pap pap pap and he's
just tagging me and I'll take the l,
I'll take the l if I have to,
I will.
But I'm just putting it out there
that I think it would be good.
You know what I'm saying?
Stuff like that for us to do it.
So why not reach out people?
I can't believe it.
Have you listened to the show? Hit up
crazy. Lokes uh, if you don't know,
his youtube channel is crazy.
Lokes
a, l, l, O, c s
and crazy as ca c r a,Z ,
I. E. Crazy loans. Yeah.
So Tom Segura throwing down
the gauntlet to crazy low,
cause you know what I'm saying? Yep. We
represent all the homies doing your stuff,
which just goes to show how
empty those phrases are. Yeah.
They don't mean anything.
Shout out and homeys doing your thing.
What the fuck are you talking about?
This guy doesn't know what with your
nonsense. Yeah. It's all rambling.
Nonsensical motherfucker. This is a
whole new, you know what I'm saying?
I feel like crazy. Lokes
has his own lane. Yes.
The crazy looks.
You know what I'm saying?
Speaking of fighting by the way,
um, last week I played for you.
I'm living or whatever the fuck I want.
Life kind of Mcgregor,
he lost,
he lost over the weekend.
It was a huge upset.
Um,
Nate Diaz took the
fight on 10 days notice.
Beat Conor McGregor for the first loss
and then Holly Holm who knocked out your
home girl Ronda Rousey.
She was choked unconscious,
uh, by uh, Misha Tate. So two
huge upsets on the same card.
If you had bet a hundred dollar parlay
that Misha Tate and Nate Diaz would win,
you would have won a little over $1,400
at most last Vegas betting houses.
Pretty good stuff.
No,
you know, I love Rhonda Rousey.
I just think she's wonderful.
She's a real nice lady. I really like, uh,
I like to see her when I hope
she challenges that lady again.
Yeah. Well I think what will happen
is I think the UFC, you know,
they don't want to waste time
making money. So I think, right.
I think with Misha being the new
champ and Rhonda still being every,
you know, a lot of people, so
they want to see what's up.
I think they're gonna put
those two together. Good. I
had a big fight coming up.
What,
what just fight was that,
was that one 96 or for out to
forget that it was one 96. Right.
So maybe that like the big 200, something
like that. Maybe. I don't know. Hmm.
I would imagine that
that's what they're gonna
oh, that's exciting. Oh Wow. Crazy.
Lokes there we go. Front of new, uh,
you know, saying stuff like that.
Nonsense.
I'll show you this for a while.
Um,
okay. Oh, um, oh, is this, well, there's
some other stuff on the right there.
We probably can't.
Hi. I'm, Oh yeah.
And I'm here to fail at.
This is such a beautiful villa.
We seeding with the first time of my
ever experience in my life with the two
young men and they had
big car to offer me.
This villa is really quaint place.
It's very quaint.
So it's important that we
know the quaintness of the
villa where she's getting
random by two guys.
Can I tell you what I do love about Kenai?
Yes. Positive. Always
looking on the bright side.
She's not, you know what I
mean? The villas. Beautiful
looker. Yeah, no, I'm smoking.
I looked up some stuff by the way,
because last week we were
talking about what's the story
Ameren and ideal theory.
My theory was that she used to be maybe
heavily pursued and that maybe now
she wants a little charge in her life,
a little bit venture because she's
getting older and she's like, well,
I probably still have a few years
left where I'm holding it together.
Might as well just go all out. Um, and
then I found this interview. This is a,
another interview with her. And uh, we,
we learned a little bit about her in this,
so I pulled it up to this
moment, her backstory. A
little bit. A little bit. Yeah.
I got to say, look at her
tits. Her body's amazing.
She's 61 years old. It's incredible.
She looks better than her abs.
Crazy. Jesus. These Asian
ladies, I tell you, they hold
together. Well, white ladies,
we fall apart. Yeah. Fuck
white ladies. It's true.
We hit the wall 40 the wall fucking
white ladies are sogging wrinkles.
Here we go. Damn. So
what Kim is here. Oh God.
I'm pulling all the way from the
Midwest, right? Yes. By the way, the guy,
the guy that does this in every porn, the
interview guy, they're always the worst.
You can imagine what creeps
they are by their voice. Well,
and they're always kind
of shitting on the girls.
There's always a tone of like you stupid
bitch instead of being like, no, no, no,
you should be nice to her. She's making
sure you have a fucking Gig. Retard.
Be Nice. Why do you have to demean
them? I know you also try out.
They do like a lot of dad jokes,
like boner jokes
with her husband. She's here with her
husband after how many years? Five years.
Five years. Five years. Your
husband watching you have sex,
is that common?
Unusual because it's the first time
it's ever happened or have a hand. Uh,
this is, I feel like it sounds like
Baba booey. Oh, right. The guy.
I got a picture of him.
This is the pre interview shit that
he got nervous and Horny and weird.
And of course it's my first time
that my husband absorb what?
Observed doing what you're doing,
what you're doing,
what you do and gross.
I feel that for him is
really exciting for me.
I feel that is maybe I'm
testing my own strength.
Testing your own strength.
What can I do?
Did you enjoy it while you were doing
testing the strength of asshole?
Yeah. Yes. Sorry,
I didn't know you guys
and said, okay. Yes,
but um, she's really mad. A Ding
Dong. This chick is smarter. Yeah.
She's not your average porno girl. Like,
look how thoughtful her answers are. Well,
she's lived a full life to a four rife.
Yeah.
Nine inches. Press.
What is wrong with you?
That's not what she said.
Hear her saying no, no.
I'm going to pull that up in a moment.
Prove that you're wrong. It's so horrible.
It's very bright. She's brighter than
the asshole interviewing her. Oh,
without she could fucking
school that guy. Yeah. Yeah,
absolutely.
Okay.
Um,
what are you good at it?
Um, I'm not sure. I think very honest.
She's so thoughtful.
Yeah. I think someone,
other people have to be the
judge of that while I'm doing it.
I feel super good. Yeah. And that's,
that's what everybody's kept on asking me.
How are you doing?
I was an answer up there.
Don't hear yet. Orchard is a sure way
to know if you're doing it right. Okay.
At the end of your scene with the guy,
did he come?
Yes, you did it.
Congratulations. You succeeded.
Wow.
Okay.
At the end and each column I fixed score.
We can tell the guys that you are how old?
I'm 61 days from now
60. When you look spectacular,
spectacular. Have you always been that
asshole looks nice. Selfie, Suede
or on monster. What happens?
You can tell he has 10th degree dad mouth.
You can hear the sadness
in his voice. I agree. God.
A real rock and body and you made
him come real hard. First of all,
like making a guy come.
Is that big of a deal
at the end of it?
Stupid.
A few of that.
I always be as such and yeah.
Um, so now to prove to, you know, like
her even more now she's the master.
Wonderful Lady came in. Uh, whoops.
I was truly amazed. This is the, this
yeah, it's really, really
comfortable with a lot of articles,
a lot of artifacts.
I feel really,
really comfortable of being outside
and especially with the two especially
really treat me very special.
Oh,
she thinks that's like ultimate goal
is to really get them to be really,
really hot and feel that me
[inaudible] have a lot to offer.
You
do girl, you do. I look at
her positive self esteem.
This girl was like the Aristotle of four.
Now some reasonable video though.
I just feel like I'm talking
to my friend's aunt, you know,
like it's not that I feel like,
oh, you're not attractive.
It's just that she just feels,
you know, maternal. Yeah, she is.
She's all right grandma.
Like right here. If you go
like, okay, I'm a bit
cheeky and you go, Whoa,
Nice Lady,
you know,
and I feel really satisfied with my whole
body being caressed and you're like,
wait,
will you being um,
chemist and save beautiful words.
Think they did all that to her?
I don't think that a touch. Yeah.
And I feel very,
very excited if we could just really
unexpected, we can't show it on youtube,
but I feel like happy if we
could splice in the actual scene.
Really us. It's not that what
she's describing because at all
the physical innovate I feel that
they have, we'll really big hawk.
I'm nine and a half inches and pause.
Okay.
Fry's FRY's.
Never expect,
expect to have sent to um,
beautiful experience plus
a beautiful experience.
I was so hot for them,
especially on the scene that they put
their hard cock even to my asshole.
Yeah.
It's so amazing.
This is like,
especially like just on the sprayer.
Dave put that hard cock into my asshole.
Sure, sure. This pleading. Yeah. Yeah.
She's so into it. Yeah. This
lady is just us. She's amazing.
Plus she said right there,
the physical innovator prize.
Really big topic.
Nine and a half inches and plus,
no, she doesn't say it
cause I have to express.
All right. Maybe you need to get these
switched out because I'm hearing press.
You're so mean. He a nine. She's so
earnest. Yeah. That's what he is,
is earnest. It's, I've never
seen a porn star be earnest.
Well, let's see how sweet.
You're right.
You're
not gentlemen and they're not being nice.
Being Nice.
I hate when they fingered so aggressively
like, but no one's no one's one.
Whoops.
This is just a her,
she was screaming, man,
that's going on cheese with animals,
animals,
animals. Is Roy just animals. We're
all animals. You know, I can talk.
I think she's really going after her.
Um,
most repressed feelings for 50 years.
If he's 67 years old
and she's taking a car,
can shout and get against her as another
guy rails or she's been holding on to
sup, man. She's been
making up for lost time.
Do you think she was held
as like a slave in a Thai
kingdom? I don't know man.
Maybe she was a slave.
She hasn't been around
gentlemen like that.
Maybe she has been working on at the
time massage place for 20 press years.
Sleeping on a cot in the back,
microwaving her smelly food.
Third where you walk in and you're like,
it doesn't really smell like eucalyptus.
Also smell like yellow curry
all the time.
It's a smell like their lunches and
then maybe it's 20 years of her going
mapquest show and feel the most
pressure and she got sick of it.
Yeah. Maybe man. Maybe
as she realized after
20 plus years,
you know,
20 competitors come out as polyamorous
and now I'm excited to share that I'm
bisexual.
I'm excited to share that makes
I'm Paula and I'm by, yeah,
maybe that's what you said was one
of my favorites and a good moment.
Bye Buddy. Dead Buddy. Hey,
you got to tell you something.
I'm Paula and I'm bi.
I'm poly and I'm by, Oh, I don't
have the part where he goes,
all right.
If I told that to my dad,
he would not ready.
No clue what Holly. Yeah, but
he knows. He doesn't know by,
he knows ACDC.
That's how his people his age and
European say ACDC means Pauley and bye,
bye. But he doesn't know. I don't
think he knows by then he would know.
He think he got, oh
yeah. That's interesting.
Okay. Like he wouldn't be like
supportive. Oh yeah. It's fucking weird.
We wrote to Dr. Took out
your head a little new gay.
That's my favorite is the old school
thing of somebody saying something and
someone goes, Mary's going to talk to
somebody like that. It couldn't be real.
It's gotta be something's wrong
with you. Fixed yourself. Yeah,
that's true. Yeah. They
just see it as wrong.
Ah,
so low all I pulled this up because
this guy has the same name as our son.
Now
I was sent this,
I liked that the video is called, uh Oh,
this is, no, this is the wrong thing.
Actually.
This is the remix.
Oh Geez. It's going to be a good
one. There's already a remix.
So this is Ellis lengths are a few,
I guess there's a few years ago at
a post game press conference and a,
he's tripping out man. That's, I
don't know why that makes me laugh,
but I'm just tripping out.
Right?
Quarterback the Rockies drafted
in the seventh round it.
So they're asking
like,
like, like, like, like, um,
I was like, um, like
I was on just on like,
I was just reading and writing.
What happened?
What happened there you think?
I think he's nervous. I think it's,
I think he's nervous. You know,
like these guys are not public
speakers. He's it. He's an athlete.
True. And I actually support that
100%. That idea that you, you know,
if somebody's,
um,
underwhelms you at their communication
skills and their job is something else,
it's not your Jack. It's
not getting job, sweetie.
Yeah, it's really not. It's not, but
they should. But that being said,
the other guys on the team know like,
Hey Ellis, not so good on the mic.
So maybe we should, maybe we shouldn't
let this guy talk for the day.
Every one of these teams, by
the way, has a PR person. Sure.
They know everybody's strengths,
they know everything.
They know that Ellis on the
mic is going to be a problem.
So like if Brah Brah Hey,
you got to put Ellis in front of a Mike,
you want to talk some shit that's
going to go down. Okay. Because
Ellis Ellis man, you like, um, like
if were you like if you would be like,
Oh,
if you put Ellis on the mic,
like I'm just going to go poorly man.
I worked with a guy that had
that same thing like little
tick. He'd be like, like,
like, like let Christina you want me
to like lately like upload a Lego Lego.
Do you think that this is a tick?
Is that what it is?
Yeah. At some kind of nervous tick. Sure.
It's like saying like the
way you say in California,
I. Dot. I got a problem with
like, I probably lag tool.
You know what I'm saying?
Shit. I would say that to everybody.
Filming. I have a like problem,
but nothing like has like, I'm
problem Lego. I'm like, um,
like, um, lag, lag, lag. I'm like,
so do you think,
uh,
would this constitute us making fun
of somebody with a problem like that?
He's not touched. I don't
think he's special. No. No.
I think he's nervous and he doesn't know
what the fuck to say. Yeah. It happens.
Yeah. It's a gluten thing.
You know, Mike's on him. He's,
do you think this guy has a problem?
I'm a Martian.
This does our URL like guys
are, well, here's our mom. Mom.
Yeah.
Now that guy,
but he has something going
on. But then yeah, Ellis like,
oh wow. Like, um, I was like, um,
like I'm, I'm just on my own.
I was just reading it right.
I was on and I'll read it on
my man or whatever. Any hail
camp.
What else on a mic man?
[inaudible] by Amy.
Maybe Ellison speaks into halo and it,
and picked it out there. Okay.
You're driving it. Yes sir.
Maybe he should just do yes or no answers.
Correct. He's nailed that twice, right?
He did. On the partners on the positive
side. Ellis, you can answer yes and no.
Pretty much say yes sir. Knocked
that shit out of the park, man.
Just all the other words aren't
really working. I just remember two,
we also found Auntie Fifi
remember her? Yeah. Oh yeah. Um,
an angel's fellatio secrets. Yup.
We brought her to angel's, ours.
A auntie Fifi was, she sings. There's
two, there's Auntie fee, I think,
who does the baking.
We're talking about on the fee fee fee.
Who's the religious lady from Texas soon?
Things that don't even always add up.
We haven't checked in with her lately
and I've looked on her Facebook.
I didn't see any new video,
so she may have stopped doing the,
the music like today. I was
thinking, Oh man, Dan. Oh
yeah. Yeah, a little out there.
She's uh, she's great. Um,
but this one we all bleed.
Yeah. Um, let's see if he
can do the second question.
Oh, Christ, you got to pick
up ice tripping out. Right.
Trip it out.
That's so funny.
Just dismissing that. Like
was he's bugging out, right?
Moscow like,
uh,
like I just didn't work at Holiday Inn
all been praying and stuff and it's um,
and his own coming to you thinking you
were getting it to the end down on.
You didn't want to know. What were
you, I was trying, I was trying to use,
yeah, no, he's good. Oh, I
know him. He's our eyes shut.
We, since the emergency outside,
try to make it early and,
and Jean and that. I was like, Oh shit.
She called the seven round cakes.
I like,
oh, what tripped him up. What do you, what
do you think sends him into the spiral?
Um, it's just wanting to, to, you know,
where is it here? Just wanting to, to
Rena,
right.
People saying, what's the sound
like he knows what he's saying.
Knows that he's in front of people. Yeah.
Just nervous about it. And then his, like,
I'm thinking over here.
Yes.
How can I go home?
This is a new thing. Or
from like, I'm recording.
I'll put the house on
that microphone long.
He's got like a western, some
western European. Yeah, he is.
He's probably got Austrian
or Dutch. Yep. I see that.
This reminds me,
this reminds me of Rodman when
he was in North Korea. Oh my God.
He was given the press and
while, while watch this, yeah.
And the whole team was like, dude,
could you fucking dial it back?
Yeah.
Don't let Donald
that the interview, I'll, I'll,
I'll, I'll watch this bullshit.
Yeah. He, um, that was
definitely not his best day. Um,
so speaking of, uh, the king of Improv,
there's a new,
mmm.
Steven Sea Gal.
Where is it? Here? Yes.
Trailer. Yeah. Oh, you're kidding. No.
Didn't we just see it a
new Steven Seagal trailer?
The answer to that would be
yes,
but
I mean
I am the king of him province naturally
natural is such a piece of shit that I'm
about to show you.
And again, if you're listening to the
show, I encourage you to look it up,
but you can also watch it with us.
You can go to our youtube channel.
We are on youtube or watching this on
a monitor that you can see with us.
Okay.
This trailer is called
the Asian connection. Um,
it's brand new.
The Asian isn't there like a, um, it's
a pretty common title. Like the Asian.
Can I the European, the [inaudible]
is a very, very famous movie. Okay.
So this is, they really went out on a limb
the, to find something else there yet.
Well this must be a play on that
film. Yes. That's an exceptional film.
If you haven't seen it,
it's real though.
You don't think this is
going to be exceptional time.
I've seen this and this is a
fucking dog Turd. Um, I mean,
okay,
so the last one was like the member of
the Iraqi Afghanistan wine that they shot
in Calabasas and this one man.
Well,
the premise of that film was just
shoot, shoot, shoot, Bang, Bang.
Steven Seagal kills people. And yes. So
what do you think this one's going to be?
There's a lot,
a lot of emperor that he
holds up to his improv.
I think in the the trailer you go,
he improvised that. Yeah, I think
there's a lot of Improv. Okay. Yeah.
So, so you just went up the first hole,
not down to the other one. You gotta get,
you gotta get your ass hole snip.
Ma'Am. I do. Okay. Let's, um,
let's run through this room. I'm
really excited. Okay. Here we go. Oh,
Jesus Christ.
Not enough room for the most, some of us.
That means one of us has to die.
So He's standing still. The other
guys doing all the words. It's just,
you can tell. Yes, he, he fights.
Yeah, totally. Still. And they also,
they make sure to shoot it where you
don't see how fat he is. Of course. No.
And that is very, believe
me, old black dye.
Make sure that he's just like shooting
from the ceiling and cut around me.
Yeah. That and the fat. The
attorney's guy out. But he's wearing,
what is that called? AG , I dunno.
Well this is very forgiving.
This outfit is basically pajamas thick.
Heavy. It covers the flaws. Yeah. Yeah.
And it's all black. The medallion, I
don't know. He's got, and he's got on his,
his, his range glasses. His gun
range glasses, yellow, 10 sure.
Blacker than black dye for the goatee.
Head wrap covering up the
jet black dark hair on top
would,
that means one of us has to die.
So there's a premise of the film is that
he's going to kill people, right? Yeah.
Not enough room for the most. Some of
us. That means one of us has to die.
Yeah.
Out of practice.
Smile friend.
He's from the crazy Logue
school of fighting me. Oh,
he is from the cause.
You love.
Wow.
No,
these titles look better
than the other me see out.
He paid for the title.
Now
what else are they said? Michael J. White
is in there. Okay. Okay. Okay. Alright.
Um, and show Jack Budand.
Tanka guy. That guy is this,
is this a pim poo? Bear Poo. Bear.
Do I have the Michael Dry white wine
in there? No. No. That's the one
before Otis. It's a one
right before this day. Okay.
Telling Harry.
Yeah.
I don't know why I can't or
60 press mills there, right?
No. Getting to know Kimmy.
Maybe it's not on here.
Hmm.
Oh, make a can get on
makeup. Dreaded. Get over it.
Okay. All right. Um, all right. Well in
many ways make note of Michael Jai White.
Okay.
Michael Jai
[inaudible]
also for a trailer.
Like that pacing on this thing is
so fucking, it's an action trailer.
Should be, it's a robbery
cut to Bam. Bam money.
Yeah.
Like let's go walking in.
We're going to take everything
now. Shoot, shoot, shoot.
Show them going into the room.
Grabbing the bag rug. No.
Yeah. Look, it's a four and a half,
four minute, 12 second trailer.
Should a trailer B 90 90 seconds,
usually the standard and then long
trailers are considered two minutes,
maybe a little over two minutes.
That's a long trailer.
These 32nd trailers.
Sometimes this is cause and you know why?
It's because Steven Seagal himself self
indulgent and he's standing behind the
editor at the Edit Bay going, oh
no, you got to put in there longer.
You got to put me in doing this and that.
Whatever the shot of me standing there,
I'm like,
didn't think that would put a fucking in.
Stephen thinks that he's the director. I
guarantee that's why. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know what? People like to see what's
happening in the movie. Um, so look,
this is just getting started,
man.
Who the fuck are these guys?
Who Cares?
You don't have to work
at the club anymore.
That could have been quick robbery
where
we get it.
See how it shows how it shows
like the Buddha, he's always like,
but it showed them,
why don't you just cut to,
you don't need in the trailer to
establish how you do that in a movie.
A movie.
We need to see where are we for context.
But trailer you just cut to his mind
and usually they tell you where you're
located. They would say
Vietnam or whatever, where
they're shooting this. Yeah,
your money was wrong.
They get away with about 200,000 voice.
You the motherfucker told me that.
Wow. And the effort and the trailer
to the motherfucker that totally,
he put a little hot sauce on it.
He did and he did eyebrow acting,
aren't you? Aren't you? Aren't
you the mother fit and said,
aren't you the motherfucker? Is it,
aren't you the motherfucker? Yeah.
Aren't you the motherfucker that
told me to put the money there?
Aren't you the mother fucker?
He's ridiculous.
I just want fucking results
to Fox.
Yeah.
And the sound mixing where you can
barely hear him talking as though that
angelic singing background over this.
So there are three of them
are mixed together. Horrible.
I just want to see fucking results.
This is a new level for him.
This is usually you see actors doing
stuff like this once they're full blown
alcoholics, you know, and they
had a queer like 30 years. Right.
Then they do the straight to DVD thing
and it's, this is his Gerard Depardieu.
Ah, yeah. He's at the end.
I just want to see fucking result fucking
results. And they're like, Steve, uh,
I don't know if we should curse.
Yeah, much shut the fuck up.
I don't want to hear any stories about
how it's going to be. I just want
to give you the names of the banks
in Cambodia. Did you want to run
my service?
50%
it makes no sense.
That's a weird moment to,
I'm going to tell you where to rob banks
and he just went to Steven and me a
beat before I was like, my
banks are being wrong. Yeah.
And then his fee for telling the guy where
to rob is 50% so he's robbing his own
banks, but the, now he's having Steven
Seagal find out who's robbing the banks.
I Dunno.
Nice to see. I'd be like this
greedy. I want to buy some heat heat.
That's Michael Jai white guns,
man.
No,
I'm like check
another fun.
The guard was killed.
What are you getting self nearer
the gardens.
Ah, ah, ah. Did
you see that?
There's a little sexy playful time and
I think that's the girl is dating the
bank robber, right? That was the girl.
Now she's dating Steven
Seagal who you know,
knows a lot of special sexual techniques.
Of course. I think he's a study.
Uh, all the eastern love
[inaudible] he'd be like,
well you leave your girl [inaudible]
she's going to come out of butthole for
sure.
You will come from your butthole
can make it come from your bud
off. Fucking real good. Jeez.
JKD yellow sunglasses off. You're going
to paint them brown with all that bucket.
I think he's definitely
going on with you today.
You know what?
We should do it down for later butthole.
Oh
yeah.
I want to talk a little bit about the
white tigers practices because in this DVD
we're using some of the
techniques from that practice.
I practice as a white tigers for about
a year and one of the premises and
there's a lot to the practice.
A lot. It's a lot too.
I bet he knows. Oh, on your face. He
knows about white tigress practice.
I bet he does.
I love that scene.
That's such a,
it's such a typical scene from an action
film where he's training and Gung Fu.
He's training the girl or
the two of them are training.
It's like the Matrix does it.
It's the karate kid moment.
The Mister Miyagi Roman mentor
moment. Yeah. It's so awful.
Oh,
this was shot. No sense. This
is how this went. They said,
we have an idea for a movie and we
want you to be in a Steven. Well,
tell me about it.
Yeah,
well you're going to be this bad ass and
you're going to kill the other boss and
you're going to make this girl come
out of her butt and you're going to,
you know, all of this crazy
person. He's a problem is
all we have right now are iPhones
to shoot it on. And he goes,
that's not a problem. And they
go, you sure I don't mind. Well,
the thing is we need to raise
financing to make this movie.
I'll pay for it. No Shit. I'll
give you thousand dollars.
And then they're like,
okay,
that's enough to buy chargers for
all the iPhones that made this film.
And then to edit it and I moved,
comes with your mind, your will,
your fucking iPhone. Nailed it.
And then they were like, no, I think we
have enough money to make this movie now.
He was like, make the
fucking movie. Right.
What the fuck
lot of Miss Shabi um, blended. The
bullets are ricocheting off anything.
None of them are hitting glass.
No, no. It's terrible that guys, that
guys, I don't know who these two are.
I Dunno.
Imagine if they just thought they
played this trailer on the radio.
Like they play movie trailers. If you've
seen this, you'd be like, what the fuck?
Black Bang, Bang, Bang, remain.
And also when does this ever end?
Well, it's ever, ever been. This is,
we're halfway through it and this
is the longest hurler my life.
And not only that,
usually when there's a motorcycle scene,
they'll play the audio of the room.
They're not,
they didn't even bother putting
the audio of the motorcycle.
No going fast and they used
the same effect for the gun
over and so I'm the gun. That's
when he pulls out a handgun.
That guy,
who the fuck is this
sky? I don't know athletes like just run
on that building and jump out. Right?
Motorcycle.
Hello.
It is finally pay for that
by tomorrow.
I'm not going to spend the of my life.
He said I wanted to fucking
in this tray by tomorrow.
You can actually hear him say that.
I couldn't hear because the audio
was because the mix is really cool.
Do you look at the IRS?
Look at him,
look at how crazy and his
eyes are so bloated. Shut.
You can barely see the eyes.
Look,
he's such a bloated salty mess
and we're rolling. Where am I?
Yellow sunglasses. Uh, somebody
got Steven's the sunglasses.
How? How drunk was he the night
before and he's eating up lines.
A shit is fucked.
Look how black is so dark.
Hey,
the Adam is money
tomorrow.
I'm not going to spend the rest of my
life looking over my shoulder near Neren.
I don't even want to know
how this ends. Well, why?
Because there's a fucking
minute and a half to go. Wait,
look how bad that is too.
It's like splatter paint.
Oh, I gave you 1000 bucks.
Good catch.
Casual from the crafty tall.
This is the guy that was
just on the telephone.
Do the only reason I know
that it's because of the
tattoo. He was on the phone.
I think that's the guy that was just
saying, I don't want to look over my back.
Neren look, if you throw some
hot coffee on him, oh, blood.
It will be a page that's
dead. Fuck. Listen to me.
I've made 55,000 a little bit.
He's a piece of shit. Well, wait,
what's going to happen? I don't even
want to know. It's so upsetting.
Can we just forward a little, I got
to know, maybe we can put it together.
Just mystery.
I'm going to jump ahead.
Yeah. We're at two 48 I'm going to jump
all the way. One minute ahead. Okay.
This isn't the subtlety of Downton Abbey.
This full minute ahead.
What happens a minute later?
Let's see something crazy.
Z Shit's
happening. Exact same shit.
He's wearing black sunglasses.
This is terrible. This is, and why
is he have this Bandana? I email?
No,
I'm the king of wardrobe.
Same outfit.
Every scene.
Thank all the big bang.
They saved the money for that coming soon.
Just soonish I dunno. No, we're
done editing on the Mac book.
Here's what I want to show you.
I don't know
Stephen C Gow on Michael.
There we go. So this is it.
This is what I wanted to show.
So they're in the movie together,
which is what,
cause I remember seeing this a while ago.
Hollywood tough guy. In your opinion,
you've accepted. Of course.
When you say tough guide,
you mean martial artists are
just timing. I mean Steven, for
real. If he was on the street and there
was a situation you wanted this Hollywood
guide by your side because
he could defend himself.
So do you understand that
the question clearly?
Just one moment. Yeah. I got to point
it out because I have the same problem.
I bags look at the
bloated mess. Yes. That,
and I know this cause I fucking
have the same problem. This is diet.
This is all night drinking,
eating sausage,
pork rinds for breakfast and look at
the Chins. Yeah, I know. It's a lot.
It's a lot. It's a lot. This is all diet
is all what you put into your mouth. Yeah.
Yeah.
So our buddy there,
so he's asking,
he's asking him which
Hollywood tough guy would you,
if you were in a real situation,
would you want by your side?
Okay. Okay. And he's like,
it's that hard to think of a legit one.
Can you think of one?
Michael Jai White.
Can I laugh in your face? Really? Yes.
Pretty crazy, right? Holy Shit on
him. But he's in the movie. I know.
Years later. I mean that
was, well, not years,
but that was probably a
couple of years old. And, um,
but I just thought it was interesting
that he was like, do you see his,
his eye roll? He was like,
yeah, John, I think your face.
Oh Wow. Yeah. Wow. I
really put him on blast.
Like you put them on the Liz asked for
sure. Is there anything
else I wanted to show you?
Anything else we need to talk about?
Yeah, there's tons. I mean look, I've
got some other topics. First of all,
crazy low cause you know what I'm
saying? Huge News. What's that? Uh,
we got a lot of emails translating
that Juggalos clip from last.
Ah, yes, yes, yes. Um,
that was um, pretty difficult
to understand. If, uh,
if you missed last week, I'll give you
a little bit of a taste of this. This,
I dunno.
I Dunno what the fuck this guy was saying.
Well we blew up boy here and
you might recognize this shirt.
This is the same shirt monoxide was
wearing in the homeys video. Oh,
I believe juicy j also born in a three,
six mafia video too. Right, right, right,
right. Anyways, that's not
what the video's about.
This video was about the mighty dark
carnival and how only real juggle is true
down ass.
Real Juggalos believe in a dark carnival.
Believe that the carnival is God and they
all Juggalos find them mother Faco and
the hatchet man.
Alright. Anyways, yeah,
we got some kind emails explaining from
like former Juggalos what this guy is
talking about and I don't
think you want to know.
Do you want to hear a
little bit? Sure. Okay.
What he was referring to about the joker
cards was a six major albums that ICP
came out with as a series and he's
sugar card has a deity slash. Entity.
The only one that did it was the first
album called the carnival of carnage.
Each of the characters perform some.
It's like, no thanks. Like I get,
thank you for the explanation,
but no thanks.
I'm not sure we need to know the
Juggalos talking about no, no, no, no,
but thank you. I appreciate you guys
looking out. But that was, yeah,
that right there made my brain hurts,
but also big news, uh, our Buddy Matt,
shout out to Matt. You know what I'm
saying? You're filming all the time out.
Apparently there's a new flavor of shrimp.
Nibbler at White Castle. Shout
out to Matt, your favorite,
uh, treat Trev Nibbler is now
available in Saracha. Hmm.
Can you think of anything more disgusting?
No. Then his shrimp. Nibbler no.
And out there right now,
someone's like,
that's my shit right there as my
favorite shit shit right there. Yeah.
Disgusting Sriracha.
By the way, before we are the, uh,
what'd you rather songs
in a specific folder.
Okay.
So that's blue band right there in case
you didn't [inaudible] so here's the,
would you rather tag? Um, so as you know,
we have uh,
some copyright issues we have.
Would you rather needs for a
new song for the introduction?
We also need it for fill her
up. Um, the filler up is a,
I guess a well known, so I don't, I
didn't know, but it's a well known oh,
Mexican Mariachi.
Yeah.
Yeah. So that's really
good. I thought so. Um,
if you guys want your song to
be the official, fill her up,
seal her shut anthem,
submit.
Send an email to your mom's
podcasts@gmail.com and put
fill her up anthem in the
subject line. Same thing here for
would you rather a, so here's,
here's one that just came in here.
Let's see how it is.
This would mean that you hear this
and it's would you rather time right?
Can
Show it's pretty chill.
Nice.
I kinda like it. I like it. It's good.
Um, do you have any other ones? Yeah,
there should be a couple more
in here. Right? Um, okay.
What'd you rather theme?
Here's another submission
cause the thing is,
the first one was great,
but I think we need the energy to be a
little higher because it's kind of a bag
of chips. Moman bullhorns
it's chips in a bowl.
One also has feelings.
What's it going to be?
Tock. Tick Tock, right. That's
good. Which do you choose?
Right from Ryan.
Patrick.
The first one was from how the air.
Nice.
And then another one came in here.
Another would you rather submission?
Let's see. Oh, is that an odd? Yeah.
Oh,
might be
the top layer.
Oh Shit.
Okay.
That was obviously not the way I wanted
to play that we had a knock at the door
and we needed to get it. Um, so here it
is again. A check this, this is another,
would you rather submission
the top layer
sex?
Where did your sister give a face?
Grandmother walks him masturbating
and never have another orgasm.
[inaudible]
yeah, that's great. Listen,
they're all stupendous.
This is just a for a segment.
I think it's got the tone.
It's got the upbeatness we're
looking for context too.
Oh, that's our body of course.
Crushing it again. Newman.
This guy's home runs always maximum.
All of these come on now him Max and make
it your life. You know what I'm saying?
Max Newman.
He did breezy.
Oh.
Oh God.
He did love seeing an email from him.
Right now we all know way what jeans he
so I said that I wanted to make a song
called your problems.
Make my Dick's off for a long time.
He submitted something. Oh Man, we
missed. Yeah. He said it like a month ago.
Hmm.
Tasks. That should be my dad's
theories. That is his thing.
This is awesome. His theme.
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
Unbelievable backs now. That
really is, that's amazing.
So good dude. What a talent
this guy is. Well, look,
I think we're settled
on that was you rather,
although I want to thank Javier
and Ryan for their submissions,
those are really good as well. Um,
but let's focus on the fill her up.
Seal her shut. Yeah. We
need new music for that.
I actually feel like it wouldn't be
bad if we can keep it in that Mariachi
theme. Yeah. I mean why
not stick to the roots?
I think the roots of
it are good cause some,
some kind of Mexican flavor that
led to Latin flavor. That'd be fun.
Maria Maniaci is a specifically
Mexican. Yes. Yes. Yeah.
I like that box. It's like I'll, yes.
Um, is that it? Jeans? Anything
else? Hold on. I got to see.
I got, we, we covered the double
pipe. That was a huge deal. We moved,
we didn't even talk about
that. We didn't move, man.
I have a new blog that's big news.
Big News. It's on my youtube page.
Um, so Garah I'm also, listen,
let's cover it on the next episode.
It's too big a topic.
I don't want to do it at the
very end. Okay. Uh, but, uh,
what is it? It's about the day. Oh,
that's okay. Yeah, we'll do
that next time. I also hold on.
Um, no, I'm thinking, wait, no,
I can wait if you wait. Shrimp. Nibblers I
covered that. Okay. Okay. That was great.
I thought that was a great show.
It was. That was really fun.
It's better the second time around,
you know, back. Come on back.
Have a look at those us. Yeah, she's got
it, man. I got to get her milkers on me.
Yeah. When I get my mom boob
job. You know what I'm saying?
Let me get my soccer's fixed.
Yes. Big fucking sloppers.
Um, all right, well listen, this
was, um, 60 fun was the second time
we've done this show. Uh, let's hope
the audio sounds great. You can.
Time's a charm and a hope you
enjoyed the youtube version.
If you're watching with us. Thank you for
joining us and we'll be back next week.
Don't forget your mom's house,
podcast.com Tom [inaudible] dot com
for new door for tickets to shows.
Philadelphia is on sale now.
The Trocadero theatre and jeans is PR,
uh,
doing shows all over the
Los Angeles general area.
Go to thousand ranch Dotcom for those
was maximum and blew us away with a new
song. Will take you back to
one of Max's Oh gee songs.
He's sending a few. He also did a, one
of the crazy sexual ones that we did,
but I just found greasy, so why
don't we do that? I think he did.
Mike, this is one of my
favorites. I love the sound. Oh,
it's so good. Let's turn it up. Burn.
Smell.
Burn Breezy.
Breezy.
Yeah.
Crazy.
Sorry.