Well, well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
No, I take taking your dad
glasses on. My Dad dies.
He just took it down dumb.
It was great.
Why are you not sharing this?
I feel like everything's very tight
lipped about it. I'm not. It's normal.
What do you mean it's not normal? I went
out to take care of business. I'm fine.
I ran the big day for a while and
everything was fine. Was it a clean wipe?
What's their food? Remnants on the
paper. A little bit itchy or know?
Very nice. It's like a three. Yeah.
That's kind of lumpy,
right? No, it's good.
This dry little dry, right? I mean it's,
it's in the ideal window.
It's a little drier than it
could be. Not Bad. What I
fit into now, I'm fat in it,
but I fit into it.
I saw someone wearing this and Mahalia
and that was very jarring to see my
husband's face on someone's.
Yeah. I'm not sure.
Check it out. Try it out.
You know what I'm saying?
Was talking about Philly,
you know what I mean?
It looks like I'll be in a urine
Irvine,
California
at the Improv.
June nine,
10 and 11.
Um,
I think that you sent me
why I need it.
Here it is.
There's too many things up and um,
so that's,
that's coming up to nine, 10, 11.
Then the week after I have Gash Ceville
Tennessee
xannies June 16th,
17th and 18th,
which is also your smurf day.
Then west nut sack New York.
June 23rd through 25th into July.
I have shits on that Matt.
The shirts on that deed
shut down.
That D, Ohio. That was submitted.
Not the best flow on that one.
I'm going to be honest with you. I
agree with you. Shit on the natty.
No, I spit on her nasty. There you go.
Good work it on her nasty Ohio.
Wow.
I'm doing the brand new liberty
township. I'd work 20 bone. June,
July seven,
eight and nine.
This is about to end the July to July,
July.
That's how my dad says it too.
MMM,
that's right.
It's like famous music. We
shouldn't, we shouldn't be playing.
MMM.
Then I have, what's the next week, Ben? I
don't know. Where are you? And you know,
August? No, July. I have
man Diego. Oh Man. I,
and everybody who came up to me and was
like, we're coming back to see Tommy.
You're at the American comedy
company. That's right. July,
1415 16 that's July 14th.
July 15th and July 16th got a July mark,
although no.
And then Saint Jude Lips.
Uh, July 21st St Juleps. What's that?
Louis Jew Lips.
Yeah,
that's really July 21st 23rd,
Geez.
Say Yeah.
And it keeps on going.
Go to [inaudible] dot com same Lou blips,
Lube Lips.
I'll work on it. Let me work on
it. Yeah, I know. I mean I'm,
I'll go on a button. You know,
I got Cox hard coming up. Uh,
Oxnard. Oh God. I got fill her pelvis up.
Has Sylvania good,
good work and fix my cracks in New York.
These are really good.
They'll her pelvis up.
That's the Trocadero we added a
show cause the first one sold out.
Please tell me you have some kind of a
tour poster with all these names on it.
Not yet. It's a good
idea. Great idea. Yes.
Okay. What else you got? Well, I'm
working on a tour for the fall.
I'm doing a series of one nighters.
Uh, we're looking at Houston,
we're looking at Dallas,
we're looking at Seattle.
We're looking at Portland so
far. Um, and the dates aren't,
I can't announce them yet, but keep on
the lookout. Yeah, I'm excited to do it.
Also,
I'm at the comedy store now.
Most Saturday nights to seven 30 show
and the o are generally, I do that one.
And you might see Mr [inaudible]
Guerra there. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I've been going there. I went on
Friday night is a domain room. How Fun.
So Fun, man. The place
was electric. So much fun.
The comedy star is where I
sat and now guys are here.
If you're visiting La and you want
to know what to do with yourself,
go down to the comedy store and you
will see all of us hanging out there.
It's just the most fun, the most
fun. But this Saturday I'm doing,
are you doing it Friday? Maybe.
I'm going to put in my avail,
so I'll try to get this right.
We'll our Twitter. Yeah.
Accuracy at Toms does.
Gora it'd be good.
Hey, do us this flavor. If you
shop on Amazon, use our banner.
He gets here. Um, I love when I scare you.
It feels so good.
Thank you very much.
The kid mode is for this song that
one night, Kim. Modus. I like it.
Soundcloud, check them out. Yeah.
Yeah.
These, our Amazon matter.
Did I mention that you did.
There's a thing now you can use a,
you,
they give buttons and you put
buttons on the stuff you always buy.
You push it and then they just
automatically it automatically. Yeah.
Your orders for you. Yes.
So should I addiction? Um,
I never have to leave my house
again. Yeah. So check it out. Um,
oh, also, uh, patriotic. Put that down.
Patriot starts June 1st, which is
why got most, if you're hearing this,
you're waiting a few hours.
So it's patrion.com/mom
patrion.comp.com/mom and
patriarch is spelled p a.
T. R. E. O. N. Is that correct?
Patriotic Pride. Trout.
Put that down. patrion.com/mom is
going to give you extra access.
Bonus episodes. It's going to be a lot
of fun. Please check it out. And, um,
join us unpatriotic and
um, uh, as Christina said,
please support our, um,
Amazon. Our mom was on page.
Go through the banner at your mom's house,
podcast.com,
and by what you were going to buy anyways.
And we have Amazon Canada to,
somebody tweeted, do you
guys do Canada? Yeah.
So if you're Canadian
and you live in Canadia,
you can just go through our Mama's on
banner for Canadian Amazon. It says dot.
Ca. That's um, the short for Canadia.
Also check out that Steve Brow.
If you have an already I talk about
this week, why my mind is an asshole.
I'm reading a Michael Singer's
book, the surrender experiment. Uh,
yeah.
And if you sleep on a mattress that's
still dropped off on your front doorstep,
you're dirty and disgusting.
By the way,
during my other podcasts that stick a,
it's called a farm to the game. What
if we are getting better? You know,
I had some hiccups. I've been
working on it. Uh, we had, uh,
Gibran Hamden on this past week,
half Palestinian,
half Pakistan football player. That
was, um, really interesting story.
Went from, started playing football
his senior year in high school.
Went to the NFL, ended up going to
NFL Europe, was the MVP over there.
Now he has a clothing company.
Really cool guy.
This week I have a major get for my,
yeah, we haven't recorded
yet, but we have it set up.
I don't want to announce who it is because
that's how you screw yourself. Yeah.
But it's, I'm a big, big get for
the show. Okay. Very excited. Okay,
so that's that. Charge it to
the game. Okay. Tom [inaudible].
All right. I'm ready
to do this jeans. Yeah,
let's start our farm show.
I'm from Nico from the face of the method.
Kayla on Facebook told me
that when she gets stressed,
she grind her teeth at night.
Oh, Kayla, you are not alone.
I do that too. And I know it's
not good for my teeth either.
Well,
in this field I will show you a very
simple face exercise you can do whenever
you feel stressed. You can do this
in a shower or in the curse of that.
Nobody sees you and hears you.
This is how you do it.
You're very exaggerated.
Minor, open your mouth and say,
wow,
breeze out completely.
Let's try it together 10
times. Sure. Ready? Right. No.
Wow. Wow. Wow,
wow, wow, wow,
wow, wow. Wow.
Wow.
Well No,
we'll go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Okay.
That's really cool, man. Is there a
big cock and balls on? Yeah, that's it.
Really mature. Really,
really mature. Wow. Oh Wow.
Completely breeze out to Kim
in school of Yoga. Ready?
Ready?
Wow. Wow, wow, wow, wow,
wow, wow, wow.
Wow. That's her. I don't
like it. Wow. Right.
Wow.
Do you feel like,
wow,
she's got a very natural delivery
on her youtube video too.
Wow.
Look at the size of that mouth open now
you can put the whole dog in the bathtub.
Right?
Are you feeling,
what is that from what Frat boy
committee came up with that,
but when you tell it about the, you could
write, yeah, cock and balls, like all,
all of it. No, I understood
what the dog in the back,
but I'm saying thank you
for explaining it to you.
Do you think you could get both
balls in? Yeah. And the cock.
She, she does have a big,
uh, big mouth. Wow. Wow.
How are you doing this?
Oh, it's just on. Oh Man.
I'm starting to get a little
turned on right now. Ah, yeah.
Ah Jeez. Ah, and then, and then as I,
and then I finished and she goes,
uh,
yeah.
I was just thinking about,
I was playing a song earlier when
you were like slick. You're like,
I'm just looking forward to going like
an eharmony and maybe meeting somebody
that like I really
click with and you know,
we can listen to music
together and just have fun.
You mean I got a 15 year old girl.
Why would she be 15 who listens
to that ridiculous music
listening to it. It was really bad. It was
so damn. What are you guys going to do?
You and your 15 year old guys can watch
the voice together and we could call it
and vote at the same time. I'd be
like, who we vote for this week?
And we could be like, I could be like the
song. And she's like, yeah, I'm a tall,
my friends,
you're like the best DJ ever.
Panty Jenga party. And she's like,
yeah, we're all coming. It's like slide.
That must be what it's like to really
date like a 20 year old when you're 50 or
60 year old. Oh, right. The person.
That must be what it's like right now.
Like I got,
let's go to, what does that festival
calm? I've heard the big scandal,
apparently.
Rumor scandal is that this chick that uh,
Johnny Depp
is a big black mailer. Like this is, yeah,
all a conspiracy.
You know,
that she's faking that he's beating her
and all this stuff. I believe, I mean,
Doug Stan hub came out and he's a
comedian and we all trust comedians saying
that that's not true. And I mean, what do,
have you ever known Johnny Depp
to be a violent guy? Well, he's,
I mean there's all the time that we hung
out. He was always real chill. So yeah.
Well, he's so down to earth. No, I
love Johnny Depp. Can I tell you?
I don't think he beats her.
I don't buy that. It's a
sound. It's not an initiative.
It's suspect, right?
It's really like, well,
I mean he's had so many other women in
his life. Nobody's ever come forward.
It would have come out by now if he
were a violent guy and it was also
interesting that they went to court. The
the, the, the wife amber herd is her name.
She went to court and ask
the court for like, you know,
all these things immediately. So she got
her restraining order because the grant,
those, if you request them then she
requested spousal support denied. She
requested a right. Yeah. This
is an immediate, you know,
it doesn't mean that you're not
going to get it in the divorce.
She had requested, he paid
for her legal fees, denied.
She requested of their vehicle,
denied the court,
rejected all those
requests and interesting.
But she is must be a real evil
person to do something with it.
Great. You can look at those eyes. I see
those pictures. She cry. She loquacious.
Beautiful. But it's just crazy.
It's really, um, but I do,
I love Johnny.
I've always had a crush on Johnny Depp.
I below the two of us are 21 jump street.
I had a life size poster of him
and my room growing up. Yeah.
But he is insufferable when you listen
to him on like the actor studio and he's
like rolling his own black cigarettes,
you know the craft like talking to
craft and all that horse shit. All are,
they all are there for all of the craft,
the craft,
any of them he gave that he gave a speech,
a pretending to be somebody else
for a living. It's such a challenge.
All that stuff is nauseated. He
did a, he got an award recently,
I guess right before this all went down.
Yeah.
Where when he got the award he thanked,
you know,
he's thanking people and he goes,
I want to take my wife, amber,
amber for forgetting her name too,
for dealing with all these
characters I bring home. Uh,
I know it's gotta be difficult on her.
It's hard on me.
So all these people that I'm
inhabiting,
that's why actors are not comics.
Cause if you know you can't do
it. No, that mean, how do you,
how do I live with Tom [inaudible] Guerra,
a talented comedian I with all these
are the jokes and amazing things in your
head. I know it's hard
on you. It's got, I mean,
it's really hard on me being
so funny and so talented.
And the thing is I liked that there's
no pressure to be on what I'm owed.
I mean, everybody's like Tom, Tom,
make me laugh, make me the lash. Yeah.
And I love giving to those people.
I'm like making people laugh.
It's my greatest joy, spreading
joy. It fills me with a story,
but tell it should show up please.
Tom, please have black Dick joke.
Do you have it still?
Can I hear it? You do.
Imagine if comedians talking about our
process, the way actors talk about layers.
Oh my God. Well I wake up around 1:00
PM I had just come on my stomach.
I thought that's kind of
drawing in a funny way.
I should talk about that tonight.
I wiped and I wiped and I
thought there's a new bit, right?
Yeah.
I mean it's too much.
Yeah, they're so serious.
So serious. But the,
but I guess it needed serious and not
so serious as to live together for,
for the not serious people to thrive.
Really.
It has to be against
all the serious people.
Because if we didn't have the
Johnny Depp's to make fun of you,
it's like I've asked Steven, see gals,
oh my God. I came to realization about,
you know, I can't stand the offended
people. Yeah, but you still need them.
They'll always be there.
Otherwise I wouldn't have a career.
You need someone to go like, Whoa, I can't
believe you said that. That's, thank you.
Yeah, that's true. I was, thank God
there's not an inside the comedian studio.
That would be so funny. Is
there other, I guess mark. Yeah,
I saw him.
He was really fun at the store.
He does the seven 30 show usually
with me or sometimes. Yeah. Yeah.
Well that, that is inside the community
is city, but that's all we talk about.
It's like depression or shitty families.
Our process
process.
So this was so fun. I got to get
in. Well, I'll show you this first.
Can we just announced that we're back
on video because blue van, oh my God.
You know what this fucking guy did
last week? So let me pull this up.
He got sick,
he went and got sick.
He went and got sick like a
fucking dumb bird. And uh,
so let me pull up our channel here.
It's been getting bigger and bigger.
Thank you for everybody that's
been prescribing to it. And um,
you know, watching. Yeah. So
last week's episode goes up,
it's episode three 45, I think, right?
We've never ever had this
many thumbs down on a video.
And it's because there's no video.
It's just a video of the audio, right?
She's so late, man. Let me,
there are 54 thumbs down.
So it never happened before
to one of our episodes.
So blue ban uploads this episode,
right? I send them the file, he flies.
It was nasty. Downloads
it. Here it is here.
And he says,
due to genes being low and loose,
there will be no video component. So like,
of course impulse. That's funny. Yeah.
Well except it's also very misleading.
So I made sure to write here a little
misleading that no video was attributed to
low and loose jeans when in fact
it's because blue band got sick,
his nest got infected by some
cardinals and he was doing better,
but he wrote this on this vid,
jeans are loose and not true.
Bird is sick. Oh, okay.
Because it's a very big distinction
distinction. That's true.
So I just wanted to make that clear.
One could argue blue bands,
logic being that he got sick and
therefore his jeans became low and Louis,
he should have,
they should have put that in the text.
You don't want to mislead the listeners,
the viewers.
People could just think like,
we don't feel like it.
Our jeans are loose this week.
I want him to be like,
I got bird aids, fucking bird
and you know, fucking bird
flu brain's not that bad.
There you go. You feel better now. Okay,
we're back.
We're packing video.
A bird is fat and that has been,
I wasn't going to,
I just wanted to address it before
we forgot because we get it wrong.
You need to forget. First of all,
a big shout out to the people who,
who I think understood the distinction
of just tweeting that to him without
tagging us. Cause that way it's
like, why am I getting these?
Which I thought was great. Now some people
ended up tagging us too, which is fine,
but I really wanted to give a shout out
to not tagging us because that is the
idea of him waking up.
Why am I getting this right?
Once you see I as tagged in it, then
he goes like, oh it's from them. Yeah,
the mysteries. It's better. Yeah man,
it went so it was crazier than I
could've ever imagined thing ever.
And then Instagram is
Instagram and here too. Oh,
oh my God. The Instagram is
what I didn't even realize.
So my Instagram,
God, thank you. It was called sex with me.
It was amazing. So we
told you last week, right?
Cause I think what happened was I read
a tweet from him where he called me fat.
So I go right.
It was something like,
well we've been doing this kind of for a
long time. I mean, we're years of, well,
I spent a year or so of who's fatter
you are. Yeah. It's always, you know,
it's always the third. It's always bird,
but it's always a thing and it's fun.
So I just last week we go send him
a tweet and say, why are you so fat?
And then, and then it became a
Hashtag. Bert is fat at the end. Dude.
Not only did you guys sent him
maybe over a thousand tweets,
but I got it. Okay. Some of
these are just incredible. So
that's really good for it. So
fat, right Burt and I liked that.
That looks delicious.
You started just every tweet,
no matter what it has to do with
anything had been tagging it. Uh,
Burdis fat bird is fast
tag. Bert is fat, right?
So you go all tweets or
Burrito a full charge.
And I are fucking up at the comedy store
in La Jolla this weekend. You know,
bird is fat. It's just, I think we should
just all hashtag everything Burdis it,
no matter what. No matter what.
Then, uh, people were doing.
Lot of shops from my
photo shops are amazing.
Who Does Vegas?
Vegas seven Oh two crushes.
She crushes the Photoshop stuff.
Here's another one on hers.
I think that's Joe.
Joe.
Joey's body
especially facile,
that stupid grin on his face.
He has the best expressions for fat guy
stuff because his regular expressions
always like, oh so you put that on like
an enormous body. It's really amazing.
Um, well then he wrote, he tweeted,
cause he got after hundreds of them,
he goes just when you think
the joke is getting old and he,
it was he tagged,
he quoted as somebody who wrote braking
and it shows these scientists looking at
something under a microscope.
The nation's leading scientists are
working around the clock to determine why
bird is so fat.
Then you put this up, I had so much fun
the night more about nonbinary friends.
Tomorrow night bird is fat and I
also got them all saying a video,
why is you're fat?
And I got people at La Jolla,
somebody put the civil war
stand up team time team bird.
Which side are you on? Oh,
that's, and they burnt by the way,
I'm the number one fat
shaming person today.
Oh my God. He put, I know
exactly how Amy Schumer feels.
I guess cause she had gotten, I
dunno, some hatred or something.
I think she had a picture of her
in a bikini and um, some tablet,
but she looked great. She's not fucking,
this is like, no, she looks great.
This is how, uh, let's be,
let's be clear between Amy Schumer
and Bert. Bert is legitimately fad.
Oh, Bert parts. Enormous.
Yeah. Amy's not normal.
This is like if you just
looked up his name. Yeah.
He retweeted these. Burt, why are you so
fat? Just curious. Why are you so fast?
So like is it a steroid thing? Thyroid
thing. Why are you so fat? Hey,
Burt Chrysler,
why are you so fat?
Then two accounts
started of Burt Chrysler.
Um, this one says breakfast tip, 600
kids have less calories. Three pancakes.
You're trying to watch your weight. I
put syrup in the Heinekens for it as fat.
Six, I have less calories
in three van gigs. Oh Man,
bear Chrysler is the best too. Yeah, man.
So then I'm talking to him on the phone
Saturday and I look at something on,
on, uh, Instagram and I
go, I'll just, you know,
I pulled up his, here's the
comments Bra, all the fat,
man, why are you so fat? Why the fuck
are you so fucking fat? Low fat alert?
Why are you so fat? So you guys went
to his institute, Bert Chrysler,
why are you so fucking fat? You
are so fat. It's all fatty fat,
fat burn. Why you so fat? It's
hundreds of comments on every picture.
And then he goes, he
has to post, of course,
a shirtless picture of himself
just asking why so fat? Why so fat?
Huge Fan. But why are you
fat? Why are you so fat?
God, you're fat. It's endless.
And I gotta say my favorite thing I've
been a part of in years is this so much
fun. He said that, uh,
one of his daughters,
it was posted on one of
his things. He goes, sure,
are a lot of people calling you fat today.
Dot.
Oh my God. So anyways, thank you so
much for, I'm going to work guys.
Really outstanding. That really
was outstanding work. I mean,
that one's my favorite.
The breaking scientists or the
breaking science thing is great. Yeah.
And the photo shops or maze. Yeah. I
mean, Vegas, it's really, uh, you know,
we challenged you and I think you just
leaped over the challenge above and
beyond. It was really a crest dangerous.
Once we get the mommy's on something,
yeah. You Better Watch out. Watch yourself
get on the mommy's bad side. I know.
I mean, that's on the good side.
We'd love, but, but that's, you know,
so you remember a while ago
the, the Trump song, right?
It's China to meat, meat,
meat, meat, meat, meat, meat,
China, China, China,
China,
China.
So it's so good. It's
great. That's by a island.
And then I finally, this week
we got a Hillary song. Oh,
now we can go back and forth, check
out this Hillary song. It's by a place,
Boeing, um, really, really great work.
[inaudible] [inaudible]
[inaudible] not a laughing matter.
I take it really seriously
to
me because
on all these mothers
don't. For me because I'm
a or because I'm a woman,
I'm a woman and all these brothers
Don for me because I'm a woman,
because I'm a woman, woman running
to be the first woman president.
Not Imagine anyone being
more of an outsider,
then the first woman can be more of
an outsider than a woman president.
I can't think of anything more of an
outsider than electing the first woman
president,
a woman president.
It's amazing. So good.
I love her laughing.
That's the clap is so horrible.
Really Tan. Wow. Good
job. That's placed Boeing.
Who did that one and
then the Trump has had,
I didn't realize has various
China, China, China, China,
China, China. Now did
you read about his hair?
You're telling me some article you
read on why it looks so horrible.
What's the story with him?
It's, it's basically the,
they come to the conclusion is
hair is completely not natural.
You know,
obviously people are fixated on it
looks terrible that it's a $60,000.
We've,
that he has an elaborate we've,
that he opted for this years ago when
there wasn't an option for him to do and
obviously really expensive
surgical one or nonsurgical.
And he opted for the nonsurgical,
which is that fucking dead
dog you see on his head today.
That's terrible. Yeah. So it's
uh, but it's uh, it's a long read.
It's a really funny read
about how elaborate his pro,
let me see if it, but why does he
have to style it like a Douche bag?
That's the weird thing is
the styling of it. Yeah.
It looks like cotton candy. It's
a Gawker piece actually. Um,
so Google that Gawker Trump hair,
Donald Trump hair Gawker and it's a yes.
It's really,
they go into incredible detail.
Oh my God,
it's so horrible.
There's just so there's, so,
there's so much of an investigation.
I mean it really,
really is elaborate cause it looks normal.
If this is one of the interesting
parts of the article was it said, um,
look at what happened last August,
part of a time interview when they
had a bald eagle name, Uncle Sam.
But in an act of performance,
it was truthfully a bit too
on the nose for my tastes,
the living symbol of American pride.
It's hack the angry orange candidate.
And as Uncle Sam's wings flap frantically
Trump's hair piece of migrated.
It was ever so slight in ever so brief,
but migrate.
It did end in one impossibly solid piece.
So it was hair removed all together.
They chunky, they made this little,
you can see.
Yeah,
it's not his hair. You know,
here's, here's the, Oh,
they had it all moves together here.
Yep.
Wow.
You can see it. So yeah,
it's so bizarre. Dude.
Look at this article
is all about the hair.
Why don't you think that one of
his wives will be like, baby you,
you got to divorce. You look
crazy. The guy that started the,
this particular hair restoration procedure
used to have an office guest where my
really helps in Trump tower in New York.
And he has since left there,
but they said that,
you know, that's where,
that's where Trump had this
done. Oh, it's, it is really,
really crazy. Micro extension. But he
has to know. It looks like shit. I mean,
of course she does, but we all
have our own levels of delusion.
You know my little face looks like
shit though. He's orange and he, yeah,
he looks so chapped and dry.
Like that guy in the Americans,
he just looks like a dry hot dog,
you know.
Would you like to like a dry Dick? A
dog deck. What'd you ever kiss him? No.
Like you just mouth smells. It's such
a dad mouth. Yeah. He has a drill.
Charlie.
Margaret.
Just
somebody from shiny shiny.
Am I supposed to dislike?
Let's say
China,
China. China can't be.
Whoa, Beth's got into it. She liked it.
What are you barking about? She hates
Donald Trump. She's not voting for him.
Which she's not going to vote.
What are you doing this?
You're just having a time talking to
the voices in her head. Um, anyways,
great music. Great
submissions. Both of them.
I can't wait for you to do some hair
restoration. Are you going to do that? No.
You're just going to let it go. No,
I'm definitely of the, you know,
everyone has the thought as the
hair starts to leave, you're like,
what should I do about this? But you
know, it was pretty, I tried for,
it was years ago. I tried it for
a month. A pill. Yeah. But um,
my doctor subscribed to me
and uh, for one month I
tried it and wow. Wow.
I did not like the way I felt.
No,
it made you not want to have sex and
it was still depressed also. Yeah,
because testosterone, high testosterone
can lead the hair loss. Right.
Anyways, it was, I didn't
like it. So that was it.
I tried that pill and then I was like,
I don't give a shit.
What about the Propecia?
You can rub on, I dunno.
Topical Ointment. I don't,
I'm not that interested. Well,
I would say that you might have a good
chance of keeping your hair because if
you haven't lost it by now, right.
I mean it's thin, it's thinner.
It's been this thin for the last 10 years.
I'm saying no,
it's the not more over the last 10 years
for sure. Oh yeah. It's definitely,
I mean it's on your mother's side is
your mom's dad. He had that widow's peak.
Go what I have and I don't know.
Well, we'll see. We're getting
that 23 and me thing done. Oh yeah.
We'll see what's going on.
I think it tells you all that stuff.
If you're going to go bald and die and
stuff, it says you're going to go bald.
Die. Yeah. What you're going to die of.
Thanks for signing up for 23 and me.
You're going to go bald and
die. Probably. Well, okay.
I'm excited for that.
Very exciting.
I'm a little upset. You told me
the news today. A lot of people,
this is memorial day as we're recording
this and some people have been
supportive of commemorating
the Cincinnati Fart. Yes, yes.
Now you came in the kitchen and you told
me that some people are doubting the
validity.
I, Cincinnati Fart. I can pull up.
I just caught this moments ago.
I mean, I was, I just happened to
I'm, and I'm so upset.
I'm so beside myself.
I can't even believe that people would
doubt the authenticity of my Cincinnati.
Well, somebody wrote today, let us
not only remember our fallen soldiers,
but let us also remember the
Cincinnati Fart. And, um, they,
they did a salute. All give a round
of applause. This says a fart.
I saw that.
Then Gary Thorne wrote the
Cincinnati Fart is a myth.
There is no documented evidence that
ever existed. Wow. Okay. Pretty.
It's pretty bold, right? Well
then, well, let, let's, let's,
let's continue then. Somebody wrote,
let me guess. The Holocaust never
happened either. Get Real, bro.
Cincinnati fart matters.
Never said that.
Lots of evidence Holocaust happen. Unlike
Cincinnati Fart, which is all hearsay.
Uh, somebody said, well, I
heard if you go to Cincy,
close your eyes and smell deeply, you
could still catch a whiff. Urban legend.
He replied, yeah, we can debate this
forever. But none of the change,
none of this changes the fact
that Bert Kreischer is fat.
That's a good point. And then he other
guy wrote, you're right, Marcos wrote,
you're right. Why is burnt so
fat? So it ends, it makes sense.
Well,
allow me to address these please.
Firstly that Cincinnati fart happened.
And uh,
in July of last year I was pregnant.
We just gone on a cruise on of what
body of water is that in Cincinnati?
Uh, yeah, it's a forever. Whatever.
Raw water. Anyways, I ate, um,
the buffet, I had, uh, several
different things. I had mashed potatoes,
chicken, roasted vegetables,
everything. I, yeah.
And Look, the Cincinnati fart
happened. I couldn't prepare for it.
It's not as though we could get a camera
ready is just one of those things that
happen. Now. Tom was there to
witness it was there and I,
are you suggesting that my husband
Tom is a liar? I'm not a liar.
What did it sound like?
Let's relive it.
Oh,
it was like,
let's relive it.
It's when I got back,
I remember I stayed out later
than you and I was tired.
You retired back to the room. I took my
cousins to a restaurant cause right. Um,
yeah, we ate, we had drinks. Yeah.
Um, so we went out, I got back,
I gave you a hug and then
it happened tomorrow.
Oh,
uh Huh.
I mean my eyes almost fell out of my head.
Yeah. I'd never heard anything like it.
And the thing is,
I felt that fart building all evening
because I was laying down and I remember
being like, oh, there's a lot
of rumbles in this man guts.
You couldn't believe it either.
I remember. Yeah. That was never,
ever seen anything like it,
you know.
Are we calling the hotel
called the hotel room?
Good afternoon.
Thank you for discovering the
renaissance and Cincinnati downtown.
How may I direct your call?
Hi Ya. Um, do you get to,
can someone book a room to commemorate
this Cincinnati Fart that happened last
year?
We'll go around to commemorate what?
I'm sorry. Could you repeat that?
The Cincinnati Fart
last August.
Has anyone done that or would you like it?
Yeah. Well, yeah, I mean
there's a lot of people.
I have actually quite a few people
that want to, I think it's room three,
1313 is that right? I think so.
Three 31 I forget one of the two
at our hotel.
Yeah.
Or maybe it was eight 13.
Um,
can I put you on a brief hold?
Sure. Yeah. The Cincinnati
Fart. Thank you. Yes.
Okay. All right. So we actually don't
have a real number. Is there any one,
is there a way I can check in which
room I stayed in last time I was there.
Um, I, uh, do you
remember around what time your stay was?
Yes,
I can actually give you the exact dates.
Okay. So we've never actually
had a fire in our hotel.
Oh, okay. Yeah, no, no,
I, I didn't mean that.
So last August,
1920 21 and 22 I believe.
Yes. So last name would be Segura, s e, g,
U, R, a, Tom and, and well,
there was a few cigarettes,
so this would be the one with
Christina, c, h R. I. S. T. I, n.
A
on on one second. SD, J. U. R. A?
No, no, no. S. E. G. G.
Oh, I apologize. Yes.
And the first name is Christina.
Sure. It was undermining.
Okay.
And this was last year around August.
It's exactly, it was exactly August. Uh,
I think 19 2021 and 20
and 23 we left the 23rd
okay. So was there a different name
for saying that it could be under,
uh, yes. Thomas or Tom
and then Christina? Yeah,
we had the same room though.
Okay. So I do see a reservation
that we did have for you in room
18 and your arrival date was August 19th
six 15 1618 six 18 now there was two
Segura is there though with the same name?
I just want to make sure I'm not because
it's my dad also stayed there under the
name Tom Segura.
So do you see a second?
I do see a second one,
but it has a different date of arrival.
That one is August 21st Oh,
okay.
So we have to a cigarette.
No, you know what? I arrived, she
arrived the 21st so that would be,
so what's that? That might not be
the correct room. What's that number?
What's that room number? Eight zero
eight eight zero eight that's it.
That's it.
That's the one eight zero eight yeah.
Now can we do group packages for
people wanting to pill? Yeah,
cause I know people that want to
pay extra just to stay in this room.
What was so special about that room?
The Cincinnati Fart.
Yeah.
Could you spell that for me?
F A r t like passing gas.
Okay.
And it was like this elaborate huge deal.
But I know that people
want to like honor it.
I see.
Okay. So they can read, they can
just request the room number then
probably right?
Yes.
And then there was a,
I see something on the Internet.
It says Sidney much room 1618
1618.
So I'm not really sure.
I don't think that's it. Oh, she's
looking enough on the Internet. Yeah.
Since 94 she says 1618 is eight oh eight.
I remember it anyway because
I have the alternative.
There's an industrial band called eight
away state and I remember thinking that
it,
okay.
So, um, the two rooms. So Mr Seeger,
we had your in room 1618 on August 17th
and August 21st we had you treasure or
two reservations. It was a room share
for room eight zero eight okay. Okay.
One of the Bulls.
Figure it out from there.
Thank you so much for your very welcome.
Bye Bye. Sorry, it was a little confused.
Oh No, no, it's great. You're
wonderful. Thank you. All right.
You're very welcome sir.
Wait a minute.
So at 16 eight I don't know.
Here's why I'm saying that we have
to figure out when you arrived.
I rattled later because I got in and I
got out. Remember cause I was so pregnant.
Right. You don't want to stay
long. So I got in and I got out,
which leads me to believe that I'm the
later check it and the 21st and didn't
you move rooms?
You started in one room and then we
Matt or something like that.
Which hotels? That's what it was.
I'm thinking eight Oh eight okay.
Okay.
Hmm. Well I mean one other thing we
could do, by the way, what if you,
you guys all search online?
Cincinnati renaissance or
Renaissance Hotel. Cincinnati Fart.
Then whenever anybody starts typing in
the Renaissance Hotel in Cincinnati.
Okay.
It'll say Cincinnati Fart.
If like a few hundred of you do it,
it'll definitely Google. Well yeah,
they'll definitely like why does it say
this is that he fart when people look up
our hotel. So here's the
uh, the Cincinnati part.
Oh my gosh. Yeah. So right
now its renaissance hotel,
Cincinnati c and right now the things
say renaissance to toss him steady Ohio,
Cincinnati wedding,
Cincinnati parking.
We can make it say
Cincinnati fart right here.
Besides Hotel Cincinnati Fart.
Okay.
Now war room.
Are we going?
I does anyone know the precise location
of this isn't a far as the first result.
She must have looked that up.
[inaudible] 16.
Must've been the room.
That was the route we must have
talked about is we announced those,
this is back then. Okay. Oh
it's, that's why she goes 16,
18. Yeah, but she said six
18? No, she said 16. 16,
18. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. So
then I guess it's 16, 18,
cause that's hot off the heels of
the actual events. Spell that for me.
That's, that's what she was
reading. She was reading.
Oh my God. How funny is that?
Yeah. Hilarious. Well good.
Now you guys know where to go. Yeah.
Renaissance Hotel. 1618 you know what?
Maybe just walked by eight oh
eight and see if anything's there.
Maybe you could still smell
it. Yeah, maybe you do. I
end up staying in that room.
Please send us a picture. Uh, I like to
see it, tweet it and be really funny.
And it happened in the doorway and if you
could actually in the doorway in form.
No, it was, it was inside the
room, Babe. Oh really? It wasn't,
I didn't know my thought. I went to
hug you and I'd come in the room.
And where was I standing?
We were standing like the bathrooms over
here near the closet were in the room.
And then I farted. Right. The
Renaissance Hotel rooms 1618.
So this girl just pulled this up.
She took it very seriously.
Yeah.
She googled Cincinnati
fire fire. Yeah. She just,
she just realized she was
talking to this fucking face.
So fun. It was amazing.
Yeah. That's so funny.
Do they have a banquet room there?
Oh yeah. They have everything there.
You know, maybe we should do like
some huge, that's what I was thinking.
Why don't we do the podcast from like
their banquet room one time and then all
walk up to the room. 1618 pilgrimage
to the room and let's see. Yeah,
maybe reenact it.
And maybe you the reenacted,
like civil war reenactment.
What
guys? It was a right here
guys. Everybody gather around.
The longest part of my life happened
and in this hotel and I were,
I'll never forget it.
I will never forget that fart.
That was a powerful long and it can only
happen with a gift of pregnancy. Yeah.
I think that was why it was so
special. You're definitely, uh, yeah.
Ooh.
My name is mark.
I'm 20 years old and I'm in a
relationship with 15 inflatable animal.
Okay. What do you think
you want to fuck this guy?
He's not that bad. He's better than
Trump. You'd fuck that guy over Trump?
Of course.
Well,
he's probably not gonna want.
Those are the punish and preachers I
have to hang out with in my life. I know.
I'll eat with him. Boy, you want my phone?
Because you're on watch TV together to
find a blender show. You like my base,
my blade doubles. That's
good. Short, snappy. If I do
take my levels out swimming,
what do you feel like though as it,
yeah, that's a good face. If, uh,
if you're a parent and this is like, I
was just thinking that if this was Ellis,
yeah, I'd beat the shit out
of him. Really old school.
I'd beat the inflatable shit out
of him. Snipe. Make them going.
What might make them go harder into it
though, right? I, there's some kind of,
what's wrong with this guy? You
know, there's a lot wrong with them,
but how does this happen? That's
what I want to know. How does this,
how can we make sure Ellis doesn't,
cause that didn't start overnight.
That's not like I'm just gonna
fucking play doubles from Nolan.
These white marks
and six years ago when he
purchased a whale for cool.
Since then, the 20 year old college
student has added 14 animals too,
was inflatable family and even
prefers that he's mentally ill though.
Severely. Right? Well, if you prefer them
over people, then it becomes a problem,
right? Yeah, I think so. Yeah. I think
c'mon inflatable pool toys I love is
that they're soft. They're cuddly.
The bigger they are, the better they
are. Kind of means there's more to love.
It's really nice to have somebody to
talk to him. You don't get eaten my soda.
Okay.
I mean you could also talk to a person
he's not going to get across. Right.
And you can't be separated
from them for more than a day.
Oh boy.
At school when I start missing them and
it's almost like if I'm going a little
bit crazy once I go home,
basically give him a hug.
Give him a kiss. Yeah. It's been
like family time together. Okay.
We can knock them over by you if we want.
Every one of my inflatables
has a different personality.
A little down there.
They don't ya
the out for everybody. Yeah, and the food
he's wasting. What are you talking about?
They're going to eat it.
Okay.
There's probably just not hungry right
now. You've got to give him a minute.
Do you think when this airs
that school gets better or no?
What'd you guys do this weekend?
Well, we were watching TLC.
Plain bowls has a different personality.
They don't sound like
different types of music.
Some don't like to just
be lazy and sleep all day.
Okay.
Different types of music like me and my
girlfriend. Me Harmony. What's her name?
Your 15 year old? Yeah, January
Courtney. Courtney Retina,
but Brett was covered a wise,
my boyfriend [inaudible].
You guys want to cover or not? I like to
just be lazy and sleep all day and yeah.
I won't say they get along together.
I would say they all like to sleep all
day from what I can see forever. Yeah.
God so troubling. Yeah. Now I look
at that. Every time I see a Weirdo.
Now I got a, what are the parents feel
like somebody's changed. Yeah, I know.
I go that that somebody
signed. Of course. Oh my God.
Somebody loved and nurtured and
took care of you. Is it any fucking,
you're a fucking retard.
Cool toys now, asshole. Yeah.
Now he's so dependent on gene is inflated.
This appointment can be separated
from them for more than a day damage.
But I'm at school. When I started
missing, we already covered that.
My mother really wasn't there for me
when I was a child. Mom's fallen mom,
mom,
double whale actually started feeling
all that love and compassion and I never
go,
I'm never leaving you Alice. What? She
would give him a hug right now. I know.
Can we pause this extra sun?
No. 11 no, I'd never do that.
That's what it is. Mom was never around
and play double animals were, you know,
he's lucky and fightable animals were
around and not some creepy guy. Neighbor,
Huh? Yeah. Kids like
him get preyed on. Yeah.
Hmm.
That is terrible. Well now I feel like I
should have for making fun of that guy.
He had a bad mom.
Yeah.
That's what happens. They can all fuck a
toy if you're not a good mom, like a toy.
Yup. Uh, by the way, we've been getting
a lot of people on Twitter as well, uh,
wondering when they're going to
have a double pipe. Classic one.
What happened for me? When
will it happen guys? You know,
when will I see a shooting star?
When will I win the Lotto? You know,
you gotta wait, you gotta be patient?
Yeah. Give it some time. Let life happen.
Live your life and it'll
just happen. Yeah. Like love.
Do you think I'll just stumble into
a foursome today, right? Um, no,
maybe, but probably not a forced some,
Huh? Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
That the equal of it.
It's the same. Yeah. Okay.
Are you thinking of another
couple? Pacifically a foursome
know three other like,
Oh, if you're a guy, like three chicks
are going to bang me today all together,
you know? Oh, you weren't thinking
like another married couple,
no kids swing or something. I think I
know what you're thinking about, but no,
it wasn't, I didn't even think it what
I'm trying to give people real world,
you know,
positions like, ways of thinking
of this. Yeah. Okay. Um,
I want to thank you for your, uh,
dismissive wave the other day.
We can have it. I did not
do that. You're exaggerate.
You're lying about how that
went. I'm always like, you are,
you're like amber heard and
I'm Johnny Depp. However,
I'm just trying to bring my
character's home. All those characters.
I was looking at you lovingly
out the kitchen window. Yeah. Uh,
the kitchen overlooks the backyard
and I am lovingly looking out and my
husband's playing with the two
dogs and the baby's asleep.
It was like the end of a perfect day.
And I look through and I did lightly
tap on the glass. I go, hey sweetie, hi.
And then you go,
wait,
what was that?
That's not how that
went. Oh, how did it go?
You stood in the window and you went like,
like that.
And I just went,
okay.
Like, hi, I see you. But, but did you
see the shittiness? It was like, yeah,
dummy. Hi, dumb con. Yeah,
I see you retard. Like I was a retarded
kid. Like I was licking the glass.
That's a slight exaggeration.
Someone's goes to live school
day when they get back home.
Oh,
what happened?
Yeah, I like that. No. Yeah, no shit.
It was the same. It was like a no shit.
But for your hand you to get her
a push present. Yeah. No Shit.
Same weekend as the Cincinnati Fart.
Yeah,
no shit was the same week.
It's room 1618 yeah it is.
Oh no confusion now cause we must have
set it on the air when it happened.
Now that I'm remembering it was we
were up higher. It was 16th floor.
Where are we? Yeah. I'm trying
to remember the view and I just,
I know I see them in my head but I,
I know cause then Jane came over with
Eric and they open the window and he was
smoking out the window and I remember we
were high enough to do that whenever he
was smoking cigarettes out the window of
our room. Yeah. You don't remember that?
No, I don't remember that.
Maybe you weren't in there.
It was just pregnant me like hey,
thanks for putting that out the window.
Oh fuck man.
Yeah.
I remember when they came here and
smoke and we were like, no, we weren't.
So again, did they? I don't
remember. You weren't here.
You were either out or in bed already.
Yeah.
And they went on a walk and you
guys just go smoke. She goes, no,
I go, are you ha do you have a
breath mint? She's like, yeah, just,
just breath man after a walk. Yeah. Yeah.
Your sister also feels that liberty to
just rummage through our pantry too.
She studies, I have real sweat till thrive
now. And she was just rummaging. Yeah.
You got,
why do you got like
starts opening cabinets.
Refrigerator. But do you have
hair is you don't have shit. Huh?
Um,
why are you opening your Oh,
I can't look at my fucking brother.
I can't look through your stuff.
Yeah.
Okay.
Can families a little worst? Isn't
it just like whatever dude? No.
This morning we are talking
about a childhood stuff and uh,
you asked me, you're like, were your
parents super affectionate with you?
And I was like,
and I thought they were,
apparently
I'm learning all this great
stuff about my childhood.
We were raised in basically a work camp.
See, my therapist says,
she's like, you grew up with
extreme deprivation. I'm like,
it wasn't that bad. Come on.
Like I, I even am like we were,
cause we smother our son with so much.
Yeah.
Physically to the point where
he's like, yeah, he's like,
cause I'm just all day hugging
them, kissing and hugging
or kissing, kiss, kiss,
kiss, kiss till he's like,
sometimes I'll kiss him,
he's happy and I'll keep kissing him
until he cried and he'll be like, stop it.
He does this. It's too much affection.
I can't stop. So I go, Huh? I go, yeah.
I was talking about my family,
super affectionate to Latin,
very effusive. And even my dad, my dad
hugs, kisses all the time and I go,
was it like this for you too? And
you basically were like, like your,
your brain basically stopped working
for a second and you're like, excuse me.
And I go,
yeah.
So like do your dad didn't
hug you and kiss you go,
well he would do things
like grab my shoulder and go
like, Hey, I love you. Okay.
Like what?
Yeah, my dad grabbed your shoulder and
squeezes it and he goes, I love you.
Okay, I love you. And then
he pats you. I swear to God.
And you wouldn't get all over yourself?
No.
If my parents said that to me, I'd
lose my mind. I know. Really? No.
Now my mother would hug me, but I
didn't like it cause I didn't like her.
I didn't like her. Everything, you know,
shoots every now and then
she would hug me. It was,
it was too hard and she smelled too
perfumy and her hair was always like a
helmet. So it was just like, ah. It was
like, I didn't like it. We'll see that.
I think about that. I understand
that your dad's thing must be,
because he also just didn't come up
in it and affectionate household,
you know, people usually duplicate
what they're used to. You know,
and I don't know if you noticed
last time I think he was here,
he went to shake your hand. No, didn't I
went to shake his hand. He gave me a hug.
Okay, so he hugs, he hugs. Hello?
Yeah. Now, yeah, that's after it being,
you know, training him.
Yeah. But no, he never,
I don't remember him, you know, hugging
me as a kid. You hugged me that day twice.
And then when we went to his place,
he hugged me again. Yeah, so he's,
he's become more affectionate.
It's an older person but happens to
have some older people too, but not at,
not in my youth. No, not really. No,
it is. I love you. Okay. I love you,
but like good morning kiss
and stuff like that. No.
What really? I Good Morning
Kiss. Yeah. No. Oh God.
You got home from school. Hey, good big
kiss. You're hilarious. First of all,
my parents were nowhere to be
found when I got home from school,
but like when they go home and relax,
kiss you, you're out of your mind. Really?
No,
no. My mother would come home and
I would hear her and I would hide,
but he doesn't sound that crazy to you.
If you think of it in this terms,
imagine a Ellis getting home. Oh, I will.
I'm going to go nuts. I mean, I go nuts.
Just I haven't seen him in like a day and
I'm going, no, no. It wasn't like that.
My Dad or my mom would come home and
they would say high or low or whatever.
Treating you. They screaming in
the hall law and then you go, hey,
and that was it. But I don't recall ever
being like, I'm so happy to see my folks,
you know,
that wouldn't be disappointed them down.
You're going to eat or I'm gonna fucking
make you shit. Yeah. So in Hungarian,
I heard a few sayings. Okay. There's,
there's one occur on buff on the cubs,
which best sauce. That's, I'm
going to hit your head so hard.
You're going to shit in your pants.
Yeah.
All [inaudible] is, I'm
on a hedge. You so hard.
Your head's gonna fall off.
That's another nice one.
And get a sub on the buzz
mag that's come and eat.
Fucking come and eat basically.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah. Welcome. Surreal.
Welcome to America. Now.
I know I now and I,
now we're watching.
The Americans were such a
good show. I love show, Dude.
If you're not into the Americans, great
show to dive into and lose yourself for,
we're in the second season. Yeah. Um,
it takes place in the early
eighties, so, you know, Cold War,
they're KGB agents living in America
under deep cover. Keri Russell,
which is great. It reminds me a lot
of you. Thank you. She's just so cold.
Or you can see the coldness in her eyes.
Yeah. And then, uh, what's the guy's name?
Who plays her husband? I don't know,
but I like him too. Eyes. Right.
So like something like that. He's
tremendous actor. They both are. She's,
she's amazed, but they're, the
writing is just phenomenal.
I also knew there reminds me of you, cause
she gives it up immediately in a lot.
So she reminds me of you.
Yeah. Uh, blood farts his back.
We got to start watching. We haven't
even, don't you even, we have to start.
We have to watch. I can't wait to see if
that idiot, uh, the Daryl, oh no, he's,
he's gone. Yeah. But then it's the
son of, yeah. Yeah. Derelict Pos.
Pos is back. I owe him a pos. Danny.
Danny was such a piece of shit.
I just, I love that Florida trash
though. Are you feeling today?
Oh,
well,
let's see what's on the chart today for
how we feel about our gender. Let's see.
Um,
I feel I like this one.
Arrow gender agenda that is
influenced by your surroundings.
I kind of feel like that right now.
Okay. A little arrow. January. Oh hmm.
Okay. What about affect,
affect, do gender,
a gender that is effected by mood swings.
That's pretty good too.
Let me see that. How about I just hit the
scroll. See where we land, right? Yeah.
Look,
we're still in the A's right now.
Okay, hold on. Okay. See transgendered,
we know that once legit cause people
about cut their stuff off to be that,
that you got a real bio gender,
a gender that feels connected
to nature in some way.
I'm definitely biogen. Oh wait, is
there a dog gender cause I love my dog.
So it's funny you mentioned that.
Um,
not only is there that there's a,
there's actually this what,
how did I know that?
I swear I didn't know this was coming
from a role model and I'm not running
around on the falls are looking country.
I can totally understand why people
would think it's strange to identify as
being a dog.
It's so well relax after a long day.
I'm not having to cope with
normal human life. Sure, sure.
I get it.
I'm
not having to deal with
normal human car moves.
Uh Yeah.
Did they go number two outside like
dogs and number money that you mentioned
that no, I don't know actually.
I know that that was so bizarre.
It was you just feeling you're feeling
very um, a canine gender today.
Yeah. And connected to your
bio, gender wow. Status.
Which the two come together from
your astral gender non binary.
I can't be non-binary but then
identify dog gendered. Right.
I think you can, can I be, I
am non binary and dark. Gender.
Okay. I can't wait to meet
the president and tell him.
And what Pronoun would you or should
you be referring to me as because I am a
dog gendered. Am I, it's
a great question. A,
I'm not a he she cause I'm on binary.
Yeah. How would you refer to a dog?
Well, it's a him or her, but
they're non binary dogs. Maybe the,
then you go back to the and then they
and them preferred pronoun. Okay. Yeah.
Okay. That's a great point. It was
really good that you mentioned it.
You have to say the right
pronouns, pronouns, or not.
Any preference. We show that.
Do we have that on deck?
Sorry to that guy because I
feel like last week, oh right.
To see him and he really needs to be seen
and heard and validated and everybody
needs to know the proper pronouns
for that guy. Interesting.
Color,
gender agenda associated with one
or more colors and the feelings.
Hughes. I can't read it. It's too small.
Emotions and and or objects
associated with that color.
Maybe use like pink gender, blue gender,
yellow jet. That is such horse shit.
Color, color, gendered.
They've, I mean listen,
I think this isn't a front to people
that really have gender identity issues.
You know, if you're like I'm a man
trapped in a woman's body, vice versa.
This stuff, this has to be
an embarrassment to people
that are, have like Ge,
like genuine gender problem
or gender identity things,
you know, I don't know what makes you say
that? So this is, this is, I'm offended.
I am a fan. Yeah. Let me see.
I think like here's one burst gender
agenda that comes and intense bursts of
feeling and quickly fades
back to the original state.
Now this is under, where did you find
gender fluid? support.tumblr.com guys,
look at the site and figure out which
gender you are and make sure to tell us
and let everybody know your
proper pronouns this week.
It's really important
that you let us know.
We would definitely want everybody to
get their proper pronouns in their,
so astral gender colored gendered.
I can,
I think we could.
Oh yeah. I think people
need to see this guy, right?
We didn't really show him before,
so let's see if I can get into play.
Don't you feel like this is totally
offensive to people that really have like
gender identity?
We get her fucking,
this is the newest video on my Oscar
gender terrorist playlists on my channel,
Dakota, all my playlist because
I posted anything in a long time.
If you would like to know why,
check out my ass Dakota life
update coming out video there.
You just want to make a video
that I can link people to me.
There's a lot of homage to
everyone in the world to bear.
My pronouns are not preferred.
They're not a preference.
They are mandatory for
interaction with me. Um,
you know what's crazy? I don't want
to interact with you all you've met.
You've made us a lot of points. Yes, he's
got, she shaved his eyes. Yes. Sorry.
They shaved their eyebrows and sanity
have their beard going and total insanity.
But the eyebrow shaving is
almost universally. Yeah.
It remember the movie mental illness, the
movie, the wall, Pink Floyd, the wall.
There's a scene where he breaks down.
He has a mental breakdown and he,
I believe he shaves his eyebrows
off and his hair and everything.
And that's a sign of mental illness.
Uh,
royal Tenenbaums Richie Tenenbaum
tries to kill himself. Yeah.
He shaves everything off. It's a, it's
a metaphor of some kind for losing.
You're not,
or just out of your fucking mind.
You and I have eyebrows or walk the
streets of downtown Los Angeles. And, um,
every time you see somebody with a shaved
eyebrows, just know that it should.
It's really about to go down with them.
Yeah. Shit's gone. And, and I love the,
the Old Lady Turban. This
is, I got out of the shower,
my hair is wet and then the
various Wicca Jars, you know,
full of warlock things.
And here's a apples and boy he has a
little shrine. I chart for the DMV.
I mean there's a low cut,
low cut.
So much happening for you. You know what?
This guy is so fucking confused guys.
I'm shit.
I mean
expect everyone in the world's
who understands. Yeah. Asia,
you don't have anything to stand on.
This is what you're going to abide by
if you're going to be in our lives.
And that's all there is to it.
So anyway,
I hope you guys are doing well.
My Non Binary folks. I love you.
I hope that you're having a
fantastic time. I hope you
have a good Halloween. Um,
if you choose not to go out and you
want to stay in and thank you for taking
care of yourself. This is not something
that you're obligated to deal with.
I know it's hard for us at this
time of year because you know,
everybody thinks are
fucking gender identity and
expression and the whole thing
isn't it?
It's a fucking costume in the first place.
So costume day is amateur night oftentimes
is a little bit hard for us to deal
with,
so,
all right. How does he take, so
he takes Halloween personally.
Now it's a personal offense guys.
Got You got so many problems.
I'd say the gender identity
is the last on the list.
This guy's Super Jesus
Christ. Fuck you. Come,
come out Outta Camo gender. What's that?
Well, you know you aren't cisgender,
but you settled with your assigned
gender for the time being.
Okay. How about Delis? DALYSIA gender?
What's that from the the Latin word.
Delete him.
Any favorite?
Meaning that feeling of having
more than one simultaneous gender,
you are preferring one that fits better.
I don't even understand that.
While you shouldn't, I don't
even understand this. Do you do?
Are they teaching kids this Horse
Shit in school? They better not be.
I'll pull my phone.
Okay.
Where can we send Ellis that he won't
hear about this dumb shit. Yeah, this is,
I mean what such an asshole? Yeah, I
think it's an attention. I'm sub gender,
mostly a gender with a bit of
another gender. Fuck you man.
May mostly age,
gender with a bit of another gender.
So I mean I don't even understand.
How about surge gender?
How's that having a gender
that is 100% one gender,
but with more of another
gender added on top of that.
You can't be more than a
hundred percent that's so crazy.
That's not even logically possible.
Try Agenda,
not listen to this shit.
Try Gender.
The feeling of having three simultaneous
or fluctuating genders. You don't,
they don't exist. There's
only two genders. What do you
mean three? There's a, yeah.
Okay. You fucking square bug.
It is a fucking, hey, wait a minute.
Doris over here thinks
there's two genders.
Fucking retard.
Andrea,
what is it? You know what
it is? People are bored.
There's nothing happening though.
Life is so easy in America.
We're looking for things to get
all fired up about. Yeah, it does.
It have to invent things to get
offended about this fucking kid.
If there's a war going on in his ass was
about to be drafted into a war and you
think there'd be time for him to paint
his fucking nails and do his tats and
fill his weird, which is actually like to
see a video where they sent him choose.
Yes. Less developed countries have
him explain his situation. Yeah.
Why don't you go to Kabul, Afghanistan
and explain your gender problems.
Don't announce to people
I'm neither gender watch.
And then they just go, he's a witch.
Let's kill him. Alright, set him on fire.
Um, our Budapest go to Hungary.
My modern, amazing. Let's discuss.
Great. What about an hour later
when I smell bacon I could eat.
So at one point do you shut
out the window? You ever do
that for old time's sake?
No,
I in tubs because I just couldn't take
it no more walls up while I was taking a
shower. Why get out? No, let me tell
you something. For some reason on, no,
listen to me jasmine. If for some
reason though for about two years,
every time I hate going and I like
shooting before I go in the shower,
but I liked shooting before
I go into the shower.
I don't want to take a shot of him
walking around with a dirty ass all day
because at least you got a better,
you got to stop every hallway and clean
and then it gets hot out. I don't like,
I like taking this shit
before I go on the show.
But that like that day system don't
work according to your fucking pussy
schedule. Yep. Wash and then you come out.
Some days I was taking a shower and
sometimes the water would hit my back.
I have to take a shit and he had some
words. Let me tell you something.
Would you want to dry off and to
take the shit? And it does suck.
It makes you have to go to the
bathroom as soon as the water hit you.
So sometimes you do something,
a wet toilet and it's a horrible feel,
worse feeling. It's a horrible feeling.
So for awhile there I was just saying,
fuck it. Let me just shit
while I'm taking a shower. You
know?
I would either unscrew that thing.
Sometimes I pick it up my
hand and just draw it. Right.
That's how disgusting I am.
Sometimes I would just shit in Vegas.
Sometimes I was eating pills and doing
blow and I would just sit in the thing
with my legs open like a Chinese guy.
You know how they shouldn't try them,
but only with water hitting
my boss at the same time.
He's saying he would squat down into
the drain and shit in the shower.
Do you guys think I'm nasty?
Oh No. This is a whole this,
this is your Mother Teresa. Yes. Yes.
Guy's profile and watch the shit
come out with all the barnacles. Oh,
and then I get like the salt and
push it down the hole. Yes, I would.
I'm disgusting.
I got to admit to it right now.
Anybody who's ever taken a shower at
Joey Diaz is out. No, not this outcome.
I wouldn't do it in the
hotel. Oh, okay. Oh Jesus.
We should down the peanuts would
get stuck to the thing drain.
Couldn't go back down.
Oh no,
we're speechless. Just when
you think you know, Joey Diaz,
we thought him shitting
on the tree was cray cray.
He has such a crazy story
that I want him to, uh,
to tell that I heard,
uh,
from somebody else in the whole story is
the kind of story I have to check first.
We were like, I can't just bring it
up, you know? Yeah. That's not say no.
I mean, I'm sorry, I'm still
processing what I've just heard.
Like I can't move on just yet.
I need to process it. Hold on.
He said he moves the drain thing and then
he squats like a Chinese guy and shit
in the shower in a way,
you know,
like as far as like addressing
your workflow, it's,
it makes sense. Like I have to sanitize
my hands, but I want to also feel dirty.
Just hearing. Yeah. I want to,
I know it's so weird, right?
I don't know why this makes me feel.
I think I'm going to take
a shower and just not shit
right after this. Um, but he,
uh,
he's such a savage Charlie.
Okay.
Does it makes sense to do,
except it says no sense. No,
it makes sense to do if you go to,
to just shit where you're standing.
It doesn't make any sense.
Of course it does because that's
because of the water cleans it.
Know what I'm saying? It's so filthy
and repulsive that nobody does it.
If you were to be like, Hey, where
should I? Shit, you just share wherever,
like where the water's flowing right now.
But you're shitting in the, yeah, no, you,
you gave me so much crap.
It's not,
I'm saying showering and you're
letting Joey get a pass on
squatting in the drain or I'm not
explaining, well, what I'm trying to say,
but I'm trying to say is on some level,
the act of shitting where
water is flowing makes sense.
Except doing it where you're
bathing is just so disgusting.
You know what I mean?
Like,
it's like you're pissing in the river
because it's right. The, you know,
you don't have to get out and not find
the spy. So you're saying, but it's so,
it's so good. Disgusting that he above
and beyond anything I could do or Ari.
Ari and I are both straight shed the
shower people shower people. This Joey,
this is okay. I'm speechless. Yeah,
it's a Joey Diaz has a wife.
Doesn't that blow your mind?
Some woman. I love him. I love you Joey.
It's just so great.
Gnarly.
Okay. Alright, so it's over.
It's over. It's over. Okay.
What is wrong with you?
It's in my dealing.
He just made himself on his eating stuff.
That's disgusting.
You're going to fucking throw
up there. It's gone. It's gone.
I thought it was appropriate to
play after shitting in the shower.
Okay.
Are we done? Yeah, we're done.
Y'all finished. Wow. We're done.
We're finished and we're done.
We're finished. And we'd done it.
I hate that. I don't know what
I'm going to do on Ellis bars.
You're going to have to take care of him
if he's sick. You know? What do you mean?
I don't know if I can stomach. Yes, you
will have a hard time. It's different.
It's your boy.
I know it's your boy guy and I'll be fine.
Um,
how bad do you feel like that is?
What, what'd he did?
What was going on there,
Joey or the gagging a Joey.
Uh,
I just don't know how his
wife handles that. It's a lot.
You know what I mean?
What do you use? I'm looking for
what is this sphincter relaxation?
What does that, I dunno, man. Must
have been, it could be my mom.
You can fucking tribe called quest.
That's not a song. Is it? Sphincter
relaxation. That's what it's called.
Yeah.
All right. Anyways. Anyways, any ever,
any way. I know a big shout out to all
the mommies who came out to La Jolla.
So many mommy's. Thank you. So
for coming, it was the best.
It was so fun to walk upstage,
walk on stage and just hear a litany of,
Hey Hitlers and uh,
know all the sayings.
It was so funny. It was so much
fun. Yeah. Yeah. Thanks for coming.
It was really good. And you were there
with, uh, the full Fart, the full,
full charge, full charge. Crushed
it. He had some killer sets.
We, uh, weighed some
talks down the streets.
Breeds big shout out to
Ryan down the street.
Who opened his a Taco shop
for us. Oh yeah. He also, um,
is that your name? I hope so. What was it,
Ryan? All right. I'm trying to remember.
I have no memory, but yeah, and it gave
you a late night talks, late night talks.
Thank you for that. I've never been
to La Jolla. It's fancy San Diego.
It's nice. Okay. You've never been
there at all or just to the comedy store
have never been to to La Jolla San Diego.
Yeah, it's, you know,
it's like the nice part.
It's like the Beverly Hills of
San Diego. Okay, cool. Yeah. Um,
hold on one second. Okay. Okay.
Let me find out this guy's Tacos.
We're back forwards. Uh,
the name of the Taco Shop,
Don Carlos Taco shop right down the
street from the La Jolla comedy store.
Thank you for hooking us up with late
night talks. Nice Polish, Ron and myself.
Thank you dude. That was really cool.
Yeah, I was almost going to eat some, uh,
you know,
protein bars from where you got real food
and liquor store because of that guy.
Very nice. You Sir. Um, let's
get into some two fees, right?
No.
Okay.
Oh
Wow.
Cyber Dental update. Oh, I love
these. How are your teeth doing?
Are still yellow.
Did you use the whitening size?
How many times have you tried the
white name? Once. Just one. Yeah.
Did it burn a lot? Yeah. It hurts for
the next couple of days too. That's good.
That means it's working. I'm
going to do it again. Yeah,
I'm going to do it again.
Yeah, you got to repeat it.
Are they going to do it
tonight? Okay. Been a while.
Uh, but I'm going to do it more
often because you're not, you're not,
I saw how much we're putting in, so it
was too hot. You got to just put like A.
Dot. I thought it wasn't dark.
You are like, like a glop.
There's a way to minimize the pain.
That's definitely it.
Here's the deal. I'll update from
some listeners. Uh, Tom and Christina,
I just wanted to share my appreciation
for the dental updates segment and your
overall awareness of dental
hygiene and care. You got it.
The reason I shared the love of dental
care is because I am a dental hygienist
and it's my job to stop people from doing
the stupid shit that people write in
about.
Fortunately,
I rarely see that crazy shit because I
work in a military dental clinic. Oh.
And we are required to have a dental
exam cleaning once a year no matter what.
I just wish that people would understand.
They get one set of set of teeth that
last a lifetime and once those are gone,
that's it.
If you fucked that up,
you're stuck with a lifetime of not
biting into an apple and you're stuck with
denture cream.
Keep up the great work.
I hope to make it to a live show
one day. Remember, floss them shits,
peace out. Fuckboys tray the
floss boss. Thank you. Tray.
That thing got kicked.
That moved. Came. Okay.
Um, I would like to ask the professionals
out there and dental industry. Yeah,
I have a cap that's kind of wonky.
Let's a back tooth.
It's Kinda wonkily placed. I'm going
to have to replace it eventually.
Crown Sarno. Cap a crown your own. Yeah.
Um, thank you. And when I floss it,
I feel like it's tender Rony like it's,
it's just precarious and I'm just
wondering, is there a way I can floss?
Is there a technique I can use it?
Maybe I'm just afraid of flipping up that
crown if that's possible for flossing,
you could do that whole thing of
uh, going to a dentist or, yeah.
I mean I was kind of waiting until I was
a little recover from childbirth. Oh,
you and your fucking son, Huh? Before I
started messing with me. Wait, they can,
did you give birth again or something?
How learned six months go.
You can't go to the dentist.
They have your teeth checked.
I had them cleans after I had Ellis.
What?
I have to have this crown replaced
and I really put in that off.
I've got to tell you I needed to do
the new dentist because we moved.
I don't have one yet.
I know we should call 'em oh, the
doc and ask him. Oh, for real?
Yeah,
we'll do that cause I don't want to go
to one of these like showbizzy Dennis
down here in La and the,
you know they had jack you so
fucking hard on these prices
and they do the whole thing
where something happens
to me and then you say it
happened to you. Remember? That's the one
that's so funny. Oh my God. Did I swear?
That's why I don't have dental insurance.
Did they?
Did it did.
It happened that way to me.
Maybe we could go to a dentist and find
out why your teeth are so yellow candy.
All right,
look like candy corn.
Somebody else wrote in.
Hey Mom and dad mouth.
I just wanted to let you know you're
talking about getting your teeth fixed.
Don't mind the cost finally inspired me.
Good to get the work I've been
avoiding for a year. Good for you.
It includes 24 months of nonbinary
braces or gender fluid extractions,
including a top front that needs
an implant. As I've failed,
I have a failed root
canal with a huge abscess,
which requires a cow bone graft.
Fuck. Finally, jaw surgery.
It's the final step to polyamorous to
extend my bottom jaw forward to correct my
bike,
which has been the root of all these
problems about six months and I'm so happy
with the progress. Every time I see
myself in the mirror I ask, Hey Hitler,
where's the com?
Yeah,
it feels like my browns
are all fours and I finally
got my life. Good for you.
Weirdest thing is my front tooth,
which is essentially a flipper. Oh,
except it's connected to braces. Wire.
Okay. All right, so he's saying that the
fake to this connected to the braces.
Okay.
Yeah.
Love from New Zealand where the
gender pronouns are not optional.
Fantastic. I wish I knew who wrote
that. I don't know who wrote that one.
Doesn't say ah, but yeah, New Zealand.
Shout out to all the Kiwis, man.
Good. Good for you, Mommy. Yeah.
Gotcha. Take care of your teeth.
You'll feel so much better when they look
good for sure. Oh yeah, man. You know,
sometimes I look at pictures of me and
everything else can look all fucked up,
you know? But if your teeth
look nice, it totally look,
makes you look so much nicer. Really does.
Um, do you want to read some Fan Mail?
I don't have it in front of me. I have
it in front of me. Like do you want Oh,
okay. Yeah. Put it up here.
Sure. Here we go. The top.
Yes. Hi Mommy. Just
wanted to say fuck you.
I wear a condom on my tongue.
Love Danielle.
That's from last week, right? It was
last week's episode. Who said that? Uh,
the Cruzee arm Muslim guy. Oh,
that's right. I'll fucking wear it.
Kind of where my tongue. Yeah.
Yeah. That guy was really nice.
People are looking for that video. We
got to put it on our site. All right.
We've been rebuilding the site.
If you,
if some of you guys noticed
lastic immediately. Oh shit man.
We had a,
a problem with our old site,
so we got a new site built
kind of a as much as we could.
And what did we use? Squarespace.
Squarespace. So it's a Squarespace site.
And um, that's your mom's
house. podcast.com. We're
working on getting the clips.
You got the Info on how to get those
up there, right? So, all right, cool.
We'll add those up. Um,
here's another email.
Hey, Hitler's. Yeah,
I had an experience today that I am not
sure qualifies as a double pipe classic.
Here we go.
While at work,
I went to the bathroom cause I stood in
front of the toilet just about to pee.
I felt the sneeze coming on and
wouldn't you know it. I farted,
sneeze and Pete at the same time,
all three bodily functions shot
out of me simultaneously. Oh Wow.
I'm not sure if this is as good as a
double pipe classic or even better.
Please let me know your thoughts.
Are you out of your Goddamn mind? No,
it's not better. No, it doesn't count. I
keep getting this fucking question. Hey,
if I sneeze and far, is that a double
pipe? It's not the same. You know,
you just have a little extra
turbo boost on your fart.
Yeah. You have that night trope and you
just add a little extra juice to it.
The rules of a double pipe are
burping and farting. Same time they,
it doesn't happen often. It's not going
to happen to you every Wednesday. God,
you just have to relish it when it
does happen. Just stop. You sit down,
you say a prayer,
you thank y'all way for,
of course it doesn't happen a lot.
No last week you to shout out to the
bear community and you requested some gay
bears to clarify some shit,
so here I am as a burly gay
dude to set you to straight.
Here's how it works
within the gay community,
especially when it comes to
the sub genre of bears, a bear,
simply an overweight guy
that is covered in body here.
It's literally that simple,
Aka Tommie Hines or Chewbacca.
With that said,
there are sub classes within the
gay community in regards to bear.
When I get interested in now this is what
I'm talking about here and odder is a
hair fit and slim guy
and otter is not fat.
No Dad Bod?
No,
nothing in auto is just simply a
regular fit dude that just happens to be
hearing my friend. John's
definitely an honor. All
generally otters are very fit and have
a six pack or less and they do lots of
labs and an Olympic size swimming pool.
Okay,
but that said you have the fake bears,
Aka smooth skins.
These are just fat guys that try
to identify themselves as bears,
but they are not bears
because they're not what?
Well what that said they are the chubs.
It's just big bears are smooth skins.
You have to be Harry in order to be there.
That's what he's saying.
If you're fat and hairless,
you're just fat. Like
Burt.
His chest isn't very hairy.
They probably would be like, why is
this guy so fat, fat Ed herring. Ah.
These guys are just straight up
heavy dudes. Like 500 pounds,
500 pound types of dudes.
The type of guys where the smells come
out of the roles of their fat. Yeah.
They try to come within the bear
community and then you have the muscle.
There's these guys are straight
up. Jack. I've seen these guys,
it's like Mac as that.
These are your typical muscle gym
freaks and they have body hair.
They don't have the typical beer
belly or anything like that.
What they are are just pure gym jocks
and are jacked to the tits with whatever
supplements they are using. Either
way they are kind of fucking hot. Wow.
So basically those are three typical
sub genres of bears within the gay
community.
Cope.
My experience with the Dick has helped
you to and understanding the mystical
bare sub genre,
Keith and jeans high and tight cognac
explaining to us we appreciate it.
That's really interesting. Yeah,
that's a lot of sub genre. Mac SF will
be considered a muscle there for sure.
Yeah. I don't know what
episodes those are awhile ago.
I love Mac and then we had his partner
at the time was listening to the show and
he um, he's like, we'll
answer your question. Also,
his partner was I think
an editor and it was like,
hey thought you might enjoy this.
A edit of some sort of Mac stuff.
I just worked on it for Gore.
Shit,
it's hard. Is is real be
spin. He's a real animal.
Only one Mac, SF, Google, m a C K,
s f or just download a hair suit.
Pursuits of their albums,
but don't look at work. All
right. It's intense. Real intense.
Um, I think that said jeans. Yup.
You got anything else? No. Good.
Tom Treats me like a frat brother.
Oh, maybe that's on the next step is,
excuse me. I'm I telling you that
career ago. Fart. I got to shit.
I'm like, am I a Frat Bro? I'm your wife.
Then you got to say that
we sit down for breakfast.
We're eating breakfast. I'm sitting
right next to you. Lift your leg up.
Fart at me.
You don't lift the other way.
You lift towards me as I'm
eating and you're like,
hey,
you're calling me the fucking Frat guy.
Unbelievable. Unbelievable. I
love you though. I love you too.
Um, okay, so we want to address this.
This is a really a big deal.
You know,
in this episode we called the hotel in
Cincinnati to get people the exact room
number where the Cincinnati fart
occurred. And there's, there was a little,
you know,
misunderstanding as far as a,
what I heard and what was repeated back.
And we're,
we're not yet at the exact room number.
We need to figure it out.
Right. And I want to be, I'm going
to come clean on little something.
So when we went to Cincinnati for,
it happened and we recorded
that episode August, 2015
and we said, oh, it's room 1618
and I remember in my head going,
wait, that's not the right room. That
was I think your parents room now. Yeah.
And I'm like, what? Because I know
at the time I go, that's not right.
I said that in my head.
So either at six 18 or eight oh eight or
eight oh eight and we're not giving up.
That's the thing. We just
want people to know, like,
we're gunna find out the
correct room number. We're just,
we're just not there yet.
We don't want to mislead anyone.
And we don't want you to think that
we're just going to quit on the room.
We don't want you to plan your summer
vacations around this information. Look,
it is the Renaissance Hotel in downtown
Cincinnati and it is either eight oh
eight or six 18 I'm almost
inclined to believe,
but not 1618 right? That
one of the numbers, right?
Because she said we listened
back and she's clearly said six.
I thought you said 16 I want to say
it's eight oh eight because of the band
eight Oh eight state.
It's an industrial plant and I remember
being like eight Oh eight state in my
head at the time.
You know when you make dumb association,
maybe you could check in and say,
can I get two keys,
one for eight oh run for six 18 and just
walk around both for a moment and see
if you smell anything or just stand there.
Close your eyes.
And if you feel a little extra movement,
you're in the right room. You know,
we're going to do a little more research
and figure out the correct room.
We'll make sure you guys do the
right, go, go to the right room,
the right things. Um, yeah.
Yeah. This is a big deal.
Yeah, this is a big deal. Well I
know and we're commemorating it.
It's very important stuff.
Figure out the correct room by looking
back at our flights and figuring out
exactly who checked in first.
You checked in first and I
flew in as late as I could.
We went to the wedding and
then I left the next day.
And you stayed on a day after my,
no,
but I don't know that I
checked into that hook.
Did I check into that hotel first?
You came from another room? He and I,
we started fresh together in
that room and the room stop.
So I don't know if you were, if you
were in a different hotel. I was.
That's what I'm trying to tell you. Okay.
I wasn't a different hotel. And you want,
what day was the wedding?
The wedding was on a Friday.
I think we'll,
all we have to do is look at the calendar
and we can look at the calendar and
figure it out. Yeah, because
I came as late as possible.
I came in the night before
the wedding, I believe. No,
no, no. I came for the dinner.
Yup.
Okay. Mystery. We're going to
ask too. It's a bit of a mystery.
Let's look right now. August it
was what day? Saturday of August.
22nd of 2015 is a Saturday.
Okay.
Yeah. Look here. Flight.
I flew from CVG to lax
on the 22nd on Saturday,
on Saturday from CVG,
so I flew in from lax to CBG on the 19th
so I checked into the hotel on the 19th
you wouldn't have checked it on the 19th
let the record show unless this is your
flight. Why would I have that in my phone?
That let's me confirmation crowed. Look,
it's all here. Christina flew in
was the, oh, that makes sense.
Cause the rehearsals Thursday,
the wedding's Friday, Saturday,
which means it was the first room number
she gave us the 19 which I think was
eight oh eight state
guys.
The Cincinnati fart happened in a,
it's eight oh eight and I know I
make a correction to the episode.
It's a very nice title.
It correctly because I know the day we
recorded it on the show, we set it wrong.
And in my head I went, should I say the
right number? And I was like, who cares?
You know, under the episode title, this
Cincinnati Farts.
Right?
Can we tag this audio onto the episode?
Maybe eight oh eight this is important.
This is really, really
vital information. Um, Gosh,
I'm really happy we were able
to resolve this. If you want,
you could address the fact that there's
a diaper in front of you on the table.
I don't know if went that'd people,
what's going on there?
This is a dog diaper. I got an Amazon
using our banner. Your mom's house.
podcast.com.
Deter the dog from urinating
on our staircase cause there's,
it's carpeted for people that are
curious too. She doesn't pee in it.
No, she just doesn't until
she goes outside. And where
are we taking off? Right?
It's part of potty training and yes,
when she's house broken for the most part,
she's just young. Yeah,
she's stupid. Sit on.
Or are you guys Cincinnati fart roommate.
Oh wait,
it's eight oh eight eight oh eight.
It's eight oh eight. All right.
We should get out of here. This, oh,
this says, what is this gaping dad.
Yeah. Is that good? Yeah. Yeah, it's good.
It's really good guys. You
really going to love it. Okay.
I don't know why this is a, having a lot
of, uh, Internet problems at the house.
Last couple of bad problems is really
cool cause dad doesn't know how to do
things. I don't know why I'm dad's never
know how to use technology. That's,
thanks dad. Was that a lot? So, all right.
I gotta go. This is a
bye. Bye. Gaping Dad.
It's called vocal fry jam.
Oh good.
Okay.
Bye guys.
Hi Mommy.
Ah,
speech pathologists, order, order,
order,
order.
Yeah.