Well. Well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Yeah.
Thank you Joey.
Nunchucks we're sending this in.
We always appreciate your guys'
instrumentals and original songs.
You can send them to your mom's podcast
at [inaudible] dot com you and mom's
podcasts.
There's no house in that email address.
Thanks to everyone that came out
this weekend. And then why Iowa?
It really was a maze for me. Um, I really,
I had a blast.
I hadn't been there since September,
2016 and, uh, so, so fun.
So you guys were awesome.
Great shows. I love you for it.
Um, gene, where can
people see you coming up?
February 23rd one night,
one show only at the
Colusa casino in collusion.
So California and then March
30th and 31st in Portland,
Oregon at hearing him comedy
crab and tickets for that one.
It's going really fast, so you're, if
you want to come see it, uh, get the Sh,
get the tickets.
Christina p online,
add some more stuff in the works.
Okay.
Um, let's see. I'm a, I'm going to be
in Lexington, Kentucky. Oh, you are?
Yeah. In March. That's sold out. Columbus,
Ohio later in March. That's all sold out.
Oh my salt lake city in April.
That's all sold out.
Australia.
That's all sold out here.
Then I'm going to Spokane in May.
Some tickets left there.
Sharp Lake titties. I'm also going
there. Oh No, I'm sorry. Charlotte,
North Carolina. Uh, tickets are there.
Omaha Braya, brass balls, beach, Florida.
Um,
we're adding a third show in New Orleans,
I think that goes on sale this week.
Friday, uh, that's in September.
So thanks to everybody in Louisiana.
They got tickets.
Is there going to be fun shows and that's
that pretty exciting stuff going on
gene. Yeah, amaze, amaze, excite,
boom.
All right. And a huge
thanks to everyone who, uh,
got mugs.
There's a bunch of,
there's a couple of mugs
on sale at our store.
One is next stop brown talk course cause
that's what coffee does for coffee does
makes you brown.
And then the other one,
um, through my special it says,
don't you hate everyone and uh,
both have been flying off the shelves.
Thank you for that.
There's other merchant on sale.
There's some new stuff coming I believe
next week. I'll let you know about it.
You can go to merge method.com/tom Segura
or go to Thomson [inaudible] Dot Com
and hit the store. Um, that is it. Jane,
are you ready to get this started?
Yeah, piss on me. Beat me.
Okay. You got it. You got it.
Jean, what's your driver's license?
I don't have to give that to you.
Let me see your driver's license.
You're out of police officer.
You just hit my vehicle, ma'am.
Your driver's license.
He pulled right out in front of me.
Poles in front of you
because there's an emergency
and your staff.
Okay.
Don't bring anyone loving to live
well. Well, well go to your mom's house.
There it is. Gene, do you think, um,
there was a day where she
woke up and was like, ah,
I don't want to be a woman anymore.
You think that she threw in the towel?
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
Or do you think it's gradual or
which has she always just been like,
I don't feel like I don't
feel like it today. Ah, man.
I think it's been a slow process.
Yeah. First of all, I will.
I don't like pointing this out.
But you did a hundred percent assume
or pronoun and Sodas. I right.
Then we don't know.
There's no way of knowing any anymore.
There is no way. And how cruel
of us to assign a pronoun
to some, I apologize. Hey.
Hi. How are you? What's your
name? What's Your Pronoun? Well,
I'm assuming it's a she.
It's used to be a share now it's,
it's a day. Do you think so? No, they ish.
That's interesting.
It does happen to women at a certain age.
I mean we've talked about the, shut it
down. Why? For the shut it down lady.
So it's a phenomena.
It's a shut it down.
Usually the shut it down starts with a
haircut. That's what we've learned. Oh,
with the, with the moms? Yeah. Mom. Yes.
Do a more masculine cut and they go,
yeah, part of my shut it down.
Move. It's the Tony Hawk.
Yeah. The bags shut it down.
Happens with bodies too. I mean, we
always see, I mean with both sexes,
it's not just a female thing, but
you see people, they're like, oh,
they threw in the towel on that
hunt nuts. Yeah, no self respect.
Nah. Yeah, yeah. Total disregard.
Yeah. It to me, look it.
I just say it because you know, you gotta
fight. You gotta fight. You gotta fight.
You can't just throw in the towel. I
mean, look to fight every day. For me,
I'm struggling. It's always hard for
both of us. Yeah, I'm pregnant. You know,
you're tired. I'm tired. Anything
I want to fucking put on makeup,
we're going to say no to sweets.
Hire a trainer.
Try a man is making an effort.
Just try to make,
so that's the thing is that
your significant other sees
the effort and they'd go,
well, he's trying. He might look like a
fucking pile of dog shit, but he's trying.
I don't think you look like a pile
of dog should. I think it was great.
Much better than that. At least we're
both swagged out in our three stripe life.
Finally, I'm so excited that
you've joined and my tribe,
I've been in euro trash my whole life.
I came out of my mom's vagina
wearing one of these. Yeah.
And I'm so excited that team Adidas has
given you, threw me some nice, I love it.
Gave me a bunch of stuff.
I would just been,
I've just been flexing stunting on
these pools are all my newest like it a
welcome to team euro trash.
How do you feel? Fucking great.
Right and Free Shit,
you know,
I understand it's gross to be able to
buy stuff and get free stuff at the same
time.
It's a massive box of free Adidas.
Shout out to Adidas. Um, you know I got,
I got some nice messages from executives.
I gotta write some Adidas Shit in
my next special dude. Just do it.
Do any product that you like.
I know I should. Any free
new baby coming pampers. Yeah, I'm going
to do that. Actually. I like pampers.
Huggies,
Pampers.
I can't even use fucking Huggies
man. Yo, I didn't know. I mean,
of course I had no idea cause I
had never bought them. But Damn,
diapers are expensive as shit.
And I buy like a month's supply at a time.
$50 dude,
I know for like a box.
And then you got to do the wipes.
You can't just dry wipe the baby's ass.
That's another fucking fortune, man.
You gotta get the quality wipes.
You get the cheap wives, you're buying
double, you pay, you pay the price, man.
I know they sent you the
track pants that go with it.
Are you going to go full euro trash and
do that? And they also sent me this gray,
uh,
Adidas sweatpants,
sweat matching top 11 flights almost over.
Let's say I tell you in the 90s,
I was all about the matching Adidas.
They had the roll over sweat
pants and I had the tearaways,
the three stripes airways that match this
jacket. Yeah, I mean that's fantastic.
Also, there's products, you know,
you'd never think of trying,
but someone gives it to you.
I'm telling you,
this is not a paid thing,
but those boosts,
they sent me pure boosts and ultra boost
shoes so I never would have bought them
because I just don't,
I don't buy everything that I hear about,
but I went crazy on it.
Can I ask you though,
because now looking back in retrospect,
those tear away pants,
not very like practical. Like what? Two
people? I guess just for bath it's a,
it's a spinoff from basketball because
in basketball you were there your warmups
so you were more warming
up and then it's game time.
You just go group and your shorts or on,
I don't have to pull them down. Right.
You can just rip them off. I always
thought ways were the coolest thing too.
I remember I remember playing
Jv basketball and we had
tear away pants and that
was the thrill and the game was
just doing the terror weapon.
You feeling like you're a, yeah,
I mean I wasn't athletic at all,
but I just liked the idea of
snap up pants. So silly. Yeah.
And then like the super cool guys,
you know,
they didn't bug them all the way down,
so they had like two open at the bottom.
Yeah, I did that. I'd give it a
little flare flare. Yeah, Kinda Nice.
When you kind of half Giagos things, you
didn't really jarring when you had them.
You're like, you know what I
do love about the three stripe.
A full track suit never goes
out of style. No, these, yeah,
this is timeless.
It's timeless.
This is the same thing that
run DMC was wearing. Yeah,
it's fucking dope.
It's still looks fresh.
Does Adidas, I love this. This
is official Hungarian gear, Dude.
I'm so stoked. Deputy. The all white
ones. That's, that's real gangster.
I need to get you a gold
medallion. Where's your gold
jewelry dude? That's coming.
Let's see what they continue to do here.
They're really pissed that I believe
this is the garbage truck driver. Oh,
poor guys. Just the worst.
It's the worst job to have.
I don't know if it's the worst job. It's
like, but can you, can you give the gun?
I mean, listen, hard job. It
really flips out. Oh Geez,
these are not cars.
They don't stop on a dime.
Big Boy.
I left the carpeting and the
note,
four bags aren't so much more than
ordered.
You know,
it's uh,
I'm always amazed by this ladies so angry
and she doesn't curse when someone can
do that and she's like big boy,
your rear end.
She so heated and she's not dropping any,
I don't know how people do that.
She keeps it Christian
Christian temper temper on him.
Oh No, I can't do that if I'm super
pissed. The worst things coming out.
Yeah. I mean she's really,
he keeps saying shit.
I'm still blown away at how man masculine
she is and the shoulders and the
shoulder. She might be a weightlifter
though. I don't think so.
You don't think she, she, she ain't
shit better shit to do if she were,
I just feel like she got him up and going
on. I won't be doing a strict press.
A lot of power cleans.
Okay.
And you're going to pay
you liked your job now.
I'm a garbage man.
Good luck.
Cause you ain't going to happen.
Okay Weirdo.
It's always crazy to me when someone
thinks they have that much power,
but what is she fuck?
Are you,
you're going to decide whether
this guy has a job or not.
She's going to spend that energy doing
stop.
Don't stop.
Don't stop
time.
I think the interesting is what do you
think those tits way we were talking
about doors, those are no joke, right?
She's not wearing any kind of support
bra. What size do you think those are? No.
H H h sloppers and they're
not even contained,
but I'm surprised there's no wild tits
on that top is not flattering for that
either. Yeah. She's got some big fuck.
She is special is touched,
but you know,
I just think it's such a,
I don't,
I don't know how people have
time for this shit to call up.
The man's boss was fired up.
I know.
What worse cares?
Well,
what
you were supposed to do.
Yeah.
Who are also, have so much empathy
for people that do pick up our trash.
Did that stop? Was it ever
turned on? Yeah. All right.
I just had to do a little
camera card switch up.
Um, I'm just saying like I can't,
I don't, I mean, isn't it hard?
Is it his day? Like hard enough.
He's up at the crack of dawn.
He's picking up trash. It
doesn't smell good in there. Oh,
you don't think she has these
thoughts? Like who cares? Let the guy,
but don't you also at this point, this
upset at some point? Don't you go,
you're not upset about the trash? No,
she's upset because she weighs too much.
Didn't get the right Bra. That's what
she got. The wrong fucking support Bra.
I know she has 25 pounds each.
She's upset because she woke up a man
cause she's so fucking, she's so gnarly.
You know, she's just angry.
She's angry at other stuff now.
She loves in look,
listen to this mocking.
She's would like Ab psy fucking talk
to you like a baby. And she goes, no.
All right. And you can even
follow. Why don't you go back?
Yeah.
You know, my mom was like this, so, and
I think that's why it also bothers me.
Balanced.
Exactly.
My mom would like yell at salespeople
like this or she took everything
personally.
Yeah.
Crazy. She's good at the alphabet. Jesus.
Yeah. Okay. What'd you
rather do it with her? Yeah,
or at the Moose suit lady.
That's a really good point. It's really
good thing to think about actually. Yeah.
Um Hm.
Or menstrual blood lady and she's got
managed her blood on her face as you're
doing.
You guys are good.
You guys are doing good.
Yeah. It's just in the same family.
Yeah. They're kissing cousins. These two
new soup lady. She's sweet. She's what?
She's trying to offer you something to
this lady's raging out. It's terribly,
terribly attractive.
She's just
tier.
Yeah, they're moving. I didn't see him
move before and now I see him showing him.
You've got to restrain those
tests. Yeah. Oh yeah. Oh boy.
Yeah. This guy, I mean,
she's kind of feels like an audition
way that she's very theatrical.
What she's, yeah, sure, sure. I'm a
kind of impressed directing skills.
It's pretty good.
Pretty good
look.
Oh yeah. She's on drugs or mental
illness. No, you do that sometimes.
The chicken thing. The
Gog, like, damn you do.
I've heard you do it every do chicken
things. That's my thing. Do it. Do it.
See,
hey,
she's really losing it and
see if the tape until now
with that mirror wasn't there.
Oh,
she got that.
The fucking world.
There's a big old milkers
goes flat wagons. Oh, am I
guy
dumpers yeah.
She's got big old fucking dumpy to hate
when these videos and like this and I
don't know what happened next,
what the resolution was or anything.
It is compelling.
It is compelling stuff.
If anybody knows what
50 pound tits did next,
anyone has a follow up,
we'd love to hear about it.
I mean hers way more than mine,
right? Oh yeah, of course.
Those are three times the size of
your test. Speaking of your tits,
um,
at least I hardest mine properly.
Like I buy the right size
bras. I got it. Do that. Um,
here it is.
Where is it or is
it a better, I'm sorry.
See it a lot of, uh,
votes on how much my tits
way. Yeah, that's what I was
trying to find. I saw. Sure.
I'll just tell you the tweets.
I've been getting people who have been
ranging from six pounds each to two and a
half to 15 or 20 I have some relevant
info regarding the weight of money.
Mommy,
Tina's mushy perps.
My girlfriend had g size slobby hangers
when I first met her due to them
interfering with our com
hugs and her spine curvature.
She had them reduced to see cups and
lost a total of five operation genes.
Hangers have got to be high
and tight with mommy milk.
So 15 pounds a piece is a fair estimate.
You both.
Wow. So when I'm, when they're full
of milk for sure. At least. Yeah.
Cause they keep growing
during your pregnancy. Yeah.
They're getting bigger now
even more because there's
the milk ducts are starting
to and then people have
submitted different techniques.
Great quick solution for tit.
Wait,
just have Tina Stan on
irregular bathroom scale.
Then have her do it again
while Tommy holds up her tits.
The difference that's from Dane.
Okay, well let's think about that.
Does that really work? Yeah, I guess
I guess that would work. I don't know,
but I feel like,
I mean that's a technique but it's not
going to be as accurate as just getting
that team. I'm not so sure. Someone said
they weighed the tits on a Deli scale.
Um, if you'd be interested. Years
ago when I was just last double D's,
I worked for a deli. It was a slow Sunday.
It's working with the all female staff.
They were not as blessed as I am in the
10 department and like to gently tease
me about my abundance.
We wildly,
we wonder how much they weighed a well,
we had it happen to have
a deli meat scale at hand.
We were silly on free milkshakes and
all the weed we smoked in the basement.
He gave it a try after placing a
sheet of Delhi tissue on the scale,
I stepped up,
popped out my broad,
proceeded the way that my had
a lefty at 4.7 pounds, right,
was 5.2 don't sanitize the scale and
everyone got their tits out and there was
hot scissoring. Just kidding.
We cleaned up and clocked out.
Now I have a great story to tell it.
My job interviews your Moshi purples
high and tight. Lisa in Virginia,
if you would like any advice on
how to accomplish a tit weigh in?
I consider myself pretty
much an expert in the sport.
Well now I just have to get my
hands on a deli scam. That's right.
People had mentioned that.
They have been mentioning that somebody
else said that this kitchen scale is
something you could do.
A couple of months ago,
my boyfriend and I had the same question,
so I got out that glass top kitchen scale,
laid it on the edge of the table and
got down to the level of the table where
the bottom of my tits lined
up at the top of the scale.
Plop the tit on top 34 double d and
each one rounded out to six pounds.
Whoa.
How's total Holly?
Who Found Lynn Canada? He asked.
I estimate Christina's tit.
Wait at 18 pounds. Wow. So we
can just buy one from Amazon.
Yeah.
Glass scale too.
Here's the thing though,
but how do you know that the pressure
of you? I know what she's saying.
You're going to plop it on there,
but how do you know you're not putting
more pressure on the scale by how you're
standing or something to consider
for horse? These are all factors.
I think the Deli scale might be the only.
Yeah.
Do you think we could try the whole farts?
You think they would let us do it?
Yeah, we were friends
with those workers. Yeah,
that's totally possible.
Deli meat scale cause a deli meats scale.
I feel like it's used
to being very precise.
You know he measure out
thin slices of meat.
It's very precisely right.
Those are big tits. Oh,
those are real big double D's. Even.
I'm surprised how much those way.
Huge Teddy's I want to get
mine reduced after. Definitely.
What do you wanna bring him down to see?
Yeah,
a C Cup will be like being in fifth
grade again for me. I can fucking run
right before we started recording,
I saw this came up that I'm
Sony pictures has apologized.
Yeah. After Peter Rabbit, the movie
exploits a food allergy setting.
Some parents. Oh, the a food allergy. Huh?
Her Son has food allergies and a scene
in the film shows blackberries being used
as a weapon.
The backlash to the scene has already
drawn an apology from the filmmakers. Oh,
good. Good. Holy Shit.
Well,
I'm glad we're apologizing.
The big corporations are yielding
to these idiots. That's great. Oh,
good example. Encouraged the
other dummies to come forward.
Allergies are often not
taken seriously enough.
Haven't trivializing the big screen by
such a popular character is immensely in
a statement. Sony pictures apologize.
Food allergies are a serious issue.
Our film should not have made light
of Peter Rabbit's, arch nemesis,
Mr Mcgregor being allergic
to blackberries. Even in a
cartoonish, slapstick way.
The statement which attributed in
part to the films, directors, writers,
and producers added.
We sincerely regret not being more
aware and sensitive to this issue.
And we truly apologize.
She's just,
is this, the end of us is
as a CN of America. I mean,
this is a food allergy joke. And
here's the thing. I, you know, I was,
as I was posting Christ,
uh,
a joke about he man the other
day on my Instagram, it's a,
it's a meme that someone
sent me on Twitter.
It's like he man is now changed
it to himself to the man and I,
and I was just picturing the backlash
though. Yeah. That's pretty funny. Yeah.
And um,
and somebody being like,
but I'm non binary and I was really
thinking about this in a logical,
philosophical way. Yeah.
Okay. So what's wrong?
So someone has a food allergy.
What's wrong with making a,
putting it in a story that somebody has
a food allergy? You know what I'm saying?
Well, cause you're making, they
made fun of like he was written,
it was trying to find his
epi pen and then he went in
shock. And that was the joke. He did
not, yeah. Oh, is that right? Yeah,
but so what,
so what if somebody is upset about it?
I have that thing and you can't make
fun of it. That's the logic, right.
Affects me. It makes me sad.
Therefore you can't joke about it.
Claude. Things that don't affect
me personally, but here we go.
If we keep apologizing to everybody,
then it's an infinite apologies
and we can't talk about shit. Yeah.
I'm sure that you could go to
some of these people and be like,
how do you feel about jokes about
Mexicans? And they'd be like,
I mean that's fine.
I don't know any Mexicans I know about
these fucking peanut allergy remedies.
Blackberries are upsetting to my, to me
personally because I have the allergy.
It's very selective.
Yeah.
It's just always about only
what affects you is offensive.
It's just a logic.
So I was thinking to myself,
let's say somebody is going to contact
me from the non-binary community.
I'm non by. Okay, so what,
so why does that mean I can't joke about
it because you're being, I dunno, it's,
you're being insensitive to
something being insensitive.
And so why is that?
Is it necessarily immoral?
Is it wrong to be not funny?
It's not funny because
it's something that,
that, um, that I've,
I've been going through and I
can tell you that it's not funny.
It's not funny for you,
but it's funny for everybody else.
They shouldn't be laughing
cause it's not a fun day.
So we should control the external
world to make your internal. She just,
if you were actually funny,
you could figure out something
else to joke about that didn't,
it wasn't at the expense of people with
allergies who haven't decided their
pronoun yet. It's my favorite. Yeah,
no, it's a, it's an endless cycle.
I mean it could just go on and on and
on. And the problem too, like I said,
as the Sony's are cowtowing
to this horribly stupid logic,
amazing part is that they extended
her an apology for that. I mean,
is there a huge blackberry allergy
community that there must be somewhat,
I think it's also not even just
blackberry allergies. It's just parents.
I mean I have friends,
we,
we know people whose children
are allergic to. Um, you know,
foods peanuts. Are you kidding me, Lj?
I put him in preschool when I
was doing the enrollment papers.
They give you a sheet this long.
Just reading you the riot. Act On,
do not pack any, not related.
No peanut butter, almond butter,
nut butter, soy butter at any good,
no nuts, no nuts, granola bars.
You have to buy them without nuts.
Is that even possible?
Is there even a bar thing?
Is that I totally get that part
and I get some kids going to die.
Yeah, no, I get it. I get it and
I get it that it's just, you know,
this is a really serious issue for some
families. I'm glad we don't have it. Yes,
of course.
But I still think you can make
jokes and make fun of the allergy.
Not you're not making fun of the kid.
You're making fun of the fact that they
gave to give you a sheet now because of
the thing or whatever the joke is.
I mean, people have aids jokes. Oh,
such good ones and you know,
we haven't heard enough.
I feel like people have been writing
it in. People have holocaust jokes.
Yeah. Rape. Rape is great. Yeah.
I'm glad that was your sentence.
But yeah, people joke about
all types of things. Deafness,
disabilities, everything. Yeah. We've,
I think you and I have covered personally.
I've heard from a few people
I know. Yeah. Yeah. I
mean, I think the thing is,
the answer for all those people is like,
just don't laugh if you don't think it's
funny and also watch something else.
Let's move on with your life. Are there
no other movies playing right now?
Here's the thing.
You know me and I don't like vomiting.
I have a phobia of vomiting,
so whenever it's in a film,
I just don't like it for that brief.
Second,
would I write the movie people
and let them know I have a phobia?
I don't like seeing it. You should
take it out. You just go, oh,
that's a moment that I'm not going
to care for in this guy's act.
Or it's just so silly.
People are fucking out of there and I'm
kind of enjoying watching people spiral
though.
I'm kind of getting off on it now.
Like now that it's extended to
food allergies now it's great.
I hope it keeps going.
I hope it, I hope the,
the outrage keeps going to more and more
absurd things like I hope they start
going like,
and then he made fun of his friend for
not liking cheese in the movie and I come
from a dairy family and then
somebody was like, you know,
we should have been thoughtful about
the dairy community in Wisconsin and we
apologize for that joke and that and
then just let it keep going, let it.
But the only reason that the Sonys of
the world are apologizing is because of
the internet and the visibility of
these dummies who rallied together and
Facebook groups and groups on Twitter
and they use social media to collectively
be idiots. And you know, Sony doesn't
want their name being tarnished,
I'm assuming. So they have to shut these
idiots up somehow. It's ridiculous.
Anyway, speaking of lunacy, we found the
best goddamn reality show last night.
Oh my God. Well, what's the called? Love.
I posted it on my Instagram.
I'm Christina [inaudible].
Mais I'm the Christina p.
It's called love after lock up.
And you would think that it would
just be a show about like dating,
but it's better than that.
Oh my people that are
marrying convicted felons.
It's amazing. It is amazing. I
wonder, what is it called again?
You just said love after lockup.
It's on we TV and we were
scrolling through last night.
You were taking a shit as usual and I
saw this jam and I thought it doesn't get
any better than inmates
dating non inmates.
Jesus help me.
Jesus.
I discovered thought, oh
my gosh, it's beautiful.
Lives in California.
Convict Grandad.
Oh Wow.
They looked up and saw as
mugshot. I was like, wow,
this guy takes a really hot mugshot
out.
My man is a good man.
Prison man.
Once released
my dream wedding, my dad would be walking
me down the aisle. If you're crazy,
do they have to?
Why do they have to marry immediately?
My Dad and mark it down the aisle is hard.
I had a twin that daddy would walk me
down the aisle that will be hospice and
all my bridesmaids would
where? Few shot. Yeah.
That girl is obsessed.
They're all fucked up.
These people are actually super sad.
Yeah. You could tell that they're all,
they're all scared, like they were
like kicked dogs. They're like,
I just want a nice owner,
and oddly enough, ironically,
they feel like this will be
the good owner. Well, yeah,
because what it is is that they
say it in the shell like, well,
the thing is there's less quote,
less risk dating an inmate because there's
less theoretically things they can do
to you. Right. They can't cheat on
you. They can't do anything bad,
but the irony is they're actually way
more harmful to these poor souls because
they're criminals.
They're manipulating this.
This woman took $20,000 from this guy.
Well,
he's sent her and she admits.
Then she's like,
at first I was just like trying to
pull money out of them. You're like,
I'm a con artist, but now I'm
not now change. Yeah, they're,
my favorite is that one lady's dating a
guy who's been locked up for eight eight,
eight eight 18 he has not seen
the outside for two decades.
He's never like see the enter and she
has kids, she has kids. She was like,
I'm gonna marry him. And like this
will be their new debt. Instant Dad.
And you're like three small children
and they're all like young children.
Yeah.
Nice little sweet kids and she's new dead.
Well he has been uh,
doing some stuff and he's finally here.
It's nice and thoughtful of her because
she also likes to think of what gang
affiliation he has when she gets
dressed and stuff believable. He's like,
well he's a crip so I can't wear red
when I pick him up. And you're like,
really is that important right
here he is talking about it.
I never had a job in my life until I
started working in and out of jail.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm not saying maybe these guys in prison
can't turn it around and maybe they
are a nice cute cause.
Not everybody's all and no such
thing as redemption and all that.
But I mean how about you give it
a minute before you get married?
Running into the, to the wedding is it
cannot be a good idea. So then the girl,
this is her daddy or looking
at and she's 26 or 26,
and her boo is getting
out of prison and he's 24.
Just a laundry list of when is it vehicle?
He's stealing cars.
All kinds of stuff. Yeah,
he's stealing and um,
he's broken in the homes and credit
cause he's my favorite. He's one,
he's one of these white
boys like, yeah. You know,
relationship with a female in a minute.
What Dude?
Transracial I believe he's
really adaptable. Lingo. Female.
Yeah, he's cute relations
in a minute. Uh Huh.
Mormon girl.
Shoot somebody.
She gets mad when they teaser. They
like, you married a guy prison.
Where did you get that ring? Like in, uh,
at the little penny slot machine
in prison. And she's like,
you gotta make up funny one. Now
she could, that's disrespectful.
You're being disrespectful. It's like, no,
they're actually being honest with you,
dummy. Uh, so the, the,
the 26 year old girl,
her whole thing is, she just
wants the wedding. You know,
it doesn't matter to who,
just that this guy comes out and that
I can't wear a dress and my bridesmaids
can't wear burgundy and
we can handle anyway.
Then it's like you don't even
care who you're marrying a lot.
Both of these women are like, I
just want the dress. I just want,
they just want to have their fantasy
wedding. Yeah. It's really fucked up.
And I think that's what's really fucked
up about women and how they raise us
little girls from the very beginning.
A lot of this Disney horse shit. Uh,
it's called, I mean, listen, my parents
certainly didn't pump that into my head.
The, no, I know. But I
think now there's such,
there's such a level of awareness that
you have a chance if you have a little
girl, Ooh. To not put that in her head,
that the greatest day ever
will be your wedding day,
most important day of your
life or into your life.
And you can be a princess prep for
one day. Get to be the princess.
All the colors that you love the most.
Yeah. But remember like those Gypsies,
the Big Gypsy wedding show,
that was her whole thing my mother had
put in my head at one solitaire diamond
with diamonds all around it.
And then horses.
That's my dream.
And then you're just uses live in
the memory of that day? I think so.
That's the best day.
I mean it's so,
it's so crazy to me that that's the
biggest highlight of your life is a stupid
fucking wedding. You gotta
be kidding. She's a real,
I guess
you could call him a trick.
It wasn't true.
And the thing is though,
that the way he was with me,
how I was able to be honest with him,
he was okay with me being me.
He's broken too. Just like, oh,
okay baby. I ain't buying shit. He
can't afford for her. Yeah, she's gonna.
She's gonna Bleed them dry leave.
It's of course it's, it's all,
it's so great though. What a great,
what a great show. In delusion,
you get to see how people talk
themselves into bad ideas. It's fun.
If you guys want to show love after
lock up, I wish I could find this guy.
This guy is guys, the Trans Racial
Man. Yeah. Yeah. The trans racial
identify with. Would you say is he
here? He has Garrett. That's his name.
[inaudible]
and then, um, that's the other
thing is that they're Marion people.
They've never also slept with,
never had sex, never had a date,
never had anything normal,
nothing.
Can't have conversations on the
phone longer than 15 minutes.
And then there's the guy marrying the
heroin girl. Ah, forget that. He's sweet.
He was a, he's a marine. He's an
it guy. Crazy eyes though. Yeah.
Doctor drew was telling us when
you see the tops of the whites,
it's like a pulmonary thing.
No, that was the best thing.
Is that crystal meth or
drugs? Dr Group. But uh,
yeah, so he's sweet as
can be. He's a good guy.
And then just eastern European hall,
one of my tribe,
a ropes and in with the Internet
pictures of her and she's a former yet
recovering heroin addict and
she got put in prison for,
for what was she doing? Possession and
intent to distribute or something. Heroin.
Special heroin.
Yup. Good stuff. Could you
imagine your child being like,
I'm marrying this? Well that's
what this shows you. These,
these parents did Fallon fuck
that one guys. So he's like,
you're gonna marry this guy. She's like,
he'd give him a chance. He's a great guy,
but the great guideline is my
favorite. They should, I don't know,
just earn the great guy. Satisfying.
If you have to tell people,
you know what I mean?
What is up with this great guy?
He's doing 18 years for armed robbery.
Oh yes.
He's great at crime.
That's what I meant to say.
Oh,
and then waiting and waiting for this data
is going to pick them up.
I'm freaking out.
She's about to get out of jail.
She got some a matching outfit.
That's the priority. Is that
2198 Oh yeah.
And then the lady,
he goes and buys a car for the
one of the 18 year felon guy.
She buys him a new vehicle. Okay.
Let's see. She's Mormon too,
so her community is not going to be
pleased with the shit. By the way.
Watch this first full episode on Youtube.
Okay.
[inaudible] please,
please people so we can hear
him. Tom, I think he's held
in prison for burglaries,
grand thefts,
Dnn from people's homes,
cars and a jog, jog,
use and drug possession.
I was sentenced to eight years in prison,
five years probation and judge treatment
when I was 18 it was definitely crazy.
You know, going to prison for all those
years. Living with 80 guys in the room.
I love it. Everyone has onto your motives.
Everyone always wants something from
criminals are shitty people.
Like a hundred best days of my life.
It's one of the best days of my life.
All right.
Can we go
bibs? The layman's part is that this
bitch brought him a matching outfit.
Does that,
you know what I'm saying? Like if I,
when I come to get you out of prison,
do you want me to bring our
matching? Of course. Of course.
We'll walk out and be like free again.
You know, Sam, I've been locked up.
I ain't been with a female and
about six and a half years.
I would love if you as a president
came back talking like that. I'm like,
who are you? Who am I a bitch? Who
the fuck are yous? It's Florida talk.
He's from Florida now.
I mean he is from Florida,
but he's um, yeah, he's been
doing this thing. Dade County. Uh,
I think he's a Tampa boy. Oh yeah. Tab.
I can see you with a guy like that
for sure. He's actually a cute his,
you know what she said. So
they, these people out Mugshot,
these people find the inmates on an
inmate dating site and they put their
mugshots up and she goes,
well he had a hot mug shot and I was like,
this bitch is crazy. And I saw
it. I was like, you're right.
He kinda does on Mugshot.
Same with the truck driver.
That's what that scam, that
hooker, she's got a great mugshot.
She's smiling and hers and Shit.
She knew her and code as the heroin girl.
She was like modeling before hot inmates.
So that's what happened.
You know what it is?
Is these broken people go,
that hot person would never wait.
That truck driver said like,
okay, so like out of jail she's a 10,
but in jail she's a nine and a half.
Remember he didn't say it that way, but
he goes, I'm like a five. She's like,
I'm nine, nine and you go, why do
you take away the half a star? Yeah.
Like whenever you're talking like
star search, your significant other.
You don't be, you don't dial it back
just like a nine and a half. Yeah,
half a point. Cause she's a felon.
But that makes sense by the way,
somebody's got their mom to do this
just in case you're wondering. Okay,
well I have to do this thing for school.
I need to just to say something. Okay.
Can you say my name is Mary Jo Ann.
I'm a ball hog.
You gotta say it like sexy. Like my
name is Mary Jo and I'm a ball hard
for school high school.
My name is Mary Jo.
Good job. I like Mary Jo. Uh, just
a little cool little audio note.
Maybe turn down that TV if you're
trying to get audio next time.
But nevertheless, good job,
Tyler. Get your mom on the,
on the ball hog thing and then
they're cute. This is for Eugene. Uh,
last week you made me
order for artichokes. Yeah.
And somebody ordered
me help people.
I want to make a or pick up.
Could I get some chicken fajitas
without,
uh,
the vegetables or no vegetables.
Okay. All right. So that's the
chicken Fajita Nachos.
All
right, I'll be there to pick it up. Yeah,
man, I can't get enough of this
show. That was fantastic, Donald.
Man, I was hilarious. I can't,
I can't laugh enough with those.
And I love when people fuck with
people like that. Furniture.
Forteo's um,
people have been sending me
this on Twitter and now, um,
emails notes here that there
is a job that you could really,
uh, look, you can read it here. What
does it say? What's the job description?
Scrum masters semester
senior project manager. Yeah.
Some people have been sending me this
scrum master a master. I didn't
know that. That was a job.
Fuck my stoma. So scrum
master. Yeah, you can,
you can be a scrum master. And I don't
think I have to read the description.
I'm just says as a scrum master, you'll
play a major role in shaping our success.
I can about a ball hard. What am
I, a ball hog or a scrum master.
I want you to be a scrum
master. Um, this guy, uh,
sent gusts, sent one of these and he
said, I've been doing some job searching,
stumbled upon what could be
mommy Thomas next dream job.
I don't know how long the job will
stay up here it is. By the way,
I'm the guy you met,
uh,
with Ari and Brent Chrysler when you
guys were leaving top golf in Atlanta.
And to attest the toms story,
Brent was the one who proposed.
I take a picture with him
and later with you guys.
So if there's a trophy for
attention whore champion,
I think Brent takes it easily.
Yeah. Love all your guys. Shit.
Piss on me and bite my balls.
Gus from Atlanta. Uh, he's a,
he's referring to when we
left, uh, top golf. This guy,
Gus was just like, oh, hey,
what's up Burberry? What you want to
take a picture? And then was like,
you were three picture with the guys,
so it's kind of hilarious.
But sue this, so basically
Bert saw him was like, no,
we'll all take a picture and
made him take a picture of,
you guys all have beards.
Yes.
Beard grew French kiss each other with
your beard's. Yeah. It's so funny.
I was who was, I was a full
charge this weekend. Yeah. And uh,
I got recognized a few places and he
was like, you get recognized a lot.
And I go,
just depends on where and he goes.
But basically every guy with a beard
seems to recognize you. Like, yeah,
I think it's true. Oh, that's funny
guys that look like me or like, Hey,
I know who you are. Yeah. The
bearded group, the bearded guys.
Will each other scrubs all scrum out on
each other. The sauce and your beard's.
Yeah.
Yeah. Sniff those balls. Sniffs.
Yeah. That's terrible. That's
pretty cool. That's terrible. Um,
what is this here? Oh, have
you seen this? This is like,
okay.
Happened a couple of weeks ago and a
lot of people were talking about it,
but I don't know if you
heard about it or saw it.
And that is Tom Brady the quarter.
Tom Brady is how you're supposed
to say. Some people say that. Yeah,
I've heard that.
I don't know anything about,
he did this show for Facebook where
he let cameras follow them around. Oh,
I heard about this and he his son and
kissed him or something and it wasn't good
enough. And he went back for seconds.
Well just here. Just why. Okay.
Let me see.
So getting like treatment,
I was wondering if I could check my,
we won't get
every now and Jack.
Everything comes at a cost,
but it was like a peck is your
fantasy quarterback check Cam Newton.
Yeah.
See now that I see it because I've heard
people talking about it. Yeah. Okay.
So he goes in for one pack and then he's,
he goes in for a second one and the second
was really meaningful mouth cast with
his dad. It's weird to
me. Okay. Yeah. Look,
I know that some families they mouth kiss.
Yeah.
But I think the same sex is kind of,
it's a little for me personally,
it's just not my thing. I don't mouth
kiss our son. I don't think that that's,
I've never kissed anyone in my family.
No. I accidentally did my Stepdad once,
he wa he turned his head. Yeah.
My Indian stepdad accidents.
But I'm talking about the regular
[inaudible] that happened in the early
nineties and I'm thinking about it ever
since. Like it was a bad moment cause
cheek kissing is so big in,
um, my mom's culture. Yeah.
Like there's never a mistake
for a mouth. No, I don't. I don't know
if I didn't, if I didn't have her,
um, I think my dad's family, I probably,
I don't even know if we'd go past hugs.
You know, your dad's more formal. Yeah,
they're definitely Gary. And
you kiss both cheeks. Yeah.
Now it's where cheek kissers we're not
mouth kissers this is a very weird thing.
I don't, I'm not into this man. So
He's coming back for number two.
It's so sensual to, it's so weird
in this account. It, let's go
already know Jack. Everything comes
at a cost. That was the short one.
He says, come back. Oh,
that's weird. I'm, is Dan here?
Wait, did you hear him say,
but I'm his dad. It was like,
here he is with his dad.
So yeah,
this has caused a huge
conversation before. So
he's 11 years old, Tom,
because this is a family thing.
Maybe it's a little bit
longer than it should be.
Oh, they didn't show it because he also,
they show him Tom with his, you know,
70 year old dad and they killed the mouth.
The mouth.
Could you imagine kissing top dog's
mouth feel so bad for my mother? Yeah.
I mean the smells alone that
come out of your dad's mouth.
His Dad mouth on your dad mouth.
Yeah. And I keep drinking coffee.
It's going to my dad. Matt's going to
kick in generational dad mouth kissing.
Disgusting. I Dunno. What do you think?
I mean, would you kiss Ellis? No.
You don't kiss Ellis on the mouth? No.
I mean, I think, I mean probably as a,
I don't, I kiss him on his cheeks. I
think it's an appropriate personally.
And
I don't,
I don't want to as a little
kid personally, like,
you know how Nasty Your Dad's mouth is?
My Dad's mouth has been nasty
since I can remember like,
just try putting his mouth on.
I don't even like the idea of it.
Just Devin mouth
is nasty. I don't like that. I know.
I Dunno. I don't wanna
like I don't want to, um,
I'm sure we just contributed to that.
That kid probably got tortured at school.
Well that's enlisted and that's Tom
Brady's fault for exposing his children on
the fucking show or whatever.
But now that being said,
I grew up with a family.
A friend of mine,
he would mouth kiss his mother, his father
and his sister, good night and hello.
I am it. There are nice family
ethnicity. They were Jewish,
White Jews. Uh, and uh,
he was a goth kid with us,
which is even weirder.
Mouth Kissing and they were a nice family.
They're are super nice.
And it was like, I remember
the mom would be like, hey,
give your sister a goodnight.
And then he would go and mouth kiss
sister goodnight and then goodnight dad,
mouth kiss, dad mouth kiss mom.
What's a weird one too? I've had,
it happened only a few times but kind
of had some high society girls that are
like theirs that they're friends.
It's not a dating thing.
Greet you with mouse case.
Not that I know I've had it
before too where you go like,
and what I mean by high society is,
you know like a fluent types who like
country clubbers who greet you with mouth
kisses and, and like a, they do
with all their friends, you know,
friends.
I do think family,
especially opposite sex
might be a little hanky. No,
I'll say I think it's kind
of odd in my family though,
we bathed together and we
have for years and you know,
when I go home and I see my folks will
take a bath, I took a shower together.
Well a lot of times I'll tell you
what, my mom and dad and we, you know,
we soap each other up, but it's like
I've just never thought twice about it.
Family shower.
Well,
in California two we have strict water
regulations and I remember in college
when I would go home, uh, if I brought,
like sometimes my friends would
come with me, it'll be my dad,
myself and my friend.
We'd all take a shower or bath together
and that was just how we do things.
And then sometimes when you pooped,
your dad would poop in between your
legs or I would put it between his legs.
That's right.
So we poop at the same time,
which is also a nice water
saver to water saver. But again,
some people think that's weird.
Sure.
I mean that's just how we do
it in our house. I don't know.
My family was not affectionate either,
but I think the mouth kiss would fucking
Allen like that to you with hung goes,
you guys do cheek kisses shakes.
Yeah.
You give one to sometimes a
third I've seen have been, uh,
I think in Spain it was
always two, one, two,
and then there's places where you
do three, one, two, three. It was a,
I think the Swiss do three. Yes. Yeah.
Hungarians you say that's
a lot of work by the
stupid Poussey for people don't
know is kissing. Yes, yes. Yeah,
I do. Um, I think one, two, three
is a lot of work too much. Come on.
And I didn't like kissing Hungarian guys
growing up because they were a lot of
aftershave. And I remember
like my dad's friends would be,
have really greasy,
smelly cheeks and then they kiss you,
they kissed you as a kid and then you
smell like what that fucking hongos face
smelled like.
You know the Argentine men,
you kiss each other the same
way because in like in Peru,
it's only opposite sexes that greet
with a kiss. The Argentinians,
the men do it to each other. That's
fucking gay too. Yeah, it's Super Gay.
I thought. So the first time it
happened, I pulled back and uh, my,
one of my cousins was like, I dunno,
this is, I was like, Nah, Bro.
And then he grabbed her nuts and then
he's like, let it go, relax. And no,
Hungarians are way too homophobic
for that shit. They'd be like,
fuck you fucking me. Kiss me,
kiss my Dick. Right now. Yeah,
no way, Bro. Here's some foreigners. These
guys are, let's see. This is the, uh,
the shepherds,
Bush Raiders rugby team.
They are an Australian rules
football team based in London.
Apparently this speech helped him out.
Account a comeback.
I love this type of sports shit.
Yes.
Fuck these cuts.
That's what I'm asking
God, these guys. But he's saying
these cunts, which I respect. Yeah.
They came down,
there were 48 points down in the second
quarter and they won by two after that
cut speech. Wow. Yeah. See,
I feel like I would just
talk that way normally. Yeah.
Doc was like, those are the kinds
of speeches I'd be giving. Normally.
You'd just talk like that. I feel like
that's the kind of fiery need to win.
You know? That's how I talked to
myself before I go up on stage.
Fucking cons is fine. Take this. You
take care of yourself down before you go.
Do you really need that? No. No,
no, but I can't be in a good mood.
I can't feel good about
myself or feel, um, happy.
We have a hundred percent
opposite requirements.
What do you do?
I don't like go.
I've obviously you've everyone who's
done it this long has gone on stage with
the full spectrum of
feelings. So I know, you know,
I've gone on stage in a horrible mood.
I've gone on stage and a great, uh,
I think I'm a much better show and a
better comic when I'm in a great mood and
when I feel loose and I'm laughing about
stuff, I think I'm a better comic. Yeah.
Um, but some people, you
know that energies is weird
on that doesn't work for me.
I have to feel miserable,
have to feel a little self loathing
and I ha I just have to get,
it's like it's not that I'm really
feeling that way but because I'm a pretty
happy person actually.
But from my comedy brain to flip over,
I have to go in there before I can get up.
It's like a weird thing.
I have to switch into that mode.
I can't,
I can't just be like happy go lucky and
go up there cause I won't focus. I won't,
I won't be funny. I don't know why
you won't be funny if you, if I go up,
they're happy, everything's
great. It doesn't work for me.
I have to get content out
to get miserable. It's just
how, it's just how it goes.
It goes, I got to my
Tonya Harding, I gotta,
I gotta fight the imaginary, uh, you know,
mom figure I think is what's happening.
Honestly, I got to prove somebody wrong.
I'm so crazy. My brain. I
got it. Yeah, it's a lot.
Well, it's a, it's a lot
only for comedy, but I don't,
I don't do it in my regular life,
but I just know like that's where I have
to access to do the thing that I do.
You know what he's,
what do you say to yourself?
What if you're in a good mood? Yeah.
Then I have to talk myself down too.
I mean I just have to get,
I have to remind myself of the harder
times to stand up and when I used to have
to fight for the audience to pay
attention to me. And if I like,
I have to go to a like Toledo
comedy connection with two axes.
When I was opening,
it was an opening act and I'm eating
fucking Nachos for dinner and I'm staying
in a motel. I just remember
those times when you really,
you deliberately take yourself. Yes,
I do. I have to go back to like the,
the grime and the hard stuff.
I don't know. And then the
performance feels better.
Yeah. It's like Rodney, no respect. Think.
Imagine if Friday went up there
and was like, everything's great.
My wife loves me, my kids
respect me. It just wouldn't be,
I think for me how I'm funny is to
be just a little miserable, a little,
a little saucy. Right. I
have to be a little spicy,
by the way,
I didn't even see that this was here.
We were discussing the pronouns earlier.
Um,
I worked for a Social Services Agency and
recently my agency forced all staff to
declare our gender
pronouns, public emails. Oh,
can coworkers and anyone in the
public we might email. Well,
I support individuals rights to declare
their own identity and pronouns.
I feel like this top down decision is way
overreaching plus for the people still
nervous about it.
My work is basically forcing them to
make a decision they may not be ready to
make.
That's interesting.
I wanted to hear your thoughts before I
sent her a long email about my thoughts.
Hi, how are you? What's your
name? What's Your Pronoun?
Well, here's the thing about
gender identity is that it's fluid.
So what you may want to say
to HR is today I'm, I'm a her.
Tomorrow I could flux and be a hero
is actually an excellent point. Thank
you. Would I would highlight, I would,
I would make that an even bigger
point and say, um, you know,
I don't appreciate being forced.
Ooh,
good declaration right now.
Although I see that you're doing it so
that people who have made their pronouns
decision can let people know.
And people can not offend them.
But one of the things that really bothers
me is as a gender fluid individual,
um, I am only into using
this pronoun for the moment.
That doesn't mean that at all. Like it
tomorrow or even by the end of this email.
Exactly our hourly,
I can change my gender.
You could also speak for others and say,
and others also have the right to
change their pronouns on a regular
basis.
Here's the way I suggest that this email
go out at the beginning of each day.
I would go a step
farther. Every hour. Yeah.
Hourly and update as to what
everyone's pronouns are.
So nobody's affected negatively. When
somebody miss identifies their pronouns.
What's Your Pronoun? Yeah,
maybe keep up. I Dunno.
Like we used to have these
when I worked in offices,
you know the messenger window.
Yeah.
And whoever's fluxing at the
moment can update the entire staff.
So we all so nobody gets their feelings
hurt when there are misidentified. Yeah,
that's true.
It's so complicated.
Mistake. It's very, you
know what? It is. Logical.
Makes Sense. Makes a lot
of sense. It's a good one
way to spend the HR energy.
You know what I'm saying?
Corporate energy needs to be spent on,
on pronouns and identify them.
Yeah. Um, what is this world?
Mommy's loved the show.
Can't wait to see Tom and Omaha.
I have a story about my cousin who was
born with six toes on his left foot. Yeah.
When they went to the doctor to get it
removed, they cut off the wrong tone.
Shut up. So instead of
cutting off the outside Pinky,
which I don't know what you call that,
the cut off the actual pinky toe. No,
look at his foot.
He has a two inch gap between the ring
toe and his pinkie and being the mess of
person I am. I would laugh
every time I saw it. Sure.
Fuck all the haters and the cross eyed
doctor who can't tell the difference
between a regular tow and the extra
one, Billy Jesus. That's bad luck.
How does that happen?
You don't have like a big marker
that you point to the fucking thing.
Yeah, I will. I've read,
I've seen that in movies where people
put an x on the leg they're supposed to
have amputated just to make
sure. Yeah. Yeah, I do.
How do you get the wrong one off dude?
I Dunno. Fuck that. I remember
in town it was Tampa. Um,
it was a big, it was a, it
became a national story,
but it was a guy who was supposed
to have his leg amputated.
Amputated the wrong one. Yeah. Cool. So
he became a double amputee. God dammit.
Hang on. Oh one sucks. But
at least it's, you know,
survivable kind of.
Yeah.
Yeah. Cause you, your equilibrium will
be off with the, with a missing toe,
but you won't be
completely horrible. Or at least
that guy, the guy who, you know,
I'm sure one of those last thoughts.
And last they said it was like, hey,
at least you'll still have one leg.
And he was a true,
and then you wake up and they're like big,
actually
I second sake you're going to lose both.
But also we're going to give you like
$6 million. And he was like, all right,
for, is that worth it? Does that mean,
what dollar amount would that
be worth to you? I'd be super,
do you know that's how the
law works though. The idea
is to make you whole, again,
that's the phrase I used in my two weeks
in law school to make somebody whole
again. And what that means is
monetary compensation. It's,
that's literally what they're doing is
like we'll just fill up the leg hole with
money.
Oh
that um,
those monetary settlements
are based on the,
you have
and your ability to earn
money. So like when, right.
Tracy Morgan was in that huge accident
with the Walmart driver. Oh, right, right,
right, right. He, you know, the
terms has never been released,
but it's been a reported
that his settlement amount
is astronomical because he's
earned,
you know,
he's worth a lot of money
and the potential earnings
that they could affect when
he was out of commission are
off the chain to diminish.
How would it affect it as potential
turning and you saw it like with him,
they don't go like,
like for a regular Joe they might say,
we'll give you $5 million. Right, okay.
Yeah. And with him it's many, many,
many times. That's his definition of
making him exactly, which is just money,
which is bananas to me.
I would also throw in stuff like,
I mean like if you got murdered by
someone, like I be like, I want to,
I want that guy to apologize to me every
morning I wanted to come to my house
and like get down on his knees and
beg forgiveness and stuff like that.
Like what is this like for instance carry,
you just demand that whoever did the
wrong common repent like every morning to
you don't think you can do that.
I'd like to, if someone murdered,
did you see that guy
that wanted to kill the,
the in the courtroom? Who is it? It's
that famous trial and he's like to the,
to the judge, like can I spend
some time alone with this man?
The one that was at the coach
that was molesting? Yeah.
The doctor that the USA
gym and then he took off,
tried to attack them and the,
yeah,
the cops tackled them and yeah,
but that was great. He's like,
can I have money alone in the room
with this guy? And she was like, no.
It's like I was going to do it
anyway. You like good for you. Yeah,
totally understandable. Was even held in
contempt or like, I don't know, probably.
I'm sure it's one of those things
where they have to, you know,
protect any citizen from that happening.
They pry pull 'em back and they're like,
that's $5. Yeah. It's all good man. I wish
we could give you five minutes with him.
Yeah, yeah. God Damn. Doctor Nassar. Yes.
What a scumbag.
He was like,
he molested sexually abuse
like hundreds of girls,
so horrible real piece of
garbage. Um, this was great.
This is from super bowl
week. Uh, this is a guy,
his name was Al Sean Jeffries and I
think he played college ball at South
Carolina, if I remember
correctly. Plays for Philadelphia.
And one of the big things about
the super bowl is you have,
it's basically media week.
There's a lot of hype around the game.
So the guys have to do media day and
there's just all these things around the
game and he could not be less interested.
And you could tell that when he's being
interviewed. I mean, this is just magic.
I love shit like this.
We were talking to lane earlier and he
said that he and the team and everybody's
trying to keep this as
normal of a week as possible,
but this is anything but normal.
How much fun is this and how much are
you enjoying this experience so far?
All right, misty. God
Man, this shit terrible.
Donatos I find that we
could have stayed in Philly.
Come on Friday or Saturday.
Yeah. Love it. I love it. Totally
honest. Yeah. He's not doing the,
um, the answer that they want you to
like the NFL wants. You'd be like,
this is great, man.
I'm having so much fun.
Then you wouldn't get to see Timberlake
and all the other celebrities.
It's part of the experience,
right? Uh, you're a normal person.
Then he bleeds just like, I believe
he got through. It was just like, so,
I mean he's, he's a celebrities
to you. I mean, hats off to him.
I listen to his music. I'm here,
great guy. I mean great artists,
but I'm here to play football.
I care less about other shit.
Agreed.
It's such a great answer.
Did you see the temperature for Game
Day on Sunday? Can we plant indoors? Oh,
she wear outside though. How
would that affect it? I mean,
we'll be here. It makes sense. The
headache calling New York, right?
I don't think super. We'll
be here. Fair enough.
Yeah. Good for him though.
He's got a point. I mean,
do you see the temperature for it?
We're playing indoors. Doesn't matter.
What if you weren't, I think those
hypothetical's it's like what?
But can you imagine if you guys weren't
allowed to wear helmets on Sunday? Yeah.
That would be crazy. I mean, yeah, don't
bother me. The temperature doesn't matter,
dude.
You know what I was thinking about these
athletes and they're traveling to China
and even these guys would
have to play foosball.
I mean more time you could spend at home
sleeping normally eating normal food,
you know,
not in a hotel room.
When you can't sleep and
they're disrupting their lives,
they're not going to be in optimal
shape. The distraction, you know,
the potential for distractions
is the big thing. Yeah.
That's really what the worry is
when you play in these games. No,
it's just sad it he's right. Let me stay
home. I can be with my fucking family.
There's a double pipe validity questions
here. Okie dokie. Let's see. Hey,
Hitler's today at work had a double pike
classic for the first time in two years.
I have a question about its validity.
I had been chewing gum all day. Oh,
interest heard acts as a laxative.
So does it count if my body was getting
a little help from a possible laxative,
fuck me, piss on me and beat me. John. No,
chewing gum is not a laxative. It's not.
I thought he was going to say
it probably contributed. Um,
and he'd be correct in assuming too.
Maybe that burp. No error. These,
you're chewing and you're swallowing
air cause somebody beat me. Um,
I think it's definitely still a double
pipe. I mean everybody who has one,
nope, ate or drank and has
some ahead of time, you know,
you can't listen. But he's,
this person is saying that they've kind
of enhanced the odds of having a double
pipe in it and that's manipulating the
score. I'm sorry, I don't agree with that.
That's like saying I chew gum,
I had a can of beans and then I drink soda
and then I had a double pipe. Classic.
Well yeah,
because you're manipulating.
Definitely still count because people eat
beans and drink so it all the time and
it doesn't because you're
still like the air.
It's not that that air is going to
come out because you ate a drink.
That's why you have that gas buildup.
It's that they came out at the same time.
If they really did BURP Fart, same time,
then you had one, well let me tell him,
this is not a sneeze.
Take steroids and you win the race.
Is that still going to be winning?
And I think that if the double pipe
classic occurs in nature, it's natural.
It happens without forcing
it. You're like, no,
I think it's equivalent to using steroids.
What do you mean the 20 friends?
Anything that you eat is going to affect
your gas. So then you're saying like,
okay, I had a Tacos for lunch as
account. No, because you had to go.
But we're talking about gaming the system,
talking about purposely loading up on
re fried beans and purposely drinking a
lot of soda to create the effect of the
double pipe. That's what I'm saying.
I'm not saying you happen to have
tacos and that's a different thing.
I'm saying this person,
this person is saying they're forcing it.
They didn't say I forced, they said I
had gum and then something happened.
It is a rare event and you get credit.
It was a double pipe classic. Uh,
you did it John.
You did it all right.
That's what you think. I, you know,
potato Patato I think it should occur
without interference. Do so when,
when like let's say he's like, I had
a coke before, does it count now?
It doesn't count either. Like what,
what can be hearsay? Here's what,
here's what it'll count. It's fine if it's
just a coke. Okay, let's just say no, no.
I'll tell you why. Yes, yes, you
may. You may increase the Burbage,
but you're not. It's not going to affect
your [inaudible]. Now, if you were,
say I ate a bunch of re fried beans and
dried apricot and then I loaded up on
coke.
You're trying to game the system and at
delet pipe classic has to kind of happen
organically. You cannot force it.
You just can't unreal and if you do,
it's cheating. I don't think that's fair.
I don't think that's right. I would say,
what is,
I'm going to go out and say this.
I don't think you should be able to
weigh in on this if that's your logic.
I mean you're like one of those corrupt
referees that's also betting on games.
Okay. Now I know a lot of people
have been writing about last week's.
Would you rather we did.
Would you rather,
all the music you listened to is the
song the heat is on or all the movies you
watch be sister,
act two and now people run back in the
habit if you don't mind doing the full
time. Sorry. Uh, and people
were like, Christina,
what about when the music happens in
the film? Is that the heat is on? No,
those are two separate things.
If you're,
if you chose the only film you can
watch is distract too back in the habit,
you're entitled to all the tunes
and all the music you will hear.
It just drags you back in the habit.
It's not that you'll hear the
anxious all the time. Yeah. So, but,
but they're saying if you chose the ages,
oh,
as your only music than if you're watching
sister act to will you hear the h is
oh, oh, that's interesting. Well then
that would be, yes. Sorry, sorry.
So I'm, I'm fucking flipping here.
Well, let's say you choose the Hso.
Every form of music you hear will be,
the heat is on.
So you watched sister out to as you
get to watch. No. But that's the thing.
You get to watch whatever
movie you want now,
but any form of music you hear
will be the heat is on. Right.
So in the movie sister act too, they
could be singing. Hallelujah. Jesus.
But you're going to hear the
heat is on because you're,
the only songs you can hear are the
heat is on. You don't want, I'm sorry.
So you don't get to think you're confused
by the question now what be initially
it was if you choose one or the
yes. Sorry, I'm confused if you,
if you pick songs. Okay. If you pick,
I get to listen to any music
I want. Right, right, right.
And you're only movie his sister act too.
Back in the habit.
Okay. Yes. Then you can
listen to any music you want.
You only get one fellow sister act to,
Oh hey, sorry. Go ahead. Quite yet. Okay.
If you pick, I can listen
to any music. Sorry.
You're only movie his sister. Act
correctly. Correct. Back in the habit.
You can listen to any
music you want after that,
but you can never watch any TV or films.
You only get to watch sister act too
back in the habit and you get it.
It's an in it's entirety.
Okay. The way it's performed.
Okay. If you pick, I don't,
I'd rather have the other choice.
In other words,
I'd rather be able to watch any film.
Right. Then you only get one song.
In that case, the only music you
ever hear is the ages. Oh, okay.
Right. Yeah, that's, that's
good. Yeah. That makes sense.
Does that answer the question
though? Yeah, I think so. Um,
all right.
Is there anything else Jean?
I don't think so. I mean, I
got to get a deli meat scale.
That's right.
Am I get my hands on one of those?
We should just look on Amazon. See
if it's possible. Look at that.
We've got a ways. Our banner. Yeah.
I mean we gotta be able to wait.
I'm going to get a glass one.
Like that lady said Yeah.
Using our banner or your mom's
House podcast. Click on the better.
This bombing homepage, isn't it?
Huh? Kicks a little back to the show.
So, all right. That's it then gene.
Yeah. How's it mom? Tom? cigarette.com.
Christina p online.com your mom's
house@podcast.com thank you.
As always for listening to our show.
Here is a song I haven't heard yet. Uh,
it's called,
how do you not find it funny by Alan Bell?
Ready Gene? Yeah. Goodbye
everybody. Genes. Jane.