This episode of Your Mom's house is
brought to you by Saatva luxury mattress.
The only online mattress company that
provides free delivery set up and mattress
removal.
Your mom saw
Christina.
Let's get it.
Okay.
All right, gene, that's going to save you
all. Can't see my sweat pants, hopefully.
Are you wearing pants today?
I'm wearing pants. Yeah.
Very excited to wearing pants.
What's your dates? June. Well,
uh, uh, November 24th man,
Diego at the House of Blues
tickets are moving very quickly.
I'm almost completely sold out, so get
them now. That's Thanksgiving weekend,
you know,
and that's Saturday.
That's when you're over your
family and you're over at all.
Or maybe you want to take your folks out
to come see your favorite pair of jeans.
Do that. You know what I'm
saying? You know what I'm saying?
I'm talking about
December 7th fill her up.
Delfia and then December
8th Jude or titty is,
I've added a second show at the Gramercy
theater. 10 30 so get those tickets.
Everything's almost gone guys.
It's excited. It's a maze.
And then 2019 I'll be
announcing hopefully soon.
Jane. I can tell you this. I'm
going to blue jeans, Oregon.
20 tickets left home early show and
Jean and about 60 to the late show.
That's it.
Boys seed is all sold out.
All Sacramento has tickets for the
late show on October six where Paul
Sacramento. Oh, ball sack a fart. No,
also known as Fresno,
California.
That's October 26.
There are tickets available for that
show and the next day in Bakersfield.
What's Bakersfield?
I don't know if all the
haters field. Hey, I like it.
Then I go to the dirty,
dirty south Florida.
I go to Fort Fort Myers,
Jack me off.
Bill and Orlando and Augusta.
Come on, you're George. Hey,
those are all in November. Uh, very
few tickets remaining in Orlando.
Jack me off.
Phil and a Augusta a Fart.
Meyers still has tickets.
The third show and fill her up.
Delphia it's moving along nicely.
Uh,
all those tickets@thompsongrow.com
slash tour.
A lot of people hit me up
about the Chang because it
sold out very fast. They're
giving us a second date. Um,
it w it's not going to be the same night,
but that second day will be sometime
in 2019 and I'll have that for you soon
along with some big announcements.
Go to [inaudible], grow.com.
Click on the tour page and
sign up for that mailing list.
She can get the news before anybody else.
You know what seed about Pachanga is
that it already sounds like a dirty word,
doesn't it? Does put it in my Pachanga
whoa. Right. Like your pipe notcher yeah.
Yeah. That's what it sounds like.
Pen out yet. That's a problem.
Or maybe it's not a problem. Maybe it's,
maybe that's why everyone likes it there.
Okay. Okay. All right man.
So much to go over today.
How tight are your genes?
Minor. Very tight. Of course.
Super tight.
Got post-pregnancy genes and they're
always tight right now until I can lose a
few lbs. Wouldn't be tighter now. Uh, all
right, let's get into it. You Ready? Yeah,
I'm ready. Let's do it. Let's do it.
Did you shit in your fucking pants?
Yeah.
Well go to your mom's house.
I'm looking forward to these days being
a dad and I'm having the kids fart in
the car and torturing mom. Yeah, I
know why you picked this clip. Why?
Because this mirrors are real life.
Yesterday on the way home from my dinner,
it was pretty bad.
Walk me through what happened.
This is a liquid ass pranked by the
way. You know it's that spray. Oh yeah.
We've had, we've people have
said to us that one. Yeah.
It's not nearly as volatile as what
you've got in your real ass. Well,
yesterday was an interesting
day because it was a travel day.
I'll always a recipe, cross country
travel day, just bad things happen. Sure.
I'm at the hotel early, eating
some breakfast, having caught,
did you have for breakfast? I had
a mom lit okay. With veggies. Uh,
yeah. There was spinach,
onions, mushrooms, and you
don't eat those very often.
It's very volatile. It's
not true. I ate that,
uh, had some bacon. Coffee. Oh yeah.
Then you were up early, early, too
early. Just does something to your guts.
I know what it is. I know.
And then I shit at the hotel.
Then I drive more than an hour.
Get to the airport.
You have another like half coffee,
another coffee and I just started now.
I just started, honestly I get,
I got on the plane with it.
I gave it to the flight attendant.
Right. Can you just throw,
someone's going to say, because usually
I drink my morning coffee and then I,
shit, I don't really want
coffee right away. I was like,
I don't really enjoy this and I
slept for a few hours. I don't know.
But your whole, your whole digestive
track is messed up that day. Yeah,
it really is waking up super early.
If it would mess my stomach up to
her and my stomach would just hurt.
And then I got back here eight something
here, I don't know. Then we went out.
What do we have for dinner? Oh yeah,
I had that um, salmon, salmon, salmon,
the hardest. I had the salmon and then,
um, yeah, on the way out of there,
just,
you know what's fun is because we say
Saulman as a joke and that when we're out
in public,
so many people say Saulman with
a hard l and that it's not right.
Including the server. It's a correct.
Yeah. Look, do you want to Solomon?
And I go, I do. And I go, can you
make it medium rare? He's like,
they don't make take temperature.
Change it for the Salomon here.
It was like that.
And I hear library a lot too.
And there's a lot there. Sometimes it
get tweeted you directions for things.
So we sit like it will be
like intentionally to, to
really say pacifically.
Yes, it's jokes. So, so
wait a minute. So we,
I remember this, we had is we had
our Saulman I had some seafoods too.
And then on the drive home. Oh
yeah, yeah, yeah. So I farted.
Well it's not just a fart.
It was like an atomic. Yeah,
that's what I'm saying though.
And you had your head out the window.
You're like my husband,
he farted. First of all,
here's the shit thing you do is
you don't give me any heads up.
There's no warning, and then you don't
cross ventilate, which everybody knows.
If you're going to fart in the car,
all the windows have to be down,
passenger and driver. You got to cross
ventilate that fucking thing. It was hot.
It was hot. It was hot and it
smelled like a dirty diaper.
Like it smells like our newborns farts.
I got to give it to me,
give it up. To me it was real nasty. What
did it feel like coming out? Was it hot?
Yeah. Yeah. No, I knew it was as it came
out. I was like, this, I told you I'll go,
this is going to be bad. Oh, I know. And
I was saying that before I smelled it too.
I just knew by the feeling. I was
like, oof what you're telling me.
Did you tell us on this show?
Some guy you,
you saw him dancing with
headphones on and then he farted.
Did you say this on the show? Said it
was so funny. I'll never forget that.
That was in DC.
It was on a lunch break.
I was working with another guy named
Tom and he was really into music.
We went to a record store and it
was back when the record stores,
they had the listening station
and the guy was like,
he just ripped a huge fart and
we fell out turn. It was like,
I think he really thought we
were laughing at his voice.
Well you didn't because you think people
can hear what you're, what you're doing.
And he was a big guy. Yeah. And I think
that that fart escaped without him.
You wait a minute, Tom, this is a bit Eh,
sizes to view.
Are you saying that fat people have
girthy or or smelling your farts?
Cause I don't know why a smelly or but
maybe girthy or in media or maybe you
think the fatness is directly
proportionate. Maybe has
a, it's a factor. Maybe.
Maybe they're eating more garbage,
but your mom's got monstrous forest.
That's a good point. He's like 80 pounds.
Great counterpoint. Yeah, the 40
as far as I've ever heard. Right.
And smelly. Very slowly. This
is a question for science.
We have to ask a doctor.
Yeah. Yeah. It always
real here late. Let's,
let's examine this dad's reaction a
little more to this, uh, smell in his car.
Sure.
What God
did you shoot it so
it's not all farm?
Just like fucking dumb shit.
They were us yesterday. I
am expelling here. Yeah.
All right Kate, how far looking? Yeah.
I feel like these words come out of my
mouth every week of my life with you.
That can't be a 5,005.
I've said this exact thing over and over.
What is that? Since
we've been together. Now
you're just going to help
and then he eats his ramen
or whatever the fuck.
Great spray in there. I was there ice
cream in there. He's not eating top ramen.
I don't think that's wrong.
Oh, smell anymore. Well, God
know I love this guy. Oh God.
These guys
believe that came out of here.
Now I'm nervous now.
Somebody somehow like that.
That's like every married couples
discussion. I mean that is,
that's ultimate dad too. That's
a real dad. You know, his dad is,
the dad should fart. Well. Yeah,
but I mean that's a bad reaction.
I remember as a kid, we would take these
road trips, especially my uncle Dave,
he'd be like, oh, he's like Jesus
Christ. What do you piss pots?
Just because this spots and Ding
dongs Jesus go to the bathroom.
Christ stinks. You guys stink. Do
you rip a Fart? You always said that.
Cut apart. Cut. You cut a foreign
ramp. A fighter. My favorites. Yeah.
Cutting a fart. That's social
foreigner thing. Oh my God. Yeah.
Um,
here's another dad here.
Take it to the east coast.
Hello son. Hello Butch.
You're gonna fuck up your
stinking dirty. Pasty. Yeah. Yup.
I'm a big smelly fucking Turd,
which didn't, can do get it busted.
So I'm going to talk to our children to
see exactly how can fantastic talking to
her.
That's sick. That drill. I'm not
getting that. No one looked at
under a place. You the top.
Oh Man. No, I'm not. Fuck
No, I'm not getting in there.
You big dirty corn. It's
good though. As he fuck gone.
It doesn't
see.
First of all,
this is way better way to communicate
with someone or your children devil. Yeah.
The way that he calls his kid a
dirty, rotten ginger headed con. Yes.
I mean,
I just love that so much.
He rarely find American parents like that.
No, I know this is a foreigner thing.
My parents used to curse at me all
the time. I love it all the time.
I immediately smile when I see somebody
to talk to their kid like that.
This is more normal to me then you know,
oh sweet.
I actually feel like that means you
like your kid even more. Yeah, I agree.
I don't like that.
I agree.
You don't think of them as an
experiment that you're raising? No.
Like if I would farm, my dad would
be like, oh, so, oh real hardcore.
[inaudible] like you've rotten
whore mother kind of and like,
yeah, I think I was normal. Why that
never got mad. You know? My Dad,
he was always like, he's just, he's
like, Jeez, wow. It's like you do that.
That really stinks because you probably
need to take a ship away because your
dad doesn't like lay blame.
He's so sweet. He loves it.
He loves the game and loves shits.
He does.
So as soon as you are like you've
rip one, he's just like, wow,
that's really something. Now you saw it
ever gets mad. You saw him in breast,
a breast balls, beach. He saw him. I
saw a top dog and Charo and any updates?
Um, no. I mean it's pretty much same
shit. Different toilet, you know? Yeah.
Yeah. Did he tell you any
poop stories or anything? No,
not really. Okay. So it's
consistent or good? Yeah. Uh, oh,
I have a hemorrhoids update. Oh, we're
not done with this though. I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
All right Jordan. I'll save it. Oh,
come on man. There's no
throwing him on. There's no
up God. It sounded like it was Gunna, no,
he's just grossed out by his sons.
Fart
dirty Boston
children.
I love this guy so much.
That's it. That's it.
Sorry you have a hemorrhoid up to,
I didn't mean to.
It's a little late on this queue,
isn't it?
We've been talking about shit for
the first 10 minutes of the show.
Well I just want to say it
[inaudible] Huh?
Or late than never. That's right.
So anyways, I at first of all,
thank you for the outpouring of emails
and concern about my hemorrhoids.
I really appreciate all the
thoughtful advice. It is
really nice guys. Yeah. So, uh,
many of you recommended
a Tux medicated pads. Um,
I got a recommendation for this Chinese
cream you can buy on Amazon to that's
coming and if high fiber or
things of that nature, but,
which I tell you I already have
pretty fiber's good dumps. Um,
and I started using talks.
What I would do is I like if I knew I
was kind of sitting around for a minute,
like to breastfeed the kid or something,
I'd take 'em a tox pad and kind of fold
it like a Taco and then just put it up
against my hemorrhoids.
Like just kinda like a,
like a pad and have it soak on my
hemorrhoid. You know what I mean?
Like just sitting there.
Good News.
It's already worked on going to dry heave.
There's no more pain.
It's the pain has gone and, and that
must be the power of Tux. So thank you.
Thank you. It's gone. I mean it's not, the
bump is still there, but there's no pain.
If that makes sense.
Is that how that's supposed to resolve?
I guess so. Like does a bump go
away or it's just, I don't know.
I've just done an expert. Yes. You are in
hemorrhoids. No, I'm not. You have them.
Don't you have, I mean I've seen
blood before, but that's not it.
Those are internal ones, right?
Yeah. But I don't have a your issue,
the external ones. No.
Ari has the internal ones.
Ari's issues are vast.
Yeah.
And series should have asked him.
I can't believe he's alive after seeing
what his asshole looks like is so
horrific.
Everyone's seen his butt hole.
I almost passed out when I saw it at
the fire. I swear. I've never though.
It's like, oh, you so nasty.
It's so nasty. He's so nasty.
Um, poor guy. He really has serious ain't
home problems. Real serious problems.
I did also want to point out,
um,
I'm doing a Conan tonight.
Come,
so that'll be up by the time you hear
it or listen to this. Yeah, that's it.
I've been there a few times.
It's always fun to go back.
Burt was there last night.
Who, uh, Bart. Yeah. And uh,
I didn't get to see it,
but, uh, that was sent, uh,
just a small clip from his appearance if
you guys want to listen to what he did
on the show niggers. Oh,
all right. Well, you know,
we each have our own
different way of performing.
I wonder if Conan and brought
him out as the world's fattest,
most racist comedian working
today. Good thing to look up. Yeah.
That's really caught fire and I'm pretty
happy about that. Well, obviously, I mean,
he is. Yeah. Was that, that was his
opener, right? He sat down, I guess.
And you just did that. Yeah. Conan was
like, oh, okay. Hey Conan's not racist.
No, no, neither is Andy. I wonder
how they dealt with it. Yeah, no.
Um, interesting. So I think these
are the same guys, by the way.
That made that, um, my dad,
he never made us ashamed of a heart
penises. Christ. Yeah, that was terrible.
Another clip. You want to see
it now? Here it is. Oh, thanks.
Said that mother fucker. Randy. Every
time he gets more than six beers in them,
it gets pissed off and leaves us.
Tell me about it.
I'm getting fucking sick of
walking home from work every day.
I'm going to cut his balls
off the see him don't balls.
My wife's gonna bite mine off
for not being home on time.
What's she making a big
dinner? Yeah. Nah, it's Friday.
She expects me to fuck her all night long.
What the Hell is wrong with that?
Nothing. I mean, I just put a
pillow over her face and go to town.
It's just what?
Geez. Is that, is that what you do?
She likes to start things
off by giving me some head.
Her teeth always make my
Dick Ra her teeth. Oh,
bitches can't suck a dick worth a day.
I guess because of my size.
She can't open up any wider. C'Mon.
Let's go. Where is this headed? Huh?
I don't know.
I've never had good head and your whole
life and go on hikes like this to all
the time.
Is this your hiking?
I don't think I ever really have one
kit that fucking cock out of your pants.
Yeah, that's cuts off right there,
unfortunately. Hulu man. What the fuck,
Ben? Well, do you not know
what's happening next? No,
I don't know what's going to happen.
Yes. I just went on a hike this morning.
This is, this is eerily reminiscent. Yeah.
This is all your hikes and by the way,
yeah. You're always like,
oh, I'm going hiking. Yeah.
I met a lot of Nice guys on my
hike. Yeah, there are. There's,
there's guys just like this with the
hats like this and with sleeveless vests
and a tight jeans.
I love the tight Jean for a hike.
I didn't even think about that. Yeah,
their attire, they're wearing like what?
Boots? Yeah. And this is a uniform of
straight heterosexual Niagen guys. Yeah.
Oh,
bitches can't suck a dick worth a damn.
Just a couple of straight guys hiking
and cowboy boots and I'm worth than a
bitch that can't suck a dick worth a
damn. You know, I got to fuck my wife.
I'll Friday night long. All right. I put
a pillow over her head and I go to town.
I sure hope our deliveries
or fact that fucking
cock out of your pants.
Our pilot, if it gets picked up. Oh
yeah. Then the acting is terrible.
It was pretty terrible. That's what makes
it great. And they just stand there.
Really
cause that cock out of your pants.
Come on. Be Honest. If you met
some guy on the hiking trail.
Yeah and he was like
vicious cancer car for shit.
[inaudible] trying to try me out.
Try it out.
I was taking my 10 or 12
Benadryl piss on me, beat me.
Would I give it a shot? I'm a hot
white trash, calm dump. I mean I'm the,
I'm not totally opposed to it. I just
feel like, I mean, you know, I'm hot,
I'm on the trail. It's
all dirty or sweaty. Yeah.
It's like also people are going to
walk by, where are we going to do?
They don't care. And Gay guys don't
care about that. Oh really? Wow.
They just fuck out in the streets.
When I lived in San Diego,
I'd see guys to see this fucking, this
is in the height of like the 90s though.
Wouldn't when, you know gay guys ruled
that place. I don't know if they still do.
Now it's more yuppies.
But I'm telling you,
one time I saw two guys just
butt fucking on the street. Uh,
clubs everywhere guys.
So fucking quit putting their dicks
through holes and other guys just going to
suck. I'm their savages, dude.
They're awesome. They used to rule it.
It was like awesome. Well this gay Mecca,
like if he were a gay guy, you should,
you should live in San Francisco.
You want to make, it makes me crazy.
When gay people write
to me and they're like,
I live in fucking Alabama and they hate,
they hate me because I'm gay.
I'll get the fuck out of there.
Yes.
Not just the gays who
are doing the butt stuff.
Do you want to know something
that's really amazing. Oh, what?
A couple who were desperately try and I
can see they'd been having sex the wrong
way for four years. No kidding.
Yes. 26 and 24 years old.
Oh my God. They were like, we
keep failing to get pregnant.
The sex on a regular basis.
During the appointment,
the woman admitted that sex
was usually painful and uh,
they were very young, very healthy,
hilarious, couldn't conceive.
They were having a lot of stress.
And uh,
the doctor discovered that the couple
had mistakenly been having anal
intercourse rather than vaginal conceive
four years of marriage. And either the
husband or wife knew how to get pregnant.
Goodness. Porns banned in
China. Right? I Dunno. Maybe.
Probably the state controls,
you know. Yeah. I mean,
these people aren't being educated.
I doubt they teach them
about the birds and the bees.
That's wild.
That is wild.
Oh yeah. It says sex education faces
great challenges in China. Djing. John,
a professor of sociology at Beijing's,
I don't know how to say the Tsing Hua.
I'm fluent in Chinese university at Tang.
Ha.
Students take sex education to you?
Not even going to comment on me on
my beautiful pronunciations. St Claw.
Yeah. Take sex education classes where
they learn basic melanose any condoms.
Okay.
Anyway.
Huh?
Wow.
Good stuff. Bad stuff for, for for
how many years? That's terrible.
But now that that is, I mean this
has to be a stupid couple. I mean,
why would you put it in?
That's where the chocolate comes out.
It's pretty, pretty. Uh, pretty wild.
Oh, is it time? Hold on one second.
I might have 18 seconds and my timer,
go ahead. Let them know. Ching Chong,
Ching Chong. Where's that one? No,
you want to fuck with my main memory
that I remember. Just singing what?
I know. I'm just singing
what I know from this show.
I'm not making fun of Asian people.
That's an actual drop.
Okay. There you go.
Alright. Okay. There you go.
So there she is. So I dug it up.
[inaudible] I was referencing a
song and you know, come on guys.
It was
a really back in the news
heavily. These last four hours. Is
that one? Louis Ck. Great.
He did too.
That was an actual audio recording
of the incidents. Right, right.
But he did two appearances,
this, uh, this weekend,
one at the comedy cellar,
a famed New York City Comedy Club.
And one I think out in governors
in Long Island at the comedy club.
And uh,
both were surprised sets
and these are both a new,
these are his first appearances
doing standup since he admitted to,
um, jerking off in front of people
without their consent. Yes. And, uh,
that was a huge bomb drop. Yes. Uh,
it was a huge bomb that dropped last
November and everybody, you know,
at least in comedy, has been
like, ah, will he come back?
Like, just jump the gun,
just what will happen again. And He,
uh, he's doing spots. It looks like,
you know what's interesting is
that huge backlash, by the way,
people aren't exactly applauding
this return. Most people are not.
And it's interesting because we've had
conversations with other people in our
business. Like what's
the timeline here? Right.
How long do you think he's gonna hold
out before he comes back and it's been
nine months.
Yeah.
I have to tell you like I
didn't hate him before this.
I was kind of like them on the scale
of shitty things that have happened.
He's not a Weinstein. He's not
exactly a Cosby. He sucks. That sucks.
But it was not on the scale
of Shit. Shit Bird. Yeah.
This makes me not like him
cause you're like motherfucker,
if you don't know to stay the
fuck away for at least a year,
you don't got no sense. He has no sense.
And talk about the sense of entitlement.
Like dude, you're clueless. Like
if you're coming back this early,
that's just my take. Wait at least a year.
Don't you think? Uh, you know it's funny,
I didn't really think of the specifics
of it because it's not my life.
You know what you mean? The specifics
like how to come back like was,
I didn't like lay out a plan because
I'm not anything that I deal with.
Not your concern in life.
Yeah.
So I mean I was always of the mindset
that I believed that a path to redemption
should exist, not just for him.
I mean, just for most people in,
in life, like people who do bad
things like Cosby though. Well, okay,
how has it really bad? My point was that
is that, you know, somebody gets arrested,
let's say goes to jail for
any number of terrible things.
You could be accused of
assault, armed robbery, murder,
manslaughter,
all these horrible things.
Eventually some of those people
get released and it's like,
you can't just be like, that's
it. Like you don't get to, well,
you're back in society now. You have
to figure out ways. So for, for a lot
of people, they go, you know,
let's say somebody is accused
of a horrific violent thing.
They're locked up for 20 some
years. They go, well, they did,
they paid their debt to society.
So they're entitled to whatever now,
even though people don't have
to hire them. Right. You know,
so this is obviously not the same thing,
but there is some parallel to,
um,
there's a bad thing done.
You need to pay some type of price.
There's pennants and yeah.
So the, you can make an
argument that, you know,
part of the penance is the
public shame of it all. Yeah.
Part of the pennants is
losing, you know, your,
he had big television deal
with FX that went away.
Touring business just stopped. Obviously
there's monetary monetary punishments.
Sure. Then you have to
go, well, um, if he did,
you know, he did admit to doing these
things. Like the probably, I mean there's,
again,
this is just an opinion needs to be
some type of interaction with the um,
people that you or you know,
uh,
let them dictate some
terms of making it okay.
In other words,
some woman that he jerked
off in front of gets to say,
you know, it'd be great if, uh, yeah,
if you were to donate
to this organization or,
I dunno,
I don't have the answer,
but I'm saying you need to at least
consider probably some of those peoples,
um,
feelings in this.
Well, I think what you're saying,
which is I agree with too,
is like the way the law functions,
right?
Like there's no real due
process with what's happening.
People are being accused and then it's
like you're gone off with your head
disappear. Whereas there's no like
legal system being involved. Yeah. Um,
if we could have, I wish gotten legal
system, maybe there's a way to get,
if the legal system had been involved,
it's a much clear cut because path, right.
Because the whole point is
to make somebody whole again,
that's the whole point
of the legal system.
And it was also like a direct punishment.
So you go, right, you're going to jail,
you're paying a function.
Pennants dependents. Yeah. And I,
and I think that might be the,
the biggest flaw of the me too
movement is just like, okay, I get it.
Like we're not victim blaming. If a
girl says I should happen. Yeah. Okay.
It happens. So let's get
it. What are the next steps?
Let's be very clear and specific about
punishment and, and, yeah. And we weren't,
and that's why this shit is not
fucking working now and now he's back.
I think he should,
um, you know, you, you can't stop someone
from doing whatever. I mean, no, he,
you know, seems like illegal.
Seems like he's, I dunno,
it seems like he's going
to keep doing spots.
I imagine what I think is crazy actually.
Is that so crazy?
I do think it's crazy that the clubs,
um,
let surprise droppings
the [inaudible] case.
Somebody should have been the
gatekeeper here and been like, oh no,
it's not cool to have a polarizing person.
Surprise. Poppin right.
Because there must be, yeah.
Cause then you're basically saying that
people who are in the audience who's
night might be ruined by it.
You're like, so it's like, dude,
let them let the person,
I'm all for the market dictating what,
what's okay and not sure. So if you
go, Louise, on this show tonight,
you're allowing audience people to go,
okay,
I support the venue and the
comic. I'm spending my money. Um,
go ahead. Right. Let me
show me what's what. Right.
Let the consumer decide
whether or not there,
because you're not really letting that
happen. And I know some people were like,
yeah, but they can get up and
leave. It's like, yeah, but no,
they don't want to get up and leave.
Let them figure out whether or not
that's the place they want to be.
To watch that. It's so funny because
we were talking about this yesterday,
even before this happened.
So fine.
Why don't we just talking about Louis
before this story broke like yesterday at
dinner and uh, and we were like,
you know, at the end of the day,
a lot of people don't give a shit
what people do in their private lives.
What's that director who lives in
France and he was fucking left Polanski.
Hollywood's still gives that guy, you
know, the, the high five on his work.
I made a documentary about
how great he was. Yeah.
A couple of years ago called wanted and
desired and I watched it and everyone in
Hollywood was before me too.
Stuff took off. Everyone was
there. Like, he's a great,
amazing men. Like you fuck a
13 year old girl, the hot tub.
Like nobody fucking cares. Yeah.
People were like, he wanted Oscar.
He wanted an Oscar. Years
later, a few Oscars.
Woody Allen's been shipping his
stepdaughter for what, 20 years now.
People are like, oh, talents.
And now they're like, no,
no, no, he's no good anymore.
But it took all the other stuff.
But no one should be marrying his
fucking adopted. I mean, look and,
but the point being that yes, there's
more awareness draw bought, brought to it,
but people still can separate. There's
still came from the art. I mean,
and look,
he's going to have a massive audience.
Of course people still
want to see him do stands.
He's so silly to go out this early
though. I just don't think it's, it's not,
it's clue.
Can I tell you what it is?
It really shows to me an arrogance and
an obliviousness to the gravity of this
movement and the gravity
of what he's done.
It to me reads very callous and like my
younger chefs going to do what I want to
do and you know, it's interesting
his approach to it of like,
I'm just going to show up and do this
and he doesn't bring it up on stage.
He's like, Oh, is this okay?
Very similar to what he was
doing to women. Right? Like,
I'm going to jerk off.
I hope this is okay with you guys.
Like it's the same fucking approach of
like is there's, okay, I'll a too late.
I'm already doing it.
Like there was no,
there's no consent in both of those
scenarios. Right. Him showing up,
doing a pop in and then him taking his
deck out and asking if it's okay and he's
already come.
You know,
it would have been amazing if he did his
like top in 15 minutes set and then the
host comes back out, you know, take
the money and just start streaming.
Hey man, good side. And then Louise like,
oh come on man. And he was like, oh no,
I'm a big fan. Yeah, that'd be fantastic.
Everybody knows, hey standing ovation.
There was
no clapping.
Everybody give him around a jerk
off. Yeah, he didn't bring it up.
He didn't even bring it up. I
heard in the set. I Dunno. I Dunno.
I heard that he didn't, I heard it was
like the usual stuff like waitresses,
donuts, whatever, the subways. Terrible.
Wait a minute,
are you not going to fucking address?
That's the thing is it's kind of,
there is a,
I'm fascinated by what the step must
be like what the hour will look like.
No. Cause who's buying that
one? That is are not Netflix. No
Netflix.
But he's going to,
I may probably the best business solution
for him 100% would be to like do his
old model, put it on his site and
whoever's on board is on board.
He'll still sell a ton of them.
I mean saying for him that works and
that leaves it to, you're not surprising,
uh, any body with it. It's just here's
content. Do you want to pay for it? Yeah,
I dunno. I want to see too, it's
like, do you open talking about it?
I would get the elephant,
like to not address it.
Here's the other thing
is like as a comedian,
do you want a somber apology at
the beginning of, uh, I mean, no.
You know, it's like, no, but don't, you
can't go up there and not address it.
You would be like,
so anything happened in the news
lately and he just starts jerking off.
Do you think he should do like that?
Um,
the drop curtain where they show the
silhouette and then he just turns and
starts going like that and he's
like, what's up guys? It's me again.
He's back. Well there's the trailer, it's,
it's a silhouette of him jerking off
and it's like your favorite jerk off
comedian. He's bad. It was called.
Do you mind just kind of gesturing
like, do you mind if I come?
Yeah, I have to say I was more partial
time if I come might, if I come,
oh, I'll make you come. I'm sure
you will. For stroke comedian.
Yeah.
I have to say that I was more on his side
kind of on this thing and now I'm more
like, oh, this guys doesn't
get it. The fact that he,
he thinks he's welcome back.
It's like he doesn't get
the gravity he doesn't get,
that's the opening sentence right now.
I'll make me come.
That's the next hour I
can make me make me come.
Jesus. Yeah. I mean by that.
Here's, okay, here's what somebody
else's thinking. Because like I said,
I didn't lay out a plan for
him so I wouldn't know. But
it's like you go, you go,
this is, you shouldn't have
done your spots now. Okay.
When is he supposed to go do spots at
least. But that's a few more months.
So what at least waiting for the holidays
for some other Creepo to come out.
One other big fish,
one other big fucking creeper that Asia
Argento story's pretty great. I kind of,
you know what,
maybe that's what did it,
cause that kind of minimize the movement
a bit is having that thing with Asia
and she was paying off the guy who
accused her of sexual assault teenager who
was a teenager if for those of
you don't know what happened.
And so Asia Argento was one,
it's like one of the leading
people and Rose McGowan. Right.
But I'm saying so we're talking about Asia
buddies. Yeah. But they just been like,
one of the faces of this,
she was also was dating Anthony Bordain
and it turns out that she was accused by
a guy who had just turned 17. So a
kid who was 16, like the week before,
uh, so nasty. She fucked
him. And she's like,
I didn't know he was a teen or something.
She was 37.
He was 17. He, uh,
came after her and he can't enforce
drugs for sure. The story at least,
you know,
what is being reported by some people
is that she then had bore Danes,
lawyers and um,
money to pay him off.
Right.
So that more Dane actually paid it
came out of board Danes pocket 380,000.
But who knows? I don't know. The,
I don't know who knows what the
fuck is really happening there.
But I do think that that deal
legitimize the movement a bit.
Having one of the people,
like one of the big people is full of
shit accusing Weinstein. Yeah. Right.
Which started this whole thing, which by
the way doesn't mean that why it seem,
didn't do that. I'm sure
he did, but I'm saying it,
it definitely lends itself to
de-legitimizing a lot of this movement.
So maybe that's why Louie felt
a little entitled. I don't know.
I'm just speculating. I don't know.
But it seems an odd choice. Um,
why now? Why not? I, if
I were him, I would stay
underground a little bit longer.
Yeah. I think, I think
seeing it happen and um,
the reaction was not positive from
what I could see, at least online.
Everybody was like pretty heated about it.
Um,
I mean from, from people in
comedy now, nobody was like,
it seems really tactless and clueless.
And honestly,
like Cosby touring right after
his accusers, it's a little,
that was super checked out. So, yeah.
So it's on that scale. You're right.
I didn't, I didn't think about it.
You know what people ask me, they're
like, you a Rachel one mother passed.
He was like,
I'll be at the club tonight.
Yeah, yeah. Walking out
of court, being like, bye.
And then he did, he did after he was
convicted, he was like, aw, yeah.
Aw, yeah, that's,
yeah, but that's what I'm, is this so far,
craziest thing that's
like level 10 being like,
it's fine.
I can just go out there and tell jokes
like I always have and I'm not going to
address it. I'm just going to, it was on
nine months ago. Big Deal. Like, dude,
I dunno it,
it definitely reads is like I'm oblivious
to the reality of the situation and
you're right, there's no pennants,
there's no closure for the women,
and he did put out a press release.
It was kind of bullshitty going back
and forth on this. They're like,
what if you're him? You're like, what is
the game plan is supposed to be? I mean,
you know, I'm serious. Like I mean, so
it's like I get that we get to say like,
no dude, this is not the good
time. Another good strategy.
But a lot of people don't know what the
strategy is. That's the whole point.
You know what the strategy is?
I'll tell you what it is.
It's what that director did who fuck
the 13 year old, you moved to France.
That's what he should do. He would
be accepted and pull that one too.
You go to France,
go to France because they don't give a
fuck about kid fuckers and master baiters
and and uh, you know rapists. You
say funny.
How'd you say come guy in Mexico.
He comes
how you joking? Joking. You
come, they invented front.
They don't give a fuck. So you moved to
France for two years. That's your penance.
You leave the country, you, you
disappear. You just have to disappear.
And that means don't check on media
to see what's up with your name.
Like fuck off the,
let the French embrace you.
And then once they've embraced
you and then you come back to it.
This fucking that director do did.
Yeah. Yeah. Leave the country, Bro.
Take your fucking family and get out.
Why do you want to be here?
Would you want to be here
when your name is being off?
I had gone through what he went through.
Oh my God.
I feel like that has to be
psychologically so devastating. Oh my God,
I have to have PTSD.
If you go from being so celebrated the
way he was celebrated to being just
destroyed. I mean, and you earned
it and this thing it's out of no,
not because of anything but
like that going through.
That's interesting point you make too.
It's very traumatizing for going cause
I was just thinking of Monica Lewinsky
who was like one of the first people to
be really publicly shamed for a sexual
thing. Right. But that she
wasn't very celebrated before.
I'm trying to think of what
that must be like. And also the,
that's the second part of it.
First,
don't forget that he
wasn't just like thought of
as like he's a funny comic or he's a guy,
he was thought discussed
and spoken of like, like a,
an artists like Monet.
I mean people talked about him in an
almost unnatural way in the comedy world
cause he was just iconic and he was just
associated with being brilliant. Oh,
he's like the car land, one of those
timeless. Yes. Yes. So it's like if you,
if you,
you know,
if you go from those types
of conversations about you
and your name every time
your name is said, it's like
people are like, oh, that
guy's really something else.
I mean, his comedy is, you
were talking about your,
your jokes as if you're talking about
poetry, you know? Oh yeah. And then to be,
just to be torn down,
thoroughly torn down and discredit
a couple of other perverts.
Jerry Lee Lewis married his 13
year old cousin. That's true.
Elvis Presley was a shipping
Priscilla 15 we have a long,
rich history of pedophiles,
perverts and rapists who are beloved.
It's true. Why the public? It
doesn't fucking matter. Ooh, yeah.
Oh God. Yeah. Oh, isn't that nice?
Women Bait.
Ah, Kevin Lord, what is happening
in this world? I don't know.
We are in the upside down this, this last
couple of years. It's just been bonkers,
right? It's been nuts. Yeah. It's
a great time to be a comedian now,
that's for sure. Fuck, man.
Yeah. But it'll be fun.
It'll be interesting to see
where this storyline goes.
I'm fascinated and that kind
of fascinated if he keeps,
if this makes them go like,
ah, it takes a break. No, no,
let's put bets on it right now.
Do you think he's that
clueless and oblivious and
checked out that he's going to
persist? I think, does he
have the self awareness to go,
I better take a step back.
I think he,
he accepted that he was going to
take his lumps when it started.
Like he knew when I, whatever the,
whatever, whatever time I come back,
there's gonna be some backlash.
So it's like, just go with it.
So I think it's going to persevere.
I think he's, well, I think,
I think he's going to go,
I knew this part was going to happen.
Just stay in it so that it kind of,
you know what I mean?
Stay the course so that the initial
blow back is the worst part.
And then just you keep doing it.
He's going to Trump his way through it.
I think so. And I think, um, it'll
be interesting to see how, you know,
reactions go with the clubs because
you need a platform to do standup. Yes,
he did. He the venue. So, um,
obviously a couple of clubs
just let them do those Poppins.
Will the other New York clubs go through
or some of them going to be like,
fuck no, it's just interesting to see
how it is and what I brought up. The,
whether you're not you announced or
surprise people with it, I think is a big,
big difference.
I say announce guys,
I think you should give the audience
and I agree with you to let,
let the market dictate. That's what we're
all about in this country. He let the,
let
the market tell you whether or not
it's working. But man, I don't know.
I don't know if I'd be interested to see
it. Only if he talks about the truth.
Only if he addresses it. Am I
interested in hearing about, you know,
uh,
the stuff he was talking about before and
now all I want to know about is what's
life been like for you
the last nine months?
It must've been fucking horrendous
and there's a way to make that funny.
You talk about the lows of being a pariah.
Many people don't get to experience that.
That's pretty fucking fascinating,
right? It's true. No. We'll see.
Yeah. Who's on board with him?
Definitely not Hannah Gatsby.
She's got a lot more to say on this.
She's got her work cut out
for another hour right now,
but just I'm writing frantically writing.
She made that.
She did an interview where she said if
Louie comes back, my work is not done.
That's what I'm saying. She's just
pan is at home writing right now.
She got her a whole hour.
It just written.
She'd be great to be having that seat
right now. Where does she live? She,
she's English and Australian.
Ah, we got to get her anything.
She was in New York for a while.
She might be in New York right now.
Well that'd be great if they
were on the same line. Oh my God.
She's like her head just exploded
backstage and these came out and was like,
the biggest piece of shit ever is back.
I would just be here to ear smiles at
that show and that's head explodes.
Oh my God.
She was just like,
just straight up. I've got
fucking cunt bag. So Matt,
just shit on everybody
there. Oh Man. Yeah.
You know the world is changing and by the
way, that is Donald Trump's um, method.
Whenever some huge shit breaks,
like the stormy Daniels and
this last one was the Guy Colin.
He's just like, I don't give a shit
fake news fuckers. Let's go. Wow.
That was brazen.
Like don't give a fuck.
I just attacks whoever he's like,
like cone was his lawyer,
his personal lawyer and fix her for
years. And then he's, he tweeted out,
if you need a lawyer,
I would not hire Michael Cohen.
He's terrible lawyer.
What are you talking?
Just like he sucks whenever someone
gets turned out of his thing,
there are a piece of shit like I'm a row
set too high or that piece of shit like
you did. Hugh did Weirdo. Weirdo.
Very fucking crazy. Yeah. I'm
excited to see what his next move is.
I am guessing more
obliviousness more entitlement.
That'd be more mad at me.
I'm moving along.
You guys ever noticed how,
you know,
we talked about how much
we hate people that uh,
speak on speakerphone in public. Yes.
This, this guy wrote in, hey water champ.
I found another level of,
of noxious public behavior and this also
makes me crazy similar to the talking
on speakerphone.
This guy
in this video attached decided to
double park between two spaces. Ah,
half his car into the lane and
uh,
so that he could do his scratch off
tickets for this while he waited for his
party to run into the store instead of,
you know, parking like a human being. Um,
can't wait to see you. Philly Burt's do
specialists. Good. But he's still fat.
Piss on me and beat me.
I'm a hot white come hot white
trash come dump right after that.
What was it? He goes, I'm a hot white
trash. Let's fuck. Let's fuck. Yeah. Yeah.
New level of ass over here. Double
Park. Two spots of his legs. Still
waiting for his to go into
the grocery store and a,
he was just doing the scratch
offs like half parked in the spot.
There's still sitting there and the
guy just got in the car, Bro. Yeah.
Double parked in the grocery store
so no one can pull through and no one
can work in either one of these spots.
Really even go this lame right now
cause he's still like half out. Totally.
Oh my God. Parking space. So
it's total asshole.
This guy gets a bullet when he thinks
oh to two to the head for sure. This,
I'm somebody in front of us.
His family to somebody emailed this,
which is unbelievable.
It says all our mommies to take
the cake during my sister's burial,
my grandmother answered her phone as
my family was standing around the grave
site crying. This was, as you
could imagine, disturbing.
But what really upset my family
was when she loudly said,
yeah,
they're putting her in the ground now.
Love the show. Keep up the great
work. Love the Sissy of Maryland.
That is so fucking funny and terrible.
That should be a scene in a movie.
Oh my God. Answering the phone at her. Uh,
I guess granddaughters funeral.
It's crazy. It'd be like, yeah,
they're putting her in
the ground right now. God,
human beings again up, Olivia
says, shit, we're doomed.
You know, we're, uh, we've been
talking about it for the listeners. Uh,
we're coming up on 10 years of a marriage.
Oh,
I thought you meant the show.
I was like, really? Yeah.
You and I have been married for 10
years almost. We've been doing the show.
It's going to be nine years pretty
soon. I think. That's crazy. Yeah. Um,
it's amazing how we've evolved.
I know this show,
it was started out as far it's
and mentally ill people know.
Anyways, there's, you know, you're,
you're always thinking like,
what can I do to keep this
spice ally? What can I do to
keep it going? Oh boy. Um,
and then you, you, you
start thinking of, you know,
I want to do something special for the
10 year anniversary. So good for you.
So get it. It makes you happy
and excited. So I found, um,
what would be like a boy,
I guess a seminar of type so
we could go to and just see if you
like it, you'd have to check out.
I had a feeling
making sound together is one of
the natural ways to have intimacy.
Bill 82. Right? Yeah. And there's
a continuum of it where, you know,
there's a really, really casual
way, like the most casual way.
He and I were just going lab, Nah, Eh,
you know,
we're just start playing
just like vocal. Yeah.
I got intimate. Yeah.
All the way up to what Debbie does know,
teaching.
Really teaching a structure.
Yeah.
Lots and lots of schools.
There's a lot of education to be had,
so I totally love and local and from,
because you're trusting the moment.
It's whatever wants to come
out right in here right now.
Really, really believing that what
is going to come out is going to be,
I'm going to file for
divorce if you do this.
It's pretty cool.
I want to go. I'd rather blow my
brains. I rather watch Lisa Kate,
your golf all day, every raising Rasta.
Kristen. That's a cool necklace. Huh?
I'm going to get to that necklace where
you don't have to remember what's going
to happen. No, that makes a lot.
It gives me a different relationship
with the future resident.
No, it's just really tough. I just,
the world is fascinating with how many
different types of people there are.
I mean, dumb ones. Yeah.
But I also just mean,
wow,
it's good that these people
found each other as a group.
I know there's that positive spin
and then the, I mean, I hate them.
I'm saying terrible.
I just can't believe they
also exist in the same world
I live in. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You know, these are the people that
you pass and the trader Joe's. Yeah.
It's guys at Ralph's right now. It's
fucking dumb necklace. There's a way that,
you know,
there's a
chance you could start a small
conversation with this guy. Like, Hey,
is this that peanut butter
that has the uh, yeah, natural
oils. And he's like, yeah.
And then he goes, uh, he would try to
vocal Improv and you're like, what?
Like, you know, I have the group tell you
about it. Yeah, no shit. I don't know.
He's like, just give it a shot. No, I
don't. I don't think that's for me. Oh,
I think,
uh,
Whoa,
whoa.
This is the worst. This is worse.
This is worse than scanning.
Is it worse than the, I was
just thinking about that. Uh,
the boner that guys got
handloading a little more skill.
A little more like I've got a lot more
skilled and he's got the most scale of
the stain align guy saying that United
States United States stay United. Yeah.
This is, you know what,
this is, I need attention.
I need so much attention.
I'm going to inflict this to horse
shit onto another group of people.
It is that who needs so much
attention to what else it is.
I don't have a real skill or
talent, right. For music and see,
but um, you'll let me feel
like I do and this thing,
can you sing? No. You want
to act like you can say,
you know it does remind me of a,
used to have a bit where you talk about
how toddlers tell you stories. Oh yeah,
this is,
this is akin to like it
and you're like, nobody wants,
okay, that was cute. Yeah.
This is a horrible,
here's the right through their plug.
Hey guys,
you want to sing together
Bob,
this is kind of how you do it though.
Coming to a space near you or
maybe later cause I'm kinda tired.
They listen to each other. Do it. That's
the part I don't understand. I don't know.
It just reminds me of when you sign
up for an Improv comedy troupe. Yes.
100% and write it.
You know,
usually the comics like the standups
and up going like, oh tapped out. No,
you can't really do this. This
is real. Cringy no, I know.
Cause I did like a couple of
Improv and I was like, I'm out.
This is not for me Bro. This is not
funny. Like this doesn't feel good. No,
it feels wrong. Stupid. We fill out
like I'm going to be embarrassed,
but I mean they all want
attention individually.
I'm saying like how can they have the
patience to listen to everyone else's
bullshit? I Dunno. Do you have to learn
how to listen really listen or no,
you are. You can I go with that?
Can I really listen? Oh Shit.
You asshole.
Are bringing,
so we're weaving our sounds together in
the moment and it's absolutely just soul
satisfying. Oof. Embracing
that vulnerability.
There you go. It's like acting class I
don't like that I don't like long ago.
And then being able to do it with the
others is definitely coming together.
Miss of vocal in spirit,
mind and body.
That sounds like fun. Like I like
that you like his pitch. Well,
I like the idea of all that,
but that doesn't feel like
that's going to get me there.
Do you know what else would make me make
my asshole? Pucker what I drum circle.
Oh yeah. It's like similar. I've
seen those live a few times.
I've been invited to a few and I was
like, no thanks. I think I know myself.
I'm surprised you didn't go.
It's usually Spanish guys or I was a
Puerto Rican guy. That environment horse.
I know my people. I know, I
know he was, he's married,
but the big Puerto Rican guy and he
goes to other fucking married guy. Yeah.
And he goes, come over on Sunday.
We're doing our drum circle.
You're really gonna like it.
And I go, what's a drum circle?
I kind of knew them in San
Francisco and he's like, we all,
we just get high and drunk, whatever.
And you just, you just bang on the Bongo.
And I go, I don't play the,
this is the million years.
I was 24 oh boy. Now I found
out later surprise. He and his
wife were swingers.
Yeah.
So what were the drum circle would
have come out at some point? Yeah.
Just come over you inviting this coming
through other married, spic friend.
Like you're like, oh, he's Spanish
and he's married. But I mean,
I just talked to him
on Facebook sometimes.
I said, good. We all went to
college together. So a cage,
I'm telling you once every few sky
here. No, this guy's a grown man.
This was an adult person and I
was 24 this is the other guy.
We all went to college together.
I'm saying,
oh, every one to four years there's
an update about, oh, you almost,
that's being almost a lot boy.
Oh.
Or Gall FTT RTD artwork coming in.
This one's by Jake.
That's what's the carrot about.
Oh, you haven't ever seen that now.
Oh,
there he was in like Ukraine
or Bruce or something.
And the president handed them
a carrot and he was like,
thanks to getting the carrot you never
seen. That must have been like a cultural,
like in Belarus, it's a symbol
of fertility or something stupid.
He just starts eating his carrot.
It's a very popular meme.
Pretty good stuff there.
Wait,
can I,
can I give you my update on the discussion
we had about Forrest Gump in Gma?
Yeah. I really liked this. This was a
Janna.
So a couple of episodes back,
we had a discussion on
whether or not it's ethical,
uh,
to make love to a,
what do they call it? Developmentally
challenged person. Tom,
what about them? What are they called?
Developmentally challenged. I mean,
what's the PC? What am I supposed to
call him? Okay, so I don't, you know,
I don't want to ruffle feathers
by not using the right PC term.
The certainly this is not a
feather ruffling type of show.
So I would hope that you would
respect the feathers. So,
uh,
it was whether or not it's okay too,
if they're really attractive to
have sexual relations with somebody,
have to have diminished mental capacity
and we can the conclusion that no,
it was not because Forrest
Gump actually is a movie.
The whole premise is that Jenny has
sex with forests and that's really not
ethical. It's not cool. And I ended up
being one of the most beloved movies,
so Steph to death on Twitter,
at Steph to death rites to add to the
Forrest Gump slash Jenny conversation.
As much as I love the film.
If the gender roles,
we don't like talking
about gender on there,
she certainly don't resent that triggered
if the gender were reversed and it was
a guy coming back and taking advantage
of a mentally challenged girls,
it would be a much different
movie. True. That 100% movies,
that's just a porno. I also
was a red one really, um,
well-written assessment breakdown of
the film that I don't have with me.
Um, about how she was horribly
traumatized, which I didn't remember.
She was abused by her father. Yeah,
that makes sense. Yeah. She's basically,
you know, a broken person. Ah, yes she is.
And she was traveling around
as a hippie doing drugs,
trying to find her way in the world,
which gives you permission
to have sex with yes.
Developmentally disabled person and
get aids. So it's all excusable. Right.
It's almost a,
somebody else wrote in mommy jeans while
talking about Tom Starbucks experience,
only mentioned one LJ little jeans
that she waited in the truck with.
This begs the question,
did she actually give birth to a second
LJ or did she really just have a huge
dump? Oh, you guys think it's
a conspiracy that there's no,
no tiny baby around here. Want to know,
hey man, these tips are feeling it. Well,
we just didn't take the newborn out that
day. We left the newborn, uh, in a crate,
right? Tom Left it in the
crate, some water and some food,
and then now the did
the newborn was at home.
Some other FTT RTD submissions.
Forget girl troubles. Rim,
the dude's Ah, four GT
rally truck drivers. Yeah.
Fun Gun tricks.
Rallies the Democrats.
Finding God's teachings
replaces the demons.
Wait, wait. Fighting guys. And finding,
finding God's teachings.
Teachings replaces the demons.
A failing.
God's teachings replenishes the devil.
Fabulous golden tweens.
Resist their DNA for good times.
Remember to dance. Those are all of these
are, and here's the thing about f, g,
D, F, g, t RTD, is that
it's open to interpretation.
That's really the beautiful thing
about it. Yeah, that's really,
there's no one definition of it. It's
just, it's all these things. Guys.
F Gt RTB.
Pretty good. Uh, good.
What else are you got a,
I'm sorry. I was just,
those were all of those who were just
mesmerized by your thoughts. Yeah,
I kind of was so hard out. Oh,
my back hurts when he going to
give me a back massage. Hey,
speaking of our 10th band a Smurf,
Ernie, we do have to celebrate it. Yeah.
What do you want to do? Just fart
real big. Oh my God, I forgot what.
Oh Man, I totally got
distracted. This, uh,
this guy, um, was in the
news. The security guard.
Yeah,
he got fired.
Okay.
So you get the point. I love
it. Yeah. It's good to hear.
I heard he got fired. Um,
and I'm trying to see if I can
actually get them on the phone.
Do you want to see if we can,
I would love to speak to him because
this man is the people's hero. Yeah.
He was doing the Lord's work here for
us. He really is. I forgot that I, um,
said I would, let me press pause
real quick and Tri Muggle peachy.
What do you do that? Okay. I'm
just gonna do this and we are back.
And the clip you just saw of course,
um,
was from the actual footage that
was recorded by and released by one,
Paul Florida.
The security guard,
who in my opinion was unjustly fired from
his job for simply singing a different
way. Um, he just, you, you, you,
you made funny in my opinion,
just short 32nd clips of yourself at work.
Yeah.
Farting. Um, and did, did it start
out of boredom? I mean, is that,
you know, where you just like, like
when you first started doing it?
Um, so first of all, if your video
froze for me, I see that that's not,
that's not a big deal though. Um, but
yeah, I mean it just started off, uh,
just the acoustics in the hospital lobby.
Um, you know, I let one rip one day. Yeah.
I didn't want to hold it in
any longer. And uh, yeah,
the acoustics just, you know,
gave it, this is life, this volume.
And so the next time it happened, um,
I sent a video to my group chat
and they, they loved it, you know,
just some guys from home and
another guy was down here and yeah,
they love this raptor a couple of times.
They were just like,
you need to share this to the world.
Yes.
So after some brainstorming and stuff
like that and came up with, uh, uh,
Paul Flirt Moniker, you know, which was
just fantastic. And I'm a security guard.
I got the hair cut, they got the
mustache bat, you know, all the,
all the key things. And so we just,
you know, boom. Went with that.
I started posting the videos
right to the Instagram. Um,
it's been about six months. Yeah.
So in that, so you're doing that,
are you doing pretty much videos daily?
I'm guessing. I tried to do on every day.
Um, I really wish that I could
fart on command and just, you know,
have that going for me.
Or for your daily farts?
Did you have a diet and it was just, no, I
just, you know, I just, you know, I'm fat.
I eat food. I love food, like
food is my thing. I love to cook.
I love to go out and eat food and all
that. So I would just hope that, you know,
in the amalgam of crap that I
ate would produce, you know,
you know the fart factory by the way,
it was not lost on us that you had uh,
wide range
of farts,
little squeakers and big bulkers and
you had the engine revs and you mean you
really are an artist artist.
That means a lot.
Yeah. So I mean we definitely enjoyed it.
So you're doing this for a while. It's,
it's harmless fun is what it seems like.
So how like everything came in the
news like a week ago is that when the
employers took notice,
like somebody took care of it.
So this went on for like six months
without them. Any, anything with nothing.
Nobody knew, nobody saw it,
heard it. Smelts it, anything.
It was just me doing my thing until,
until it got picked up by a,
I think barstool sports on
Instagram and then, you know,
slash Sunday night and my
Instagram just blew up.
I went from 500 followers
Sunday night to 5,000, uh,
by like midnight that night. Yeah. You're
going to have some more, some more.
So, so I also watched, we haven't
played it on our show yet,
but I watched the footage of
you getting fired. Yeah. Which,
which was amazing that to see that take
place because that guy, it was funny,
like your superiors like turn that
off. You're like, I'm not filming you.
And he's like, and you actually go like,
are you firing me? And he's like, yeah.
You're like, okay, then I'll just keep
this role. What are you gonna do about it?
Yeah, we've got fire me
again. Um, now can I ask you,
is there a Mrs Flirt and your life? There
is not a missus Florida. No ma'am. Well,
maybe after this era as you
might find your nose. Yeah.
I've been getting hit up by people saying,
I don't know why,
but this is sexy as hell. They
tried to talk to me. Honestly.
That is something. Yeah. So of course
what everybody you mean, you know,
obviously,
uh,
I created a petition to have a
statue of you erected in DC. Um,
I'm hoping that tonight when I do Kona,
they let me talk about it in
the preinterview they said
yes and you can't always
dictate how those things go,
but hopefully that will get on the air.
Um, but what I guess what everyone
also wants to know is like, you know,
the, the, the simple fact of it all is you
were a guy with a job who lost his job.
What's going to happen now for you?
Are you going to pursue this
lane as this great farter?
Like what are you going to do?
Yeah,
so I'm keeping the content going
is number one for me. Yeah,
just try to keep people love it.
Why not?
Why not keep giving them what they
love regardless of anything else,
mummy or whatnot,
that content needs to keep going.
I've got the Patriot and set up,
which I'm still not 100% on how all that
works and how to use that accurately
and efficiently. A lot of people
were afraid to use patriot.
And a lot of my followers,
they never heard of it, never
saw it. It was confusing.
So they were like put up a go fund
me, put up a go fund me. But uh,
I didn't want to beg for money and I
feel like go fund me is more of like a,
just throw your money at me, you
know, whatever happens, happens.
We're patriots like on creation
based stuff. Sure. So I set it up.
People are donating. Um, so
that's something, but you know,
we're going to keep puff
weren't on vacation coming
up, so we're gonna, you know,
throw in a Hawaiian shirt, traveled
around to well known places, you know,
let them rip all over. Oh, that's a great
idea. And if you thought of a website,
maybe you have a website going,
I don't have a website.
You got locked down that URL, dude. Yeah,
man, it's probably already locked down.
Somebody, the amount of like the Internet,
you know, as you guys know is a crazy.
It is. But you have, have you checked?
You've got to go check. Yeah. It's, um,
puff fort.com is definitely taken already.
Um,
I could probably get that from
whoever owns it though, maybe.
Or just take of a variation,
you know? Yeah. You know,
the fart authority or
something. And so, uh, I'm fine.
I have to la next week to do
a TV show came to talk about,
you can't talk about it not next week.
Thursday actually. So quick, so quick.
I can't really talk about
what that is yet, but you
know, so things are in motion.
That's great.
You know,
we're trying to get shirts and all
merchant stuff like that. Just out.
That's where something,
let me tell you Paul,
we love your accessibility because there
is another fart person and we play it
on the show and he's very at
reluctant to be in the spotlight
if you've never looked up king
ass ripper. He is. Yeah. He's um,
he is your brother from another
mother man and a very impressive work,
but he's not a media savvy.
Yeah, he doesn't want it then. You're
like the people's farther. That's right.
The people is harder for white people.
Kind of a elusive,
mysterious,
just Kimbrough cause you don't
want to lose his job. I would be
so surprised if he had a job. This
guy does not seem employable. Um,
no, but we're big fans man. And um, you
know, we wish you nothing but the best.
So you know, if you get that site going,
you tell us about it, we'll plug it,
hopefully we'll get a lot more signatures
on the petition to the statue that you
deserve. And um, uh, your
patrion if people want to know,
is it just like at Paul Florida?
Slash patriotic,
everything's,
yeah.
Patriot and slash Paul Flirt calling
me slash Paul for Facebook, Instagram,
all slash ball Ford.
Great. I think, um,
I think our audience is really going to
dig you and what you're doing and um,
you know, it was a, it was a pleasure
to talk to you man. Yeah, man. Anytime.
Yeah. And keep us, keep us posted on
what you end up doing. You know, if,
if this travel thing goes or whatever,
where we'd be more than happy to,
to plug it on our show.
Excellent. Awesome. Thank you guys
so much. All right, buddy. Take care.
See you guys say, wow. What
a real talent. You know,
if anything,
your mom's house is broken.
So many talented people
I know rappers charters
about um, you know, uh,
crazy. Lokes. Yeah. Um,
then there was the guy
that likes smelling farts.
We had him on machines within a machines
within great singer. Talented rapper.
Yup. We've cream fart. That's right.
And we started his career in porn.
We hooked him up with it with porn people.
Um, we also, yeah, a
beautiful guppies. Yeah.
Try it out guys to try it out.
Guy became famous on this show.
Made you into actors. You guys doing your
own monologues, interpretations of it.
We have graced. Hi Mommy. Thanks genes.
It's a many a drive through and now
Paul Flirt and now Paul, I got to say,
I really like his person that
he wasn't, yeah, I'm above it.
He wasn't too cool. He was like, it is
what it is. I'm going to keep doing it.
I think it's great and I think he can
have a very lucrative social media career.
Yeah.
I think that this is a lane that a lot
of people like and enjoy his talent and
why not? Why not go to his patrion
and help him out? And you know why?
Why not people do it for just
being good looking right?
Like that camera Alyse kid.
Dude,
I can't tell you how many times have
ended up on an Instagram and you're like,
you've never,
you've never heard of the person's name.
And it's like 5.6 million phones for what?
Uh, they're hot, they're in a bikini,
then they're a shirtless flexing.
They have great bodies. Like, okay,
so they have great bodies. This guy has
a great talent. What about gray fighters?
Yeah. What about him? Why doesn't he does
there? And then see someone will be like,
well yeah, but I mean that hot chick,
you know, she's super hot. Like, yeah,
that's it. But that's her God
given innate talent and this is,
this guy's God given and let him run with
it. What is more American? Yeah. Yeah.
Paul flirts quest. I agree. I agree.
It's capitalism at its finest.
I think it's great. Market demands
him well, good for him. You know,
getting fired from that job might be
the best thing that ever happened to him
because now he's going to go into this
lane. That's true. Yeah. Good for her.
I like how he's like, I'm just fat and I
just eat a lot. Right. That's the best.
Uh, the make come guy has
another message. Nope. No thanks.
Hold on. Oh, I hate him so much. Huh?
Hello out there.
My Heart's good man.
Couple of things that are
really going. Yeah, sure. Let's
go. All right. Let's start.
Uh,
the television is not only on,
but it's on full volume while you record
a video message to post to share with
people that you want to listen to you.
Um, but Anderson Cooper today not right.
Yeah. It's very interesting
listening to some very liberal media.
Um, took the teeth out. It's also a
choice, but he shaped, so it's like,
what do you like,
what do you not like a framed
up real tight and starting with,
I'm tired of white women, so it's
kind of a, Oh yeah, it's a kind of a,
I'm triggered already. I mean, let's see
what you got to write this guy in email.
What I'll make it comes
going to say right here.
Hello out there with the American. I'm
kind of hot women last break. My heart.
Certainly good man.
You work hard.
Good bye everybody. Like the Bible says
apple fans. I don't think these people,
yes,
but all good.
I'm working on a beautiful woman
with a little peck, Michael.
I don't think they really are out there.
Yeah,
a beautiful woman with a little pecker
plastic and this plot really thickens,
Huh?
A beautiful woman.
I'd be all good. Me. I'm working
on a beautiful walnut, right?
Oh, maybe I'll get me a hermaphrodite.
Okay. That's what he said there.
Is that what he wants? So that's what
he's saying. There's no women left.
Maybe I'll get her magic.
Oh, maybe I'll get me, I'm
working on more for diet,
get donation. But for a little Pecker, I
don't think there really are out there.
I think he's trying to ease his way into
feeling comfortable with a transsexual,
a maybe or he's trying to be funny and
it's just maybe I still don't understand
the choice to not put your teeth in
for a video that goes on the soliciting
love.
Yeah.
Don't care about race, you know,
maybe an eight him, Roman or
to now be accident IBM black when I'm
asking taxpayers to him so that he doesn't
break your heart.
Okay,
well it's always scanning
was just laying there in bed
one time.
They weren't my bud out,
so I'm just out here looking. You
believe that coverage, God bless.
Have a good night.
Able to compose the question.
I still can't get past the decision
to not put your teeth in and maybe,
I mean it might be I'm vain.
Yeah. But even just leaving
or just around the house.
I got to tell you, I can't imagine
walking around without teeth.
It's a lot. It's a lot.
How do you get that way?
I Dunno.
Your level of not giving a fuck
is pretty high, dude. Yeah.
No teeth. No teeth is serious. And then
to be like, I'm sick of white women,
I want to demanding shit.
Yeah. Yeah. He nasty as hell.
Yeah.
Really something.
Is it true skinny women don't,
don't do anything and the black
women are like this and all that.
I have, I don't, I don't
know. This is not my world.
This is this man's interesting.
Right.
Okay. If anyone has any ideas
for our 10th anniversary. Yeah.
That was nice. Yeah. Well you're not
supposed to call them that anymore.
I don't think so. Oh, you were
saying that you stay United. Um,
it was like your favorite guy.
He is really talented. His time.
He's doing a Michael Jackson
Song. Oh, here we go.
I don't know what you want is to you,
dude.
Dude,
dude, dude, man,
I don't know what song that is.
No,
but I think those people were amused
and terrified at the same time.
People in the car, we're like,
oh cause he's fully in their car.
Like leaned in. Yeah. In his mouth.
It's all open for teeth are out and
they're like, I'm stay, you'll notice.
Stay United States, United
States. United States. Yeah.
I don't know what's song that if an,
if you guys know what that was,
please let us know. Are you sure it's
Michael Jackson? That's what it said.
I don't know. I don't know
actually. I really don't know.
I don't like them laughing
at him. No, I know.
It makes me upset cause he's my
guy. I know. Of course. Yeah.
Don't laugh at my guy like that. Like I
get that. He's funny. It's, it is for me.
I just, I feel like I'm protective of
him. Of course. That's your guy now.
He's my dude. Don't
fucking laugh at him. Dude.
What?
What can you do?
We don't serve chicken nuggets.
Fantastic.
Don't you fucking run away?
God.
Nope.
I'm going to go in front of me.
Drugs or they're on drugs to health.
Everybody's on drugs.
My father used to say,
everybody's on drugs. Everybody's fucking
stupid. That's a good drive through.
Do you know?
Did you hear about the,
I'm just going to turn
into her ultimate form. No,
the lady that was a working the drive
through that left her microphone on.
No. So when the guy pulls up, he
just hears her having a conversation.
Before I even made it to the clock and
clock and I'm here for, and I said, oh no,
I'm not.
I'm just my ass right back.
No, if I'm at clean on my
day off, I'm a clean at home.
It was hotter than a motherfucker
in your name. I'm like,
not cleaning in this.
She's got me fucked up.
I'm kicking my ass right back at that.
And you're out and you walk down. No,
I know. Great. I'll tell you when you come
back in to work, when to get this order.
So Brittany, she's a Joe. Okay.
Loaner twain. Ours. Right week after
she couldn't pay her phone bill number.
We were discussing that. No, I
just let her borrow $20 phone bill.
Girl.
I had to ask her twice for that.
Finally she gives me $10
of it, right? It's correct.
And then says, Oh hey, I got weed for
sale off. Give you a front. I'm like pit,
you can't afford to get fraud.
You owe people money.
This is so great. I would love
to hear this. I know that,
I mean this dude had the
right idea. Yeah. You know,
I remember when people started,
but with the cameras came on cell
phones and everybody was panicked. Like,
what's the world going to be like
when you can record anything?
Like the got pretty fucking
awesome. Actually. You did
the videos like this exist.
This is the greatest
thing. Yeah. I like that.
Because this guy telling you about this.
Not In the same,
yeah. I almost said to her, okay, give me
an end guy away. But then I'm like, no,
let me just see if she'll actually give
me the damn cash. You know? I don't know.
She had some low looking dude in
the car with her yesterday. Yeah.
Oh look like he's all there on the head.
Well,
I apologize for the way.
How can I help you?
Oh yeah.
Let me get your two for four one sausage,
egg mcmuffin and one bacon, egg
and cheese. Mcgriddle please.
She got fired. No, too bad. Yeah,
that sucks. It does suck sex.
How would it kept for,
on course will be better than having
that lady represent the company?
Um, earlier I was going to show you
this footage of your dad. Oh yeah. Yeah.
Let's see.
I haven't talked to him in a while.
The best methamphetamine
have anywhere in this bar.
I would have to 55 gallon drum and I would
pull a lawn chair in the middle and I
would stack Budweiser this high and I
would have to titty dancers dancing on the
tables, stripping and having a good time
and I would start drinking beer and the
mainstream would be in here ready to go
except for the aluminum and I will drink
the beer and drop one lemon cane in this
side and one in this side and continue
until the bubble started jumping out of
the camp and started tearing the skin
off of you.
Pretty good stuff. How can we
not talk to him? Um, my dad,
hi Deb participates and things I
don't want him to participate in. Like
one day I had this girl been over the
toolbox in the back of a pickup and she
was screaming more baby more, maybe
more. We passed by this buffalo,
he had a dog about this long.
Then the hand to the ground.
I screamed at him and says, Hey, I love
some help over here. She wants more.
She looked over at the buffalo. She said,
oh, I'd never leave. He had that. Awesome.
That's a good story.
Do you like him so wrong?
This is what's wrong with our country.
This guy,
I'm all getting on nap and everybody
gets within that distance, gets stabbed.
Anybody,
anybody stay away from me?
I want to die of old age and stage 89
I'm going to be chased out of the bedroom
of the 18 year old jealous husband and
I'm going to trip over fence made out of
crank into the street and get hit by a
Budweiser truck going 80 miles an hour.
That's my idea going out.
It's pretty creative actually. He's not
bad. He's thought about it. Yeah. I never,
I wasn't. I don't think that was
in the moment. I think he's like,
this is my real fantasy is jam.
Well good for him.
I'm pretty good stuff, Huh? Okay.
Would you rather French
kiss and you got a French,
that guy, God dammit or
the stay United guy. Oof.
I like to stay United so much more.
His mouth probably smells worse
than the next guy. I Dunno.
Well cause he's always got mouth
rot to. Yeah. But stay United.
He's been drinking in the sun all day.
Beer like hot beer breath.
I don't think that the math master brushes
his teeth in prison. No, of course not.
But he doesn't drink beer
all day in the hot sun.
The beer breath is really what I'm
thinking about. Yeah. And the rot.
You got to pick one state.
United Way United.
I think I'm still going to stay United
cause math guys just, he's never,
he's real nasty. He's a really nice and
he's violent, you know. Yeah. That too.
Like the math master might
be like, ah, let's do it.
And then he just fucking shank
stabbing you. Yeah. Yeah. It's true.
Somebody said they made um, a studio
g parody or something. Not Cool.
Well,
I guess it's official taking a shit really
wasn't sure about this at the start,
but a friend of mine said something
to me that made all kinds of stuff.
Think about it as a conversation between
the food and your digestive system.
I like that and has
some funding on my own.
It's turning between my ass in the sewer
I really liked that allows us into each
other's lives or in this case,
the rest of them.
What I think about the kind of shits I
want to take, want to take big shifts,
smooth shifts.
Most of the shits,
I'm going to take her just
rough shits like this.
This is just who I am,
so this is like an asshole.
I say let the conversation begin.
Wow. Bravo sir. Good
work is really good. Wow.
Just a reminder.
Yeah.
Has Anybody does that? I guess it's
official. We're now on Facebook.
I really wasn't sure
about this start then.
A friend of mine says just made
all kinds of sense. So creepy.
You should think of it more as
a conversation. Okay. All right.
I can only take so much.
Oh
damn creepy. You know, we
haven't watched that in a while.
I forgot how like creepy he is.
Let the conversation begin.
Yeah, he is so weird.
How do you feel about public kinks
and stuff? What public kinkiness.
What does that mean? Well, I know
you're talking to they'll most
normal boring person sexually.
Do you feel like, um, he's too
weird for you though, Garth. Garth.
I think he's got demons that are darker
as in anything you and I could ever
muster our imagine.
I think that guy is so fucked up inside.
He's got all kinds of
shit howling and his,
I really like that and he's fucked
up, man. Nobody Cosby fucked up.
Yeah, it's a rapist and you're
super famous. You know it's,
I think it's so unnatural. No, I
know. And this good guy persona,
that's always the kiss of death.
You know,
it's the preacher that is
preaching against gays and
then he's blowing dudes in
bathroom stalls. It's like, I'm perfect.
No, you're not cool stuff. Slick stuff.
Neat stuff.
I just don't trust anybody that doesn't
have a bad day every time. Oh yeah.
Every time. Cool stuff.
Slick stuff. Neat stuff.
Just what made you think to say that?
He's trying to be,
he's trying to be perfect. He's trying to
be awesome. He's trying to not be weird.
Yeah. He's Goddamn weird
inside. You think this is weird?
Yeah.
Okay.
Did he was eating her food?
So for people who can't see this guy was
at a stoplight and like chowing on his
wife's foot or some lady in
his car. Oh yeah. Some lady.
He's like eating it like
it's a cheeseburger. Yeah,
he's, he's chomping on.
She's on her iPhone just like, anyways,
she's recording it or I'll look at it.
Something. She might be trying to tune
out what happening to her. I mean,
I'm not against it. I'm just
saying like this. Do you need it?
Like you need it at the stoplight?
Yeah,
sure would be like to be
like, all right, we got,
we got eight seconds ready
and why is he jerking it?
Like he's stroking it like it's a hog
that's, I think his method is a little,
I've tried to see if she's on her.
I was recording it.
I don't think she's recording. No, I think
she's checking her Facebook. She's like,
oh,
fuck this.
Fucking Fred in the foot thing again
at the stoplight to stoplight is my
favorite part, and she's
like, God damn and all right.
There's just not much time headed over
to handing it to, so he's like, yeah,
he's shoving it all the way in there
and then look it up, look at it,
and he's like, I'll,
I'll, I'll Blah la blah.
She's like, Bro, what you doing?
And look at their reaction.
They're just like, yeah,
what'd you do and how?
I work van. I'm taking a shit.
Yeah. He's like the trash collector.
He's like the city. I don't know.
It's like a van. Yeah. Yeah,
Bro. Yeah. It's the best. When
someone call someone out like that,
are you done with that? Let's stop light.
I don't know how to stop, you know,
handle your business behind
closed doors, y'all. Yeah.
It's like we were talking about people
that have to fight and come out to their
family about what makes the holiday card.
I'm Pauley and I'm buying. Yeah. Yeah.
Like, hey guys, you want to know what
makes me calm? Mom, Dad, mom, dad.
I gotta tell you,
I got to tell you that what makes me come.
I got to tell you now,
I'm proud to have come out as polyamorous
and now I'm excited to share that I'm
bisexual. Why do you have
to share? Why? I don't.
Why he has to share it with his family.
I'm going to fluid bond with Jesse.
You're going to tell your
parents about it. Yeah.
Let me ruin Thanksgiving by
telling my parents I'm bisexual.
It's definitely ruining
stoplights for some people.
You know the problem is in our culture,
there's no fucking sense of shame anymore.
You know,
there's no sense of public
versus private life, man.
You know [inaudible] people
always did this crazy shit.
They just knew to keep it behind
closed doors. Man. It's true.
Now everybody's got cameras. They can
video you being a fucking jackass.
It's true. The shame is back. Well,
that's true. That's a good part.
Let's bring shame back.
I want to bring it back just a little bit.
Just a little bit. That's
a little bit. Mm hmm. Oh,
what'd you do? You do it, bro.
What you doing? It's always us.
It's always that voice that calls out,
ah,
in the car. They're like, roll the window
down, leave. They're excited to say it,
you know? Hey homie. So funny.
Like in anything else, Jean,
this is real because he's
a real kiss. No, I'm good.
I really feel deprived now.
I feel like that was a,
an especially deprived episode. This
one. Yeah. We covered so much weird shit.
It was, I love it. Toothless guys staying
alive. Guide a new jam. Farter Paul Flat,
Florida. It's pretty great. This
was a, an episode for the vault.
Like this is a good one. Yeah,
we covered it all man. Okay.
Uh,
here's a song to go out on.
It's called Tom upsetting
his mom remix by l smiths.
Perfect. I love it already as always.
Thanks for listening. Oh, quick thing.
We restocked a bunch of stuff
in the store. Shirts, socks,
hats, including, uh, we hear
you and we respond to you.
The ladies who asked for a restocked,
I believe it's tried out female sizes,
just restock those.
So if you go to the store,
you can see it.
It's merchant method.com/tom
Segura and uh, that's that.
Thanks so much guys.
We'll see you next week.
I can believe that you're,
my song
came out of my womb
and
I got to do that again.
You want to hear a different
story for a change.
I realized I to go and I
walk into the kitchen.
Christina comes out of the bathroom.
She just went Gaga and then Ellis walks
by me and he has a gun in Cypress,
so we all,
we've got going at the same time.
They went like 10 minutes later.
You can
family,
anybody wouldn't catch on.