Well. Well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Okay.
To the new dignity by Eddie Bojangles.
He's always sending in some things.
Oh, you got your new mom
glass. God forgot. Leave mine.
I like him now.
Now I'm used to him.
When you turn 40 your vision gets bad.
I need my dad's glasses. I wrapped them.
Where are your dad? They're upstairs. I
need a male. I can't read all this copy.
You got a bunch of stuff coming
up. Jane, you want to go first?
You want to do your dates? Oh yeah. Okay,
I'll show. I'll go February 2nd and third.
Charlotte Teddy's who?
Ta wiseguys comedy club tickets are
really rolling on that you guys.
So if you're going to go, go now
because listen, moms pregnant,
I ain't add and shows.
You know what I'm saying?
During going to be no Sunday night and
go Beano third show Saturday cause I'm
too fucking tired. Oh fuck
that noise. That'd be wary.
23rd Colusa Casino Calusa California one
show one night only March 30th and 31st
Portland Horrigan at the hearing
them a comedy club should be fun.
Check it out. Christina P on line
for tickets. Thank you. I love you.
That's what's up. And I'm adding some
stuff too. Well, I know it's coming.
I'm at the Ice House was
done February 2nd and third.
It's sold out. I'm in Moyne. That'd be
right at eight, nine and 10. Sold out.
Oh, I am in Lexington, Kentucky.
Comedy off Broadway. March
1st, second and third. Uh,
I just this morning
added Columbus, Ohio. Ah,
that's a wonderful place. How I'm
coming to the funny bone and Columbus,
Ohio.
March 22nd through 24th.
Um,
then I'm going to Shart Lake titties in,
um, in April. And then how lucky they're
getting. They're getting both of us.
And, uh, let's see. Uh,
Melbourne, Australia,
April 27th is sold out. Ooh, there are
a few tickets available for Sydney.
I believe Brisbane is sold out.
Perth might be as well as May 1st.
That's in Australia.
And then Spokane,
Spokane,
no cane sperm camp from can Washington.
That's in the state of Washington
here on the west coast.
I'm coming may 17,
18.
It's all very exciting.
Uh,
I go to [inaudible]
dot com slash tour Tom,
cigarette.com/tour to get your
tickets. They're moving, man.
They are core rules in thank you very
much for everybody that has a purchased a
ticket to come see me.
Do a show near you.
All right, Jean, lots of get
into, uh, let's, uh, let's
get the show started. Okay.
Ready?
Yup.
Genes getting over her sickness right
now I'm talking about the music so I can
blow my nose.
Okay.
Hi,
this is jasmine.
I'm coming team guys with a short
tutorial about how to link files.
Okay.
Don't bring anyone in loving to this.
Well,
go to your mom's house.
You've really been on a ball
tear late. Well, I mean it
kind of makes sense, right?
Tis the season kind of makes sense.
It's kind of makes sense.
Why does it make sense?
Uh,
that was an old school one. That's a
super old school man. No, no. I'm here.
The man now dog.
Possibly the lamest,
lamest line ever in a movie.
Well, yeah, if that's the word.
That's right.
That is Sean Connery.
Tell him the black kid that he's
like mentoring or something.
It's got to be a writer and it's like
that the moment of triumph where all of
his lessons have come through, you
know? And it's like montage. Yeah.
And then he did it and he's like,
you're the man now dog.
Can we stop making those movies where
white people turn around in the lives of
black kids? I would actually like to
see you ride. Really go for it. Now.
Like in today's world,
like really do one that's so on the nose
that we can all mock it and I need more
directly. There's a movie now on Netflix,
I'm itching to watch. It's on my list.
Is it that genre?
Well it's a reverse of that.
So it's the black girl teaching
the white girls how to be saucier.
Oh that's also such a blade out. So lame.
Yeah. So it's a step, you know that they,
it's like step stuff,
whatever.
And she's going to teach the
white girls how to step Ah,
was called like stepsister.
Oh,
is that kind of like a like what's
going on with the fuck? You don't know.
Stop stomping the yard. Yeah. It's a
stomp in the, uh, what they do in man,
she's just stomp on the gas stop
in the yard, but she's gonna,
she's gonna teach them how
to be more flavorful color.
And the best is that on those trailers,
they're like, stop in the yard.
They always have the
guy that can't say it.
Say why this person doing the voiceover?
So embarrassing.
It is so embarrassed.
They stopping the yard this spring.
Lace up your sneakers,
get ready to stomp a little harder.
Yeah. That's horrible. I've never seen a
step crew or whatever. Have you seen this?
But I'm confused. It's a real
thing though. Yeah. A step crew.
Oh, California. I'm just never,
have you seen a step approval for
an urban step crew?
MMM.
It's wondering if it's real
or cringeworthy stuff is like,
um, is that, is that like,
I'm going to teach you how to be from
the hood and you teach me how to hang out
with white people and like
member, that's like, first of all,
it's been done a lot already. Like
had like 10 of those movies. Right.
But then a few years ago,
Steve Martin,
who's pretty highly regarded
and respected in comedy,
like he's kind of for a lot of people
on the Mount Rushmore of, you know,
comedic minds. Yes. He did one of those
with Queen Latifa. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
I saw that one in the,
in the trailer.
He ends up in like a bboy pose
and he was like, what's up?
What's happening girl? And he's
like, and she doesn't think like now,
now you get it. Yeah, that's right.
And then he's like, Yo, Yo Yo,
I mean you go like
this fucking turd cracker who's like,
I can see blacks dance. I get it. Sure.
Cultural differences or
funny. Oh my God. I mean,
I mean in the 70s and the 80s that
was kind of a new thing, you know,
like Ed was it Eddie Murphy
doing a Beverly hills cop
and he then he had a white,
yeah, yeah, buddy cops that,
that was funny and I was a little less
on the tailpipe, that whole thing.
It was pretty funny to make fun of white
people is always funny. That's true.
But like, I dunno the way
that was done, like there's,
there's nuance to jokes,
you know what I mean?
Like that's the only thing you have
to make the characters people, right?
Not just staring, just
characters, you know.
So that's the thing is that
that was done really like,
you believe that white guy was that white
guy and Eddie Murphy was kinda being
himself and Eddie Murphy had
all the carts. He actually,
he had the power because he was the
funny guy. Yeah. Genuinely funny too.
They weren't like,
and then just smack these crackers around.
But I do love those step cruise man.
You know,
I watched bringing on every item that's
cheerlead. You know what you would love.
I love the clovers.
I can watch those clovers take a shit on.
Or you should even just youtube this
historically black university marching
bands. Oh, they are so amazing.
I'm talking like Grambling, you know, uh,
what does it McNeese state like I'm
talking to southern Hellman, uh,
Hellman. Isn't that where cast weekends
went? Oh, that's where different.
Where like Morehouse,
I'm telling you that historically black
universities that have marching bands
will blow your mind. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. I, we got to go watch some,
I'm saying the whole presentation from
the uniforms cause it's always like crisp,
clean.
I mean it's like a military style uniforms
and the coordination of the movements
and the music it and like it's,
well what about the blackness Tom?
It's super black. That's what I'm saying
now there they're already there. Yeah.
And then like sewing,
like usually every one of those
performances we'll begin with like a black
person go
and then you're like,
that means like pay attention
and then they'll like,
they'll do a snap and then
the show will start. Yeah,
it's called right. Be Some
clovers and the APP. Anyways,
I don't know how we got on sidetracked on
this. Um, are we talking about Oh yeah,
yeah, yeah. You, uh, well you've had
aids and you're getting out of that.
I, this is like the only
time you guys don't know.
But like I live with aids and have,
for years I've been fighting it.
I take my meds and I always had a sinus
infection and cold the fucking flu.
And like for years I'm
sitting here living with you.
And I would go through these horrible
sicknesses that would last five, seven,
10 days. And you'd be like,
to me like, yeah, no, I don't
know, but I didn't get it.
And then the next year I get sick
four times. And you'd be like, yeah,
I didn't get sick this year.
And then the next year I get six,
six times and you'd be fine. You
know why? It's my Goddamn cockroach.
Cockroach. Cause my eastern
bloc genetics, I can,
I've survived the communism.
I've survived World War Two
because my genetics are superior.
My immune system is superior
to the average American.
I don't doubt it. Now the problem
is I'm pregnant and so I've got,
my immune system is lowered
from pregnancy. So it just
took me down. I'd never,
I have a laid in bed sick,
but a decade.
When's the last time you
ever see me laid out?
But the good news is I got into
this Korean soap opera and Netflix.
Uh,
I think it's a poor translation of
the title or just lazy translation.
They do that. They do that both
ways. Yeah. Why be so, like,
why not really try to think,
excuse me about the title.
I know there they'll do things like,
I dunno,
there'll be like a, what's a
big action movie here? You know,
it'd be like some like taken.
Yeah.
But like in, um, uh,
in Korea when they release it there,
they'll,
they'll call it like he's had enough,
you know, like they give it like these,
because words don't have the same impact.
What's this Korean show called? Well,
it's shittily translated to,
hello my twenties,
and I was looking for some light bullshit.
I'm so fascinated by Korean culture
because when I was in Seoul like 10 years
ago, I would watch their TV and I wish
I can understand what these people were
talking about because it's so
dramatic and they're so beautiful.
They're such beautiful people
and always frustrated me.
And I finally have access now
at subtitled and I'm hooked.
I'm halfway through it
and it's a dark show.
It's actually very dark and
very complicated. And very cool.
God, I would give anything for this to
stop right now. Oh, he telling me, Oh,
it's the worst. I hate. It's annoying.
Yeah. People don't want to hear it.
Nobody wants to stop it. Thanks. Now
you are also into my Tele Novella.
My abuelita watches her tele
novella before bed. I got, I mean,
I blame Diaz and I'll
tell you, I, you know,
anything did Joey Diaz tells you you're
like, yeah, okay buddy. Like you know,
you're out of your mind, right.
He um, he was telling me when I,
when I saw him last,
he was like, you know,
we're talking about different shows and
how much I love narcos. And he was like,
Oh, you have to watch
the show hot, the hotter.
And so what is Ho to hoe to me,
Jj,
so the letters in Spanish. So I'm
like, what, what is he talking about?
So just out of curiosity,
a few weeks ago, I, uh,
I pull up this show. I see it, I think,
I don't know if it was like a new
release that time. It's called Soco.
UBN though Escobar alias with the hotel.
Which means surviving Escobar.
So I'm like, and I've been on
this Escobar, um, you know,
rabbit hole as have a lot because every,
every time I pull up Netflix there's
like a new show about them. So yeah.
Cause I pull up your profile and it's
like Escobar, Escobar, murder, murder,
drugs, murder. Yeah. It's the whole
thing. And they have a new series,
a new series just came out about,
uh, uh, drug, uh, you know,
cartels and more documentary style though.
So anyways,
I pulled up his show and it's a
Colombian show. It's a series.
I pull it up, I watched the first
episode, I get roped in and it's about,
um, Escobar's righthand
man has hit man Popeye.
That was the is the guy's nickname I
love on gangsters. Have cool names,
pop by baby name.
Kinda think papa.
He personally killed like 300 people.
That's it. So he's a mass murderer.
He's free now, by the way. He's of
course he did his time. So weird.
Like we get,
so in this country you associate your
experiences like certain crimes aligned
with certain punishment and then like
you start going around the world.
It's like sometimes in countries
like look, this guy murdered a guy,
he did his five years though
and like he's like all right,
the value of life is significantly
changes diminished is he?
Where is it Columbia, he's Colombian
and give a fuck about life there.
But the series is so good
because it basically picks
up at the end like the last
day or two that is alive and he and Pop
I part ways Escobar tells him he's his
right hand hit hitman. Like I know this
is coming to an end and they say no,
just the feds are close. Yeah,
yeah. The search bloc is, is, is,
is closing in and all his guys
are dying and it, it's just not,
he knows it's so he tells
Popeye like go ahead.
Like you're,
you've been invaluable to me and
basically go for it and cause Popeye's.
Like I'm going to turn myself
in. Like, I know that I'm either,
I'm going to be killed,
they're going to keep searching for me,
so I'm just going to go,
go for it.
So he turns himself in and the series
starts with him basically arriving in
prison. God Damn, now I have
to watch this thing. Yeah,
but here's the mini episodes behind you
then becomes the most unbelievable story
of him turning himself into
a crime boss from prison.
Of course the dramas in this
prison of the different cause.
There's like the paramilitaries
and there's the gorillas
and there's the narcos
and they each are unsafe, separate
sides. And they each have, you know,
different storylines of
trying to get each other.
And then there's romance and there's
relationship anyways. You know,
sometimes when you start
a series on Netflix,
he started watching it and you're like
six, seven in and sometimes you're like,
Ooh, like how many do we have left? Like
we were watching Ozark. You're like,
how many are left because you want it to
be longer and you'll check and there's
nine let's say, or a 10 and then relief
washes over you. He's a relief. No,
there's enough. Yeah. Or
like, or you go like, Oh shit,
that sucks that this is about to end.
So I'm like, episode seven of this show.
I'm like, this is good. I
wonder how many are left?
I back out of more episodes.
60 what are you fucking talking about?
How many seasons today?
It's considered one season.
It's just the way that they have
have it uploaded on Netflix.
I th I think what happened is this is a,
an original,
like a Colombian series and that's
what I think. I didn't, I didn't,
so I think it aired there over
however long and then they bought it,
licensed it for whatever reason,
they just call it one season.
So it's 60 I'm,
I'm 32 episodes.
I'm wondering how long have,
well,
Lisa is going to be watching her shows
because every night I sleep and I'm going
to get super depressed because I know
that if it's 60 that's the series,
you know, it's 60 episodes. It's
not like they're gonna be like,
next season we'll have 60 more episodes.
It's gotta be the, you're done. Yeah.
But I'm super into admin and I wake up
every now and then and I look and there's
the ugliest motherfuckers
on that show too. Shit.
This fucker's on TV. Yeah. Uh, yeah. Well,
it's exciting.
You know,
the problem with my Korean show is
these bitches are always eating this
delicious Korean food.
I cannot believe you on this.
She's watching this Korean show and
then every day it's Soondubu Bulgogi
eating all this shit for days. And I'm
like, are you serious? She was like, well,
I was watching it. So because they have
good food, they have the real stuff.
Yeah. The Kimchi and the, the
noodle soup. Oh, I love it all.
Kalbi I see them eating and then
I want to eat the same shit.
Fuck. Speaking of Netflix,
uh, the reviews are in.
Yeah. Yeah. And disgraceful.
Yeah. Hundred percent.
Everybody loves it. You're
kidding. Well, congratulations.
That's really hard when
everybody's on board.
I've never had something
where it's only love.
Unanimous. It's unanimous fans.
Yeah. It's pretty exciting. Well,
I'm so glad to hear that. Yeah. I've never
had anything like it where everybody,
everybody likes it. Everybody.
There's not one person left out.
Well that's wonderful. That's kind
of the goal of a good comedy show,
I think it sure is. Well,
listen, if you're a comedian,
you gotta be able to entertain
everybody at all times.
You don't want to upset
people or a polarized or fed.
Let make anybody feel bad that
this guy's show. I mean, my show,
that's what I usually begin
my shows by going like,
I hope each and every one of you has a
great time and I hope each and every one
of you leaves here feeling
good about everything. Yeah.
That's kind of how I do it.
You know? I was thinking today,
are there any topics that
nobody can take offense to?
Like even think so,
but let's say
going into our five o'clock hour,
it's going to be a lively conversation.
I expect we are going to
be talking about Tom Seger.
Huh? That's a radio show. Yeah,
he is a standup comedian and
on a recent Netflix a show,
he did some jokes and he did some stand
up about specifically here in Lafayette,
Louisiana as a whole, any Cajuns.
And so it's pretty Bulger.
He has some vulgarity in there, but you
don't stand up comedy. It's vulgar. Uh,
and there's been a lot of
people watching this video.
A lot of comments about it.
A lot of people very angry,
very offended, very upset because
he really goes after Cajun.
I never thought this would be a thing
really like of all the topics you cover,
isn't it surprising the
ones that kind of catch
dude, I'm beat. I did. By the
way. I heard somebody talk about,
um,
I think it was on the show.
I got sent the link that like this
guy was on there being like, oh yeah.
Um,
I know,
I know that he's talking about a specific
guy he met in Louisiana. I'm like,
what? Like I met a guy in Louisiana. No,
I met a guy from Louisiana
in Kansas City in the first,
like during the first
week of 2017 last year.
If you were in Kansas City and you
came to one of those shows? I did. I'm,
there was a guy in the meet and greet.
No. Okay. And that's what I say. I mean,
I don't say Kansas City in a special,
but I say like I was on my first week
of this tour is where I met this guy.
Yeah. I just thought it was weird that
some, somebody like he met a guy here.
I'm like, that wasn't even,
why would that even register?
I'd be there anyways. Um,
uh, I think it's funny,
like the backlash of like people
from Louisiana being like,
I mean, first of all, I have to say,
I've never gotten so much fan mail in my
life ever for anything like a half for
this special. Like I've been
bombarded with this, you know,
just amazing fandom and,
and support and people telling me that
they love the special, which I tell you,
it never gets old. Like I totally, I,
I can't tell you how much it's
crazy how much it has come in. Um,
and I've gotten a lot
of it from Louisiana,
so I don't want to make this sound like
only people from Louisiana are upset
because a lot of them are like, I live
in Louisiana. I love the bit, you know,
like they, they've been very
supportive of it, but people,
the ones who don't get it or
who don't like it, it's like,
you know, this is a joke,
right? No, it's not a Joe.
I feel like there's so many people
out there that are, I dunno,
they,
I think they're taking,
it's like they're holding people on like
what they're saying on stage as equal
to what you would say offstage. But
you know, that's the same thing, right?
Well, I think there's a thing
called context, right? Yeah.
So if you're going to a comedy show
and you're all agreeing in this social
contract, then what we're going
to have in the room is called fun.
And it's not meant to be taken
literally or seriously in context.
It's called a joke, I believe, unless
you were giving a lecture on, you know,
geography or one of my
favorite parts of it.
This is, these guys are going to
discuss this thing for like a while.
But then this is one of
the comments I have to say,
uh,
when I heard it the first
time I was a little oh wow.
Man, that's pretty, that's pretty
rough. Yeah. But it is funny.
It is funny.
It is funny material.
It's just that we are the,
the target of that.com.
Oh, okay. So a lot of
people don't like that.
Yeah. I mean that's,
that's how jokes work out.
Well,
you know,
every joke has a victim and I feel
like you can get upset. You know,
you tell jokes about cats in
the cat. People get mad. Yeah.
Told you about the dog dog.
People get mad.
Just so you know, a couple things
I'd like to point out a, um,
the joke, did I tell that it's, you know,
has Cajuns in it basically ends with
my saying that we should build a wall.
Uh, if it's around the state
of Louisiana, um, and, uh,
we have a build a wall shirt.
It's build a wall shirt and um,
the wall is in the shape of Louisiana.
Very nice.
That is item number one. You can
go to the store. I'm offended.
Um, they're using bricks
then that wall. Yeah,
my cousin was a brick.
And here is the other piece of news
that I'm super excited to announce.
I didn't say it at the beginning of
the show, but I'd like to say it now.
[inaudible]
to show you how much love I
have for the state of Louisiana.
I took the very first available date
going to the civic theatre
in New Orleans Saturday,
September 29th. Oh, uh, the,
the tickets are on presale today,
the 24th of,
um,
of January,
beginning at 10:00 AM is
when the presale starts. Um,
so you can get tickets to that.
There is a code word if you're,
if you're participating in the
presale and the code word is Cajun.
See a j u n perfect
Cajun is the code word.
If you want to get tickets. Again,
I'm coming to New Orleans Saturday,
September 29th.
It was the first available Saturday
at the civic theater this year for us.
So it should be very interesting show.
I'm very excited to be going.
I just wanted to let you guys
know that. Um, and again,
I can't thank you guys enough for watching
this special. I really appreciate it.
And I know that, um, you know, it's,
I've been getting a lot of back and
forth how it's always, how this works.
These things trigger other things.
People watched the special and then
they have watching your special,
cause I keep getting messages
about your special really.
I've been getting so many complimentary
texts from our friends and family and
Twitter messages about how fantastic yours
is. So I'm, I'm really happy and, uh, I,
I just, I wish you would just tell
jokes it didn't hurt people's feelings.
I know. Can we make a list of approved
subject matter? Well, yeah. I mean,
can we do a consensus of, of
what's a okay. O'Hare talking
about it's a bull here.
I don't want to hurt feelings
anymore. Um, grapes. Grapes.
That's good. Remember yesterday
we had, there was grapes in that,
like the lunch for a Lj.
Yeah. Who would say, oh no,
no one will take offense to that. I don't
think so. Right. Yeah. Fruits. Let's see.
What about wine makers?
Uh,
there are probably going to get upset
about cause you stopped grapes. Yeah.
Oh that's true.
That's hurtful to the grapes were not
taking grapes feelings into consideration.
That's true.
Whether that doesn't seem to agitate
people. Hm. What if you live in a
bad weather area? Then you're like,
why are you boasting about how good your
weather is as what I always hear from
people that live in shitty places.
When I tell them I live in
California and they're like,
I fucking hate Los Angeles. And
I'm like, but the weather's great.
And they're like, so I live in this
shitty place and we have shitty weather,
but I like it more. You know
what I mean? Like it kind of,
I feel like it gets people in a
bad mood. Now I'm going to, I,
you know what I'm gonna
do for your next special,
I'm just to help you here is I'm going
to start making a list of preapproved
topics that everybody
can get onboard with.
I liked that a lot and that
way people don't ever get
mad. Yeah. All right. I know.
I know from experience
that cyclists get very mad,
I think. I think you're right. I remember
that was one of the first times, um,
you'd ever received hatred.
Significant amounts is,
it's so funny cause you really can't
predict what will set people off. No,
you really don't because let's be honest,
we both have said pretty inflammatory
shit about lots of other people and both
of our specials and yeah,
it's always surprising.
It's always surprising when you're like,
you know there's a comedy show, right?
I Dunno actually.
I feel like most people do understand
that most to what happens is the people
that are upset are very vocal.
So yeah, they're so angry.
They're so emotional that they like the
person that loves your show usually will
message you. I love the
show. They don't then, right.
Like eight more messages to better,
you know.
Well and I also think that people
have always been offended and upset,
but now because of social media,
they are given a platform to kind
of Bob together mentality. Yeah.
And it's just, it takes on a bit of a
life more so than it could 10 years ago,
20 years.
When you have a mob,
they'll also like not actually,
uh,
watch the thing or they're not reacting,
reacting to a,
like a story that they heard about.
I heard that you talked about, yeah.
You're like,
you're not even paying it.
You're not even going to give it
its due diligence. Yeah, no. Yeah.
They just feel it. I've heard enough.
I got, I got messages like, you know,
I don't need a watch it, I've
heard enough about it. Okay.
People got mental problems. He
got it. You got to get your life.
Get your ass in a therapy. Let's talk
about something. Don't worry about it.
Oh yeah.
What do you think of that? Well,
that's kind of a good message.
It's kind of what the self
help movement is all about.
If you're going to give a blow job
and you're not cool with yourself,
you'd feel probably really depressed.
As you're doing that.
How are you going to love that come
if you can't love your own comp lit.
That's way more than I was
thinking. What's up? What's,
what's even the ball's lately. You
seem to be on a ball thing. I mean,
I just opened the folder here.
Oh, it's blue bands on a ball.
The ball's right.
Send it to him.
He's to get in his balls attached and
licked and stuff. Yeah, maybe he is.
Yeah.
Bird balls.
That's true.
Yeah.
I don't know how people
have indiscriminate sex or
licking indiscriminate Coxson
balls.
Like a lot of people do that.
Like a lot of girls will opt
to give a blow job. Oh, you
have to be like, I don't,
I don't give it up on the first day.
That's a good one.
That's one of my parents is like,
Hey,
I'm not easy and you're just
going to get in my pants.
I was sucking on your balls though
because to me that's way more intimate.
I know intercourse. Like I've heard this,
what are you doing?
I've heard this from you and other people
that graduated college that, uh, that,
that's a pretty intimate thing to do.
So yeah,
put your mouse on someone's genitals
is, is, I mean, that's their everything,
you know.
Thanks.
You
give us a demonstration. Who
she fucking 12. We know this.
Here's the thing. Who's saying bite my
ball? Nobody. Here's the thing. You know,
bite fucking balls, man. Sniff, sniff.
Let me put it right.
Bat your eyelashes and no one buys.
No one says bite my balls. But this is so
fucking seventh grade. Of course it is.
We covered this shit in junior high
brow. Like, you know what I'm saying?
Like welcome to this podcast.
Are you talking about,
I'm saying that girls have been talking
to each other about this shit since like
seventh or eighth grade.
So like bitch,
you're too old to be
like making these videos.
You can fucking cover
this and junior high,
the finger banging and you know,
maybe she's,
maybe she's just like really good
at this and people keep their jam.
Like maybe like how about every
guy she hooks up with is like,
you gotta make a youtube tutorial
because he's so good. I need,
I need other girls to find out about
how good you are at this. Again,
she can just be like, remember the
grapefruit lady? Uh Oh yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Got It. Great for
your man. Stupid show Dick.
Between your legs out Dick,
between your legs and stomp the yard.
Want to take
them shot here.
I'm just focused on for today.
Oh, ah. It's actually an
ad for her to get laid.
Yeah. She's welcoming
customers. Her inbox when,
when this, you know what I mean? Like if
you're, if you're putting that out there,
this is what,
this is one thing that I'm annoyed by
as somebody that is not participating in
the back and forth of a meeting,
people online.
This is somebody who will put out a
video like this and then their next post
will be like,
do I have to say that I don't want your
sexually suggestive messages in my inbox
and you're like,
you put out a ball so I can post a video
of me sucking on some borrowed like
cherries, like balls and how to be
about me. It's my form of expression.
Look like you want to suck dude's balls.
They're soliciting Balsa.
They want to get their balls sucked.
You're putting in by now
too many jewelries,
too many bracelets and shit.
You know it's not too weird.
I mean
that's the everybody is,
this is what I mean,
but I feel like everybody
knows how to do that.
Like isn't that kind of intuitive?
She's not really giving me any new skills.
Not Everybody knows how to do that.
There's people out there that
are definitely washing like,
but if you were to suck balls,
isn't that fairly?
I think she's introducing of
that to people. In other words,
there's ladies out there
who are watching that like,
I don't really fuck with
bowels, you know? No,
I mean going around the world and
that really kind of, you know,
yeah. You know, there's not, there's
not everyone's a triple d slot wife.
Hey, we've, how about fun?
Is it to call slots, slots?
Man,
we've been doing this for a long,
this is a fun way and you
got to do it by the way,
don't be like the fun is to do
it with your, with your friend.
Don't be a jerk and do it loud.
But it's for now it's in the car
windows up. It's just the two of you.
And like a girl walks across the street,
maybe a jogger or just like a normal
girl in jeans and assured the more normal
or like the more professional,
the less uh,
promiscuous or sexual her
attire and look is the better.
So when you see a like a pant suit,
just executive woman with a
briefcase crossing the street,
you just go in your car,
you go as a slot right here.
Total Lily Slutsky sluts
walking into work right now.
I also like to do it, um, to
like, like young teenage girls.
I only say that because I can kind
of get away with it. They're not,
they're not slides by any stretch,
but it's funny to be like look of
sluts over there walking sluts.
I Dunno why it makes me laugh when we
do it all the time. We laugh too. Yeah.
Get some inappropriate or if they're like,
if they are dressed super slutty,
then it's funny too if it's on the line
or if it's just like a nice looking,
but it's like when they're like,
if also if it's like two 80 year old
women and their slots Taylor sluts,
that makes me laugh for me
when they're like older,
but like when we're in a restaurant
and like couple like girls walk in and
you're like, oh, it's a couple slots
are going to go have dinner right now.
That makes me laugh. Well you like it when
I say it. Yeah, yeah. Yeah. It's more,
it's funnier when a woman says it.
It's one of those things
where it's like the origin,
the source of the line makes it
funnier. Yeah. Contacts. Tom,
you know, one of those things, I'm
just learning about this like context.
Um,
I'm learning about like how reading the
words isn't the same as like hearing and
seeing somebody say, oh yeah, it's all
these lessons. It's so fun. I mean,
I didn't know that like a
certain expression can be
said satirically ironically
sarcastically.
And that then changes sort of the intent
and the meaning all of this stuff is,
I'm going to comedy camp right now
and I'm learning so much. So yes,
I do.
I do appreciate that.
I like to do a Mac when
we are in the brown stuff.
You'd done it in awhile. Whenever we see
a pregnant lady, you know, it'd be like,
what's wrong with her belly? She so fat.
That always made me laugh too. Oh yeah.
One time I posted the uh,
a lady on TV who was like seven
months pregnant and I wrote like, hey,
how come maybe next time don't have like
four beers in 1870 [inaudible] before
you did television. And all these
people were like, she's pregnant,
she's so pregnant. You
know, she had a small frame.
It was so clear that she's pregnant.
One of my favorites,
another one of my favorite games to
play in the car is there's your dad.
What's your dad doing? What's your
dad doing? Is another good one.
Any guy eating out of like a trashcan
and he guy with like, you know,
six shopping cars, shit fallen
off of it. He's barefoot,
he's white, but his skin is turned
black from walking on the pavement.
Black soils.
Tell me Your Dad was here
once your dad doing here is my dad is a
super mean joke because I mean he can't
hear it and neither can anybody else,
but it's not cool. It's not okay.
It's not funny.
That's not funny cause someone's
feelings could get hurt theoretically.
Like if he was in the car with us that
we were like, Hey, are you my dad?
And he was like, what? Why does milk
and ham not taste good together?
And we're like, what? Get out
of here right near radically.
We were having a conversation with, um,
a mother yesterday who were acquaintances
with over the phone and uh,
and she was talking about a nanny.
She had with our son and and something.
She says something like,
you know, I don't teach my children
to point and laugh at strangers
and both of us, Tom and I looked at each
other. We're like, yeah, no, no. Wait,
what are you talking about? Yeah.
How many? One on one people.
That's what you're supposed to do and
it's how you get a sense of humor.
Definitely. She was like, you know,
we don't teach them to look and laugh
at somebody for their appearance
called funny. I don't understand. What
do you teach them? Yeah, isn't it?
Like, what do you say when you see
someone if you don't point and laugh.
All right, what's the point of life
now? Our kid yesterday, not like,
I don't like,
you know somebody like pointing out like
at the thrill of seeing a Porsche and I
was like, Oh really? Yeah, one of those,
aren't they awesome? I thought they
were. I liked stuff. Hello stuff.
The problem with being a comedian and
a mom is that I laugh at a lot of this
shit that our kids doing right now
and I should be disciplining him.
Yesterday we caught him,
he got into my red lipstick,
like my stage lipstick,
like the shit that I wear for 10 hours
state like it's really saturated color.
Yeah, just dark as red, red
fuck all over his hands.
And of course ware on our white ass wall.
Some for like 30 seconds cause
he's at the age now where like,
you know you could be in this room and
you hear him dragging like an Amazon box
through the halls and you're like, all
right, that's what he's doing his thing.
And then it was quiet for like 10 seconds
and then you're like kid over here and
I'm like, come on, you have to see this.
He was smacking the wall and he was like,
do you want me to get the
other wall now? And I'm like,
Oh yeah, smack, smack, smack.
Just so happy.
And of course we start, I start laughing
and then he's laughing like, Oh God,
this is cool.
I guess I'll keep doing the other walls.
So then he starts to take
off to go the other way.
I scrubbed the shit out of that though.
We got it out.
But that's a good woman balls.
We got an email.
Always eat the scrum. Hold
on. Mommy's just an Fyi.
You can't spell
scrumptious without strong,
therefore the scrumptious scrumptious and
there was no reason to be afraid of it.
Just think of it as a delicacy.
Slow cooked in the cock pot all day long.
I marinated in all the feral pheromones.
Pheromones.
You fell in love with Alexandra. Wow.
That's a lady who I think is probably
Tom. Don't slut shame her. I
know, I know. It's a lot. Oh,
there was like women marching this week
and they know it's a lot of slides.
Marching, right name. It
was like a slippery. Yeah.
Um, I don't know. Hey
Hitler on a recent podcast,
Christine mentioned meeting,
I forgot my different,
so for every part of the body I have
one bottle of shampoo that I use for
everything. Why can't I wash my
balls with shampoo and beat me?
Kind regards Johnny, because
somebody beat me. Uh,
first of all, Johnny, I'm
100% on board with you.
That shampoo is soap and you don't need,
so if you have shampoo,
you can watch every part
of your body with shampoo.
All you need is suds. Uh,
it's not different. Nasty.
I've survived for years before I
met you with just a shampoo bottle,
shampoo suds up. Do you do your hair?
Do your beard, you do your underarms,
you do your, your butthole, you do your
crotch. I mean, it does it all. I mean,
I bet technically you're right because
the detergent is a detergent or soap is a
self. However, I think it's
more of a text textual thing.
Is that the word I'm looking
for? Texture, all text, texture.
You know what I'm saying?
It doesn't feel good and I don't think
you should put soap and I mean a shampoo
in your vagina because women,
we have to,
we have to wash,
not up inside of our Vaginas,
but you got to get in there and
I'm thinking that it might burn.
It might hurt my badge.
So that's kind of like a utility thing,
you know? That's true. Um,
like a mint shampoo probably wouldn't
be good down there. Uh, another,
are you still doing that by the way?
Shampooing was not. We have soap,
so I'll split it up.
Yeah.
As long as the thing with you
is you'll adapt to whatever,
whatever's there anyway.
I swear if I,
if it was fucking 409, I
would claim myself with that.
It's just whatever's there.
So adaptable. Yeah. Uh,
an email. Hi, Mommy's,
I've been thinking about this theory since
I was the brown master of my house in
middle school.
It seems more and more clear to me that
my body gets certainly a weekly brown
cycle here. Me Out. So I'm
currently a college student.
In the past semester I decided
to try out my theory every day.
I would pick up precise time
varying each day of the week,
whether I felt I needed to or not
to make some chocolate soft serve.
Sometimes it would be
difficult to hold it in,
in some shits for a few hours
after taking 10 to 12 Benadryl.
But after one or two weeks,
my body seemed to have regulated
to what I now call the fecal cycle.
I have now been able to find tune this
weekly cycle to a time that fits my needs.
So is he saying he can dictate the
Times that he, that he wants to go.
You can train, you can
train your, your asshole.
It's absolutely tribe done it with when
I used to work a nine to five so he's as
good as anybody to do that. Congrats
on little jeans. Two Point Oh yeah,
try it out. Piss on me. It'd be nice. Um,
yeah, I mean I feel, I guess I know
that, I don't know that I dictate it,
but I do feel like it happens,
it happens at a regular time and then
would always fucks me up is you know,
travel or schedule,
but he's saying you can retrain your
duties so that you're like for instance,
let's say you start a new job and you
want to take a dump before you go to the
office, but you're, you've
been unemployed for a month,
so now you're taking your dumps at like
10:00 AM you can retrain your bowels
such that you're shitting at 7:00
AM versus 10:00 AM. But I mean the,
the training involves but also
just intense training. Well,
the training involves also changing your
probably your sleep cycle because if
you're getting up, if you're shitting
at 10:00 AM every day and you're like,
I want to be shooting at 8:00 AM,
you can't get up at 8:00 AM and do that,
you know, you're going to have
to like six or something. I mean,
you have to make some change.
You got to wake up. I, you know,
if anyone out there listening is
having and struggling with this issue,
we both Brown,
I would say you brown quicker and
earlier than I do every morning.
You're like up and you're like,
I got to shit. Well, yeah,
I mean we go downstairs but within 30
minutes you're 45 you're definitely like,
as my body is trained, even just the
smell of coffee can induce. That's true.
I happens to Brown, but I, I usually
shit about an hour after you,
I'm telling people I'm trying to get
valuable life tomorrow. Tell him,
tell him if you want to train your dumps,
I recommend you wake up two hours earlier,
drink your coffee.
Like for those of you who aren't
drinking a high powered coffee and then
complaining that you can't,
shit, we'll get your life, man.
You gotta drink high octane
coffee. I mean, daddy jeans here. I
greatly appreciate my French press that
you got me. Yeah. Tell me a review.
How do you feel about it? I
love it. I love it. I love it.
I was intimidated by French Press. Can
I tell you how fucking not smart. I am.
Well,
I didn't know and didn't think to
research making my first pot of the French
Press. Yeah, he went on intuition. Yeah.
I looked at it like, oh, this is obvious.
Yeah.
So I put all the grinds at the top on
top of the press part and then like press
out there and I was like,
that makes sense. Or like, no,
it was like between the, uh,
you know, there's like a screen
and a and a Ma, whatever.
I put it in the wrong place.
The first day I made it,
I still drank the cup and I was like,
was pretty good. Then I was like,
I should probably just, it's amazing
with Youtube, you just type anything in.
I type in the actual brand
that you got me and make it.
And then like in two minutes I'm like,
oh, I was doing it completely wrong.
Yeah.
But now I make this brown
lightning and I drink, uh,
like basically one of those crafts.
I got a moderate sized one.
It's not like a crazy size,
but it's uh, it's delicious.
And I love the process.
I love the ritual of getting those
beans out in the morning, grinding them,
uh, finding out, you know,
what size grind you're supposed to go
to for a French press and you know,
even the ritual of you're supposed to
stir with a plastic spoon because a metal
spoon can crack and scratch the glass. I
did not, I mean, all these little things,
I'm like, I feel like I'm a
Barista when I'm doing it. Yeah.
That's the whole point. And then,
you know, you're waiting for that,
the coffee to steep and I don't know,
I love trying these different
coffee be like what I missed.
We were doing the pods, you
know, they're very convenient,
but I missed that ritual and I miss the
smell of the beans and grinding it up.
So now I'm buying coffee beans
again and I love it. I love it.
Originally I was so opposed
to the Nespresso machine.
But you're hooked on it.
Well, because that's what
I'm saying. But I loved,
I missed the PORTA filter and locking it
in and putting the grinds in there nice
and fresh. You know, I miss
that stuff too. Cause that's,
that's a real cup of coffee. Oh
yeah. Whatever's, you know. No,
I don't have to fucking time for
it. I got a kid crying. Yeah.
Cooking another one in my belly.
And no time to fuck around making
coffee gets your life, man.
I know it's time for that shit.
Do you know what I'm saying?
I know there's, um,
let's see, there's email,
there's looking at the different
emails that came in, uh,
the infinity wipe no. Solved. Yeah.
Tell me how mommies, I've struggled
with the infinity wipe all my life.
Every once in a while life eaten.
Some Moose suit might be whole.
Behaves like a dirty bitch.
Heres the high and tight solution.
Once you've identified that the
cleanup is likely to go into infinity,
simply flex your pooper as if you
were trying to squeeze out a little
dingleberry and proceed
to wipe when you're,
how you say asshole is in the slightly
flexed position at hand with toilet
paper, toilet paper can reach
the hidden Brown and Hitler's,
your life will be changed forever.
Try it out.
Nick from Boston,
he's saying if you push push out,
basically you're pushing and
you wipe that you will get the,
the remnants that are
causing the anesthetic and he's saying
flex that whole push push and then when
it's fully flexed, reach
back there. Yeah, oof.
I don't know the problem with my be whole,
it's still got it's tender or from
like hemorrhoids from pregnancies.
You know what I mean? Like I don't like
to get in there. I don't like that.
I like the water of the day.
You do. That's what helps. Yeah.
Or the shower. If you
don't have a day. Sure.
You can get a fucking Badass on
Amazon for like 50 bucks though.
Guys are 40 bucks a tushy so great.
You got to get one dude's.
It's really great. You know,
I know everyone loves a
squatty potty. I tried it.
It's okay. I personally,
I think a day is way more.
Get one, try it out banner. It's
really, it really is the whole,
the best thing ever. Um,
it's like a fire hose.
The tissue one is 60 bucks or
something. Yeah, maybe that's right.
I mean cheaper ones and you just hook
it up to your toilets. Super simple.
And then now your whole life
is transformed. You're not,
I think it's so gross now to mash
toilet paper against shit on your skin.
It's so fucking gnarly. I
know. I go, I got a minute. I,
I finished browning now and
I just let water run courts.
Oh my God. I've been telling
everybody about this shit.
Do you ever have a poop where you sit
down and you're like, that was it.
And you're like, there's not going
to be anything to talk about.
Like I'm going to just go be,
I'd be disappointed.
And then I looked in the bowl and you
think it's going to be a rabbit pellets or
something that was so fast?
Like nothing came out of me though.
That happened to me their day I sat down
and after Korean soup and I was like
whatever. And I looked down and
it was the most gigantic brown.
I pro like a one top 10 of my life.
And why does that happen?
Like sometimes you think it's not going
to be brown and then the real big one.
Well why did I come out so fast?
Like it was so big.
Love how you asked like
a little kid would ask
you asked exactly the way it
kindergarten or when I was like,
how come I didn't think it
was kind of be anything.
There was a lot of chocolate in there.
But you what? I'm, but you have that too.
Of course we are like,
it doesn't feel like much.
But then I looked in the
bowls are amazing, but what
is that? The mystery poops.
Those are mysteries. Yeah.
Then there's the ghost.
Shit totally disappears.
No, I consider it go shit.
When you shit and you wipe and nothing's
on the, how is that even possible?
And you look, you're like there's a big
shit in there and you're like, wait,
is there shit somewhere else on my body?
Like you reach around, you're like, no,
she's on the cheeks. There's no how
is there no shit. It feels like you,
like you won a lottery. It doesn't
it feel special or the best day.
I think part of that too,
I think you can prompt that a little bit.
Somebody told me he's was,
if you spread your cheeks before you sit,
so everything really goes apart.
But I still,
I think God could fall on, you know,
that's counterintuitive honestly.
Because if the hole is bigger,
you're not pinching it off.
So that to me would
create an infinity wipe.
A scenario actually. Yeah, I disagree.
You want it pinched? Well, interesting.
So many different theories, you know?
Um, let's see. The world is a
mysterious place on a United flight.
They just suggested the seatbelt be low.
And tight.
This goes against all my beliefs.
Should we start a campaign to educate?
I'll love no hate. F all the haters,
Nick. No, I'm offended. Yeah.
I want to be high inside is the
only way to live your life. I mean,
low and tight. So terrible.
Now. It doesn't feel good.
No, it feels a little tight.
God, air travel is the worst
in this country. Yeah. It's
so demeaning. It really is.
It really is the worst experience.
I was watching this show.
No, the new one I'm watching, I
forget the fucking, this is us. Yeah.
There's a surprisingly good show.
So good for a network show. And um,
there's a character on there who's
battling with her weight and she's,
I don't know like what she weighs,
but she's really large and she gets on
an airplane and the woman next to her
totally eyeballing her and she's
like, don't worry. I bought two seats.
And then the, you know, the flight
attendant comes by and he's like,
I got your seatbelt extender. Like totally
loud. She's like, thanks. I got it.
Like I'm already fucking embarrassed
enough. Yeah. And then she's like,
I know how to do it. You know, like, and
I just felt so if you feel so bad for her,
cause you're like, ah, like
you did the right thing,
you bought two seats that you're
not like ruining anyone else's day.
But it just seems,
I just feel so badly for those people.
The seatbelt extend nerves and everything.
Yeah. I mean terrible being fat.
I imagine it's hard cause
that's your addiction, you know.
But everyone gets to see
what your addiction is.
I know it was so hard on
a flight actually with um,
Bert.
Yeah.
And the flight attendant to
like a discreet seatbelt extent.
Like they to him, to him, they gave
it to him. Yeah. And he was like, hey.
And then she came back, she was
like, you did anything? He was like,
fuck of sort of like, Gosh. Yeah.
But it was the thing I've seen them,
I've seen it done discreetly,
which is nice to do it that way.
Like they do it kind of like, like walking
by like the dropping something off,
you know, like not make a scene
of it. Yeah. Don't be a dick.
Okay. I mean, they're embarrassed
enough, I'm sure. Yeah.
It's terrible to have to buy two
seats on a plane. She's, yeah. What?
Bernd does it all the time. Yeah, he
does. Or he just flies first class.
Isn't that why?
Because the seats are beggar.
[inaudible] do I does it?
Yeah. A little bit of room.
He barely wedges into
those seats. I know. Hmm.
Drank in the whole time. I Super
Fat. So another email here.
Um, this is one for you.
What do you think of this?
Why don't you read that out loud? I
can't. Okay. Hi, Mommy's congrats jeans.
My aunt and I have gotten into heated
discussions about what pre prenatal
prenatal vitamins due
to your nose picking.
She thinks that because the vitamins
make your nails grow so long hinders your
ability to pick.
I completely disagree and used my claws
as shovels to grab that shit up from,
from up in my brain. My
question is obviously for
Christina, queen of personality,
do use your prego
clause to your advantage
or do you cut them?
These are the thoughts I have after my
husband has left for work and I'm picking
my nose waiting for my coffee.
Thanks. Mommy's love you Sarah.
Well, Sarah, I have to tell you, you're
right that your nails. Do you know that
like those crazy people that
we play videos. So you have to,
I like them short. I think it's disgusting
personally to have long nails. Well,
think about how somebody with long
nails feels hearing that right now.
I mean, seriously even see I
prefer long or short nails.
You say those people are
disgusting. I mean, it's disgusting.
Not The people. It doesn't matter. Do
you think that they, I mean I got to,
you got to think about everybody's
feelings all the time. No,
I find it unhygienic cause I personally
get a lot of people with poor hygiene
feel when I make fun of it. Yeah, man,
that's not okay because somebody beat me.
Oh, the trauma. Oh, so sad. So,
uh, anyways, to answer your question,
I keep them shorter because actually I
found that nose picking is enhanced with
a shorter nail.
You're going to do more damage with a
longer nail and you're also going to
introduce more bacteria in your
nose, which is how you get sick. Now,
apropos our discussion earlier,
how I avoid sickness.
I'm a compulsive hand washer. I washed
the backs of my hands like a surgeon.
I sing happy birthday. Happy Birthday Song
three times as I wash. That's the rule.
I do not pick my nose if I know there's
sickness in the house. This is truth.
I will use a Kleenex instead
because that's how you get cold.
This you pick your nose, you,
you rub your eyes, he put it,
you put your fingers in your
mouth. True Story. All right?
Don't touch your fucking face.
That's how you're not,
that's how you avoid sickness can,
you're not a nose picker like me.
You're a thumb picker. I've seen
you. You do this. You do this. Yeah.
You pull out a scrawny honor roll
and then you flick off the bat,
but sometimes I dig with the
index finger to I'm seldom seen.
I've seen you do with a pancake.
Thank you. I'll do it too.
He used to roll your boogers in my car
and I flipped the on the floor. Yeah.
Thanks for doing that.
It's really cool. Click,
click was so nasty, man. I'm
into picking my son's nose.
It's a fun game, kind of the
best thing. And he's like, he'll,
he'll raise it. Hey, let's you, and
then he doesn't know what you're doing.
So whenever you're doing man,
whatever,
it's just as gratifying to pick your
son's nose as it is to pick your own.
I had no idea.
It's one of the joys of parenthood now.
I don't like picking your nose
though. I think it's disgusting. Yeah.
Um, but our son, I love
it. You remember last week,
I think it
was last week,
there was a,
there's this big news story
that dear leader Trump,
um,
so supposedly in a meeting referred
to African countries and Haiti as shit
countries said like,
why are we getting all these people from
these shithole countries when we could
be at one? I prefer to get people
from Norway. I mean, oh boy.
You tell me if there's any subtext.
But, um, yeah, so obviously,
and then, you know, he came
out, said, I never said that.
And then people confirm that
he said that. And then, uh,
I think Republicans that were in the
meeting said they couldn't recall what he
said. Either way. Uh, there was a,
this came in that some big words were
said on CNN by somebody who was trying to
make a point about Oh,
offended.
He was by hearing the president say,
or the alleged comment that he said that
there's people from Chicago never takes
responsibility. Nothing ever
happened. Never his fault.
Well, Mommy, get the,
your reaction to what the president said
about these brands to want to come to
the United States from
countries like Haiti and Africa,
because I'm going to give you a reaction
if it's personal. I'm a proud shit hole.
My family was called Watson macro leaders.
We came from the Italians and Irish who
were regarded as people from shithole
countries. Oh, a century ago.
We call people slamming eyes,
Chinese immigrants that were now ashamed
of speaking about it in those terms
because they came from a shit hole country
and now they're our backbone of this
country.
In the 1940s we call people traders
because they came from a shingle country.
We call Japan and we're ashamed.
We call people who fled from conflict
and set full America spics and what backs
and we're ashamed
growing this country on the backbone of
bigotry that comes from when I saw my
family called Styx waps and macro leaders.
We should be ashamed, man. We've learned
too many lessons and history will.
Okay. What's a macro eater? Macro eaters.
Is he talking about
like macaroni macaroni,
Saudi saying Matt girl like the fish.
I Dunno,
I've never heard that one before.
You learn something new on this show
every week. Just like macro you dog can't.
Yeah,
Mackerel.
It was a oh a macro what?
Linked off the fish, right?
It wasn't a sectarian slur
for Roman Catholics. Oh right.
Cause they eat fish on Fridays or,
oh, that's funny. That's hilarious.
What about Hungary? I'm fine. I'm a shit
hole country. Yeah. About Eastern Europe.
I know what other slurs, but
Slovakia or, or you know,
whenever Ukraine,
Russia or we all shit hole my
anti anti sing Hungarian sediment.
Oh, let's see. Uh, it's
called Hungaria Phobia.
Anti Hungarian ism is
dislike, distrust, racism,
xenophobia directed
against the Hungarians.
It sounds like it could involve
hatred, grievance, distrust,
blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Do to Hungarian background.
I'm trying to see if there's any, uh,
yeah, no. Um,
Hongos I don't see any like list of
slurries and patriots in English.
Oh, a Bolo, honk, honk.
And he's a combination of
Bohemian and Hungarian. Cool.
And hunky derived from both hunk.
It's in the movie 16 candles.
It is long duck Dong says oily,
honk.
The Dad calls her fiance about
hunk. Hmm. Let me see if there's a,
yeah, so it was hunk here. Yeah. No. So
He's hung out. No, but I'm saying that's,
that's one of the, it's like the
slur. Oh, cool. You are a SPEC,
right? Pretty much through
and through. I mean, you're a,
you're a Christine, the bow hunk.
I think that's pretty accurate.
Yeah. I got called Polak a lot
growing up. Did you that makes sense.
So it's more common. Uh, yeah.
This here spic as defined here is
just a person of Hispanic descent.
Um,
theories include no speak English and
that's where SPEC comes from. Oh No,
SPEC speak English.
But as it believes that it's the
abbreviation of Hispanic and other ones.
Interesting. So, all right,
let's speak English. I no spic.
I no speak English.
Everybody says like that though every a
Taco head cause a Mexican person never
heard Taco this as that's from born on
the 4th of July. And that's where it was.
It's not real.
It's kind of a made up one.
Spics pretty good pics.
Pics big or spaghetti.
It sounds so mean though. SPEC
SPEC sounds harsh. Greaser,
isn't that a Greaser
greaser full metal jacket.
The see grease ball. But that's
an, that's an Italian, right?
I guess you could also have
Italian grease ball usually.
So what they say right? Tele in Greece.
Are you fucking me? Guinea grease ball.
Yeah. Yeah. Then that guy goes on, uh,
uh, Don Lemon, same guy. And he,
he puts these conversations that
this is economics. So let's be clear.
Phillip mud from Norway can come here,
but a black dude from Haiti can't.
What does that tell you in an America
that one in one generation called you a
nigger. What does that tell you?
Dot. Whoa. Big words. Very big words,
but he's just throwing,
throwing all of them out there.
I didn't know you were going to
go straight to that. Holy Shit.
I've got to kind of big words.
It's very fired
up this to tell you that. What?
That tells a honky like me,
we're no different than we were a
generation ago and we're learning the same
lessons that we learned when we
call the Chinese man a slanted I,
when we called the man from Guatemala
spic and a wetback call a black man in the
Sam Hill. I think he likes to run through
his knowledge of that. Yeah. He's like,
I got good one guys.
Gimme a gimme a country gimme a gimme one.
That is kind of a real gift he's got,
that's what it tells me.
We got a ways to learn,
but we can step back and say we're proud
because I spoke this on CNN 30 to one
the emails I got were saying,
you speak for us and we are not from
Africa and we're not from Norway were from
Italy, were from Ireland. Okay.
Wow. Well, are any Haitian,
speaking of all the Chinese man
a slammed I, oh my God. God.
When we call the man from Guatemala
spic and a wetback. Holy Cow.
I got Ya. That's such a
beautiful region of the world.
I don't think Trumpers has been
to a t I t Dominican Republic.
That is a beautiful region. Conan.
He went down there to do his show,
you know that. Oh, very nice. When the
earthquake happened or this last week. Oh,
he did. Oh, just to show
show Trump. I mean, yeah,
he just like did a few shows from down
there and that's wonderful. It's awesome.
It's like the most beautiful,
they're so nice.
It's really like the sweetest culture too.
Like to be diminishing of them.
To me it's like what Saba
it. Yeah. You're so sweet.
Conan. Um, ginger boy Brian. Yes. Uh,
I'm going back on a show that will
be a on there. If you're listening,
I'll be there Thursday, the 25th.
That's excite. So, um, please watch.
Please enjoy, uh, we talking to
Mr Conan O'brien. He's wonderful.
You went over there to him today.
Oh,
not him produce it today.
I forgot about that. Um,
yeah,
you went on there when our son was first
born and then I went on again last year.
Oh, right, right, right. I
forgot about that one. Yeah,
very excited. He's a nice dude.
He's the nicest and so's Andy.
They're very, very nice people.
They're so funny together and they're
great. They're really nice people. Um,
check this out. Check it out,
check it out. Try it out.
So there's a new wrapper
on the scene. Oh, okay.
I'm from Australia.
I love Australia.
And here's the thing,
is it a shit hole country that is not,
it's definitely not a shit
hole country. Um, no, and,
and our president will be glad to
accept them as Australians. Why is that?
I don't know. It's weird.
Um, anyways, this rapper
might have a cease and
desist headed his way. Oh,
because guess what he's
using as his m c name,
his artistic name? No, he is going by
top dog.
No,
stop stopping. I won't stop.
I make it pop. I'm make it
drop by. Hey, make it stuff.
This is top dog.
He,
he listen what you're bad to
hear cause I'm back for good.
And you might even Hollywood,
he needs a fan of the show. Must be
no. Must Be. It's not impossible.
I mean, you heard those was presales or
good for Australia. That's interesting.
This guy just out there
using the top dog's name.
I like his rap some flows though. So far
the words of rhymed. Yeah. That's not bad.
Cilla black to Umaine.
That's six feet tall.
I'm at wall.
Yeah.
Am and I don't care what
anyone says cause top dog is,
he said bring it cause suck.
Can you guess what I'm fixated on?
Just knowing me for 12 years
to married to a technique,
the way that he goes from the duck is
cadence kind of set himself up for the
next line. No, no. Uh, facial hair.
Um, just knowing me,
wait, let me, hold on,
let me watch a little more
and I'll see if I can come
really hard to watch. Not a snitch, man.
Joe Beach. But baby, you know what I mean?
I'm the craziest man you'll ever see.
Yeah. Wow. That's um,
yeah, it's pretty good.
It's pretty good. It's hard to,
it's in case you haven't guessed it.
The teeth, you're rich. It's hard for us.
I think you're a snitch
man. Joe Beach. But baby,
you're not crazy
walking down the street, walking down the
street, walking down the streets. Yeah.
See I think our machines where they
guy just has a little more passion.
I Dunno, this guy seems pretty
passionate. I just, I'm,
this guy's got more technical ability but
our guys like I just feel it more for,
I think again, you know what he's missing
is just a great producer as always.
Can we get Jimmy Ivan [inaudible]
as I wasn't even on the phone. Yeah.
Oh let's go get, let's go
down to Malibu. Find Him.
Could be and get him to produce this guy.
Cause I am
fucking one day.
Definitely one day.
Slay the AK. Yeah, this
is my day. Get those days.
Well, he definitely, I mean, he definitely
wrapped a lot. He raps. I mean, it's good.
Again, it's so distracting the mouth.
I can't, I can't get past the team.
There we go.
Rocking shoes was
walking down the street,
walking down the street.
She had the worst day.
Yeah. Yeah. That's good. So that
top, what were you fixated on?
I got it. Teeth? Yeah. Oh,
I didn't think about that.
They're really bad. Uh, I mean, yeah,
but that could be part of the
hook of the like, you know,
just be called Dj bad
mouth. Right. Dj Dad Mail.
That was great.
That's really good.
We should suggest that. Yeah.
I mean, that was terrible.
Let's see. Here's the thing,
if you embrace it, it's
like you embrace, so yeah.
What's The lady? She has kind of
crooked teeth. Which one? Uh, she's the,
you know,
talking about jewel. Jewel.
Oh yeah. Snaggletooth yeah.
So there was a time years ago when
she was going to fix her teeth.
Oh yeah, no, no. And her fan
base flipped out. No Way.
Like Barbara Streisand's knows. Everyone
told her get a nose job. She was like,
no fucking way. And that people love it.
Just like me with my quadruple d tits,
super slut, 15 d tits. Yeah. I
really, the more pregnant I become,
I've, the more I feel like dog, the
bounty hunters wife. It's not a good luck.
I just feel like I look great. You look
great. But you know what I mean? The,
the bigger they get, the bigger I
get. Yeah. You got a big Ole knockers,
you're going to feed a whole bunch of
babies with those titties. Yeah. Yeah.
You got, there you go. Oh my
God. We were watching dark. Aw,
Jesus. Cry. I can't watch missing kids.
Do you? Okay. So if you haven't seen dark,
it's on Netflix, Dork,
Dork. It's Dork sided,
but it became, it's kind of been this
international, you know, sensation.
But I've heard a lot of people talking
about it. One thing I'm fascinated by,
I've never seen this on Netflix or
really you don't see it that often. Uh,
if you are watching programming at all
in the United States when a foreign show
has dubbed as opposed to subtitles.
It's rare,
but I have a theory on this.
My theory is this, well,
because they have a lot of
subtitled stuff. Yeah, like Netflix.
It's not uncommon to see subtitles.
I think my guests and I,
I wanna,
I wanna research and find out if this
is true that they dubbed as opposed to
subtitle because through
their own research found
that Americans didn't want to
listen to German.
It's a beautiful English.
I think that's what I really didn't dairy,
I'm offended.
I studied German and college is a
beautiful other because why would they?
Because there's a bunch of
shows with house in high school.
Like why would they do that
if that's not the case?
Why is narcos all in
Spanish and subtitled?
I don't know. I mean, my guess
is narcos a biggest show as Dork.
You want those? Is it
bigger than Dork? Oh yeah.
I don't know, Dude. I mean it's
fucking great. I don't like it.
It always reminds me of those KCLA morning
movies where they used to play Pippi
Longstocking and then they dug her shit
over and I don't like going to lips not
moving.
I don't like watching things not match up.
I admit that or follow you
ended up being lost. I mean,
but there's so many Latin, I mean so
many Latin people in the u s yeah,
maybe we're just more used
to hearing set on the same.
And I feel like Americans for
the most part are like what?
Or maybe they found that people were
clicking off the show because it was
subtitled and they're like,
no, this is such a good show.
We need people to be watching.
Actually the first time we tried watching
Dork at the subtitle feature wasn't
working. Really? Yeah.
We tried watching it twice and they
just weren't coming up like it wasn't
working at all. And it was all in
Houston. It was all inspections. The yeah.
Yeah.
He should be nine Belinda shots.
Shites well it's a bond.
You know, he really bad.
Why don't we just wrap it up? Oh yeah,
try it out. Try it out. Piss on me,
beat me because one of us
beat us. Try it out. Uh,
thanks as always for listening to the
show. Thanks for watching on Youtube.
[inaudible] tubes.
We have some great guests
coming up in the next few weeks.
Your emails are always appreciated.
The email address is your
mom's podcast@gmail.com.
There's no house in that image.
Your mom's podcast. I'm Christina.
You gotta tell us next week
about this, uh, show you did
good though. Someone said this to me on
Twitter and I've heard it before night,
apparently looked like the girlfriend
in super girl and that felt out.
It really does. I was like, oh my God.
Did something for her mouth and her eyes.
Yeah.
She's this expression similar face.
Plenty,
but she's missing something else.
No tits.
I do love that Gal Godot. Yeah, she's
sweet. You got to see wonder woman.
It's so good. Yeah.
This girl's got hungry.
Agreed to feed them.
Take a spoon.
All right. We gotta get going.
Thank you for listening.
Calm Christina p online.
Uh,
is that it? Is that all we're doing? Uh,
here's dog can't buy brass. Uh, we'll
see you next week. We've got some,
we got a good one for you
next week. All right. Love you
vague.