Well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Yeah, we're rolling. Did you
like my song? Yeah, it was great.
I'll say it for them would
be nice if I had matches.
This episode is so loaded. You have no
idea. I can't wait. That's so great.
Our hotline. So many good things. We got
an Ali [inaudible], that's his new name.
He made a new song. Um, so many new.
Hi Mommy. Thanks Jean. Submission.
It's kind of money. Thanks jeans. Uh,
there's just a lot. There's a lot in here.
So, uh, would you like to get started?
Yeah. All right. Let me, uh,
respect my pronouns. This bag, my
guys, I'm nonbinary. Of course you
are. Hmm. Pauley. And I'm buying.
Yeah.
About to take your fucking Dick back
inside me while I've still got remains.
If you're calm and then expect
me to fucking suck it off,
my swatches think finish up.
Let me do to come run.
Let me have a shower. You jump in the
shower. Fuck me in the shower. Okay.
Each other in the shower.
Don't bring in one. Loving to this rope.
Go to your mom's house. Tone. Circle,
Christina.
Personality.
Lot of people,
a lot,
lot of people weigh in on the
personality of Apple. It's not,
it's not really a battle when we know
that if there's one clear winner,
obviously, oh my God, I bet
you overwhelmingly people
voted for me. Uh, yeah,
that's not how it went,
but my mom comes up,
thumbs up. Good. That's
what my mother used to say.
That comes out good for
you. Made no sense. Uh,
that'd be embarrassing. Right. It was
always embarrassing. So embarrassing.
You know, I was realizing I
was out. I took the dogs out.
Yeah. I realize, you know,
I'm your mom and the fucking
stands that plays. Yeah.
I realized that I have
entire speech memorized in my
head. Do you know that word?
Personal verbatim. Why? Why did you just
think, what? Did you rehearse it? No,
when you were laying the dogs out,
they do think about the, the speech.
It just in my a moment off the glasses.
I can't even look at you serious
personality, but stop it. Uh,
for a moment.
I was just was thinking about it because
if you have the playoffs are going on
right now. Yeah. I was thinking
about football and I was like, um,
his speech. Yeah. I used
to be so obsessed with it.
Did I have it memorized? Coach ice?
Yeah, I see e you want to hear it?
Not e y e s is Dom Zap.
Good.
40 here's a, this is, I think
this is a verbatim. Okay,
let's do it as personal. Personal
right here, man. You and my house,
my face disrespecting me.
I got no,
not doing it with feeling. Oh No.
I'm telling you I have it memorized,
but do it with feeling. I don't
want to now you're ruining the fun,
but that, but that's because you're not
having fun because you're not averse.
Now any champion a personality champ
would do it with feeling. Now I don't,
I don't want to perform it and saying,
okay, well then do it from memory.
You're in my house.
It got the remote control
and your personality ruins
moments of of a good time.
I was actually like really wanting to
do something and then your personality
entered.
You still can do it,
but like you see how you put
like the brakes on the phone,
but I tried to make it more funner. It's
good grammar. Just do it. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Do it
again. I'm sorry. Take two.
Go ahead coach ice speech.
Take two. Alright. Right.
Personal personal right here, Bro.
You and my face math disrespect to me.
I got to do something about
it. My family right there, bro.
I gotta protect my Momma. My
Momma sitting in the stands, man.
Your parents sitting right there.
Then your house man,
your mom and the fucker stands.
Chai disrespect being grabbed.
The fucking grabbed the fucking remote
control. That's exactly what they did.
They come into your house.
Derek was control your motherfucking TV
in your motherfucking house. T diddy.
They came riding our house, put on the
same shit you got on and said fuck you.
Wow. That's the whole speech. Wow. I
mean that's from like seven years ago.
Oh Wow. I don't listen to it
regularly. No. In my head.
Do you think that you have a photogenic
memory? I think so. Thank you.
Saying your ag. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. That's
a healthy thing. It's a good thing.
And when you memorize important stuff
like the coach I speech versus like Martin
Luther King's speech, I know I could
have memorized that. Yeah, you are.
Anything else or this chick speech
here come run speech. Let's see.
I hate when you get mad at me.
Are you over it now? I'm not even.
There's nothing to be over. It just
makes me so upset when you get mad at me.
Not Mad at you. You're so angry. Cause
your personality so sour all the time.
Okay. Hold on. If I, if I nail
this. You did. I feel it down.
Correct
based my house this than me.
I've got to do something about it.
My family right there. Whoa.
I got to protect my mom.
My mom was sitting in the
stands. Man, your person wait.
There it is.
Remote control have exactly what they did.
The remote control
the TV.
Fuck
you.
That's pretty close. You know, I never
ever missed a fuck or an extra here.
I think it was very good.
I think you got it very either
have the beginning of it. Yeah,
they, that it was edited where they
didn't have the beginning of it.
That's why it's so,
no,
I don't understand.
When he says wearing the same
shit you got on and said Fuck you,
what does that have to do with anything?
He's implying that they put on
pads in a uniform like you did.
Oh,
you know,
this whole time I just thought it meant
like that guy shops at the same place
you do fuck him. Like it just
like he was style psyching me.
Like you went to the Grammy's
or whatever in the same outfit,
put on what you put on shoulder, show up,
all that stuff. Yeah. And then they said,
fuck you. What are you going
to do about it? Interesting.
It's probably the greatest pregame speech
I've ever heard in my life. Yeah. Yeah.
My coach never said Shit like that.
One time my coach told us a story
about these neighborhood boys. Yeah.
That were fucking with his,
one of his brothers.
And that his dad told my coach at
the time, who was a, a young man,
that they,
that him and his brother should go
over there and kicked the kid's ass.
That was his pregame speech.
He got real emotion. And then,
so that was to motivate you to go
kick their ass, the other teams? Yeah,
it was, um, but I'd never seen them get so
emotional. It was interesting. I really,
really liked it, but I would
have liked this much more.
Yeah. Yeah. I would have to,
I prefer Cochise is my coach.
I mean,
if I was 15 or 16 and
I heard that speech a,
I'm either hysterically
laughing and biting my own
tongue to not get murdered by
him. Yeah. Or I'm so scared
shitless of him that, you know,
we're ready to go out there.
See, I think you and I grew up a vastly
different in that I heard inappropriate
things yelled constantly so that,
that was my norm.
Yeah.
Um,
I don't know. I don't, I remember
one time Diante the, I had the,
the driving instructor, Mr
Cou, I shouldn't say his name.
He was actually the PE teacher and he
taught his driver's Ed and he would tell
us about the bikers and the
street. Yeah. These, uh,
faggots on their bicycles were
in their faggy bike shorts.
You don't want to fucking hit
these guys cause then you get sued.
Mr [inaudible] laugh or
no, no, cause back. No,
my friend Shauna and I did cause we were
like that's a rad and this guy when we
laugh or like, yeah, no Sean,
I are both like this guy's the best.
I'm going to come every weekend.
Cause it was like the funniest thing
here. A Guy Freak, Alec that you know, um,
no one else. No, I think there's a,
it was all girls school you went to.
So it was all girls in the class
and there weren't like fun.
They don't have the personalities that
I have the personality and I have this
girl's got personnel. It's
something she's got neat, uh,
tats till. Yeah. So she
did this on Facebook.
Um, that's, this is what it comes.
She calls it a come run, which is uh,
you know,
basically running to the bathroom after
sex after I got Jesus in you. Yeah,
I've done that before.
Did you always call it a come run?
Never had had a name for it.
Well the common wrong,
unless you used a condom and let's face it
then you get to experience the km run
past to be the biggest sexual struggle.
Wow. What is it? No one talks about it.
Like this is the big dilemma of,
of our era of this age of living and
come run and no one talks about it cause
it's not that big of a deal. I Dunno. I
Dunno also who the fuck? Where's condoms?
Oh No, I think it's more
the alias queers. Um,
a few people where he talks about
the camera and is your sister Maria?
Yeah,
I remember one time just like Jeff and
od come pouring out of me for like days.
She always has talked like that and
has always been so descriptive and it's
always upsetting.
Cause like I know when I got pregnant
because like Jeff and I had sex like four
days before I've deleted and then like
the Campbell's dripping out. Oh my God,
you guys are so disgusting.
It's really foul and I wish you
didn't talk like that. I mean, yeah,
the camera is not fun, but it's
not the biggest sexual, oh my God.
Seriously. I honestly, and I don't have
it so I don't know, but I feel like,
but sex would be the the most
embarrassing slash well let's,
why don't we dive a little deeper into
this topic that's being ignored by the
masses,
I suppose. That fucking tissue. Yeah.
What the fuck is that going to to
a tissue and fucking stick tonight.
It's going to help me for my shy pepper.
Masha Masha,
she sold down there. I mean they're
Downton Abbey cast wipe up their come.
They never, they never did, but she's
right. They never explored that.
It's like this big elephant in the
room that no one's talking about.
We come run down now.
Be have been a perfect series.
There's calm all over my legs right now.
Which sort of limit lady.
My lady allow me to lap it up.
Carson was a com lapper cheers.
Run right into my mouth.
Carson would do that for the
family. Yeah. He loved lady.
Is that come dripping from Carson?
Uh Oh. Where did that go? Why did that,
anyway,
I have mastered the comradery,
but this is what I
personally do is coming over.
So you need to prep the room for two
towels next to easy access. One for you.
One for the bed. Yeah. Designing.
No fucking white patch.
Smart. So far so good. I'm also
a big tower fan. Yeah, I know.
I like towels. You don't like him?
No, you're the first gentleman.
Well let's be real. I so many
guys talk about, no, let's,
let's be real.
It wasn't always a towel with you.
It was shirts for awhile.
Socks.
He got a stiff Dick.
You'd like handmade.
You hand me like wet,
like not wet white tee shirts and stuff.
And I'm like David towl Tom. Yeah.
And then I think I got into towels.
Oh man, I got towels. I like
towels. I liked how it was too.
But then you're saying I evolved into
towels. It didn't start at towels.
That's fair.
Between the legs, legs crossed. Oh,
never got sort of hot and
wobble to the bathroom.
[inaudible]
do you set on that toilet for
interesting.
This chick's asking all the important
question she saying how long do you wait
for that just spill out?
Well,
I mean as long as it takes well
but, but no, but think about it.
When do you say that's it?
You give a good push,
you know, push and then after
that, you know, so that it's
a legit question though.
Yeah.
Cause you could sit there and then maybe
a few minutes later a little more falls
out. Yeah, I get that ges out. Yeah.
I'm so glad she shared this on Facebook
and on the internets and a lot of family
members of hers probably up Facebook too.
This is a good thing to have
you fucking hear. So would you sat by
you scraped? What? You can wait, wait,
come still coming out. Oh my God. Master
vaccines. What the fuck did she just say?
Nine Times out of 10,
nine times
five scraped what you can out.
I'm still coming out. Yeah,
we scraped, but you can stand up. Come
still coming out of you. Sure, sure.
It's nice. Maybe. Maybe granny saw this
video. That'd be nice for her to see too.
Right?
How far are you scraped? What
you can out? I'm still out. Yeah,
come so come here.
Yeah, I, she's scraping.
I wouldn't scrape my badge for that.
Geeze,
you're little that come stay up
there though. You know, I don't know.
Oh,
dude's sound like they're shitting,
uh,
of then go get in the shower because
there is no lie. I'm with him.
Come inside and they call me [inaudible].
Yeah. What, what's she talking about?
Going to the bathrooms.
Look at the next thing I'm
doing is getting in the
shower cause I'm not going to
get back in bed with calm. All
these come inside of me. Yeah. Okay.
So she was a nice shower fan.
Yeah. Back in the bedroom that
coming in, get your likes open.
Don't really want to fuck you and
you father. He's not let that bad.
You ain't going to
change yourself yet mate.
And I'm know I'll come
multiple times over that penis.
Hm.
Interesting point.
So what she's saying is she gets out of
the bathroom back into bed with some of
these dudes. They're like, listen, let's
give it another go. And she's like,
you're still, you're still
nasty. You have a clean up. I've,
I've come on you. Why don't you clean up?
I'm cleaning up. Why don't you clean up?
Sure. You know, equal
rights, equal rights.
I respect the lady for
making that very valid point.
And I also know you're a batter.
Dip Your fucking Dick back inside me.
Am I still got remains?
If you're calm and then expect
me to fucking suck it off my,
so I'll just finish up. Let me do
to come run. Let me have a shower.
You jump in the shower. Fuck me in the
shower. Cleaning each other in the shower.
Done.
Wow. This chick's got it all figured
out. Yeah, I really, I really like her.
I admire her too. I like the, uh,
amount of energy and the
thought she's put into this,
the time it takes to make a video.
Also the,
I realize that within this video she
brought up an issue and it came to a
resolution. Interesting. She solved
the dilemma. She offered a solution,
a constructive solution. Just guts. Go to
the shower then we can do it all there.
When I met around when you saw him,
did you do to come on.
It never seems to get any less.
It is a sense of fucking embarrassment.
Comey fuck him a about with a fucking
towel would turn your legs in fucking Paul
move. You started. Where did I put it?
The fucking copy up there
should definitely just fucking
swallow the con instead.
Another good.
Oh,
there's an interesting resolution to the
problem and see how she said to her it
would be a practical solution to
swallow the km. The km run. Yeah.
Just put it in there. Yeah. And then, uh,
wouldn't that be a treat
for, you know, I don't,
I think I'd rather, and she's not doing
it to the cloud run leisure. Yeah.
That's the best part is it?
She's like, look, the easiest
thing is just right here.
I just swallow it. Yeah. Then one of
to clean up, then guys were like, oh,
this makes a lot of sense.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I didn't think about that.
She really hates to come run that
much. Well, I'm sure the camera,
I don't know about. I mean personally,
not that big of a deal to me,
but to some people that's a big deal.
How often are you getting comed in?
Maybe that's her. That's a big thing
for her. What if she's, I mean,
she doesn't seem like she doesn't
do it a lot. Right. Right.
And how many different dudes? We don't
know. Yeah. Yeah. Hmm. No condoms too.
She's in that no condom life. She's
like, who does that? A condom.
In other words,
one big fucking bowl like that.
We all have to go and don't fucking
wanted a bowling ball. A curve ball.
One big fucking boat. Egg.
Wow. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wow. Classy girl. I liked her.
I really like her. Um, yeah,
she's called a Chav. Right?
Is that a Chav? I don't know.
I'm not sure in England.
Um,
speaking of British slang,
there's a guy,
a Brit who teaches you how to speak
like a roadman is the video up?
We got it sent.
That's a roadman heroes.
Gonna go check in on those with Amanda.
That was bad.
Jokes bled Aircrafts are say farm.
The Bay farm.
You're ate my chicken nuggets in it.
You so bait fab.
You might might say
hello everyone does this belly today
I'm going to talk about roadman.
Dallet was in London.
They're going to talk about London
street slang words or so called roadman
darling. It was, I liked London
street slang. Yeah. And he has,
he's English as a second language even
though he speaks fluent English. Right.
Cause there's a, you can tell that his
accent is there, but he's also, you know,
he's trying to become a master
of accidents, which is rad. Yeah.
So he's teaching people, um, Road Rodman.
Is that like cab drivers roadmap? I
don't know. The knowledge, knowledge,
knowledge isn't that way.
What's, what's the the car,
what does it Cockney what is it? The Co,
yeah, that's when they're real low class.
He taught? Is that what
Roadman is now? He said,
well it's London street
and that's called roadmap.
I'm assuming the road man being like
a Cabbie or something made me just,
all right. English people. Collar Guy,
right in. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
Learned his reasoning is the first one
is mandarin man's London means mate my
and it usually means male friend.
Manda Mandarin sometimes means I
grew up off friends as well. Jesus.
Well then this is, it reminds me of
that girl who was like a Coca Cola.
Remember that? The you don't
remember that are cocky kind of,
I remember that. Yeah, I did. Yeah,
like a gimme.
I want a cock.
It was a Korean lady I think,
and she was teaching people,
uh, friends, English. Mike. Mike,
yeah. That was the, we played it long
time ago.
But it's so crazy.
This is the same language.
Skim it.
Yes. We do have car and
this guy, so Amanda,
I'd never knew this shit.
Here I am, you know,
teaching people how to learn
different dialects. People hire me.
They hear that.
I do that.
When they reach out and they say
consultant for accents and you know,
a lot of CEOS have been contacting
all kinds of people, athletes,
actors, um, artists, all kinds of
people in government,
senators, congressmen, yeah.
You know that the incoming
administration reached out. They said,
well how are we supposed to do this
without your help? I'm already no
man data. When someone says like, oh,
Munda this person is calling a friend.
Or Amanda can also use the
word pled or farm boy blood.
We know that we know blood
and Fam. Fun, fun, fun,
awesome. On my blood. What
happened in that much black?
Jeez, that took so long because
these chairs are not conducive.
Why don't you treat me like that?
Really?
So you're going to say that
you're the one blood thumb.
You've been treating me like
I'm a 10 year old boy, but
you treat me like I'm a 10
year old boy the other day.
The other day you don't treat
me like a wife is what I mean?
Like what would a woman who
you're sexually attracted
to you treat me like a 10
year old boy the other
day. You Go, let me,
let me check your di Di is it brown in
there and then you pulled my underwear
and then you went to sniff my,
but like we do with Ellis. Yeah.
You fart in front of me.
Constant. That was affectionate.
You don't think of me like as a woman,
you think of me,
you treat me like a 10 year old boy.
You call me my boobies.
Mushy purples and saugers and sloppers.
Hold on,
I made a list of things that
you do that um, indicate that.
Oh you go, you go, oh you have
chocolate down there. Cause I saw your,
I saw your bare butt cheeks and I thought
you had some chocolate that you smear
it on there. Yeah. But most husbands
don't treat their wives like boys.
They certainly don't ask to sniff their
diaper and they don't tell them they
have chocolate on their butt holes and
stuff. Well I sniffed your diaper. Yeah.
As a form of affection.
But also if it was full,
I was going to help you change
your diaper. Oh my God. Oh my God.
And there's a lot of demeaning
staff were like side meet Mommy.
Remember when he said that? I'll see
how you laugh already at that one.
Remember side meet Mommy. I was laying,
I was laying in bed with you. Yeah.
And I put my arm around. We were
spooning. I was the little spoon. Oh,
here you are. And then I pretended I was
you. And I went, I'm side meet Mommy.
And I left. It was just so not
all you did. You grabbed my,
my stomach meet as you said it.
You squish it and then you go,
I'm citing me mommy. That's the
real game. That was years ago.
I know. That's the first to know.
What's funny is that, you know,
cause we called them hangers and sloppers
and bushy purples and everything.
One of my buddies goes, uh, he goes,
oh I was, he was with his girlfriend,
his girlfriend for years. And he goes,
you know, I liked this big sloppers.
And she goes, what did you just
say? I liked those lockers.
And she goes, what does that, he goes,
oh, it's just something that, um,
that I heard on a podcast.
And she goes,
I don't like that and I don't want you to
say that to me ever again. And he goes,
okay,
let's see.
That's the appropriate response
for something like that.
And that's what I should have said to
you 10 years ago when you started on this
kick with side me,
mommy and sniffing my diaper.
The thing is I didn't have the self
respect or the self confidence to do that
and you know,
really.
So you think it was a matter of self
confidence and that I was raised by a
single father who had treated a lack
of respect. Really? Yeah. If I, if I,
if I were more of a woman,
like a womanly woman,
the fact is I was raised by my single
father and half by my mom and my dad
treated me like a 10 year old boy.
So I think in some ways it's
familiar and it's funny to me.
What are you saying you
really want it to change? No,
I'm just pointing out the obvious.
I mean I love you.
I've been with you for 12 years
for a reason cause it fits. It's a,
it's like a hand in glove at this point,
you know?
No I just noticed it cause cause you
told me that story and I was like yeah
there's no woman, not a lot of women
which always every other week now you go,
you realize no other woman can be
with you. And I'm like wait what?
And you're like no woman would tolerate,
tolerate you pulling their underwear,
sniff your diaper or led on
your butt hall and stuff.
Maybe your farts and
you know you fart a lot
cause I was raised like a 10
year old boy. All right, look,
let's take a look out on
example sentence example.
I'm going to get some those
chicken with my friend. Loved man.
Wait a minute. Yeah. Cheeky man.
Why is Nando's cheeky going to go to
chicken out of your mind them God get a
cheeky Nando's.
What the
fuck? Ah Man. Usually me snot
cupboard, right, right. Bunching.
Roadman dialect.
Bad Means Berry or a lot didn't
know that bear means very or a lot
there.
You have bear mushy saugers
paint a lot of them.
You've got 10 times the amount
of tickets most people have.
See if I were a woman, if I acted
like a girl, but how it bothered me.
Didn't those numbers handy
lately? Yeah. Actually,
thank you for bringing that up
because I went to get a Mammogram,
which you should obviously at 40. They
tell you to go to it saying we should, uh,
highly recommend go do it. It's
not that big of a deal, man.
Get your prostate exam.
Yeah. It's not a big deal,
but I was thankful for my mushy,
mushy purples because they
squish them in like a vice,
like a glass of ice to, you know,
Lou, whatever, x ray them and my,
my tits before I had a kid. It would
have been very sensitive and painful,
but the blessing in the skies is that
they're all deflated. A mushy. Yeah.
It didn't even hurt. I didn't even
feel it really. It was great. Yeah.
So it's a good thing that I had these
big mushy purples now. Yeah. Yeah. Mushy,
mushy, mushy. He says
mushy. I say mushy. Mushy.
Mushy.
Mushy. Purple Bear. Also
when something is very funny,
people sometimes say bad jokes for
example. And that was very funny mate.
That was bad jokes that,
oh my gosh, I like his, um,
when he changes to a roadman. Yeah,
I like that. He wears Adidas gear.
I'm a huge fan of this jacket. Like
he froze his, that was bad jokes.
Blood. That was bad jokes. I oh,
fucking jokes.
But the led Kreps means trainers,
her interested in cold trainers.
So you would need a person here,
this blood from rosemand. Yeah, we
don't say trainers here now. Trainers.
Totally English. English show. If you said
like, I'm trying to get some trainers.
Everyone talking about, you
mean running shoes? Homo? Yeah.
Fucking silly. Willy. Did we
even say sneakers? That's real.
Like that's real middle America.
Say sneakers. Yeah. Sneak sneaks.
Kicks. Kicks. Yeah. I say running
shoes. That feels real foreign.
Cause my parents called them
running shoes. What do I say? Yeah,
you say kicks. Yeah, I do. I'll
say sneakers, sometimes. Sneaks.
Yeah. Or I'll just say,
I'll say brand name.
You know your Puma's. Yeah, I do this.
Yeah. Euros, Love Adidas and
Puma. I do too. I love that shit.
I love it.
Did you see those pumas more?
A lot of the Latinos were them upscale
Latin people like when you see like,
uh,
if they're over here visiting,
but there of money the
Latinos will all have on Pew.
Like when we used to skin tight,
so snug
key at all.
They,
they're built to just like hug your
foot and not and be nonexistent.
Yes. My mom, by the way, a
few years ago for 'em, I go,
I need some running shoes.
Yeah. Uh, just for working out.
And she got me track shoes,
cleats,
like one for actual tracking,
too foreign. I was like, mom,
I don't train for the Olympics. He's
attract. She's a, you said it on anxiety.
Got To these.
All right.
Do you know what shoes I loved growing
up that I don't even think they make any
more. I don't know if they
do. Are Kangaroos? Yeah. They
still make those. Yeah, sure.
Blood thump,
thump does chose off bat.
Yeah. You can get those trainers at
uh, like save on back in the day dude.
They were like Kangaroos and the
I like a pocket or they called.
Well anyway I found a pair when I was
visiting Germany like 10 years ago and
they are rad and people hide drugs and
I'm apparently and that cause I had that
pocket with the velcro. I was fit for
drugs going around you too much now. Yeah.
11 and Rad slipped and you made
so much fun of me for saying
yeah but that's,
you know,
that's the nature of self studying
with people around it for so long.
I said it the other day and this guy goes
did you just fucking say this is Rad?
Yeah.
And you've been saying
gnarly, which is rad. So you,
it's I love gnarly.
Yeah.
Cause you used to make fun of Kat von
d when she would say rad cause she's a
total la girl
and she's like, dude, it's
so rad. And He'd be like, oh
she said that's her
new crops.
This person needs new trainers.
This guy is really helping his native
people though. It was like, this is,
this is how people talk
when they talk like that.
Oh Man. Damn. Craps craps Reps.
Kreps or trainers, Huh? Crabs are,
I don't get the shit all dude.
We know. It's crazy that this is the same
language that we speak, but not really.
It's the queen's English.
Fucking
a man. I got to open this glass.
Yes.
Just
so go to Moose. That
always means, as you know,
uh, that, uh,
it's time to go over some live stuff,
but this is real important.
I don't want to forget.
Um,
the live podcast, February 12th, uh,
at the Irvine Improv sold out.
Thank you everybody that got his tickets.
It's real exciting.
We decided that it's a month away.
We figured that some people, you
know, just didn't get to it in time.
So we decided to add a second
live podcasts. Yo, 9:00 PM,
we're going to do an all
new, um, podcasts at nine.
So now you have a month. Do you have
a month to get tickets to that one?
Um, it's gonna be a lot of
fun. That's going to be a,
I can't wait a pool day of jeans.
[inaudible] Sunday,
February 12th, Denim on
denim, on denim jeans.
How are they going to
handle the denim load?
Everyone's going to be shaped because
they're all going to be sitting next to
each other and their genes you're
going to rub. It's going to be so fun.
She realize how big are they? Brine
is. Yesterday I was in Oxnard,
the guy that oversees all those said
we they're shipping extra like an extra
truck load of water just because
I'm at either me, you asshole.
I was looking at you like what are they
get a, what? Do they get a sense? So, um,
yeah, we're real excited about
that. In addition to that, um,
I should say thank you to
everybody coming to my tour. Um,
I do know this so far,
New Orleans Orleans sold out.
Atlanta sold out a clear
Farder might have 10 tickets,
I dunno.
A Tallahassee few tickets.
Milwaukee's close to sold out.
Madison is sold out.
All three Minneapolis shows are sold
out. Um, so thank you for everybody.
If you want to see where I'm going to be.
I have about 30 plus cities.
I'm going to, um, a lot of them
are on the brink, so check it out.
If you want to get tickets
for Tom segura.com/tour jeans.
I know you have some dates as well.
Yes. I'm so excited about Irvine.
I can't wait. It's going to be so many
mommies. It is. Love it. I love it. Okay.
February 17th, locally, I'm
headlining the Hollywood improv.
February 17th and then the
18th of February. Flip pairs
comedy club in Burbank.
I'll be headlining there. April
13th through 15th, the Brand Improv.
May 4th and fifth fart next Arizona.
It's stand up live.
May 19th and 20th Jew Dork
titties at Gotham comedy club. Uh,
June 16th and 17th, man friend
disco, the punchline comedy club.
And I got a couple more common Denver.
I'm going to be at Ya. Ooh. Uh,
I don't have the date locked in yet, but
I'm coming there too, so super stoked.
All right, come see me. There you
go. Listen to that steep, bro.
It's a good show.
Thank you for the instrumental. Um, sorry,
this next door app that you signed
me out for it. I just got another,
some lady is stealing people's points,
said he has and then there's like
an update on is a screen grab of it.
Um, El Chapo, El Chapo by Eddie. Uh,
Bojangles for that instrumental.
Thank you very much.
You can always send your songs or
your instrumentals to your mom's
podcast@gmail.com.
There's no house in the email.
Address your mom's
podcasts@gmail.com genes.
Uh, we put it out there last week. Um,
obviously there's a big dispute
between the two of us up who's the real
personality change
and people wrote in and uh,
here's what they're saying. Oh,
okay.
Now what people are thinking about this.
Mommy,
Tina thinks she is the personality champ.
Just like how she thinks.
She went to a dentist at one time and
the Dolans told her to Dennis lawyer.
She had 67 of cavities. Tom Is
the main mommy, the water champ,
the weight loss champ. And know that
personality. Champs. Sorry. Tina Dylan.
Thanks Dylan. Next email.
As a professional. Mommy,
this is no fucking contest. Hands down
the personality champ is mommy. Tina,
why?
Well,
having been to every live podcast and
hanging up before and after the shows with
the two mommy, Tina is always excited
and truly happy to see my bear and I,
she goes out of her way to ask us
how we are and gives massive hugs,
which I know she hates what she does it.
Anyway, that's called a warm personality.
Uh,
meanwhile buns gives a head nod,
Woo Hoo and side hugs with a look that
reads. He'd rather be anywhere. But there
now I have more. We have seen the
mommy's separate. Stand up so many times.
I can't count mommy. Tina without fail
acknowledges us. Wow. And honestly,
heres how we are. The hugs, oh,
the hugs, pure warmth and love.
Tommy on the hand has never
once recognized us or put him in
any sort of conversation. When we
have talked forced, I might add,
his vibe is one of coldness and boredom.
We almost feel embarrassed for
having put him through the torture.
Now maybe we've caught buns on off days.
Every single time we've seen him.
Who knows?
But there has never been a time when we
didn't feel real love from Mommy, Tina.
That's how you become a personality champ.
People.
Let's see if bonds can change our
minds at the Irvine live podcasts.
My hopes are high,
but only because I know the
true personality channel
delightfully shine like
always real mommy forever at Jean's
higher than my eyeballs. Leah, Leah,
I know Leah. Leah d'oeuvres. I have
no last name. Derbs on Instagram.
I like her photos. I like to be
intimate with our fans. Thank you.
Hey Hitler. Let me start by saying
I'm a Puerto Rican male and yes,
big Moshi purples and blond hair
definitely do not make my dick soft.
Oh, thanks. But with that
bias being addressed,
I must say that Jean has
a way better personality.
You can tell that Tom will be
unbearable for long periods of time.
Time Tom, maybe better at first glance
that it was only because he is around.
He is fake around people. Right.
I am also a fake person in public,
so I say this as someone
who can relate to Tom.
Gene on the other hand seems to always
act like herself, no matter where she is.
The difference between the two can be
seen on many podcasts that they have been
on.
So with this being said,
I can only imagine the real times
to grow up being way worser.
Gene has the better personality
and I will bet my life on it.
Psi had been a fan of the show since
episode 50. Thank you for all the laughs.
Uh, they always remind me to pull
my jeans high and tight. Tyson,
he does a very thorough assessment.
Yeah,
that guy really put a lot of thought it
up here. I'm sure you're going to read.
You don't worries now. Uh, that's, I
don't know where I was coming in from.
Um, gene, the real truth is, Tom is care.
Charismatic and compassionate has never
been a more clearly composed dialogue
from an individual, was such
talent. He has friends everywhere.
Every individual I talked to you about
it agrees men want to be him and women
went to be with him. Oh Wow.
Christina has a personality dud.
A really sweet person,
but not someone you'd want to start a
conversation with that I think people
would definitely want.
I think people would definitely want to
interact with her if it had the chance
to see Tom probably from a distance.
Tom is obviously the
personality and water champion.
Christopher so funny about these.
Um,
these emails is that they're serious.
That's the part.
They're really actually,
because you know how other things are
like toms water champ because of the,
you know, the arcade. It's nonsensical,
but people are really taking
this to heart. This debate,
this nonsensical to me.
So great. Hey, a was one more
here. Hey genes. Clearly,
purple genes gets overwhelmed
by your water champion status.
She feels the need to challenge the fact
you are also the personality champion.
Her voice cracks face gets red and
her mannerisms present. Clear anxiety.
I mean, come on. When
you drink so much water,
you feel so much better and therefore
ra better person to be around that many
factors as to why the the undisputed
personality champ. It's okay though.
Let Purple Jeans. No, she's
married to a great role model.
Half the battle is knowing
the path to take. Thank God,
after your efforts to lose so much weight
and become the weight loss champion,
she has no choice to be filled with
motivation and become a better person all
around. Thank you. Stay
safe. Mom is best. A sincere,
my face does not turn red.
This is my face. Turn red.
I think when you're faced with
the reality of your personality,
this is my face. Turn red. I
wouldn't know. I don't see myself.
You see me all the time.
I don't see color.
I don't even know when a black person
walks in there. Well that's true.
You don't see colors. You're colorblind
in. Yeah. It's a personality flaw. Yeah.
It's total personality flaw.
Um, how people are really
weighing in on this. Yeah.
I mean,
I don't know if serious debate.
It seems like it's settled that I am
the winter, but you know, we'll see.
We'll see. Time will tell. So Ali, uh,
who used to use his real life, I
don't even remember, starts with an m,
then became all these hymns are right
and now he's all the z's or Zinzer and
he's producing some really great, great
songs for us. Um, you know, if you,
if you're familiar with the show,
you go back through the catalog,
especially in within the last,
I would say 50 episodes.
He's really hit some home runs.
He created a mix,
a song that's a,
a remix where he used king ass
rappers farts to make a song.
I have always a big fan of
these farts actually made to,
that is the bread and gosh, the bread
and butter over. Yeah. So let's see here.
I haven't really had a chance to hear it,
so let's hear. Let's hear it for sure.
Thank you Ali. [inaudible]
for the fart master. Um,
let's see how he titled it.
Fart sounds only the mommy mix.
Here we go.
He always has a nice build up to this.
Yeah.
Was exciting.
Quiet
parts too.
Wow.
Very talented.
I mean,
I feel like two of the
wow to come from the show.
Thank you. Obviously King
asked Trevor, discovering him,
but then Ali together, that's
magic right there. It is.
And what I just imagine
putting it together and studios
and to all those farmers
are farming.
You have to think of the
Fart as an instrument at that
point and be like, where?
What pitch is that hitting could make?
And his girlfriend walking in and
being like, what are you working on?
And he's like, ah, I
gotta finish this song.
So
I was doing this one.
So let's say that dogs are getting hungry.
Oh he wrote an email and he did.
I think I did. I did myself
with this one. Agreed.
I made an entire song only using
fart sounds. All of that was far too.
Everything from the drums to
the melody is 100% sports.
Then I think you guys will be proud.
I've came a long way in
the first couple of beats.
I think I might have changed the
game forever. I think you'd love you.
Mommy's all these e's are
Zim Zur. Yeah. You really,
I didn't realize that was all either.
That's what I was asking.
Like the beats and all farts.
Talent.
What a talent. Yeah, time.
Well spent. Thank you.
That's a really impressive
man. Really, really something.
It's like that is that ob one
who pieced together Theo's jam.
Hundreds bought and he pieced together
all the time. Steel was on the show.
That's right and made a rap
out of it. That was just
wild. You remember last week,
right? Do I remember it? Yeah.
I've only been thinking about it all week.
Somebody wrote in a McAfee related story.
Paige jeans.
When I was a 30 year old student in Nyc,
I knew a generous older guy that
had a fancy version of this chair.
It had a glass window that could slide
in and out about four inches below the
seat.
He used to lay on his back and watch me
push out steaming turds onto the glass
for 250 bucks a session. Hold
on. Hey Man, who come around,
sit down and dump. Once the
dump was done, I would get up,
dress and leave and he
would play with the deposit.
Now I know.
Now I know a story of somebody on a
reality show that I was friends with
acquaintances with.
I remember you told me this story that
he would go to this man's house and the
man would leave a plot,
a brown paper sack on the counter,
and this person would have to shit into
the sack and then leave it and there was
money on the counter.
Wow. That's really, yeah.
$250 is not nothing to sneeze at.
Well,
especially if you're a grad student
or an Undergrad. I would say that's,
that's a really good price
for that. I mean, you start
talking about the costs of,
you know, your tuition, your books, your
housing. Imagine if that guy's like,
just do it once a week or twice a week.
It'd be 500 bucks a week.
And for some you do for free twice a day.
Yeah.
Could you imagine a money?
There was a couple that came to a show
that works in the adult entertainment
business. Yeah. And, uh,
the girls told me that a guy
made that request one time,
a fan did of her. They do, like
they're, they're a married couple,
but they do like online videos and
they sell. So one of the fans was like,
I want you to mail me like a dump, you
know? And she was like, yeah, she's like,
I'm not doing that. And he's like, ah, it
would, he, he offered two or $3,000. Wow.
So she said yes, but he, he was
like, but I want you to eat this,
this and this specifically. And I go, did
you stick to the Diet? She goes, yeah,
absolutely. Because you
know, he seemed to really,
and he's going to know because obviously
he's thought this out enough that he
has requests. So she ate what
he wanted him or what was it?
What was it that she ate? Oh.
Oh, wow. But he, she was like,
I ate it for like two days.
She nailed it, send it off.
And how do you mail a dump
though? Uh, I didn't get into it,
but I would imagine pretty, pretty well
sealed. A couple layers of ceiling,
old FedEx. We'll FedEx. You
can't tell them what's in it.
I don't think they'd be happy about
it. I don't think so. Yeah, send it.
I guess you'd have to do
regular old fashioned,
I mean you could watch Siki just
you put it in several packages.
Think about it. He put it in
Tupperware. Let's think about this.
He's dumped in your Tupperware tub or the
kind that I have, right? The labs over.
Yeah. Okay. You put that into a,
maybe you put a wrap around that too.
Like Saran wrap or gallon bag.
Like a Ziploc gallon bag and you
put that Tupperware wrapped. Yep.
Okay.
Uh, in, in a box and you,
you see all that box up,
sit in right in the box,
and then you put that box in a second box.
So that will prevent the smell
because it's going to smell very bad.
It's going to smell like someone took a
shit. Yeah. It's not going to be good.
Especially if it's hot.
If it's a summertime mailing,
realize that that box
gets to this guy's house.
He opens it and right away.
Yeah.
This is fantasy. It's Christmas
for him. Yeah, that's it.
That's all he's ever done.
It. It's so crazy. Now,
did you have time this week?
I know you're very busy. Yeah.
Did you have time this week to run
your finger on your crack? Yeah.
Yeah.
That was like a question.
I know
that wasn't even a fight. I couldn't tell
him that was what I was bad. It's like
your first always smiling. God
No, you didn't answer my question.
I know you had a busy week.
Yeah.
Did you have a moment and your busy day
to run your finger along your crack?
Don't put it in your asshole, but just
along the crack to smell your own.
Smell your fingers. Yeah. Yeah. I um,
I did and I uh, I feel,
feel much better about it.
Have you learned your own smell?
You know that guy is
so God damn ridiculous.
Stupid.
He's just
smell what? You're not smell like
a different times of the day.
Yeah.
Run your finger along the crack of your
ass. You don't need to finger your whole,
you don't want to come back
with shit on your finger.
Thank you. Yeah, but you want to
snip. You want to sniff it, you know?
Oh burn. What's your ass smells like?
What's your cock and balls smell like?
You got to learn that stuff because people
don't know. We got an email this week.
No,
it's funny because the person is,
is right on board with what we're
talking about. Deer, Mommy's,
I believe it was in episode three 67
where both pairs of jeans question whether
people got into pup play to relieve
sexual desires or just burn off some steam
and a fun,
harmless and nonsexual way that that is
something that we highlighted last week.
We showed you the TV documentaries.
Like we're just having fun.
Just a couple of lads and
the latex. Exactly. Make sure
you give yourself a phone.
Don't have a phone.
Um,
so I have a phone photo.
If you have a moment in the day as well.
If you have a break, go to
a cubicle. All the bathroom
if you're not too busy.
I love that.
It's like you can fit this into
your schedule. Like a workout. Yeah.
Take the stairs instead of the
elevator please. Well he wrote, yeah.
What you both a question that
whether it's fun, harmless.
It has to come to my attention.
That pup play is almost 100% sexual.
I've done some digging and boy,
I sure did find a bone.
You will see in exhibit a
filled
and sealed. Um, and then,
and then with what is referred to as a
tail in the pop world and the pop world
or what sane people call it, butt
plugs. Uh, Andrew, let's see.
So
he's 100% right.
Andrew is right. And
uh, this pup play. Oh,
so here is a pop getting
a tail at the vet.
Oh boy. Oh boy. Oh, vets. The
vets like a normal bed. No,
this doesn't look like our vet.
She's, yeah, she's very different.
Oh boy.
So right now the vet who's in a full
laid text, uh, outfit and a mask,
a just put the human pop
on all fours on the table.
I also,
for this dog,
his examination there appears
to be handcuffs, Lube,
and a butt plug on the table and
a phone and the iPhone. Yeah,
no take taking, pick, steal.
Someone's people know he's
here. It's updates. You don't
want me to use those two?
No, no. We don't need those two
weeks. Yeah. So the pump is a that
now that the vet is doing the right thing,
keeping the pup relaxed, right? Yeah.
Okay. Yeah. He doesn't
like the vet either.
You got to keep petting him and be
like, sorry buddy. It's all right. So,
so far it does seem like a
very thorough medical exam
and it's just, it's not sexual
if you start like this, uh,
thing to do. Oh. Oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh,
oh.
So the vet just opened what appears to
be a zipper on the back of this dogs
late. The human dogs lay texts,
um, uniform. The poop shit.
Yeah.
And he said he's going to give that
little little area an exam as they do to
dogs. They do that to
dogs, you know, they do.
They put a thermometer in there and
they express the anal glands. Yeah.
Fifth doesn't like it at all.
You don't have a title?
Good puppy. Oh good. Yeah.
You push down on that if you
think it's feels okay. Yeah. Good.
You can push down on that if you think
it feels it's not sexual though. God.
I wish people would stop stigmatizing us.
Poor guy,
or just people that look just like to
wear latex and we'd just like to act like
dogs.
Yeah.
Oh
yeah.
Now you and I had this debate in the car
because we couldn't stop thinking about
pup play in the Hammock is a which one is,
is definitely sicker. Like
what's what's, Oh yeah. What's,
what's Weirder, I guess. You know
what I mean? Yeah. I mean definitely.
It's not good to be in the hammock world.
Well, my argument is the hammock world,
it's, it's one and done. It's like it's
a short thing. The pup play. It's a,
it's like you're taking a semester, you're
taking classes, plays a lifestyle. Yeah.
It's a whole thing. It's really, really
good at dive in, but if somebody goes,
I mean, here's the thing, what
side of the Hammock are you on?
That's all the difference in the world.
Why I'm the one depositing? Yeah.
That's your only $50 I need to make.
Yeah. That, that's not that big of a deal,
I guess. Yeah. It's still just like a
gross thing to be doing. That's horrible.
Yeah.
It's hard.
It's hard and I don't even know if I
could shit in front of another person.
That's really the truth that
way. No, no, no. Not in front
of them. Into their mouth.
They're not watching you take a dump.
They're under you receiving your time
and the thing that that might make the
pressure, but the pup play lifestyle
that's just so involved, like that's just,
that's a real, and you've got
to buy the latex and I tell you,
I don't think latex outfits are cheap.
That's what you're concerned with.
The lifestyle is so much the expenses.
He's got time for that stuff, you know?
Yeah. I'm just saying that it's a real
investment to be into the pup play.
I've only seen two that this one pig just
benefit from the whole pup play thing.
One Guy, one guy, he's like
the, who's your owner guy?
He's the only guy that actually
gets off on this thing. Right?
And he has all these pups. He's like,
I'm training. Smell your cock and balls.
That's, he's just, it's just him. It's
him in the five dudes that are into it.
They're like, where are your dog? Where
you, when the best time just loving life.
Why don't I see more of this medical exam?
Oh, I don't, I think I know
you don't have a title. Oh,
he'd go have a title puppy.
Now. Do you see the way he said he
goes, oh, you don't have a tail.
Like we can fix that though.
Right?
What's creepy?
I don't feel it's okay.
You know what I don't like
now that they're doing actual,
it's like it mixes the animal stuff.
Yeah. Now it's like, okay, is this,
it's kind of weird to think of a,
uh, a dog. How do you get hard?
Of course, that's the whole thing.
You got to mix those two worlds. Yes.
Now I'm confused.
Now are these guys into fucking dogs and
this is sublimating that need to fuck
dog.
Our dog's,
now you've come because you need
a title. Yup. Yeah. There you go.
Oh Shit. Oh No. That's so big. And you'd
like us. We'll give you, oh my God.
It's so long too.
So now does it normally?
No.
So now the idea,
and he's human pup doesn't have a tail
poor guy and they're going to give him
the tail in the form of a very long
but plug so that he'll have a tail.
Yeah. But by the way, it's
just a fun just oh, that's
where you hang out and this Guy
Watch football is the fun thing.
Stop making it sexual.
This is like the girl scouts.
The boy scouts were just
all community people.
Could you put that nine inch Dildo and
did my asshole for a second though.
It's just for the dog thing
is nothing to do with sex.
Oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh this guy loves it. 11
months right now, boy.
Oh
yeah.
Oh.
Reminds me of that.
Oh,
come on.
So hey was very tight down there
aren't, you know shit. It's my asshole.
You Derek. That's your, but
let's have a quick close. Um, no,
you'd get down. That's going to help.
Well thank you sir. Yes sir. Oh boy.
How much to do this one?
Okay. Now would you rather,
would you rather do pup play or, or the
Hammock, but as a guy, what role am I in?
Either one. You're the fucking pot, bro.
I'm the pup or what your the pub here and
you're the shitter and the other snow.
Yeah. Taking a shit. Yeah, of
course. Easy, right? Yeah. It's easy.
But last week you were, I think into pup
play. You weren't needing to pooping.
Well No, I'm, I'm never going to
receive a poop. No, neither. Okay.
If it's between receiving the poop or
getting the butt plug, get a butt plug.
Easy. Yeah, right. Of
course. Get 10 butt plugs,
but butt plugs in my mouth and put them
everywhere. Shoved Butt plugs in my ears.
You can't even really eat brown.
I mean it's like not a good
thing to eat brown ever.
There's gotta be a brown
eater that listens to this
show too. I please write in.
How do you, how do you eat brown?
Cause doesn't it make you subs?
How do you do it? I mean physically,
you just get ill. If you eat brown,
it Kenny Brown,
you can drink,
you can drink yellow if it's separated.
I read that in a survival handbook cause
it'll separate into layers and you can
drink the top layer of urine, but
you can't, you can't eat brown. Yeah.
It's just a no, no, man. Everybody
knows that. Yeah. Crazy. Stop eating.
There's, um, do you,
do they bite the Turd?
Like do you think they really
eat it or they just play with it?
The people who like it,
you bite into it.
I didn't want to be
fucking sick. Why? Guide?
You're such a square. Why don't
you open your mind? I know.
I'm such a fucking square it.
Yeah.
Why don't you be a little more open minded
about other people's sexuality? Tom,
last week we had the dad boner,
uh, who saw him or the whales,
which was actually really cool.
That was a really cool like, whoa.
He's like a glass and Dad. Yeah, super
glass. We restock glass and by the way,
a bunch of people hit me up for it. It's
fully restocked. Also, I got your emails.
Uh, if you got that first order of Gildan
is you got to hook them in to you. Um,
we restocked that we
restocked, uh, the water champ.
We restock, um, a double vibe classics.
So thank you for shopping at the store.
Go to your mom's house, podcast.com.
Dot. Au. Click on quick, quick, quick.
Don't we just added Amazon UK.
That's right.
So if you're in the United Kingdom and
you like our show and you shop on Amazon,
you can now click on our UK banner
on your mom's house, podcast.com,
because we have one for obviously for
here in the U S and we have from for
Canadian Canadia. Yeah. And now
that you UK, yeah. Thanks a lot.
Thanks for your support. Um, so
here's a new clip, uh, of a dad boner.
Uh, I haven't seen it yet, but it's
uh, uh, reacting to a solar eclipse.
Those are pretty
fantastic. Oh yeah, there it is.
Wow. Look at that. Oh my God. Look at it.
Look at this. Oh my God. It's
coming. The Moon's shadow is coming.
It is coming. Oh my God,
here, come look at this.
I never seen him like this.
Ever sincere. No flashes.
Oh my God. Here we go.
Look at it. Oh my God.
Whoa. Look at that. Oh my God. Here we go.
He's got so much,
so excited and you realize that we
have found an entirely new lane.
Yeah. Like we have found like
dad's dorking out basically. Yeah,
the glass and dads and guys.
Wow. Oh my God. It's coming
right over thinking, oh my God,
we're getting close to
the top. I got corona.
Them is dilute Bailey's beads.
Very big diamond ring.
Totality,
totality.
Oh my God. You realize if that was your
dad and you're there, you'd be like,
oh my God, please, please.
Oh my God. Look at that. Challenge me.
Oh my God. The middle stream. Or just
look at the, come to the talk. Prominence.
He's such a science day. So
many big words. He's using
all the technological word.
Must read Wikipedia.
Right?
Going up to the atmosphere. Oh, look
it down there. Speeding. It's called.
It's a flare. Look at that
diamond rig. Look at Dad
Double Rainbow. Look at that. Oh my God.
Wow.
Such a wow Dan. Yeah. Yeah. The
fucking ultimate dad boner. Yeah.
Yeah. We have him. We have a,
what is it? It's the, yeah,
no, sorry. It's uh, the whale dad. Well,
got a diamond.
Yeah.
What his well dad did they breach feeding?
This is cool though.
Stoked.
That's awesome.
That is awesome
man.
You get juices flowing through
shit myself.
Oh Lord.
Wow. Those are super dads.
Yeah. Those make me so happy
though. I know. I hear him.
I get like the,
it's the excitement is contagious
ultimate then just glass,
glass,
Lakota moves so many fucking bet.
I get tagged and a hundred things a day
that could just glass in here. Dude.
Did you see um,
was it USA today and had Aaron
Rodgers and then it's one of those,
uh, you know, it has the
caption of the photo,
like Aaron Rodgers against the New
York giants, but they also like,
we'll give a little title to the,
to the side photo essay today. Yeah.
And it said just glass and just glassing
but they said glassing with a G.
Yeah. Glassine. Yeah. But I know,
but it was us and the glassing is not
a word we invented. Just glassing.
If you hadn't, if we hadn't played
that and, and I saw that caption title,
I'd be like, what the fuck does that
supposed to mean? Right? Yeah. No,
we invented just glassine. Yeah,
it's pretty nuts. It's nuts. Um,
that in double pipe closed, we didn't
invent it because it was a, it was a term,
but just glassine is, is now definitely
why I'm h yeah, yeah, for sure.
That's legit. I found out that, that
remember that Rockwell automation
guy that can then relate to most boring.
Yeah.
Apparently that is like an aristocrat
scope for engineers. What number?
The aristocrats. Oh, right.
So apparently that video
with all those terms,
that's like an aristocrats joke.
Uh, engineers. Oh my God. Okay.
So it's all the big words.
And then basic joke is you create a video
about the turbo and cab and calculator
and you fill it with nonsensical,
hilarious.
And other companies have done it like, um,
it looks like we have another one here.
Okay.
So it was a jibberish.
It's a Jibberish joke for the engineer's
laugh at all. This is hilarious.
It's funny.
Yeah.
Even if you're not an engineer and pretty
good. Okay. It's funny. This is like a,
an ongoing thing here at Chrysler Motors
automotive operations research has been
proceeding to develop a line of heavy
duty transmissions that establishes new
standards for reliability,
durability,
and quality with customer needs.
As our primary focus work is proceeding
on the crudely conceived idea of an
instrument that would not only supply
in verse reactive current for use in
unilateral phase,
detractors would also be
capable of automatically
synchronizing Cardinal Graham
eaters.
An instrument is the turbo and calculate
your original machine had a base plate
of prefab emulated emulate by a malleable
log rhythmic casing in such a way that
the two sperming bearings or in a
bourbon blind with a parametric fam
separations,
and then these guys just hilarious,
so fit into the amputation.
Lunar Lunar Winter,
I believe presented.
How did this, this guy learned all
this stuff. He's not reading off cards.
It looks like he has be. Yeah. Wow.
The main winding was of the normal Lotus
Oh delta type placed in pen and make
some bull Lloyd slots of the stater.
So that's what they do. That's
amazing. That's so funny.
All right to know that engineers have
a sense of humor. I know that is. Um,
I don't know if I should
keep you waiting any longer.
There is more submissions of,
Hi Mommy.
Thank you guys for sending them in.
It's been absolutely one of the most fun.
I can't tell you how
many times by the way,
I can pass in the last couple of weeks
when you guys have been sending these in
and we've been playing them
that I then get messages.
Does it go like I had to pull over my
car cause people are laughing at what
you're doing with these high marks.
People are really enjoying these.
I'm really enjoying. I am
too. I think it's super funny.
This is the best. This is,
here we go. Here's things we've ever done.
A third installment. Oh my God. Hi Mommy.
Thanks jeans.
Richard Starbucks. You can order
whenever you're ready. Thanks Mommy.
Okay, I'm ready. What can I get?
Can I get a grande iced coffee
high and tight with soy milk?
Unsweetened please. Yeah. All right.
I just coffee with soy milk and just wait
one second. I'm glossing. Don't
anything Hitler. Oh, can I get a water?
I need to stay hydrated or
anything else. That's it. Alrighty.
It's going to be three Oh two today.
We'll see you over doing nothing.
Genius. Yeah, that's great.
Yes. Thanks. Love you. Bye.
Oh Wow. The bar has been elevated.
Yeah. And I need to stay hydrated.
Hydrated. And she goes,
Hitler. Do you want anything?
She turns to the guy I need.
You want anything that was
masterful, really well done. And the,
I like her ease with it.
She just, she just did it
naturally. That was what we do.
Well, you do it. You know what? You
act like. You've been there before.
That was Kristin. Thank you, Kristin.
Good work. Uh, here we go. Here's Ben.
So impressed. Probably have hang
out with you today. I'm good. Um,
I'm going to get a medium black coffee
and I'm also going to do a medium coffee
light. Ice Black. And I taught
here, okay. Excuse me one second,
but that
shit. Sorry about that. Um, yeah.
I'm going to do a medium coffee black and
then a medium black coffee with sugar.
It's going to be it.
Thank you.
Wow. That's really good. Really
good work. Introducing Patriarch.
Wow. I'm really impressed.
Really good man.
Absolutely. Really good. He's up there.
He's showing, so that's been really good.
I think we to finish that off with
Cinnabon delights the Tupac please for a
dollar. Mommy want to come help me?
No,
I think we're good to go.
Yeah, it looks perfect.
Okay. I love you. Thank you.
How many,
how many people are,
are hearing in the background?
Yeah. And they're like, wait,
what did that person just say?
Okay.
If you were the person taking the
order and somebody was doing this,
you wouldn't, you wouldn't imagine. I
know. People are saying, you'd be like,
I know. You're just like,
oh, they're saying. Um,
Richard. Thanks Richard. Very well done.
Good luck. Thank you for
calling the Hollywood improv.
We always keep our jeans high and tight.
Hug.
Hello.
That is sold by.
Wow. We're holding up. All right,
thanks for holding. How can
I help you? That's fair.
At nine 30 you,
I don't have good hygiene.
World famous Hollywood improv.
Improper were just glass and how can
we have one time show that sold out and
one that has picked scalable, sold out
sardines. Yeah. Unbelievable.
Katie, Katie, who obviously
worked at the Hollywood Improv,
we got to say hi to Katie. That's unreal.
Okay. If you buy tickets to my show,
by the way, at Melrose, let me see if you
find Katie. I'm going, what am I going?
February 17th man, I hope she answers
a call. If she, if someone named Katie,
I hope somebody go, she goes
like, hi, thanks for calling.
How improv games and then they go,
hey mommy,
I want to get February 17th I'm at
this club, the Hollywood improv.
Ask for Katie and buy your tickets.
So fucking
right on when we got a spark and say
what's up to Katie? Thanks Katie.
That is so crazy.
So thanks very much.
All right, we roll on.
Here is Matthew.
Okay,
can you just give me one minute?
Thank you. Hey, look,
can I get just to plan double
cheeseburgers and ketchup and cheese only?
Yeah. And then I see the, you,
I'm just glancing at the menu here and
I see that you have a 10 piece nugget.
Can I get two of those?
And then a large fry
with a large Dr Pepper.
But can you do just a little bit of ice?
And I'm talking about filming, I mean,
just a little bit ice
and then that is it.
Can I have that?
I can't see the screen can either read
back to me and make sure that these
hindsight
terrible speakers.
That's it.
Unbelievable. Wow. Really good. That
was so good. That was really good.
Um, calling them Hitler
is a whole new level too.
High and Thai people are.
Wow. Really? You know,
I'm just blown away by this.
Sorry.
I know I'm always just blown away by the
level of talent of our audience. I know.
It's really funny. I can't believe I
remember the one you told me about.
I think he told me this.
Off you go that email it somebody goes,
I want you to know that
Tom said that you're fart.
Didn't register on the, on the recording,
but I want you to know that we here.
I know
this guy wrote that.
I almost died. That's so funny
dude. Incredible. They're
funny. They didn't grow.
How did I not have this drop?
So for earlier,
man,
it's their pool anyways.
Um,
Australian
international and James, can
I get um, a family bug, a box,
meal place.
Can I get all burgers please?
And can I get them hot and spicy as well?
Now I just go.
Awesome.
Thanks.
Thanks Molly.
Nobody it never registered.
James, can I get um, a family?
I Dunno his name. Just how funny. Um,
love the international
international is really great.
Interesting to hear what people are
eating. I know other places do that.
One did order two cheeseburgers, but then
he might be ordered for somebody else,
but he's like two cheeseburgers
and pizza in the car. Not this guy.
The guy before. Oh, who
knows? Yeah. Oh my gosh.
I look like a normal build guy too.
I still can't get over. Katie. Can I
get a coffee with a blueberry please?
Blueberry coffee with a blueberry Danish.
Perfect. Right away for care coffee. Uh,
just one milk. Uh, yes, please. That's it.
Yeah. That's so great. Thanks. Jeans.
Ah, English jeans. Um, it's
so funny. Really funny.
See Nc,
do you see the sense of accomplishment
on people's faces as they feel good about
it? Yeah, of course. You
feel so much pride when you
get away with it. It's like,
it's just, it's a, it's a victimless
crime. Yes. That's so fun though.
Just feels right. It does. God,
it's so much fun. Yeah, it is fun.
It is fun to do.
Daniel says awesome shit in the mouth.
That's right.
Another person on CD shit. Not only
in your mouth, but on not around
inside your man. So, ah,
yes. I'm laughing this episode. This has
been a really jam packed episode. Yeah.
God Damn it. She was funny. She
knits all needs to go out. Okay.
She's got to go pee. Gee, she's
laying by the door. Hold on. Yeah,
she's a little girl.
Go ahead. And we're done. Yeah. The uh,
oh, so funny. Good place here that the,
there's dogs around every wall.
Like behind every fence or whatever yard.
The yard split. Yeah. So all the dogs
go crazy. That's in the evening. I know.
Super Nice. So this, uh,
I thought this is something
you'd like to give a shot to. Um,
a lady,
let me get the correct thing here.
You know exactly what it is.
A lady has decided to live
without money for a year.
Oh, cool. To reduce her
environmental impact.
And the narrator has on
believable vocal fry.
Oh No.
Yeah.
Joe Nemeth leaves off the
fruits of her own labor.
It's been one year since she has earned
or spent a cent choosing to live without
money to lower her impact
on the environment.
Um, that's a cool
documentary. I'd like that
swatch.
And she grows all of her own food,
cooks it on a fire powered stove,
relies on rainwater and hitchhikes or
transport odds of soy keeping stove yet
become toilet.
Uh, don't know about that
one. Serviettes no thanks.
Would you want to use your, your dinner
Napkin to wipe your ass later? Yes.
Did he get food on your butthole?
They're the ones,
you know when you go to a cafe,
people have like a serviette at
the bottom, underneath your car.
You might spill over to coffee on it,
but actually then it gets thrown
in the bin. But it's okay.
It's not dirty as such.
Kind of collect those secondhand
Soviets to recycle them.
I love this sweet lady. I could see you
being best friends with, I love this car.
Yes. Yeah. Cause I love Lou.
I love lunacy like this.
I love people that stick it to the man.
I love these people that are off the
grid or like growing their own food and
dumpster diving. I love, I could do this.
You could not do this in
100 million. Yeah, yeah. No,
I would say a lack of personality.
I lack of, of tenacity.
See, sometimes it feels a
bit isolating because to me,
because I'm just a little bit
odd, you know, I don't, yeah.
Fit what everybody else is doing. I like
it. And most of the time that's okay.
You know, I can hang out with my friends
and it's just like normal, but it,
you know,
to live low impact like I am,
I really would like to share that with
other people who want to do the same
thing as me. He wanted to leave as
radically lower. I love it as I am.
You go there for awhile,
you know Australian. Yeah.
I feel like I did this. This is called
living your 20s as a comic. Yeah, no shit.
We kind of already did this.
I think we've done this lifestyle.
Maybe we had more of an environment in
environmental impact, but not much more.
Not much been broke down that
some friends, his name is Lance
Nimbin in northern New South Wales.
New South Wales is Australia's shack in
exchange for working on their orchards
back.
Oh yeah. Oh, it's bad. It's bad. Yeah.
Uh,
uh, yeah. So there you go.
It's just like the gays.
So would you, how bad do you
think her box smells though?
I don't think regularly. I mean she,
she bay, she's hygenic I think. Yes.
Okay. But I don't, I mean, I don't think
it smells particularly good, but I don't,
I don't think it's,
it's wretched or anything like that.
How annoying do you think she is to
have over? Oh my God. She's like,
you guys use paper towels? I, Oh
yeah. We love everything. Everything.
Every time you turn on the sink, she'd
be like all that water and going away.
They flushed the toilet. Did
you brown in there? Uh, no.
Why are you flushing like
everything you do? She criticize.
How are you going to use those serviettes
throwing them in the trash. You Go,
what is that?
Pipe up blood.
She's collecting all the
fucking dirty napkins.
Yeah, it would be annoying. Nightmare.
She's super annoying. Le Quoc had,
would be used. Do you recycle?
Yeah, I know. We'd be like,
yeah, when it's convenient.
When you do it. Come on man. We're
American. We don't want to do recycling.
I recycle boxes. Look in European
shit. Come on. All right.
I gotta get ready to go actually.
Oh yeah.
What are you got to go for blood
farm. Go Away. Can trainers.
I am going away in my train.
We have a closing song.
It's called itsy is terrorizing free.
You're free now. The glutton just
glassine hot mix by
Mitchell Davis. Cool. Um,
thank you guys for listening to another
episode of your mom's House podcast.
I'm the main mom. No, I'm the personality.
Shannon may mommy. Thank you. You are
not. Nobody likes you, but listen.
No. So, uh,
please continue to support the show
and um, we can't thank you enough.
We'll see you next week.
Anything else? Jeans? Uh,
my face is not get red. There
you go. No red faces here.
When I look up and I
know I'm getting excited.
I'm getting excited.
I'm getting excited. I started
out on my knee, my left.
I started out on my knees to my left,
to my left.
[inaudible]
yeah,
yeah.
Ow.
Ow. Ow. We're just crashing. You ever
seen him lose go down right quick?