Well.
Well go to your mom's house.
Christina
ponder.
What is that?
How do you not know this?
Because I'm, I have,
I don't have the musical tastes
of a seventh grader. Okay.
Do you listen to Gwen Steffani too,
bro.
Oh my God. Do you hear that?
Yeah, that sounds terrible.
What is that? I don't know,
but it happened when I did
that. Steve Rowe last week. Oh,
that it's probably this
table. Oh, there you go.
It's fine right now.
Oh yeah.
I hate fucking cable issues.
You feel bad for,
we don't hate stuff.
I'll go broaden it. So check it out. Yos
but says at Drake
designer. Designer. Yeah.
God,
you're such a seventh grade girl.
Are you going to go to the
mall later with your friends?
What everyone's going to be?
I get a cramp. Your hair,
you're going to get a slumber party
should just shut up, man. Yeah,
June. It's my birthday month.
No one cares about that.
June nine 10 11 I'm in Irvine iceberg
rewrite and rude or sperm bind in
California at the Improv.
Five shows come on out.
Then the next weekend,
June,
1617 and 18 your smurf day? Yeah,
I mean, Gosh, Bill, Tennessee.
Wow.
Xannies west nut sack New York.
That will be June 23rd 24th and
25th July seven Spit Cincinnati,
Ohio. Spit on the Smith. Next spirit.
Since the spirit to sit and
spin natty and spin Benetti hey,
that's where I had the Cincinnati farther.
You're going to go and commemorate.
You don't think I'm going to go
make a video paying pilgrimage
and Amash July 14th or 16 man.
Diego,
California American comedy company.
Yup.
And then July 21st through
23rd St [inaudible],
Missouri. Ry, Horace. Do Dork
titties warns that one? Oh,
that's not until September.
I Have Baltimore and uh,
come on me more and uh,
come lumber us, Ohio.
What do we do for Ochsner?
That's a new one that's already
got some nards. Oh yeah. Oxnard's
see? Nah Dude, she went to
that door though. No, no.
She went to snip the trashcan. She was
looking for things to do. She's bored.
All right. Jude Org kidneys
is natural. September 8th.
I'm doing Lexington, Kentucky as well
as that's what I was telling you.
I'm not supposed to. It announced
that Shit fucked up. Um,
Philadelphia fill her up.
Delphia filler Alfia uh,
we added a show in November.
That's slut Sington that's good.
But my um,
Philly show added so you can
by that now for November 18th cause
19 soul music is too mellow. Well,
I mean just thank you Brian for making it.
Thank you Brian.
But it's like for a sweet love making
times who says this isn't a love making
sure. That's what most of the focus
of this show is. Was it everyone?
Everyone does when they listen.
This is a, it's a married couple.
They talk about how to
effectively make love. Yeah. Um,
guys, May 27th, May 28th.
That's this weekend.
I'm at the La Jolla comedy store
with Matt Full Shrine.
Oh my God.
Yep.
That's how is going to open the show.
He's going to come on everybody who's
there and tell him your mommy and he'll
come on.
You're mixing up the love making music.
See what you're doing. Brilliant. Also,
I'm working on dates for
cities like Portland.
Oh, I'm working on Seattle. Houston.
You'll see,
see
Dallas the last,
it's coming the last,
just hold your panties. It's, that's
almost ready. Ah, also if I'm,
I'm usually at the comedy store every
Saturday, uh, the seven 30 show,
come see me side cause I'll be in Lajolla
the other comedy store. Right. But come,
uh,
come to that early show.
It's been full of mommy's every weekend
on Saturday and it's been so fun.
That's what's up. And I'm usually in
the hallways. You can say hi to me and,
and you'll see like have all the famous
comedians. Everybody's there. Yeah,
that's great. Oh listen to that steep
bro. Please, please, if you, you know,
if you want. And then use our
Amazon banner to do your shopping.
Go to your mom's house,
podcast.com.
Click on the banner at the
bottom of the homepage.
Do Your shopping as you normally would
and it just kicks back some change to the
show. Thank you for everybody
that's already been doing that.
We really appreciate it. Yeah. And we
see it. You buy printers, you buy lube,
you buy socks, you buy everything. Don't
tell him that. Nobody wants to know.
That's exactly what the email said,
but, but we don't see who buys it,
so we don't see who buys it.
But we're saying we see items that are
purchased through our banner. Yeah.
We're saying keep buying that. Lot
of Lube. Lot of Lube. Yes. So funny.
There's a lot of dry pussies in this
audience or a dry hands are assholes.
Assholes. That's true. Awesome. Awesome.
You say awesome because we have
a lot of bears that listen.
Do we in a huge bear community?
How do you know that?
Judging by her fan mail baby, I don't
get a budget bear fan, man. Yes you do.
Yeah.
No.
If we convert a quarter of that fan mail
to your mom's house listenerships Oh my
goodness, they, but you're
huge in the bear community.
How many bears? Only tours
have you done? Tell me.
Yeah, seriously. What are you going
to do? Bears only for real bears only.
What do you mean just do shows tailored to
the bay. The, the gay bear market. Look,
Ben, I just, all I got to see is that
check, you know, if you guys hire me,
I'll come do your bear your bear show.
Yeah. You know, just fucking pain.
When's the retarded act coming?
So,
um, I'm working on, I know you want
me to tour as a retarded, retarded,
retarded comics mix.
So I'm just saying that there's a market
out there that's not been tapped into
and I think that retarded
people need to laugh too. Okay.
But we're ready to get this
going. Uh Huh. Remember?
Oh, we should mention there's
no cameras rolling. Oh right.
Blue Band got sick. I know. I did that
thing where what people do when they,
they want permission to be sick, you
know? I know which, I've done that too.
And it's, and then I've gotten other
people sick by doing that. He was like,
I'm not feeling so good, but
I'll be there. I was like,
no, don't do that. No, no.
All right. I feel better. Blue Band.
Y'all better blue man. His little,
his feathers are sick and yeah,
to stay in his, in his nest nest.
And just kind of drink warm,
warm tea and yeah,
he's nuzzled up and is necessary.
And other birds or blue man.
All right,
here we go.
Hi. How are Ya? Join us. It's Jason
car coming down to enjoy some salad.
Be You have messy. You have been very
impressive. Kelly, you get Jason out here.
We love, everybody wants a younger
girl, right Jason? That's right.
And I know you want me to toss your
salad tomatoes. All right. On that. No,
don't bring it in one.
Loving to this. Well, no,
no.
Go to your mom's house,
Christina.
The fuck.
Yay. Okay. And it's retarded.
Ah, Shit. Ah, shit man.
Yeah, great. Was that,
that was on one of those morning
news shows which so painful. Yeah.
The ones that I've been going
on lately where they have,
they always have a cooking
segment. They're like, hey,
this morning and this lady is I guess,
uh,
in town and she's has the, you know, the,
they're making salads and then
I guess she's a yoga person. Um,
she's wearing a shirt. I don't know,
it says seven Greens, I dunno.
But, um, I, news guy walks over,
she just,
she starts to get kind of flirt
coming down to enjoy some salads.
Might be you have,
everybody wants a younger
girl, right? Jason,
I know you want me to toss your salad.
Those yoga girls totally shuts it
down to he looks away. He's like,
well no. He's like, he knows that
that's trouble, you know, so it goes
instead of like having fun with it.
He just
said that boss, I didn't
say nothing. I guess a,
you're not even allowed
to laugh, right? Yeah.
Cause that encourages the bad behavior.
This is an adult and you can't even
laugh man. And she's actually, you know,
she didn't say it, I don't think to
be like, you know, to make that joke.
She really was making uh,
making the other girl a salad.
So when she tells him that,
he's like,
it's so funny to me that that exists in
the world where adults have to restrain
themselves. I just don't understand it. I
have a real, I struggle with it. You know,
I used to work in a law firm and that
was the hardest thing in the world was to
restrain myself constantly. They
just really, really shut it down.
Right? Yeah. You can't have fun. Yeah. No,
you're not supposed to laugh at
your job or be inappropriate,
obviously. Very Sullen, man.
I did. It's so painful. Was it?
Could you imagine working on a morning
show how fucking hard and horrible that
would be for one for us.
Wow.
I can't wait to see this new salad.
A big of this show is
spending time just you.
You spend time fake reacting to things
so they have to go like, that's me.
Oh, it takes spending time
with a toddler, like, wow,
look at your salads.
You how much that takes out of you.
Just do that for a second.
I know, but maybe some,
maybe some people are like
that and normally is that
someone's real personality.
Some people's,
but even then they,
it becomes their personality because
they manufactured it for a while. Yeah,
no one's born like that to go like,
that's good gray.
See that they got a new donut
over on main street go. Okay.
Is that,
yeah.
Is that socialization like I grew up in
a house where if I'm not happy all the
time I got in trouble is probably,
or maybe it was just, yeah,
don't show feelings.
It was so bad in my house growing up.
I overcompensate by being
like, that's gray. Yeah,
because feelings are dangerous.
You'll get it, you'll
get in trouble. Well,
they're like that on the morning
shows a lot, you know? That's the,
whether it's local or even national,
the Good Morning Americas and shows,
it's always like an maybe that's just
puts people in a good mood, can know.
You wake up and they're like going to
work and they turn that on and someone's
like, Hey, this is really neat.
What's going on here today?
It may be it for the non cynical person.
Oh fuck them.
Maybe for normal people that's like
cheerful. Feels good. Yeah, it was good,
but it doesn't work for me.
I don't work for me.
You know what I don't understand either
are are people who want to be Miss
America. That's another one. Right? Why?
Why is that even a thing for you?
I want to be with American.
You're so going to win this year
and we're practicing your answers.
The best is when they have like the
hardest part for them is answering one
question. What was the big, it was
with fucking Steve Harvey this year.
No, no, no, that's, yeah,
that's his friend is the best.
What's the big fuck up with the answer?
Remember the girl who lost her mind in
the answer. No, you don't remember that.
Wait, what do you like? She bluffs.
She flubbed it or something.
She's like kill all the Jews. I'm,
I'm, I don't know what I'm saying.
Yeah know it's 2007 it was miss teen USA.
We're on pause.
Have shown a fifth of Americans
can't locate the u s on a world map.
Why do you think this says,
I personally believe that you had some
Americans are unable to do so because
some people out there and our nation and
I believe that our education like such
as South Africa and Iraq everywhere,
like such as,
I believe that
our education over here and then
you asked should help the US.
I should help eyes
and should help die.
I can the Asian countries
able to build on our future
so bad. It's hard. I covered
my eyes for that whole thing.
It's pretty well look at the screen.
I wonder if you ask her the same question
today if you'd have the same response.
There's no way you think she's gotten
over the correct response a few times.
Yeah. Yeah. I think the next day
it was,
it must have been just genuine panic.
You're a bit like just a panic moment.
She didn't,
she blanked and she had no
idea. You could. I'm sure.
Did you have that in stand up?
The first years we were like,
I don't even know what I'm
saying. I'm so nervous. Course.
It's like when you just press
play on your act and you go like,
I'm just going to just say
what I'm saying. She up.
She was nervous and she's young.
That's miss teen,
but I know that the older broads
they practice, she said the Iraq,
they don't own maps such as
uh, but the older broads,
they rehearsed the questions,
don't they give you worse so you're,
you're rehearsed.
And that to them is the most nerve
wracking event is having a talk. That's,
that's the funniest part to
me is that's the challenge.
I agree. I think the ratings
would pick up significant
Miss Nebraska,
here's six guys who you start with first
I missed Pennsylvania and I can suck
six.
Can I take the challenge?
Wow. We really, there should be
a porn parody of that where they
think there is. Yeah. There has to
be a miss America porns Google it up.
It's a great thing.
Miss America course,
they're triple x parody where
it's like if you want to win,
you've got to blow the judges.
Yep. That's exactly it sounds.
I don't see it. I see
parodies, but, but you don't,
here's the thing with Miss America,
do you win like a,
you want a small amount of money?
It's not life changing.
It's not like you win million. Oh No,
no. But it's, um, the exposure, if you,
if you play that exposure right, it's
also dwindled. It used to be a big deal,
you know,
that was,
that would be front page news the day
after and they would parade her around on
everything is, people just don't
care about it as much anymore.
And I think a big part of that
has been that porn, but no,
the feminist push of the last year,
the growth, you know what I mean?
Where they go, wow, it's seen as
silly now because so many women go,
this is silly. It's women. So we're
saying, well, that, and I think,
I think there was a time
in America where the only,
the only place you could see a,
a hot chicken, a bathing suit,
was during the Miss America pageant.
You know what?
Like maybe in the fifties you're like,
oh shit,
everybody get their dicks in their hands.
The Miss America pageants on
and now it's like there's porn,
there's lad mags. There's,
there's so much exposure to that.
This isn't that what they're called Lad
Fhn and maximum they're called lad mag.
I'm from almost, oh,
they're called Chavez.
Somebody wrote in those boys that talk
like, like have horrible do their accent,
master of accents.
This car,
it lifts off mate.
This call moves columns.
I've never driven a car.
Like
why do you have to make your
teeth kind of bucked out?
Cause they do all English
people have butts.
They're using the queen of
England talk. Yeah, she does all,
I'm the queen of England,
England. Um, everybody,
I started drag dead Tay.
Now that what she does,
she dictates tee time. Of course,
every day she tells me and Drake,
y'all fucking tight. No
wait, what were we saying?
Miss America, that porno.
Did you find it? No, no, no.
But yeah, you don't win a
ton of money and maybe, yeah,
maybe the exposure for like a minute
and people are like, Oh, you're who?
Cool and you wear a crown.
It seems silly now.
So dumb. It seems so, it
also, it seems antiquated.
They feel like,
I feel like millennials are
like what I was Miss America.
What the fuck is Miss America?
Even bathing suits look
silly like bikinis,
the style of them they feel
dated, you know, on the pageant.
I feel like they just feel old timing.
Yeah, they should wear like Brazilian.
I say they should go topless and then
just writing a song like Miss Brazil and
there used to be topless and then a
hole in the front of the front fantasy.
You can see how they shaved their
pizza, the gap close. But show the hair
real interesting.
My Fun.
What if, okay, here's
how they should read you.
They need to remix it to
make it for today's audience,
they need to have miss America like in
revenge of the nerds belching contests
who can light her fart best.
That'd be cool. I have my money's,
I Miss Michigan and then uh,
you know like beer drinking
and stuff like that.
And then the blow bang thing
and then that's the last event.
That's the most important.
And then we have Miss
Idaho saying she can eat
and she's never been with a black guy,
but she's about to blow eight of them.
Here we go, there's Idaho, go ahead.
Or it's Miss Universe
and Miss Amsterdam comes on and she's
like, no, I'm gonna take this shit home.
And she puts candles and or beaver
and does cartwheels and stuff. Yeah.
Pretty cool man.
I'm just suggesting it to them if
they want to get their ratings up,
I think the more that we're exposed
to this what I'm going to play,
they're more that Miss
America becomes like, uh Huh.
This is the newest video on my Oscar
gender terrorist playlists on my channel.
Um,
I'm updating all of my playlist because
they haven't been able to post anything
on time. You would like to know why.
Check out my asked Dakota life update
and we can talk there.
You'll find out. So anyway,
this video is something that
I have consistently said
in my everyday life and I
feel like maybe I need to reiterate and
just maybe I just want to make a video
that I can link people to when I was,
that's cool. I think it is
going to reiterate, reiterate.
I want to reiterate what
I've been saying for awhile.
He sounds like that Tyler Oakley
guy that I love so much. Hey guys,
I have absolutely nothing to say
in the world. I got my haircut.
Yeah Blah Blah Blah. I was like,
well it cuts your out or not
dragging and I'm tired of their
shit so my pronouns are not perfect.
You're not a preference. They are
mandatory for interaction with me.
Are you laughing? Sorry I wasn't, I
didn't see him until you put him up.
Well I'd say actually he looks a
little like he's a larger dude.
He's got a full beard, full beard,
full must. You know we mustache,
it looks like a Septum piercing safety
pin through it, which is normal.
And then he has your aunt Mildred head
wrap arm after she takes a shower.
And, and some taste, full eye makeup,
shadow with the beard. It
goes nice. And my favorite,
I think here as I see either shaved
eyebrows or bleached eyebrows,
which is a sign of total sanity.
That's, I've got my shit together.
He loves horrified and he has a tank on.
He has,
he has manipulated. It's no longer
the tank you bought at the store.
He's, he's cut it. That's obviously with
a scissors. Oh, to make it even lower.
It's very low open tank on the front.
Hasn't waxed the shoulders lately.
Um,
something I need to do to pal. Uh, Dakota.
It's a really neat luck.
So a look, this is America.
How do you feel?
So the code is talking about right now
is that his gender pronouns are not an
option.
Right?
I just expect everyone in the
world to understand my identity.
I barely understand my identity,
my salary.
That's kind of weirdly fusing.
It's an equal to everyone ever to say.
Like I don't understand that either.
So then maybe,
well then here's the thing and I,
if you're not sure what what and who,
maybe hold off on demanding that everyone
stay updated with the pronouns to
refer to you as like maybe hold off until
you've decided and then make a formal
announcement and then stick to it
as an adult. You know what I mean?
One way of looking at it,
right.
I understand someone to respect them
or their wishes so I don't have to
understand what it is to be a black person
to speak respectfully to black people.
I'm pretty sure that you can do the same
for trans people specifically nonbinary
people.
We're not,
that's what I'm talking about because
I don't think there's any problem
understanding trans people
actually think there's
personally. I understand
nonbinary as a non binary person
this week am and I wish you
would respect my pronouns.
I've been eating a lot of oatmeal and
I'm identifying I'm oatmeal gendered.
Okay. Just if you could respect
that. I do respect it. Okay.
Is there honey on it?
Sometimes brown sugar,
sometimes it just, but
it, it just depends.
They're not trendy. We're not
interesting or something that you can um,
fetishize or try to, you
know, just fucking some.
It's just off. Just shut
the fuck up. Just stop.
We're not like so hard and difficult
difficulty mean in inconvenient.
Like imagine what it is to be me and then
you want to tell me how hard it is for
you to understand me and my pronouns.
Like wait,
what wage do you think that's helping
and what way do you think that that's
fucking appropriate?
Stop prioritizing your comfort as a
cis person over the struggles and the
respect and the wishes of trans people.
Your wrong.
So shut the fuck up.
We don't want to hear about how difficult
being around us and knowing us is. He's
not a trans man.
He's saying isn't he saying
he's non good is a good point.
I mean it seems like it's two different
arguments cause there's a trend.
There's, I understand transgendered,
I am a man transitioning to a woman or
I feel more like a woman. I'm a man.
If you live on the loan for the, he's
saying I'm opting out of both. I am non,
I just didn't know that that was
a neither. I didn't know either.
And I'm so happy for you that
you've found that, that thank you.
That is kind of the thing that is nice
for me to celebrate with another non
binary person is that we
get to finally say we are.
We think you mean they know we might sell,
but in your mind I need you.
I hope you're not saying she and
you're in your mind together. Are We?
And we get to,
we get to finally be in a place where
people are so focused on genders.
I know it's so exhausting
that there,
I know everyone's like noise.
What are you, I'm nothing neither.
It's not going to house.
Why don't you know that?
Would that being said, change your
language like no one is female.
No one is born a girl.
No one is any of that.
Like we are assigned genders at birth by
doctors who look at us and see certain
types of Genitalia and decide what our
identity will be from there on out.
That's an act of violence
that should be stopped.
That's not my fucking fault
that that happened and I'm
we, but sex is different than gender.
You're assigned a sex at birth,
he's saying,
but the,
the doctor doesn't assign you a gender
identity that that's what you do.
They certainly do. Well, I'm sorry. Maybe
he, yeah, I thought it was the other way.
I didn't know. No, I guess the doc,
there's your faults prices.
I'm living outside of that, so
yeah. I told her I'm on board
with you dog. I think that
it is an act of violence.
When a doctor sees your penis and
testicles and says, you're a boy,
you know? Yeah. No, I, I know what
you're saying. Sorry. I'm not,
I don't mean to offend
they, it's, it's just like,
I guess I'm being really insensitive here
or a doctor pulls you out. He goes, oh,
we got got a pussy right here.
Has got to be a girl. Ah, no.
Well, how do you, how should we
messed up with Alice? We, we,
we gender identified him as a boy.
I know.
I'm putting him in football outfits
and stuff. Oh No. What shall we do?
We're messing him up.
I conforming to gender
em up the Hash Shit.
Should we start referring to him as them?
And they of course,
I don't want to confuse the kid.
Um, I would keep playing this video,
but I want to tear my fucking
eardrums out so you can. Um,
we'll put up a link to it later.
You know, and here's this, no one,
no one wants to hold anyone back.
I don't certainly deny
anybody whatever they are,
but I think to demand that everyone keep
up to speed with your gender identity
at every given moment. Yeah, I mean,
come on. That's a little unrealistic.
I just don't know what the
proper pronouns are all the time.
I think actually the reality is these
are just confused people, you know,
they're confused. These, I think
the, I think the folks that are like,
I'm astral gendered. No, they
need attention. That's different.
I think when someone's like, I'm a man
trapped in a woman's body that's legit.
Like if you're willing to cut her off
for some of you, but you don't even,
that's a real deal. Even have to go
that far. I think people just feel like,
I don't want it to surgically manipulate
myself, but I am in the wrong body.
I think that's totally,
but I think it's kind of,
it is a lot to ask for
you to look at like me,
like a guy with a beard and it'd be like,
it'd be like be go,
hey man, what the fuck are you? Why
are you calling me a man? I'm like,
oh sorry,
sorry.
Your acts of violence. Like
assuming that I'm a man. Yeah.
You kind of fit all the checkmarks so
yeah man with eye shadow and it's still
going to have you look at the
person we were just looking at it.
Most people would assume that's
a guy wearing eye shadow.
You don't go like that's
probably a nonbinary person.
No, you wouldn't know that.
Why would you assume that? God
Give us Allah, give us all a break.
Give us time to come around to
all the pronouns. We don't know.
The mainstream doesn't know
this stuff. No, no, you can't.
How are we supposed to
know? God Damn. It's a lot.
It's a lot to ask.
I W I wish we could show like my dad or
your dad that video and have them tell
us their feelings. I think I've
pretty much, I think I can sum it up.
What's that guy's a fag.
It doesn't guy does know it. Please. Okay.
I think that's what
everybody's dad would say.
Yeah. P is, he is a,
he's in a lot of pain and that guy,
that guy pacifically looks
like he's in a lot of turmoil.
He does.
He's not doing so well.
And the nails were painted and he
had a bunch of tattoos on his hands.
Like tattooed. I didn't they, they're
like weird marker drawings, you know,
you can deduce that he's in a lot of pain.
Yeah.
So Real,
real heartbreaking news for a
lot of listeners of the show.
Not that,
not Danny obviously,
but the hey hit the hill ever wasn't
bad girl that we played last week,
kicked off of Youtube.
What
some people actually heard her very
logical videos and flagged it as hate
speech.
Hurried him fucking boot.
Just, I don't know if she
was advocating violence,
but she was definitely in the,
uh,
in the school of,
hey,
why does this Hitler Guy have such a bad,
well,
I guess it'd be like isis putting
recruitment videos up on youtube.
We really don't allow that. It's
country. Um, that's, um, that's too bad.
I was really looking
forward to hearing her, um,
her other work on Saddam
Hussein or subscribe.
Jeez.
She's known as the valley on and she,
she had uploaded videos of her singing
happy birthday to Hitler and another
video on how to spot a Jew.
I know we didn't,
we didn't do that.
One other charming videos
include why Hitler wasn't evil,
which is what we played and how feminists
supported rape by causing the migrant
crisis.
That's her name and value
on the valley on a l.
E. V. A. L. I. O. N. She said to be
an 18 year old girl living in Canada.
And she, is she a patriots
cousin? Uh, patriotic.
I Dunno.
Pet put that down like shit.
The teenager openly admitted to
being a Holocaust denier. Oh,
cheese on April 20th. Oh Dude. She looks
like a just a regular teenage girl,
like a sweet blond, blue eyed. No,
she's got a Brunette so she's obviously
not as high up the food chain as she
thinks.
She should know that Hitler wouldn't
appreciate her cause she filmed herself
singing happy birthday in
front of a picture of the
Nazi shit bag as this is how
this is written here. Um,
she had baked for cupcakes,
decorated with swastikas. Um, she,
the channel was terminated
and then Youtube said that
channel was terminated by
us because it violated policies
against hate speech. Thank you.
I value one if I am.
I saw y'all many youtube videos.
Thank you for the cupcakes are delicious.
I please shut your mouth.
I am one of Y'all subscribers.
I enjoyed it very much.
At night I would watch the
videos and frank Stratton,
I played with my Schnitzel as I
listened to with your Schnitzel, dude.
Dude, dude, dude, dude,
dude, dude, dude, dude, dude.
Jamie just fixed my, uh, my uh, website.
He said it was back up.
So anyways, poor value. That's too bad.
She was really doing the Lord's work.
Really doing something there. Jesus.
Man,
what a nut.
She's gotta be mentally
ill, you think so? Um,
I did my own thing by the way.
Uh,
when I was in smear my
juice over the weekend,
I went on a local morning show.
Someone's doing their own thing. Do it.
God doing his own thing.
And uh,
this is one of the great local sports
local sports local shows where they have
the segment, uh, like old school, cheesy
music. This is the clip that I'm on.
It's like Tim and Eric
television credits that include
Conan comedy central live.
It got them like when
they use the old button.
Well that on your website
from 90 to Gotham.
I did it in 2007.
Why are they,
what are they pulling from Wikipedia
or something? Look at this dog shit.
Wow. Oh my God, this is terrible.
The backdrop is dog shit.
American flag. This guy doesn't
have an upper lip. That staff there.
Jesus friends.
A lot of time on stage and this weekend
he's going to be the gay destiny USA,
so we will.
Well, good morning man.
Shout out to Mercer.
Shout out to the Bristol stool chart.
I had number five,
that soft blobs with clear cut edges
cause I need fiber. There you go.
Now I got to ask him right away.
Wait, I got a Bristol stool chart
in there. That was fantastic.
I like how the guys a little
nervous and the woman laughing.
They guy's a little nit was really fun.
She plays, she played along. He was like,
first of all, your outfit looks
amazing. I have on a black,
of course fo fur coat.
People will ask me,
is that Fau for yeah,
you should tell him he paid
$10,000 I would say that if
they asked me on the air.
But yeah,
for the real mommy's.
What about your chain?
That's real shit about to get up
here again expecting a blizzard.
Syracuse obvious. It's just how I
roll man. I wrote like this in July.
I don't care if it's humid.
I don't care if it's 105 were ever,
cause there's an old saying happy hose.
He sad hose don't and I try to stay
happy words to live by obviously.
Second one is plugged. Yeah, she
was, she's fun. When I showed up,
she goes, she goes, oh, I know this
Dj Dad mouth thing and I'm excited.
Oh, that's funny thing. And
instagraming before the show, you know,
Hashtag Dj Dad Mouth,
is that what we should call you?
I mean, I appreciate it. I'm
going to be doing standup,
but my focus is on the afterparty always.
So I'll be tweeting out a
location for a surprise. Oh,
pop up show and youtube both invited.
Oh yeah.
That's like a bonus freebie Friday
party like that.
So, um, Dj dad mouth. I
have a question for you.
Random question guys.
Bear Chrysler so fast.
I love it. She flubs the name
a little. That's the best
for Chrysler.
Kleiser that's a good question.
Why is bear Chrysler so far?
Great. Christ Kaiser so fast.
Yeah. Random question.
Wiseberg Chrysler so fast guys,
let's do this.
Let's do this.
Do you know the mommies
following a strong,
and we have as a community because of
the strength of little followship on this
show, we've made some amazing,
amazing things happen. You guys, we,
we landed brace from Juggalos.
We landed Gloria. Stefan,
just because of how many
of you tweeted her? Yeah.
How about we all this week tweet at
Bert Chrysler who also goes by Bert
Kreischer.
Just ask him why are you saying
and
just that way so fast.
I want him to wake up Wednesday and
log on to his Twitter and be like,
what the fuck?
Just a stream of thousands.
Thousands of people have tweeted
him. Well, why are you so fat
version alcoholic?
He's not.
He's diabetic and he's
on a lot of medication.
He's just a sad,
he's a sad whole.
Like we were just talking about sat hose
I suppose to not eat, but he's so sad.
He's extra and that's my birth. So fat I,
I had to ask [inaudible] I know.
That's what happens
to a comedian. Oh God. What do you
think's coming next? Here we go.
What do you think's coming next?
Million Dollars.
What's the meaning of life or Mary
to a comedian?
Do you guys make each other laugh all
the time? What are you talking about?
You think is going to ask that married to
a weird meeting. Yes. So she's a woman.
So is it, is it like just totally
hilarious at home there? Yeah.
Really low key.
Look at my reaction to that question.
Dead Pan Dj deadpan.
It's a,
you hate that.
A lot of laughs man.
Lot of smells that you smell your house.
So we have a baby. The kids. Yeah,
no it's one kid kid.
But he fought sometimes at all.
He didn't even want it all it takes,
yeah,
I mean there's a lot of action in
the home too. You know, like I got,
I got kids and she doesn't know about.
So sometimes when she's out of the House
I'll bring other kids over that are
older than our baby and they kind of
play in the house. Then they leave.
You know, I do know how it
goes. And speaking of House,
let's talk about your mom's house.
Your mom's house. That's a lot of fun.
It's the best man at your mom's
house. Podcasts. It's where, you know,
it's kind of like, it's, I feel like
this is the Bible for a lot of people.
You know, there's, we cover
the important issues, you know,
like likewhat farts.
We cover how you say that with just
such a straight face. So Mercer,
Mercer was the director. Oh, okay. Okay.
So they said he said something before
we rolled and I go, who is that?
She was as Mercer.
He's right
director. Okay. So that's why I shot
at him. Him All kinds of stuff, man.
We cover what was the thing this week.
But I,
I never had a job in my life until
I started doing this. You know,
I've been in that jail
now you walk around with her,
you know what I'm saying?
And Blend reached the pinnacle and so
good right there. I'm right there man.
My sensei. So Golf, uh,
I was telling me about the Buddha
nature is just to be in the moment.
So that's what I'm trying to do right now.
I think you're doing it really well.
She's grieving in the moment.
If you want to join some funny,
she's really the moment
you can just again,
I her on 30 and nine 45 she was
with you as well. Tomorrow night,
seven 39 45 special engagement
for tickets. Give them
a call for two or three.
She is like six or visit them
[inaudible] Saturday seven 30 shows.
Almost sold out. 11 kids, man.
How do you do it? I got dot. Okay. Yeah.
I don't want to know.
I don't want to know
the full video, uh, of Dj dad mouth in
the spotlight. It was, this one is called,
yeah, your mom is on Youtube.
Then go to our youtube page,
your mom's house podcast and subscribe.
Or we also should mention that not
only can you see all the Dj dad mouth
appearances on our youtube page,
but that we are now
releasing classic jeans. Yep.
Once a week on Youtube.
So those are the original episodes.
People asked us for them
all the time and um,
they're gonna we're
starting with episode one.
Shut up. Yeah. Oh No. How embarrassing.
And it says back from red band days. Yes.
As red band. He said it's cool. Oh my God.
So some of these were videoed back in the
day. Some of them were, yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Wow.
So this is going to be,
yeah, this is going to be
how fucking horrible.
Where are we in episode one?
I bet I'll have mom embarrassed
already. You know what I'm saying? God,
that was the best one yet.
I like that one the best.
I feel like you've perfected how to do
it now. Like now you got your groove,
it's all, it's all your mom's house
nonsense. Yeah. And then they have
really funny how people react
to it who are not, who are,
who know, who know me from
a sand up. Yeah. But not the
podcast. And they're like,
they'll mess would be like,
what the fuck is this? You
know, they don't get
what's going on. Yeah.
That's kind of the enjoyment though
is it's, it's an inside joke,
but it's an inside job with like a few
hundred thousand people who other people
are just like, what is going
on? It's pretty crazy. The
podcast is really growing.
It's really kind of bizarre. Like now
I go around and people are like, Mommy.
And uh, I went to like a baby shower
and some total stranger was like,
I'm a huge mom's house man. Yeah.
What happened to me at the airport,
which is mommy's just so
crazy. It's cool. It's crazy.
Cause we started the show it
just in a Shitty, you know,
in our shitty house in Silver Lake
with the Lithuanian a neighbor.
You know what I mean? Like it's just
neat that it's grown to something.
And we would drive over it
up was burp bank berm. Yeah.
Did we do the first, we did the
first 40 episodes at red man's place.
That's right. A few of them were done.
That's right at the Ice House studio,
but most were done at,
at, at uh, at red band.
So when we started we would do one and
then be like next month we'll do another
one.
Yeah. There was no
schedule, you know? Yeah.
And then we learned that that was
important to drop it on the same day.
It's very important.
People don't know how to find young stuff
and those classic jeans are going to
be released every Thursday
on the youtube channel. Cool.
So there is a schedule for that too.
There's always something
fun at the Youtube Channel.
There's like behind the scenes
and on top of that, uh,
petrout launches June 1st.
So if the,
if you don't know,
Patriot is going to be our new
all access added bonus content,
um,
subscriber based site that a we do
behind the scenes stuff and we do extra
episodes.
Well we have one bank that is going to
come out in June that you can only do if
you sign up for Patriot on,
you basically do like a small,
you pick your monthly donation and based
on the the donation you get access to
different things. So it's a cool
thing. It helps us, um, you know, uh,
keep doing the show and uh,
and you'll get,
you'll get access and
you'll get extra content.
One of the things we're definitely going
to do is a watch Steven Seagal movies,
um, and comment on those. But, uh, the
first one was just a cool episode. We did,
we answered it. Fan Mail questions.
Yeah, it was fun. All right. Um,
hydrea hydrea hey, can we do
my Persian voicemails? Yeah.
So tell us what happened
with the, with you got more
voicemails, right? Well, yeah,
they kind of kicked into high gear this
weekend. I'm not sure what happened.
I'm here, I've saved them. I've,
I've actually had to put this number in
as a contact now because I get so many,
yeah, I've gotten one,
two, three since Wednesday.
Let's here it's called Persian legged.
Out of that, take it out of the,
out of the case. Yeah. Hold on. I've had,
I call it Persian lady now
because like I get so many,
[inaudible] has been getting a lot of
job offers in Texas and she's not getting
those. What about atus? So eight is,
we actually found out his real name
because somebody tried to log in then you
want them up and I looked,
ate us up and he is exactly who
I thought he would be like a,
he looked how I thought he would. He's
like a hipster do with Lego, you know,
like a white guy with an
ironic kind of t shirt.
Um, so the first one is last Wednesday,
right? Come here. Yeah, it's,
it's under Persian lady and it
starts on Wednesday. She says here,
hey live.
Which I dunno to add bacteria
to be modest. Don't have it. Yeah. Anyway,
I'm just telling you to take care of you.
A 50 oh he don't be doing good.
Still. Call him to them. Yes.
What the fuck man? How
are you doing? Good. Ben.
Solomon never calls you
back. Never. Never. Never.
I know.
[inaudible] some are in Arabic.
Nicona Hall.
This is the Thursday one. When that
was Wednesday before it. Before.
Here's Thursday. Yeah. Thursday. Yeah
I am. Hi Mommy. Dandelion. We should jag.
[inaudible] now that door
we call Mikey cottages.
[inaudible] a little snow badge. I'm
let me know. What are you feeling?
What are you doing?
What's up?
[inaudible] magnet going in and we can of,
so then coming back to your homies
and shit. I'm telling you man,
call me [inaudible] you need
anything? Call you. Okay,
but isn't there a point,
this is what I keep saying is it isn't
there a point through all these phone
calls when you never get, cause you
never obviously gets the call back.
There has to be some point where he's,
maybe she sees Salami and then
at that point isn't it like,
isn't there ever an exchange about hey,
you know how you get my
message about that, or yeah,
my medicine or I told you that yesterday
and then you know what might happen?
Is it Salamay might be so sick that when
this person see Salamay and mentions
that insomnia goes, you didn't fucking
call me. They go to me so crazy.
Right now she's, she's got
dementia. She's, you know,
she doesn't even know that
I called her earlier. Wow.
I see. I think Solomon is our
age. Do you think so? Yeah.
For some reason I think this is a maternal
figure to Salome and this might be
like a kid and that's why I've
always pictured sodomy is all, no,
I think [inaudible] is younger
and that's why she kind of gives,
I think it's a boy to a pass
because all, you know, Silo May,
he's always out having fun.
And then here's Friday. Yeah.
Yes. Oh man, that ass, I mean
Arigato Heidi, Daniel as one line.
I mean n e m
a new area clean only bacterial AskPat
and maybe I believe in that software.
Can I'm, I'm good. I'm
back to normal again.
I don't have any new [inaudible].
I know.
Whichever one spending gives it up all
in bacteria in your body and from the EEC
is from inside you as no holiday.
I'm telling you my little too.
Okay.
Do you get it?
Yeah. See it's, it's a, I
think she's an attorney,
was going to give it up.
All the bacteria in your body
and strongly easy is from inside.
You know, holiday. I'm telling you
my little tool kit. Okay. Do you
imagine Jack, he has lots of information
again to give you a ride there.
Can you take care of what
one of you talk to some cause
plants you shouldn't eat. Just how bad.
Crazy bright there. The answer's probably
like, motherfucker, that's 400 messages.
Well the thing is they're clearly
communicating in between because she knows
salamis not feeling well and it's
a bacterial infection. Right? And,
and she keeps asking about the lease.
This is the second or third
thing about a lease agreement.
So maybe he's in real estate or
something or they're renting a property.
She's kind of all that bacteria though,
man.
You gotta you gotta get rid of that
bacteria from the inside out. I like that.
She specified that from the outside.
[inaudible] Sullivan.
Tallow may take the fucking bills.
Jesus wanna know Solomon,
you should tell your mom that you
changed your number, buddy. Yeah.
Should we call him personally lady back?
I think at this point maybe we should
just do it on your mom's house. What?
We do it right now. Oh, I'm
so nervous. What do we say?
I mean, do you want to just, we shouldn't
keep this going to tell them was sick.
Okay. All right. Let's call
the Persian lady. Oh my God.
Alright. Hopefully what happens
so nervous. Talk to her.
I feel like we know each other.
I know.
Do you speak Farsi? I speak for, I see it.
She's not answering. Check. She doesn't
recognize a Skype number. I know.
Okay.
Say, let's call from my phone, but
then how do we record the call?
Oh,
that is fucking voice.
That's her voice mail.
Always feeling message. Three
meows. Dude. Are we being pranked?
Maybe it's somebody's fucking with us.
That could be,
give me your phone. I'm going
to try it from your phone. Yeah,
but then we want to record the
call in case. Solemnly answer.
She answers what will
should not be able to,
we can't record this on for your mom's
house. We can't. How can we record?
I don't understand why that
wouldn't record though. Wait,
if you call from my
phone, I don't know. Shit.
I think it would still recall you're
plugging in. Oh, I see what you're doing.
Yeah, I can try that.
Yeah. Let's see. Do you,
that was the craziest fucking
voicemail ever. Three meals.
This woman's out of her mind.
That's why she doesn't know of Salo
may calls her back. That's right.
She's fucking crazy. Dude.
That's so true. Let's see.
So you have this word [inaudible].
Oh my gosh. Wait, are you going to,
are you going to do it on? Not on
speaker phone. Oh, there you go. Hello.
You have to wait for someone to pick
up first before you say Hello Dad. No,
I had the uh,
hello.
Yeah, I pushed the buttons. How are you
not gonna Answer Solomon Calling? Yeah,
just keep it going.
Raising. Well, now here's the thing. We
just, yeah, we told him he just can't it.
Bang. Yeah. We just get back up there.
Shit. We just tried to put an end to end.
Now we've made a wide, you're going
to get a definite fucking, uh,
know she voicemail my legs. I
saw man, I miss the fucking car.
Oh yeah. Three me hours. Three meows man.
And I feel like it was her
making the Miao sounds.
I don't think that was a cat there.
No, Babe. I don't think that was a cat.
Jesus. Oh, it's crazy.
Yeah. She's real crazy.
How's intense?
Oh, so weird. Is that my
friend Sarah could be steroids.
Are you doing this? She's a
big meal. I saw them. Yeah.
Make CD downstairs. I know. We got to play
at one day. We've made that years ago.
I know when we were touring.
Yeah.
We actually went into a recording studio
and meowed songs with Sarah Burns.
It was fun.
They still remember me when I went back
to record to to like do my comedy album.
My second one. They're like, I
remember you. You did the meal songs.
Hey can we talk about my shit yesterday?
Oh,
okay.
Uh,
what you act like we don't talk
about the stuff on the show
next door.
Brown Todd Brown jar coming up.
Okay.
I just have a question for you.
Sure.
So okay,
I'm going to explain the situation and
then you kind of tell me your thoughts on
it.
Like I'm going to walk you through it.
So I was alone with ls. It was Sunday
morning. You hadn't come home yet.
Right? And I drank, my company
selling guy was out drinking.
You were out getting hammered partying.
How'd you come home yet?
Hadn't come home yet.
You're worthless guy.
And then I drink my coffee so I usually
get my cup of coffee ready. I drink it.
I go in to get Ellis in the morning. I
wake him up, I feed him, I diaper him,
I bring him downstairs and
then I feed the dogs. Anyway,
I go on to Alyssa's room and I've already,
I'm like three quarters of the way
through my coffee. I don't really do that.
Normally I feed him and just
as I'm about to change him,
I feel the urge to shit. The problem is,
and you know this since I've given birth,
is that I have a really hard time
holding in my stools and that they go,
it's immediately, we'll have to
shit now I really have the shit.
And so I was like panicked trying to
change his diaper and like I change him.
I'm like Oh my God. Oh my God,
I'm going to shit my pants.
I didn't know what to do.
My back was hurting so I couldn't just
put them in the crib and go shit cause my
backup fucked up in tennis. So I'm like,
oh my God, what do I do? So I hurry,
I diaper him. I, we know run
downstairs, I put them in the swing,
I strapped him in and then I go
take a shit downstairs. Right.
And it was a lot.
It was like a number four and it was
like two number four logs. Yeah. There,
here's the problem.
I went to wipe and it was like a fucking,
like a melted Hershey's
kiss in the toilet paper.
It was so narrowly, I like, you
know when you do that first why but,
and you're like, oh my God.
Yeah. Oh my God, that is so much.
And now normally I would just go into
the shower and fuck my stoma. Yeah.
But thankfully the other day and I just
bid day the shit out of it and then like
shit out of my shit and
then I wiped it clean.
But why do you think that happens to me?
Do you think that that's a uh,
post-pregnancy thing?
Does that happen to you ever?
Well,
first of all,
I just want to say I'm really glad you
asked this question and I appreciate all
the details. Um, that was really
matter because it was, it was good.
It was because I held it in a little bit
longer than I normally would came out
mushy. Yeah. That's interesting.
Um, I think, you know,
it's a real neat, the, that you,
that you told us all those details,
pool pool. Um, but that's
pertinent to the case Brown lock.
It's not like random. It's
a good point. Um, yeah,
I think it's a combination
of you probably you were,
you said you were holding it in, you're
probably drinking coffee. Yeah. Um,
and you know,
maybe maybe a little bit
of what you ate at the,
at the previous meal. Do you remember?
Do you recall what you ate? Yes.
Counselor. What did you have?
Well, Brown previous meal,
Brown luck.
I went to a Vegan baby shower or
vegetarian baby shower and I had a lot of
different bean varieties and I think
that may have contributed to my powerful
for yeah. And the coffee too,
definitely contributed to,
he makes it different. Holding it in. I
think the holding it in was really cool.
What you're saying is, yeah, it's a
combination of things is holding it in.
It's gonna make it worse though.
Wait, but why is the
wipe, it wasn't diarrhea.
So why was the wipe so
unclean? That's like,
I'm serious.
Why am I not pinching off alone?
Clean the machine. It was mushy. You
didn't have just normal logs, right? No,
you couldn't have, they were fours. They
were perfect. I mean words are perfect,
perfect logs. They were a little hotter
than normal, but I don't know if that,
yeah,
they're an exemplary for like
if you kind of look at this,
they were a little hotter
and a little more torn,
but that heat means that they weren't
perfect because perfect ones aren't hot.
Hot indicates that it's a
little higher up on that scale.
You're probably looking at like a
five and a five and a half, you know,
broken pieces. There were a solid.
But if their heaters like that,
that means something's up that you know,
you can always tell the heat
factor means this is not 100%
and I think it probably has to do with
the fact that you were having a lot of
veggies.
And I'll tell you what happened to me.
I was in smear my juice and I went,
I had three,
four meals at a Vegan restaurant and
I got to say I really enjoyed it,
man. Really, really enjoyed it. It was,
it was good food and I didn't do it
because I was on some mission to eat that
way. It was purely out of
convenience and then it was good.
So I stayed at a hotel
and right next door,
let's see,
I'll see if I can plug the place,
see what you get back to you.
But what you're saying that the log was
a little hot and torn and that's why it
just wouldn't break clean
because of the texture on hearts.
A lark strong hearts cafe is where I went.
But I'm asking you,
it's the texture of the law.
You're saying something that could
clench it off and leaves behind Mush.
You held loud. He had mud
but, and then I know those,
I know those, you know the, the real
blessing and in the skies was though.
What's that? That you were home.
I know I've had those in public
cause then you're wiping and wiping and
wiping. AndW and then somebody goes,
can I eat your ass and go, you
sure you want to do that, right?
It happens every night. The Persian,
he's calling back, calling back.
Oh. Oh my God. Oh my God. Fuck.
How did my phone just shut down?
So weird. We're definitely going
to have a voicemail right now,
man. Anyway, so the phone starting,
tell me more about your brand's
story and then we'll go back. Well,
so I ate these vegan meals.
First of all,
I just want to give a plug
to Vegan eating for a second.
They were delicious meals at, like I
said, strong hearts cafe in Syracuse,
smear my juice. And secondly, um,
it has doubled when you eat vegan
and it's good. You just feel good.
I was feeling good after meals. That's so
bad. Venus, you know, there's no bloat.
There's no like, uh, hitting you like, uh,
you know, when you
travel. Yeah. Road food.
You can even go to a great restaurant
and be like, Oh God. Oh yeah. So much,
you know, heaviness to it. You know,
the truth of it is the less you eat,
the better you feel. And the
lighter you eat. More veggies,
more fruits. But his real, she
left a voicemail. Oh, okay.
Let's hear it. Um, fuck
can, I do want to say this.
I didn't have crazy dumps.
Really. I had a lot of farts. Huh?
Dude, it's shutting down
again. That's weird. This so,
but you didn't have a crazy
dump after four vegan meals.
Yeah.
Isn't that crazy?
I think you need to wait a little bit
because you really react poorly to
veggies. Right. But I didn't, I'm
saying I had normal bowel movements,
but a lot of farts. I mean, oh
Huh.
That's a neat story. Yeah. I mean
it was,
it was note worthy. Can I tell
you my favorite new game that, um,
ls plays with us is pull daddy's beard.
Oh my God.
It makes me laugh.
Florida just, I hugged me.
Absolutely love it when he hugs
my face. So flea takes both. Hey,
he has a strong grip and he
pulls me towards him by my beard.
It's so painful and the only person on
earth that I wouldn't punch in the mouth
of doing it is my son.
Everybody else I would stab immediately,
but he pulled me. I'm like,
ah, it's so funny. Drags me.
And then you go his mouth. Well,
something's going on with this.
When I plug it in, it shuts down. Yeah.
Mean I could try it again. That's bizarre.
But that's happened twice right now.
So I wonder what's going on. Let's see.
You Shit. So how are we going to play
Salamay if it shuts down every time. No.
Okay. It didn't shut down right
there. Okay. Um, let's see.
She's gonna be pissed. Oh, she's
going to be pissed. Here we go.
Let's see. Not playing. I bet there.
Yeah. She left for a second
voicemail, but it's not playing.
[inaudible] [inaudible] bacteria.
Yeah.
I not plain bacterial
infection. Is it on, you know,
the line is working. It's
so weird. I know. Planned.
Gosh. See, this is why
we need blue ban here.
Why don't you just unplug it and push
play and put it up to the microphone. Oh,
again, it started it
again. No, no, no. Oh,
the pub in the Della Mae
measured [inaudible].
Bizarre. Bizarre, bizarre, bizarre. No,
I remember playing the Shish
Kebab and Kabobs. Ah, who
knows. Why don't we try it?
Try It on yours. Hold on Mommy.
Let's see. Okay. Persian lady
[inaudible] by the body. Oh yeah.
It's weird now it's not playing. Yeah.
Wow. Fuck it. Okay. Well, uh, let me
restart the phone. Maybe that'll help.
Oh well hold on. Give it a minute. Is
My phone still like starting? Okay,
let's give it, I'm not complaining.
It's definitely going to be like,
what the fuck? Yeah, she's going to
go but to business a what the fuck?
Solomon is, the other guy was
a fucking call back. Okay.
Let's see if I can play another
one. In the meantime, um,
have, so if you really are looking
to up your fart game. Yeah.
Maybe e V as you go forward.
How's King asked ripper are doing.
We haven't really checked in with him
in a while. Oh, it's been a long time.
Been a long time. He's a, I
mean he's still the master.
I don't know. She'll be on youtube
or is he kicked off right now?
He always goes back and forth.
Man,
let's see you to see if he's there.
King S.
Hmm.
Anyways, I love Alice new game with you.
That shit makes me laugh so hard, dude.
I love that. He just tortures you so
funny. And then he pulls my hair too,
which is awesome. Every time you
lean down to give him a Zuber,
he pulls your hair. It's so fun
to get to sign in to see this one.
It's always a good sign.
Yeah.
Let's see what I want to have
to sign in and I know Ma.
Hello Ma. Can we talk about,
look, if she calls back. Yeah,
just to answer on speakerphone.
You know,
I think he's missing
Dan.
I wasn't Raunchy as far.
Okay, there you go. Yeah,
this is King Ash. Unofficial,
so I don't think that's his page.
We don't subscribe to it and goes,
he wouldn't go by that. Let's
see. Here he is. Oh, I love it.
The stairs,
those set ups are the best
now. He's so clever. Yeah.
Well. Um, yeah he was, the only thing
that sucked about was trying to,
he was like the lochness monster cause
it was switching accounts under a new
name area and grows king asked ripper
the FARC guide or whatever. You know,
he's always something and I wish we
could just lock down where he's at,
you know. Well you, some people
don't want the fame and the glory
that being on your mom's house brings.
Okay.
Yeah.
We have made people famous on the show
and maybe he doesn't want that and that
kind of spotlight the limelight. But
do you feel like he was doing that? Um,
before he was on like he was always
switching accounts? I don't know. Yeah,
maybe he's crazy too.
That's not a normal cause.
What was the other site that used to
have all the time live leak, leak? Well,
let me see if I can play
this. Hold on. Yeah.
Now my voicemails fucked up word.
Oh it was, I fart in Yo face. I
used to be his right. His thing.
Oh Man.
It's like, yeah, it's true.
It's really like trying to track down
like a mythical creature or something. No.
Well that's the beauty of him.
That's the,
let's see if he's back on there.
Nope.
The account associated with this channel
has been terminated for copyright
infringement.
Why was that possible?
His farting that. Are they trying
to say that those aren't his farts?
I doubt. Yeah. She's at the door
though. She's going to, yeah.
I don't know if she's just sniffing
now. That's not an, I have to.
Okay.
Peace Now. We just had to replace a
couch because of her as fucking dog.
You know that we just got the new
couch on Sunday cause she ran,
she took a pen and ate
up a brand new couch.
So we got in living room,
inked it all up by chewing it on the
cushion and drawing it and it was the,
I'll tell you have, you know, every time
you buy something now where people go,
Oh, do you want a warranty? You know,
and try to sell you. If you buy,
if you buy a fucking an
extension cord that best buy,
they'll go to one of the warranty. You
pay this money, you're like, no dude.
But with this couch we did it and
the week or two after we bought it,
there's just ink everywhere and it was
actually worth it to have them throw once
and now we've replaced an entire couch
and thank God we bought that warranty.
Thank God we'd be stuck with that
couch and I wouldn't buy another one.
No ridiculous. Yeah, no, we just have
our ink stained couch. I know. And now I,
I bought insurance on that.
The replaced couch just to me.
Oh my God. Oh my God.
Okay. What are you doing?
No idea what Solomon is up too,
Huh? No, I stopped playing.
Well, we're just going to
have to figure this out later
and you want to show
you something? Yeah. Um,
tell me what you think of
this.
Told me I can't come to fucking
Prentice. Fuck you. Fuck you. I came here.
You want to fucking sell it right now?
Do it on the fucking table.
You fucking beat me. No, fuck
no. Fuck you motherfucker.
Fuck you.
Huh? This is a normal arm wrestling
match. Okay. It's pretty intense.
A little,
it's really fired up this guy.
You were fat, stupid scheming
on my fucking ass. Bitch.
Bring your fucking shit.
Fucking kill your fucking shit. I ain't
scared. Scary Shit. I'm fucking here. Huh?
You told me I couldn't fuck coastal
something out. Bitch. Come on.
Fucking spitting on you bitch.
Can't take that shit. Fuck you.
Fuck y'all were you called
them on my tone bitch.
Wear a condom on my Tony.
You know it's fun.
You get that jacked up now
you don't win. Oof. Oh yeah.
This guy's full of rage at arm wrestling.
Maybe a more aggressive Ah,
a sport that you can utilize.
Pretty aggressive sports.
Higher Body. Yeah, but he's,
he wants to punch him right now.
I think this soggy needs out.
She's being a little weird. Okay. Okay.
Let me, uh, let me let her go. All right.
The bachelor's. You took her
out. She went pee pee. Um,
let's finish this arm wrestling.
Stupid dog. I'm really anxious.
I think the guy that's losing
his mind is going to lose.
I didn't want to fucking filled out
all the table. The Shit.
All the fucking table. Big,
small. The motherfucker. I'm not fucking
invited. You're not fucking invited bitch,
Huh?
Yeah.
Shit.
I'm on the phone.
No
kidding.
What happened?
He lost the match and then
he swung at the fuses.
That is fucking hilarious.
Wow.
He got thrown on the ground.
Oh my God.
Oh my God. These are crazy. Somebody, uh,
they've got their panties in a bunch,
you know.
Fuck. You're wearing it on
your phone. I'm on my toes.
Yeah. Jeez. I feel like
that all the time. You know,
aggressive. No, just like I
want condoms on my tongue.
It was good down or you know,
stupid. As the master of accidents.
I'm always looking at studying
other accents. This guy,
he's Asian.
I'm at the stay away fishing and yeah,
I never seen shit like this before.
Okay. Yeah. Agent. I'm black bolts
with goddamn serious talent. Blacks.
This shit.
You Never Asian people
talking black like that.
Oh, it's Texas now.
It's for Shanaze let it go. Of course.
I'm going to let it go. This is like,
this is an Asian guy. Oh my
God. Watch this shit. Why?
It's weird.
Here he is again.
I want you to know that this man did
this shit with biting our nails and not
paying a nail all living. You all
need a medic, you but this shit.
So the guy is a nail tech.
Hilarious. He's like,
he's like two nephrons stereotypes in one.
It's amazing.
It's incredible.
Amazing.
You don't see that usually you don't
see that many Asian dudes talking back
talking black. He's just
sounds southern, right? Oh No,
I think he sounds like Medea.
I think he's doing a Medea and you know
used to watch all her movies and the
dead and you haven't put one out in oil.
You never talk about him anymore.
Well I haven't had much time with the kid.
The baby kind of messed up my
Medea watching. But you know,
you and I got into a show and to the
Americans and there's a guy on there,
Gregory, who I recognize. I
thought, I know this guy's
face, man. It was killing me.
I looked it up and he was in a Medea
movie. That's how I know him from.
You were saying that I recognize them too,
but it wasn't from a dia,
so as I was like, what would we see for
it? You Go, Oh yeah, Medea. I'm like, no,
it's not what I'm talking about.
You would know from that.
I don't know what's up with Tyler
Perry. I haven't heard of it. I just,
I just haven't heard. I'm sure
he's still doing a million things.
He produces tons of very successful
as jeans are always up there.
I like the Medea Christmas stuff
and I love Madea goes to jail.
I think the, no, the family reunion.
That one's actually my favorite one.
That's your favorite one?
Yeah, my Angela's in it.
You know that she's in the
Maya Angelou that yes. Yup.
She's like black Yoda. She fucking
tells him what's up. It's awesome. Oh,
you wanna read some Fan Mail? I
do, yeah. Go ahead. Okay, hold on.
Oh, there we go. Look at this guy.
Been using your Amazon link to buy stuff
for a while. How about a shutout for us?
Buying Lube? Yeah, you got
it. We, that's so weird. Okay.
64 ounces. She keep my Ding Dong.
It's what he says. How do you say?
Amazing. Thank you Chris. Thank you.
Thanks Chris. Um, we've got another one.
I'm a bisexual polyamorous
bear with two boyfriends.
I'd be happy to answer literally any
questions also, I love your show so much.
I would not hesitate to marry it and make
it part of my poly pile. Smack Hound.
Thanks. Smack Erin. Yeah.
Can I ask you something?
Polyamorous bear with two boyfriends
now you refer to them kind of equally to
boyfriends.
I understand in the,
in the polyamorous community you
say you have your, that's his,
he was looking right. Oh Geez.
Am I my phone case? Great. Uh,
but usually they say I have
a primary and a secondary,
but I noticed that you kind of equate
your two boyfriends. So how has that work?
I would ask that. Good question. And
why don't you read the third one? Yeah.
When Christina was talking
about European nudity,
I was just chuckling,
but I can say with a lot of certainty
that Polish people both in Poland and
living in the UK would freak out if
you are walking around and just your
underwear. Nudity is Devo, not normal.
Maybe they were in it called
hippie in the cult. Slash. Hippy.
It sounds funny though. Piece and much
love Malar I think. No. Yeah. Well listen,
uh,
me Milosh I am not a fucking Polak.
I'm Hungarian and I tell you,
if you go to Hungary and you go to the
[inaudible] hotel and you go to a thermal
bath, uh, which is the most popular
thing you can do in Budapest,
that you have to go nude budget.
What Mila is pointing out is then
we're really adamant about European,
European, European euro. No.
Did any Europe in Europe,
US Europeans in Europe.
Here we are all naked all the time.
And was telling you that
that is not the case.
Also too, I believe we're just
more comfortable with nudity.
And I say that because look,
you try the TV at 10:00 PM in Europe,
Western Europe, you know, and there's
tents on TV and commercials for like,
you know,
fucking lollipop commercials.
There's a girl with her
tits out or whatever.
So I'm just saying,
and there's tits and magazines like
normal magazines in England. By the way,
those lad mags, yeah, they
show their tits. Okay.
Okay. So, uh, yeah.
MMM.
Why don't you read the,
this one?
Hi, Mommy's here too. Hi, Mommy's,
I noticed you guys talking about
flippers on a few of the last episodes.
So for those of you don't know what
those are, flippers are like retainers.
What is she doing now? Do you hear
her course out here? Does she,
who fucking knows?
We just have a distracter uh,
flippers are like fake teeth. Uh, it's
a retainer with a tooth or two on it.
And that's what people do. Instead of
replacing teeth, they'll get a retainer.
And I had a cousin that did that for
a few years. So this person writes,
I make a lot of these pieces of
shit as I work for a dental lab.
You would not believe what some trashy
people ask for with these things.
Some include gold front
teeth with dollar signs.
Some even want a picture of their
ugly kids put on. Oh my God.
Like they're proud to show off how
poorly they take care of their teeth.
Feel free to ask any more questions
you have in the dental world.
I'm also poly by,
and when I tell people how it worked,
they look at me like I just burped in
their faces anyway. High and tight.
You fellow mommy. Nick. Hello. Oh,
that's so finally hate Hitler.
Yeah.
Longtime listener from the days you
lived in the ghetto and your neighbor's
stench would come through your
walls. Yup. It's been so long.
That's how I remember the story. Being
a gay man and having many bear friends.
See, I would have to say Tom is
definitely a California grizzly
care. He is very comfortable
with his primitive ways,
marking his territory with his boogers
and making brown ferocious. Yeah.
Throughout the day. Otherwise we
would just call him a Pooh bear. Yeah,
because he is cuddly and
likes to eat a lot. You sure?
Oh my gosh. You know, it's weird.
I was reading Winnie the
Pooh last night to the kid.
Oh,
it has the noise box. That's one
of them. One of them in the store,
like Winnie the Pooh sees his friends
and I thought you're the Pooh bear. You
do remind me of pool. Yes sir. Yes, sir.
Equine diarrhea, diarrhea.
Is that on there? Oh yeah,
I would have added a died down.
Well, I don't know. Why is it just
the music? I don't know. That's weird.
I don't know.
First we have to understand
the characteristics of
normal equine to Kate fecal
balls,
loose stool Spico balls that have excess
water before or after the application.
Cow Pie, watery diarrhea or
even projectile diarrhea,
projectile diarrhea,
fecal matter or fecal fluid that's dried
on the horses. Russia, crime, diarrhea.
Wayne,
diarrhea,
diarrhea by an access of water
or fluid in the horse's stool.
Darn. That's a good, yeah, it's good.
Yeah. Yeah. Let's see.
Another one. Another page. No.
Let's see. Go old school here.
Oh my God. These are old.
Real old.
Watch your profanity.
There's the Atlantic Ocean
and the Pacific Ocean.
But some of you pronounced
specific as Pacific.
The word is specific.
The ocean is Pacific.
Okay.
Some of you
a man. There's a lot. Yeah,
that's
a good one. Jj. Jj, JJ,
Jj fish. Yeah. Yeah.
He's really no profanity.
Oh, shark. Kesha,
remember it's Turkey
just showing right there.
Sharky Kesha.
No.
Sharkey Sharkey's
no,
it was good.
But he supposedly mine.
He's supposed to be money.
He supposedly Meninga Sharkey Shit.
But he supposed to mean,
oh my gosh.
He's so
honestly supposedly,
man,
I gotta you have to wipe down he
Sharkey shirt or no,
where did, um, she's, I forget her name
that says me. See? Yeah, we met her,
right? Yeah. Do you see, I think yeah,
we actually get to the reader. So amazed.
What is amaze is that you made that
song. Yeah. It was a really good, um,
there's so many funny people
who listen to this show,
this board. Yeah. The board. So much fun.
White Tigress and yeah.
Yeah,
I remember that. Yeah. Watch
out for Fran and so much stuff,
man. We've done the
show a long time. Yeah.
This is so funny. God, choking and
gagging is certainly a turnoff.
And giving a great blow job doesn't
require that to reenact a deep throat porn
scene.
It's,
Oh Paul do put your Dick between your
legs is that right there and the angel of
the Lord Show Dick Between your legs.
You're going to start with the tip of
your tongue on the top right side of the
head of his penis. You're going to
cross over the shaft to the left side,
the testicles over to the right,
and your ego is bevel of the shaft to the
left side. And then you're gonna suck.
Okay?
Then you're going to take the tip of your
tongue that's of the head of Red Cross
over this shaft,
the right testicle over to the left hand.
You mentioned the Tamar is leaving dude.
The A,
the ta or the real. The real, yeah.
There's the real of the talk. I
don't know. I can't remember now.
You've watched it. I
have, I, you know, again,
having a kid puts you on a fucking warrior
hall and you miss out on everything.
Uh, but yeah, so she was on, I think
it's the real Loni love who I love,
who's a great friend. Uh,
yeah. Uh, is on that show.
And then there's like, oh, and also
what's her name? One of the twins.
The famous twins from the stupid sister.
Sister show comp drop balls.
Yeah. Yeah. They're a full game ball.
Did that guy was in our old neighborhood
and rampart. Yeah. Anyways, so much.
Why is she leaving?
You're the one who told me.
Well I saw, I saw a, an
article about it that said,
um, you know their parting ways. They did.
They did a one of those joints statements.
You know,
she got the all the pair on that,
um,
shout out to all the payer to all the
hair. Let's see if it's in
this here. Hmm. Braxton? No,
not there. Um, did I not texted to you?
Uh, you, I didn't see the story.
I didn't have a minute too, but I,
you've just had a tamer is
leaving the view. I mean, yeah,
I keep calling it the wrong show.
It's the real,
and I'm curious to know if it's cause
she got a better offer or she wants to
tour. I know she just
on Instagram, she goes,
I'm finally back and she was performing,
singing. It is the real, but she was,
she's like, I haven't sang
in six months. I'm like,
how far do you don't think for six months
unless you're sick or something. Yeah.
Okay.
Let's see.
You had a bio pic coming out
lifetime called Toni Braxton.
Unbreak my heart.
MMM.
Smell my farts.
Were you in the creative process? You
know, outside of writing the book,
I didn't want to be involved creatively
because [inaudible] is on the page. Okay.
It says buy.
Now.
You probably have heard that Tamar Braxton
has been cut from daytime panel talk
show the real well,
there has been major speculation
as to why the singers says betrayed
as to who betrayed her.
Oh.
Potentially leading to her getting fired.
New Port shut may not have
been any of her co host.
After on the day before the day
before the joint statement came out,
she posted on her Instagram that she
trusted somebody that she shouldn't have,
who betray,
who betrayed her.
Wow. I wonder, according
to the jasmine brand,
all four remaining cohos were blindsided
by the news of Tamar. His departure,
a source said they were completely left
in the dark and are devastated by the
news since they all truly
got along behind the scenes.
The lady's allegedly didn't even know a
show issue statement was being put out
to the public.
Also,
even if they're remaining host band
together to stop this decision for moving
forward. They couldn't, since they each
have their own individual contract,
which causes them to have
different compensation Blob,
I'm guessing it's money.
Yeah, it's always money. She probably
wanted a lot of money. I don't blame her.
She's kind of the the star,
you know.
Right. Yeah. I mean, cause the, the
joint statement came out and said,
you know, uh, we're,
we're parting ways and all this stuff
and like we wish her the best and she was
half, but it was one of those
things where, see earlier,
this is before she the the statement,
I love you all,
but I've been stabbed in the back
by someone I stupidly trusted. Oh,
not my man or my sisters.
I am not about to be tried
and tested to snitch.
And it's not in a good taste to tell
you who, but as you Tara [inaudible] no,
you're very smart. You can figure
things out on your own. Uh,
and then it goes on and on.
But,
but the day after that she got the boot.
Wow. Yeah. Cheers. Cause
this is a bullshit statement
here. Read this statement.
This is,
um,
okay.
This is what Henry and here it says,
the real and Tamar Braxton have
mutually decided that Tamer will not be
continuing with the show for
its upcoming third season.
She will be leaving in order to
concentrate on her solo career.
Everyone is so state of
the Real, associated with
the real appreciates Tamar,
his efforts and the contributions she has
made to the show's success and we wish
her all the best for the future. Wow.
Well that sounds like some bullshit.
Okay.
How different she looks. Yeah. She's,
I mean, she's had a lot of work done.
You got to work, work, work, work, work,
work. Got To do work on your face, face,
face.
She looks like a totally different human.
She really does. Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Well you never let me get like
that when I started out with this.
Really sad if you did that
to yourself. Hmm. Really Sad.
If you did that to yourself, that's
just a sign of losing your mind. See,
now I'm curious. I got to ask
Lonnie on the downlow one. Yeah.
Well then you can't report it here
though. Cause it's gotta be, I gotta know.
I know.
She told me that they got along.
I've heard that they get along on the
show. I believe that it's just, you know,
like fortunate. All right. Um,
we got to get going here. This.
I'm so excited to play for you.
Uh,
one of our very talented listeners.
Let me get the uh,
the name right here.
Jordan Wolf took previous Salo
may voicemails and made a song.
Wow.
So here is Salamay by Jordan
Wolf featuring Brian days.
Um, and that's going to be our
song for the week going out.
Thank you guys very much for listening.
Please go to your mom's house,
podcast.com also,
don't forget the youtube channel,
youtube.com/your mom's house podcast,
new content. Um, uh, click
classic jeans every Thursday.
All the videos that we play,
we put them up and patro starts June 1st.
Don't forget to sign up for that.
Please go to Tom segura.com for tickets
to my live shows and go to thousand
ranch.com for tickets to Christina's
a tweet at Bert Kreischer. Why are you
so fat? Hashtag [inaudible] is fat.
Let's get that trending hashtag whereas
red bird as bad that and uh, that's it.
Fat Part.
Thanks guys.
Me
that Farsi Lanes
Buddy John.
Tricia.
The most amazing part of these messages
that Christina keeps getting non stop on
her phone to me or the person who's
leaving never hears back from whoever.
She's kind of her thing.
Whoever you're contacting hates you.
How about you? Just so you guys aren't
friends, there's seizures. No love there.
You
feminists
sexted for you tax.
That sounds good.
Sam. Sam, Sam,
Sam.
Tell him,
tell him, tell him. He says fuck about
any
show
is finish. Hold on.
The medication,
blood pressure.
She forgot her blood
pressure. This is serious.
And
tell him, tell him he
doesn't talk about him
then
[inaudible]
fucking
right.
I'm going to wake up in the morning.
Oh Man. So good. That's good
stuff. That's good stuff.