Well. Well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Your mom's house is supported
in part by the song.
There you go. All right. Sorry.
The bandwidth anymore.
My brain,
something happens when you pump
a child out of your vagina.
It's your mind. Okay. This
is a cheese keeps cubes.
The song is
Cadillac. Oh, I like it. It's by ob one.
Of course there'll be one canola.
Um,
very talented. He is very talented.
Very talented Hawaiian. Yeah.
I remember when we went there
and everyone said it like that.
E I'm going to breath
bomb beach this weekend.
Tickets are moving real well.
So if you're in the breast bomb area right
down the street from mar a lago where
our president elect chills
sometimes, um, come see me.
I'm only doing four shows.
Make America great again.
Maybe Gary. Good, great. Again,
come see me at the Improv in
West Palm beach this weekend. Um,
right after that I'm a home for awhile
doing some la shows, the genes machine.
Christine's, uh, we'll be
at the Washington Dick Hum.
Improv in the nation's capital
where then you are kind,
Kinda Camacho will be
running the country soon.
I think five people voted for
him in that state. In what state?
In Washington district of Columbia and
District of Columbia. Yeah. The state.
You just lost all your
points. A kids. It's in,
there you go. You're doing the one of
the best clubs in the country. Yeah.
December 9th and 10th. It's really great.
I know. I can't wait. I can't wait.
I I knew at one point what stayed
out. That was it. Yeah. All right.
It's not a state babe. It's still
not a static. I know. It's a major,
uh, small city. There
you go. Um, New Year's.
I'm in Orlando,
Florida at that Improv.
And then my big tour starts in January.
We've added shows in Minneapolis,
Chicago, Portland, um,
Boston. Those are, those cities have
added shows. Other cities we're probably,
you know, not going to
add in. Get your tickets.
Now I start off in Kansas City
at the beginning of the year. Um,
I head Oxnard and then it is
on. Man. I, I'm doing some,
I'm doing a new New Orleans clear water.
It's going to be nuts.
It's going to be really quick. Were you
hear Ochsner? Don't you think of ox balls?
Yeah, I do. I've planned a
whole life. Cox nars. Yeah.
I've never said it out loud until now.
I'm really excited for this.
What do you think? Yeah, we added um,
Calgary, Edmonton and this Friday.
So in a couple of days the Vancouver
goes on sale. Just want it to look.
Put that out there.
Do you think Trump's first order of
business will be to move the state,
the country's capital to like Miami?
That'd be awesome. Somewhere more fun.
I don't think he would.
He's a swimmer.
He doesn't know what Miami vibe somewhere
where there's more hot chicks. Yeah.
It's still fucking hot chicks around here.
You guys are all serious talking
about likes and he likes,
he does like some hot chicks,
but who can blame them for that?
It isn't like those bummer chicks.
Thank stuff. How opinions, boom.
Boom. You're ready to start the
show. Oh my God. I'm so ready to,
let's go jean
the honorable member or for a
Senate Gulf islands. You're rough,
my friend and her speech,
but I heard her to say a word that I
know is distinctly on parliamentary and I
think she may want to withdraw it.
The word was f a r t,
z. Honorable men, uh, member
for Calgary Signal Hill. Are
we saying, are you serious,
Mr Speaker? Like is my
colleague actually, seriously,
I just gave an impassioned speech
that's about supporting Alberta jobs and
that's what the leader of a political
party stands up and has to say. No,
I don't withdraw it.
Oh, it's Ryan. Don't bring
anyone loving to this.
Well, well, go to your mom's house,
Christina.
It's interesting.
Feel the base. That's a good one. Oh Wow.
Okay.
The sound is so immense.
My, my ear candy rumbling,
those, you know, I got those for you.
That's a gift. I got you. These are no,
not recently, but yeah, a while
ago, right? You just said no.
I thought you meant you just got these
from. No, but that was a present.
Like I love these.
These are what I used to wear on airplanes
when I traveled a lot so I could lock
out other people. Yeah, you just
seal out the rest of the world.
You're a huge fan of noise cancelling
head. I haven't got the mini ones.
The inner ear noise. Canceler
yeah, they're awesome. Does
that work? Okay, fantastic.
Put it in your rectum.
Yeah. And then your,
your butthole closes and you can't
hear anything. It's fantastic.
All right. You know what I wish is that
people in our country, I talk back like,
oh my God. Like why is no one talking
to a president elect Trump this way?
Like are we fucking serious
while he gives us state of the union?
You're orange.
Nobody's making any sense.
This is great. This just goes to
show how sensible Canadians are
by the way, were, were in the studio.
We made it. It's still a mess.
We made it though.
This is better than last week.
So you can actually see a little
bit better than it used to me.
You can see we have an actual
production desk. Look at this.
This is like your, um, your
Dj Dad Mouth Central Station.
I got my turntables
right over there tables.
We got special soundproofing on
these walls and on the ceilings.
I missed him too. I'm glad you
brought him back into the fold. Yeah,
that's the American. And then
this is Canadian. So that's our,
our Congress. It's how
we talk. We talk funny,
I just gave an impassioned
speech and then we go and then
a,
this was amazing. This
is a, this is incredible.
She said f a r t
talking about how to retain skilled labor.
Thank you.
Why isn't the infrastructure minister
talking about how to implement
infrastructure funds and get
construction workers to work in Alberta?
Why does this government treat
Alberta like a fart in the room?
Nobody wants to talk about or acknowledge.
I like that is where my constituents had
been out with this government for over
a year. And you know what? We're tired
of it. Oh. And by the way, constituents,
as I'm giving this speech,
there's liberal members across the aisle
that are laughing at me and they're
laughing at you.
Okay, Ooh, I like her. Can
we get her to work down here?
Fan of the honorable member.
I'd like to use me,
my friend in her speech,
but I heard her to say a word that I
know is distinctly on parliamentary and I
think she may want to withdraw it.
The word was f a r tape.
The honorable men. Hey Oliver.
He signals are you serious?
Are you serious? Are
tape, whatever it was. F,
F, a, r.
T. F. A. R. T. A.
You know who that is? That's the
tattle tail tree school teacher.
Teachers.
Yeah.
Elizabeth, you fucking tattle tale
nurse. Such a fucking nerd. Nerd alert.
He said, what's going to happen? Are
they gonna punish her for saying that?
I have a lot to say about the
content of my friend speech.
I am deeply concerned as are all people
in this place for Canadians who are
hurting economic downturn,
but the first important,
excuse me.
Oh good. Well just sit down.
Maybe she has to follow it.
Maybe she had to fart right then.
I wonder how often she farts.
She looks like she can,
she can. She farts a lot,
but it looks like they just
like kind of like fallout.
I think she eats a lot of TV dinners in
front of the television and she farts
and she pets her cats.
Yeah. Oh, oh, oh, oh.
What's going on?
Yeah.
And we're back. So this is part
of a living in a new place.
We've had a constant stream of
workers work things. Nothing.
Nothing really works. When you first
buy a house, Internet's terrible.
Internet blows the heater's not working.
Uh, the pool needs where it's all,
it's all under construction, but it's
coming together guys. Yup. Our life,
our life is almost gotten.
They uh,
they just shamed this lady
and just sitting down.
The lady who was like far T, well
they should, you know, like I said,
we could use a little bit of this and our,
and our politics from the no fun patrol,
you know. Fine. So what if someone,
she said Fart in the wind.
It was in the context of an event.
She's The lady that when she was a kid
and the teacher left the room for a
second, she told the
teacher came back, she said,
who said that everybody could have one
cookie and Simon had for Robbie had four
cookies. Yeah. Fuck yeah. This,
this is the syndrome of someone
who needs justice all the time.
Not about justice at that point.
They know dickhead.
This is speaker.
Uh,
the leader of the Green party has been
probably one of the most vocal opponents
of every part of the Alberta economy.
So I will take no lessons
from her on Oh shit.
Alberta Bitch
for the set of shut Gulf islands.
And I feel it's important
to make something of the
member's choice of words is
that she then accused people opposite
her for reacting at in that context,
decorum is important and respect
is important to this place.
I remind those who are now heckling me
that you are breaking the rules when you
do so. I've never heckled
in this place. Not once.
And I've never used language that
was on parliamentary, not once.
And I recognize my friends passion,
but I do not.
Stephanie's, she just sat down
again. Yeah. She got fucking shot.
Hold. What's up? You know as a r t
I love that. I could hear her say
that. Oh well she didn't even,
she didn't tell her. She didn't
say the word. She spelled it out,
which is extra juvenile to me when adult
can't repeat a bad word. Of course.
That makes me crazy.
Just say far dummy.
Like you've never said
Fart in your private life.
She didn't want to sink that low.
Shouldn't listen to this
show. I'm like, oh my God.
Elizabeth would have a real problem.
This, this show should be like,
it was the most offensive,
most offensive. Far. Yay.
Four. Yeah, four,
four. I remember she was from last
week, the big, the big flip fluff.
Ms Fluff. Great. Big forever. She is.
Yeah. She was so fucking fat. Oh my God.
Yeah. That was way fat. Cause
bird is fat. But that was like,
oh, obese. Oh yeah. That
was easily to Burt's today,
which has enormous, yeah. You
know what I'm saying? Yeah.
So yeah, so big. Speaking of that, I mean,
I'm really hitting this, this weight loss
thing hard. You're really, first of all,
you're really hitting your drops today.
I got to say,
you're on point with your drops.
Thank you.
And you've been hitting the weight
loss game harder than I've ever seen.
You hit it. He's serious. Mr
Speaker, like you have been, well,
first of all, working out daily. Yeah.
Jammin on the one the diets clean as
fuck right now. You bought the, uh,
that tank that you sit in for an hour
a day. Sweat the sweat tank. Yeah.
So you're losing water weight in addition
to fat. So there's a lot going on.
Yeah, it's pretty great. It's
pretty great. I mean, it's a,
it's a full on challenge
at this point about who is,
you know, who's going to be less of a pig,
right. Beginning of the new year. Well,
and I've seen Burt's propaganda on
Instagram. Yeah. I don't buy it.
I don't think he's doing anything.
Yeah. You, you shouldn't buy it. I mean,
now it's nonsense. He's a
big liar. You know, he, um,
I see him telling nothing but
lies all the time and he's, uh,
he's also somebody who you
have to remember. Oh, this
is him right now shut. Oh,
okay. Burnt Chrysler. Hey,
sure. Clean it up. No, no.
Rock tweeted us in a ticket. 10. Friedberg
oh, what'd he say? Uh, no.
Okay.
Watch my news video and then call me back.
Well, um, we're doing a podcast
right now. Oh, son of a bitch.
What do you, what is your new,
just tell us. Just tell us.
I ended up dealing with you today.
I'm running on the treadmill after I did
my line was I call these
two bearings for those.
Y'All didn't get posted
back in high school.
That's where I was real men put hair on
the balls and the rock just back in high
school line.
Happy Rolling.
That's hilarious man.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. I watched the video
and then, and then call me later.
Where's the video?
Is it on your Twitter?
It's on everywhere. It's
on Twitter. On Instagram.
It's a video a day during this
weight loss challenge. And, uh, and,
and just instead of doing a blog,
post them on Instagram.
Oh, another thing I want to
talk, I was talking to Ari,
he was saying that like we're just doing
a straight up weight loss challenge.
That's how I understood it.
Right. He was like, well,
if he's a half inch taller than you,
then he doesn't have to leave. I'm like,
no dude, I'm not playing that. We're
doing a straight up challenge. Yeah.
Here's the deal. Here's the
deal. We both measure. Okay.
Okay.
We both come in at six one
and the whole deal is we just,
all we have to get really is the pure 27
but we can get below 27 you have to pay
for the trip.
Both of you. Does he understand
that that's on him? If we hit that,
yes.
You get totally gets it.
Just simply overweight and not
our number is two 27
okay. Okay, so 27 all right.
Yeah,
she did a fear.
Okay. Okay, so that's this.
That's the addition to thing.
That's the on that
a den Denim you mean? All
right, so I'll look up.
I'll look up this video you just posted.
Call me later.
All right. All right, sounds
good. Bye. I didn't know that.
So you guys only have to get to
being overweight and not obese.
So two 27 and above is considered
obese. Well, for our height,
I mean, yeah, so two days right now we're,
we're grotesquely obese and if we get
done at two 27 we'll just be overweight.
Like if we want it to be healthy.
But also you should,
you should remember this though.
The BMI is a super outdated measuring.
No, it really is. It really is.
How so explain to me how
the BMI like takes into,
it doesn't take into it like it wasn't
taking into account like at your muscle
mass. Really. It's just saying
like based on an average size guy,
oh you should weigh this amount, but you
could, you could be a muscular guy and,
and could be considered obese by it.
You could also just be kind of
a normal build guy and still
be considered obese by it. Cause
it's, it's an outdated measurement.
It's just taking the number is
what you're saying. But yeah, it's,
it's just saying, oh, you're six feet
tall, you shade weigh 180 pounds,
but you can see guys that are two 10 that
are healthy guys. They're like, no, no,
you're obese now. Cause you're, you're,
so you're saying instead they should do
a ratio of your body fat to muscle tone?
Well, I'm saying that if somebody were
to really want to find out on this scale,
you should do like a, a real, uh,
modern day body fat percentage.
So you know how much,
right, like a trainer,
when you see sometimes they paint your
fat and then they tell you how fat you
are. Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Yeah. That's interesting.
I was like, Bro, I didn't find them. I
don't believe he's doing two a day. Oh,
I think it definitely just did you
think so? He did it today. Okay.
I'm not saying he's doing it every day.
Does he have a sweat tank like you have?
I don't think he has a sweat
tank. Um, you know, Diet.
I just can't see him sticking to it
for the month, especially on the road.
He's going to have so much
boost flowing through a system.
The problem with him and this challenge
is the road that's going to be a huge
obstacle for him.
And that's something thankfully you don't
have to contend with because he drinks
a lot. He drinks on the airplane,
don't forget, he doesn't fly sober.
So that alone is going to be quite
a challenge. Oh yeah. And it's,
it's a month of that, you know of
him trying to flush cannolis. Yeah,
I think so too.
It's impossible.
This is what's cool about this Internet
right now is that I can't fucking pull
this up because the Internet here fucking
sucks even though we've paying for the
top tier that they offer.
So that's always our problem.
We always pay for the top tier and
we never get what we want. Dude,
it's such lush cause it's so hard to
get high speed internet and we've had
different companies and they
all our garbage man dog shit.
Here we go.
Here we go in the morning, but
I'm ready to go to crossfit,
waiting for my workout partner,
Johnny Blade to come pick me up.
And that's how you start a day.
All before Tommy bonds just
had his first jar of honey.
Oh my hat fucked off.
Doesn't look good.
It doesn't look good at all.
No,
he's wearing a rock tee shirt.
Oh.
Oh my God. He looks like shit.
We are in jungle. Heading
back to the man cave. What?
I call it two a day. For those of you
who didn't get pussy back in high school,
uh, two days with us. Bad ass used
to do to grow hair on her fault.
It's getting real up here.
Can you hear the music playing?
It's funny,
he goes funny.
He didn't do two a days cause he didn't
play ball. Well wasn't he like a,
what did he do in high school?
He would fucking hung out. Yeah.
He's one of these guys too that like,
oh my God. I remember one time I,
when I asked him, I go, did you play
football in high school? He goes, oh,
supposed to be like one of the
next best players at my school.
Like supposed to be great.
But then I injured my shoulder.
I was going to like everyone was talking
about how good I was going to be like
hypothetically, he was
proud of himself in college.
His movements are terrible in
college. Wasn't he van wilder? Yeah,
he was a lunatic. Partied.
He didn't even do the sports,
so that looked really
bad when he was terrible.
It look like I got a 50 year old dude
trying to work out and you're like,
stop it. You're going to pull
your back or something. Yeah.
He's gonna hurt himself.
I hope he got approval from his
position before he started. I should do,
I should do a video just where I show
him how to do this. This is bullshit.
He did once you've been doing
this already for months,
I'll take them to a class. Oh, remember
when you did crossfits? Oh my God.
He come home and you're like,
oh, it's a burpees. Burpees.
Yeah. I did a plank
yesterday, uh, two minutes.
First Time my entire life. Pretty
cool. You're just going to,
you're not going to give me any
kind of props. I am proud of you.
I think that's great.
I think I really do think that's great.
I'm glad to 27 it's a magic number.
That's your record.
No booboo to 27. Oh, I thought
you meant to 27 was how long
you planned for? No. Oh,
just to two minutes. That's
fantastic. Yeah. Two 27 is not obese.
Okay. So No, you know, um,
yeah. Pretty incredible,
right? Very. Can't believe
I didn't do two a days and you throw it
to today's joke out. So fucking funny.
You know, bursts never even
been to Russia. No. That
whole story is just, it's,
it's all exactly. That's right.
Yeah. They didn't really call him no.
And he calls himself,
I'll stories guys.
It's all stories and his diet's
probably not clean. Oh my God.
He's not eating clean and not boozing
mean maybe for a few days. Maybe a week.
I could see him when he's
home. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
He's got leftovers because they blow it
out the crushers. Oh yeah. And there's,
I'm sure he's eating leftovers. It's
still sugar. We throw it out. We got,
we ate one day and then I throw it all out
the next day. Stuffing, green's paints,
tomatoes, tomatoes, checking,
Bam, Bam. Throw it out. Yeah.
So we didn't have,
we're not tempted to go to it.
That's how dedicated I am to my husband.
Winning the obesity challenge.
Challenge and not obesity challenge.
That's right. Two 27 jeans.
You're almost there getting closer.
Oh Dude, I'm getting closer.
Yeah. Written clean, clean
eating, clean living,
fitness, jumping rope, making boxing.
Boxing's I wanted to bring up a story.
We had the electrician come this week
and he pushed the doorbell and I answered
and he goes, Oh hey jean. And
I had thought that I was heard
and I let him and I go,
I think he just called me gene.
And then later he goes, all
right Jeanne, you very much,
cause he heard me call you jeans
a few times and like jeans,
do you want this here? So he was like, he
was like, I'm picking up on it. You know.
He was like,
oh there's like Jane.
You loved it though.
Yeah.
I mean for a split second,
because we have had workers come through
here that are fans of your mom's house.
And I thought for a second,
maybe this guy is like a fan of the show
or something. Oh, for sure. He's a little,
he's a little older so I don't,
I didn't think so, you know,
but just the fact that someone called
me gene based on you is pretty great.
Pretty Great Jean ll the
morning gene flow gene. Um,
that was fun. It was fantastic. Jane Jane,
we still say jeans and mommy
to every drive through.
We do have the Starbucks drive through.
We live by a Starbucks now,
so we drive through all the time and
it will be like a mommy, can I get a,
a Venti iced coffee, extra ice, no
sweetener. And they're like, okay,
it's going to be three 58. I'm
like, okay, thanks. Thanks jeans.
Say it fast. Yeah, because now I
do it. Yeah. And it's the most fun.
They never say anything.
And you can do it to waitresses were
Starbucks employees to anybody that you
have an exchange with quick, quick, like
the grocery person, you go, hey mommy,
I'd like a blah, blah blah.
Thanks genes. I say things genes.
Cause that one's easier.
Yeah.
I think we should start, um, uh,
phenomenon around the world where
people start doing this. Hey Mommy,
I like a double cheeseburger, blah, blah,
blah. Thanks jeans. Those, by the way,
those fucking international
Burdis fats are so fucking funny.
Aww.
I love that Indian one we got from the,
the female end major
Japanese wine was great.
So profesh so profesh profesh now there
was some controversy I noticed about
last week's master of accents.
I noticed that too.
It looks like your title
is being challenged.
Okay. Um, let me pull it up here.
Yeah. People were like, oh my gosh.
Her Vaccines, Huh? Okay. Pops.
We've had a bit of a rest
time now for some training.
What's involved in, she would pop
place now I have to say we were,
you were saying something
about how dignified,
I remember you were talking
about dignified breads and then
when this club's up, I would say that
you actually said, oh, interesting.
First you're blaming, wait a minute,
I'm the apprentice of accents.
You're the master of eggs, but
you lived there. Yeah, I know,
but I was tired and not paying attention.
I'm just saying,
I think I followed your lead, but
you're the master. I'm just saying,
I think you polluted my mind for a moment.
Uh,
but then we had a number of people
write in a very upset saying this is
absolutely very clearly not British.
It's Australian.
And then people on top of that wrote
in and go, this is Kiwi. Well yes,
you're right.
Now allow me to clarify cause I read
all the emails and I've done my, uh,
my research here.
I heard the first speaker is Momster
alien and this key, this guy,
this New Zealand guy wrote and he's like,
I was so happy to hear that we're going
to shit on the ozzies cause I gives us
Kiwis. Great Joy. Yeah. And then he
goes, the rest were Kiwis. Oh really?
The first speaker is mom's trillion and
then all these lunatics so that the dog
wrangler is Australian and
then these little savage pigs,
what's of his are Kiwi, right? These
suck pigs and they're laid texts.
Dog Fetish costumes are Kiwis. Wow. Right.
What a masterful right accent this
man has. Right. It's really weird.
Pops. We've had a bit of arrests, but it's
training.
What's involved in here?
Pop place at first seems really simple
because most people think you just get
the most value. Right. Waddling
around and for the buck buck,
but it's really so much more complicated.
Oh my God.
Complicated than this. When do you
guys pull your dicks out? Yeah,
when he sent that he's Seiko that belongs
to somebody in the room. We'll dump up.
See, I knew it was mine. Well
done. Oh God. It's so fucking bugs.
Petting the puppy in the latex costume.
It's upsetting. It wasn't any other
trainers. There wasn't anyone to teach me.
You lived in Australia to Adam.
I know put together,
but I will say, can you press
pause? Yeah. Is that his accent?
His accent feels subtly Momster alien.
It's,
it doesn't sound as much as like
Gig you go day by. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
When they toggling tog o we have a big
Australia now I'm here. Yeah. Yeah.
One of the clips coming up.
That's right.
Pop lately.
Yeah.
How much for you to do pup play with this
guy in charge and just all these other
guys and they all recognize you from
your Netflix specials. Even with my dog,
mass gone.
Well,
they cut your beard out of the mass
of people can recognize good die my FM
Netflix. Hey, you sure this guy? You know,
he pulls his dick out and just Mal Fox.
All these dogs, they don't mention that.
I know, but you know
that's coming. Of course.
Why else are people
wearing this tech shit?
Oh my God. He's smelling the other guy's
ass and aesthetics and SafeWork. Oh,
for fuck's sake. Putting
that altogether. I've become,
I become a trainer and I
own and backing it again.
Hey, who's your honor? I use
your own. No, that's right.
Yeah, I should have gotten
this. It's very disappointing.
It was a sad day in your mom's house.
Yeah,
I was going to be honest and I'm
going to be open about who I am.
That's who just said that this guy in
a full fucking ridiculous dog mask and
latex suit, dammit. And by the way, fate,
perfect smile, dog teeth. Perfect smile.
By the way, these late full body
latex dog costumes can't be cheap.
No, it's a real investment
of real investment team.
Also investment of your time to live at
this fucking perverts house in his cage
to get the realistic dog face
costume with your eyes cut out.
I guess a really aggressive like,
you know,
costumes and masks can go one way and
yet that's a really aggressive looking.
Doesn't it look super aggressive? Of
course. Yeah. But that's his puppy nature.
That's his nature. He wants
to express Tom. Oh yes, sure.
So gross. I is so, it's so not my lane.
I'm just so, I'm so not into this stuff.
Yeah. Where'd it go though? I don't know.
Make Fun of them,
but I want to hear the difference between
the Kiwis and the mom's sterling. It.
Okay. Okay. Cause I'm not sure
and I'm going to be open about who I am,
about who I am.
I'm not ashamed of the fetish or
muffled of the people that you should be
ashamed though. A little beautiful, very
ashamed. I'm not ashamed of the fetish.
I'm not ashamed of.
Why not people that I hang out with.
I think you should be just a little bit,
I suppose that I want people tonight.
It's a normal community.
It's not,
I don't think that I
should be hiding it away.
You can read it 100% sure.
Just like the guy that Mary's,
there wasn't any other
trainers. It wasn't. Can you
want to hear that difference?
Right? Yeah. Wasn't well, I can't
cause a muffled. It might get,
it wasn't any other trainers,
Thales and tried anyone to teach me,
so I had to go out and learn and
put together. The idea is well done.
Secret got a present for
me. Pretty boy. Good boy.
Yeah.
I took it off of a relief to get that off.
So now put it back on.
Your parents are watching
and I'm going to be open about who I
am that I'm not ashamed of the fetish.
I'm not ashamed of the people that I have
and I suppose that I want people
can buy and normal community.
We live in this guy's cage hiding it away.
A relief to get that off. So what?
What the little relief to get that off.
Yeah. So Kiwi, I mean,
I guess sounds a little more of the bling.
What are you doing?
No checking a message. Oh,
who's calling? I don't know.
I got somebody just left me a voicemail.
I don't know if it's a, Oh, okay.
It's a different guy. Um, I don't
know if it was the guy in the house.
Oh, I gave my number. Oh, it's the Harry
is he let letting you know. I mean,
he seems happy. He's fine.
He's very happy. You would
think for a sense of like,
Hey, I want to keep my day job. Yeah.
I don't need my friends and family to
know that I dress up like a latex dog and
sniff other guy's butts and then
you know, yeah. F them. You don't,
you don't need people to know.
Just like what we said last week.
Sometimes my trainer, he, he helps
me. You know your dog trainer? Yeah.
It's just like the
gays. Yeah. I asked him,
would you ever date your mom asked him,
would you ever date your mom? He was like,
Yo, really word. He calls
me mom, you know? I mean,
you know what I mean? Yeah. So dumb.
So dumb.
Fuck him.
What's up man?
That's something else.
I wouldn't even open up that can of
worms. It's just like the gays. Yeah.
God. It's just like the game is still one
of the most alarming things we've ever,
in my opinion,
played ever need to buy.
It's one that lingered
around the house for days.
He kept quoting that one for
days. It's crazy. I asked,
I'm your mom and you're my son and I
if falling in love with him. He said,
are you really? I said, yes, I
am. He's thinking, don't what?
I was scared to let you know too.
I am too bold consenting adults.
If it comes down to it, you know, it's
just like the gays there, you know?
As long as they're over 18 everything's
fine. Yeah, yeah, Yup. Same thing.
Yup. Exactly the same. I
asked him, I asked him,
you day, your mom, how do
you like, that's such a,
she just brings it up.
When they were just one day who are
talking and laughing and she was like,
I asked him, what would you ever
day your mom like? Yeah. Hello.
How are you responsible as a parent,
right? It's on her. It's on her.
You're not supposed to, so you want to
hear a distinctly Australian accent? Yeah.
Let's figure the difference out
between the Kiwi and the Australia.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Oh, it was always in
bed and we will have come and wake me up,
not coming into letting me Jaxa.
I'll say saying,
I'll make running towards the light.
He was up on the straight and then he
come back towards the car and I said,
Oh hey, what are you doing there? Am I
doing there, Mike? You got to wait here.
And he's like, Nah, Nah. Oh. I fell asleep
behind the wheel and I'm like, what?
What ride I ride,
I,
he needs a perfect smile.
A devil.
He's missing some paper.
I don't know where a perfect smiles are.
I have a perfect smile on my travel case.
I traveled with it so that if I
ever need a smile on the road,
thank God.
Definitely. Then he just decided to start
walking up the street again and I said,
what do you know,
Mike?
You got to wait to hear the cops in
common and he's just started taking off.
So I was reading,
so I jumped in me little purple car and
started chasing him up the street and
then he went down a solid straight,
told the cop as he went in the psyllid
straight and I went and got him.
This is awesome. No, it's
just tasting me jokes.
Should I see the memory jogger and
he's got four teeth? They know.
Don't Australians just sound adorable
no matter what they're saying. Yeah.
Even chopper chopper. Joe died
his pubes ginger JOPPA. I love it.
Yeah, they do. They're, they're, they're,
they're a fun group. Sweet. Right? Yeah.
He just don't sound like dicks.
I don't know how long you lived there.
Six months there.
I did road rules.
There were saying you lived there and
filmed for like almost three months,
I think you lived there and nineties
I know, but you lived as well.
How does that make my point? Well,
no, I mean it was an extended trip.
I don't know if I would
consider three months.
You wouldn't say you lived there
for three months. All right.
Then I guess it's living, I mean I lived
in Boston for a summer, I still say yeah,
but I lived in a, I lived in youth
hostels and a Winnebagos. Yeah.
In the winter you were doing challenges.
Shit man,
you're wrestling crocs sitting on ice,
just glass and you're just
classical house. Glassing just glue.
I got a bad bite. I got a
bad, this guy looks so happy,
really happy. And you know
these Australians, they
always, they're always happy.
I don't know.
I've never seen a bummed out Australian
and they were like that in the 90s
everyone's super nice then it was a
90 thing. I don't know. I mean, look,
I just know that I didn't meet a
Root Ozzie when I was there. Really?
No Americans are Douche bag.
We're mean to foreigners especially,
but there are so nice. I loved it
there. Canadians. Australians. Yeah.
K We. Oh, nice. They're
all nicer than us. Most.
Most other places. Would you say,
oh, this is, this is New Zealand.
Ah, shit man. Hey, this bundles of energy,
right? Snacks to keep them going.
That's why I moved my kids pretty bad.
Pretty bad.
No,
you're laughing at it because of this.
Preventing trips around your home
can be as easy as tidying up toys.
The breathing is, they're obviously
very close though. That's Kiwi. Kiwi.
It's a bit of, yeah.
Fruity fruity bars. Yeah.
It's stronger and I feel like a struggle
as a stronger accent he bought. Yes.
It's a little more fairy cutie
energy bundles.
Right?
Snacks to keep the snakes and that's
why I don't say x already. Buzz.
Oh my God. Do you know that I clean up
the toys now a lot more because of that.
Yeah. See if it worked then oh my
God. No, I don't want to see it again.
Fruity bars,
snacks,
snipped down right there.
No Way.
Do you ever seen a moose
coming down that quick?
We've been slipping along here.
Just glass with glass.
We're just glassing looks glass glass.
It makes me so happy. Oh man, that
makes me so happy. Ultimate Dad Boehner,
that guy.
Yeah,
like hearing our son laugh and this
guy made me happy no matter what. Yeah,
just glass and I like his dad.
Move Lenient Thompson Gore. Whoa.
This is the dad move.
Just glass. Yeah. Oh,
they do this like he was
really such a dad move. Yeah.
Got Out here. Look at
the metal. This is why.
This is why we came up here.
Been slap it along this big huge metal,
big long call meadow slipping along here.
Just glass and just glass
and glass and all of a sudden
put my head on. I'm like, oh, we're just
glassing. He's pick your two of those.
We know.
I was wrong that this guy's Canadian.
No. You thought it was going to. Of
course. Yeah. No, he's from Colorado.
I don't buy it. How do we have a
Canadian living in Colorado? Dude,
he has no Canadian accent it and
looking for Moose. That's, I mean,
there's nothing more Canadian than
that. No, no, you don't know. It's um,
it's really bad. How, how far off you
are with that one? You don't know.
I'm really, I'm really
disappointed. Yeah. Okay.
Okay.
First of all,
yeah.
I want to bring up something that
I'm really thankful for. You know,
we just celebrated thanksgiving,
thanksgiving giving mate.
That was a perfect English accent.
Thank you.
And we invited her friends over.
Yeah,
we did straight friends and straight
friends and no good friends. Nobody.
Non binaries. Yeah. And
I'm saying, wait, you know,
we didn't do anything we didn't
want to do. So the point is,
you and I made sweet love.
Oh yeah.
In our home for the first time here.
And I wanted to thank you because you
put on deodorant before we did it.
That's really and showered and I thought,
wow,
what a special occasion. Yeah. Okay. So
you did, you said that and
I was like, what are you
talking about? How you go whoa,
deodorant. What's, what's going on?
What's the, what's the big deal here?
Why, why the deodorant? Like I
weren't you on an every day? No.
Do you mean no?
I mean what I mean is usually
when you're asking for set Scx,
I don't want to say the word STX you,
you don't usually grow them up
or do anything special for me.
Right before sometimes you'll have
flown across the country tape the night
before you'll have a show and
then you'll be like, can we do it?
I was really impressed that you took
the time to put on deodorant as well as
shower prior to us doing it like right
then. That was really cool for me.
The most memorable moment was
we did it Saturday and yeah,
it was at the tail end of the Florida,
Florida state kit
and I turned it off,
especially when as soon as I get over,
like as soon as I rolled over I go because
it was a game on that would to me it
was like the special moment
that you turn the game off.
I thought,
I thought you just mute it while I
thought I would mute it and just watch.
But then you were like,
I could tell you weren't into that.
So I turned it off and you know,
I tried to get through it as fast as
I could for you. Um, and then yeah,
for me.
And then when I rolled back over on me
like I wasn't game on and you were like,
okay,
I'm going to go to the shower for me now.
I thought that by the way,
that's a sign of a real
marriage is when you get,
you can do it and then your husband goes,
can I put the gate back on?
And you'll go, yeah, fine. It's fine.
And there's no anger. Oh, right.
It means you're in a good place and your
mass truth because I know how important
that game was to you. There's
Florida, Florida state,
and we won the gator
chomp killed the gators,
the gay turds turds. Ah,
that was really neat.
And we've been playing this a little
roleplay lately, which is fun.
Well because we were making kissy faces
the other day and in bed and you'd had a
glass of wine. It was kind of like three
quarters done was the side of the bed.
When I went to kiss, you know, I was like,
oh, I like this. This is like back in my,
uh,
bar.
My bar in the days when I used to just
kind of troll the bars and you go,
oh my God, really? I go, yeah, you
remind me of, uh, what's a good bar? Bar.
Troll name Karen. Karen. Yeah. Total care.
Then you're Karen and
just make it the bar.
I want to do a smoke
a cigarette too as it,
because when you have that on your map,
then I know you're down a lose and smoke.
I'm like, yeah, what's up? And
Karen has really low standards.
She's not used to being treated well.
That's the thing. Karen's like, Whoa,
you're kissing me. Usually I
don't get math. Pat My head.
And that's what's with all
these sheets on your bed
and Karen doesn't get mad when
the guy flips the game on. Right.
That's what she's cure.
Karen's actually used to have the game
on in the background as they're doing
full volume.
So Karen's thankful that you turn
it off and that's why I let you go
back to you would've been
what would've been cool.
If you want to be like really cool.
Why points we do it in the dog face,
in the TV, all the Games
on. That could be cool.
This might be the guy that
let me check. Uh, who's that?
That's the guy in the house. Oh Shit.
There's a dude in our house. Oh,
there's so many dudes in our
house. Always. What the deal
is he is he calling? I
Dunno. He just said I'm done.
So I'll be asking me if I need to come
over there and not asking me. No. Okay.
We'll see what he says. Um,
glass. But anyways, and then
what I really liked. Yeah.
So you have been taking, you've
been smoking cigars lately. Outside.
I've been enjoying getting back into
cigars. I like them like, I don't know,
20 years ago and you were 10 and now
I like them more than 20 years ago.
You're only 37. Yeah. So like a teenager,
late teenage, what are you talking about?
That's what I like. Cigars,
Florida. That's when I got
into cigars in high school.
Yeah. Who the fuck? Smoke cigars and
high school. That's how I got into him.
I was doing two days. That's how it
fucking calm down. Calm down. Yeah.
That was a grown man
already. That is silly. Yeah.
So you came in after you smoke your
cigar and I kissed you and I was like,
well it looks like Karen found a
match. Yeah. You're Bobby. Bobby.
Bobby again. Cause I
had cigar breath. Right.
And Karen's got such low standards. A
Bobby can walk around and the shorts. Yes.
Unfortunately. Oh, for crying out loud.
What's wrong with the heater? I Dunno. Uh,
I gotta go. I gotta go out there.
All right, pause, pause number two.
Here we go. Here we go. Here we go. Oh,
I got to stay with the dogs
and back for interruptions.
There you go. High traffic today in
the Segura. Yeah, a lot going on.
Well, I got a little tree for you. You
want to hear it? I got a little treat.
No Robbie, here we go.
Hey Buddy. That's top dog.
Hey Buddy. Stop Dog. I was the
Georgia. Oh God. Hey Buddy.
Good job doc.
Do you need to wipe down?
Stop talk gave, uh, gave dad a call. Yeah.
Oh my gosh. Pretty fantastic conversation.
We haven't spoken with him in a while.
Yeah, it's been a while.
And I got lucky that, um,
not only did I get to talk to top dog,
I also got to talk a little bit too.
Charro oh boy. So it was,
uh, it was something,
they're coming out pretty soon.
Hello? Hey Buddy. Hey, you're home.
Yeah, I'm home and work every
day. All Day. Some of them.
Oh, it's great. What, how's it going? What
are you doing watching Perry Mason with?
Oh,
cool.
Hey,
did you tell me the other day that
you had like a new fart smell?
I did. I did. I did. What, so
what do you attribute that to?
You know, I don't know. I don't know. I,
I think maybe a combination of
some different foods and things.
Uh, but, you know, I, I kinda have my,
my fart smells down to bed,
eight or 10 basic smells. Yeah.
And this was a new one and
it, it, you know, cause it,
and it was ugly, I have to tell
you, but it wasn't so ugly,
but it was just different. It, you know,
it was almost like it was somebody
else's heart. Were you surprised?
I was surprised. I was
totally surprised. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. And then, so what, what did it
lead to though? I mean like, was it a,
were you sick or
do you think now, now there wasn't, there
wasn't any, any event. Usually, you know,
if you have some need, it's a
restaurant you've never eaten before.
You go to somebody's house,
you know,
I have some greasy Italian
food or something and yeah,
I guess, yeah, but this was,
this was,
uh,
crazy Italian or something like that.
Some guys in like Italian
hates a time for this.
The only person alive
that hates Italian thing.
Hates means I really, you know, I tried,
I went back and tried to remember
what I ate and I can't put,
but it was definitely different. You
know, it was a real job, a real discovery.
That's really something,
Huh?
It is. It is. You know,
and I thought I was kind of past the
point of new discoveries, you know,
I'm 69 years old and kind of everything
is pretty much routine. So Emma,
there was a little bit of high excitement
there that I may have opened up a new,
a new vein and the old, you know,
margin testing, I don't know.
Yeah. So, but you still,
your movement afterwards, it
was standard. It was normal.
Yeah. It was standard.
Yeah, no, absolutely.
That's really something,
you know, you, you, you just came
to Thanksgiving and of course that,
that changes your,
you know,
you have a lot of things in quantity
and stuff you don't normally have. So,
oh, this was, this was the thanksgiving.
No, it was a pre thanksgiving, but just
coming through thanksgiving, you know, uh,
you know, I should, uh, I'm
back to doing, you know,
I had basically a twos and three
there ever since thanksgiving.
Wow. That's good. Anyway, but I,
I would just stop by that
one. Smell. I've never,
two is a little hard. It's hard,
but threes and fours are ideal.
So if you haven't twos and threes, I would
say fours and fives are ideal for me.
No five's too sloppy.
Threes and fours are the ideal.
I don't think so. I think, no, it's
not a matter of opinion of me. Look,
the reason for is or where you want
to be. Yeah. Yeah. I know this stuff.
I go four or five. Don't go for
a five. It's too sloppy. You
went threes and fours. I believe
me, I've studied this stuff.
I know the whole scale. When's your
colonoscopy? It's next one. Hold on.
You want a four and now you're right.
Three or four. You want to four, right?
That's what I just to
three is kind of hard,
a sausage shape with cracks in
the surface. But that's all right.
You want a smooth soft sausage
or snake? Four. Four. Yeah.
No, sorry, go ahead. Okay.
Smelled that smell before.
Yeah. I mean having a new, I
kind of know what you mean.
Um,
one thing that was weird was I was on
a flight last week and somebody kept
farting and it was the same smells. I knew
it was the same guy. It's far too. Yeah.
And then about two hours into the flight
I farted and my fart smelled like his
fart.
That was weird.
That was weird. Yeah. I couldn't
be, I tell you, we are, we are.
We get on like,
like you're on a tram or something,
you know,
people,
but sitting down so they stand up and
I am the 80 do that a lot in Florida
because you know,
if it would cold weather climates and
you have a party kind of get in a crowd,
it kind of hides in your,
your overcoat or jacket or wear
everywhere and you know, it doesn't,
but time it gets out,
it's kind of diluted.
But if you live in a hot weather climate
like Florida or la and that summertime
when you're Fart, it's out
there. You know, there's,
there's an escape hatch. Okay.
Oh yeah. And uh, you know,
yeah. So, uh, and then people,
people, uh, you know, then they all
look around, you know, there's like,
you always know, the people that don't
look around are the ones that did it.
Yeah. Interesting. Yeah,
you're right. Yeah. Yeah.
I do it.
I always look,
I always look around with like this
discussed of what the hell's going on.
Yeah.
Kind of to kind of misguide them
all.
The other times I went to this one
conversations with my dad, or like an
eye, I'll reciprocate. I'll be like, oh,
I'll say this back. And then he'll
be like, so something else I did.
Yeah. And yeah, there was an older person
in front of me, so they don't know.
They're not aware if
somebody is behind them,
sometimes we're not aware of
somebody in front of him. Okay. Yeah.
And so they had no idea. And all of
a sudden this not only hedge smell,
but it had noise too. I have
no idea. Somebody is them
and they find it a big one,
Huh?
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. And, and then,
and then when they step up to the counter
and they realize you're behind, you're,
they, they, they pretend they don't
have any ownership of the problem.
You don't. Right, right.
I remember one time I was, uh,
I'll never forget, you know,
just memories that just stick with you.
I share an office with this guy also
named Tom when I was working in DC.
Columbia. Yeah. Uh, that was
working at a America's most wanted,
he was a producer and Onair guy. And
I was just a researcher, so I was 20,
um,
and he,
or maybe 21 and he was probably 40
at the time and we both like hip hop.
So one time we just
went to a record store,
like during lunch break just to
look at the records. And this guy,
this was back when there was record
stores everywhere and they had headphone
stations. You remember that
whenever it came to that.
So you put headphones on and they would
have like five or six things you could
listen to at the time. Sure, sure.
So these are albums that are out.
So this big guy is standing there
with headphones on and he hits like,
so obviously you can't hear
what he's listening to,
but he's singing the notes
singing the song. He was like,
and as he hits the high note,
he rips a massive fart. Right.
But it was so weird because he turned
around and looked at us cause we were
busting out laughing and it was all,
he looked at us like,
oh you laughing at my voice. I think
he didn't know that he farted. Yeah.
Because when you're wearing your ear buds,
even in here,
you don't hear your far. And I
think because he was singing, yeah,
he didn't actually realize that he
pushed out a fart because I've had that
happen before when I've been on treadmills
where you're farting and you think
it's silent and maybe it's not
and everyone could hear it. Sure.
That's a real common problem.
Yeah.
Yeah. I know what you mean. Um, did don't
tell mom about this new smell or no,
no, no. This is where it gets good.
She's in the other room.
She's not into this.
I haven't told her baptist. Is she
around by any chance? Can of talk to her.
You can talk to her. Hold on. Okay.
Hold on. Let me bring up right away.
I'm both of you then when you
took this side. Yeah, it's good.
It can wear on you
sometimes. Um, what's up?
Did you know that he had a
new fart smell the other day?
Yeah, he said after all these years
he has about eight to 10 fart smells
so great.
I'm so disappointed she disappointed at
you or doesn't want to hear about it.
Doesn't want to hear about it.
Which Tom she referring to when you are,
you're telling me it's
telling me. I thought I heard
I Tom, which made me laugh.
I thought it was your dad.
Yeah.
No, I did them come and you have a new,
you should see how serious
he you sending me. It is
a my life. Okay. Person
hated in my life. Who?
The person I'm talking about this middle
of the French and kicking him out is
anyone can do
70 oh, by the way, I want to tell you in
front of him. This is serious. Yeah. Yeah.
Oh my God. It hurts to hear. Say,
yeah, it's only wants to talk over you.
I don't know. I want to talk to you.
Oh, okay. Did they remember you?
I don't want to talk about farts,
but this is like,
can you mag it smells.
I mean definitely still.
How does it know when to change your
[inaudible] part? It will make so much.
I didn't recognize the smell of yours.
Let me see. When I farted.
I do recognize this man.
I know it's a new one,
but isn't that kind of amazing
when you think about it
then tell me. I cannot believe
that. I mean, I know if it,
mine is metal doesn't
smell as far as I know.
But to recognize the smell of this heart.
He says there's a new one.
He says he has eight to 10
different smells that he recognizes.
Yeah. I want to put you on a
speaker. Yeah, hold on. Okay.
Oh crap. Damn. Yeah.
You said you have eight
to 10 different yeah.
Different snow in the kid from China.
Okay.
So I know by the way my car.
Oh,
what kind of taxes did you hear that?
Yeah.
Testing.
Well isn't it? He's, he's,
it's kind of a, a nice, uh,
a skill that he has that
he knows what's coming.
I just needed to know about history.
Know about the flowers.
I know like the smell of the flower.
Roseway Iranian.
Oh, I know what butterflies coming by. The
color of this. Tell me about the fight.
What kind of,
but dad can do.
Dad knows the age that she's the
one that skill that's for shoots,
can God.
Okay.
But he also wanted to give him discovered.
I think that the real thing is it,
not only does he have that
skill after all these years,
he was able to detect a new smell,
which is really signal.
Yeah. That really was kind
of like, ah, you know,
it's like we ended a stronger
word finding a new planet.
Yeah, that's really true. Yeah.
It's like they, they find,
they find new new solar
systems and galaxies.
How long,
how Lope Andrew did on your own that
you're going to live at Gordon to their
fights and this male [inaudible]
that would be my goal and my,
the meditation where we live,
I might have went on to be a ration card.
When you go to the bathroom, knowing
what's coming to see, I'm retired, I paid,
I know it's coming today and I am
a lot of toilet paper.
I need an extra role.
So is the main the main advantage
to knowing what's coming?
Just toilet paper usage?
Nope.
Actually toilet paper.
Then the real main advantage is you know
how close you are and sometimes they
come quicker than others. You
know, they don't come quick,
so do certain fart smells, let you know
you're going to have a really explosive,
huge shit.
Yes.
By I all. Absolutely.
Yeah. That I tell you.
I know because sometimes we're talking
and then he runs out. I guess. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm good. He out. Say, ah.
I knew that I thought
was going to be a five,
but it wasn't the biggest exploding. I
said, don't please don't go the leaders
an eight and it goes all over them.
Oh Wow.
Well, I really clear. It's really,
I don't think you do have that discussing
as your fired because to call that
really cool. I think that's awesome that
he has that skill in a book. I don't,
I don't know, like I'm not at dad's level,
but I, I have some Cochise that yeah,
they paint the ball and stuff. Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
I'm going to teach my son.
It's going to pass it down
from generation to generation.
Absolutely.
I'd be sure to be sure to be sure that
your phone knows that he's getting mad.
Never argue with any of
this disgusting stuff. Okay?
You should be hearing protection. Okaka
don't forget to talk about God. I made it.
Okay? I gotta go. I love you guys. Okay?
Yeah, but you know what? I
don't see. You said that you go,
you talk about [inaudible].
Do I have you forgot to say
I'm walking into a meeting.
Somebody here at the house. I have to
go. That's the reason why I got to go.
I said, if only for the
person I, he did. Okay. I'm in
another room. I love you guys.
Okay? I love that.
Okay. Bye. There you go.
Your mom does the same thing I do to
you because you always go, I gotta go.
I gotta let you go. Here you go.
So rude. I gotta let you go. Yeah.
That was probably one of the best calls
and a long time. I laughed so hard, man.
My stomach hurts from that call.
I love how upset Charro gets.
That's the best part is how upset she is
and how disappointed she
was when she found out what
you guys were talking about.
Oh yeah, and she's disappointed in you. I
she couldn't read. What was it
here? I think it was here. Hi. Hi.
He said,
after all these years he has about eight
to 10 fart smells and he had a new smell
is, believe me, it's my favorite
thing too. That's why I do this.
Disappointment is so profound
in you, right then. Yes.
So fun. I'll both of you then when
you took this, that's funny. She goes,
how bored do you get? What you talking
to your friend and you sometimes.
What's up? Did you know that he
had a new fart smell the other day?
Yeah. He said after all these years
he had eight to 10 fart smells.
Any of that new smell.
The smells.
She's so disappointed
in you right there.
Yeah.
I don't think I've ever heard her and
usually she just gets angry. Yeah,
but this was thorough disgust,
contempt and obsessiveness
at you and your dad.
It's a very nuanced emotion for Charlie.
This one's a little more than once.
Usually she just goes
to rage. Ah. So funny.
I don't want to hear, oh, I thought it
was your shit. Both from the streets.
That's how I like my answers.
It itch.
And so that's when she's a bit
Ghostface man. Yeah, she is. Yeah.
You know what I thought was really neat,
which you have been teaching.
Our son is in the mornings.
You and I,
we get our coffee together and he'd go
into his room and we wake him up or he's
already up and we have like a family
time and there's a, there's a,
a rocking chair I sit in,
I said was sitting there with Ellis and
you are sitting on like a plastic chair,
like a step,
the step stool.
And you are in your dad boxers like
you normally are with your, uh,
your slippers and just a shirt and you're
sitting on this plastic stool and your
legs were spread open and the fabric was
pulling against up against your nuts.
Yeah.
So we could see just a hint
of balls to the side to side.
Yeah.
And you spread your legs,
you lifted the legs in the
air and then you farted. Yeah,
it was like a snap, snap,
snap, snap, snap, snap, like
firecrackers and the street.
And it was cool that our son
got to see that firsthand. Yeah,
it was pretty cool. I agree. It was
kind of like a that uh, what's that? Um,
that, that great art that he had a kick
ass ripper. It was sitting on a dresser.
Right, right. His Dresser Fart. That's it.
A getaway.
Yeah. Good one. That's a neat thing.
Yeah. Yeah. Oh my God. That was so good.
Now how does your dad was another clip
from, uh, when I talked to my mom too.
I have a question though.
Earlier she was like, ask them,
will you ever date your mom? I was
like, yeah, mom, what do you would,
would you do mom? Um, so
how does your dad hold it?
Does he hold in these as
a, the men? No, no, no.
So how does he fired around your mother
who has honored contempt for them?
He just does and he'll be
like, baby, I go, it just came
out. I got it. I got to go.
She goes, well, go to the
bathroom. And he's like,
I don't want it to go to the
bathroom. She was like, this is this.
And then he'll get matches and stuff,
you know? And She just gets upset.
She just yelled. But she loves
it. Ha. Yeah. I have to say,
I think one of the greatest things about
our relationship is that we just fart
in front of each other because could you
imagine 2040 years of having to get up
and go to the bathroom? We know
people like that though. I know.
But that's especially because your dad
has a sickness. He has a diverticulitis.
So those a rancid, it's medical.
Have you smelled? Of course.
I've known him for years. Of
course. Bad. It's disgusting.
It's really rancid.
His farts are like just
wallpaper peeling any crazy.
So I wanted to play this
for you. This woman, uh,
Shah's Rad Morgan. She's an
author of the book, the fuck list.
A memoir about the two years after her
divorce where she fucked a lot of dudes.
Cool. Um, we always talk
about this. Yeah. Oh yeah.
We're going to blow bang whenever
after. Oh yeah. And by the way, yeah,
you
had a dream and then you tried
to kind of like dismiss it later.
You're like, ah, yeah, whatever was just
dream where you said I watched you, right?
No,
the dream was you had an idea for a bit
for your mom's house where I blow the
entire cast of Juggalos. This is your
dream. This isn't my dream. Yeah. And I,
I went through with it. I did it.
Reluctantly reluctant. No, I just did it.
I didn't think. Yeah. And then afterwards
I was talking to Bryce about it. Yeah.
Brace was like, wow, you
really blew all those guys.
It was really crazy. And then I had
second thoughts. I was like, oh,
we can't air that. We can't air that.
Right. And then I go, that's your concern.
And then I go, Tom, I blew all the
guys in Gigolos. We can air this bit.
This is going to, it's a
ruin my reputation as a
lady. Yeah. And that was it.
Yeah. Look at him. And I
liked it as you, your dream.
Tell your shrink about that one.
Let me know what she says.
Who I roll. I mean, you're like, oh,
I had this dream like, like somebody,
it sounds like someone really twisted
your arm. He's like, well I just did it.
I blew these five guys. But I
only remember blowing like, whoa.
I only remember, I only remember one
Peter. Really? Yeah, like in the dream.
I didn't go one. You remember who was it
was through the braces. The Jesus guy.
No sprays. It was praise God. You
blew brace in your dream. Right.
But then I didn't,
I just remember seeing the painter.
I don't remember it like doing anything.
And then I remember Bryce being like,
wow.
And then I asked to take the bed out.
The breeze philosophy,
philosophy,
philosophy, degrees, philosophy.
You blew them. Yeah. And your
dream really cool babe. You got it.
Hi. I'm sure was at Morgan.
I'm author of the fuck list.
So this is a very unusual video. I
have come all over my face, kind of.
You can see it and thank you
Brandon for leaving it there for me.
Bryce. Uh, it looks good. It looks
like a nice lady. She did. Yeah,
she did before she said that.
Well,
I don't know why you have to make a
video of come on your face, Donny.
Well she's going to tell you why
we've all had come on our face.
The reason I'm showing this to you is
because I want you guys to realize that
come to me as a woman come just to be
something really disgusting and gross and
slimy and I would have never
let a guy do that on my face.
I concerted so disrespectful.
I want to tell you how I came to see
calm is not some Yucky slobby slimy stuff
and make it something that turns me on
and this is how I realize by talking to
men, they associate the come with
their pleasure with their orgasm.
They will identify with it almost
like a woman might identify with her.
I don't know,
with our hair,
something about our bodies that we like.
She's a really weird accent and she's,
is there some kind of expectation? Yeah,
but so far I'm 100% on board with her.
Do you agree with that?
That is an extension absolutely.
In guys do identify,
identify it with their pleasure and
everything. I think that's that part.
And so the fact that it repulses
me is that bad. Um, it's just,
it's just reality. I just
have to deal with it. I mean,
I wish it wasn't like that,
if that's what you're asking.
I wish it were a candy flavored.
Mine tastes pretty good
as far as I remember.
I had a couple of cups of it last
week wasn't, it wasn't that bad
and
not only up for a man has come is
a very precious part of himself
at all. He loves his
comedy, still proud of it.
She looks at it like it turns him
on when he sees it coming out.
He's proud of it because like he
sees how much there is parked shoots.
It's a measure of his manliness,
you know,
like there's so many things about it
and when he could come on a woman,
it makes him feel so close to her.
He's giving her part of himself. Right.
This lady's a genius. Can I tell
you something? Or eyes are really,
everything's right.
Can I tell you some?
What's so great is when women
get hosed into this horse shit,
that guy's feel things about their calm
and we need to be more respectful of
letting guys come on. Gimme a break. Yeah.
This one is a little bit
about cell phones practices.
I practiced as a white tigress for about
a year. Then the oral sex tradition,
there's a lot of things. For
example, we have a technique,
she talks weird.
They both king deeply the penis and
you're almost like gagging on it.
And when I first heard about
this technique and then solid,
I was like saw my goodness.
And it was like the instant thing that
came up in me was that it's degrading to
women or the technique where
you're holding the back
of the head and the man is
holding her head and then
circling has hips and holding.
How day this lady's cool is she
needs a mill approval too much.
What's going on? What is this?
Why can't this get addressed?
It seems like the eyes, oh, I got that.
No, I'm not like that. What's going on?
Their bags. She's old. Yeah.
But I mean God damn, she
should put come on those bags.
What I'm saying,
there's so much.
So much bags and you've got all
this access to all this come.
Why don't you marrying the two?
Right. If it's a skin tightener. Yeah,
cause I think she'll get more
calm, which she loves. She,
if she takes care of those eyes,
her teeth look good though.
She don't tell us your teeth look good.
She's an attractive woman. I know,
but these are real bad.
Real well I can't. Exactly,
and she has come on her face.
I keep forgetting that it's on the,
I guess it's kind of dried. It's
usually gets flaky, right? Yeah. Crusty
and it's a turn on. It's not
disrespectful. Great teeth.
You can see that like guys come
on in your body or anything.
Like if guys come on your face or in
your body or anything like they just,
they just will. It's just such a
respectful, loving act to deal. Thank you.
No leverage.
With riverbed,
the guys,
she's a sesame street character.
So after they come on my face,
I like to rub it in and it makes really,
really good.
Facial skin is so smooth.
Yeah.
God Damn Hoes job you're talking about
and she's totally hosed this bride in
more than one way.
The only thing is when I get into my eyes,
it makes my eyes burn a
little bit and no shit.
I get in my eyes because I like to
look at the men when they're coming.
I like to look in their eyes and I like
to see the come come out of their penis
and Charles Murray on now. So I opened
my eyes to look and then always,
I always get some in my eyes, so I have
to figure out how to get better at that.
Yeah, you got to get better at that
needs really oversexed I think.
I think this is too much of
a focal point in her life.
I'm going to go out on a limb and say that
she's talking like a fucking teenager.
She might have been really super
repressed I think so. This is her reverse?
I think so, yeah. Because usually when
people lead with the sexuality card,
it's their whole thing.
I like to watch, come,
come out on the come lady. I'm come
face lady, come on my face. I rub it in.
It's definitely, you're right, it's
years of repression and now she's,
she's the official. Come on my face
lady. It's so funny. I love by the way,
the thought always being that like,
oh,
you really gotta be so accepting of
guys to get them to be indie. Like, no,
you don't.
You don't need them.
You don't need the guy to come
on your face for someone to come.
You know what I mean? Like dudes
will come no matter what, dude,
don't worry about it.
Can we stop fucking worrying about
their feelings about their fucking calm.
You don't want to, we don't have to
worry about guys know why. Who Cares?
What do you mean? I'm just saying that
they're not an underserved demographic.
Sexually. Men historically.
What do you mean? I mean,
you guys are ruled the world
this whole time. Who Cares?
The way we have things we
need to take care of baby.
Okay guys do you're a holiday
shopping using our Amazon banner.
We haven't mentioned that yet,
but if you want to buy, uh,
the calm cocktail cookbook, we just
got that. I've come all over my face.
They use our banner, God,
Your House House Pie guests.
Com. Click on the banner at the bottom
of the homepage of your shopping as you
normally would. It's very true for
Christmas. Do your Christmas shopping,
the shopping there.
Also,
we have a bunch of great
shirts on sale on the website.
We have some posters on sale. They
are go to Thomson [inaudible] Dot Com.
Click on the store to shop and
it'll take you to our, our uh,
our merchant page. Um, uh, can
I read an email that we got?
Please read an email that we got.
Okay. Ready? Yeah. Can you please
settle this debate once and for all?
My wife and I argue all the time about
wiping techniques and we are in need of a
neutral third party to weigh
in on the subject Grady.
So I myself am a sane person and I wiped
from front to back until the toilet
paper more or less comes back white.
She on the other hand,
goes back to front wiping
shit towards the clit.
She justifies this aggressive,
she justifies this by saying she has
this claw technique where she essentially
uses toilet paper as a make shift.
Shitty finger condom scoops it
out from inside the beholder,
so make sure she gets it all.
I agree her bunk hall is probably
definitely a lot cleaner than mine,
but what are you mommy's thinking? My
crazy. It's real crazy. Sounds a really,
really aggressive on a lot of levels.
Wiping back to front is never recommended.
No for nobody in that. She claws
at it and just, Oh man, wait.
Let me just see though.
I do see the point like she went like
this with the paper in there that the
problem is you aren't putting Cutco on
your machine and that's not sanitary.
You can also do the claw
through a reverse claw.
Do a claw front to pull out and use
your thumb as the claw right away from
there. No, you should definitely reverse
your claw. You should get the toto.
Yeah, get the total washlet three
50 on Amazon using our banner.
It's really the best podcasts.
Did you know that?
That the button that turns it on.
If you press it twice,
that's how you get hard pressure.
No,
it's soft on off and then there's stop.
So you do soft on the second time.
Makes it hard. You're fucking kidding.
Cause I've just been increasing the
pressure by pushing the button. Wow,
that's amazing.
So we are using the washlet
from the nineties we got
the total three 50 and love
and you do the model number
because the guy at the total store,
I went to their showroom and he walked
me through it and he goes oh you got to
get the three 50 that's the latest model
and get it on Amazon and it's pretty
painless to hookup.
You need to have an outlet by the
toilet and the water sources there.
This thing has a remote control,
a heated seat. You just basically,
it's like your old shit to shower thing.
I mean I still like to do a
cursory wipe wash. Let uh sure.
I'll do like a wipe. Why and then
I let it rip. Yeah. Why do you,
why do you do that's what the wash led
is for. No, I still like to do one wipe
cause if you have a like
a lot of Kaka there,
you don't have a big hairy asshole like
me. So yeah, I'll do like a cursory why,
but I just, I don't even
look, I just wipe it,
drop it and then I hit on and
then I just let that stream go.
I mean there's nothing on the
paper afterwards. It's amazing.
Have you used the dryer? Yeah.
That's so nice. It's a nice,
it's a hairdryer and your asshole.
It's a hair like a full powered with art
there is the front setting and then the
rear settings.
But as a woman I have to use the
frontline so it pushes the Kaka away.
Do you know what I'm
saying? Yeah, I understand.
You can't do the front
to the back to front.
We got a horrible are hilarious
clip to watch. I haven't watched it.
Do you want to weigh in?
We'll see what you think.
What the fuck?
Ah,
ah,
ah.
My fucking nuts.
Jesus. What were you thinking
dude? What accent master?
I think this guy was driving. So
when you ask, what were you thinking?
I think I have a pretty good idea.
Not a whole fucking lot past the dope
summer of 63 that's what I was thinking.
Jesus. Yeah. He goes,
did you hear that?
I don't think it's funny.
Bummed
out.
It's pretty funny.
Well,
I think it's a bummer that that's the
guy that hits you. That fucking cunt.
That Kippy asshole smoking dope.
Yeah.
All over my face.
I have come all over my
car and I really like it.
It's an excellent skin softener show.
Aw, I don't like it in my,
Oh, he's at birds, boy.
Super Dumb. Dumb. Do you see the
Hungarian email? I did. That's funny.
You notice that? Read it though.
Okay. It says, dear main mommy,
Tina and surfer of the water
champ champ thrown Tom.
You surfer. Yeah. Hmm. Okay.
Inspired by your wonderful podcast.
I pulled my jeans up high and tight and
sent off for a DNA kit from 23 and me,
I use the word I use,
the code.
Bird has fat jeans to pay an extra
20% to pay an extra 20 bucks,
which goes towards Burt's
liposuction surgery.
I received the kit fluid bonded with
a test tube and a few weeks later I
received my results. The test identified
several very close blood relatives.
I didn't know I had you see my mom was
adopted and found her bio mother several
years ago,
but she never found out the identity of
her bio father threw some detective work
and by comparing DNA results on
another website called g d match.
Um, they compare DNA from
different testing companies.
I discovered my mom's biological father.
Hmm. His last name was Joe Hahn sick.
Does that sound, how'd you say it? Oh No,
you have to spell it. J. O. H. A. N C.
I s.
I k.
Yo hand shake at sound check.
All right,
well he was 100% cockroach
DNA having Hungarian.
That makes me 25% Hungarian.
Excellent. We'll do. I know.
How do I connect with
my eastern bloc routes?
Is there anything special about
being Hungarian? Should I take this?
Go dancing and start being rude to people.
Should I plan a pilgrimage to
Budapest? Yes. I'm really lost here.
See you at the next family reunion.
Yeah.
Andy p s my wife and I saw Tina
and Houston a while back. Uh,
we already have tickets to see the fake
water champ time when he comes to town.
Unbelievable.
And as you'd say in Hungarian. [inaudible]
yeah, I think that's wonderful.
I think you should go to Budapest.
You said you should start eating sausage,
drinking beer and abusing your body
because you can cause you got cockroach
eastern bloc DNA also,
uh, work on your scowl,
right Tom? Yeah. Work on your depressive
illness. You're going to need it. Yup. No,
it's nice. It's beautiful. Beautiful
cursing. Get, get a good curse. Going.
A disdain for humanity. You got to work
on that a little bit. I think it's cool.
You should go check it out.
It's fun. Yeah. It's fun. How,
how grumpy some of them are. I don't
know if they are anymore, but you know,
last time I went shoes,
everybody in my family's grumpy,
super grumpy stirs. That's
fun. Good for you. So that's a,
that's a pretty cool message. Very
resilient jeans. Very resilient.
Well, someone else told me this.
A Mommy's long time, long time.
First Time I was listening to a podcast,
three 71 when a listener wrote in saying
their dad picks up an Asian accent.
Whenever we're talking to an Asian
person, this is my favorite thing. Well,
this seems to be an epidemic as deeply
ingrained and dads as dad mouth is.
My father does the exact same thing from
the unintentional horrifically racist
accent to reverting back to a
caveman sentence structure. However,
my father's dad accident
goes a little further.
Not only does he do the accent of
the person you're speaking with,
but he is in contact with them.
Over the course of maybe an hour,
he starts to switch up accents,
even throwing in words from different
languages and it's, for example,
after an entire meal of him talking to
our waitress and a Sushi restaurant with
an Asian data accent. For some reason
over the course of a few sentences,
it morphed into a Hispanic accent,
even ending the night with Eh,
with him saying see and respond to the
waitress question of whether or not he
was finished with his
plate. Oh my God. Oh my God.
My father is neither Hispanic nor Asian
and has not had any extended periods
with anyone.
Um,
he would not have a familiar familiarity
preference like a was suggested by the
main mommy.
I think this matter needs further
investigation to get the source of data
accents, keeping them high and tight
Blake be wow. That is just remarkable.
I mean, I have so many countless
memories of my dad doing that.
Juan Nieto, did you have, did you,
would you able to buy some Nice
space today? He's good. No.
See why aren't you telling you like that,
that, and maybe this weekend we, uh,
should I show you some of the
things in the church is nice here.
You would like it and they were
like, okay, boom, boom, boom.
And it was like Jess,
Jess, so ridiculous. Um,
Miss. Say, uh, Oh yeah. Oh, by the way,
do you remember the, um,
master of accents last episode?
Um, which clearly we, you
know the fatty play? Yeah. No,
the also the other guy. What was
the, uh, um, the redneck. Oh, right.
Yeah. From Louisiana. That's right.
Somebody gave us a,
someone to give us the old one too.
Huh? So what? Four. Hi y'all.
I'm old man. Hey, I ran
five. You out balloons.
I got hope of will fold eight
wellness pick up fro. Oh, well
scare. Looks good, right? He
looks awesome. It's chin. Looks
Golf. I'm, I ain't go with state
prison here. Had a facial or bad at,
I'm wondering how paring it
back and forth out the failure
makes a lot of sense.
We said he was hauling printers.
It's hauling prisoners back and
forth. Oh, Angola state prison.
All right. That wouldn't make sense.
Yeah. Instead of printers. Yeah.
Cringe.
I had [inaudible] go [inaudible] have
to look it in tanker and then thank you.
Thank run and thanking. Yeah,
but now we know that, uh,
there's no printers that they
need and goal this state prison.
What a dumb fucking, well, yeah. Listen
in your defense as a master of accents,
I think that
your batting average is pretty
high. It's pretty, it's pretty easy.
It's substantial. That one word off. I
mean, you translated all that hillbilly.
I know, I know you hear this
dog. Of course. Of course I do.
Hey guys,
I don't have a man of video in a while,
but I'm gonna make up to make it up to
you because this year I've had held the
super,
super purpose where I worthwhile and a
lot of air six down to my stomach and
then I saw and more air because it makes
her up and said, I'm just burping it.
Write it up right away. So give
me a little bit, be patient.
I'm going to have to
swallow amount of air. Okay.
I like how all of those are like, hey
guys. Like it's always like, hey guys,
you know, you have your, your
little team of um, you know, yeah.
People who are dany acts.
Yeah, the Dany actors or crew.
It's always super upbeat. Hey guys.
So today on this makeup tutorial,
I'm going to show you how everybody
opens their view. Youtube is. Hi Guys.
I just want to talk to you.
Uh, hey guys. Hey guys.
Hey guys.
It's me,
Haley and I just on a target run and
I wanted to show you everything I buy.
I got some little candle guys.
I'm going to show you what I got.
There was some great emails.
Remember the Yankee Candle Guy and he
would do candle runs and then he would,
he would review the Yankee
candles. I like, I actually liked,
I really liked those
good smelling candles.
It was just like unbelievable that that
was somebody's whole plight, you know?
That was the whole thing.
Yeah.
That's everything that they do in
their life. It's just that, oh,
I just did a target round, but
there's no power. Like who's watching?
Who is watching that maybe got to only
be somebody who's also doing the exact
same thing. Right? Like teeny
boppers. Yeah. Well, teenage girls.
Well I think just know that other like
just sad shopper. Is that all right?
What'd you get? Oh, I
got something to wet,
so she gonna show us the Super Burp or,
yeah, let's, let's pull it up. Okay.
I'm really painful too,
so
yeah, that's right.
I don't know if I can watch it.
I didn't like,
wow.
You should see how that red
on the fucking Holy Shit.
That was disgusting. Even
I'm like, I'm disgusted.
It grows rarely rice.
Jesus.
I can't hear it. It makes it sounds
like Aaron, one day. I don't like it.
Hmm. I don't like it. I
like it. I don't like that.
All right.
Aww. That's so gnarly. You know how many
come? Where's the, where's the Pey Info?
I mean, why isn't she
like, guys, hello guys,
you need to pay for this video.
I don't like it.
Yeah.
Do you know how many complaints we're
going to get from people for this episode?
Here? Buds listen to that. And it
was a lot of cards. A lot of burbs,
Brown talk. There's a lot today, but
that one in particular was so loud.
Fucking gnarly. Blew up the
levels there. The chicken,
this is the, hey guys,
whisper born. Oh God.
This shit
as it given me so much anxiety.
It's making me so angry.
It's so gross. I can hear it.
The saliva on her. My, I don't like
that. Well, if somebody stealing,
I really hate this.
I really don't like this.
I'd rather watch the bug.
That's somebody's favorite thing.
Okay. Right. Okay.
Okay.
Huh.
I knew a girl in high school
that could do that. Yeah. Yeah.
Her name was Tiffany and she would drink
a Dr pepper in burp like that. Ooh.
I don't like this. This makes me so
fucking angry. All right. Isn't it?
I have no patience for this to you, right.
I mean, I, I'm not into it Tom. Yeah.
Talk to, yeah, I like it.
I don't mean dumb the show.
Huh?
I have come all over my face.
This is our [inaudible].
I have to come all over my face.
So disrespectful.
O f a r t and those are
the best ones of today.
So it's a really good show.
It really was a good show.
It was really fun. Uh, so we
go out. Should we go out? Yeah.
You got to come back to some patriarchal.
Put that shit down. Put that shit.
That shit down. Yeah, let's do
it. Oh, can I request? Yeah,
if you have it. Yeah. I was
just thinking today that, yeah,
mom's house.
You wanna hear that song? Yeah. It's
your mom's house. It's your mom.
And I like that line.
Let's see.
Jeans a and a dead.
Remember how that goes?
Let me see if this is it.
Really listen to this one too,
and we've had some fun.
Yes, he is. I said,
well, that's it. Go into that. This
is done the dinner. Then the bitch
is this it right here.
Bye guys. Hi, Mommy's lap
top
on task
jeans.
Wow.
Oh.