Okay.
Do you need to wipe down
what's with the jeans?
Mm mm mm.
Jeans.
Yeah.
Time for another episode of
your mom. Parts, your mouth
and your mouth around
your mouth when your nose
everywhere cause I love you.
So I'm going to ball sac,
Sacramento,
California, AAA this weekend.
I will be there Thursday,
Friday and Saturday with big urn.
Andy Erickson and I just found out
we're going to be doing an additional
Saturday show,
three shows on Saturday.
So make sure if you don't have tickets
you can get one to the new show Saturday.
Um,
a couple weeks from now I'm going to
Cleveland Steamer polarities in Cleveland.
It's actually a really great club.
So Cleveland please come out and I
have a couple more dates on sales.
Spokane.
No sperm can wash Washington.
Um, Syracuse is now on sale.
What would you say for Syracuse?
I don't know.
My juice segway.
Just New York and then Jack me off Ville.
Florida.
Jacksonville. Yeah.
Accident Bells. Now on sale
on the ground originated. That's sure
is very sacred. Your mom's house. Yeah.
You guys might be able to request the
room that it happened in the hotel.
Are you doing that comedy? So No.
Yeah. Oh, you are. Okay. Yeah.
So then you can definitely
request the room. Yeah. Yup.
Pretty exciting stuff.
Turds on the ground flashed in my shit.
Came up and spilled out onto the
bathroom floor at that hotel,
at the comedies out and I had to
tell the front desk staff and I left
immediately after. You never told
me there were turns on the ground.
I feel like it was inferred.
Unreal.
All right, well, um, what else do
you guys need any dance Jane do I do.
So guys come out April 1st and second
to flip pairs comedy club in Burbank,
California. Uh, April one and two
April one and two come out and see me.
And then April 7th, I'm at the
Irvine Improv in Irvine, California.
The eight o'clock show, April
20th. Hey, Hitler's birthday,
I am at the venture already colleague.
She says,
I did not request that date or anything.
It's just natural. It just happened.
It's like your mom's house dictated that.
And then May 27th or 28th the comedy
store in La Jolla, California.
And also generally I'm at the comedy
store. Saturdays eight o'clock show.
Not all the time, but that is my jam.
If you're in town and you're like,
I want to see Christina, I'm usually
at the store, the stove, the stove,
and then uh,
this Friday will be a flavors just
doing a spot flood pay or seven minutes,
nothing fluff.
Hey,
I did their five o'clock show on
Sunday yesterday and I was so much fun.
Do you said, man, dude,
five o'clock on a Sunday.
That's how you should do it on a Sunday.
Talk about practice.
So true. Who is that? It's
really open this show. Okay.
You Ready? I'm, I am. I'm
ready. I'm waiting. Let's
get this party started. Okay.
He did booty booty in the way.
I eat the booty.
Booty, booty. If a car to smell, I
don't give a mother fucking hell.
I eat that booty.
He'll definitely eat dead booty.
I eat it in the fucking train.
I need it in the bucket. Right?
The fucking side.
He did would a bucket bath.
Okay.
Don't bring anyone in loving to them.
Well,
well well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
What's
a wedding? Um, we, we Angie, you're crazy.
Low cost crave legs.
We've got,
we're going to get us some crazy
lugs here in a second. I was doing,
how does he do at Bam? You did
a really job. Homeys totally
was.
Homeys God is good.
You me for
real though.
Shout out to everybody all
over the world doing the thing,
stuff like that and stuff
like that is the best. Yeah,
that's right.
Now your Vlog.
I don't know if you've seen a everybody
listening seeing Tommy's blah. Oh yeah.
Uh, but it's up on your mom's house.
Pike. Yeah. Should I can pull it.
I mean this is all part of the show for
sure. And um, he threw down the gauntlet.
Well Shit, I didn't know you were
rushing the end of this stuff so
well I just got,
I got excited.
I thought we were going to land with a
bloody go ahead for sure. But I just,
it got me like, I'm so fired up
about your challenging him. I,
I wanted to go there. Well, yeah. Okay.
Um, well for people that
don't know, you know,
my man lokes um,
you know,
I sort of,
I sort of took his original,
this video as I thought he was
talking to me. Kind of an yeah.
Yeah. What's up Holly's? Yeah,
it's crazy. It's right here.
How many,
how many no frills dough.
So it's all about the
movement like you have,
he's got, he's got that swag for sure.
Yeah. So for reals though, he talks to me,
he talks some shit, you know, he gets in
damn. For reals know how
Michelle goes. That's it.
Everybody doing the [inaudible]
stuff like that. And then Bam.
Yeah,
fired up free shadowboxing fire session
and then I wouldn't mess with crazy low
cause I feel like boom.
And he's not afraid of it.
Do it in Walmart and show everybody.
That's what I'm saying.
Oh Wow.
Then this other dude I'm me
decided, you know, the
talk back to crazy horse.
What's up homie? For Real. God is good.
You know what I'm saying?
Shout out to everybody all
over the world doing the thing,
stuff like that.
You know what I'm saying?
I was getting training, no
days off. You know what I mean?
No.
Like my boy Burt and all fat and shit.
How cholesterol medication.
But that shit
crazy lopes.
See putting it down.
It's totally, you know, I mean I respect
the shit out of crazy legs. Yeah. Um,
for being, you know,
legit being like, yeah,
he's in the game is in the
game. Yeah. And um, you know,
he's in the shadow came he's a,
he's a rapper also. I didn't know.
I didn't know that. Yeah.
But he wraps a lot. Um,
and then he, uh, you know, I just,
I basically put this out
there so that he could,
uh, see it. And then maybe if
you wanted to do that fight for,
because I, you know,
I um, you know, right.
Every day shadow he's got punches,
man. I just wanted to give you a challenge
video, you know, why don't you and I
step in the brain and shit and you
could show me some of your moves.
We can sell tickets, we could donate
them to charity. Uh, we could, uh,
winter it takes on that because one
of the things, I know you're there,
I noticed that he, uh, he
does know how to throw a jab.
He knows how to throw a hook.
Right. He throws an uppercut,
but then he does really unusual Skype
hunches were like, he goes through,
you know, so I figured if I am
going to step in the ring with him,
I have to kind of get my Skype punch
game down at the end of this video.
I just do, I train for um,
weighted Skype punches.
They're called scribe punches.
Yeah.
That is right.
Then inspire but crazy
low CEC kettlebells,
but not yet,
but I'm not doing, I don't
consider myself doing kettle bells.
I think I'm just doing weighted Skype
line. I see you're saying. Yeah.
Because it's kind of the same
movement. Yup. You know? Yeah. I know.
I'm talking about, I'm
filming what I'm saying. Um,
I mean if you want to get a better
idea of what I'm talking about,
you can look at, um, these right here.
These are what I would say are like his,
probably what he's best known for.
Um,
oh right.
You can see,
see Skype punch, punch, punch. Got It.
Bam. Punch Skype, Skype, Skype budge.
Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
Crazy. Crazy. Maybe that's why
they call him crazy loads. Yeah.
That's his signature move.
Yeah. Damn. Damn boy,
you got to move. Got a
lot of speed dude. I,
I don't know how you're going to
fight this guy. He's got yeah.
All the moves. Yeah, I
know. It's pretty real.
It is pretty real. Um, and I gotta be,
I gotta make sure that I'm ready for it.
You know, you're not afraid,
but I wouldn't say that,
but I'm ready to,
you know,
see where this takes me.
Yeah. Um, I was brought,
it was brought to my attention that
there are some other crazy load things we
could, we should check out. Okay. Um,
one of course is his rap rapping prowess.
Um,
okay. This is a, this is a
crazy load. This one here.
Um,
oh, you really are in love with crazy
looks right now. It's really normal.
What's the fascination with him so much?
Why do,
why down the crazy looks rabbit
hole? I don't know, man. I mean,
he just is interesting to me,
you know.
What about his style
appeals to you the most?
Um,
probably
okay.
Just that he doesn't give a fuck.
I kind of really,
I was like that about people when
they're like, I don't give a fuck man.
He's really himself. Um, and I
like, you know, I like fighters.
Here's a
bitch.
You better quit
right now.
Take care of it.
Shit like that.
Right?
What are you sure you want to be this guy?
I don't know it.
That's why I'm starting to train harder.
Yeah.
I don't know if I'm,
I have experienced,
I'm not sure. You want to, oh wait,
look at the header on that. Which one?
Crazy little scroll up.
I want to see up. Uh,
higher up. Look at that
crazy face. He's crazy legs.
I don't know, Babe. I kind of don't
want you fighting this guy now.
I Dunno if he's stable enough. You know,
you don't think he's stable. Wow. Scary.
Well,
this is like a lot of the fighting stuff,
but for a long time, uh,
it was about rapping.
You know?
He was really right here. Shot
Jimmy here. How here it will be.
This is not new. It's awesome. She
me to say it straight up though.
Shovels out all the homies.
You all say
gas to keep pushing with this
Sam the Shin with this dream.
Chris and lows ain't fear then.
Yes. You know what I mean? Yes.
And d Chris Willow Street, brain state
heat. Chris loss has gone a pastor Mike.
So this home you can do it right?
Yeah. Oh yeah. You know? Yeah.
There's different levels. There's so much
happening with crazy lugs. Yeah. Yeah.
It's like, you know, there's like people
who are like, I'm a writer, director,
producer, act like he's that guy. He's
that guy that can wear so many hats.
Yeah, he does. He's so talented. Yeah.
You can't contain that kind of talent,
homie.
Yeah. This is a freestyle.
Looks like right here.
Crazy slopes up in here.
We all say it shall goes out.
Some Doug's pushing his game. Close
loans. Don't give a fuck about Oh shit.
Oh, keep pushing. Like
ain't no thang, you know,
saying straight up though, Chris Los
is going to spit. They'll feel bored.
I said a straight do I burn a kid?
I spray do it from the brain.
And those gaming APP pretty
play. No playing. What I Gus
to say Chris Lowe, sal about GIM
paid all about his dog for Shell.
Some of the yard did nub with our rep
to be a yeah, it's not that good. So,
um, he only moves his mouth too.
Everything else is perfectly still.
Have you noticed that? Yeah,
no blinking. Just Kinda,
well I gotta say I was getting really
into preparing for the fight and you know,
I was watching a lot of his
boxing video budding. Yes.
That didn't seem like, what
does my opponent, you know,
doing cause then that video that I put
out, obviously I'm challenging him. Yeah.
Turns out crazy loans
might not even be well.
Yeah. What do you mean?
Well wait a minute.
Not Well,
how like he has a cold or something worse.
Yeah.
Brain not well, what a
shocker. You're kidding. Well,
I mean, here's a, um, that's a weird,
here's an email we got from a listener
who also teaches a w people with special
needs. Um, he says, hi
Hitler. Mommies. Yeah.
Work with special needs kids.
I'm on spring break,
so I had some extra time on my hands
and I think I can fill in the blanks
a bit on crazy lows that watch youtube
videos such as this wonderful wrap
classic cop car.
Okay.
Um, that's the one we just saw it. Right.
I know he was robbing next to a cop cart.
It's all syndicate.
He never
did this. Never always pay me. Sure.
Okay. We get the idea.
Hmm. Hmm. Hmm. Anyways,
so he says,
judging from his somewhat slurred,
repetitive speech and wide set eyes.
I wanted to at first say
fetal alcohol syndrome,
but I think that crazy lokes yeah.
More than likely is on the autism spectrum
and probably to the more severe end
of it at that.
Yeah.
His occasional speech disfluency and
intense non blinking eye patterns make me
think this seriously. He doesn't
blink, surefire sign right there.
He also has some delusions of grandeur
and a general detachment from reality,
which are also signs. He's
a bit touched, as you'd say.
Also watching him spar and his movements
and his rap video lead me to believe he
has some form of Dyspraxia,
dyspraxia. How do you say that?
I'm not a medical professional time.
Another symptom of the spectrum which
can manifest itself with difficulties,
understanding movement patterns,
punches directly outputs,
ports in this case or things
like handwriting in school,
issues with motor skills, shuffling feet.
Well, spire, sparring, poor balance,
miss time movements,
general flailing about.
This is just one man's opinion, which is
legit to say. Yeah. Any way you slice it.
This dude is pretty fucked up of the show.
Keep those genes way up high and tight
by Hitler.
Um,
s I'd rather be retarded.
It's not so bad. Retarded people can
be happy and have good lives. You know,
I take that over GRANDPA's Dick in my
mouth today. Even with the funnel cake.
Yeah, but your GRANDPA's not, he's
not his Dick's. Not In your mouth.
In that scenario. He just jacking
you off. Oh right. Yeah, that's true.
That is a little less severe
than second way less severe.
Lowing your grandfather versus just
getting like a nice hand job from him.
Plus his hands are kind of old and softer
to try to do it unless he did a lot of
manual labor and then his hands would
be really hard and it could be calloused
and cross the hands.
But still it's soon as your
grants granddad's hands
like they were nice. So you,
we get a nice softy. Hmm. Yeah.
He never had final down ever.
I Dunno. Never brought it
up. Never brought it up. So
this is kind of depressing.
Yeah. It's another funny, funny background
story to a clip that you presented.
Thank you. Well, I'm saying,
oh glad I know this.
The depression for me now is that
I don't think I can fight him. No,
but you maybe you can rap battle him
that
it's really good idea, right? Yeah. Yeah.
You know what I'm saying? Yeah. All
people out there doing like, well no,
not if he's severely mentally affected.
It doesn't, it doesn't mean that it can't
be a good rapper. You don't think so. No.
It's just, it just affects
his stop. Remember that kid?
The Hay did the rap battle and he was
like, you're like, um, Rosie O'Donnell.
Adda bisexual baby shower.
That guy,
he actually was really good at rapping.
Right? It doesn't mean the clown.
I'm going everything. Yeah. But he was
really good. So, yeah. We don't know.
Crazy looks. Could surprise
you. True. He could.
You know what's happened to some creative
at place that you don't know about
because of his autism.
What do you want to bet on it?
It's like a back rub.
My back rub.
You think it will be good? [inaudible]
crazy legs. You don't know. Uh,
speaking of rap battles. Yeah.
Sorry. We got sidetracked.
You sidetrack the hell out of me. This
guy, you know, I thought you have to do,
don't you put grills on when
your teeth are kind of bad?
This guy's got great teeth.
He doesn't need to have bad teeth.
Covered a bad teeth or
something like that. Insurance
through like gold ventures.
He's about that life
right now. Oh, okay. Okay.
He did booty booty in the west.
I eat that booty in the
hood. I eat that booty booty.
If a to smell. I don't give a mother
fucking hell. I eat that booty.
He'll definitely eat that booty anywhere.
I like it. It's good, right? Yeah. He's
actually really, it's kind of Nice.
It's charming. He's got,
um, got good stage presence.
I let him be my buddy.
Really? Yeah. Why not? Okay.
I didn't think you were like that.
I'm really not,
but I like his enthusiasm and I might
let him just because of it. Jesus. Well,
this was submitted by David Camp. Thank
you, David from Twitter. You know what?
I'm looking at this Bristol stool chart
today and I think I had a type two
sausage shaped but lumpy.
It was a little lumpy.
What was yours are harder.
You know, they're harder. Oh,
I was definitely like a five or
six because they're a travel.
Yeah. I mean this is, this has
been a bad 24. I know, I know.
I've been living with you. You came home
and you started farting. It was just
horrendous. And then he farted in
the bedroom. I couldn't go in there.
It was just bad. It was really bad. What
do you think did that to you? I Dunno man.
Just living, you know, um,
probably wasn't the best final day
of eating the org evening, you know,
all that say, see that. But I asked
her yesterday and you're like,
I just had had some chicken
breasts on the plane and uh,
he didn't mention bad eating at the club
the night before the truth comes out
because you said, what did
you eat today? I didn't. Okay,
well Brown lock is on the case,
so let's go back in time and
see what caused the nice look
or I left Seattle Tacoma,
uh, which by the way, many, many
thanks to everybody that came there.
Always a good time.
I had a girl came there,
they all came all over me and I had a
great time. They bring in their ges.
Um,
anyways,
it was a great shows the last night,
Saturday night I um,
between the second,
the first and second show,
I did have some chicken fingers.
[inaudible] what kind of
dipping sauces they gave you?
Three for me, I think the dipping
sauces as it's what pushes like the,
all the mixtures of those strong,
tall though they do a different
style chicken breasts. There are two,
one clinic to comb the comedy club.
They don't do
the prepackaged frozen chicken finger.
You're used to,
they take actual like chicken breasts
and so you get like a massive breasts and
they, they flower it up and
so it's not as crazy. Yeah.
So I had that and then I had,
um, probably around one 30
in the morning, half of a,
an Italian sandwich. Um, and then,
and how many different kinds
of Salamis and there's more,
no, no, that was it for Saturday night.
The next morning I woke up and I was like,
I think I could,
I needed to take a shit, but I, I'm not
quite though. You can feel like, oh,
this feels bad inside of me.
And then I was running late.
So what I did was I just carried that to
the airport and then I didn't even have
time to ship before the flight. So
I shit on the plane first. Oh No.
Horrific. Now Walk me through
now you were in first class.
Obviously I'm not a diamond medallion
and were there a lot with our line of
people waiting cause
I'm those short flight,
sometimes people stand in
line and it's horrible. Um,
did you feel the pressure
is what I'm saying?
Just take that shit of hurrying through
the shit, which is why I don't show.
I saw this,
this lady go up in there and she
was in there while fucking bench.
She was a big bitch too. Like I knew
she was taking a fucking mean growler.
But yeah, by the time she was
done I finally got in there,
um, and it was like, I'm so
big for that size bathroom.
My shoulders touch the wall and like,
and the sink,
I can barely move around in there.
I went to wife and I got shit on my thumb.
So upsetting.
It's so upsetting.
And I'm the worst.
I tried to clean it.
Was it like diarrhea? Yeah,
just pool. So I'm like,
fuck some, you're sitting there
and washing it in the sink.
And then when I pick up my wife and I
do it again, so I'm like, God damn it,
I can grow. So I'm like
cleaning my hand anyways.
Then I spend like 10 minutes washing
my hands after that I go back.
But I just don't feel, I don't feel sick,
but I just don't feel great, you know?
And also you didn't have your
big day and it's an every day.
So hard to shit now without,
oh, I forgot to mention,
I probably had a couple of drinks too.
Like hard alcohol or beer. Hard alcohol.
Yeah, I'll do it. Yeah. Because
I'm going to drink a ton. Yeah,
that'll slap up your shit
real quick. Yeah. And then,
and then so I get off the flight
and I get a coffee. Oh. And then I,
I fucking crazy lugs.
What are you doing? Uh,
you can't do that.
No.
So then I get back here
and it's just fart.
Cities are ready to come.
I know I smelled them all.
And then I made you eat pizza. We
ordered a pizza. Yeah. And you that was,
and I was like,
son just got home and you're like,
let's eat pizza cause
I don't want to cook.
And it was Sunday and he treats
you well then the far, the far,
it's just came out even more.
And then how he showed up this morning
like five times already twice today. God.
So, but the, here's what I've had today
though,
Kinda of flipped up the game a little bit.
I had some Greek yogurt
just start today. Yeah. Um,
some coffee and then you made a delicious
healthy egg scramble with mushrooms
and tomatoes and a piece of, was it
a plum? Yeah. It's delicious. Yeah.
So, so far today doing good.
Never not shitting. Never know.
That's your Twitter handle.
Yeah.
You're always shitting. That's not
true. Every time I talked to you,
we're having a nice moment.
We're cuddling with the kid or the dog,
like we're having a nice family moment
and you're always like, I gotta Shit.
I gotta I gotta go, I gotta take a shit.
People Shit. Yeah, but not as much as you.
Lately, I feel like you've been shitting
a lot more than most people. I don't shit
more than most people. I think so. Um,
I kind of feel like I got a,
uh,
I feel like I got to pull back
when had crazy looks challenge.
I can't stop thinking about it. Yeah. I
don't think it'd be safe to fight him.
Well, like I said, I mean
maybe a rap battle instead.
All right.
Maybe. Maybe it might be,
it might be too intense.
He got really mad at that guy in
that video. He got really mad. Yeah.
That's somebody that's not stable,
Tom. And that's the guy that knows him,
you know? Yeah. Okay.
Um, speaking of poop.
Okay.
Oh,
look who's there.
Look who it is. Yeah. Look who it is
alive and well in Argentina.
Answering blogs,
answering Vlogs,
like ending the rumors.
Now did he invent that mustache
or was that a mustache? No,
at the time it was a fight for them. No,
I think my grandfather had a mustache.
Like I read it
about the mustache. You did. Why
it and why he initially went to it.
Because in a, when he was in the army, um,
I guess leading up
through World War One a,
they had to have gas masks and he had a
bushy mustache and it wouldn't allow the
mask to seal so trimmed it. Gotcha.
A lot of guys done did it. Oh,
okay. Yeah. All right. And
then you, now you've got this
really cool mustache. Yeah.
It's fashion forward.
Yeah. So, um, you know,
yeah. Don't, don't be, don't be
quick to judge this guy down.
Hey Hillary. So turns
out, look, look jeans.
I know,
I see.
Our man was in the pool.
That's what they say. Uh, turns
out there's these stories coming
out that he had a micro penis,
which I don't know how I discovered this,
but on top of that,
he was a fan of hoop and women
or women to stand over him while
he was lying on the floor and have
them defecate on him. He believed that.
You know what though,
I've also read things where a lot of,
they always want to do this with a
unpopular figures in history is make them
insane. It's like, it's
like it stops, it comes out.
It's not necessarily true is when I was
saying to demonize further demonize the
shitty person, you know,
you can say anything about
Heller. Nobody's gonna be like,
wait a minute, I know the guy and
he's not into that stuff. You know?
It's like I would just a way to
go. Can we take it easy guys?
You're being too rough on me.
Can I just keep hearing all these
mean things said about this guy? Um,
so you know, and this is the same document
where they describe his micro penis.
I don't know.
I said this,
the practice of this perversion represents
the lowest depth of degradation.
I guess. You really, you really are.
The piggy is peg of all. I think so.
I think Scott stuff is the
weirdest in my opinion. You know,
it does do anything.
I don't think it needs to be just,
I don't think you need to
qualify it in my opinion.
You're the foulest motherfucker.
Shit, it's wrong. It's taboo.
Yeah. So right here you can
actually picture her dumping on him.
Ava Bond. Yeah. I don't know.
I don't, I don't think so.
I don't think he was in all of that.
I think he was into killing Jews and
that's it. That's it. I don't know.
I believe that he was upset
with him. I do, I believe.
What do you think? He's into
me kind of. Hey, not poop.
Like I really sweats himself. Oof.
Maddie mcconaughey loves himself son.
Matthew mcconaughey. Yeah. But he, he
definitely, he sweats himself pretty hard.
He masturbates to himself a lot. I think
so, yeah. In the Lincoln and the Lincoln.
I just like these cars.
I've been,
I've been into these Lincolns
since before they paid me too.
I was jerking off in my Lincoln.
He is so fucking into math and Kona.
Hey. Yeah, I know. And, and
Lincoln's. No, and I'd say,
I do believe that he loves
his Lincoln. Um, yeah.
Yeah. So would you do what I was
going, well, I did some shows.
I went, uh, I did the ice
house. I did the comedy store.
I did full pairs, had lunch with
Sarah Burns who's been on the show.
We had Mexican food. That
was pretty interesting. Yeah.
And hung out with the kid.
Man. You know, he's, he's a
full time Gig. Three month old.
Oh, our kid, that one. Oh
yeah. Yeah. He's Super Rad.
My Dad came over with my
uncle Steve and that was fun.
What was your, what'd your dad say? Nice
House. This is nice. You know, you know,
they don't really, my family's not
very effusive. Nice. This is good.
As it's going to get them.
Yeah.
Yeah. But he's really into ls boy.
My Dad. Really no good. This kid,
this kid wants to move.
This kid is going to be walking soon.
Kind of curious to see your dad like that.
It's so rare.
He never is that adoring ever.
He wasn't like,
he's not like one of these guy got
Google guys. No, but it's cool to see.
I think when your dad's become
grandparents, they tend to chill. Yeah. I,
they become a little bit softer, which
is cool to see. You should get softer,
you know, as you get older. Yeah. Nothing
more terrifying than somebody that,
that doesn't get softer
now. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And he is happening to him. Yeah. It's
nice to see. Yeah, it's really cute.
He's really in, in our, our son. Yeah.
It's nice. Yeah. This is the good kid.
Good kid. Some boy. Nice.
Everybody on my family thinks that the
kid looks like you and everybody in your
family think the kid looks like me. No.
Weird. Yeah. I don't know why that is. Um,
by the way, uh, uh, do
you remember of course,
this clip from a,
uh,
a while back in the show?
A shock you on Chinese?
Yeah. Yeah. Sorry, that was really
loud. I don't know why that's so loud.
I shock you. Like Chinese. Me. Oh,
and if you don't remember,
we did a whole episode on this guy.
Turns out he was kind of a crazy
person and he was known for,
I'm going to restaurants and I
think this is Melbourne, Australia,
and eating elaborate meals and then
being like, I don't have any money,
like my drug that I like to do.
He would get arrested.
So this was, you know,
a clear from that we were sent a video,
a remix of his arrest to
music. No, that's always fun.
Yeah. I think it's actually,
oh yeah, it's back there.
Here it is here. Um, so this guy, yeah,
it was [inaudible]. This was like one
of the best clips ever on the show.
And somebody made a
song. Hi. So remix song.
Does this guy,
do you remember it actually of Hungarian
descent? Of course it does. Of course.
Crazy. And it was a chess master. Oh,
okay. Yeah, that's right. Yeah.
The Hungarians are great at chess and
polo water polo and acting crazy and crazy
shit. Yeah. We don't give a fuck. Yeah.
And then he told them here he
was telling the news cameras.
I had to suck your led Chinese man.
Get y'all hand off my penis.
It was submitted by Tony Mcfadden fall.
It's on his youtube channel.
Well,
Mondo Judo,
Chinese Kudo,
Josh Bullock.
Kudos.
Fantastic.
That's really good song actually. Good
job, dude. That's how my dad said.
I showed him the bid
day. He's like, oh good.
I'm going to come over here
to shit now. Oh, he did? Yeah.
Because he lives closer now. He's like,
well, I'm pulling me minutes away.
I can save my shed for your
house and like, thank you. Yeah.
It's so funny is how cold my family is
compared to like how we are with our kid.
I was watching my uncle and my dad
yesterday just sitting on our couch.
Just ice cold gangster. His
Hungarian style. Eastern bloc.
Fucking hardcore. Yeah. Dude. Like my,
our son's never gonna know
that sweethearts. No. Yeah,
the killer. Nice. Yeah. Yeah.
Nice. Good place called. That's it.
Yeah. Such gangsters. Yeah.
Remember when you met my ex mom? She's
Hungarian too. You were like Ice Queen.
Yeah, but that's not, she's
not like, that's how they all,
that's pretty Hungarian. That's just
standard dude. Because if you smile,
they see it as a sign of weakness. Like
eastern blockers. If you're like, hi,
I'm Christina. And they're like,
this girl is a fucking retarded.
They think you're retarded and
weak. That's so sad. Horrible. Yeah.
Well, if you look at Putin, like
if you watch how it's this. Yeah.
The Russians similar. Yeah. They
think you're just a week pussy.
If you show any kind of vulnerable
valuation for your stupid yeah,
like whenever we go to restaurants and
a waitress would be kind like high faux
can I,
what is faux fuck you don't call me Fox.
Like they're just so upset
and like they get super
mad and like did you um,
leave any room for dessert or like when
they ask you that question like, oh,
like there's so offended by it.
So funny.
I guess in Hungary they will ask you that.
Yeah.
I mean it's just all about
how you're raised. Right.
So I mean really your reaction to things
is it's based on your own environment
and culture. Yeah. That's a
pretty hard culture. Hard.
I didn't realize it until I had
been with you for the last 11 years.
I was a baby. Yeah, he's cute.
Good looking baby. This is a
good look to move. And your uncle
okay. Cut. Yeah,
he's a little softer because he travels
and he's like kind of more hippy leaning
a little.
Yeah. I think, you know, he's a little,
he goes to India and he went
to go on like yeah, you know.
But no,
my dad's all about the neon track suits
and those who are so funny together.
Ice Cold. I like seeing your,
your dad and your uncle together.
Such a trap man.
Especially hanging out with your family
where you guys are a little more normal
and Americanized. Like I didn't
realize how cold my family was.
Just like ice.
We would probably be colder.
We're probably a little warmer because
of my mom's side of the family cause
they're really,
that's the other end of the spectrum.
And now for sure Latins in the best.
Yeah. They're always like hug and kiss.
I love it up at all.
I know.
Yeah. All that stuff. Like
that's cute.
Latin soul into lobbying everything.
He's four
so love culture, man. It's,
you know, it's tied into,
I think it's some of the root is in
how much they adore their mothers.
That's that Virgin Mary
Catholic maternal a society.
It's very virgin Mary. That's
absolutely true. Yeah, for sure.
So it's always, you
know, the virgin money.
And then there's just very affectionate.
It's a very affectionate, you know,
you greet people with kisses.
Oh yeah. Hungarians do too.
So by that theory we should
be sweeter, but we're not,
you know, she kisses and all that. Yeah.
Yeah. I don't know if men, I don't
think men do that to men though.
It's considered kind of gay. Right. Do an
origin. Tina. Thank you, Amanda to men,
which is really weird to me and aren't,
were Hitler lives like Hillary
will do it when he says hi to you,
like if you see Hitler and
you say hi, he'll give you a
kiss on the cheek. But, um,
I didn't experience it anywhere else
with men, just Argentina. I'm never,
never improved. Never. And um,
definitely never in Spain it
was always just the women.
I just had this vision of like, when
you go to Peru and they grab your Dick,
is that what they do? Yeah.
That's the common thing. Like
if you're a painter, yeah.
They go, hello. And they all
law and grab your deck. Yeah.
And then if they know you, they'll blow
you. That's what I heard. And Yeah.
You know what's neat about my country
of origin is hungry is like the porno
capital. It is the world. I don't
know. I married a Hungarian woman.
My favorite, my best friend in the
whole would have been married to him.
Think about it. He married a, been
married. He married a Hungarian.
I'm not living in Hungary though,
but I'm saying like,
let's say your parents hadn't left
Hungary and you were born there.
You could be married to Rocco.
Right. Okay. Yeah. That's
okay. That's a possibility.
You know,
I heard the porno industry happened there.
It's because the Russian mafia,
once a communism ended,
the Russians came in and just started
doing all that business there.
They took over. He's so legendary.
The Rocco. Yeah, I know. Well,
he's out of retirement now. He's back in
the game. Right. I thought I heard that.
No, just behind the scenes. He's
done. He left his mark. Yeah.
Can I tell you a funny story
about Red Ban? Red Band?
Yeah. It just reminded me, um,
I was at the comedy store there at night
and apparently Jerry Seinfeld stopped
in to do a spot and he did like a Q
and a session. It was pretty crazy.
First of all.
So people know that Seinfeld was a
normally drop in and in that way, no.
You know it's not a common
everyone else does but not,
and I had heard also just to make,
to make the point of how
big of a deal this was.
He hasn't been to the store since like 79.
That's what they were saying.
So not a lot of that.
Yeah there's a lot of drama between the
Improv and the comedy store back in that
era about being a paid regular at one
club wouldn't let you do the other.
And then what happened
to the comedy store?
Some crazy booker was holding the reins
to that place and like wouldn't let
major acts do drop ins cause they weren't
quote passed by Mitzi who's the owner
of the comedy store.
So like you'd have like Sarah Silverman
wanting to come and do drop ins at the
comedy store 10 years ago and this
book or we'll be like, no you can't.
And so that guy, you know, he,
he's gone now and the doors have open
so now it's like become a better place.
But anyways, so Seinfeld was there,
which was a huge deal. Huge deal.
And he's doing like this Q and a with
the comics afterwards in the audience I
guess.
And our friend Brian Red Ban
raised his hand and goes,
I have a question.
Do you wipe standing up or sitting down?
Hilarious. I think it's so funny. I
apparently not in a lot of people. Agreed.
Yeah. And people can see, I think he
walked Seinfeld then he was like cyber,
all the answered it and it was like,
all right, I gotta go. That was the last
good job. Good job. It was really,
I thought it was really funny.
I would have been like a,
I have a question.
Do you jerk off to your portion in
them are just looking at them? Yeah.
Seriously. How much money does
that guy have? Um, I mean, he has,
I don't know. There's, there's
different, you know, uh, accounts,
but I think he's probably in
the high nine figures for sure.
And Jay Leno. Yeah. Supercars too.
He loves his cars. I haven't touched
any of way tonight. Show money.
It's been my standard line. Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, they love cars,
man. Yeah. So just, uh, he just
sold some cars this weekend,
so I felt it was needed.
He auctioned off some of
his, uh, Porsche's. Aww.
Good for him for a lot of
money. Wow. Yeah, he has like,
he needs the collector.
Well, he said he was, he wanted to put
them back into circulation. He goes,
I've enjoyed them. It's time
that I respect that too.
It seems like a nice dude.
I don't think there's anything wrong
with that guy. No, I don't either.
And I think, I believe that he's
probably like, I've had these a while,
he's probably just put it back out there.
So all of them.
But I love that Bryan asked that question.
Sorry.
Do you wipe sitting down or standing up?
And he answered it right and he
answered it, I think like, all right,
that's enough assholes. Did they?
They walked him, which is Brian.
People are mad.
People weren't happy about that.
Other comics were upset with Brian.
That's really funny. I liked it.
I liked it a lot.
That's hilarious.
You know you were watching
that documentary on twins.
It was twins that didn't know
that they had a twin sister.
It's called twin stars.
And then Lex, this um,
came in here,
let's see who,
who sent this twins were swimming by
a whole bunch of people. Okay.
It's kind of just weird. These,
these are two identical twins,
but the kind that barely
ever leave each other's side.
It's so gray gardens.
Yeah. It's really, really,
it's kind of just odd to
watch their act and speed.
This kind of shit.
Yeah.
32 and they've hardly ever been apart.
It's just one time when they were 17,
one of the swearing hospital
getting now appendix out.
But Bridget used to come every
visiting hours when I could,
but if I was allowed to sleep there,
I would have, they talk funny.
Yeah. Can accent is that master
of accent is all the heirs are,
oh, Jay could by news Aylien oh
yeah. It could be. Don't know.
It's hard to tell the Kiwi and the
Aussie. Um, well no, I can, you can.
Sorry. Master of accents.
There are so creepy. A retard.
Maybe not retard able to,
yeah, I mean, Crepe is, that's,
you know, this is more than I can
Sklar brothers handle, you know?
I mean there really are not just,
they're not just finishing
each other's sentences,
they're just talking over it and it's the
same. Yeah. It's pretty amazing. Yeah.
I liked,
I liked watching them bicycle tandem.
Do you think they rub 'em out together
the same day, but that's so rude.
Yes.
I think they do,
but it's an impossible date.
One of these girls, you can't,
no way they're going to,
they're going to be tethered to each
other until they're on our deathbeds.
These two, they're going to ruin
their own lives. They would do,
if one of them did meet somebody
and talk to him,
she would say, well, you have
to have a friend. Oh yeah.
You know,
these two are going to be old
and together. It's adorable. It is
children.
They resisted efforts to price them
apart apparently when we were little,
mom did separators as one rent.
Little total is one state
at an [inaudible] and we
just just stopped swearing
and that's when we were little
by ladies in of screaming.
And then when they put us back
with ticket, we are happy.
Wow. That's so cool. By
creepiest shit. Crazy.
They're like, what is that
movie Jack Nicholson in the
shining. The shining twins
girls. Little creepy. Yeah.
Well that's so crazy. I know.
I like that. This lady looks
like you. I like your haircut.
I'm going to get that. I love the front
swirl. That's the mom cut for sure.
Has Your expression, and you guys
have the same now my favorite,
just the back hair here is really nice
and I think my father has his haircut.
Well to me it just says lady,
this is Eastern European tennis player.
This is Ethan Lendl. Right. Then Lendl
have this just to your hair differently.
Right. And whenever I see that, I'm like,
you're just doing this to yourself. Well,
she's fully resigned to mom hood.
You can see here she's wearing the Hoodie,
but she's still tying it. It's weird.
It doesn't want anyone to know sex.
This is a look that says, do not come
near me with a penis. Ever. Ever, ever.
You know, I figured out why
mom's dress frumpy, mom fashion.
Especially if you're a breastfeeding,
it's because you have to access your
boobs all the time and there's not no cute
stuff,
but she's given up for sure.
She doesn't need her boobs to come out
anymore. No, no, no, no, no. This is,
she's almost the dude at this point.
It's really close.
She might be transitioning. You don't
know because I haven't played the
game on my [inaudible] took place.
Well, I'm happy to put your
mind. Jesus Christ, Jesus Christ.
It's really, it's really bad.
And here's the thing, okay. Okay.
You don't have to be a
supermom as saying that.
And I'm not shitting on her for like, I'm
shitting. Here's what I'm shitting on.
Just try all it is. Work with
what God gave you. You know,
just try a little man. If you want to be
a woman, if you want to be heterosexual,
I don't know if she, why don't you
tell everybody about your dream?
I dreamt that some other guy busted nuts
in me and I didn't know who it was and
then I got pregnant again and I was like,
oh,
I have to tell Tom and I'm pregnant again.
It's a dream vein. Well, let's
see what she, what she has to say.
What does this nice man
at school, they teach us,
couldn't believe it was school.
We're sitting at the same table and
they accused you of cheating because I
thought we were all looking at
one another and sailing. Now he's
questions. No, we rub the die and cheap.
So they split us up and they gave,
is it different for not,
not be exactly the same questions,
what we hadn't before and where we came
out with the same answers and questions
and, and I would just
shop together and I said,
sorry.
Oh my God, it's so weird. So weird.
They didn't really let that guy talk
at the beginning of [inaudible].
Gentleman was going to
say something again.
How do you think his tennis game is?
This guy doesn't even speak.
Holy Shit.
Some parts of the Midwest.
This is the norm. Where do
you think this chick? A Guy,
what do you think it is?
Nice human gets their haircut and
what did they say when they walk in?
Do you know what to do? Waiting. They
say it's gimme the tennis player.
Give me the tennis player.
Yeah.
Gimme a ATP top five 1989 rock it out.
That is an egg in 89 90 haircut.
Of course,
Jesus. It's all as a Midwesterner.
There's a lot of ladies in the Midwest.
Oh yeah. Here we go. Sam
Kennison lookalike women. Oh No,
the last, Jesus Christ.
I don't know. Again,
I'm not knocking her,
but all of a sudden this still,
this still is more a feminine,
you know it's also a little lady di
circuit nuts. He know what it is.
I think she was going for Lady Diana
at 1980 and you know it looks dated.
It's a little dated. Is it? No, it's
very dated. What I'm saying is though,
as far as the stills go,
this one is more dude,
and this one is before she transitioned.
This is a woman
because here's,
here's what would fix this.
I'm just saying grow the hair
out just a little more. Yeah.
I need to cut my ears out
so that I can hear. Well,
when you see my hair fall over,
my ears cut them out so that
could hear stuff that is so much.
Otherwise I don't hear anything. That's
what it is. Because being a woman,
there's not a lot of utility in our
clothing and there was no utility in our
hair. There's no utility and wearing
makeup. Right. So when a woman gives up,
she's going all function over form
function for sure. Fuck you. Fuck.
There's hear nothing.
Yeah.
It's all function at her, at her
appointment. I guess a terrible haircut.
It's actually the only thing really.
She needs to it to try with it.
Just get a fucking haircut. The haircut,
it's bad. It's really bad. But then, okay,
she's Ozzy
and you can afford it. You
got a nice microwave. Yeah,
we're have a friend that can do it for
you. Yeah. Just grow it out a little,
but a lot. Ozzie women, I hate to say this
too, I've seen a lot of stuff they, yeah,
yeah. They got this haircut,
the outback steakhouse
and half back. We don't need long.
Huh? This is not an Ozzy cut though.
Yeah.
You just said it's a Midwestern guy.
It's a Midwest then it's Australia
because there's a lot of parts of their
remote in Australia, like the
Midwest, so basically and uh,
in remote locations,
Indiana and Illinois and Australia.
Path path. Yeah. I Ayers rock hits
where you're going to see it as kind of,
uh, I think crocodile dundees hair
was like this still hasn't it done?
Dundee had a nice custom feathers.
Yeah. It says the feathery look. Yeah.
This is the ultimate,
I don't want to touch a dig ever.
Let's see if she's anything between
stream of married life together.
Well,
my plan is probably just next door to
one another and have the exactly same
identical house.
Even now furniture probably
being the same spots
or by a creation.
Helpful to have a real huge
be combing or live together.
Aw, wonder, would it be like
to double team them? Yeah.
He should ask. Well, I mean, I can't
ask him. We can just talk about it.
Like I wonder if they do the same,
but I want you to ask them that
question and just see. I'd love to,
but I wonder if like,
if,
if like she starts eating your
booty and then she's like,
she knows what to do or does she
wait her turn, you know, like, no,
they think it's simultaneous.
So you think she tries to do at
the same time or no, it was like,
I got to get on the balls and cock
right now. Oh my God. I don't know Tom.
It's a really interesting question
now I really thought provoking me.
Fund the Double Dip.
Let's do it on nasty, Bro.
Let's talk about it to move from one to
the other. Boop, boop. And they're like,
yeah, yeah, yeah. And, and in
unison. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. Right in there. Right in
that right. And that right there, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Um,
yeah,
they're cute.
They're going to live together for the
rest of their lives and then one of them
dies and it's going to be horrendous.
Yeah.
And then the other one will be like done.
Yeah. Done. It must be nice to have,
but it must be nice to have like someone
that you're so as a coach to them for
Titus 25 years.
Okay.
Australia's premier tennies
players. They're all so
identical. Twins. Same Becky.
And
she doesn't say anything. That's one.
They both both serve pretty nice.
Have a nice set of
it's bad. Yeah, it's bad.
Boy, I'm gonna say Minnesota.
This is a Minnesota look.
Not Everybody. Right.
But basically if you leave Minneapolis,
this is the state here.
It definitely is.
And I know this from the airports,
like when I've been hanging out, I lived
in Minnesota. You're not that wrong.
Wisconsin, Nebraska. I've seen
this in a couple of packers games.
Yup. What do you, hey, here's
what we're going to play.
What kind of footwear is she
wearing? Oh Man. It's real sensible.
And like you said,
really nothing acute going on down there.
Um, she's probably either
wearing burkin stocks,
toe shoes,
or like really pat like
heavy orthopedic tenant,
orthopedic mother, the
straps, the many layers.
Think about the Velcro is
easy on,
easy off. Yeah. What do you
think your panties look like?
They're sensible. They're big.
They're not a pretty color.
They're not like pink or fun happening.
She's got, I got chocolate brown.
Does that matches my dicky? Whoa. A year.
Me. Shouldn't we be getting a call
from those guys bringing our TV?
Now you know what people
have been asking us.
Why haven't you covered
the Downton series finale?
Why haven't you covered how so far?
It's one way we don't have our TV's
hooked up yet. We just moved in.
So it's going to be a minute. Hopefully
today. Yeah. I supposed to be today.
We don't have TVS.
We haven't seen the Downton.
We haven't seen house of farts. I know
he's been out for 10 days, so bummed out.
I'm so mad. It took a lot of
resistance to not, you know,
jump online and watch. Oh,
right. A lot. Uh, you know, uh,
discipline, discipline. So
not to resist watching it. I'm
so glad he did. Yeah. Yeah.
Cause I want to watch it on the
big, on the big stream maybe. Yeah.
I want the baby jeans goes to sleep. We
can catch one episode night and catch up.
That'd be fun. Oh my God. It's tremendous.
Railey and wondering what Claire Is.
Bud Hall smells like this season.
It's got to get better.
It gets better with every year. Yeah.
And there's probably scenes of her,
I'm sure they incorporated that
into the story where she's like,
oh I'm the president's wife.
Presidential ass smells.
It makes people come up the
stairs and Neil remember orange.
You see they had orgies in the other
seasons already. Not Orgy three ways,
like the first season. She's like,
you need this. And then they do it.
They did it with one of their secret
service guys. Dude. Cause he's leans,
he's ACDC is my dad says
suit about cock double cock.
Yeah. Do you think we could get
into that kind of lifestyle? Yeah.
Yeah. I'm Paulina by of course.
What about her? Could she join in?
I think that'd be like one for you to
test drive and then, you know, here,
I'd like to hear the report afterwards.
Didn't you get offered to go
to some BDSM clubs? Yes I did.
I met really cool couple.
Um,
it's like everyone had left except for
six, eight people after the show Friday.
Yeah. And this couple was talking
and then I was there with a,
a comic named Amy Miller.
Really funny.
And she was talking to the lady and
somehow through their conversation,
uh, led to, they're like, oh yeah, we do
porn. And I was like, Whoa, Whoa, whoa,
Whoa, wow. Washed is bullshit. And then we
just started talking and they were like,
of course the most,
um,
like laid back, cool,
warm, all always made,
no big kind of thing of it.
And then they're like, oh,
we're hosting this a BDSM party tomorrow.
You guys want to come?
And I was like, that would be a lot of
fun. And they were like, oh, swing by.
I'm like, I dunno man. I
go, I got a late show here.
I'm going to be showing up at like 2:00
AM what am I going to do at a BDSM part
is like, it's just fun to watch.
I don't know. It's kind of like,
I remember in first year in
college in San Francisco,
they have this thing called
the exotic erotic ball,
which is like their version of
that around Halloween. And uh,
my friends and I were like, we're
going to go, we bought tickets.
And if you're not really
participating in something like that,
it's so fucking uncomfortable cause it,
the room just smells like a hot diaper.
I look so gross. I would like to
go, people watched at that thing.
But the thing is, I think if, if
you're a non participant and you're,
and you're watching people, then they're
like, whoa, what the fuck are you doing?
That's rude. You just be like,
Nah, I'm watching you be weird.
Yeah. So I'm not against doing
it. They were super nice.
So I really do appreciate the invite.
Very nice.
I wish it would go to a BDSM party.
Yeah.
And then use all of a sudden you're just
scrolling online and you see me, uh,
strapped and leather hanging from a, from
a ceiling, Tom. And you're like, what,
where, when did you do this?
I'm like, Oh yeah, I forgot
I did that. Like all casual,
you know, that was a while ago.
How long ago? Like three weeks ago.
You know how many people will
be in you? I think so. I did.
The bear community are huge
in that community already.
Huge and huge in that
community. I'm no Maca SF. Oh,
that guy was the best. We were supposed
to have him on the show. Mac. Yeah.
In San Francisco.
I think we want it.
We invited him out because his
boyfriend was was right. Yeah.
We got to get back with that.
Yeah.
Four years later we definitely should
reach out again. He was great. The number
that the boyfriend sent, um,
some clips we were like, whoa.
He's intense.
Yeah.
He's real intense scenes and like
bathrooms with four dudes and yeah,
it's really beefy and a lot of,
you know,
you share a lot of that stuff.
A lot of that stuff. This is
actually from a Mac. I
sat right here. This is,
oh,
wrap your head around
that sound for a second.
That's not Mac.
That's the other thing.
Yeah.
You've never heard that sound and
your own personal life, right?
Oh,
I mean that is eh and S.
Yes sir. That is Mac. SF.
Yeah, that's the other guy.
Yeah, look at it. Sure. M a. C. K. S.
If even if you want to see some real shit,
it's intense.
It is not like a, you know, novice level.
It's a really fucking, yeah.
It was gnarly. This is,
this is the pros man. This fear, if
you're into the amateur stuff, don't.
Nah,
no.
Oh Geez.
Scott.
Yeah. Yep. Just put it in there.
It makes you think you're
really missing out in life.
You know when you listen to those clips.
Yeah. Like what have I been doing?
And now that, yeah, that no one's, no
one's talked to me like that before.
Wow. I eat the ass and busy all the
time. I got nothing. There you go.
Excellent. Yoshi too. I
ran into him last week.
I'm in a black woman in Yoshi last
week series. Tell your story first.
I just saw how many came out from the
Middle East. He had some crazy stories.
So hooker stories of course,
I'm sure. Um, I was at Fedex.
Fedex,
yes.
And, um, I'm looking
at the woman across me,
a black woman working behind the counter.
I'm,
the light is reflecting off of her name
badge. Kind of oddly like, you know,
you go like,
I can't really make out the letters.
There's like a shiny name badge and I,
and then I go like, this can't be right.
I go, you is your name of Yoshi? And
she goes, yeah. And I go, Oh really?
And she goes, yeah, I go where you would,
you have a military parent? And she goes,
oh, cause he was stationed in Okinawa.
So that's why they named me Yoshi. I go,
I have a Japanese friend named
Yoshi. And she goes, yeah, yeah.
People always trying to figure it out.
But no, my name's Yoshi. That's my real,
you think as a man's name is weird.
Oh fuck. I don't know. What do I know?
I liked it and gave it to
her. Oh, look at you. Yeah,
sure.
So shout out to fed ex
and what not and whatnot,
you know, say for real though. I'm
like God. Okay. Alright, I'll write.
You know what I'm saying? God is
good. God is good all the time. Yeah.
Wow. Good. I keep pushing.
Did you get to sleep at all while
you were away? Lucky one night. Yeah.
That was a dude notes Friday morning.
Yeah. I would ask how that goes,
but I can't really talk about,
no, I know, but I had to like,
so people know that means I had a
phone call with agents and networks.
Like here's what's wrong
with what you wrote. So that
there wasn't so bad.
It was just that I had to get up to do it.
I was like I never one day a week,
one day I know that I could sleep.
I had to get up fucking socks and then I
was up cause it was an hour phone call.
It's the worse. I know what
happened last night. Um,
there were these two girls from Alabama
sitting in the audience and they were
young and like hip looking and I'm like,
you guys are definitely from here.
And they're like, no, we just moved here
from Birmingham. I'm like, good for you.
Good. That is huge. You know we have
like one listener in Birmingham. No,
we don't play monk, but he's
not the only one. Yeah, no.
How five others? No, it's more than
that. It's not that, it's not that small.
Birmingham's got like a tiny city and
when we went there and you order like five
different thousand chicken wings,
all of the show,
we did a show at the uh,
whatever dome started and then Whoa man,
fucking phone of your phone.
Yeah. Yay. Then the um,
we went to a wing place. It was like a
popular wing place. What is it called?
Buffalo Wings are wildly, I think
while wings. And then I was like,
I don't know which one is like the
one to get, you know, when you go,
like what's the good one though?
Like, oh, people like this.
So I walk out and you're like,
what'd you get? And I go,
I think I got like 40 or 50 wings,
no more than that. Even get so many.
And then we sit in there in the,
in the hotel, it's like five,
10 wings. And it's like, I feel pretty
good. I'm like, well, just so you know,
I have 45 more weeks.
We literally had like 10 boxes.
I'm like, baby, what did you do?
Dude did. Yeah, it's a little,
I did like a Sushi order with
wings. Good Roll Tad. Well
some nights, Tyro, Tyro,
Tyro tower. So weird.
And they're friendly to you in the south.
Hey y'all.
Hey y'all roll tide route happy.
It was really,
that was a good trip. Yeah, I did actually
enjoy it. We drove through the south.
Remember some of it was really pretty.
We did Nashville. Yup. Did we do Atlanta?
I don't remember. No, no, no. We
did. We did. We did. Yeah. Yeah,
we drove through Tennessee. I
remember, you know what I'm saying?
And talking about, you know,
God is good. God is good
though, by the way. So
speaking of the south,
thanks guys for keeping a
Trump alive in the polls.
I'm an embarrassment. That
is, it's pretty wild, right?
Can't really, Wayne County. Yes you can.
Um,
but we thought,
why not bring out another candidate who,
you know, maybe you could
rival, uh, Donald Trump,
so we have a clip of another
candidate to consider.
Well, of course I believe that I
paved the way for Donald Trump.
I brought ridiculousness of politics and
he saw an opening and he jumped on in
there. So I think there is,
I think I drove my own base.
I played towards my own constituency.
You know, I have my own people, so yeah,
there's plenty of room for me
in this mass for sure. In fact,
I am on the ballot here in New Hampshire.
I won the Democratic primary ballot.
It's vermin supreme. Oh yeah. Yeah.
So, you know, I'm just thinking that if
you are considering voting for Trump,
why not consider voting for vermin
supreme? Okay. He has a lot of ideas. Um,
if you want to take a look for are people
that aren't watching our youtube bay.
Um,
could you describe what you see?
Yeah.
Is that a helmet,
like a GG Allen helmet or is it a s?
I can't tell.
I think it's more like a wizard.
A wizard. Yeah. He looks like a,
like a hippie wizard full gray beard.
He's got an American flag embedded in
the beard. Is there a broom? It does.
You have a Bruin? Is Is, oh, I can see
that. Yeah. He's cleaning up the streets.
I think that's what that metaphor
is. Um, he's got supporters,
guys was rainbows and Unicorns behind him.
It's all kinds of cray cray.
Well I've known for for a basic
platform planks do my platform,
the hours falls of course
Zombie preparedness.
The only caters with the
Zombie Preparedness Plan.
And I'm going to a harness the zombies
for energy sources by utilizing the
latest and giant hamster wheel technology.
We will have lots of zombies and we'll
just sort of dangle brains in front of
them and then they will turn the
giant turbines creating energy. Yeah,
that makes sense. It makes
more sense. And Trump,
I think he makes a lot more
sense than Trump. Um, and the,
the whole,
uh,
I tell you the idea that I didn't know
there were that many stupid people.
I knew that there was a lot
of stupid people. I didn't
know there were that many.
Yeah. It's really appalling that people
are into, I think it's such a, well,
my family or even into
trial and really very bad.
Who can't sell? You want to tell
you off the air, off the air.
It's intense. Right? It's so
dumb. It's so fucking dumb now.
He's the dumbest buffoon ever. I
mean, he's a failed businessman.
He's a,
he's just a complete failure as a
megalomaniac personality disorders.
We're talking about a guy that just has
filed bankruptcy fucking five times and
you know, he just licenses his
names out the place. It's the only,
he's not even like a
really savvy businessman and
he's a big ad pretty openly.
It's kind of crazy.
So fucking annoying.
I actually feel bad for conservative
people because he's not one of you.
You know, he's not a conservative,
doesn't really give a shit. I know.
He's just like, whatever.
What are you doing? I Dunno.
I feel like you were selling my shit.
Oh. Oh. So I don't know. I just ate.
It's horrible. This guy has got
some, so that's what I'm saying.
This guy's got ideas.
That's the other thing is Trump actually
doesn't know any policy stuff. Yeah.
If you,
if you bring up any point,
well what are you going
to do about immigration?
You're going to see lot of things
are going to be different. Uh,
what about terrorism? It's going to
be way different when I get in there.
You'll see I'm not gonna I'm not going
to get pushed around anymore. Oh,
okay. Great. That's really good.
Cool. Number two, of course. Time travel
research. I, we'll go back in time.
Kill Baby Hitler with my bare
hands before he said Bush. Well,
once again, Jeb Bush said he
would kill Baby Hitler. Hell yeah.
Would I say I've got it.
He's promising he's going to go
and kill Baby Hitler. That's huge.
Wow. I mean huge. Your politician
nowadays will make such bold claims,
but a lot the wizard.
Wow, that's awesome. And
the thing that I want to know is
how will that affect this drop?
I mean, you realize if he actually
does what he says is going to do,
when I go to press that button, there'll
be nothing there. Nothing to Ah,
you're right. Yeah. Time travel. Wow.
That's kind of ruins a
few episodes of our show.
We're going to have to write into this
guy. Yeah, Dude. Um, maybe could, I dunno.
Maybe it was. Yeah. So now,
now you're seeing somebody who's
out of the box, but makes sense.
I'm not like Trump. He does make more
sense than Donald Trump. You do it.
And then of course,
mandatory tooth brushing laws.
This has been eroding the gum line of
this great nation of ours who were too
long and this great country has been
suffering a great moral in oral decay in
spirit and incisors are country's future
depends on its ability to fight back.
We can no longer be a nation. Indentured
are very salivation is at stake.
What does mandatory to request
your law is really about,
is strong team for a strong America.
May we become a sea of shining, smiling,
shiny, smiling, shiny, smiling,
smiling, smiling, smiling,
shining faces from sea to shining sea.
Thank you. I've referenced the brave.
Wow.
This is a lot of stuff
that's tapped into the show.
Did a dental updates. He's into, hey,
Hitler's and all of it, man. Wow. Yeah.
But I will say that he was a son.
Feels like he wants to stop
saying hey, littler. But you know,
I would say that in this case.
That makes sense. Yeah. You know?
But he definitely likes dental updates
to clearly and again, those, that,
the little
bit we've seen here, much more policies
savvy than Donald Trump actually has.
Tangible ideas. Yeah.
Real ideas. Real plans.
Oh, one, two and four. What about
number three? Oh, number three of card,
three ponies for all Americans. It is of
course a job stimulus creation program.
And it is a federal pony identification
program when you have to raise taxes for
that. No, they're free.
Tony's. That's it guys. Great.
Yeah. Is he in San Francisco?
I Dunno. This seems like a San
Francisco kind of guy. I don't know.
But he's really, I don't know. I'm a big
fan. I'm a huge fan too. Vermin supreme.
All right.
So, um, I dunno, uh,
if you're a Trump guy,
maybe reconsider you start thinking
about what is he running under vermin?
Uh, I'm assuming an independent, uh,
we got to wrap this up pretty soon.
Oh,
do you want to see this real quick?
Cause we've been really high on ours.
Second Chinese male and a lot of people
have been asking you about it on the
show. Here is a, um,
well I'll let you just see what shows
you wouldn't use a dry paper
towel to wash a dirty car.
So why use dry toilet paper
to clean up in the bathroom,
the water to get clean yet prove your
bathroom routine and get completely clean
with a new good day, buddy.
Look, traditional toilet
paper is rough and scratchy,
but the day buddy Sprague
gently washes your clean paper,
gets messy paper and can be expensive.
But with the bid day buddy,
you don't have to worry about any of that.
Wait a minute. Well, you still have
to use paper. You dummy. Well, yeah,
but I all I could think about in this ad.
It's just thinking of this
woman taking a shit. Me Too.
Everybody that speaks in this,
I'm like just picturing them shitting.
I picturing her wiping,
not shaming and I love the argument is
you just don't want to waste toilet paper.
Yeah. Instead of like,
Hey, it feels nicer there.
She also said like you ran out of
paper like, no, you don't like,
it's a big problem in every household.
You're always out of paper. Yeah.
It's an efficiency. Save money. Yeah.
A picture of me taking a shit right now.
You wouldn't,
not even in this nice blonde lady
takes shits or the fatigue shirts. Yes.
I never would've thought that. Listen
to this lady, but then she does.
Eve how clean you feel after
you go to the bathroom?
Don't now I picture her with like the
sweetest, cleanest little ass hole.
It sounds like a pink waxed. Okay.
Just super plain asshole. Relax.
You just want to eat
up the boot and relax.
I only go to the bathroom.
She should just say it's specifically
for shitting this product.
I've literally never
felt like this before.
Water toilet paper just pushes the wipes.
Leave residue behind. Yeah, it's true.
I tell you buddy uses fresh water to
rinse. You clean leaving nothing behind.
Now why didn't they use Brown
stuff for this? This is like a,
that purple purple is an
interesting color choice.
Make it brown so we know
what you're talking about.
Or black or red because of the deep,
deep blood red.
You're probably used to
seeing a lot of blood.
When you go to the bathroom with the day
buddy, all that blood gets washed away.
If
you're used to,
pulls a blood leaving you when you sit
down to go potty. Now with the day buddy,
all that blood gets flushed away.
Read a book and you can adjust the water.
Right?
Oh,
you're perfect for kids.
She high five them and she's like,
you could wash your little ass
hole and you high five drinks.
I like the firm setting
sounded really from, yeah, that
sounded like a hose. Yeah.
I don't know if you wanted
that hard on your asphalt.
Happy she is at her son's has a
clean asshole. Yeah. You took a shit
at parents do
hemorrhoids or IBS
and he's so happy. He's like, he's got
a newspaper under his arm. Right. Him.
It's like my daddy's going
to come over and use her day.
My grandson clean is the asshole
in my old ass holes. Clean too.
Needs of the day, buddy. I'm
a truck driver. I sit all day.
You know he could take a shit. Yeah, and
that's what, that's what he's saying.
He's like, I'm a truck driver
so you know I can shit. Yeah.
Nothing queens like the day
buddy. I just love it. It's just,
it's just easy and toilet paper,
you know, it's not as cool.
Okay.
No,
it's fine.
They're making this sound like you bid
day as opposed to using the toilet paper.
Yeah.
It should be in conjunction.
In addition to water on
your ass hall. Yeah. Wow.
What a neat commercial. Thank
you. Yeah, man. Pretty good stuff.
Oh God. We've got to get going. Yeah,
that was a lot of fun though. Yeah.
God, I thought I was fat and
that picture. All right, great.
All right, the day buddy,
I'm sick of wiping. We got,
I could just stop wiping during the
show. Thanks for watching on Youtube. Uh,
your mom's house, podcast.com. Make sure
you check it out. Bye guys. Bye now.
Right?
Cause the toilet,
the water
everywhere are on the ground.
Yeah. I thought it was panic
on the ground.
I heard you on the ground,
on the ground
back up and out. Oh my
God. Yeah, yeah, yeah.