This episode of Your Mom's house is
brought to you by Saatva luxury mattress.
The only online mattress company that
provides free delivery set up and mattress
removal.
Christina.
Oh
ooh.
Is that the one that tycoons that me?
I feel like it is.
Well, I hope it is tacky when thanks
very much. If it wasn't you place it.
Whoever else did it.
Um, gene, where are you going to be?
A February 28th through March 2nd Madison,
Wisconsin.
At that come on your comedy club on
state April four through six mini apple
tits, Minnesota at the acme
acme meaning comedy club.
May 10th and 11th, Tempe,
Arizona at the temp Tampon.
Improv May 31st through
June 1st sperm bank,
California flap or hours.
And then June 20th
through 22nd Washington.
Dick come at the Dick come and price
tickets at Christina up heat on line.
All right,
Jean needs.
I'm going to be where I'm in Tampa.
Um, you could probably still get
in. Those shows are sold out,
but you could probably still get into the
hard rock at the seminal hard rock and
Hollywood, Florida. And
then I'm in Portland,
Maine. Red Bank, New Jersey,
Long Island, and new haven,
Connecticut. I think new haven is
the only one with tickets left.
March 30th from there.
Madison, Wisconsin, myself.
Two shows. Still tickets available
to the late show. Milwaukee Mara.
April 12th late show has tickets
and then Nashville. April 14th,
late show with tickets there.
Let's see the added a show in
Medford at the Shavaya April 28th.
You can get tickets to the late show.
They're all available at
[inaudible] dot com slash four uh,
check it out. Try it out.
Try it out. Try it out man.
Thanks Jean Jean around.
Very excited about today.
We had to uh,
pour new cement slabs under the studio
and we are going to have a lot of fun
with my dear friend and your dear friend,
right close lawyers.
Crysler Burke, k, k. K. K Chrysler.
Interesting to his career.
It's gonna be a lot of fun. All
right, let's kick off this show.
Let's get this party started.
Alexa,
what do you look for in a man?
Black guys who look good.
If you were hot black guy and he
wanted me at 2195. If you want to move,
then you can move in, but you got
to me, I, I need to be a lot man.
Free Food, free rent and everything
else. Now here's the deal,
man. Then from jail, homeless
world, if you're a thug,
you want to come move in.
Your a friend can move in to rent.
You give a lease in a key me,
this on me. Beat me. Oh, here.
Now if you see me and you want to
come over today and try it out,
try it out. If you're in
my building, try it out.
If you want to piss on me,
no serious repairs.
Just me.
I'm looking for hardcore guys and mean
it and want to do it and I want it
delivered. I'm a hot way
trash dump. That's him.
Well,
go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Wow.
I thought we were just
doing a little teaser.
I didn't realize were going
to get the whole, the whole
thing, the speech on that.
I thought it was just like, here's
the deal man. That's real quick. Yup.
Well I like Alexa saying.
Yeah.
And especially with the emotion taken
out of it, you really get a man,
you really get to understand
how crazy that guy is. Yeah.
And how absurd the, the speech actually
is. Oh yeah. With all the emotions
have no emotion. No. Just on a verbal,
like on the page level, you're like, wow,
this guy's really out of his
fucking be like reading the car.
Like if you're writing a
script and being like, yeah,
what am I gonna do with these words?
Yeah. I'm not sure what choice to make.
It's pretty amazing. Uh, I don't know
who did that. Do you know who, um,
put that together. Oh, no.
Shit. I'll, I'll look it up.
Okay. Yeah, we should probably,
I didn't know you could train Alexa
to turn your lights on and off to,
what was that all about?
Whereas the last
episode, Tom is a hard, hard dick.
Nick or whatever his fucking name is hard
hard shits nick.
Shit's nick. Yeah. Taking glass dumps.
Yeah. He was um, really something, right?
Yeah, man. Try it out.
Try it out. Try it out.
Your episode is on the beat me all man.
Out homie on yet.
But you know that now I think about him,
the tryout guy.
What? Yeah. I think about
him like once a week.
You should think about it
was that was home. You're no,
no home here? No. Leon. Yeah.
No hold man out as people think it's,
I think it's home here now. Yeah.
Oh me. No, I'm home. He and
now I'm home here now. Yeah.
I'm home here now. Uh, but I think about
him every now and then and I, you know,
what I really think about is how he's
managed to be this internet famous and he
hasn't reached out to us or like somebody
in his life has got to have heard it
at some point and been like, Hey, do you,
do you know that you're on this podcast
and these people are like talking about
this video. You May. And
he's like, oh yeah, I kind of
fucked out. That was silly.
Like, what do you think his
reaction? Oh God, it would be, oof,
it was garlic has it together
in any way whatsoever here.
Now guy is not, his life
is not like, oh yeah,
I finally pulled it together and
I can reflect back that time.
He's getting pissed on
and beat on right now.
But that's what I wonder too is
do you think his dreams came true?
Did he get what he wants?
Yeah, in some way. I don't
think someone moved in did it,
but I think, I think someone is, there's
probably a couple of ups guys, but like,
yeah, I've been in that building. You
on that guy beat the fuck out of them.
Do you think he found a black
guy who likes to flash? Who
Likes A and photo? Yeah.
Yeah.
Black guys at a jail.
That has to be the craziest
video besides Terry.
But even Terry is of sound mind.
He's just an exhibitionist.
Yeah.
Scotty Kay did the lox I clip,
so thank you Scotty k for
submitted that opening clip.
That was really good talent.
You got a real, yeah.
So a couple of weeks back I shared
a bold confession with Eugene.
Yeah, I can if I should. I
shared the for the first time,
Michelle. Fuck it. Oh
fuck. Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Oh
dammit.
See that guy's lucid though. That guy is
just having a good day. Yeah, that's true.
He's cast came too fast.
I feel like the guy,
the try it out guy, he's trying
to improve his life. Yeah.
He's looking for the answer.
And the answer is black guys who like
to fuck and fuck gut. Yeah. Yeah.
You know, what was your
big confession? Oh,
so my big confession a couple of weeks
back is we all remember it was a y a
matrix inclusive,
uh,
that I had my very
first liquid chart ever,
ever in my life. It was a big deal.
Yeah. Yeah. And so interestingly enough,
this last weekend I ordered the same
exact meal that produced the first shirt.
Yeah.
And what it is,
I order from a company called Pizza Rev
and I get the cauliflower crust pizza
and I order all the meat toppings on
there. I get two types of Pepperoni,
spicy and regular.
I get the Italian sausage and garlic.
And what I noticed was because
I ate the same thing this time,
halfway through my meal,
I thought,
I think it might be the garlic
that's giving me diarrhea. Yeah.
And I took off the garlic
and lo and behold, yes,
I had runny dumps the next day.
But it wasn't bad.
It wasn't as bad as it was before.
And I think it's because of the garlic.
That's my, my hip hop. Sure. What are you
thinking? Uh, I think it's really neat.
I had a sharp scare.
Your kid in Washington,
a scarer legit sharp. Well,
here's what happened. So, wow,
I'm on the bus or about to get off
the bus to go into the theater.
I'm, I fart. Like I'm going to
rip it this far right now. Yeah.
And I'm like,
that's more than a fart.
And I panic because you
don't shit on the bus.
So I learned to like
shuffle over to the theater.
I dropped trout and I realized I don't
see anything in the underwear. I'm like,
God. But like I don't check my butt
cheeks. I just sit on a toilet,
but a disaster come out. Yeah.
Well, here's the thing, I,
I started having like a couple other
loose ones after that. I'm like fuck.
And this is like an hour before the show,
the first show.
So I asked them for Pepto, I, he's
drink some pepto drink a little soda.
You don't try it on. Yeah. And
then I'm okay. I do the first show,
I forget about it,
I forget about it.
Then I'm in the green room with Jeff
Tate and I go check this shit out.
Ha fart.
And I feel
the same thing I might because I forgot
sketchy asshole. Oh yeah. And
so that's scary when you forget
a little more comes out. And again,
I got lucky with the underwear.
I didn't get any underwear but yeah,
I was,
it was definitely and I think I can
check out what it was, you know?
Yeah. Well it's probably just a
road week cause you were on the law.
A lot of different cities.
Bacteria,
cause I often forgot about my shark too
and I would fart in the kitchen again.
Like oh I better not now.
I don't want to,
I'm not going to write
out who in this office,
but somebody here also had a sharp, they
know they would prefer their identity.
You know,
there's a lot of charters here.
And it occurred to me that
because there's so much happening,
it's kind of a short week here.
It is for our week. Yeah. Yeah.
It's rare that there's a guest
coming in who I'm sure has. Sure.
If you told me to bet on it, I'd be like
$1 million. Let's ask him. He comes in,
how many sharks he's ever had. Well,
should we get into who's here and what,
what we've been talking
about? Of course, man. Um, um,
we have the great, uh, Bert Kreischer
is going to be joining us here. Um,
very funny,
very funny.
Also very fat as we all know and very
racist and we've been looking at pictures
of him. Oh my God, that's
him at the store. Gene.
That's him at the comedy store
during the main room. He's shirtless.
And that to me yesterday or
the day before to oo four,
that is not at snap. Now.
His belly is so distended,
swollen, like an African child
starving African version or him,
we will give birth.
All right.
Ooh Boy,
that's a big fat.
No Sunday at the last or
like a week ago in Vegas,
he posted that. I was like,
Jesus, he's so fat now.
Do you think Burness better now
than he was before you guys?
Weight loss competition.
Mm. Clothes is clothes.
It's not good. Whatever it is. You know
what's crazy though about his body?
You can tell that he's meant to
have like a rad body because,
do you see like his cutlines Joe,
what I'm saying like his hippo. It's,
it's weird because he still has like
chiseled doesn't wear underwear. Yeah.
He never does because he has that sensory
basically looking at a naked guy with
a cloth. Yeah. Yeah. But
do you see what I'm saying?
Then he's got that hipbone yeah.
Like Ryan Gosling has that.
You should tell him
that. He'll be like, Yo,
look at that guy in the front
row with the arm folded. Yeah.
He's looks guys discussing, hey, just sit
here. He's fat too. He's like, who's fat?
Burger meat.
Um,
so we, um, we were looking at like who,
because we remember when this all started
and the whole fashion thing started
when we were talking about that he
kind of looks like Gerard dip our toe,
right?
Cause he had,
he had like naked scenes in this movie,
but then paper it has a new look now and
I think he looks more like these guys.
Like there's Dennis Hoff.
That guy kind of has Burt's vibe.
Well here's why though is because Burt's
face is getting redder and redder and
swollen. It looks like I'm right
there. I think he really looks like,
like this guy in that,
uh, there's candle to me.
He uh,
why he kicked it getting Delphinia.
There's this other piece
that's Birtle hundred percent the smile,
you know,
like the energy and the essence.
I feel like you put a beard on that guy.
Does Burt? That is Bert. Yeah. Who's he
with? Wow. Oh, who's he with? An author.
You don't know who that is?
That's JK Rowling.
She wrote the Potter series.
Pulitzer prize.
Or
somebody could put Burt's head on
that photo. That would be great.
Here's Harrisburg,
too bad.
TMZ hasn't caught on and they're not
covering it in detail and some fat there.
Fini my favorite to this day.
Soprano's I mean,
I love that show and he's so
talented. This dude, God dammit.
Um, when do you think Burt's is going to
die? Oh, Jesus. Don't go there. I mean,
God, well, no, I mean, let's be realistic
here as my friend. I don't want him to,
he's my friend too,
and I care about him and that's why
I'm being a little harsh because
it's like that. Huh? Just like that.
Yeah. Because here's the deal, man. Here's
what I'm thinking. Yeah. This new, uh,
bus life that he's embarked
on has probably made it a
lot easier to party. We,
we've gotten into it. Yeah. You know what
I'm saying? Oh yeah. Yeah. He told me,
he's like,
we got a grill for his bus.
I think I grilled company gave him one.
He was like,
we smoked meats and we drink
until it for every night. Oh,
I love him so much. And I, I don't,
you know, I don't want him to lose him,
obviously. Of course.
That is not up to us.
You can only try so many times. You
know you can't, it's, it's up to him.
Chuckleheads laughing. I don't know.
Why are you laughing at Blue van?
I Dunno what's going on.
What's going on? I'll stop.
Um, should we, uh,
should we go ahead and take a break
and one of them taking a shit in our
bathroom. Let's ask him about those
charts. We will in just a moment.
We'll be back to talking about
give it up the fastest and most
racist comedian working today.
Man, I can't wait to see what, what
moniker I add on to that today.
You get a lot of comments like
that. Oh yeah. There's so much fun.
There's so much one.
This is the most fucking exhausting
because you have no idea because
like your dad or your wife's going,
why are people saying
my agents promoters? Yes.
Everyone has said, hey man,
we're going a lot of
feedback that you're racist.
And is that what you bring
to the Joe? No, not at all.
Is My fucking dickhead friend Tom
started it as a lark and I fucking hit it
under the park.
Sorry, I fucked that up. Yeah,
it's a do with those body shots.
World tour.
No blacks allowed.
Wow. That's, I did not make
that. That's not sanctioned.
I normally spend as a whole is just going,
okay, that's not real. It was awful.
His wins when people comment
on it in the comment section,
this is,
you're such a fat ratio and then,
and then new fans that have just found
me from Netflix, it's offend me. Yeah.
They're like, he look good. God, he's
a Joe and there's no reason to joke.
Eric don't even have a racist joke in my
act and there's nothing there and were
like, it chokes to be killer now to take
a joke. He makes fun of everyone equally.
I'm like, I'm not thinking about
anybody. It's a picture of my daughter
and they yelled out, it shows you're
racist and people go, hey, we all are.
I'm like, shut the fuck up.
Oh, it's fucking exhausting.
I even have a joke in
my act now where I go,
I just had a baby and I'm fatter than
Bert Kreischer and the place just,
they light up.
That's great.
I'd like to keep it in a special if I
may. Uh, I get, I still, I mean every,
every city, everywhere. People
Yell Shit Bro. Fuck Bird.
I like your tour bus.
But here's pictures though. So
here's my picture. Wait. Oh,
what is he up picture of this
tour bus and not the outside.
Oh, that was the funniest
fucking, I never saw it. That one.
Jesus has that birds tour bus or yours.
I took a picture in
front of my adult these,
I didn't retreat that I guess I
didn't see it. So I took a picture.
I didn't see that ass
Photoshop to make it more sad
because your body language, it was so sad,
dude. The best one was the Rogaine one.
That was a good one. Oh, like
Mcdonald's. Did you hear?
We lost our Mcdonald's sponsorship.
So bummed. I would love,
I love Tacos. Oh,
cheeseburger. What we need.
You take half of the bone
off and just talk about, but
you have all these health secrets.
Yes. Tell me more. On a
Sunday, on a Sunday night at
4:00 PM take a Xanax. Okay.
Chase it with a double Tito's and soda.
You go to bed without dinner.
You'll wake up Monday a skinny,
and if it's president's Day,
you'd take an ambien first thing when
you wake up Monday and you sleep off
Monday and then it that night, you've
had no calories. It's two days.
Health advice with Bert Kreischer
such good advice. Most
doctors, Oh fuck is this?
What are you doing here?
Can we see this?
Not Ours.
Just couldn't get up
and I can't ask my dad to get me up as
to where I needed him to help me do so.
God, they put just hang
on, stop. They put my face.
I didn't realize what was happening.
I was like, wait, that looks like me,
but that doesn't sound like me. They put
my face on the 600 pound life guy. Yeah,
that's fucking genius headquarters to
be doing when you're in your thirties or
whatever. It looks like I had a stroke.
It looks, it looks bad on, you know,
it's interesting. Is that the hands,
the arms match actually. Yeah.
How many gestures, but I would say
like the way that your face like that,
that expression on your face.
Perfect. Perfect. Yeah, there's a lot.
It's pretty accurate. Yeah.
Especially that big, right nut. Yes.
Do you have a big write one and one that's
big. Starting to get up Hoopa. Yeah.
Before we move any further, this is
a Fart, Mike, if you have to Fart,
go ahead and let us know and we'll hand
it over. By the way, my body's reacting.
I'll probably shit my pants.
Oh, interesting. Hey, your
mom's house exclusive.
This is short week and we were going to
ask you if you have any excellent sharp
charted on my bus over the weekend.
I sharted in bed with Leanne yesterday.
No pants on, shorted onto the
sheets and then had to run,
you know like tippy toe it into the
bathroom and then judge rifled it out.
Hold on. I'm going to, so the night before
I was Vegan for a while.
Describe a while.
Everyone has this kind of
subjective roughly three days. Okay.
Roughly three days with a few
cheap meals. That's good. Ryan.
No. It's part of the way that told you
that the health book you're writing. No,
we were, I was drunk at an airport. Felt
like you were going to vomit. Right.
I was drunk at an airport.
How? I'm fucking sweating now.
I was drunk at an airport and I was like,
I bet I can go fucking Vegan.
And they're like, you couldn't go
Vegan? I go, yeah, I can. I can do it.
Everything I put my mind to and so
we get on the plane and I'm like,
fuck it. I'm going Vegan. I'm going
to lose some weight and go Vegan,
so drink a double Tito's and soda.
She brings me a beer with it and
then lunch comes around. I go,
what do you have? Meat and pasta. It was
Ernie cheese on the pasta and she goes,
no. I said, is there any meat on
the pasta? She goes, no. I said,
I'll go with the pasta. So the guy
next to me, he's kind of watching me,
he gets to meat and we start
eating. And he goes, hey ma,
what are you like allergic to cheese?
I go, no, I'm Vegan. And he goes,
really? I said, yeah. He goes, you know,
there's AG imposter, right? And I go,
I didn't know that. He goes, how long
have you been eating pasta? I go,
my whole life.
It goes and you call yourself Vegan,
this is what's wrong with you people.
And he starts fucking jumping into
my lifestyle choice on an airplane.
By the way, he didn't know, I've
only been Vegan for like 45 minutes.
Tell him I just kept eating the pasta
and then order to an ice cream Sundae in
bed with Leanne my, my stomach. Okay.
So after three days ago a my
stomach got really kind of, uh,
not as toxic as has been like all my
shit's come out back of the bowl up under
the toilet seat
and the ones where you got to wipe your
legs cause it splashes up sometimes.
Yeah. And so, um, but I mean
that's like his regular morning.
That's Tuesday, Monday
morning. Shit, it's Tuesday.
And so I go and uh,
I start,
I go right out of veganism, veganism,
a rec tech sent me a travel smoker.
So I go right into Veg,
out of veganism into a fucking brisket
and it just fucked my stomach. Yeah.
I just wolf like animal fat and all her
right after my Tampa show me in cow head,
Dave Williamson just in Fez Watley sat
at the back just eating brisket and then
the next day I was just
shitting like crazy.
So then you meet up in Vegas and
your wife goes there and you drank.
I'm sure we did bottomless
Mimosas when I landed.
Then did the show you had the bottomless
mimosas until like four o'clock once.
See before o'clock show wasn't until
10. Oh Wow. Yeah. And so, but I,
my stomach was just racked and
then the next morning we woke up,
I don't know what I ate
or drank that night,
but the next morning and World Cup and
I thought it was a fart and it just shit
on my butt cheeks and then had to
carry it into the bathroom. Yeah.
Like wanting like a little here.
We're like one of those egg
spoon races in the new fare.
Ooh Shit.
No she didn't.
She know I shit my pants right before I
went on stage in Fort Lauderdale and my
camera man was following me and I shit
my pants right before I want to stage and
then it was fire coming out
of my ass fired, you know,
like you know when you eat
spicy food in your lipstick hot,
that was happening to my asshole. And so
I shoved an ice cube up there and like,
uh, like a suppository to
cool it down. You know,
cause I'm figured something was hot and
then I couldn't get it out and I had to
go on stage with an ice cube up my ass
and it was literally dripping out of my
asshole there. No, I know.
I know you shit in your pants right
before you go on stage in Fort Lauderdale
and sit my butt cheeks. I didn't Shit
my pants. I shipped my butt cheeks.
Wipe it up. Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I clean it up before you perform,
you perform the whole
hour with shit in your no,
but I have done that before. Oh my
God. Yeah. You're savage. Dallas,
Texas.
Christella Alonzo is supposed to go and
do 20 minutes and she can all can shoot
you could do is like seven [inaudible]
this is a long time ago and so she does
seven minutes and I'm shitting
and I hear my name couldn't proud.
I didn't even wipe, I didn't even know
why. Couldn't have time to wipe it.
And I was like, oh. And I had to
perform a shit. My pants the long hour.
Oh, where as this said, I have,
hold on one second. Hold on.
Now that we're talking about this
in lieu in Kentucky, in Louisville,
no night tell you, what did I tell you
before he came on, which I'm actually,
I tell good if somebody said,
do you think bird has short story give,
I'll give you $1 million. We
were in Lexington, Kentucky,
at Brook comedy off off Broadway,
and I realized I had to take a
shit in the middle of my hand.
I brought the comic up. I said,
some will put a timer on the clock.
I'm going to bring the other comic up.
Dusty sleigh.
He's going to do you counted off.
I'm going to go run off
stage shit and come back.
I Bet I can do this in under two minutes.
I was back in a minute.
Now why I push,
I push.
I'm a big pusher. You pushed a little
too hard. A lot of times when I shit,
it's about art.
It's like a bouncer kicking out.
People that have a club at 2:00
AM just let's go, let's go.
He think Ari's Asshole is a fucking
pictures of his ship seen on the Internet.
No, he also sends us, he group
Texas pictures of his, uh,
of toilet paper just soaked in
blood. Oh my God. He's like, oh,
I just pulled this out of my ass. He's
the reason I put an ice cube up my ass.
Cause he shoves,
wads,
plugs of toilet paper up his asshole
to stop the blood from coming here.
And he's like, and we're like
getting their surgeries like, yeah.
Doctor said it's not really
worth it. So anyways, uh,
later on doesn't really think it's, it's
got a Tesco hanging out of his asshole.
Yeah. Like yeah, he's got a
hemorrhoid testicle out of his ass.
Like a, it's like a ball, right? It's just
a hemorrhoid, but it looks like a nerd.
It's like a fuck sleep.
It's like he got railed for
months and years in his asshole.
It's got a pink sock. Just kind of, okay.
So wait,
when you cleaned up though,
those ones one, when those ones happen,
it's so easy to clean up. Just real quick.
Spit on the toilet paper.
Wipe your ass. I'm out.
That's what your dad does called
Mississippi wet wipe my specialty.
I do it a lot now dude,
you got,
well I used to not do it and then you
know we get like the fucking bed days at
home or just game changers.
Then you travel again and
you feel like, what does it,
the 14 hundreds I'm
wiping my ass with pay.
It's like going from private school to
fucking Gen pop in a public school. Yeah,
I do. It's like, no. Yeah, you're
like, I'm better than this.
So then you start spitting on your pay.
It actually makes a big difference
on your toilet paper holding it out.
Let me tell you how to do it.
Spilling your toilet paper right on
your finger where your finger is on the
toilet paper. Right? And then
just take it. It's just one wipe.
You're not going back and forth.
Just one wipe gently to just kinda just
get everything off like a cursory go
dry, then go one more spin and
then it, I don't mind the wet idea,
but why can't you just reach
to the sank like board?
It's the same reason you don't
use water when you jack off,
you spit in your hand and Jack
off or you know what I mean?
It's spit is got a little more lubrication
to it. A little more viscosity.
So when it rubs chasse drafts,
we'll saying nice.
He kind of knows what he's talking about.
I've been spinning on my toilet paper
for eight years is still sexually
attracted. That was the best day
of very certain about that. No,
no.
She sees you as like a nice guy,
but I'm home sometimes cash cow
on the road. Yeah. It's like
a rods agents. They're like,
I don't care if he's using steroids. Have
you seen my bucket new? She's just like,
when are you leaving again?
Like going like if she does she get
like a platinum card. She was like,
this is kind of fun. Oh really?
Shopping now, you know she's doing,
I'll tell you right now,
looking at houses. Oh,
looking at houses and just,
I mean just the fucking modest
woman you met fucking 15 years ago,
you wouldn't unrecognizable.
Unrecognized. It's my favorite thing.
She, that new truck we got, she was not
wanting to get it. Oh it's too expensive.
It's so silly. And then
she got it. She goes,
this is my favorite thing we've
ever owned ever. She goes,
I've really feel like I'm driving
around in luxury and I'm driving so much
picking up George at softball and islet
school play practices. One on, she goes,
she goes, this makes me feel like
driving's not that bad. And I go,
you should get treats in life.
That's why I don't understand.
I've just been trying to work this bit
out of my life and my act and I can't
figure it out cause I got, maybe people
don't relate to the way my brain works.
But if you don't have treats in life,
what life's not worth living.
Like I don't understand the guy that
lives treat lists that they just go your
treats all day though.
Yeah. But that's yeah,
be concentrates and I have a low threshold
for reward. I'll give you that. But,
but guys who deserve treats that
don't get him. What's the point? Yeah.
Like I used to think and all that. If
you can afford it, that's the caveat.
If you can afford it, get the
treat. If you can't afford it,
don't get the fucking tree.
And it was just,
it should making your treats onto
like, uh, on, on like a sliding scale.
I've been treating myself my whole
life. I have, I, like I said,
I definitely think I earned treats
when I don't earn them, but my treats,
I've never, they haven't like, gotten
outrageous. It's just like a new car.
Like why not have a new car?
We had a car that was 10 years old and
was breaking down like lamb broke down on
Ventura. I go, what the fuck?
We can afford a new car.
Let's treat ourselves. Yeah,
you deserve it. Tommy's captain treat
over here. Oh, he's taught by placing,
I'm more likely an where I grew up in
the communist Cold War and I didn't treat
myself to shit and he's taught me how
to enjoy life. But here's the thing,
you guys go blow it up.
Both of you taught me how to treat
myself because I remember we were talking
like, I was like, I want to get the hands
on. They want to get something nice.
You can go. Oh Tommy just gets
it for me. Just for me. Yeah.
In Vegas this weekend we're
doing bottomless mimosas.
There's like a mall by the Aria and I go,
that's my tree.
And that was my trip by the way.
No, she got sick. She got sick.
The shakes from him.
And so we go to the thing
and I just disappeared.
I got myself a treat and I bought the
treat. But you gotta tell the streets,
come on my treats silly. It's okay. He
was a drunk and treat. Okay. What was it?
It was a Gucci Fanny Pack.
That's the family. Awesome.
It was good to push. I think
you had one on him. He got me.
One is a push present child
years and I was like, Oh Gucci,
Panty peg.
This is all so silly.
Yeah.
Oh cause it's such a silly item.
And then to get a designer silly,
it's like whooo.
This
all the toe it all through Vegas. Yeah. I
had it filled with all my merchant cash,
so it was like stacks up cash.
So then I went to Tiffany's and I bought
land and Nicholas not super expensive,
but it's just a nice necklace. Nicely.
You Man. I see you soon. Oh, I like it.
It's really nice. Enjoy it. Good. Yeah.
Cause you're going to die one day.
You May as well enjoy, you
know, the benefits, right? Me.
What are we getting this house man? Yeah,
let's talk about it. We looked at one.
Yeah. Yeah. It was a little out of our
price range, but I thought, I thought,
you know, roll the dice on
life. Now, if we had had, um,
it was at the foot of Fryman
Canyon. Uh Huh. I can tell you the,
I should probably shouldn't
have it on the Internet.
It was at the foot of Fryman Canyon
had had a dinner. It was really nice.
It was an old house.
I was part of a compound,
so all the houses around it and was like
excluded. You couldn't get, that's cool.
But a weight, it doesn't matter. He'll put
it on Instagram anyway. Yeah, definitely.
That's why we got to move.
I gotta get out of my fucking house now.
Everyone knows where I fucking
law. Really? How that happened.
Me Describing things in my neighborhood,
all my podcast people like
a jack in the box. Huh?
I think I figured out where you
live. Your crazy with that. I didn't.
I was before we knew that anyone listened
to these fucking things. Yeah. I just,
I overshared.
I've overshared way too much in my life.
Like that's where you guys have done
a really smart job and I tore a board,
Georgia and Eila didn't even ask and I
talked about their periods on Conan. Yeah.
Yeah. That's funny though. I left the
period party. You described those lovely.
Imagine if your island,
you've got to go to school the next day
and it goes viral and little Jason. Huh?
You named me period. Jason. She's
like, I don't know who you are. Yeah.
Four girls.
So let's say this though.
We made fun of my tour
bus. Yeah. You know,
and my picture with my tour
bus. Yeah. Uh, what about
the body shots world?
Hitler did nothing wrong.
This is your thing.
Jeez.
Who does voiceover for you?
That's a, my guy Jake. He's great.
He's a really good voiceover artist and he
is too bad. It's all anti me. No, no, no.
He's got some other stuff. Oh,
cool. Wait to see it. Yeah, no,
that's great. If you're
listening, it's just,
that was just burnt on a Nazi
train. Just to be clear. Yeah.
Of what we were, oh, the I pull up,
hang on. No, hit pause. Hit pause.
Yeah. Pull up the one that's
titled Birders are racist. MP Four.
I'm dying to see this. What
we'll see. We'll see it in a bit.
Let's see what this is.
Cleveland's, Oh my goodness. Daimler,
you're in there. Right
there with him shirtless.
Wow. What was he like?
Not that bad. Really?
Well, very artistic. Yeah. This
is actually good footage. I know.
All right.
Okay.
The body shots world tour,
Hitler did nothing wrong.
Wow. You got your whole logo on the
side of the plane there? Yeah. Cool.
That's not bad. You know, Ron
White had done that to his plane,
so I feel like I'm in good
company. Yeah. That's pretty cool.
How much would you like to get a
plane, dude? Is that the next step?
Almost got one to find me
home from Vegas yesterday,
but it was $6,000 and I can't write my
head and I wrapped my head around that.
Yeah. Like I was like, I was
like, I thought it would be like,
I literally thought it'd be like two grand
and I was like, I could do that. I can,
I can just go like, fuck it. I had a bad
night of the casinos can gamble much.
Yeah. Um, but yeah, I can't, I don't know.
I'm never gonna be able to be able
to do that whole thing. It's crazy.
I don't like flying though either.
So that's the other thing.
Wouldn't buzz life has really enabled
your lifestyle choices. Dude, it's me.
I'm so much healthier on this
fucking boss than I've ever been.
Let's talk about it. Uh, it's
great because here's what we know.
I was trying to figure out like why
I'm not getting hung over and I'm not
getting fucking super wasted at night.
It's because you're going into
the tour bus and drinking. It's,
it's kind of like drinking at your
house and so then you go, I'm tired,
I'm going to bed. As opposed to what
normally happen on the road as you go,
you have to club and then everyone would
go ends up at a bar and then you're at
a bar and everyone's like,
all right, we're going to go.
And you're like, one more,
would you get one more? And then you
get what? You go back to your place.
Maybe open one there and for
here you just get like you go,
I'm going back to my room and you
just go to sleep. So I loved it.
That are you sleeping better? Asleep.
Fucking amazing. Yeah. I think we have,
I don't know what kind
of matches you have,
but it's one of those like fits
your body like your tempurpedic.
Like it's kind of like a Lisa mattress.
He's got one of those like it goes up and
down on the tour bus. Oh yeah, me too.
Me Too.
That
it is not one light those up right
next to his chocolate fountain.
Do you have a chocolate
fountain on your mouth? No.
Do you really not have two
bathrooms though? No, we have
two bathrooms. Okay. Yeah.
I was like what the fuck? No. Do
we do shit in your tour bus? No,
we don't sit in our tour bus. Can I
tell you the invention I came up with?
You made an invention? Yup. It's called
toilet condom. Okay. What you do? Oh,
it's like a hot bag. Yeah. Yeah. You take
it and you put it around the seat. Yeah.
And then it's got like a little thing
here but you shit into this bag as soon
was almost with a reservoir tip.
So you ended up in the reservoir tip so
then you can just bag it and throw it in
the trash. Yeah. Yeah. I mean
people do. Yeah. Yeah. They called
hot bagging. Yeah. Really?
Yeah. Yeah. They just shit in
the bag on the bus. Oh boy.
You just buy like a $2 million bus like
Brian Regan and then you can just shit
on your bus. Why is he, cause
he has the state of the art.
They have like a grinder and all
types of crazy shit done his back.
I will do it too.
I would do a TV show based on tour
buses of obsessed with tour buses.
I mean the really nice ones
are really nice. Like, Oh,
like I think mine is
probably low end. My, okay.
So I have four different tour
buses. Yeah. Because I didn't,
there's weeks where it doesn't make
sense for like when I'm doing tampon
Lauderdale I'm like, I don't want a
tour bus for that week that um, yeah,
I'm like a,
I don't want a tour bus for this
a week where I have a Portland,
Maine and then I have just fly
to fort on to the next day.
Or you're going to drive? I
don't know. I don't know yet. Oh,
see for me driving it makes it easier
on my stomach. Like I just got,
I mean I probably will. That's
a three, three and a half.
So what I'm saying is,
so those weeks don't like,
but then I have weeks where it definitely
makes sense because of the way those
companies work.
I was able to get like quotes from
different companies for all the different
runs,
compare them all and then I pulled the
trigger on the nicest one for a couple
runs. So I'm going to see what it's
like, what the differences for that bus.
That bus is state of the art
though. Okay. I want to it.
I might hop on your tour for that,
but that bus is like,
it's way more than really. Yeah.
Then like the one I'm on now,
the guy, so the guy goes, uh, you
know, when you like, you know,
if you're at a restaurant and you
might order something and you're like,
this doesn't, I don't know if
this is a, this tastes right,
but you'll second guess
yourself because you're like,
I don't really complain about the
way something tastes. You know,
like you're like, I don't want to make
a thing of it. Right. So you go like,
and then you eat and you're like,
no, something's wrong with this.
So like on the one of the first, like
second night on this bus, I was like,
man, I feel like it's fucking loud
back here. Like really loud, you know?
So then I'm like, we were at the neck,
we're in the next city. And he's like,
how was it back there? And I was
like, well, I gotta be honest, man.
I don't want to complain about it,
but it does seem pretty loud.
And he goes, yes, they need
to train new transmission.
I go like, do you know this? He was
like, Oh yeah, I told him, you know,
and they, uh, they rotated the tires,
they replaced the rear axle,
but she's got some miles on her and she
really needs some work. And I was like,
so does this happen soon? Or one
second does. He's like, yeah,
I don't know. I'm like, okay. And
then it was like that. It was like,
Hey, this water didn't really heat
up. He's like, yeah, the plug came.
And I told him the soundbar also came
to attached in this TV's not working
anymore. And I'm like, so when
like do I, do I deal with this?
He was like, yeah, just till it's
fixed. Oh my God. Fuck that. I know.
But I mean, you know,
[inaudible] got Wifi, egg,
then the Wifi, the guy.
Here's the thing though,
what a difference.
Like a nice,
like great driver makes
the guys the best and um,
you know, it's not like, it's not that
big of like, I fall asleep, I get up,
we're in the next city. I'm like, I don't
care man. Yeah, you're sleeping anyways.
Yeah. I'm like, it's not that
big of a deal. There's shit like,
like when the soundbar did work on
the TV, the sound bar was dope. Like,
like you could watch movies and
like I was, I was digging that,
but for the most part
this bus has been falling
dude. And they'll fix it. Probably
as I hop on that other bus,
I want to see what it is. I wouldn't
mind splurging in order to get mine.
I had to have it for the whole three
months. Yeah, that makes sense. Good.
I wanted to wrap it,
which might have been a miss couch.
No
move. It is son Joseph said to me last
night, he goes, cause Yo, what's up?
Did you fucking rapping it? And that
kind of like, I couldn't do that man.
I'm too low key. I go, Yo, I don't think
I would do that again in the future.
Although I know I now
will cause it's dude,
it is literally people
just knocking on the door
gotta be shitting. I come in, it's
burden there. And they're like, yeah,
he's sleeping. Wait,
wake them up. Somebody.
They know we're doing these ridiculous
post to each other. My boss was in DC,
we'd driven through, mind
you, jersey, Pittsburgh,
since he Cleveland land in DC,
it's filthy.
And they wrote tour bus champ
and the dirt. Are you serious?
The Aye. Aye. Aye. Getting the face on it.
The first night I realized it was like
there's people waiting outside the bus
and you was trying to get into
the venue and I was like, oh,
this is a horrible fucking idea.
And then knowing that people that
know that that's where you are,
I wasn't comparable Dan by 10 by,
by the time we got to Tampa regionally
and Atlanta, I loved it. I was like,
well it started being like people were
taking pictures of them outside the bus
and I thought that was cool.
Like people would rip their shirts off
and take pictures outside and I was like,
oh, that's awesome. And then, uh,
and then it never wear a shirt again.
I know you're Korean,
you're going to be hopefully 80 years
old and you're going to have to be like
the shortlist of the geriatric.
Get Soggy.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Any of the other machine.
How long ago was that was that
was yesterday. Was it yesterday?
That was yesterday.
I think if I just did sit ups.
The Bu's has nothing to do with it.
The sit ups and then where's your,
where's your, uh, where's the one
underneath it? That's your Vegas picture.
Jesus Christ. How many beers in
my worry? You know you had the,
what's the shirt is that
it says a gator belts melts.
Eldorados Monte Carlos and Eldorados
is from the beginning of this fresh,
so fresh and so clean. Oh, that's your
boy. Big Boy. Big Boy. He's my buddy.
That's your dog. I remember
that. Yup. It's really cool.
Everyone lightened him up with the m
word anytime he comments on an Indian.
Yeah. Some people don't get the
joke. That's what kills me about it.
It's like some people get
the joke and it's funny,
some people really don't have
a sense of humor. It's like,
it's almost like watching Lenny from
of mice and men play with animals.
They're like, oh, and then
you're just like, oh man,
you're not doing this right at all.
The nuance of the whole thing.
Someone painted a picture of
outkast and they're like, Hey,
I made this poster for your boss.
And so I had to buy only place.
I have it as like a big picture of outkast
above my bed. It's weird. Very weird.
Yeah. Hmm. Um, do you have those
pictures of like the lookalikes.
So remember how we had
Gerard Depardieu at one time?
Don't you think you kind of
looked like this and this off? No.
You don't think you'd look at him? What
about him in the white shirt though? Well,
there's Gandel feet. No, not even remotely
in the smile and energy. Not even close.
No. No, but put a beard on him. No.
You kind of have his build a little bit.
You have right there.
I do not. He looked like
that. That was a week.
And we're like that.
Then I lived like that last
night and he let her men goes,
uh, she touches my belly. She goes, Oh
yeah, that's right. I forgot you were fat.
She goes, but you're like hard
fat. Tom's like a soft fat,
right? And I'm like, yeah,
he's just, he's a gentle fat. Yeah.
I had done, it's off all my podcast.
It was a long time ago when it was
just me doing all the audio and stuff.
So I bring him to the podcast.
I started the podcast.
He brings a girl with him and the first
thing he says is, show him your pussy.
All my couch, like, she like took her
pussy out on my couch and I'm like,
there's a leather couch like to
fucking ruin the leather. You know?
That's Nikki Haley, the former
UN ambassador. That woman
right there, there was no,
yeah, she, I don't think that's accurate.
That's, that's who she is. Yeah.
She's going to do a speaking tour
pretty soon. Cool. Huh? Yeah. Yeah.
I can't wait to hear what she has to
say. Wait, God gave her vocal cords to
you don't think you look like that? No,
not at all. Gonna look like that. No,
I hate when I go.
I hate when I see,
you know that Guy Vance Heinz
is almost skinnier than me now.
This is pretty great. It's probably
way, hold on. I have to, okay,
we're going to make fun of this,
but I have to say at the very beginning,
he's putting an amazing fucking work to
get where he is. Of course, I'm not like,
I'm going to, we're going to
make jokes about it, I'm sure.
But like I am so impressed with
this guy's fucking mindset.
You don't know anything about
this Van Times gone. Okay.
It goes back to the original weight loss
challenge, right? This is when I know,
I think it goes to sober October.
Go sober October because of
that weight loss challenge. He,
he started his weight loss journey right
in November, I think a full year ago.
Okay. Okay. So a, a little or more,
more than a year ago now. But, uh,
I said on the podcast, I said I could
run a marathon in under five hours,
which I did and I ran it and five 33 but
yeah, in building up to the marathon,
I ran a half marathon and Vance Hines,
listen to the sober October,
listen to the fat shaming,
listen to all that.
But he saw me run the half marathon and
then literally it was like, well, fuck,
if Burt can do that, I can do something.
And so he started trying to work out.
He was 475 pounds and today
he's like 42 to 50 wow.
Amazing.
He looks amazing.
But then he came and did my podcast with
Diamond Dallas page in Atlanta at the
Tabernacle, by the way, fucking
tabernacle. It's awesome.
It's the weirdest venue
in the entire world.
Did you know that was all white church?
He has a,
it was a baptist church
is all white church.
I thought it was an old black church.
No,
I didn't know that for us it was
baptist. Yeah. And I said to them, I go,
so this used to be an all black
church and they go, no. I said,
what do you mean they go, it was a
white church. And I was like, well,
it's the tabernacle. And
they're like, yeah, do what?
What part of the 19 hundreds do you
think they let black people come in here?
And I went, oh yeah. Oh yeah. And they
go to BC, Martin Luther King's church.
It's like a box.
Do you think they had this one too?
And Martin Luther King chose to
preach in a box. I was like, oh,
I never even realized
that. They're like, yeah,
this was primarily filled with racist
white people. I don't want, Oh,
that makes us very different from me in
my heart. And so, um, that came out wrong.
And so, but uh, but Valentine's
and Diamond Dallas page comes in,
uh, and he was like, brace to 200. Let's
see, you can get to 201st. And I was like,
I'm never going to fucking catch you
to 200. So what? I mean, so
the guy that, how far from
you? I started off, by the way,
hold on, hold on. How far from 200 Reu,
right?
Like a solid 40,
50,
17.
I can tell you right now
on my winnings APP. Okay.
I wait in this morning on my wedding zap.
I don't look at it.
It just registers to my phone.
Oh. Oh, you don't look at it?
No cause I want to track it,
but I want to track it.
I want to see it when I'm skinny. I
don't want to see it now. So my app,
I can weigh on the scale goes right to
my phone and you don't have to take a
look. It doesn't have to fuck with
your day. Yeah. Yeah. I just go. Great.
Affect your behavior in
any other weddings. Apple.
My winning scale on my
bus and in my house. Okay.
Two 45.8 okay.
So,
but I was two 45.9 yesterday to 50.
Uh, February 14th. So,
so you're going down,
you're going down,
but what,
so what are you doing lot
of diarrhea that helps.
I am no. Can I be honest with you? Push.
I have no fucking idea how to lose weight.
Yeah. Even when I, I've lost weight,
I just do it. And like this psychotic,
psychotic, manic kind of way.
I don't do it in like a health.
Yeah. And you don't have a method, but if
you, if you, okay, let's talk to Joe. No.
Can he make a method for you
and could you stick to it?
If someone wrote down here's what
you're going to do, this is what,
this is the routine.
Could you have a routine and stick to it?
Yeah,
I can be.
I can be obsessive compulsive but the
problem is I'm not hyper obsessive. Yeah,
hyper obsessive. But the problem
is is when we lost all that weight,
I stayed in the two twenties for
a full calendar year. Full year.
Now we were both in the
two twenties for your,
I know you're probably still around what,
two 30 yeah,
but like we were in the two twenties for
a full fucking year cause when we did
sober October we did our weigh ins at
your house when we went to party at your
house afterwards and we were
almost exact same size. Wait. Yeah.
I don't know why.
I don't know what's going on and just
all of a sudden it just balloons up.
I get really, I don't think it's that
confusing actually. I get pretty,
I get pretty like I get off the rails
sometimes. Like I'm like deep dish pizza.
I think Baird, I think part of
it too is the fact that, look,
you're a celebratory guy.
Yeah. You're a fun guy.
You're killing it on the road. Yeah.
You deserve treats. There we go.
Now we're talking like my inner
dialogue here, away from your family.
Let's hear about a strip club at second.
So vixens Fort Lauderdale,
he just, and uh, um, you know, you're, uh,
you're the good time guy so you
don't have treats in your head.
Like when you get done a show,
you don't go,
I wonder what I get to treat myself with.
I mean sometimes yeah, but your treat,
um, we'll see. Here's
the thing. I have a way,
it's not even like a party
thing or aversion to it.
It's just like I've just, look, I'm just
not wired to be a big drinker. So you,
so you go,
now I get to be alone in a dark room.
I do like that. But I mean
most, here's, here's most of
my, the second show is over.
Okay. Yeah. So I go back in that
green room. So hold on, let's, let's,
let's walk through our for you. Do two
shows. So your first show, no booze,
I'm sure. Right? Definitely coffee.
Yeah. Okay. Me Too. A Cup of coffee.
We're going to stage no booze for
a show and might bring a bureau,
but I won't touch it. I can show I
bring a a cocktail, bring a coffee,
cocktail or beer out. Yeah, never.
And when I say what I say
when I was 22 years old,
I got involved the Russian mafia.
Here's how it happened.
They cheer and that's
when I start drinking.
That's my first drink of the night
because my eyes and I told her the machine
story every night. Then you have like
10 minutes, 14 minutes. And I get it.
I get it. I'll get a little
bit of a buzz. Oddly enough,
I know that people think that I wouldn't,
but even in that 14 minutes,
just having a few sips,
I catch a little bit of a buzz.
But you're also like you're doing the,
uh,
like almost like a performance of a play.
They know, you know, so I get that. I, um,
I never drink ever during shows before,
during I just in my head,
I can't drink before it makes me,
we did it in Vegas.
We tried to Mimosas and I'll do
it on like an overnight flight.
I'll drink that evening. But
I, I can't, I have to be sober.
I can't be having beers getting on stage.
I just give a shitty show.
I usually have, I'll have a drink
after shows once or twice a week.
Whoa.
And usually it's maybe one drink.
Sometimes it's too,
this is what he do after the shot.
So, but I mean, all right, so
because we're both on buses,
it's basically like this,
it's like if I'm, so the second show
will end, I'll go to the green room. Uh,
whoever's with me,
we'll be hanging out in their music.
I have like a speaker, so we'll put
music on, talk about the show is,
talk about jokes. And then if I feel
like having a drink, we have drink.
Sometimes we have post show meal,
so have a meal delivered as I'm
coming off stage. So we eat.
So it's like having dinner after
the show. And then it's like, what,
how important is the transportation?
If it's like we got to get going,
like we get on the bus and um, you know,
if like, like I said, if it's like,
if I feel like having a drink that night,
we have a drink sit around.
Some nights I don't, so sometimes
I'll hit a like a vape pen, uh,
you know, like a mile
edible. I like mild ones,
so I keep it like real buzz level,
you know, not fucked up. Oh,
mine's a little different. Yeah, go
ahead. Tell, tell us the truth. The truth,
truth,
that'd be 100% on smartly.
And I'm worried about how are you
worried about fucking everyone else. Oh,
they know. Everybody knows. It
always comes back to bite you.
A drink on stage for the
second show starts with, when
I tell the machine story,
I go backstage and then, uh,
backstage, I'll have another drink.
Like sitting back there, we do like a,
you know, like a 15 minute chill out.
People come backstage with her backstage
passes like friends or when you know,
whatever and have a drink with them.
And then I'll take that drink out to the
meet and greet to the meet and greet.
Of course. Makes Sense.
Yeah. And then, uh,
and then what I've been
doing a lot lately is going,
is telling everyone in the show where
I'm going to go drink and then everyone
goes and meets me at a bar.
Yeah, it's different. Wow.
It sounds like my nightmare. Oh, so it's
not that bad if you can just connect,
right. If you're just, if you're one of
those people that that can get into you,
then it will get into a lot more.
If I had to do,
I actually don't drink that much cause
I can't drink. So I'm taking pictures.
I'll take maybe like, I would drink
a lot more if I had to take pictures.
I'll take like 500 pictures at
night. Like at a, like I'm white.
I'm inviting 1800 people to a bar,
you know,
and going like both shows. I go,
I'll be drinking it. Dot Dot, dot.
Tonight if you want, meet me over
there and I'll see you over there.
How do you get, I don't get
that house. I won't do shots.
I won't do shots with anyone. People. I
won't let people buy me drinks gives me,
I go in, I'll tip the bartender is usually
a hundred bucks each and just say, hey,
thanks. I'm sorry. Then I fucking swamps
your bar tonight. And then I'll, and I'll,
and they usually take care of
me and just give me like in,
when we did it in Boston, we went
to the place right down the street.
I forget the name of it. And uh, I
did, they didn't have Tito's and soda,
so I just drink beer, but I don't really
go choose Tito's and soda though. Right.
It will say it's just a little healthier.
I think it's a little leaner.
And so that's what,
yeah,
but then we get on the bus and
got a nice handle with you here.
I brought you a little,
you know,
Tito's is always nice enough to
send me handles all the time.
I have maybe I have maybe 19 bottles
of at my, all my outdoor bus.
[inaudible] I have so much goddamn Tito's
all my tour bus and you have no idea.
And Atlanta live nation just gave me
a case of Tito's. They were like, oh,
just tell you have it and we have
so much Tito's. It's ridiculous,
but here's where it gets wacky for me.
It's like,
then we get on the bus and we got,
we don't charge traveling
with like six people.
So you get on the bus and everyone's like,
uh, let's, uh, let's do another round of,
Hey, let's throw on some Netflix.
Hey, we just bullshitting.
And nine you stay up and sometimes until
four in the morning and you're like,
and then sometimes I stay up late.
I do stay up late and I have trouble. I've
always had trouble. I got, I, you know,
I have trouble falling asleep
here when I'm on the east
coast, I'm fucked. Yeah. I,
that's the one thing that
fucks me up the most is a,
I don't even want to be up that late
and I'm still like, fuck man, you know,
it's three 30 in the, but once you
get on the bus, it's healthier for me.
Like when we have to leave right
after a venue, it's very healthy.
When you go to a bar and then you
get back to the bus and you're like,
you're just like,
oh,
it's staying up talking but you're not
getting nap fucked up on the just sitting
on the bus.
Um,
I think my drinking oddly enough has
been more under control of my eating.
I was really good the first
run in minutes, just fuck.
I started to do this like when,
cause you know when you,
when you get to the theaters they'll
say like, you want food, you know,
do you want an order? Appreciate a meal.
Just have like an automated answers.
She'd be like, yeah, grilled
chicken and vet. Like just this way.
What gets delivered is good for you. I
was doing salads for awhile. That's good.
Yeah.
And then we had,
then we were in Indianapolis and
had this great pizza place crunch.
I was like four pizzas.
What?
We'll watch the NFC championship
and the port tour bus. Huh? What?
And it was just fucking the wheels
come off. Yeah. Is that Liam
look at it. What's going
on there? Oh my God,
that's a Bert. Oh my
God. Yeah, jerking off.
That's me jerking off in a window.
Yeah, look at him. Oh my God.
You've never seen this?
I had never seen it before.
That woman got almost got me fired.
Do you never heard this story?
The time you direct off? You've never
heard this story for real? No. Oh,
this is a good story. Tell me. So
for those of you who are listening,
you did not see anything. Okay,
that's true. But what you,
what was it from the shield and those
two acts? It's not real footage.
That's not real footage.
Now that's from the shield.
I thought it was from the tour. No,
no, no, no, no. Okay. So, uh, I,
the television show, the CI, the
shield. You were, I was a cook.
That was my role. It said the cock.
What was the booking like? Uh,
I did actually didn't even have to
read for it. They just booked me.
How great is that? Yeah. Tell him.
He just looked at me and they go,
he looks like a cock fucking cause.
The role was,
I was a guy who hired a black guy to
fuck my wife and I like to Jack off
watching them fuck on the outside
dressed as a DWP outfits. Boy, a guy.
This is pretty cool.
I like this very specific and I didn't
even have to read for it. They went, yeah,
this checks off the black
guys fucking his wife.
So how turned out would you be if
that were a thing? Not at, not at all.
The idea of someone else fucking
Leanne is not turned me on. It
was that you're opening your
opener. No, no, that was,
I don't know what that was from.
And I'm offended by that kind of
big swig.
What would you want to happen with?
Nothing.
Just me and her fucking potatoes.
Girl scout troop leader mom. That
you'd be like, oh Leanne, we should
go to like you put her in the dog
or like missionary or uh, yeah,
we did. We did the 12 nights
of Kama Sutra and December.
We did the 12th of Christmas
with a group of friends.
So we had 12 parties in December.
And then on the first,
every one of those nights.
And then the first night I said,
why don't we as a group of friends
do the 12 nights Kama Sutra?
So every night we have a party,
we'll all send each other at New Kama
Sutra pose that we have to do and then
we'll send our notes back
in the morning as a couple.
And not everyone understood it properly.
The first couple gave their kids a
Nike or a Benadryl and then did all 12
positions at night. It knocked their
kids out and fucked him. 12 new position.
That's not what you said. And
so yeah, there's not oldest,
but Leanne and I did it.
We did all of them and it
was fucking awesome. It was
this one position that, uh,
that she pulled up and it was so cool.
Imagine if,
imagine if you're sitting here,
she's sitting on my lap at her legs
are over to the side right now.
Take that position and
just fall back on the bed.
So her back's on the bed and you're on
your side and her legs are up over your
legs. Does that make
sense? It was awesome.
It was awesome. But yeah,
I'm more berry meat potatoes.
I just want to have regular sex.
Can See big anal guy or no,
never done it. Not with her once
in a camp. This guy did it to me.
Nice guy or no, no, no, I'd
never done anal. Yeah. Really?
I tried. It's the way you booked this
role. You said I booked this role.
Um,
and chiclets is I think Chiklis and this
other guy are directing this episode,
but chiclets is onset.
So I,
I read the breakdown and I the scene and
it's me watching my wife fuck a black
dude, right. And the bike guy and
my wife, we're both in this house.
I see them in the house.
And so I just got into role and
I started playing with my Dick,
like legit playing with
my deck, right. And uh,
they pull up and she gets outraged.
This lady, this lady, that real person,
she calls cut, she goes, this is
ridiculous. He's touching himself.
And in my head I'm like, I
read this wrong. I was like,
I thought it said playing with
yourself. And I'm like, Oh my God,
I'm so fucking embarrassed.
I've never acted in before.
This is the first ever acted in. This is
when we were shooting hurt by the way.
So she goes, I'm not going to
work with him and show she moves.
They split us up. And uh, Michael
Chiklis and this other guy,
I forget the other guy's name, come
up to me and I go, hey man, I'm,
I'm really sorry. I think I
misread this. I can do it again.
I don't have to touch myself. And
he was like, no, great choice.
I want really got her fucker.
It's a great choice. Did,
that's definitely what we want.
As a matter of fact,
what we're going to do is we're going
to hold her in position a and then we're
going to close it on you.
We're gonna do some tights.
We're gonna move the camera around,
but I want you to just play with yourself.
I was like, really? He goes, yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah. Go at it. And then,
and then what am I doing when I
call her back the second time? Uh,
touch, no touch, no touch yourself and,
but we're going to use you touch here.
Should I go? Okay. She goes,
all right. All right, hold
on. First position. All right,
action.
So I'd walk up this whole shot that you
see and I'm fucking playing with my deck
or play with my deck.
And then my dick starts getting hard
and I'm playing with my deck and we're
calling off for like five minutes.
I'm like,
are they even filming or do you
think they're just sitting back?
They're going to watch this
guy, Jaguar xe becomes, yeah.
And so then at finally he goes, all
right, cut. I ain't goes to let you go.
And so then in a little more burden,
they pulled up, they pulled her up,
and then the scene,
I did the scene without touching myself,
but they use me touching myself and
just inner cut them. And then, uh, yeah.
And then I walk around, they
arrest me, put me in cuffs,
had a panic attack in handcuffs,
walked me to the front door,
big black guy comes out and I was like,
honey,
can you just tell them what's going on?
And he's like, yeah, dudes with her.
And then you find out that I liked
to have black eyes. Fuck my wife. Oh
yeah, yeah. Oh Wow.
I know that all you're going
to do is enter cuts my voice.
I'd like to have black guys. Fuck
my wife and I will use it. Yeah.
Yeah. Thank you. These
are all audio recordings
and they're online. Make sure
you mark that by the way.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We got it.
Okay, good. Um, yeah,
we have this other, uh,
footage of the room. Was it, oh, is this,
what is this secret time? Oh yeah. On
Netflix. You can watch it right now.
Does he fly to get easy? Been
Pass it down. What I did on it,
does he need a and yard duty gang?
Is that Tom and Mike Domitrz focus.
Ah, that's, that's a clip from
secret time. It's, uh, yeah,
they're doing an international versus
release of it. They dump it everywhere.
Good job man. I appreciate it
man. Yeah, thanks. I'll be killed.
Another one of these beers.
Do you have it in your audience?
Do they yell like Burdis fat when they
see you or they probably all Thomas Rhett.
Tom Thomas, fat Thomas about the old
tour bus champ a lot. Yeah, the one,
the one, I mean, I told you this,
I hate to even bring up because I,
because obviously it's the,
some regret I never settled the Puck,
but uh,
the very first date I did after doing
this podcast when this in Oxnard and some
guy clear as fucking day in
the middle of my set goes,
tell your n word joke, like what
word? The n word he, but he's had,
he's had the real word,
he said the real word and it was in the
cleanest white version of that use of
that word and it ruined the room.
It ruined the fucking room.
And everyone was like, oh. And I was
like, listen, I don't, I apologize.
I go, listen, I, I understand
that you're a fan, but, uh, I, I,
I'm not gonna, I'm not
gonna do that. And I,
and I just wish you hadn't done that
and it really reset the room and it,
I had to like win them back and
it was like fucking nightmare.
So I get done the show,
I'm doing the meet and greet and this
black guy comes up to me and he goes,
he never told it.
I said,
it was a black I do on a white guy voice
and it fucking, and I was like, I go,
why didn't you tell everyone
you were black? He goes,
I don't care cause he's black.
He's like, oh, I'll give you shit.
But it was fucking horrific.
That was the one that sucked the most.
But mostly people y'all tour bus champ
burns fat and Mickey Mantle. Jean,
is that the black guy?
But no, just a black guy.
Different black guys.
Dude. How about all this black
face showing up, huh? Yeah, yeah,
yeah, there was, there was the fashion
stuff you're talking about. No, no, no.
I'm talking about all these fucking,
oh,
like the Virginia governor.
How funny is,
I mean how fucking comic goal is that
the governor gets caught in black face.
The next guy raped some women and that
allegedly and then the next guy goes.
Actually I've been in black
faced all in Virginia, Virginia.
You did you ever see anyone a black face
in college and like Florida or in high
school? No, no. Our,
our high school cheerleading squad in
like 1980780980 eight came out to babies,
got back in all black face
with wigs and gold chains.
There was a picture of it online.
There's a picture over the line and I
actually hit some of the chicks up and was
like, hey, you guys work with kids. You
might want to get rid of that picture.
One girl I be, it was a picture
online tagged yourself. She's like,
I love this thing. No, there's one girl
that works with disabled kids that had,
there's a picture of me and
her in college. It was a,
this party I threw and she is in straight
black face like like legit blackface
and I ran into her in San
Diego. I was like, Hey,
you may want to like scrub the
Internet of that, like just pull down.
She had posted it herself
and tagged me in it.
Just oblivious to the idea that that
you don't think I was even aware of what
blackface thing?
I'm trying to think of like awareness.
It wasn't like,
I don't think that people were,
I mean I wasn't throwing around
definitely in high school, but I,
if I had seen a probably,
you know what I mean?
I wouldn't notice to my attention as
being as crazy as if you notice it now.
I mean I don't, I never even thought of
it to be on, I mean I'd never done it,
but it's only because I
don't like makeup on my face.
Like I'm not saying that I
would have or I wouldn't,
but I don't like makeup on my face.
Like clowns freaked me out so I don't
never put makeup on my face. Yeah.
That's how I know I've never done.
I know that I did the talent show in
fifth grade. I did young Mc a thing,
but I wore a dress. I'm like,
wait, why did you wear a dress?
A forget, I think I played the
girl that's in the story to move.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So like I, I act
it out now. That's a hate crime.
You were mocking train.
I know
Kevin Cranston,
Bryan Cranston,
because he played a disabled person with
a naval bombing. It just makes me crazy.
It's insane where this is going.
I mean,
Kevin Hart tried to fucking give a
shout out to Jessie, small lat and a,
and it's talking about here's what we
would ask you. Well, what do you think?
Like if you were orchestrating that hate
crime, what do you think he did wrong?
Oh, I'll tell you what would you have
to, how should he have done it? Right?
I can tell you all the things,
all the signals that I picked up on
when I first read the story and I went,
I'm not going to say this out loud, but
this is bullshit. Let's talk to an expert.
You can't,
you can't say this out loud because you
look like a person that is promoting
violence, but I go,
hold on one second too.
Racist White guys
recognized you from empire.
I at two in the morning.
I watch empire like,
but I wouldn't recognize you.
I've watched empire,
but I wouldn't recognize you and
two guys and Maggie has like, Hey,
you're that gay guy from MPO.
That number's going to happen.
No one that's Amaga guys wa is
watching empire. That's just doesn't,
it's not there. What they enjoy watching.
It's a good point. I never thought of.
The noose was on his neck for
45 minutes when the police,
when the police talked to him,
who keeps a noose on their fucking neck,
the cops came to his apartment
to interview him and he
was still had it around
his neck and the bleach.
No one wants,
they're not trying to get you
lighter. No one's like, hey,
we want you to be like us. Come on
man. Let's let, let us help out the,
what the fuck it was
as, as a white person,
you wouldn't want him to be
white or he wouldn't be like,
okay well if this bleach works then
old stop in the middle of this.
I'm so sorry man. Right. There was a lot
of that that I just didn't, I called,
I called bullshit in my head,
but then I'm also a cynic.
I'm and I'm also a contrarion so like,
so like as soon as that happened, I,
that's what I thought.
And then once I found out it was a lie,
I then get empathetic for that kid.
And then I go like,
you feel badly for her. I feel
badly for him. It said, cause I go,
where's his brain at?
And,
and I don't want that to be used as a
lightening Rod to light up true Maggie
racists to go, this is why they're
that or this is like, cause I got,
so like whenever,
whatever side is that,
I'm always going to the opposite side
and trying to argue the other direction.
Yeah. But yeah, I feel bad for that kid.
I don't know what the fuck's
going on in his brain.
They thought that would help him. It's
not good. It's not good for anyone.
I thought the same thing.
It's just,
it's nothing good's going to come
of that could be mental illness.
I don't know. Breathe. You gotta breathe
dude. That is a, that is a great,
your mom's house challenge
to put stuff in your budget.
It's a viral challenge.
There'll be put out on
Facebook my associate like
the ice bucket challenge and
it's right, it's a tight
shot and it's like, hey guys,
my name is Bert Kreischer. It's ready for
the, it's ready. I'm ready for the uh,
the butt plug challenge right now.
You've got to try to guess.
Am I putting a butt plug in or
am I not putting a blood put yet?
And it's just a shot of my
eyes and it's being going
and people have to guess if you
really did it or if you didn't do it.
And then do you show them and then you
pull back and either pants on or your
nick will you do about plug
video? I did a, I would know,
but I tell you what,
I would do a suppository video.
Have you ever put up a sub pository
in your ass? Won't have one put in,
but it's been a long, this is my
impression of getting into some hot,
this is my impression of a suppository
getting put in your asshole.
This is me as the suppository
Okay. Ready? Yeah. No, no,
no, no, no. I'll take it from here. Okay.
So I've put a lot of depositories.
How often? A lot. Cause I,
cause sometimes I fucking ship fire and
source depository is what cools it down.
See how you do it. Like [inaudible]
I've done it very recently.
Like if I eat a lot of spicy stuff
in my fucking assholes burning,
I'll just show what Chabot preparation
h suppository up there. Wow.
And that cools your ass off
immediately. It feels good. Oh,
positive. Never. Never a toy
or a toy. What kind of toy?
Like a little car or something.
Oh No, no. I take him sex toy.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no. I never, I got the little
one. No, I've never had any.
You never been pegged
or anything like that?
Never been pegged to finger
up my ass, obviously. Okay,
so then we're getting somewhere.
Yeah.
I mean who hasn't had a finger in
there as well? I mean how often? No.
Like a college. That was the last
time. Uh, yeah. Leanne, we'll do it.
This is how much you do it.
This is my impression of me and
Leanne during oral sex. Ready?
Put your finger in my ass. What?
Nothing. She would not do that.
That's not the end. Because as soon
as I said that Leanne was just like,
are you gay? That's where they embrace
down. I'm not putting fingers in your ass.
I mean your wife, I would
input a guy, put a shit.
No. Yeah. Well I don't know.
I mean we're asked is a real dry.
Anytime I would ever offer that,
it would be a Coleen doubt.
Okay.
I don't have any shit hanging out in
my body that I'm not getting rid of
immediately. Yeah. I don't know. But
you're asked. Seems real dicey to me.
If you had to put your finger
on one of our assets. Who's who?
Did Tom ask the question?
I mean
nobody like looked on base. Let's
say. I'm not married to him,
young guys,
just my friends.
Just knowing what I know about
both of your personal hygiene.
His is way better than
yours. No. You have very,
a very lax slack idea of personal hygiene.
It's about his personal life.
I remember one time I picked something
out of my body or something and I smelled
it and Tom goes, you would
smell that I grow. I'm sorry.
If you find an object on your body,
your first thing isn't a smell it.
That's a first thing I do. If I bought
it. It's like, where are you finding it?
What better thing? Something between
your toes. First thing I do it well.
What's that? I don't smell
between my, no. Oh, Mike.
I would investigate but I wouldn't
smell out. Look at it. I'm all.
Then just start to smell that
bubbly. Okay. Say belly button. Lynn.
I wouldn't have been here. You don't rub
your finger behind your and smelling? No.
Why would you do it?
Try it.
Do you use, does your smell your behind
my ears do right now. All this nasty.
I'm wearing headsets. No, it's
because you're nasty though.
It's not cause I'm nasty.
I'm 90% of the [inaudible] told us.
Remember when you used to live on set
up sixth street downstream from us?
I just treat whatever that you use to
clip your toenails and then you collect
them on a piece of scotch tape and then
you tape it under a coffee tea coffee
table, which is so nasty, nasty,
nasty. Why is that not nasty?
It's so nasty.
If you had to smell balls right now,
you think smell better. Minor Tom.
Tom's a thousand times
hotter.
Always bet your balls smell
her horrendous. And here's why.
I'm going to tell you why you don't wear
underwear and your genes are not clean.
You wear the same jeans
every time I see you.
And on top of their cell phones
like you usually think of like, hey,
this guy drinks like a 1590 bottles a day,
like probably smells between his legs,
stinky.
You really think you're to do your
balls smell good right now. Right now?
Right now.
I'm good right now,
but I don't think they're quite at that
sour state. You showered last night?
I showered this morning. Yeah,
but guess what I'm saying?
You're naturally stink here.
Well, my balls right now are ripe.
I can tell because they're all in these
genes and these genes are a older,
they're a little older.
They're three, three weeks old.
That's how long you go between
washing your jeans. Yeah.
I've actually had a pair of jeans.
One time I was flying back from South
Africa and I was on the plane. I went,
I think my jeans smell.
I could smell my jeans and then
I washed them and I was like, oh,
they're not that color for real.
How old are these? Yeah. Yeah.
I think Leanne is just really accepting
of the fact that you're disgusting.
My teeth, my teeth are good right now.
Brushed their good cause I know I don't.
I floss, I floss like aggressively, but
more importantly, our waterpik every day.
That's pretty good. That's good.
Let's see a smile. He brush. Why not?
Cause cause I already know, I already
know one time you go, you were being,
you were talking, you go,
hey, why don't you get your
teeth fixed? Why don't you go,
you got money, just get your teeth
wigs. You got to get them whitened.
Wait one brown one the top though.
Now your teeth look good there.
Okay. No till your teeth are good. But
I bet your beard smells like clean.
It smells like balls often.
Cause I played with my balls
and then I played with my beat.
Leanne will be kissing me and go, have
you been playing with your Dick Today?
And I'll go, why? And
she goes, you're a face,
smells like balls one
time you got you so gross
Tom. You Go, I was on the phone with you
and you're at home. You're like, Hey,
I'm a finger, smells real bad. And I was
like, why you like it smells like shit.
And I go, what'd you touch? And you
were like, oh no. And then you're like,
oh Leah just got upset. And I go, wait a
minute, you don't know why your finger?
It smells like Shit and you go, oh, I
go, were you toying with your asshole?
And you go, yeah, yeah,
it'll hold on. You don't play with your
ass sometimes in bed? No. What the fuck,
Bro?
Let me tell you what I do get.
I don't play with my asshole
and here's what I do.
I don't like, but stuff I'm not into,
but never had a finger in your butt.
I've had a finger in my butt.
I don't like it. I'm not.
It makes me feel like I have to Brown
or Lewis and Clark.
I haven't had one in mind in a long time.
I'm afraid of getting shit on my fingers.
That's what happened.
I don't bear scratch my
be whole with my hands.
I don't bear scratch my arm
pits. I do it. I'll do it over,
but then I'll just change my clothes.
I'll just take off the underwear.
I take off the shirt.
I usually only toilet paper.
I will
do an investigatory
super wet.
I smell every part of my body. There's
not one part of my body. I don't smell.
I wretched.
Your poor wife.
I have a pimple on my lip.
I got a thing guys.
Hard core. By the way, the hardcore
fun shirt is now in our store.
Uh, it's uh, your mom's house.
New Item exclusive. Go at a time.
So girl or emerged,
gretta.com/ [inaudible]
Tom Segura, I don't think, I
don't know if it will be up as a,
the recording of this,
but there's the new bike stuff.
There's the new mousepad.
There's going to be a special water id.
We'll see very soon.
It is on sale too at this website.
Tom Skirt. I like the Torah. Postwar
us off for the ride or die tour.
It's cool. It's really
cool. They also have the,
the overstock from the,
uh,
the last tour that I did the tour bus
champ with a vert taking a shit in the
corner that will also be in the store.
So there's a poster that this
designer May, he uh, he's awesome.
He listens to the show and he
was designed posters for me.
He'll just come up with things and he
put this one tour bus champ was the theme
and he puts the location and
all this, uh, you know me on it.
And then right behind the bus you
were squatting, taking a shit. And,
and that was like, the people
loved it. They were like, hey,
there's partaking tickets chair.
Oh, cool. Nice smell behind yours. Yeah.
Is it moist?
I shower,
I shower, I shower every day. I
know what you're talking about.
Ross is the one that turned me onto that.
That's if you were heads, if you'd like,
if you didn't shower and you, and
you would put on headsets. Yeah,
that makes sense. You'd be sweating.
They're right. And maybe they don't make,
you know what I mean?
They're not like sweaty
lots of people. Oh really? Greg
Fitzsimmons was there before, you know,
had set smells. Have you
seen, uh, blood wave,
the trailer for blood wave?
The Netflix doc? No. Oh my God.
This is, yes. Turn it up. Turn
it up. And this is pretty cool.
Check this out.
Was a sudden violent
crimes across America,
several high profile violent crimes
have gripped the nation these past few
months around the same
time unknown fattened,
racist comedian went on to
work in a similar pattern.
I just want to show you what a real tour
best champ does to hold down the title
from the shooting deaths of two African
Americans that it can Tuckey supermarket
to the killing of 11 worshipers
at a Pittsburgh synagogue.
This documentary [inaudible] between
Bert Kreischer at these hate crimes from
Charlotte and Atlanta.
Georgia is one of only five
states without a hate crime law.
Right now I'm at the hard
rock live in Orlando.
We're seeing is that the bulk of
these crimes are, are aimed at
immigrants and Muslims.
A man is still in jail tonight,
charged with a hate crime after police.
Say he threatened to kill a
woman in downtown Portland.
Crushers stop heinous crimes.
Uh,
netflix.in 2019 that's great work.
That's got to be awesome to be so good
active with them.
Yeah.
You know what was going to be cold.
It's like it's going to become real news.
Oh, this out of context is going to
fuck somebody up. Oh, out of context.
They will believe it.
We're going to,
we're going to drop these like
kind of everywhere. You know?
I remember that there was a person,
that's how I was responsible
for the synagogue shootings.
Someone said that, oh,
I sent it to you. Really? A long story.
I'm not getting into into it. Yeah.
Somebody tweeted you that. Not Don't
let it change the fucking subject.
Someone genuinely wrote an article saying
I was responsible for those synagogues
shooting. Okay, let's
change this second. Okay.
But how often do you shower for Leanne?
Everyday. Everyday. Everyday? Yeah.
So this is the type of guy you got it.
Oh cool. Yeah. I saw her every day.
We're talking about these guys.
Right? Burger. Right. Here's the,
so Bert is where bridge right there.
Right
where? Just the way, way
in. Right? Why is this
slow?
Right?
So we can say that bird is in,
what place is he in first place?
Second place.
He's in fourth quarter. Right births
and fourth place. First one second Sam.
Right. So births and forth. Okay.
This is crazy. Yes. I've
never seen this. Yeah.
People are still learning about math and
stuff like that based on how fat burden,
by the way, whoever who just
said that, I don't know.
One of your fucking laugh
tracks back there. No.
People sent that in a long time ago,
but apparently I've never seen this.
They're still sending it out. This
one's new. Okay. Oh cool. Yeah,
I was super excited to keep playing.
The rest of it.
Turn up my volume of my head
says I'm not hearing it.
Fair enough. Tell me again
who's first place jail. Jasper,
Joe and then second. Hi, sorry. Second.
Tom. Tom. Tom,
who's in fourth?
Kids laughing. I don't know.
I think they like your name.
I bet kids like your name. Yeah.
It's a fun name of a great man.
You don't hear it a lot either?
No. Like Burton earnings.
What does that some teacher that's just
basically talking about the weight loss
challenge.
It's a teacher who's a is usually we
get like English as a second language
teachers and like when they're just
trying to come up with sentences,
they'll just, you know, they'll
throw in something like,
and then what happens if you eat too much?
And then the kids go,
you get like bird like that.
I don't know,
they just send it in. I'm starting
to understand this fake news thing.
It was becomes real.
There's people that come out to me after
the shows that are massively overweight.
They're like, Hey, are you fat? Fuck.
And you're like, and you're like,
you're fatter than I am.
Like I get that when they're like,
um,
when it actually,
the only person who will say something
to you like to my face will be like a
really fat guy. Oh yeah. Or the most
abusive fat comment. You're like,
who's this guy will be like 380
and he's like, Hey, are you fat?
Fuck or block someone today?
You did. Yeah. I don't mind.
I get,
I can,
I have the probably the thicker skin
out of most of the comics out there.
I get I, I can take a joke and
I'm fine with it and I get,
I can understand an attempt
at a joke to fall short.
I understand that they're not pros at it.
I've fallen short,
but sometimes you get guys who just say
mean shit and I'll take it if you like.
I mean, I'll be like, you
know, if the guy follows me,
I know he was trying to be funny. If you
don't follow me, I'm like, sorry man,
that's not how it works. You got fucking
blocked. Yeah, you get to suck a dick.
Or if like I blocked people because they
said way too much mean shit about you.
And I'm like, oh no, he's my friend.
I like him more than I like
you and now I'm blocking you.
I would like to a lot of people
on Instagram for the comment, Oh,
I've blocked a lot of people on Instagram.
We just get all my thing and
start fights with people and just,
but they're trying to do like an inside
joke, but they're legit starting fights.
I just go, man, you can't play anymore.
You've got to understand the nuance of it.
You've got to get out of a sense of
humor about it at least. Yeah, I agree.
I don't like, I don't like
the super abusive stuff. Like,
or if I post a picture of
my family and they go, ah,
they say like really horrible shit
about like whatever. I'm just like,
ah, you're not gonna play. Yeah,
but I think that's the right we have
is to say, Hey, I'm not going to,
cause I know,
I remember when,
when we first did the fat shaming
at the very beginning, uh,
there were people that did not,
would,
you weren't in on the joke and they
weren't getting it at first and there were
picking sides for real. Fuck
Bert. I fucking hate that guy.
He'll have sued his own jokes.
He's a fucking,
you don't even have a Netflix special.
Who the fuck is he anyway?
He's just some guy from travel channel.
I remember you going like, Huh?
He's blocked and go fuck
himself. Yeah. No, I don't,
I don't like to really mean stuff.
I thought there's like a circle of
people that we kind of like is not racist
guys.
Like this is a circle of
people that get the joke,
but then there's people that just, Oh
yeah, we put them in World War II footage.
It's a joke.
I didn't think I'd have to say it.
That's not real.
Not a Nazi.
Do you realize that that was an off the
cuff comment though. This started it.
You were just sitting down.
We were promoting it was a perfect time.
It was a part number, like here's the
fattest and, and we just pause. Like,
what's another bad
thing to say? Uh, super.
Unapologetically Reddix the racist
guy and like, if that was it,
we've got to get a new thing going.
What do you want to be?
Oh,
the vessels in comedy and comedy.
I drove with the biggest
dick smelly his balls.
Um, grossest brighter,
exciting
stage presence.
Charged with rape, but never too late.
Someone's already done that.
Yeah. Some fucking guy used to be my
friend did that. What am I going to say?
His name. All right, let's go
tour by the way. You Maniac. Yeah.
So your tour is a huge success.
Probably bigger than you ever thought.
It would be way bigger than I ever thought
it would be. And everywhere you're,
you're adding shows you fucking touring
every week like a psycho. Um, when,
so when are you, uh, what's,
what's the next stops where you,
that you want to people to come to?
Where are you, where are you going to be?
I know you have everything,
but I think, no, I think, uh,
everything's sold, but you know,
there's always like single tickets,
there's always available
tickets. So like, uh, on,
on their second shows there's
always like, you know, like,
like a two packets somewhere.
I'm in New Orleans this week,
Austin, Dallas, and then, uh,
and then I do like jersey,
Philly, DC, and then that
run to the Middle East,
middle, middle of the country.
And then I'm,
and then I'm in Australia and Europe.
Yeah. Yeah. I think
Europe's already sold out.
And then Australia has got open tickets,
I think,
but that's like fucking three months,
four months away. That's great.
Are you ever going to do Australia? And
we're talking right now for real. Yeah.
The main thing is I didn't
want to announce it a way
ahead of time. I was like,
you can't put me in a
position where I get fucked.
So we'd have to announce it closer to
the date. So we went a little B. Wow.
I mean it would,
I would announce it later in the year.
And so it be later in the year
ball.
No more like winter. You got, you
know, you've got to do when they go,
ladies and gentlemen,
put your hands together for Tom Segura
and don't walk out on stage for 15
minutes.
You've done a story with Joe though,
right?
And I did the Melbourne comedy festival.
Hey,
what's going to be our sober October
challenges here? I don't know.
Think about it now.
So we're not thinking of it at the last
minute and we're not doing the surf
thing. I don't, I mean, I don't know
how he would, yeah, I know it's October.
It's gonna be cold as
fuck. It's really cold. Uh,
how about we each raise a wolf
children?
That's a great idea.
I'm trying to plan my touring around it
because I don't want to be touring to
aggressively in October. Yeah. You
did not do well if you did that. Yeah.
Right now I'm out.
They want me to go out every single
weekend in October and I'm like, I can't.
I can't. I sober October. Too much
fun. I want to be present for it.
I want to be here. I want to do
something where we all do it together.
Like we did hot yoga where
it's bringing together,
we're going to say first one was better.
The first one was better
than the competition got
intense and the only person,
I mean I didn't, I didn't even talk
to Ari. I couldn't even talk to rex.
He was so competitive about it this year,
this year's or whatever,
and I didn't talk to Joe wants and we'd
all be in our taxed by the only person I
ever spoke to is you. Yeah.
Like I want to do something.
His cohesive kidneys were shutting
down like he was doing stupid shit.
We can't do that. We talked about
it last night and he was like,
it's good to know. I still got that part
of my brain around where he's like, ah,
oh, it's survival mode. Let's
fucking go. And I was like, yeah,
that my brain didn't do that at all.
What did, did it bother you? What?
When we did sober October. Yeah.
It's stupid. I think it's horrible
and it ruins our family life.
It puts a wrench in everything.
Wow.
She sounds like Leanne hard
fucking core rolled out. Yeah,
because where are the other
half to sober? October. In fact,
I think she and I should do a podcast
when you guys are doing sober October so
we can let people know how
much it wreaks havoc on.
Everybody's glad our
wives to see which uh,
which wife could milk the most
semen out of us. It be cool. Yeah.
That's a good challenge. It's a
great town. I liked that. Hey,
someone dropped the artwork. Sober October
milk. The men, the Milkman challenge.
I like this one. Well Ari needs a milker.
He doesn't have want to feel fine.
If you find someone who's got some 25
year old hippie that makes put Julia in
New York. Yeah. Who doesn't know it is.
She'll, she'll milk them through a table,
you know, that'd be fine. Let's see.
What can you guys do that's inclusive
and fun and cause I think you're right.
The solo nature of the last one wasn't
fun cause you guys have enjoyable. It was
interesting. Yeah it was a good journey
but it wasn't, it wasn't, you know,
what kind of stuff, here's the thing
about the hot yoga. It's, it kinda sucks.
It is doable.
It's about going there.
What if it was more like a like at spin
class kind of thing. Like that sucks.
It's doable but you don't want to
go fucking 15 times in a month.
You know what if we paired up with,
I mean I think all of us
are pretty anti corporate,
but what if we did pair up with a big
corporation to do something of theirs so
we could, I don't know. I mean we're
already gonna lose jokes. He's like,
we're not going all financially
benefit off sober October.
I think part of the fun of it is
that it's organic, you know? Yeah.
I mean going in like,
I think going to the like making yourself
go to the class and knowing that you
can miss a day, but man, you
better not miss too many.
That made it interesting to me.
Yeah. I I liked, I mean, when Ari,
like when we were in Arizona and art, he
was like, hey, we gotta go. We gotta go.
We have a hot yoga class at five and
then we're doing a show at eight.
It was kind of fun to dip out,
go do hot yoga.
Did you already do that
week with him then you guys,
weren't you asking to do Salt Lake, Utah?
He already did it. Yeah. How was it?
It was great. Ari Is fucking
hilarious to watch ski. Really.
He's the ugliest skier you've ever seen
in your life. He is, first of all, he's,
he's taller and lankier than anyone out
there. He dresses like he's a child.
He has like Stars and Stripes Pants,
a Dirk Novinski Jersey on.
He covers his face, all black. So it looks
like he's like one of those Gi Joe Man.
And then he skis, uh, like a pizza pie,
whereas he just snow power the whole time.
But he goes 60 miles an hour.
Snowplowing like it's disgusting.
Uh,
yeah, but he, uh, there
was a phone we can, man.
All we did was talk shit
about comedy. Really? Oh,
that's your favorite thing to
do? 100%. That's yours too.
Not as much as you, I enjoy watching you
gossip more than you had caught me. I,
we like gossiping because at the
million, but we, I mean like,
do you think you're like, you, uh, enhance
it for me? I get into it. I get into it.
I like to punch up a good chaos.
It's fun to watch.
You get excited about shad target.
Oh Dude. When we've, we've,
we went down this blue run,
it's called boomer,
and in the middle of boomer and Salt Lake
City, there's a bar and we went down.
We'd been skiing like half the day we
like maybe five runs. We get to this bar,
boom or, and we sit down
when again, won't appear.
We want a beer and then something pops
up on the Internet and I have someone's
like, dude, have you seen this?
And all of a sudden we're at boom
worth this bar for two hours.
And then at one point were like, fuck it.
You just want to get out of the bottom,
get drunk and finish this conversation.
Dude, it was the greatest.
Sounds like a lot of fun, dude. I have.
I could talk about comedy for days.
I love it
now just to keep it up and stuff. Don't
worry. What do you texting them for?
Texting. Laugh track.
Oh, you mean laugh track?
I hear them cackling in there.
They're laughing at moments.
They went to that and I don't,
do you think I'm instructing them?
And I thought it was, oh, it was
legit. Laugh track when I was outside.
I was looking at their fucking cackle
it you're here to get, but that's,
that's just him. Why is he had the
fucking mask on his face. He's, he's, oh,
he's black. Got Aids. Oh. So
he didn't want me to know.
I'm like, hey dude, I got friends
coming. You mind covering up?
He's like, yeah, no problem.
You got a legit set here.
Yeah. Do you like it? Well,
not when Mcdonald's was sponsoring,
because when they gave us,
they gave us two point $3
million and they were like,
if you paint the set or a Mcdonald's
colors and when they pulled out
and Morton's jumped on and then
they fired us like two weeks ago.
Really?
So what's it like? What's the ideal
a sponsor for you guys? I mean,
we'd love to keep it in the steak house
wheelhouse, but I dunno man.
I mean we have a couple of,
there's this, a Korean steakhouses
looking to do something,
but the only one to throw us a few hundred
bucks, you know, they got that. Cool.
I'd rather, I'd rather have one of
the big dogs do it. Really? Sure.
Like a like,
oh yeah.
Or Smiths. Oh yeah, that'd be
great. Oh, that would be me.
They get crazy food to go all
green and white. It would be great.
And have a guy with like a nice little
butler coat come out or view a stake in
the middle of our Houston's
even I like Houston Lot.
Baby back ribs are the best
ribs in the fucking world.
Pregnant with the first kid.
We would go there once a week
during even say his name.
That's how private you
are. Oh God. I'm so glad.
Well we gotta get you a travel
smoker, Tommy. So you're really,
you're smoking, smoking meat during the
show, during the show, during the day.
Who sets it up? Dave Williamson or myself.
We can mostly Dave Williams sentences.
Such an inherently bad idea.
Jude. We set up the travel smoker.
We put out some chairs,
put the awning out and crack some beers
and sit on the sidewalk outside the
theater. People were walking by
going, hey, wait, is it, is that you?
All of us didn't even know who I am. I
go, yeah, they go, hey, I got a picture.
Don't even know who I am.
I'll make sure it's hilarious.
And then your meat's ready by the end of
the night or what? Oh yeah, yeah. It was,
well, we did a brisket in Tampa. We
did. She sign a sore ribs in Orlando.
We did a pulled pork in Atlanta.
We've done it every,
we did Vegan burgers in Fort Lauderdale.
You set this up every night.
Set up every night. It's so much fucking
fun. Shout out to rec tech. Wow, dude.
They got great gear. Where did they
meet you to like to give it to you?
I don't know. You know they sent me a
grill a while ago. Just, I don't know,
it's just send it to me and I didn't open
it. I didn't even, I just was like, ah,
I'm busy and I'm busy. Yeah. It was
just this big grill and I was like,
I don't have time to put it together.
They send it to and they gave me like a
custom great where it says the machine
on it and then one day I'm with Leanne.
We got to talk to some
time off and I'm like,
I'm going to put that smoke
together and I put it together.
It's a really nice smoker.
And then I was like, Hey,
I'm going to smoke some stuff tonight.
So I smoked some pork ribs and the
girls loved him and I was like, it's,
I enjoy, you know, I'm a,
I am the quintessential American
like homer Simpson male. Yeah.
I love setting up my grill,
grilling out, having a beer.
I'll say this by the way. Yeah, 100%
true. I've always told people this.
You're an excellent cook.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
I mean it genuinely and sincerely.
I think back on those early
days when I was coming over,
we would go over to their apartment
and, uh, I was looking, I was,
I would look at going to your
place almost like, you know,
when you go home from college, I'm going
to have some good food. When I'm home.
You would cook feasts. Oh, I would ban
it. Those days are the best. Those were,
I missed those days so much.
And the Nakey time,
Nikki time number that when
girls get naked running around.
I remember I took a shit on the roof.
If I got to get together one time
to squash it was running around.
She just looked at me and was like,
oh, just pinched one off right there.
I looked at that house on my parents pool
one time, just jumped out of the pool,
put her bathing suit, offside shit in
the yard and then jump back in the pool.
I was like,
that's my kid,
you know,
the rooftop and we would all go out
there and watch the sunset and drink beer
and
eat McDonald's. Mcdonald's. Sorry.
That's right.
Good time. But those are the, that
was the beginning of everything.
I think Tommy and I were just becoming
feature acts and you were coming a
headliner.
You just had to choose girl.
I did see before I even
knew anything about
bonuses.
You guys came over and I did Columbus.
It's right when we started doing
Rogan's podcast a little bit.
You guys came over and as
Stroup was like, Hey, uh,
you hit your bonus is how do you want
it in cash or in the check. I was like,
I'll give it a cash. And he gave me like
$6,000 in cash and I was like, what?
You came over to my house at night
and I was making it rain on Ios.
She was on the ground and I
was just making it rain on her.
And I know it was like, look at my bonus.
I had $6,000 in cash. You were like,
Holy Shit. I was like, I know.
Can you believe this dude?
I look back to those times so
fondly because it was like,
even like little things like,
um,
do you remember the time he
told me I burp a lot? Yeah.
Like we were in the car and you're like,
yeah,
this is such like something wrong with,
there's some, you like the, if you don't,
if you only know Tom for this podcast,
there's a part of his personality
you don't get, first of all, he,
me and him are very similar in
that we, we right. Think so. We'll,
we'll be writing a joke like
this. Oh yeah, yeah. That phase.
But then there's another part of him where
he like wool. Like, it's almost like,
uh,
like a child where he looks at you and
you can tell he's got a thought isn't it?
You burp a lot. And I was
like, Huh? He was like, Yo,
you've burped like a hundred times in
this car ride. I was like, no I don't.
And you're like, no, no, you actually
do. And then I started going,
God damn and I do burp a lot.
And then the next thing was I saw him like
a week later. He was like, guess what?
I talked to my doctor and he said,
there's definitely something wrong.
I was like, really?
Because he was, I told him,
you said it was burping a lot and then I
was thinking about it and talking about
it to them and I definitely have
like some acid reflux. I was burping.
I didn't realize you still do. You
always go, well I do have, I'm drinking,
but I was, I wasn't even drinking.
We're just in the car. Yeah.
And I was burping like a lot.
And you're going, oh yeah,
I remember that was it. Yeah. I
err, err too. That's my big thing.
Like if I make some things
that someone to eat,
something to eat and I watched
them take a bite, I'll go.
You also, by the way,
but aside from you. Yeah,
like you have told me, everyone told
me my whole life, they're like, ah,
you slow down.
Just going to say that.
I'm like a word made me feel like the,
I was a slow eater.
Like he'd eat a steak and four bites. I
was like, are you all right? He'd be like,
whoa.
Oh Dude. That should be the
sweat when I eat. Yeah, no, he's,
you're a fast eater now.
I don't know if you can do quantity,
but I know that you can do speed.
Can we incorporate this and sober October?
Maybe you're staying sober, but can you
start eating faster? Why didn't like that?
Eating faster and faster. Whatever.
Eating contest Rocktober I could eat.
Can't get fucked up, but you can eat.
We're gonna lose Joel and eating contest.
Yes.
Fatter on October.
Yeah. He was to get the
fattest. That's not, we've got
to make it something that's,
no. Yeah, he would definitely,
although he would just take it to the
next level of gain a hundred pounds and
he'd be like, I'm going to lose it
this week. I'll lose it on a jog.
We need it to be,
uh,
something that is folds in
easy to Joe and Ari's life,
but makes it fun for our family. So it's,
we're not, you know what I mean? Yeah. Oh,
there it is. Oh, those are not the
burbs I'm talking about. I know, I know.
I did a different on purpose.
I was almost doing the regular ones.
Have you always been a fast eater?
A very,
my dad was a fast heater
and so I looked at it,
it's like a rite of manhood and you eat
fast and that's whole man back then.
I eat horrifically fast. How, how?
He's really fast to my daddy's real fast.
Like,
like I'm like a shark. Like
I, I literally, my eyes go
back in my head and I just,
and I just can't stop. I can't, I, I,
I don't know how to do the thing. It's,
this is a super fat person
thing where you're like, well,
like even it's really good,
but I'm totally full,
but like I can't not eat everything.
Right. And then you're like, oh,
it's really hurts. And you still like
Keith deedee and you're like God.
And then sometimes it's somebody like a
sensible not fat person. They'll be like,
you know, you don't have to keep
eating that. And you're like, oh yeah,
I didn't think about that. If someone
makes me a meal, I'll let you know.
I'm not going to leave one part, not
eaten all of it. I'll heed all of it.
I find it disrespectful
to not eat everything.
Last night I had fought a friend's
house and I didn't, I was not hungry,
but they served me a big bowl of pho,
ate the whole thing. I didn't want it.
I just ate it cause I was like,
I was shitting at the comedy store last
night because of it. I was a store.
I'm like that. It was great. It was, it
was great. It was really awesome. Um,
I also,
if I'm that way with booze you like,
I cannot leave.
I cannot leave a d. Like if someone
gives me, opens a bottle of wine, I go,
we're going to drink the whole bottle
of wine, not gonna drink half of it.
If someone gives me a beer,
I'm not going to leave.
I'm going to drink the whole beer.
I'm not going to say,
you're not going to leave here unless
you finished six more beers and a bottle
of Tito's I have to finish. Yeah, that
makes sense. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
You're fine.
One of the first times,
one of the first times I started and drink
for like six months when I was dating
Leanne, because we, she dumped
me for early on for drinking. No,
it wasn't for drinking,
but I,
but what we got into a fight was I was
drunk when that happened and I got,
I felt like alcohol betrayed me
for the first time. So I was like,
I'm putting alcohol in timeout. And then
I was like, and then I got to a place,
I was like, maybe I'll never
drink again. I thought that.
And then we went to Italy and it
was snowing. We were in Venice,
it was snowing and we were,
and it was like during a vacation.
So gnomes on this roads?
No, it was on the streets.
And we went to a little restaurant
and it started snowing and she said,
I say we just walk around all night. And
I was like, I gotta be honest with you.
I really want a glass of wine and I
hadn't drank or wanted to drink in six
months. She goes, do it. I
don't give a fuck. And I was
like, really? She goes, yeah.
She goes, I don't think of a drinking
problem. I just think you drank a lot,
but here's now, but this is
going from not drinking at all.
So I have a couple of glasses of wine.
They bring the bottle out and I go,
we're not going to leave
the fucking bottle.
We're going to murder the goddamned
bottle. Like I'm not going to.
And I hadn't drank at all and had
one glass. I felt really buzz. I go,
we're killing the whole bottle now.
I'm burping a lot. And I notice it. Um,
and then we killed the bottle
and we walked out in the snow.
It was one of the most romantic
nights I ever had in my life. Oh,
it's fucking great. And in
Venice? In Italy and just snow,
it just started falling.
It was brand new.
Snow covered streets
known had walked on it,
it was like midnight and it
was right after New Year's Eve.
So everything was shut down.
Like your honeymoon or no,
it's that she thought I was going to
propose to her. Yeah. And I didn't,
I did it in our bed and of later.
So the way that you walked through and
she was like, here it is. I can't be like,
oh, I gotta take a shit. Pretty
bad going on at the time I shoe.
Huh? What, what are you crying for?
Wait,
why did she dump you?
We got into a fight with her
friend and I wouldn't let it go.
Her friend picked a fight with me at a
dinner and I wouldn't let it go. And I,
I like, after three days I was still
upset with it and, and, and I hadn't said,
I love you to her yet. She
had said, I love you to me.
And I hadn't said Olivia. Uh,
four months. She's like, I
love you and you're like, cool.
I said, cool. And she goes,
I said, no, actually. I said,
she goes, I love you. And I
said, you do? She said, yeah,
and you love me. And I said, I do.
She said, yeah. And I was like, cool.
And I just wasn't, I wasn't,
I wasn't ready to settle
down. I didn't want to like,
I didn't know.
I didn't want to put labels on it at
the time. 28. God, you
guys are old now. Two
kids are grown ass kids,
man. No Shit. Brow.
We have babies in this for forever now.
He just fucking started.
That's cozy. That's crazy.
Dude. I, I was 33 when you were,
when I was when, but that's not that
different. You're like seven years older.
It's not that I'm not seven years
old or you're seven years older. No,
you're seven years older than I was
when I had kids. Oh really? Yeah. Oh,
so it's not that bad. Wait, how old
were you in Georgia was born 30 George.
I'm 46 now.
She's 14 so 32 okay.
No,
I was 30 when we got married.
He was 28 I was 36 when you had the Ellis,
the oldest. Say his name now. Yeah.
Well I say the oldest for 36 that's
not too bad. No, it's not too bad,
but it does make you old one.
He's going to be a hundred when
his kids in kindergarten. Well,
he's going to go to that high school
graduation and they'll be like your
granddad. So Ollie mean
looking. Oh my gosh.
And that she'll be like,
that's my dad. Come on. Hey,
I'll be able to smoke pot with my kids.
Yeah,
I'll be like 55 and George was in
college. That's pretty cool. Georgia,
Georgia, me that dads or
when they ate, when they
come home from the, they'll bring a friend
when they call and he'll be like, hey,
you guys want to rage tonight?
God's going to get the cue fired up.
Who wants some smoke? Dinosaur
Barbecue ribs. Speedo on George.
We've got a pool of 40 of her friends
are going to be like your tats.
So much fun. It should be. Yeah. Uh,
George George's friends do not
think I'm pulling it all back.
No two fucks about me. Really? Yeah. I
lose friends who could give two shits.
No one cares at all.
None of the friends.
Right. I figured that some of
the friends, here's the thing,
are any of the friends guys, boys?
No. Yeah. When they started having,
I don't even mean like, I mean a
boyfriend, but like a friend that's a boy.
The friends are gonna go nuts for you.
When if I go, this is a, you know Kyle,
I have classes him, he's going to go
fucking crazy. You're dad's a machine. Oh,
he's going to love it.
He's going to love it.
And then we'll end up attracting just a
bunch of mouth breathing window liquors.
Just, yeah. Oh Dude, I can
do keg stands. Yeah. Yeah.
I shouldn't have a pizza box and want
to login to, I'm just like your dad.
Oh yeah. That's when they start
dating. Yes, they're wiring.
You know that you've
wired them the like the,
it's like you date a guy like your dad.
I did in the past before
Tom and I fucking hated it.
It was such torture for me.
Nice running car washes.
I thought it was big. So
we go to dinner tonight.
You get in the car, you dress nice. Put
on the red lipstick. All right, let's go.
That's how I picture in my head.
Yeah, that's exactly right.
It's not that far.
You've got the gold chain.
No Way. Tommy is the opposite
of, of everything in my family,
but that's why I was so attracted to
him cause he's like stable and sane and
kind and he does what he says he's
going to do and like he's just
for him. Do you feel like, and I'll say
this, I know that you're successful,
but none of us in this room are
as accessible as Tommy. Of course.
You feel like you picked the right horse.
Oh my God.
All the time.
Whoever's on common.
If you had said to me one of your friends
is going to be famous, I'd be like,
whoa.
I say to him all the time, what do I tell
you, Tommy? What do I say to you? You him,
you said, uh, she goes, he's a winner.
Yeah. I knew. I knew you were a winner.
Here's the truth.
Burt shot is that I knew Tommy was a
goddamn winner from the moment that I met
him. We know. Remember, we're all
fucking open. Miker is, will you're,
you're in a class ahead of us whenever,
but like Tommy was 23 and he was funnier.
Everybody, like he's the kind that
started standing up and was amazing.
It's Dan so far and I bombed in
front of Burt 10 times. Yeah,
but you also think fucking
you're thinking was straight.
I always knew that you would be,
I'll tell you what I heads, I'll tell you
what I knew Tom. He was a winter. Yeah.
Is, uh, we did a TV show
and they were like, hey,
I was like, we need to bring in a writer.
Do you have any suggestions? I go,
my buddy,
Tom Segura is a really great comic.
He could be writer and I was, I think I
was doing birth conquered at the time.
And so I went to do birth conquer.
I came back a week later and Tom head,
not only taking the head writers job,
but he was also executive
producing the show.
The guy who was the executive
producer was now doing crowd control.
Mary go buddy Tom James the
whole fucking show. He's like,
so here's the breakdown,
I'll show you how it works.
And he show ran the whole show.
And I was like, shut the fuck up.
And that show was the funniest fucking
show that's ever called buzzed.
Oh,
I remember
fucking brainer like it was. And he
was, but that's why I picked exactly.
If it makes sense.
And it was designed for Bert,
like literally you
couldn't have anybody else.
And the pilot was hilarious.
Hilarious.
And they knocked that, they shut it
down immediately. Like it wasn't easy.
Was involved. Yeah. And they were
like, the show's called buttons,
but there's those dating shows where
they put boo boos and all those people.
The premise, the blind date show
is boozing. No, no, no. Remember
they had a sober, for those of you
listening, we had a segment called, um,
called, uh, was it, uh,
look at her, stick it, yeah.
Where it was like we'd put up a slow
celebrity and you'd have to guess if she
was straight or gay. Yeah.
And so hilarious. It was
hilarious. And it was like,
it was like Hilary Swank,
uh, uh, Jennifer Garner.
And then it was Jamie Lee Curtis
and this guy goes, stick it.
My Dad fucked her and we're
like, what? And he goes, my
calf, Fuck Jamie Lee Curtis.
And I go, I always heard
she's a hermaphrodite. And
he goes, no, my dad fucker.
But then again, what would my dad
say? He fucked a dude. Probably not.
There's only one way to find out. I'm
going to call him. And we go, I go,
if you call them,
you get an extra hundred dollars.
That the Bose speaker phone
speaker mode. He goes, dad,
did you fuck Jamie Lee Curtis and
his dad on the back goes affirmative
duty. Do you remember the Mexicans
and headbutted each other? No. We,
these two Mexican guys and Tom
had a segment called, uh, uh,
Mexican or an automatic
scan. Maybe get one. Right?
That was all Latino's. Jennifer
Lopez. Mexican. That's right.
This was a guest they were basing it on.
Whoever was the most successful was
Mexican, Mexican. And they're like,
they're like, yeah. They're
like, she kills it. She's
Mexican. And we're like, Nah,
she's Puerto Rican.
This show is so great.
We've got these girls in these hot three
girls and there was this thing that
we're going to have one girl put lipstick
on. Another girl with her toes. Yeah.
Like hold it and draw it and, and
do lipstick. Yeah. With their tall.
And then she goes, can I do
it with my tits? No, no, no.
This is exactly where I go.
So ladies, I don't know if
you noticed this, but none
of you are wearing lipstick.
And one of my favorite things in
the world as a woman would lipstick.
So the challenges now, and she goes
to put it all on my tits and I went,
yes it is. Yes. And she goes, what
have I put it on her with my tits?
I'm like, that'll work. Also,
there was no rhyme or reason.
It was so fun. Facts as you guys
were drinking during the show, and I,
they have a problem with that. Here's the,
he was not, I was not the guests could,
she could be on buzzed,
they were on buzz,
but with what they blue was their
bank account. So if you boil,
it blew over 2.25,
then we added a zero at the end
and you started the bank with $250.
And on the ride home you
could win more money,
but that's money you had to gamble.
My favorite segment, what was that?
Was I would read a description,
you'd guess that this was a
television show or not. So
I'd be like, you know, like,
uh,
um,
a divorced mother or a
struggling family in the Midwest.
Uh, the mother works at a plant and the
father does this and they have three
children, and then they would be like,
yeah, that's, yeah, that's a real show.
But then we could come up with these
ridiculous descriptions of shows.
So it would be like, um, uh, a man, uh,
lost his legs in a war,
but through the,
through prayer he became a champion boxer
and they're like, that's a real show.
But just try to miss like,
I miss guided with these
absurd descriptions and
they would get most of them
wrong. Like even ones that
were blatantly clearly made up.
Oh Dude. Do you remember when the guy
was on his first date with this chick?
And we're like, have you ever performed
oral sex on an animal? And he goes, uh,
chipmunks once, and we're like, excuse
me? He goes, hold on, let me explain.
I was like, ah. You're definitely
explained. He was, it fell out of a tree.
Resuscitation did, who's the funniest
fucking show? But they canceled it.
They canceled it immediately and then
they're like, it has alcohol. We're like,
you paid for this show. It
was called buzzed. Yeah,
they did a shot at comedy central
to celebrate it. They lay on their,
all the pilots. They did a shock. They
loved it. Turned the lights on there.
Like how many episodes did we picking up?
Guy raised his hands from ad sales.
He said zero. He goes,
I can't sell that show.
It's really cool that before they ordered
the pilot. Well you would think so.
You'd think so.
Yeah. You got something there Jane?
No. Oh, you doodling. All right.
Um, the body shots world
tour is a, is everywhere.
Um, he's going to look, seems like there's
some tickets left in Australia. Maybe
Australia has got some tickets left.
It's a little ways away.
I think Europe's entirely sold out.
Um,
I will be in DC, New Jersey, Philly,
uh,
wise guys who sold out paramount and
Denver on the 23rd and then ending it in
Wisconsin, Milwaukee and Minnesota
at the end of March. Awesome.
It's been the greatest. I'm, I'll be dead
honest with you, man. I, I've for those,
those who the dewar don't know.
Tommy and I are really good friends and
so we've talked a lot and to watch your
tours and to see you do all these
tours and to to look at him and go,
I wonder what that's like.
I wonder if it's overwhelming.
I wonder like just have all those thoughts
in your head and then to do it for
the first time. Dude, it's the favorite.
It's the favorite thing I've
ever done in this business ever.
This tour is the greatest
thing I've ever done.
I've never had more fun ever my
entire life and I fucking, I just,
I honestly only wish that we
were doing it together. Now look,
it would be fun to be
on a tour bus together,
have to tour and going into cities. It
would be so much fucking fun. I look at,
I look at pass Torian going mid. Joe
would have loved this. Yeah. Joey,
Ari and red band back in the day. He
would have loved, it would have been,
it would change his life. It would
have been. It's a game changer.
That's my next goal is to get like do
a big tour with all of us and just tore
Bust Caravan. Like fucking a band.
Yeah, just pulling into venues.
Oh, there you could wrap all the
buses and each individual guys face.
Yeah.
This is Ari's buzz.
This one's toms by us and then we get
let the other people picked the wrappings
for the buses.
Oh Man. We got to do that for Ari. Oh,
you'd love this hall with your butthole.
And then we put like what I wanted to do
during the sober October thing was get
him a rental car with, um, just
like honk if you think I'm funny.
Kind of quotes on there and just put
like, Hahaha. All around the bus.
Do you like jokes? Knock on my
window. Yeah, let me know. Yeah.
Call one 800 go fuck or
something. Yeah. Yeah.
Or put his real phone number on the side.
You could never put it on my phone.
Um, I love you buddy. Congrats
on the tour and um, oh wow.
Oh, check out Leanne's podcast. Check out
white for the party. My wife's podcast.
Thanks Pat. On it coming up. I
listened to it. I love her. I,
I love hearing her talk about
stuff. She's great. Oh, thank you.
Wonderful. Oh, Louis. Yeah. All
right. Uh, that's it for us.
We'll see you guys next week.
Bye Bye.
Yeah.
Well
make sure
you
are.
Fuck
you.
Fuck,
fuck,
fuck
you are,
you
are.