Well. Well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina visits person.
Oh, okay. Here we go.
Welcome to another episode
of Your Mom's house.
I am the water god Tom Cigarette
and here is Christina has yet.
So I will be sharing my thoughts.
Interesting,
funny things. And Christina,
we'll also talk when she talks,
so back and forth, back and forth,
blah blah, blah. This is Tom.
Christina.
Okay.
Super Funny Tom. Thank you. Welcome.
They you go.
I'll tell you what I think
is going on with our tower.
Tell me the pool guys are in the
breakers because they need to fix.
I strike and I think they're hitting the
breakers. You're probably right. Yeah,
that's what happened last time.
Jeans. You had a big one coming up.
Why don't you tell everybody
this weekend I'm in Washington.
Dick come December 9th December
10th I'm only there for two days.
I'm only doing four shows Saturday
I the early I think is already gone.
I don't know. So get your darn tickets
now to those man is how it goes.
[inaudible] moves quick.
Yeah,
I've got some stuff lined up for 2017 but
I'm not announcing just yet, but okay.
Shortly listen to that deep bro.
And that's it.
What about email?
Uh, December 13th, I'm at the Ice
House. It's a, it's almost sold out.
So if you're in the area in
Pasadena, you can get, get that.
I'm doing New Year's Eve.
I'm doing a whole bunch of shows,
Jr's niece in Orlando,
Orlando.
Uh, the new year's show. Just, I,
I feel like we have to say this every
year is more expensive because it's a
special event,
but I'm also there the day before
that and the day before that.
So if you just want to come out to a
show in Orlando, come out. Otherwise,
a big fun night. We'll have on New
Year's Eve, Kansas City is on sale,
Oxnard, California. I'm doing levity
live there. That's in January.
And then the big tours starts with a,
a new horror liens,
uh, black, black Lana,
clear Farder and Talla hustling.
That's the first theater weekend.
Clear fighter is probably
my favorite new names.
We added shows in Portland,
Oregon.
We added a show in Chicago.
Yeah.
We added a third show in Miami.
Apolis well, I'll tell you all those
three cities, you name it, our mommy hubs.
Their heels.
Yeah.
So that's going to be a fun show for
all the moms coming in and just added
just outside of the Trois. Uh, Royal
Oak. What's that? Oh, I just did try.
Yeah. So we just added, so now there's
a, it's sold out the first show sold out.
So make sure you get your
ticket. That's in March. Um,
this is a 64 rider by Eddie Bojangles.
I was going to say,
is this you singing?
Uh,
there you go. This sounds like some
jamming. You would really love it.
Junior high.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Um,
want to make the show,
man,
we have so much to go over.
I can't, there's a lot to do.
There's a very important
business. F a. R. T. Okay.
Yeah, we got home. Hey our,
okay, hold on. Hold on now.
F a r.
T the show last season.
Come here. Let me tickle
you. Oh No. I said come here.
Oh, bus. Now with that fucking thing.
I said come here to call
you a pussy. Huh? Oh boy.
Don't bring anyone. Love it. Well,
go to your mom's house.
We're talking for
Christina.
Okay,
that's good guy. He
just walked away from the switch.
I just see the guy walking when I seen
him right now while we're waiting.
What is he doing?
He's the circuit breaker is there.
They're fixing the pool right now and
they need to turn off the power to get the
electrical. Believe me, I had the
same fucking shit happened last week.
We're doing this right now.
So it's kind of more, I mean,
can we tell him to not do that?
I have to stop everything.
Like we're in the middle of doing this.
All right. Do you want to tell him man?
Well, yeah, I mean go.
Tom Goes home. Alright,
so you just farted and then you
judged me for farting two seconds ago.
Here we are. Week two.
Okay. Of I'm fucking,
I can't believe you're calling the
kettle brown like that. You love,
I farted and you chastise me
fucking thing. What's wrong baby?
Let's talk about it. I
don't, it's just annoying.
That's all the constant stream of workers,
the interrupt our lives on a daily basis.
No fuck up our audio for
Venice to collegium plus
getting our work done. Those,
I don't like this guy at all.
What? What's that? I don't know.
Is he still fucking with that
breaker? No, no he's not.
That's what I'm telling you. It's not that
big. It's not that. Okay. There's just a,
there's new shit every time. So we have
a new monitor, uh, as you can tell,
it's a much bigger, much baker. My
way bigger. We were more excited.
We were excited that
it would, um, you know,
it could serve us as a great, um,
there you go. Dipped out again.
Pop back in again. It should be
fun. Can be a fun thing to do.
It's not that bad. It's not
that. Okay, so here it is.
Um,
now we,
we feed our video and audio via htmi
into this television and then the,
the television shoots back the audio
into this board. That's how it's working.
Um, I'm already preparing
for it not to work out.
That's about as exciting as the microphone
guy, the way you described. I know.
Hi,
I'm the Evie,
my guy that I almost blacked out.
You did right.
And you explain all that. God Damn
you're Schnitzel. I hear. Yeah.
Yup. I tickle it this way.
Oh look, I don't like it.
Oh, come on man. Yeah, he's
on. He's a pussy bitch.
Stupid idiot.
Cut out again.
Diamonds into the crevice stage per se.
I like the guy. I don't like
that. Our feed just keeps
cutting out. I don't either.
Yeah, so that's cool.
Does it affect audio?
Does it make a yeah, you hear
it? Of course. When you hear it,
when you hear a pop here or they hear
it pop there and sound studio. Yeah,
of course.
Cheese should be fun.
So I feel like just setting this
room on fire right now. Should we,
should we have blue band and come back
and fix the horse before we continue
recording this? I don't think
you can fix this. No, no, no, no.
He can't fix it like that.
Who can fix this? Um,
I'm probably gonna have to
get an entirely new monitor.
And I'm going to have to
use that for something else.
Well then should we just do audio
clips today so that we don't have to go
through the aggravation of the visual
being fucked up? I Dunno. We'll see.
We'll see.
Let's see if you can
goals. I said bring your
ass. Come come here, bitch.
Come when you're a bitch. You're
on his finger. Yeah. I don't know.
But it's like a ring,
right? It has to like bands.
Right. And then it, it's pointed.
It was like a coke nail,
but it's supposed to tickler.
It's not because if you take old mine.
Yeah. At that point he metal thing.
It would scrape and hurt my,
how do you know it might be you've
never had them do it. That guy.
It could be good at it, you know? I
don't think so. I took it this way. No,
thank you. Oh, what was wrong with him?
Who does this turn on exam?
You Pussy Bitch.
He's really selling it.
Yeah. Oh, the crab a stage.
I liked the end. That's,
that's really great.
Damn ins in the crevice of your books.
Say
I said, bring your ass.
Come, come here, bitch.
Bitchy tickling.
Yeah. Yeah. That guy is not into,
because that is,
I feel like a somebody that's just,
it's more relaxed. No. Well,
the glass is a dad. Yeah.
This guy is deaf,
but you might have multiple children,
but daddy,
he's not a dad.
He's not the kind of guy that
starts off his day with lunch.
Oh my God. What a crazy
week it's been. Huh? I know.
Oh my God. Oh, but before we forget,
if you're going to do your Christmas
shopping, do it at your mom's house,
podcast.com. Go to our shop.
Get a water champion tee shirt.
Let the real water champs in your life it.
Game me.
Let them know that you're into it.
Sure there. Do our Amazon banner.
Please use our banner. I beg you. Just
go to your mom's house, podcast.com.
Click on the banner at the bottom of
the homepage of your shopping as you
normally would. I hope you're shopping
on Amazon for Christmas. By the way.
Don't fuck around with the mall. Get
it mailed stupid. Get it wrapped.
You can even add a note like I was
thinking about you. I love you.
Darwin's in the crevice of your
really said that he sang that to you.
Sincere Phallic. Oh, I'm going to throw up
at least he really likes it. He does it.
He's not that bad. I think the Vegan
Vagina guys, way worser this guys.
He's actually cute. He's attractive. This
guy going to vagina. Dude is is gnarly,
gnarly, gnarly, gross fucking
guy. Yeah, he ain't got no teeth.
He bobs his fucking teeth out as nasty.
It's so nasty. He needs a perfect smile.
And then maybe I would get on board this
guy or that guy? No, Vegan Vagina. Vagina.
Yeah, he's just, he's gross. See,
but what's the difference between Vegan
Vagina and like this guy? It's the same.
Well, here's the thing. This guy is
all about sex. He's just a sex maniac,
right?
He bought a ring just to tickle post.
He's with a ticket plus Vegan Vagina.
Guy Is using like he's using sex for
his real cause, which
is Vegan Ism. How boy.
And he's a gross dude.
Like aesthetically,
he's much grosser, you
know. Facially, you know,
Shit like this guy is just more visually
appealing. He's got his shit together.
Like he's got to look. Yeah. This guy
like he has, he's put together, he's,
he wishes he was Tupac. You
know, he's got even the,
the Bandanna on nice teeth
and he can sing.
He can sing
diamonds in the crevice stage.
I saw
the crevice of your posts. Say he
said, what? Was it weird though?
He said like diamonds in the crevassed.
Did you say d? That's what I keep hearing.
They're crevassed right.
Diamonds in the crab stage.
Correct. In the crevice.
Maybe he meant to say crest
crevassed
put
into the ad and the em on your purse.
I was in, um, breastbone beach,
West Harry Paul was Harry bomb
for shows electric. So fun.
A lot of mommies, lot
of mommies, big crowds.
Fun Crowds out.
First of all,
how has your eating since you're on
this diet to lose weight? Didn't really,
well I did. I had a, I
didn't have any food, um,
fall offs the whole weekend. It's very
hard on the road. It's hard on the road,
but I was, I stuck to it. Um,
I did have two vodka sodas.
It's nothing.
And, um, it's not, it's not good if
you're trying to stay in Ketosis,
but you know, whatever it happened. I'm
sure it's many less than Bertrand had.
That's why he had for breakfast today.
Oh yeah. I don't want to give away any,
I only get what? I lost a couple more
pounds. I would say more than a couple.
You're looking, well, I'm saying her
last week, I'm down a couple more. Yeah.
I don't know. I, I love these
team, Burt losers that like,
they believe in that bloated
carcass and the, and they're like,
boots going to do it. It's just,
I use it as motivation. Yeah.
Haters gonna hate. Oh yeah. And
they're all like, all his fans,
like the guys that are like hardcore team
Burt are such fucking Zeros. You know,
like you look at their
profiles, you're like, oh,
I guess they're just kind of drawn
to their own type, you know? Wow.
Such fucking Zilch is put them on
blast like that. Well, you know,
I think they know who they are. They're,
they're attracted to their kind, you know,
and then like mine, like the people on
team Tom, they're like, oh, you know, I,
I just uh, I got promoted to
CEO Today. Oh, cool achievers.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. It's much
different. Show me your
friends. I'll show your future.
Yeah. You want to know you're a fucking
loser. Fucking losers. Fucking bums.
You're hanging around all
day, right? Yeah. Your,
your followers don't hang out with
bumps. Answers. No. Good for you.
So how were your browns?
Cause you don't have the washlet three 50.
He on the road. Juice
glass. Yeah. That guys,
the best thing that's happened to us.
Look,
you switch glass glue. Yeah. Oh, here.
I know you play the whole
thing. This whole thing. Yeah.
It's the best key row here.
Expecting to see the mousses.
Gotcha.
Awesome.
Right?
I guys from Canada.
Okay.
You want to like see his whole thing was
like, wait, okay, hold on. That's so fun.
He makes me so happy. That was
good. It's just time. Time.
Hmm. That's not what I
meant the way. I love that.
That was on deck though.
Yeah. Well that's uh, no.
The having this cord like
replace the other one is,
is what's changing everything.
That's what it is. That's a problem.
That's what we're going to have to
change this eventually. Just glass glass.
Glassing I look how thin I wasn't in this
photo and I thought I was a fat load.
Their God. Damn. And then I had a
kid. It stretches all your shit out,
dude. Come on. What are
you talking about? Oh,
I'm talking about like how you
were a fat load there. Yeah.
Look how flat my belly flab
minus how many years ago is that?
I know this is a,
we have fif 13,
2013 this is the one we first
moved to ride know. Yeah,
I remember that girl did it and touring.
No Way.
Do you ever seen him lose
his cool down that quick. Oh,
oh. Which I was raised. Just awesome.
Do you think Joe Rogan would hang out
with that guy? Definitely 100% yeah.
He would love to.
Yeah.
We got out here are really,
and look at the truck at the metal.
This is why this is what came up here.
We've been slipping along this thing.
Huge battle, big, long, tall meadow.
We'd been slipping along here,
just glass and just glass and glass.
All of a sudden you put my
head down. I'm like, oh,
we're just glad to be with him.
That's so fucking stupid.
It is fun. He is like, it makes me happy.
It makes me happy. Let's just keep going.
Let's glass. Let's class. Let's
glass glass. I'm like, holy smokes.
And I'm like, Oh man, it's a ball. It's
a bull that I'm like, no, it's a cow. A
cow right there. She sees so
stoked. I know. He's really stoked.
I've never been asked or
talked about anything.
I don't even think when I told
you I was pregnant, you're like,
I was pretty excited last
we'd been slipping along here.
Just glass and just glass and glass.
We're just glassing. It looks glass.
Let's glass glass. I bless
it. I'm like, that's amazing.
I've been loving the
hashtags. Just glassine. Yeah,
that hashtags glass and look at it.
Oh, you see how it's safe? Yeah,
there's a file for it. She
called Dad Boehner. Moose hunts.
That's a good name for
it to dad. Huh? Huh.
That's neat.
Well good.
So your weight loss has been
really kicking in high gear.
He's been great in glasses.
Yeah. Ben Glass and hard.
And I'm hot in those mousses.
Yeah, yeah. Thank you. See
any moose. But then you did,
I didn't think I did and I then I was
like, is that a bull and was a cow?
And I was like, Oh shit.
Oh I lost my mind. Yeah.
You know what's great about you and I
really admire the most is that you're so
dedicated to this diet. Yeah.
And I went to whole farts.
So this was so mean to you.
Cause I know you're dedicated.
You haven't had a sweet treat. I had
like Thanksgiving, we all had, I had,
I had a couple of pieces of Pumpkin
Pie. Right. But that's not, you know,
that's not going to break it.
That's the only time you've been
bad this whole fucking time.
You've been so good. And so I thought,
I buy you a whole farts chocolate.
I got one on the primal diet,
it's primal friendly and it's no sugar
and it's only has a coconut oil in it.
What it tastes like.
No you're not, you're not
getting into it. So you go, oh,
you got to try this chocolate.
And I go, I can't, I can't
have it. And you go, no, no,
no. I, I um, it's, is
Paleo and Keto friendly.
I checked and I go, you sure? So I was
like really trying to be good. Yeah. Go.
Yeah. Yeah. You go look,
just, just try a little bite.
Okay.
And I put it in my mouth and I actually
thought you put a piece of dog food in
my mouth. It was the most fucking
disgusting thing I've ever had.
And you were thrilled. Well,
cause I actually shoot and then I,
I not only did I spit it out,
I spent time just,
yeah.
Spitting and washing out my mouth for
a couple of minutes because it was so
disgusting.
It tasted like something you would
bake with. Yeah. It's like
baking chocolate or something,
you know, in the Ra.
It's like when they said no sugar,
they met no fucking sugar.
It just tasted like a hunk of dirt
out of the earth. Yeah. It was really,
shit was so damn nasty and I was so
excited to have a treat on my fucking diet
too.
And that primal thing.
Did she tell you about this or you
just happened to stumble bum? No,
it's on the list of things I can
have. Yeah, and so I thought, oh,
this will be exciting.
I'm a primal chocolate or whatever,
and it just tasted like such shit. Yeah.
That's the thing. When you're on a diet,
it's like not even worth it. You're
like, yeah, fuck it. I want to,
I just don't eat because I'm so miserable.
But the idea of eating,
eating so depressing now that I'm like,
once you get really, really into
your diet, then what happens is,
I dunno, you're almost, don't you? You
look forward to saying no to things.
You know what I mean? You look forward
to not indulging in things. You're like,
well, it'll be exciting
to not enjoy things today.
That's how it feels when
you break the rules.
You just know that you're fucking
yourself setting yourself back. Yeah.
So you're like, oh man, it's going to be
so good to not enjoy stuff today. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. I hear. Yeah, true man. Um,
I'm glad you liked that chocolate.
I'm going to get more for you.
So obviously you remember
the biggest nerd ever.
I got to show you this glass
and guy. Uh, no, this is fine.
Point of order. Yeah, Dude.
Fuck her for a signature golf Europe,
my friend and her speech.
But I heard her to say a word that I
know is distinctly on parliamentary and I
think she may want to withdraw it.
The word was f a r t
nerd. Yeah. Big fucking nerd down nerd.
So her name,
her name is Elizabeth
May and I guess, and, uh,
some of the Canadian circles and you know,
politics. She's, she's known up there.
Apparently she did this, um,
speech, um, at some event,
maybe a year or two ago,
and she got drunk.
So the ladies who's against
saying F A R queries.
Okay.
Is now God damn it. I'm really
going to lose my mind. I know.
Why don't you just not play the visual
for this episode? These are visual.
They're visual drops.
Okay.
So this is, um, let me see,
I got to write that down.
32 goddammit.
F A R. T. S. A. R. T.
I like how she had to spell
it out like a fucking yeah,
Todd and says Perry Belgard is here.
I want to mention we stand on
his traditional territory too.
And I want to say like
what the fuck was wrong?
That's a view you didn't notice where
standing on traditional territory.
Like what doesn't scream out
first nations about this stage.
Oh she said F U C K
pose the f a r. T. That is the
worst word in the English language.
You can and you noticed that there
wasn't like big laughs or anything.
She didn't even realize
they weren't having,
cause this is obviously like some type
of gala, so kind of nerd event. Yeah.
But I mean, she's wearing pearls and
know people are, it's black times saying,
you know, oh, she got her gown.
Maybe just like be with humans.
But the thing is now we know
that's not true. He can do funny.
He can do music and he still
doesn't show up. I don't get it.
I really don't. I mean he should be
here. That's what prime ministers do.
They show up to be humiliated
like the rest of us schmucks.
Wow. Yeah, so she's kind of Loosey Goosey.
She had a couple enter. That's a problem.
She needs to get drunk before
she goes to parliament. Oh Shit.
Should could be like f a
r. T I want you to suck on this.
T. I. T. S. Yeah, that's right.
I'm the oldest one.
I think you know this,
but I'm also the only leader with
artificial parts. You do know this?
I don't mean my boobs. I mean my hips.
Oh my God. My hips are both artificial.
Right side has a consumer
malfunction park.
The security guards [inaudible]
you can tell them I squeak.
I walked through the floors to parliament
and the guards have told me it matter
may you can not sneak up on anyone because
this is a part they don't use anymore
because it squeaks.
I thought she was about to say your
pussy squeaks. Oh, I like that.
It goes some days like a
chirping grasp popper. God,
the grass plays like a really
bad squeaky screen door.
I'm not kidding you.
Some of you know this is true.
I love it,
but the thing is I'm the only woman party
leader and I know what men immediately
sank because the poor boys,
they really bought into fried that whole
sexual maturation thing on the Friday
and scale and we go from the oral.
I'm not going to eat the mic into my God,
the anal got it.
I want to think about it or the genital.
Wow.
I can't believe this is her know.
Isn't it interesting like we were just
talking about this yesterday when you
have a couple Enya who you become.
It's really telling about how much
we're holding back when you're not lit.
And so if you're, if you're like this
when you drink, she's repressing soul,
right? Honorable member for us.
If offended by Fart, you're rough.
My friend in her speech,
but I heard her to say a word that I
know is distinctly on parliamentary and I
think she may want to withdraw it.
The word was f a r t thing is
I'm the only woman party leader.
And I know what men immediately
think because the poor boys,
they really bought into Freud.
That whole sexual maturation thing on
the guys get stuck on this Friday and
stuff.
So they immediately soon that I'm envious
of the things that boys have that I
don't have.
They assumed that I suffer from
classical Friday and dip bait envy.
But I know logger praise
the Lord free at last.
And she's like, they're not giving
her big lab. No, she's bombing.
This is called bombing in our business.
She's eating a fucking Dick Sandwich.
But isn't it interesting that
this is who she wants to be?
The woman that says crazy things.
And so when someone else does an
in parliament maybe that upset her.
I want to say f a r t and then she,
you know chastises the other does not.
Interesting.
T F a r t
lately deranged and not,
there is no sequitur.
This is a non sequitur.
Ever wake up with old theme songs from
former black and white TV shows that you
never thought your kids would ever see
and they're running through your head
like every now and then I wake
up, they got hydrate. Lisa.
I don't thinking about horses.
A horse of course. Of course.
This morning I wake up thinking this,
oh my God,
what do you,
what would you describe her eyes as?
She ripped.
No, but look at her eyes.
They're what? They're kind of,
they are kind of glass,
right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah man.
Hang on, hang on. Wait, no. What
they're trying to walk her off. Dan
is embarrassing. Yeah. Wow. Well,
well isn't this interesting?
The one who's a tattle tale,
a little tattletale has the most shit
going on. That's always how it is. Shit.
Face it ladies. There's also, if
she was cool, like if may was like,
oh,
people like her and cool,
this lady would come on and be
laughing with her instead. She's like,
get off the fuck off.
Yeah.
Just like Ted Haggard and all of these
people that were here, the gaze. Yup.
They've always got some secret
thing going on. Of course.
So repressed this poor woman.
Wow.
Welcome back Kotter.
Which spells k h a d welcome.
They're drag.
She's being okay if you're not watching,
this lady is forcibly
removing her from the stage.
Like it's, you know, when like someone's
done something it cringeworthy.
That's the way it's being.
It's embarrassing. I wish
I knew more about her.
If I was more into Canadian politics,
I would know exactly Katie.
I mean we have good politicians,
interesting ones, interesting ones,
interesting ones. But the Canadians,
I think I'm much more interesting.
Remember the mayor of Toronto? What
was his name? Oh, Rob Ford. Is he dead?
He's dead. He was interesting.
Interesting is a spin on maybe rob Ford.
I don't know. I wasn't
with May. Interesting
prime minister too though.
I think he's a cool dude.
I mean he looks like you might
want to start training with him.
Have you seen that bod? He's
regular bodied. No, he's not.
What is e Trudeau? Let's look at him.
Oh, hey. You can look at them all night.
You're going to probably put them on your
phone and look at them when you're in
the,
he's got more class in my whole
fucking cabinet. Thank you. Wow.
An effing again, I think again. And
look how unamused this lady is here.
Let me pull them up for you. Don't look
on your phone. I'll pull it up. Please do.
I'm trying to tell you, man. Wow. This
is like the Canadian Kennedy of course.
I super cute. I thought you
knew this. Like the Ryan
Gosling of a prime ministers.
This one. You didn't know this
about him. I listened to MPR.
So I hear about Trudeau, but I don't
see judo. Let's see if there's a,
Americans are very self obsessed. We
don't actually show anyone else's leaders.
Well, here's him. Here's
him, just glass and
look. He's doing. Yeah,
look at this yoga pose.
Here he is. Just glassing.
Yeah. Holy Moly. Look at him.
Jesus. He's doing like a,
what'd you call it?
Like you suspending himself in the air
with like an underneath. So Yoga pose.
I guess they're calling it, but like a
Cobra. That's raised fun. It was like,
Yo man, this guy's like staying.
Yeah. Let's see. I typed in,
let's see if you can see. Want to see
this bod? Look at this bod. Geez. Huh?
He's got an, Obama has
got a bad like that. Oh,
I would say Trudeau's got one up on
the more reps. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Damn.
Look at his family. They're all
fucking cute and a good looking family
man. I'd like to see him
make another baby with her.
I'd like to watch right from the,
from the corner
and then just go. We leave VVV. Alright.
Say Madam.
There's diamonds on the Kravis Tub.
You Pussy.
Look how look have said this lady is
the lady that escorted Elizabeth May
offstage did it the way did it like if you
were at a wedding and somebody gave a an
insulting drunk toast and you were just
like, I'm so sorry. So that's my aunt.
Did this happen before or after
the f a r t incident? I wonder.
That's a great question. Cause I mean
then you, she's really casting stones.
Fart stones fart hard fart stones.
Unreal man.
Unreal. Unbelievable care.
Do you care? These new
ergonomic chairs? Yeah,
I tried years when I was
recording this deep bro.
And this one feels much better. At the
same, I must have been sitting wrong.
And now I'm one I did share,
I'm changing the lift on mine.
You can change the words if you want to
lift how high and low it goes online to
go lower. Okay. It's a little
too high up. Oh, interesting.
Um,
yeah, there's uh, there's all
kinds of good stuff to show you. A,
you liked the pussy tickling and did
not really like it were a fan of that.
And now I have a lady who is very upset.
Oh, I should tell you this
first. This was great about, um,
about breastbone beach this week.
So one of my good friends,
Steve came and he's
one of my best friends.
We were best friends in
high school and you know,
we've remained friends all these years.
It's crazy to think about. Right.
I've been friends with this guy since
I was 14 years old. 14 years old. Yeah.
So that's a long time.
And that's when he knew you when you
were at a compulsive masturbator yeah.
20 plus yards balance. I know. It's
nuts to think about that now. Yeah.
So whenever I'm close,
he tries to come to a show.
So he comes to this show and you know,
you're old friends or really give
it to you real. So like, you know,
I remember like a few years ago, he would
come to a show and be like, that's why,
you know, it was pretty funny. Um,
are you going to do a sitcom or what?
I don't know, man. He was like, man,
whatever. I'm still a fan I guess.
But you know, you're still impressed
by you. Yeah. Yeah. And then you know,
every little achievement
you have, he's like, well,
like kind of check off a box for himself
to you. Yeah. So this time he's like, wow,
man, there's a lot of people
here to see you. And I go,
yeah. He goes, I mean, is it,
this is different, right? And
I go, what's good? You know,
there's a couple things going, it's good.
People are at the show. And he's like,
yeah, all right, that's good. And
then he loves the VIP treatment.
So he's like tests like free alcohol.
Oh my God. It's his favorite thing.
It's so funny. Like he's just like,
hey man, tell him I'm here and uh,
tell him to keep the drinks come. And
I go, okay. So I tell the staff, hey,
take care of them and I'll take care
of you. And, and then, you know,
he just kind of like indulges and
he's like, let me get two steaks,
like shit like that. So that's really
exciting to get free French fries.
Yeah. Yeah. It is free. Is Free is
just amazing. Mozzarella sticks,
like my parents entered with me
and I think they're most like,
the part they were impressed with the
most when they came to a show was they
were like, we got escorted in.
They were like, they were like,
that was cooler than the show.
And by the way,
being a comedian and those are
the only parks free green room,
free food in the green room,
which is like everything fried free booze,
free booze. If you're a bird,
that's like a lot of money.
Thousands of dollars.
It really is. Uh, but,
but those are the only parks. And then
the, they let you in on the back end,
which is usually in the alleyway next
to the dumpster, always next to garbage.
So you smell it, you smell garbage as you
walk into the club. I mean, I don't know.
People do that.
They pull you up in like a nice
town car if you're lucky that week.
And then they let you out right
by the dumpster showbiz guys.
And it'll be like, they're like,
oh, this is actually where we just,
we'd collect garbage here.
This isn't even actually to throw away.
We just keep it here.
It smells so bad.
So I walked by the, yeah,
the vomit pile with them.
They watch the show, they hung out, they
left. So Steve comes in and he's like,
you know, we're just hanging out in the
green room. Glassine just hanging. And uh,
then it's time. It's like, what do
you want to do? And I, you know,
he came down to see me. I go, well,
next door is a bar that the club owns so
they have more pull there because they
own it, right? It's called
copper blues. So they go,
we have a table for you next door if you,
if you want to go and just blown what VIP
you have a table. But they also send
security with, so nobody harasses you.
And he's like, are you feeling, are
you feeling, are you fucking crazy?
It's just fucking for real.
And I go, yeah, but you know,
it's just like, it's there,
it's their place.
So it's not like they're not sending
security with me to another venue.
It's the same. Yeah. It's like
a security guard at the club,
which is what they do when you have
meet and greets or something like that.
So anyways, we go next door and he's like,
he's like, this is fucking cool. Like,
this is fucking cool,
man. You got security,
you know people are at your show like
this is cool man. You, you're doing it,
you're doing it. Who? Okay, thanks man.
And then I pull up my phone and he's like,
how many people are following you on
social media? And I go, well, you know,
there's different ones on different
platforms. Instagram, Facebook. He goes,
you don't like Facebook? I got,
I, I'm not really into Facebook.
I prefer Instagram and Twitter.
And he's like, I like Facebook.
And he goes, oh, oh, I got it.
Put a picture of me on
Facebook and tag me. Ah, Shit,
you want me to do that? And he goes,
yeah, I go here, I'll do this for you.
So I pull up, let me pull it up
for you. I, um, I go, yeah man,
this is going to be really cool.
I'll show you what is it.
If you really want to have a good day,
post a picture of yourself on social
media, especially on the Comedians,
if you're any sort of,
if you're in entertainment or whatever,
you want to feel validated by strangers.
Definitely post a pic of yourself.
I pick,
I take a picture of us and I said Yo,
and I tagged him cause he asked me to tag
them. If you want to feel, I just wrote,
if you want to feel good about yourself,
check out the comments
in those picture of us.
It has been commented
on how many times here?
144 so it's reached 36,000 people.
Um,
how's he doing?
Is he getting a lot of love is just one
of those porns where you fuck your ugly
real estate agent because
you have shitty credit. Um,
it sounds about right. It says that he's
a real estate agent, so it's, and it says,
uh, I hope you're better at
selling houses in your choosing.
Barber Barber is you fucking slobs.
Um,
it looks like a mediocre real estate
agent with a crack addiction. One.
I slightly art. Uh, let me
see. It's all positive, right?
I don't know what's going on here.
It looks like some guy went to Tom show,
they took a selfie and Tom posted the
photo. He remember the dude's name.
What is going on? Um,
Tom, you're not that fat.
I hope that guy dies in front
of his family. Jesus. Relax.
Let's see the two of you together.
Probably way less than one fart.
Chrysler does truth. That's true. Uh,
I just had a bunch of gay guys react to
this picture. We ran out of lube. Um,
God, that's the one compliment
so far. Yeah. Somebody said,
I just saw you at the Improv. Apparently
the camera doesn't add 10 pounds. Jesus,
you're fat. Oh, nice. Anyways, it is.
Um, it's a lot of that, you know, so
it's, and it's, it's, they're all,
there's not a nice one in
here. They're all, you know,
no, you look Tom to discuss,
screw you over.
And some real estate will amaze whatever.
So he texts me,
please take that photo down.
I cannot handle the comments.
And I was like, nope.
I said exactly what you asked for.
Welcome in the spotlight. Yeah.
So you asked for this. So I'm
giving it to you. It's neat.
Um, anyways, pretty cool. Just
wanted to tell you about that.
And another cool thing that happened.
Jeans.
You know how I meet
black celebrities a lot.
I met method man.
I know I dated him in the 90s.
You did not. And he had a show called
method and red pets. Right, right,
right. Yeah. Absolutely.
100% is
what then is dangerous your neck.
There you go.
Um,
my mom's a big fan so I'm
in Fort Lauderdale airport
cause that's where I flew
it cause it's direct on this six something
flight. I mean it's fucking early.
Right.
And I had two late shows Saturday and
walking through security and who do I see
to cow Johnny blaze,
you know, the iron lung.
So I look and I just, I, I've tried
to figure out what am I going to do,
what am I going to do? We're insecurity.
I just kind of leaned forward.
I see him and I stick out my hand, my
fist like that. And he just gives me,
he was like, oh yeah, yeah. And he
leans forward and knots and I was like,
that's perfect. Yeah. It was like,
it was like, it was a, I, you know,
I'm a big fan of respect to you,
but I didn't even say anything.
Just a little fist bump and it's
like, feels good. We get on,
I get on my flight and uh, he's
in my row, but across the aisle,
so I'm aisle, he's across the aisle but
window. Right. But same row. So I'm like,
shit man, it was fucking method man. Dude.
Some girl boarded the flight and
ask them for a photograph. Oh No.
As they're boarding
Paul, big foe, the, uh,
the fucking lady
sitting next to him has to get up so
this girl can go sit down. Anyways,
the flight's a long ass shitty flight,
right? It's Lauderdale, la. When we land,
I get out of my seat, he leans in and
whispers something to me and I'm like,
I'm like, wait, what? And I,
and I really want to know what
the fuck he just whispered to me.
So he gets off and on the jet bridge he
waits a second so that I can walk off
and I'm like, wait, what'd you say man?
And he goes to that motherfucking
never shut up and he goes,
dude in front of you, man, I felt
bad for you guys. Shut the fuck up.
The whole flight. He talked to whole
flight, he talked to the whole flight.
And you know when someone like that says
something like when somebody does that,
who you think is cool. So what you do,
even if you don't know what's going on,
you just agree with it like I did.
That's exactly what I did when he goes,
he goes, you know what I mean? He's like,
he's talking to him. I go, dude,
some people never shut the fuck up.
Like I made it my problem even
though I had zero problem with it,
cause I never heard the guy.
And then when I said that he was
like word and I was like, yeah man,
you guys would have shut the fuck up.
Like I totally exaggerated that.
It bothered me and I felt like such,
you know,
like disingenuousness because I
was doing it to make the bond,
to bond more with them.
Anyways,
I ran it and then we walked
to the luggage together.
I'm fucking friends with mathematics,
his phone number and stuff. No,
I asked what he was doing shows and he
said he's shooting some show TV show with
John Singleton. Um, but
yeah, man, it's, it's nuts.
I have been a fan of his legitimately
since 1993 he's pretty big.
I've known him as long as I've been.
I've been a fan of his,
as long as I've been friends with
Steve. Wow. So anyways, that's cool.
That's very cool. I wish I had more
of an interaction with them, you know,
but I took what I get. I'll
tell you though, I've, I've
seen rappers and airports,
fist bump. Yeah, perfect exchange.
It is with a rapper or an athlete. Just
the fist bump because it's like, oh,
I get it. You get it. And I
was texting friends, obviously
I was touching, you know,
my, my, my good buddies from
college and they're like,
you're getting a picture
right. And I was like, no dude,
you can't ask this guy for like, can
I take a picture with you? I mean,
I could have,
but just his vibe was like,
not like let's, you know, like,
hey man, put it on selfie mode.
It wasn't like he wasn't in that. And
plus when you're traveling, if it's early,
you don't want that stuff,
but you now you have a memory.
You don't need a picture,
you know? Exactly. Exactly.
Kind of know by the way he looks like
exactly the way he looked 20 years ago.
Wow. Like method man hasn't
changed his physique, his
face. Isn't it amazing? Yeah.
I hope I get like that. Probably
not. I mean, I wonder if we like,
let's just see a comparison method,
man.
You think he works out a
lot? Uh, yeah, I think so.
I think actually he takes care of himself.
That dude is like,
that's the secret to their lien. Or when
I see older people now and I'm like, Oh,
you just don't take care of
yourself brown. Like it's a fucking,
it's voluntary to look like
shit mostly. Right. I mean,
unless you have some
sickness or something. Geez.
Yeah. I mean, I'm trying
to think if he, uh,
this looks like, this looks like probably
what, what I saw him as right here,
you know? Yeah. I mean,
good looking dude. Yeah.
The dude doesn't look his age.
You know, this is 93 I remember.
No, but I mean it doesn't look that
different men, it looks better now. Yeah,
pretty wild. It looks much
better. Well, I think get I shit,
I wish I had an edible on me. That would
have been the move. Like, oh Yo man,
you weren't like, it's like
you and me. That's how we
hang out. He'd been like, Tom,
you don't know me and you don't
know my style, man. Yeah, man.
I'll get all three stars to cow.
I'm not very cool.
In the radio station that
I managed in college,
so that was like the heyday, especially
a breakout years of Wu Tang stuff.
You know,
it was late nineties.
So he has so many Aka haze that we wrote
in permanent marker on the wall every
time an Aka of his came up.
So it said method man and
there was like a poster.
And then in permanent marker on
the wall it would say, you know,
to cow Johnny blaze hot nick,
whatever, iron lung. And it was like,
it ended up being like fucking 20
long watch comedians did more of that
nicknames. Yeah. Yeah man, that's neat.
That's really neat. Jeans.
That was pretty cool.
[inaudible] posted a photograph of
myself on Instagram this morning.
Yeah.
Uh, meet Sean and the studio here
with the two dogs. Yeah, a week ago.
And it's really nice to
read the compliments.
Like it look like a total mom and yeah.
Nice mom shoes nerd.
What kind of fucking shoes are
those? Sweat pants loser. Like it's,
it is nice to hear that kind of stuff,
but I'll show you these slippers or
actually the fucking coolest thing. Yeah.
You talk about these constantly.
So I was,
I was in the airport,
I don't know,
two months ago and I saw this like 50
year old lady on the tram that takes you
and she was wearing these just
glassine and I'm like, Bro,
those look like the coolest shoes,
most comfortable shits I've ever seen.
Yeah.
And she goes, oh, they're
called. Mohave us,
this is an English thing and I looked
it up and I ordered it immediately.
Scores and this is the dope
as part of these are house.
You can wear these out
and about in the world,
but I wear them around the house
cause we don't have carpet and I,
my arches are fucked since I had a kid.
But on the inside it's soft and then you
can take off the soul, which is cool.
It's plastic and you can wash this part.
That's the best fucking part.
Wash the insides.
Cause I hate slippers and they get all
sweaty and smelly and then you know what
I'm saying? You know what I'm
saying? If I'm on a time out,
I know exactly what it is. Yeah, I know
exactly what you're saying. Anyway,
they're all sponsor the show or anything.
But it's great to have like I'm always
looking for ultimate comfort shoes.
Of course I love vans, but there's no
arch support in it. Slip on Van Gogh,
like fucking tying shoe laces,
man.
You've had them now for a few weeks
and talk about them constantly.
These are the best purchase
and it's expensive.
It's like a, excuse me 80 but
almost throw up $80 or something.
But I've had him, I love him. Good.
Now we need a slipper for you.
Yeah I do.
I want to get it cause right now you've
got the Ugg slipper with the open back
style but you don't like that.
Why don't you like about that?
I like slip in and out.
I liked that.
I like being able to just
walk in like an Armenian guy.
I don't want to have to
pull up on the back. Right.
But what don't you like about your
current? Oh those are just worn.
Those just worn cause that it's not
that good because it's flat footed too.
You need some kind of
arch support in there.
I like a little warm and I like ease
and comfort of getting in and out of a,
I'm going to find it for you.
I just found some aliases going back
to mathematics for just for a moment.
Okay. Okay. The ghost
rider, Johnny blaze meth.
Mr Meth, meth. Mr [inaudible],
hot Nichols, hot Nixon,
big John Stud.
Shaquan got a law to cow,
the iron lung metaphysical
man to Cali and stallion.
John, John McLean, John John
blaze, Ini, Johnny Dangerous,
uh, the Shaolin Assassin, the blended one.
John Blaze Ini, the m e t h o
d man that he meister. Okay.
I just wanted to remind myself of those.
This is college memories. All right,
so you guys make your own
fucking Aka list and um,
will you get me some slippers then?
Yeah, I mean I like to, I feel like you,
you're wearing some bullshit right now.
Right now I'm wearing flip flops because
I can't find my slippers. Yeah, man.
Here's what I do.
I'm going to get you some on Zappos.
What you need is a material like
soft on the inside and then free.
Yeah. In the back. Yeah. Yeah.
That's what I need. Okay.
I'll get it for you.
Good pair of slippers can
change your life. It sure can.
I'm telling you because I don't like
to walk around in socks because my feet
fucking hurt.
Soccer flag dirty and then I got to take
the dogs out to shit and Piss 500 times
a day.
And I don't want to wear normal shoes
around the house cause then they tracks
and dirt and everything.
By the way, if anybody knows
it's listening, why? Um,
this htmi makes the,
I'm like,
why the screen goes blank
and then it pops back up.
Even though nothing's being done. Will
you please message me and let me know why?
That's why it's causing that and if
there's a way to remedy that so I don't
fucking, you know, shoot
someone. Thanks. Um,
how about this jeans,
where you think of this
a sweat or must fucking life.
Who's been to my house on Saturday?
It's stolen my fucking on June eight,
five pound Gucci Belt.
When I fucking cuts you above,
I swelled my life.
I'm going to buy every single one
of you that was in my house or sat.
They both pub. It's same bug. I don't know
for a second. I was
like, is she blood in it?
Like that arsenal guy both of both of
blood and she's going to bang everybody.
Yeah. Bang them. No, but I'm sure it
means hit. I know, right? It's still,
she's still saying bang. Yeah.
She's real classy. This one? Yeah.
She has her Gucci belts or down.
Why people are
design the Joe,
Tim both.
There's 185 fucking pounds fucking Gucci
Belt that everyone fintech that could
still from my house.
Both.
You fucking Bob a swell my bro Bro.
Bro. Bro. Bro. Bro. Bro.
Bro. Because English,
yeah, people still feed. They
could still from my house pub.
You think you could still my
always cosmo Janae fuck cough go.
She felt,
but I swear on my life,
every single person that was in my house,
Bob Bang,
every person that was
in her head like that,
no other shit. This happens to
her. Did you hear what started? No.
Like they stole this and then my debit
card and so their sheet people notice
steal from her
to feed. They could still from my house,
Bob, if he could still my oyster cards,
my bank card, the no fucking
on good. She felt both.
I swear on my life about
buying every single person
that was in my house, Bob. Oh,
it's both. I swear on my life
I'll go bang every single cut.
That was it.
Yeah. Maybe as you, shouldn't
these assholes come off? Yeah. I think,
yeah, that bad bad group of friends, Bruh.
Yeah. Bravo, Bravo, Bravo.
Meet them at the pub glove.
Don't make them at your hat as you fuck
them all. Like you're threatening to,
they might just keep stealing stuff.
Remember that story about the girl that
went to go bang the Wu Tang clan or had
all of them? Oh yeah. Oh, you're down
her throat. And by the way, I knew.
It's funny you brought that up. Uh,
did you ask him about that? Well,
I thought you were going to say that and
I imagined that like dozens and dozens
of comments, we're going to be like,
why didn't you bring up that blow bang.
Most importantly, yes. Why can
I tell you the reality of it?
If I would have brought up that to him,
he would have been like, wait, which city?
Right. Uh, you know how long I've
been famous for? Right, right, right.
Like world famous have the Wu Tang clan or
a him in particular because he's also
considered like the good looking one of
that group. He's handsome.
Yeah. That's what I'm saying.
So like he imagine like
if I would be like, Hey,
do you remember where you got a blow job
once on a tour bus? He'd be like, oh,
that one time. Yeah. Yeah, I
remember that. No, he'd be like, uh,
that's like saying like, Hey, remember
that time you had tacos for lunch?
And he was like, yeah, no, I
remember. Who's The guy? The,
the sweet baby. Jesus. Big Baby. What
was his real old dirty bastard like?
Yeah, that guy was in the band too. He's
not a looker, the hottest ones method.
Oh yeah. Yeah. I mean he's getting
all of it. Yeah, you could, you know,
you can make, obviously it's
subjective, but I think,
you know a Kappa Kappa Chino.
Yeah. So you're like, why
did that happen right there?
Why did that just pop the
spirits? Yeah. Cop Kappa.
Donna's definitely not cuter.
Well No,
I'm saying that like he's also
not even an original nine,
so he's going to like trickle
down post who's not getting the,
which can't be bad. No, if you're
hanging out with them all the time.
But if like one of them was like,
I want to blow method man
though he's busy right now,
he's got his dick sucked by
second aftermath after him,
you can fuck blow who's second
in line? Well you know, you're,
you have like the um, the CEO of it
all also carries a lot of weight,
a lot of power because he's the
architect of everything. No Rizza.
So like if you were like woo obsessed,
he would actually be the,
the real achievement.
So let's say I'm going to the Blue
Tang clan, right. For a blow bang yet.
So the first gentleman I will approach
is the pyramid of the hierarchy of
rappers in that group and that group here.
I think it depends on it.
That's what I'm saying.
It depends on what,
if you're talking about the
most powerful male Rizza okay.
If there is a well know and
that's not necessarily true.
I mean some people like,
cause I'm a fan of the liquid
swords. Oh, I gotcha. I gotcha.
Yeah, that makes sense. That makes sense.
And then a lot of people, you know,
a lot of people,
hardcore Wu Tang fans or feel
like there's just a supremacy,
dedication and just, you know,
something about Ghostface.
I forgot. So he would definitely
be aesthetically I'm talking,
I'm going aesthetically. I mean, you know,
I would say you would probably have
TJ's a and method as the top two,
probably more traditionally handsome guys.
Okay.
And then I blow method.
Okay. And then I blow Reza.
You could face killer.
Okay.
Still got a lot of dicks hanging around.
It's kind of waiting to get sucked out.
I mean, you got inspected decks just
hanging out there. You know, Ray Quan,
just like, what about me, man? I'm having
some ice cream. I can't get my Dick Sag.
Right. Um, you know, a lot of decks,
if you go on and you got to go all in,
you God, uh, he's suing
them right now. There's a,
aren't they always suing someone in the
Wu Tang or he's in the Wu Tang clan.
He's suing the Wu Tang clan.
Okay. For royalties. Yeah. Yeah.
There's a lot of guys in
that band that there's,
I don't know how their band's money.
He's got a bad bite. Yeah. But, um,
how do you make money in a
band with fucking 20,000 dudes?
That's a good question. It's gotta be
a bad, bad bite. It's a bad bite. It's
a bad back, bad, bad, bad
bike. Got to Pat Pyke. I Dunno.
There's 20. Yeah, there's nine guys.
But then there's all these side guys
and that's what I'm saying now the,
now you know what I heard the guy in
the rolling stones is pay to play the
drummer. Yeah. Ronnie Wood. Yeah, I heard
that. Yeah. What were we talking about?
That yeah, we were in thanksgiving.
I told you that. Yeah.
Which is so interesting to
me. Yeah. Because basically
royalties question, right?
So these pay to play, it's pay to
play. Yeah. He gets paid per gig.
I mean paid handsomely. Sure, sure.
But like rolling stones
is only Keith and I'm mic.
That's great. Yeah. For
those two bros. Yeah.
So like they get the writing
credits there, that that's
them, that's their empire.
And they get the residuals. They get
all, all that stuff. Yeah. Brilliant.
So Ronnie Wood has got to be worth
the fucking pouring millions.
He's getting paid. Right. But
uh, but that's the way to do.
I don't know if the Wu Tang
structured their deals the same way.
I don't know what their deals are.
That structure would be all,
all in [inaudible] hands. I bet. So he's
the owner. So I blow him first for sure.
Okay. Yeah. Wow. Interesting.
Well, thankfully,
only hundreds of thousands
of people here this,
so maybe your dream will come true.
Could you imagine me in the Wu
Tang blow? Bang. No. Hey guys. No,
cause you're not like that guys. What
happened? I would not even know or not.
Gosh, goodness gracious. This
little little bitty blurb.
They really bad for me. Hey
guys. Anybody else? A mom. Yeah,
they would really like that. It's
like your jeans high and tight. Um,
I want to see it. If this lady get
her, uh, her belt backwards. Oh, right.
Most importantly,
yes.
You feel you're fucking oh by
life book. I'm going to fuck you.
Stop ever. She go on. If you
don't ever stop you poker stop.
Or if your fucking face book as well.
My Lifebook can you figure the stove
people you feel you could still with me
mate.
Well that's a lot going on here.
Yeah.
Well you think she has like Gypsy blood
you think or what? Absolutely. Gypsy know.
She reminds me of the bad girls club.
I remember that one. That was like a,
come on. What's her thing? She
goes, we were saying, I don't know.
I think my privacy,
you know what I'm saying?
She Oh like that kind of
that that character. Yeah.
No,
I got no privacy.
No. Oh, I know what this is
called in England, right?
A chav. A chav. I think it's a Chav.
It's because that's their white trash.
That's their version of like a legend.
That was the best reality
show on BBC ever forever.
From lad debts to ladies. Yeah. We
fucking love that show. Lad exhalation.
It's the best show ever and it was so fun.
I don't know where to find it now.
If it's still there.
So fuck you nasal lab.
Yet people feel they can come
to my house and still off me.
You little child, you little
tribes. Lucky you. Champs.
I swear you are all
champs. Your trends, Chad.
Chad fucking cherry.
Matt. Whoa. It was people in the
background like what are you doing
when I forgot? Well, both. Both.
Watch blub, blub, blub, blub,
blub, blub, blub page blog. Both.
Both. Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah. Blahs. All Trump.
Trump. Trump. Trump. Trump.
Trump.
There you go. That's blue bands work right
there. Top Blue Band. That's funny man.
Super good. Super Damn good man.
He's, I love these angry videos.
Bravo, Bravo, Bravo, Bravo,
Bravo, Bravo, Bravo, Bravo. Bravo.
A sweat.
Oh my fucking life.
He's been to my house on Saturday is
stolen my fucking on June 85 pound Gucci
belt.
She's really 885 Oh, not the,
wait for a minute. I was like,
she had a belt.
The weight 189 she when
the UFC championship.
Okay. Yeah. Ruff. Ruff, ruff.
So you and I were watching
football last night. Yeah.
Yeah.
And the, I've noticed that every
fucking time. Football's on Kelly.
Yeah. Kelly Clarkson shows? No,
Carrie Underwood, one of the two.
I don't even know who it
is, honestly. I don't know.
Yeah.
But she's on every time there's
football. Yeah. Carrie Underwood.
And she's cute as fuck. And she's really
talented. I really, I like her actually.
Yeah. But that fucking football song is
the dumbest thing I've ever heard in my
entire, and it's so boring
too. It's like she's a s
what? Gone on. Watch that football,
football on a Sunday night, we're gonna
Watch that ball get thrown around.
It's Sunday night.
You're like,
Jesus,
I know five year old wrote this.
It's so funny. You know what happens?
You get conditioned to these things. Yeah.
So for me it's just background noise.
I don't hear it. But then when you point
out, like when an outsider points it out,
then you're like, oh, this is so
fucking dumb. Because it is like every,
it's like,
okay,
and they have like this, it's
all, I got pop video. Right.
And now they have like the
football players walk by
and go like, no matter how,
and like wave, we're all gonna
blow bang her lane. Yeah. And then,
then the lady's like,
yeah.
Yep.
Well
you're gonna love it too.
It's the stupidest song I've
ever heard. Yeah. It's so stupid.
Oh yeah.
Sunday on the Monday night,
Sunday on the Monday night.
I used to love,
there's a couple of themes that I liked.
Um,
I like the old school
college football theme song.
Let's see if this is it or
not from it was years ago.
Okay.
Okay. Um, it's no Carrie
Underwood, but I'll take it.
Let's see.
Let's see if the
everybody likes football and she
looks cute. She looks amazing.
Yeah.
Going around and high five.
There you go. That's it, man. Eric
and right there, they should have biz.
Bring that shit back.
Yeah.
But you know what is good about Carrie
doing that song is that she's so American.
Like she's so apple. Exactly. Perfect for
it. And Middle America is like, fuck yeah.
I want to catch that football
to Carrie. Come on. Oh, girl.
Yeah.
We all like football.
That's how I feel like,
Ooh, the song should be what it is. Yeah.
Except it's like honkytonky some,
somebody has to help me with this.
Html flag football.
Tasty lacked Doritos.
Okay.
Now what's the name of the stadium they
played in last night? Was it staples?
Oh, right. Fedex. Ups. I'm sorry. Fedex.
Ups. Fiji water stadiums.
See where that last?
I think the game was in Seattle
last night. So, so did they name,
I don't know what the name of
corporate oppressors. I don't know.
It is something corporate oppression. It's
definitely, there's definitely a score.
A score. Starbucks, Kentucky Fried
Chicken. Mcdonald's Burger King venue.
Yeah.
Peep up. Nightmare bleep,
bleep, bleep, bleep, bloop.
Wow. They fucking drop the
hammer on him last night. Jesus.
40 to seven. I didn't
even realize that. Um,
I haven't muted good. Let's see where they
play. I don't even know the name of it.
It's, it's like a famously, um,
oh, century link field. I say.
That sounds like,
can we mommy,
can we go to the century link field?
God,
what a bummer.
Can we go to the Kodak?
The Kodak Gallery Auditorium?
Uh,
so many are named after banks.
I know they chase national stadium guys.
The Wells Fargo arena. I know we
did this fun and I forgot. Okay,
here it is. Okay. Kansas
City is still awesome. That's
Arrowhead stadium. Thank God.
The cowboys play at a t and t.
The panthers play at Bank
of America stadium. God,
Seattle is century link. Oh boy.
Jacksonville plays at Everbank
Washington Redskins play at Fed ex field.
Fedex.
Cleveland plays at First Energy Stadium.
What a bummer.
Detroit plays at Ford field,
which makes sense. Yeah.
Atlanta plays in the Georgia Dome,
which is cool.
It's still called something normal.
New England plays at Gillette Stadium.
That's neat. Miami plays at
hard rock stadium. Hard cock.
Pittsburgh plays at Heinz field.
Well that makes sense.
That's from Greenbay Lambo, which is the
only one of the only traditional ones.
San Francisco should be our favorite.
They play at Levi's stadium.
Those jeans, man, the Levi's
companies there too. It's right.
Philly plays at Lincoln financial
field. Oh boy. That's a bummer.
The Lincoln financial fee.
Now the rams are playing
at Lee Memorial Coliseum,
but that'll change when their things
done right. Cause there who bought that?
Well, no, I don't remember.
But they're, they're, you know,
they're building a stadium for them.
So that's definitely, I wonder who,
I forget some horrible fucking,
the colts play at Lucas oil stadium.
Oh my God. Yeah. There's
Mercedes Benz. There's Metlife,
new era field, Nissan
Stadium. God, what a fun,
authentic experience is. The only other
school ones are Oakland Alameda Coliseum.
Paul Brown is where the bangles play
a Raymond James where the a plays and
soldier field in Chicago still plays a
soldier field. Um, God, yeah, they're,
they're terrible names.
Absolutely terrible. It's,
it's a, it's just shameless.
Is nothing just cook named
and the Rose Parade? No.
Like we have to call it the
Citibank Rose Parade. Yeah.
They pay so much for naming
rights. I mean, it's unbelievable.
We're talking nine figures. Oh, I bet.
Just to be able to call it
because they know. Yeah.
And then every week when they go,
we are here live at a US bank stadium.
Yeah.
You know what your mom's house needs to
by naming rights and auditorium or maybe
a public restroom facility.
No, I know. We need to, do,
we need to sell naming rights to this
place that's up to the studio. Yeah.
Look and do another episode of your mom's
house live from chipotle, the studios,
you know. Great idea. Yeah, that'd
be really cool. Right? You follow me?
A great sponsor. I like to, no,
from Armand Hammer
Studios, right? Colgate,
if we should have a tooth sponsor
and all Colgate's he knows,
or what does that toilet paper we get?
We can do that.
Sharman Sharman studios that even has
a nice ring to it live from Sharman
studios. There's so much toilet
paper here, and we say it at the,
at the very top. And then they
go, yeah, of course. We'll say it.
You guys give us $100 million
and we'll say it every week.
Welcome back to Sherman
studios back from a break.
It's live from Sherman studios.
I might not show. This has nothing
to do with, it just reminded me,
we happened to catch that show.
Uh,
outdaughtered PLC about the quintuplets.
Yeah.
And that the woman that stays
home with six kids, five babies,
one year old babies and then like
five year old daughter. I mean,
and she's really got such a better
attitude than we do about child rearing.
You and I are exhausted at the end of
the day with a one year old with one one
year old and she's like, well,
they're challenging by the way.
We had an amazing disposition. They
weren't like, we're fucking wreck.
Oh my God. Twins would have just
put us one of us in the hospital.
And they were just like, well these five
we feed and eat. And they were like, fine.
She's very spirited. Oh boy. You're
really, it really makes you feel lazy.
I do. I'm like, fuck. I guess when you're
in that position though, you're like,
this is my reality. You surrender because
you can't be like, this sucks. No, no.
You have to be like, oh,
that's what I do. You can't,
if you're five babies deep in the game,
you can't even acknowledge that it sucks
ever. Cause it's too late. You're all in.
You're all in for the rest
for the 18 years. Five.
So it now imagine if they had our
arrangement where I had to get on a plane.
And you have live in help live.
Yeah,
because we have our lovely,
wonderful nanny,
but she goes home course and also I don't
like to have my kid raised entirely by
another person.
I like to spend a lot of time and you
want to take away that pussy too, right?
Right.
Yep.
Did you see our Sassy Sassy
nanny shoes today? Yeah,
she had real Sassy.
She kinda highlight,
choose on raw Mustang.
It was quite a thing.
Do you find girl tickle you?
I don't need this drop
crevice. Can we play? Finally,
I've been dying to play this.
The guy who sent in him
doing the Starbucks,
what is it called? The the challenge
called the mommy challenge.
The genes coffee challenge
and this is how you do it.
The way this guy did it
is exactly how we do it.
Tom and I do this every time you order
from Starbucks or from a fast food place,
do this. Let me see where it to
start. The revolution. What, uh,
you forwarded it to me and me,
ma'am. Tell you to your, uh,
personal, my personal, oh, here we go
back. Me and me, me, me,
me, Betsy is such a jerk.
Last night we gave them
both t r e a t s is Huh?
And Fif was chewing his
chance. His bone. Yeah.
And Schnitzel was just hot
and just glassing it. Yeah.
Remember she was right. Not Scared of
him. Not Scared, not scared at all.
She should be. So what we did is we told
everybody when we got drive throughs,
especially, we go to Starbucks
a lot, we order our coffee,
we always call the person
genes and mop and mommy, mommy,
we say both, you know. Um, but
the way he does it, this guy,
he really nailed the right way to do it.
Right.
Because you're supposed to do it like
you're supposed to go kind of, you know,
kind of fast. You met, you make it sound
like you're saying the right thing.
It's almost like you're saying sir or
ma'am, right? Yeah. Yeah. Excuse me, sir.
Like you do it like and
then you make it hard. Yeah.
It's all about nonchalant and, and
just make it a throwaway. You don't,
you don't want to draw too much attention.
Right. You wouldn't go like a mom. Me,
hello mother. No, no, no, no. Yeah. I
want to get, yeah, right. Very chill.
All right here. It does a
great, let's see. Good work.
Hey there. What's coming
up for you? Hey Mommy,
can I get up 90 ice hazelnut
coffee with cream coffee with
a grenade bold with a cream and two
sugar in the raw figures in the that.
Yeah, and I was an MP
Para Grandad, grandad.
They polled with two sugars in the round
to do pay cream. Yes. And anything else?
That's all.
You're going to have enough nice jeans.
Nice jeans.
Yeah, that was fantastic. Perfect. It
was absolutely fantastic. Thanks gs.
That's exactly how we do it.
That's exactly how we do it
fast. Yeah. What's a bold,
bold? He ordered a boy. I have no idea.
Is it like a drip coffee flavor? Maybe.
Maybe come, I don't know if you
know this, but in the summer,
who is this a [inaudible] 97 I was
a Starbucks employees. Tom, sorry.
Tom Is the one who sent that. Thank
you Tom. Yeah. Really good work. Great,
great work. Um, uh, he goes, hey mommy.
That's exactly how many.
Yeah. Yeah. Hi Mommy.
You know what's really insidious
that they started doing through it,
our Starbucks drive through is they go,
hi, would you like something to eat today?
Yeah.
And they enter the fee to any
person and you're like, a course.
I'd like something to eat today,
but we're trying not to be fucking fat
fucks. Yeah. But there's also this thing,
they know that people
order drinks at bars,
but now they're encouraging food.
Right. Cause so they're like,
and there are so aggressive.
It's recent. Yeah.
It's the last few weeks
where they'd been like,
where you pull up and they know you're
going to get a coffee. So they just start,
they go get you some food today
and you're like, no. They're like,
you sure you don't want anything to eat?
Come on fatty.
And then when you're done and
you go, that's it. They go,
you sure you don't want any food?
And you're like,
that fat fucking piece of
shit did to me last week.
I was there with Lj and the car. And
she's like, you shoot, you shoot.
Don't want some, you don't want like a
cake pop or a pace. And I was like, dude,
you're so sneaky. I'm like, no, I'm
trying to be good dude. By the way,
I just saw on our,
on our cheat sheet here,
the tickle pussy guy is Orlando Brown.
He's the former star of that.
So Raven, no, no wonder he's so handsome.
And he was arrested in February,
2016 for hitting his girlfriend while
park police station and also having a meth
on him. And now he's at the full
finger ring that he makes videos with
the, what is it called? A full finger ring
of full finger ring. Yeah. Cause it goes,
it tickles pussies with that. So
he was on that. So Raven, yeah.
He's got those actor. Good luck.
That's for sure. Yeah, you notice that.
So we have uh, another,
uh, a couple other emails.
Can we want to get into a
couple of other ones? Um,
water champions solve that said, Oh
boy, I dunno. I don't even know the car.
It could be you. I don't know. I
don't know what it says. I'm mommies.
I was masturbating the
Fart porn this evening.
She's and began to wonder where's the com,
which naturally led me to
wonder about the evening,
the never ending debate of who the true
water champion is in head to head sports
that are combat oriented.
Traditionally gender weight,
stuff like that are
considered Christina piece.
Clearly the female water champion.
Well,
Tommy's undisputed male water champion,
right?
So the female astro is unfortunate from
Mami te or is it there is a loophole.
Tommy and alias Dj Dad mouth
are both openly nonbinary.
The fact that they who's Pronoun is
currently unknown are openly nonbinary
excludes male.
Considering the rules of gender fluidity,
Tina has the option to become male
long enough to simply the killer.
They're both feeling me male,
female,
male and female titles
within seconds of each other.
This would also make the fluid
champ in several respects.
Tom does not have this option due to
his rigid stance on being nonbinary.
Neither gender Tom may have the title of
genderless water champ Chatam choose to
claim it in order to keep his Brown's
violent and his jeans acceptable case
close. Sincerely Jesus Christ. Wow.
So that's um,
yeah,
very interesting dissertation on it.
So what he's saying is I can claim the
title if I claim my gender fluidity.
Now hold on. It's what he's saying.
I don't know. I mean I've got,
I've got an an email update.
You, I've got a report on you.
Uh, from wet balls, beach
from wet balls, beach,
Tom Tom's water intake,
this,
this weekend in wet ball speech.
He writes,
I am proud to say the champ
stayed hydrated his entire
set and topped it off by
annihilating an entire bottle in one step.
It was truly inspiring and I in turn
went home and drank an entire gallon and
stuff like that.
Truly enjoyed the show.
I can't wait to hear next
time in South Palm Beach.
Now I will say Paul to my friends.
Cheers.
It's the first time you've
drank water this entire show.
Let the record note
that I've been drinking.
I've been hydrating this whole fucking
time and I have two primaries to be fair
though. Nope. This and that. This
is my 38th glass of water today.
Liar lies.
You know,
you always say you drink water off
camera or you only do it on camera.
I know.
I just wanted to say that this is
the probably the very first positive,
uh, Tom Drinking Water
report that I've had. Yeah.
So it sounds like you're deliberately
doing some water out of posturing.
You're not even proud.
Well,
I'm just saying it's about
time you stepped it up and
pretended that you are the
water challenges. Be Proud.
I am. That's why I fucking,
I'm encouraging you to drink more water.
You need to pee clear also.
Can I read another one? Sure.
Just an interesting thing.
Just wanted you guys to know that there
is a town in Oregon called Brownsville.
Interesting. Now I think, isn't
there one also in Tay Hos? Wow.
What a neat world.
Well, we know where we're going to retire,
that's for sure. Speaking of bee holes.
Dear Mommy's,
in my 34 years of life,
I've been doing something
we all do every day wrong.
Apparently it wasn't until I saw numerous
times on the television actors wiping
their be whole in the sitting position
that I realized I must be the only one.
If you didn't guess already I wipe
standing up. I don't know why.
I don't know why not. When I realized
this was a situation I asked my wife,
she was astonished and bewildered to
the fact that I not only wiped while
standing up,
but I also thought that everybody in
the civilized world also wipe standing.
So I tried to do it the normal way and
found an incredibly uncomfortable stand
up, grab a cheek and spread with
one hand and wipe with the other.
That's how it's been. And that's
how it will be. My ass is clean.
Don't judge me. Your thoughts, rob
coon unique.
What do you think?
I'll tell you what I did before the
washlet. Well, I would also ask him,
are you seven?
Cause I think that's how they do it.
To Jesus spread and then wipe stand.
Can I tell you what I used
to do real talk before
the washlet three 50 okay.
I would do a combination of both.
If it was a difficult why now this is
before or in lieu of the shit to shower.
These are hard to fart on. Hard to Fart
on. Hardest. Sit on it doesn't feel good.
Yeah,
I know.
Sorry.
I had to get that out.
You know you look like the cars,
the cosmic your face was
like when the cause what?
It will be eating a Hoagie and then
Clair would catch him and then he's like,
you know, he pretended like he didn't
see it. Oh, he's pretending to you.
Hear that one or no? Barely heard it.
Yeah. I don't think they heard it either.
Please continue. I don't know what I'm
talking about. Oh, you said that before.
The specificity. This is if I
don't do shit to shower. Yeah.
Before the washlet I
would do a combo of both.
Meaning I would do at exploratory.
Yeah. First going on anyway.
What's going on?
If there was a lot happening,
I would do some sit down wipes and then
I went to state and then do more wipe
standing.
So I would do both.
Yeah.
What are you saying? Yeah, I mean,
I'm a, I'm a, I'm a mostly sitter.
Here's The Times that I've stood to wipe.
If I'm having a real itchy
ass whole day and I'm,
let's say I'm out and I'm, I don't
know, I'm in a department store,
right? Like Jesus, right. When I go
to check, I won't sit down to check.
I'll check standing, wait, wait, wait,
check the paper. Like you'll get like,
I'll be like, I'll be like,
my ass is itchy. Right.
So what I'll do is I'll go in the
bathroom, I'll wet some paper. Yeah.
But I'll do a standing wave that's like,
yeah, I won't sit for that one. No,
because you're not shitting
though. Right. But if I'm,
I won't stand to Wyatt and this guy's
obviously, he's mentally, oh. But yeah, I,
I disagree. I've often done a sit and
then stand to finish up the cleanup.
Yeah. Yeah. That's not that crazy.
Oh, he's good. Somebody wrote,
you know, we had the, the NFL but whole
debate I talked about Josh Potter. Right.
He also did um, wet balls,
beach with me this weekend.
I had great shows.
Yeah.
We were talking about what position
has the cleanest a whole, yeah. Um,
this guy writes the cleanest a-holes
has to be the center. If they stink,
the quarterback will let you and the
whole team know because your hands are on.
That guy's taint makes you self conscious.
Can't wait to see in Atlanta.
Thanks Mitch. Um, interesting thought.
I mean I myself played center for um,
you know many years. Middle School,
high school. Oh um, yeah. So you really
have an interesting perspective on that.
Do your, and he is right. You are, you are
more, your butthole is in your head. Sure.
Because you're, you lean forward,
you're butt's spreads a little bit and,
and the quarterback puts his hands
under your ass hole and on your toes.
Interesting. Yeah. You know what?
I've been thinking about my asshole.
Cause now I do polities twice a
week and I'm like, I really like,
I like to shower before and after
PyLadies because she's right there.
Her nose is so close to everything as I'm
sweating and everything. I feel bad for
this guy writes long listener with
a short response. Be whole debate.
I feel like you're missing
a major category here.
I feel like the worst butthole
category goes to the coaches do.
That's really funny. Just picture
rob and rex, Ryan, Wade Phillips,
the list of disastrous
old manholes goes on.
I want to thank both Eugene's for my, I'm
making my variable. Interesting. Tyler.
Yup. No, that's there. It
read it. Read on the meter.
These chairs are not optimal. Farting
tears. They're not good forwarding chairs.
They're knocking 40 chairs.
This chair or this show
was made for forwarding,
so I kind of don't know what will be an
optimal chair for farting. What's that?
Yeah.
Uh, elementary school. Plastic
chairs. Well, you know what happened,
you know, I did it again. I
sat on that step stool and I,
I spread down and I sat and I
farted again. It was crazy sounding.
Those are great steps. Steps because
first of all, it puts the plastic,
but it's also the deep
squat. Cause you're, you're,
you're squatting down all the way in our,
it's an art shit on a child's room.
Yeah. Yeah. Isn't that interesting?
Yeah. What a neat thought.
I haven't a dental update. Do you
want to hit the music? Oh yeah.
You've got to prepare me for this more.
I told you I had one.
You didn't tell me that before.
I just thought this was interesting.
And in lieu of our, okay, we
have a lot of contractor, uh,
people around.
Okay.
Is it a listener?
Dental update?
We'd do me a favor.
Will you encourage me that night
to do my a whitening trays? I've,
I've tried for a year.
I'm asking you to tell me tonight.
I feel like bitsy has whiter teeth
than you. I want to do it tonight.
Will you encourage me
or no? I remember. Okay,
so this comes in, uh, Mike writes in,
I thought this was pretty fucked up.
I'm a construction worker and I was
recently working for a contractor who's
denim as the lowest and loosest imaginable
after asking for the correct tool for
several weeks because the one I was
using was unsafe and someone was going to
get hurt.
It finally happened.
The socket blew off into my delicate
chompers and blasted about four of them
into, how do you say
oblivion. Whoa. Right.
Luckily enough,
I only have to get one fake one.
Oh and this Thursday I am getting the
other three composite and crowned and
wait, how did this happen? What kind
of tools? He just says he was asking,
he doesn't say what the socket flew
off of, what? Like is he working?
He's a construction worker.
He's been asking, he says,
he just said I was asking for the correct
tool and he doesn't say what he was
doing. Wow. Anyways, three
composite and crowds.
So I only have to walk around looking
like a cousin fucker for a few more days.
Bam. We'll send more photos after
my tea. Firs are high and tight.
That is unbelievable.
Heritable. That's crazy. Oh,
I'm so sometime around March I will
get the fake one after the implant has
healed up and up jeans up. I'm so sorry
Mike. That is a terrible, terrible.
I'm sure you can sue the fuck out of your
boss though, by the way. Yes, I know,
right? There's probably, he's the
kind of guy I'm sure like on a, a guy,
they're like gay people get two teeth
knocked out here. This is what we do here.
But he's, he asked for the proper
tool that he needed to get it.
That's why you should fucking have
someone pay for that. Um, I have one.
You have a dental update.
I was flossing very hard around my
crown on the side and I think it's,
I think the crown, it's
time to be replaced. Genes.
We got to go to the
Goddamn damn time we can,
we haven't gotten the dentist now look
after the new year after we've settled a
bit. You don't want to get to the
appointment. Mental work now. I know.
Life is chaos right now. Let's make
the appointment. Yeah, I am. All right.
We have a closing song.
It was submitted by Dj boy butter and
it's called Mommy Fart in your face.
Okay, thank you. Sounds like it
could be pretty good, but see,
I have not heard it yet, but here it is.
Here it is. Goodbye guys. Hi, Mommy's
okay. I'm to cheat here for
you. I think I eat. She again,
like [inaudible] got a
by you buy my seeking.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah. You know what I'm saying?
Take rx bars.
You know what I'm saying? Our
target, I'll pay $5 a hall
arts bargaining.
I like chills
all over my face. 40 Oh, you. Oh No,
no, no. I'm saying
Bj boy butter boy butter.
I like that. Yeah.