Well. Well, well go to your mom's house
Christina,
cause it's interesting
you wake up,
there's a shower three days. But
that means on the good side. Yeah,
she's got real stinky be home
today. I thought I would play, play,
play with me today.
I thought I would play with me.
Play with
play with mass.
Personate there's probably
a lot of smells going on.
Thinking about wholesale
is this lady's got one.
Someone can sit on my face all day with
her ass and I wouldn't mind smothering
them with snow. You asshole. What?
Today? I thought I would play,
play, play today.
I thought I would play with my ass.
She is playing with my life.
Yeah.
Hmm hmm. Hmm. Yeah, you
got it. She's early.
You got a gnarly be
whole right now. I do. I
run your finger along the crack of your
ass. You don't need to finger your whole,
you don't want to come back
with shit on your finger.
Always good advice and it's not sexual.
That's the best part about it.
That's the best part
about pup play is just,
it's just a bunch of guys hanging
out and latex dog costumes. Yeah,
just exchanging recipes.
Yeah, it's true. Swabbing,
swapping Kido recipes I like,
we're both really keyed up for today.
I both are really excited.
You know why I'm energized because I,
I came back from fart next and I met
so many mommies and then, you know,
they tell me things like your, the water
champ, your, the personality champion.
And then it inspires me to come
back and just be those things.
We'll get into that later.
But there's,
there's more than a controversy I
would say. I doubt that. No. Well,
you can doubt all you on. This is a huge
episode because you had, I don't want to,
I don't want to blow what it is, but
yeah, you've had quite an, uh, uh, uh,
past three days. Yeah. And for this show,
it's pretty much what we're all about.
So we're going to do a full hour on
what happened to you, I think. Yeah,
there's a lot, there's a lot
to get into. Um, yeah. He
didn't sound enthusiastic. No,
no. I, I mean it's, it was very
traumatizing. Very emotional.
Yeah. So that's going to be a lot
to, to talk about. Yeah. Yeah.
We'll process it, but that's what the show
is for. To process what happened. Yeah,
that's true. They give it as your therapy.
I do. I do. This will be a good for me.
It'd be good for us as a
couple. As a family. Yeah. Yeah.
We'll get into it too when you have
three and you, all right, well let's,
why don't we do a proper show open and do
it. Yeah. We proud of each other. Okay.
Here we go.
And then years later
when I was masturbating,
when everyone in my family to see
who were roused me, Oh my God,
I tried my father, my
mother, my children. Oh,
my grandparents, my cousins, my siblings,
and the only one who arouse
me with my father. Yeah. Well,
Oh,
is
she?
Your mom saw
Christina
nasty bitch.
I mean, first of all, for this show,
it's supposed to be your mom that arouses
you and I mean houses normative of her
to choose her patriarchal at she is hard
fucking core. Yeah. Without a doubt.
No kidding. She gets in
there, she never plays games.
Just when you think she
can't shock us anymore. Yeah.
And then she drives that knowledge.
Isn't that bananas? Yeah. But you know,
when you think about it,
it kind of makes sense from us from a
Freudian psychoanalysis perspective. Yeah.
Because your father is your first, your
first love. Yeah. Well she, you know,
she breaks it down. I
mean, uh, this is, um,
somebody that's not new to our show.
I always love that the Beethoven is
prominently displayed behind her.
It really does offset
any wacky stuff you say.
If you have like intelligent
things behind you. I know.
That's how I got to start doing for my
calling. She's, yeah, she's great. Yeah.
She's really cool. I like her. Yeah. She
has a lot of things going on there. Um,
she has a lot of things going there.
She has a, like I said, she's
not, she's not new to our show.
Uh, we've, we've featured
her prominently before. Um,
you may remember her. I've come
all over my face. That's her.
Um,
he loves this company.
So then she went on to come strike.
That's Ryan. I've forgotten.
How did that come strike?
Because guys kept wanting to
come on her and all over her.
They were horrified if their
own come touched themselves. So.
And did the strike work, did
she get a raise? I don't know.
I mean I watch CNN a lot and I
know that's kind of, you know,
so maybe it's covered on Fox or maybe
some BBC or something. I Dunno. Right.
Um,
so I dunno if it was ever covered,
but I know that she did make a big
thing about going on in the company.
There's a writer's strike happening.
Does it have anything to do?
I think they have averted that. So maybe
they averted the two things together,
I'm guessing. Cause we didn't know how
her, her strike ended. That's true.
Let me see if, um, yeah,
if I can pull up a w w what
do we have here? Um, but yeah,
so she, she was just, she's big on,
um, on talking in detail
about I think, oh,
here we go here. Would, she could have
had a career as a muppet for sure.
On strike against com. Com. Yeah.
Which you're going to come on sesame
street. We were looking up the character,
like who does the voices of cookie and
Oscar? I think she'd make a killer muppet.
She has a great voice for that.
Yeah. If she gives us the thing calm,
she should do that. I think we
should go on strike against calm
Tom. I don't want to share my
[inaudible]. That's pretty good.
Yeah.
You have to share.
I don't want to share my cookies.
That's pretty good.
I don't want to share my com.
Yeah, I've got this cup of common.
It's all mine in my balls, right? Yeah.
Just to come for everyone. No,
I'm going on to come strike. Yeah.
So it's really good. Yeah.
I can tell you what a lot of
children's programming. Um, Nah,
scram. Oscar's our favorite
right now. Oscars off.
See how we integrate the fact
that we have a child over into,
you know,
we're a family show,
but also we discuss things that
appeal to adults. I'll come strikes.
Uh, just because you become a mom and dad
doesn't mean you have to be lame. Yeah.
So as a mother,
I'm offended by that.
Oh
Gee.
Dad's upset. That doesn't want
to hear going on a come straight.
So do you like to join me on my,
and I don't want it to
be like that were pilot.
Like I'm not trying to
make fun of this lady.
It's just that she covers so many things
outside of normal everyday coffee talk
conversations. She really needs
her job. Yeah. She gets out there.
So this is like, Eh, this is stuff
that maybe we should be talking about,
but we're not understanding which they
should put her on the view. Whoopee.
But they don't have the balls. You know
who does? Yeah, we do real show. Yeah.
Do your incest fantasies.
I want you to feel guilt
or shame around them.
Maybe you've never allowed yourself to
have them because you think you would be
a horrible person if you ever went there.
So it's all suppressed.
Yeah. Wow. Does she have a phd in
psycho analysis too? I don't know,
but she's really this sex
Bert, right? Cause she's, yeah,
she's written books on it.
She's definitely experienced a lot of it.
Yeah.
Incest fantasies are normal.
Okay.
I first learned this from Betty
Dotson's book sucks for one,
and when I read her book in my late
forties and she wrote about incest
fantasies,
I was repulsed.
I'll be honest.
The idea of of approaching
the subject is terrifying.
It's not supposed to be like,
oh yeah, I totally, I get it.
Like you're supposed to feel right.
It's not a good top it,
those fantasies do exist.
I think the mind does a good job of
shelving them pretty deep. In other words,
it's not something that's on the
forefront all the time, you know? No,
but like again, I feel like it makes
total sense when you think about it.
Your mother is your very first sensual,
and I don't mean sexual sent,
like since you,
you literally embraced her
boobs for life in the morning,
in the morning and the
beginning of your life.
So it makes sense that that's
your first sensual experience.
Not necessarily sexual, but stimi.
That makes sense. Yeah. Wow.
So fucking deep did. And then your mother
is probably the first one that's like,
yeah, he was around now and
you kind of go for it. Wow.
But then would you marry your mom? I
mean, marrying your mom or other things?
It's totally different. It's
just, you know, it's just
like the gays. That's right.
Yeah.
Um,
and then a couple of years later, I
actually, when I was masturbating,
went through everyone in my
family to see who were roused me.
I tried my father, my mother, my children,
my grandparents, my cousins, grandparents,
my siblings, nasties. It
asked me was my father,
do you think you, your granddaddy gets you
hard for you, by the way? For me. Well,
just cause you know, you're
a woman. She's a woman.
While I was taking it
for the grandparents,
I know you have some pretty sexy grandad
fantasies, don't you? I liked it.
Her approach to it though,
it was like,
I'm going to start masturbating
and then go through the Rolodex.
Like who turns me on? Who Turns
me on? That's how she, it's just,
it's, it's different. It's a brave, yeah.
I'm not sure I need to go there.
Like you said,
that's kind of one of those things that
you can totally repressed your whole
life and be fine. Like there's some
things you don't need to go into. No,
I'm totally cool with no, hopefully
we'll explore it today. That was a, for
me,
that was the only one that turned me on.
My boys did not or my mother or anything,
but um,
I allowed myself,
I didn't judge my fantasy,
I just went with it cause it was
a rousing to me and I'm like,
well what does this pant,
is he teaching?
Nothing like that. She's exploring. Asked
him, will you ever date your mom? Oscar?
Do you ever have any sexual fantasies
about your dad? No. Get out of here
and where it showed me and what it does
do you and who I will play with Mommy
fucking price.
Say It involves a lot of the insights.
My name is Tom is about having sex
with someone who loves you. Oh,
and who you feel love for?
Is that what that's about? That's, it
would be great. Yeah, that is a good one.
Is that,
is that I'm going to ask my therapist
about that cause she's afraid in psycho
analysis that she breaks it down that way.
Does that change it at all for,
you know, if you, I don't know.
I wasn't paying attention.
I was still horrified. Like I'm still
on the Rolodex. I'm not here to,
Annecy is tied to having sex with somebody
that really loves you. Oh, like love.
Yeah. Yeah. That's the maternal,
the paternal right thing. Now,
can you masturbate to your dad? Right,
right, right. Got You. Okay. Oh,
is that what we're trying to do?
We're trying to get me, yeah.
Probably get you into the same
mindset. Oh, okay. No, it's still not.
Let's keep working on not,
oh, please. No, no, no,
master.
I'm glad I allowed that fantasy
because now it no longer turns me on.
Like it was just a step on
my sexual evolution. Yeah.
Because I think all of our
fantasies teach us something. No.
Repressing them just stops the
sexual evolution, I believe. Okay.
So what do you, but in all
seriousness, do you believe this?
Do you believe that perhaps
she is very sexually
evolved? Absolutely. Yeah.
I think anybody that can go to the dark
side, their force and come out of it.
Here's the thing,
I repress so much shit.
Like I am a fucking vault of dark
thoughts. Yeah. I mean it's, I'm,
I'm a comedian. I see a shrink once a
week. Like the darkness is Sodi been me.
I can't, I can't go here. That's
why I love shit like this.
She goes there and I can make fun of
her. Right. Like we're poking at her.
We're having a good laugh.
Yeah. But truthfully, yeah.
She's actually very sexy.
Way More evolved than me. Yeah. And
I can't stand it. Like I'm, I'm,
I'm so threatened by it. Shoreside
that's her name. Thanks dude.
It's all love girl. You just blew
our minds again. Yeah, you did. Damn,
that's not possible by the way.
Very hard to faze us on the show.
Say that know very little like rattles
our cages and sometimes things are just
fun to learn. Oh No. This
one I showed you that. No,
I don't like this one.
Why not?
Jim's normal routine was after he kills
someone that he was loved status and lay
down and take a nap.
I mean it was like
a Aphrodisiac Pharma taking a value.
It was just nice and relaxed.
Implement next couple of weeks.
Nice to relax you.
Just like a stress relief and then you
could see a buildup in again. But yeah,
like killing people a relaxed him.
Yeah.
That's a Kevin Weeks as part
of the Winter Hill Gang.
He ran with James Whitey Bulger your hero.
No.
Um,
as I was watching this documentary on
bodyguards and so they have different,
um, bodyguards, different worlds
of being about, in other words,
they have entertainer, like
Justin Bieber's body guard.
They had Nelson Mandela,
one of his body guards.
So you have like an entertainer,
you have a head of state and then this
a soccer player. Was it Nelson Mandela?
The hockey player? That's right. Yep.
The uh, great, great hockey player.
Uh, he did so much from the Blue Jays. Um,
I forget what team they believe.
He really paved the way for so
many great hockey players. Um,
but then they had this Guy Kevin Weeks
who I've seen another documentaries and
so he was a, he was like muscle
for a Whitey Bulger. Yeah.
Also a really neat guy who whitey
Bulger. Yeah. It was positive.
Like Tony Robbins telling people what
to do. Yeah. He's a real piece of work,
acting the world of love.
But then he's telling these stories
about all these different murders.
They committed God and then he tells
this part where he's like, and then,
you know,
his usual routine was he would kill
someone and then just go take a nap.
And he's like,
and then he was just cool for weeks.
Like you could see that he was like, like
killing people really relaxed him. Yeah.
That was,
um,
I know that you've been high on this
clip for days. No, because it's so crazy.
And it is. Yeah. It's so crazy. I'm also,
I also love that I play it for you before
bed. That's what I was going to say.
This thing where you're like, stop showing
me these things before I go to sleep.
Well,
yeah,
I mean we weren't let showed you something
that you told me it wasn't your dream.
The next day you'll get fucked up.
My whole green of course.
The thing is you and I were having
fun like we were like what play?
We were laying in bed petting the dogs,
just like school girls. So I was like, Oh,
I've got to show you this funny
thing and then you ruined the moment.
You're like, oh, hold on,
hold on. Speaking of which,
I have a really funny clip to show you
and then you turn on the sh the show and
I was like, dude, I'm
about to go to sleep. Yeah.
I don't want to hear about murder and
how the sky light likes killing people.
Right.
It makes me sleep nice to relax in
the next couple of weeks. He was nice,
you know,
actually was just like a stress relief
and then you could see a buildup in again,
but showing people a relaxed him.
I think watching documentaries about
people kill people relaxes you.
It makes me laugh. What? What part
of that like brings you so much joy?
It's so crazy. That's why you like having
your mind blown before bed. Is that,
is that what it is? Just so
crazy. I, here's the thing,
inappropriate behavior,
inappropriate
things said is a huge
mindblowing laugh escape for me.
So like somebody saying like the lady
saying, kiss my pussy in the bank. Yeah.
I always make me laugh. We have
a whole show dedicated. I know,
but for some reason a
murdering because it's,
it's so like to hear somebody talk about
it this way is so far removed from how
you should talk about it. Yeah.
So that's why it makes me laugh.
Like if it was somebody
saying it in the way that you,
like if this guy was scared and
talking about how scared he would,
it wouldn't register as, um, it's
funny the way that he's talking,
like he's talking about it like, like
he's talking about, I don't know,
like wildlife. I think the club is
actually very amusing. Yeah, it is.
But it's also really disturbing.
So what it is I'm not hearing from
you is like, yeah, that was funny.
It's really,
it's ridiculous.
But I'm not sensing the empathetic sort
of and how tragic that he's killing
people. Because if we go into,
if you, if you shift it, uh,
30 seconds earlier or they're talking
about the graphic details of the murder,
I don't find that funny because
they show up what's not funny.
It's funny for a guy to describe as his,
one of his close friends and he's like,
it really relaxed them and you can see
that actually he doesn't register that
it's absurd. Right. That's the funnier
part. It seems like he would take a nap.
You know what I think it is with these
murder shows is that you consume them the
way most people consume
comedies or sitcoms.
I don't like watching comedies neither.
Why very seldom do I enjoy a comedy.
But you consume them at such a high rate.
Like it really is your favorite thing.
Does it upset you that I don't share
your enthusiasm for murder and can I tell
you though, my, the really, the thing is
I'm completely convinced that everybody,
all of us who consume any
type of either books, movies,
TV shows, well, we all like our
stories, but that's the universal thing.
It's a story. There's only
like six stories, right?
So the thing that I like about crime
shows and whatnot, but the crime show,
what I like is,
I like the stories
involved in the crime show.
I like that somebody does something.
And then I like the path of the
people hunting that person down,
getting like,
I liked that whole story.
So you like it when the
murderer gets caught as I do,
I absolutely side with the killer. And
you're like, I'll be gets away with this.
No, no. But I want, I want,
if it's a good crime story,
you want him to almost get away with it.
Otherwise it's boring you hard
enough. Yeah. You want them,
you want him to, I mean, look at all the
grunt great crime movies or, or stories.
It's that, you know, he misleads
the investigators. He leaves a clue.
They think they have, he
gets away. I mean, that's
what makes those stories excited. Okay.
Look, I'm not, you know, yeah. Oh,
say anything and just curious. But
also thank for you. In my past,
I don't do any more, but when I used to
kill people, he's just very relaxing to,
yes. Very nice. Take a nap
after. Oh yeah. I mean,
the idea that somebody can take a
nap after that is in saint sociopath.
Yeah, of course. Yeah. Sociopath.
But that's why it's like,
it's jarring to hear about. It does,
it gives them a charge if they did.
Yeah. The, the last thing they'd be
able to do is take a nap. Right. Yeah.
You know, I, my step father is
dead now and my mother's dead,
so I can talk about
them, I think. Yeah. Uh,
my Stepdad was a sociopath as well,
and I know that it gave him a lot
of joy to stab somebody tires.
Right.
But not stab people.
Not People know that he didn't
kill people that I know of now.
I did give him a thrill to
do wacky stuff like that,
but it wouldn't put them to sleep.
It would just give him a charge and
then he actually got excited. It was,
it was like the, yeah, it was snowflakes.
It was happiness for him and my mom both.
They love to conspire and,
and you know, get, get,
get one over on someone you a different,
but I have killed off a lot of people.
I know there's kind of scumbags kind of,
they kill a lot of people. Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, I think I want to say that,
you know,
the original count against
Bulger and his crew was like 19.
How do you know of, right? That's
what I'm saying. Yeah. Who knows?
What's the heading it putting on them?
That's banana. That guy's a real psycho.
Fuck. Yeah. I mean I saw Johnny Depp's
version of him in that movie. Good.
He's really good. He's always good.
Right? Johnny Depp's really good actor.
Black Mass.
Not About Shaq's assholes about,
it's about white and black mass.
Yeah.
So nasty as hell, man. Yeah.
Black mass does sound like a,
like a B hall that's covered in
Brown. It's a lot. Has Chocolate.
He Shit. Dark chocolate. Pretty crazy man.
Yeah. Well neat. So can we
get to finally your weekend,
how your life is like God, it was uh,
it's been, uh, it's a long journey.
Next dog. Hands Down, dog coming up.
You've been lowered.
So if you're listening in your cubicle
guys, time to put the headphones on.
Don't worry.
This is not like,
I want to tell people because they hear
that and they're like, oh God. You know,
so people are like, are you just
going to just tell me you took? No.
What happened was I got sick. It's
a story. It's a story. So don't,
this is not just about a fart or
something, you know, this is a,
this is a real story that's in dignity.
I did something.
You're definitely gonna make fun of
me for it. But I thought I did it.
And you know,
there's always jokes about buying
Sushi from wherever I bought Sushi,
whole foods,
whole farts. I was there picking up some,
some things. I was a single dad. You,
you left town.
So I did a single dad run,
nanny was here watching the boy.
I run to the store and I go,
I got to get things for breakfast and
lunch tomorrow. So I get, you know,
the usual stuff is milk and is some fruit,
some eggs is this and that.
And when I'm there, um, I had worked
out, I'd worked out like an hour before,
so I'm hungry. Right. But a,
I'm thinking about cooking and it's
like that split second decision. Yeah,
go tired.
Just want to have something quick,
what can I get that's going to satiate me?
But also,
you know, kind of healthy.
So as I'm walking through,
it's whole foods has that,
the little Sushi, there's
a chef, they're like,
this is a Thursday. Okay. So
I'm like, you know, and yeah,
it is later in the day. So yeah,
stuff's probably been made for a while.
Ordain rule.
Like you don't want to order Sushi on a
Sunday because the fish markets close on.
Yeah, that's probably
right. But I, you know,
don't fucking so fucking,
I go,
I go, I look at it. Okay.
I get salmon. Sashimi.
You're not pronouncing it Salmon
Sashimi. It's like six pieces. That's,
no, that looked fine. It was totally
fine. It's got the brown spots.
It's perfect.
I grabbed that real white brown.
I grab some toony and then
I'm like Sasha, me. Yeah.
Then I go,
I'm going to do something else.
And then there's seared albacore chem,
so,
and that's on rice. I'm like,
ah, you know, have like a
couple of bites with Rice.
A couple of I, that's how
we, we do Sushi at it. Don't,
you don't want to get too much
rice. So anyways, I grabbed that.
I run home,
I put away the groceries,
I start, I open these three
things, I wolf down the soundman,
take a couple bites of toony.
Then I opened that seared albacore and
the first one I take a bite with Rice,
right? Yeah. And I go back and I have
another piece of like salmon or whatever.
And then tuna, and then I go, I remember,
I noticed that like that rice
balls too big. So I take a,
I take it the seared albacore
off of it and I'm like,
I don't want to have too much rice.
And as I take a bite of it,
I'm like just tastes fishy.
Which is a no, no, no, no.
Yeah. If you don't eat Sushi, it sounds
silly. But like if it smells like typical,
like when you go, it smells like a
fish market. Like fish mouth. Yeah.
Like your dog's mouth.
That's not what you want.
So I have like half a bite in and I'm
like, I'm just not feeling it man. I know,
but I'm not putting together, you
know everything yet. I'm just like,
I just not digging this.
And also you're a bear.
Bear's just put everything in their mouth.
If it's like
a beehive with the bees
swarming and stinging his mouth,
he doesn't notice the bees stinging you.
You've put like molten hot pizza
in your mouth. Did you choose to,
you chew through the pain but so,
but this is awesome.
You chew through the smells too.
I don't need anymore really stop.
So, so I have basically, so that's
good. One and a half pieces of what?
Cause I just go like I'm not digging.
It doesn't smell right. Tastes good.
So anyways, that's all
I have. Okay. I Dunno,
30 40 minutes later I shoot
a water hose out of my ass,
but I go, that's you know that's normal
for you. Well No, I just go like the,
I don't think of it as, oh
this is serious. I just think
like that didn't settle.
Right. Cause I don't feel sick. I just
feel like this is, you know, that was bad.
Something was bad, but I don't feel like
it's the next level bad. In other words,
sometimes you eat something, it
doesn't agree with you, it's out.
And it passes as an a metaphor.
Somebody who has a severe phobia of
vomiting what you did like, first of all,
I won't even eat whole food Sushi
if you've ever seen me do it.
I know because I'm in a minute. I am
so terrified of vomiting. Number two,
whenever I choose an item of food that's
out, this is going to sound crazy,
but this is one of my crazy food phobia.
Thanks.
I always choose the item that's far
back puts you. Always put your hand,
put it there. They put the
oldest shit in the front. Yeah.
So whenever I choose eggs, milk,
chicken, rotisserie chicken.
Always go for the back dude. Cause those
are the freshest. That's a fresh shit.
The dry shits in the front dude. I bet
you, I bet you picked a fucking first one,
Huh? No, I don't remember how I picked
it, but I do remember this nasty.
Don't eat that shit in the next
morning I woke up and I was like,
oh I don't mind how many shoots did you
make after this one? But it was water.
Yeah, it was bad as a seven. Yeah.
I ended up having the full fucking Bristol
stool chart over the next few days.
But yeah, it was, it was just, yeah,
it was fucking water. Yeah. Okay. Okay.
I'm trying to do the shit lock
and we during an autopsy on it,
the next morning I wake up and I have
this basically you, you've heard,
I'm sure people talk about the coffee
that has like a grass fed butter and MCT
oil and basically it, it's, um,
it's, it's richer, but it's, it,
you get good fats and it's, it's almost
like a meal replacement also, you know?
And anyways,
I have just that for breakfast
right after seven diarrhea,
well not be here, but the seven
is fucking, I don't know, man,
like 12 hours earlier and I feel
fine. I don't feel, I don't feel sick.
You're probably a little dehydrated.
A little bit. Yeah. Yeah.
But I have that and it, it
satiates you. So I'm like, I'm not,
I'm not eating other foods and I don't
feel like I need food right away,
you know, all makes sense. Now I'm free
this way. I know what happened. Um,
with the boy, I feel fine.
He has breakfast, um,
few hours later, I dunno. Oh, we,
you know, I take them to the park.
He has some snacks. Uh Ha. He has lunch.
Then I have an avocado.
I'm like as a kind of midday snack.
Then a couple hours after
that nanny comes over. Right.
So now it's like two in the afternoon.
So I've been with them
all eight hours already
eaten like real solid yet.
I know. That's why you were confused about
where you got the poisoning from. Yeah,
because I haven't really,
so anything else to push out the jams.
Right. So then it's getting, like I
said, it's around two and I'm like,
now I'm getting hungry but I
also don't want to, you know,
I have like things that I eat,
things I don't eat right.
So I have this like uh,
Kido like fuel pack where I,
I I eat that just to, it
has some calories, some fat,
and then I go work out.
But I make note like I never do this,
but when I go to the trainer I go,
I got to tell you like I feel
white and I also am very tired.
I've been up since six and it's two
and I haven't stopped. So, like I said,
it's, it is eight hours that
I've been going. I'm like,
I'm just really tired. I'm really tired.
So the trans like, you know, why don't we,
I've never asked for that. It was like,
why don't we like amend some things?
I knew something was up and I go and I,
and I hesitated to say something
cause I don't want to be like,
we take it easy on me today,
but you should look up,
what's the shame in the game?
It's just that normally how I do it.
So I just go,
I just go, I think I should. And she
was 100% was like, oh, we'll just, uh,
we'll do lower intensity. But you know,
so, you know, even through the workout,
like it was all right. I didn't
feel great, but I didn't feel sick.
I just didn't feel great and I thought
I was just really tired, which I also,
and you, you're probably were,
you know, low on electrolyte.
Yeah, exactly. I'm like,
when I go, I told her
I'm dehydrated. Didn't
eat right today. Yeah. And
I'm tired and I haven't,
I've been with my kid for eight hours.
Yeah.
So speaking of water, where's your, it's
right here. I'm actually drinking it.
I'm actually one who's been
drinking, so, oh, okay.
I get home and the night before I
had also, when I was at whole farts,
I bought a steak and I seasoned it and
I was like, oh, eat it after I work out.
Right.
So I get the grill ready.
At this point I'm actually hungry,
but you know,
you got to wait for your coals to turn.
So it's like kind, waiting more to eat,
which is like annoying me.
I finally throw that thing on.
Uh, like around, I don't know,
probably four 45 I'm eating by whatever,
let's say 5:00 AM meeting.
So,
um,
I eat about half of it and then I go,
okay, I don't want the other half. Um,
you felt full quickly. That's as,
that's another thing is that when you,
when you're sick, if you're
sick, you feel fuller,
your stomach's like create mucus
and shit or whatever it's doing.
It's telling you stop eating fatty,
you're about to get sick. I know.
So then the other thing is when I
started having to gestion but I'm like,
I don't feel like, you know, what
is it? What happened to Josh? Um,
and then I get to the point where,
so now it's like around seven or something
where I'm like, you know what? Uh,
cause I'm pretty much not just like
sugar free but starch and carbs.
Like I don't eat bread
or pasta or anything,
but I'm getting that feeling where
like I have to put some starch and me,
I'm going to feel when you're sick.
I know,
but I'm saying I don't know I'm there yet.
So I'm like,
that's what I'm trying to image it.
Diarrhea.
That wasn't enough for you to
know 20 hours earlier once. Right.
That's not a big deal.
I mean it's gone but usually one bout
of diarrhea and I'm like I have to have
toast and have to put some starch cause
it doesn't feel like that at the time.
It just feels good. It goes and
it's fine. So then now I'm like,
I got to eat something in my stomach
to feel normal. Right? So I make it,
I do make a toast. I put
some peanut butter on it, I
eat it. I don't feel great.
Afterwards I'm like, ah, fuck. I
still don't feel good. I keep burping.
I have all this ingestion, I
have a spot at the store. So,
uh, nanny looks at me and she goes, you
look really tired. And I go, thank you.
And when she does that, I go, I am, I
don't want to go do this show right now,
but I have to, you know, cause
I still am not like sick, sick.
I just don't feel up to it.
I go to the store,
it's really fun shows or show. There was
a really fun, great, great night out.
Great. But as soon as I'm done, like
I got to go home and I get home.
I still had been to Josh
and I have another toast.
I still don't feel good after
I eat it. Um, I go to bed,
I have all this weird stomach
feeling going to bed, not pain.
It's just like anxious, weird
feeling in my stomach, you know,
I can't explain it. It just doesn't,
it feels uneasy. Like it doesn't,
it's just don't feel relaxed.
I don't know what's going on.
I wake up a few times throughout
the night, no problems.
Like I don't go to the bathroom, I
just, I've just don't feel good. Yeah.
In the morning I wake up and like within
30 minutes the flood gates are open and
I'm just going and I'm with him alone
with a boy or a little worse and I'm like
trying to take care of them,
feed them,
play with them and or keep them
entertained and I'm going like two, three,
four, five times. That's when I realized
like, oh, I got like something in me now.
So I finally,
I text her because you're gone and I go,
is there any way you can come sooner?
Because I don't feel like
I can keep doing both.
And she gets back to me after
awhile. She's like, yeah,
I'll get there as soon as I
can. And then I just go, go.
I Dunno,
probably total of eight or nine times
in an hour and a half or something.
I'm so wiped after that that when she
gets to the house I sleep and this is like
mid to late morning, I sleep
four straight hours. Right.
Just completely passed out.
And then of course I
wake up like I feel dead.
I don't have any energy so I have some
toast after low while water and then
after a while after that, you know,
you start to kind of feel like, okay,
I'm getting better now.
I mean not to eat crazy or anything,
but like you start eating a cracker,
a little bite of banana or something
and then the scale changes.
I started to have like like a five
and then the next day I'm like,
oh,
I have low energy but
I guess I'm better now.
I eat something normal and
I'm like back to like six mm.
And like it takes another 24 hours to
feel like today I feel like I'm 85%
normal.
Yeah,
it takes three to four
days. Yeah, for Dare Roya.
But I got straight up Sushi food boys.
Now the good thing is you
didn't eat a lot of that.
Is it albacore that was fishy.
Smelly. Yeah, but that raw fish,
that shit will take invite eaten. If
I had four, if I was like, who cares?
And just eating the six,
you would be in the hospital.
Can I tell you to the
panic that you put into me,
you texted me Saturday morning as I'm
coming home from Bart Nicks and you go,
I have a stomach bug. And to
someone that has a phobia, Oh God,
I should've said food poisoning. And to
me who has a severe phobia of vomiting.
Yeah. My world starts to fucking spend.
I'm like, oh, what am I going to do?
Can I go to a hotel?
How do I not get near him?
I have to fortify myself like I
fucking lose my mind. I know. Oh,
I hate it so much when that,
that's the scare. So anyways,
thank God you didn't have a fucking
stomach flu. I be, I know. I swear.
We haven't had one knock on wood yet
with a boy. It's gonna. It's gonna.
It's happening. Right, right.
I'm just going to check
myself into the hotel. Sorry.
See you later. No, I understand.
I know. I know that. Um,
oh,
some backlash,
some feedback I should say over
last week's personality debate,
there wasn't even a debate. You know, I,
I have a feeling you, you coerced people.
I'm just saying, I know it didn't feel
genuine. You know, not at all. Hey,
Mommy's, I'm listening to the podcast.
You guys are talking about personalities.
How friendly or Kurt
people are at airports.
Toronto is known as the screw
face capitol of the world.
We're not openly aggressive to you,
but we never make small during
a caddy by now,
a huge west Indian festival.
We get a lot of people from New
York coming across the border.
I've talked to a few of them.
They all mentioned the same thing.
Toronto's as friendly as a brick to your
face. I had no idea about this. Agree.
I've had nothing but wonderful
experiences and trauma.
This is Anton from Toronto.
Okay.
So he's talking about just [inaudible]
personality, your personality, Twan,
uh, hey mommies, I'm a little
behind in the podcast. Um, blah,
blah, blah. I'm certainly something
about my butthole PSM team. Christina.
Finally for the better
personality. Yeah. No,
I was not paid that. I have some
student loan debt if you are offering.
Thanks Aubrey. I guess she wants you
to pay her for saying that. Okay.
Thank you Aubrey. Let's see. Uh, hey,
mommy's another one
here. Levy jeans. Mommy.
Tina is the water and personality
came through. Sure. Mommy,
Tom showboats but he's stronger but
she's stronger in both categories. Yeah,
I agree. Thank you. Oh,
here's one. Hey, Hitler's.
My wife and I were able to get glass main
Tina and Fart next last night, May 4th.
I have never seen Tommy bonds
live or met him in person,
but I still feel I am more than qualified
to put an end to the personality.
Cham water champ debate.
First off when gene was onstage,
if she wasn't saying something hilarious,
she had a bottle of water or lips and
she had throat opened fully like a Chubby
Asu sorority sister for a
maximum non Yorkie slippage.
After the show she ran to the front lobby
to show off her shiny personality to
all the adoring fans.
She took the time to show a
genuine interest in every person.
As I approached the
mother goddess herself,
I got a little nervous and the feeling
can only be described as how a young
preteen German boy probably felt
meeting Hitler for the first time.
But she immediately put my nerves to rest.
She was genuine in her.
Thanks for us coming to the show.
This email should put to rest all the
arguing over who the water champ and the
personality champ is.
I don't want to hear anything more on
these subjects as I have put them to bed.
That's Jeremy Zimmer, sir. Thank you
Jeremy. Zinzer. I, you know what?
Thank you. That's it. That's, that's the
debate. Yeah. It's really fun to do shows.
Um, and then there's always like one
drunk mommy when you walk out on stage.
He goes,
yeah.
And then the people who don't know that
stuff or like I'm experiencing a few
more than one just so you know.
It's, it's a bit of a thing. Yeah.
Tommy Bolin. Hey, what's up
brothers? Joe Rogan. Hey Dude,
I heard you're having some kind
of a contest with Christina.
I started having a competition to
see who has the best personality,
which was more easy when I
heard it because I didn't
even know she had a person.
I mean, she's a really funny
comedian and everything like that,
but like I barely even
know when she's talking.
You guys have a competition about this.
You got a way better personality
and you don't have a personality.
But my advice to you though
is to like humor her,
pretend that she has, but she's a
person. She's the mom of your kids,
right? Bam. Good point.
January brother, a whole,
well let's get together and
do some guys shit later.
So ridiculous. Anyways. Yeah,
you clearly influenced that.
No voicemail. That's kind of random that,
that Joe would just call it that. Yeah.
Kinda random. Oh, you think
so? Yeah. My favorite was,
Hey, Mary Lynn, right carb. Um, I mean,
I've been thinking about this a lot and
I just obviously Christina who was a
good friend of mine,
being a woman, you know,
we talk about a lot of stuff
together and very close to her.
So, you know, having said that,
it's clear that,
and well it's not clear,
but I also,
you know,
I've been around Tom a lot and because
I know Christina to Worldcom is just
personality wise.
Like if I were to say
personalities overall,
um, I think for smaller, um hmm.
She's very up and down and calm,
parents abused and you're very even keel.
Everybody measured, measured.
You're very logical. Yup. Okay.
I know you're very cool headed. Yup.
And you're also really cool. Yup.
Cool. You're cool to be around.
So many you want a trader.
Um, so big fan, um,
does have a better personality,
but I'm just saying generally
like that I hang out with you
just not gonna hang out with you.
Do you hear that
personality? Okay, bye.
Wow. That's one of your
friends, Maryland, right?
It's like a very good friend of
mine. Very talented actress. Yeah.
Very talented comedian.
Yeah.
And you know someone who I've
always enjoyed being around. Huh?
Definitely a bigger fan of me.
I didn't even know you guys hung out.
When are you hanging? Talk to her
store. I saw her at the store. Yeah,
Thursday night. It's interesting
that, I mean, she came over. I'm like,
when we moved in here a few times,
but yeah. You know. Wow. Wow.
I'm just floored at the lever
level of trader ship here. Yeah.
We've got Sean on my BFF.
Maryland might be BFF. Crazy.
Joe Joe. Yeah. I mean that's,
that's preposterous that
he would try me on this.
You've spent a decent amount of time with
him. Oh yeah. Yeah. Oh yeah. He does. He,
he doesn't even think you're alive.
Show me that real clear.
He did. Yeah. Gosh, I'm going to have to
ask him about this. Yeah. You'll see him.
Devastating. You should tell him how
well Millan, no, it's for Dell. I mean,
a lot of people are,
you know, I mean, yeah,
we're getting emails from whoever,
but whoever the mommies,
the fans of this show who listened
to us hours, hours, hours,
and unanimously after my shows in phonics
had lines of people telling me how
much better my personality was and
how much more water I drink. I Hitler.
I used to masturbate to Christina
when she was on MTV. Thank you.
This is hard to say. I feel like Tom's
personality can only prop is up so much.
You know what I'm saying? Beyond
the beautiful repaired cleft palate.
Christina make loans it on the podcast.
She has a lighter shade Brown. I feel
like we're seeing, I could stay on camera,
but maybe mute her and have this
personality w on the mic. Like Charro,
Fran Drescher, Phyllis Diller,
William Hickey. Just a suggestion.
I feel like that would take your podcast
to the next level. Thanks Jean. Jeff.
Thanks Jean. Singular.
That is so rude. Jeff.
I don't know this one.
I don't know if you're ready for this.
Maybe you brace yourself.
Just get comfortable because
this a celebrity one, two,
no, it's just like, it's just
people weighing in. People
call my dad. I already know
is my mommy.
I actually thought of it that my mom
back from the grave to disapprove of me
some more.
I get it.
You don't like
Sarah Burns?
I keep kind of overthinking it.
You know her 20 years. Yeah, calling
you. I'll tell you the truth.
I first thought was,
I'm going to say please don't
how Christine and I called,
but I would never want to have a secret
between you and me that didn't include
her.
I Love Christina.
I've known her for a really
long time and she's, yeah,
she's more than a friend to me,
but I feel kind of compelled to call
because I've been listening to the podcast
and
I just,
before I say anything,
I just want to say that Christina,
she's like, I don't know what is
just like if someone only child,
but
bigger than that to me,
she's so generous with me.
Um,
I don't even expect to get
for no reason at all. And
she's been there for some very
tough times for me and I'm very,
very good on,
I'm judgmental or nonjudgmental or
unjudging me and I feel like one of the
crazier people, she probably knows, but
she doesn't make me feel that way when
I'm talking to her. I'm a great person,
great friend.
I feel really bad saying because she's
always been so funny and so pretty.
She's like I say,
she's my best friend and
she just,
I mean,
she's the first person in my
life that I ever just went up to.
It's true.
It's true for a cigarette.
And,
uh,
we became friends and I was traveling a
total of to work there wasn't even cool.
And I was just like,
I didn't even see,
I just saw this person's
going to be my friend.
So in, in college, she just walked out to
you? Yeah, that's how we met Sarah Burns.
I'm Shauna, who also
called in to this show, uh,
who you filled her head
with lies. Uh, yeah,
she walked up to us in San Francisco and
we just became friends. Literally just,
Hey, do you have a cigarette? And I,
we never meet people that way. Yeah.
And so you and you and Shauna
where together walking together,
we were walking to Pfm,
the name of the cafeteria back then
and we locked up but we see burns.
She's wearing a denim overalls. This is
like the Nice picture of her. Yeah, Dude.
That's exactly right. The day you met her
all she wore those overalls on and uh,
we, I saw her and I remember going,
oh, that chick's fucking cool.
Like she looked all crazy and cool like
we did because we were a goth, you know,
and I was like, this chick's
weird too. Let's go talk. Let's,
I want to talk to this weird chick. Yeah.
She came out to us. Hey, hi. What's up?
Do you have a cigarette?
And then that's it.
We walked in the cafeteria together and
the three of us were BFFs since then and
that was 1994 and that's
how long we've been friends.
Yeah. Isn't that crazy? Yeah.
I wonder who she likes more.
She is my friend and she's like
my best friend and when she, she,
she found you.
I was so happy for her
and I just felt like
she's going to get it together
and she's going to be happy and Tom's
going to help because you come in,
you come into a room and it's just like
you're so funny and you're just like,
Christina is so funny.
You guys together or like I
can't keep up with you guys.
Is this the,
she's really suffering when
you're calm and you're so glad.
I know you am so glad you Christina.
Yeah.
So you've got a better personality then.
I think we all know this.
We all know.
I don't want you guys to fight about it
because you guys are so good together.
How dare you,
Sarah,
and your child is so beautiful. Thank
you. And just petty shit has got to stop.
I'm sorry to, um, I love you guys and, oh,
just burns by the way,
trader.
I can't see us. Do not do that. Sarah,
is she out? She's done. She's dead to me.
Sarah Burns was in a big
little lies recently. Yeah.
She's like, I love you man. That's
her murder. Yeah, yeah. Yes.
Machine that went to, I
know she did that. Uh,
the second seat she does drug history.
You know how wet hot American summer. Yes.
Yes, yes. That's her. She's
just, that was the last thing.
I don't know if it's out
yet though. Yeah. Wow. Well,
I mean I'm usually proud of such my, both
my accomplished friends, Mary Lynn. Uh,
and so yeah.
But not anymore.
I'm going to have to rethink those
friendships and Joe for that matter. Wow.
I like how it shows.
Like does she even have a personality?
I mean these are people just speaking
from the heart. Right. Clearly. I mean,
Sarah's, that was emotional.
It was excruciating.
It was hard for her to say the truth.
Yeah. The truth. Yeah, it was really,
how much did you pay my friends?
Nothing. Nothing. I just,
it's just, it hurts.
Oh,
there's a Midwest 11, Tina. Mommy,
you got the looks good on me though.
John and Kate hair.
Not so far from the road rules,
haircut. I had not that far.
There's just a little cool thing
on top there in the back. Cause I,
Alan gave me that cut back in the
day and it was the exact front,
but not that spike. Would you do that?
Harrigan are no road rules here. Yeah.
Now I'm not cute enough. What do
you mean you're not cute? I mean,
you gotta be 20 to have that
cute ass haircut. Really?
Not as a 40 year. My Mama,
you gotta be young and cute.
I remember that when that show blew up.
John and Kate, I'm talking
about, yes, not rural.
Definitely as somebody with little
interest in women's fashion.
Every time I saw her I'd be like,
the fuck is up. It's so bad. Yeah.
She really, she really trademark that
haircut. That is the Midwestern mom. Yeah.
And her outfits were just super
k Marty like super khaki shorts.
She had eight children. The hair
was inexcusable, inexcusable.
Arable and also a haircut that's
like stay away from my vagina.
Stop fucking me. Patrick made this by.
Thank you. Very nice. Thank you Patrick.
Very nice.
That is a haircut that does repel penises.
The only reason you get that
is to be like, knock it off.
Somebody said this is overwhelming
evidence. God, you're not
mommy. That's not, oh, it's a old
ass picture. Yeah. And guess what?
There's only one person in
this group not wearing jeans.
Look at this. Denim,
denim, denim. This is 1990.
This is, you know, denim.
This is such a weird time.
Those late nineties were beautiful.
Women were really baggy pants. Such a
waste of eye candy. Thank you victor.
And Jonathan's opposed to this seat.
Photo evidence. Tina can't be in Maine.
She's the only one not wearing jeans.
I'm not wearing jeans under those
cargo pay. What are you really? Me?
I'm wearing denim underwear.
You ever thought about that?
Jesus even know what the fuck I
got. Wow. That's really something.
Can we talk about our,
uh,
our romantic shower this morning?
Yeah.
It was big progress from the Hobo or
the infamous Hobo shower. Uh, gosh,
that was over a year ago. No. Yeah, it was
a year ago. We lived in that old house,
another house, the Hobo
shower. You came in,
you started peeing and it smelled
like coffee, coffee, pot, a cough,
just pure coffee. And that's when the
dehydration thing started. Cause I'm like,
dude,
you even drink water because it's hours.
I have coffee and spread the cheeks
clean that burped blue snot rockets.
Yeah. Um, feel like I maybe
farted course she did.
And then I don't know if there
was burps him maybe sexy.
And you know what's funny is that
we haven't showered together since.
Yeah.
It's been a minute.
And this morning you were in the shower
before me and I thought why not try to
spice things up romantic,
you know,
Time Nannies here I get in the shower
with you and I start, you know,
grabbing your cheeks, playing
with you, whatever playfulness,
trying to make our nice
romantic married moment.
And you started blowing your nose.
Yeah.
This is like, I'm trying to
like, hey, let's be playful.
Maybe the sun was somewhere what I was,
I know you're still sick so I'm not going
to force anything here. I was playful.
But then you started to blow your nose
in the shower, your hand in the shower,
and then the part that's really special
with you is that your beard collects all
your boogers. So it's not like the
boogers end up on the shower floor.
They're all in your beard. It's
not okay. I rinsed it off him.
No you don't because you can't see the
bookers rinsing until it goes away.
I had to keep telling you there's
still boogers in your beard.
They still boogers in your beard and
then you kept renting and rents. I got,
I'm going to throw out,
get out of my fucking face.
I had to kick you out and
then you go and then you,
and then you made me wash your asshole
number. Oh we got it. That was Kinda neat.
So I watched her be whole,
like I do Ellis and your beans and stuff,
but then you,
I consider that super progress by the way.
For what?
For the ultimate goal of you playing
with my be whole because I got you.
Yeah.
Cause I got you to kind of run your
finger along it a little bit. You know.
Oh my God, you guys are so disgusting.
Ew. I head up the crack a little bit.
And you did it. Very cursory kind.
Of course. I'm not getting older.
Really get in there like I do for my son.
Yeah, but for you, there's so much hair.
I know that I couldn't find the behold
if I wanted because it's covered.
There's a real wall of
hair and you're cracked.
I need that bottle washer.
We have. Yeah. I'm kind of,
I'm kind of on board with the waxing
now because, yeah, right. Yeah.
I think it's too much hair.
Maybe make an appointment for me.
Will you as the president?
Sure.
From my 40th 41st birthday
for my birthday. My relax.
Your asshole. Yeah. It's bad Tom.
I know there's a lot of hair.
I know. I didn't realize until I put
my hand in there today. I was so happy.
I was like, dude, there's so, it's so
much here. But thanks again for, um,
blowing your nose in the shower.
That was really special.
I didn't fart and I didn't burp.
That's big progress. That's true.
That's true. Yeah. Yeah.
But you'll notice it's been a
year since we showered together.
Think about next year, what's
going to happen a year?
One next year.
Oh Man.
One of the symptoms I had before
was discovered with crones disease.
Interesting. Well, let's just say
I knew something didn't feel right
down there on the crotch. Chile,
Crotchety Coctel Carter my area.
And uh,
anyway, uh, in mid p mid stream,
I hear a very strange sound.
Okay. That emanated from my,
my penis.
Uh,
and the sound,
I the only way to describe this, let me
just demonstrate on paying. I'm paying,
I'm paying, I'm paying,
everything's fine. All the payer,
the fuck was that.
Yeah.
So I stopped paying for
a second, you know, uh,
okay.
I don't know what to do. I was like
almost afraid to start paying again,
but now I'm starting to burn, you know,
cause if you stop yourself men pee,
it's uncomfortable.
Imagine that. And he wasn't
even sure yet though, but yeah,
what's a deal and Homie,
you're here.
Okay.
So you start letting little droplets out.
Then I get up the confidence to lift
that stream flow again and starts to flow
again,
son.
I mean
I freaked out. Yeah. And uh,
because the sound sounded
like it sounded like a fart.
I sounded like a,
a fart
sound was coming from my penis.
That's
bananas. Never even heard of that.
Well, fart sounds out of vaginas.
That's different though because air
is getting pushed into there. Yeah.
How do you fart out of your penis?
Wow. It's Kinda normal for us,
so I can't really, right. But
you understand why that client,
how does the Air Get into Your pee hole?
But that's what we are exactly what
I'm saying. This, this is so strange.
Then I got up early the next morning
to do my morning pee and then the same
fucking thing happened that same.
I'm like,
God man,
I was guy.
So I had to tell someone because I would,
if it was a major medical problem,
I dunno.
So I went into my mom's bedroom
and I tried to explain to her that,
uh, after Ip that there's a
sound that comes out of my deck.
And she asked like,
what kind of sounds and I'm live with
kind of what kind of sounds like a fart
ma.
Jeez, ask them, will
you ever date your mom?
And she said, well, is that normal?
I'm like, I said, I don't know.
I mean, I don't know. I don't know if
it's normal light. You mean the scars?
Farcical Penis. You ever hear of
anyone falling through the penis?
My is anyone. She's like, I don't know.
I don't have a penis. I have a vagina.
I don't, you know what? I forgot
vagina.
So she said, you know, you know,
maybe I'll, um, maybe I'll call Rick,
you know,
a call Ricky's mom.
I'll ask him if it happens to Rick
was one of my friends. I'm like, no,
don't tell anyone here. Of course, Santo
Scott, my brother, don't tell anybody.
This is some crazy shit.
By the way, as a kid, there's gotta be
nothing worse than confiding in a parent.
And they'll like, I'll go call this other
person to tell them all about it. Yeah,
that is the one.
I remember so many conversations.
Can you fucking not telling anybody this?
My Mother did that to me constantly to
the point where I stopped telling her
things, but that's what
happens. Yeah, of course.
So many secrets because she would
constantly backstab tell everybody,
tell my step Dad taught my dad shit
that I don't want people to know.
It's a really bad thing to do as a
parent. I know. It's really fucked up.
I was really annoyed by that is I
have a lot of empathy for this guy,
Scott Scott
boy's penis.
Your penis.
Is that a wrap?
What Bobby? No, nobody. Fuck.
Should it be farther your ass hole.
Next thing I know he comes
running into our room. Todd. Dude,
you're fighting through your Dick Christ.
This is my life.
Yeah, so it was Crohn's disease I guess,
but I still don't know how that happens.
Pre diagnosis. He was farting through
his deck, but how does that happen?
I have no clue.
Sounds Bananas.
The air has to find its way into what?
Your bladder, I don't know. That's,
I mean that pocket of air has to,
in our, there is air in your
bladder that needs to come out.
That's what I'm saying. Right. So either
the air gets in or out, I wouldn't know.
Ears not getting in your Dick Hole,
Ms. Dot. Happening. So air somehow
is seeping into his bladder.
Oof. Okay. Hey. Terrifying. That's, yeah.
Well thanks for playing that. Yeah,
no problem. Can we talk about,
oh, about, um, so for the,
we haven't had a clocks on
both of our bedside tables.
Now what happened was when we lived in
Redondo and you had the alarm clock on
your side of the bed and I never had one
on mine because I didn't have an outlet
near my nightstand. And so I reasoned, my
reasoning was, well, there's no outlet,
I guess I can't have a clock on my
nightstand rather than getting a battery
powered one maybe. Uh, so stupid.
So for years I didn't have one on my
side because I couldn't figure out how,
and then we moved twice since Redondo
did in the last place. We also had
one charger for a phone on one side.
And then one day we had a breakthrough
moment where we said, you know what?
We could plug an extension cord and then
there could be a plug for you on the
other side, and we were like,
wow, this is a really big moment.
She'd extension cord idea was,
you know, there's no outlet there,
but we could put a power source there
through an extension cord. It was a big,
big breakthrough. It took months
and months to put this together
and then that was a thing
where we're like, oh yeah.
Just because that thing's not there
doesn't mean you can't figure out a way to
make it work.
This time
I am constantly asking
you what time it is.
You see me leaning over to see the clock.
I caught you at four in the morning.
You went to take a piss and then you
walked over to my side of the bed and
leaned over me to look at my clock and
that's when it occurred to me. This,
I woke up that morning and I go pour.
Tommy is walking to my side of the bank.
I go,
I know I'll buy him.
His own alarm clock.
And guess what?
I got it.
I can now tell the time on my side
the fuck is wrong with was take us.
And you've been without a side clock
for how long? I mean we're coming up on,
I mean in this home, what, five, six,
seven months or so.
And then in the last place and other
close to a year going on two years where I
don't get to see the time at night
when you want to know is it midnight,
is it three six?
Right.
And
then before that I lived that
way in Redondo every night.
And I wear a watch. But
during the day, at night,
I remember him in Redondo beach going,
why don't we put a clock on the wall
so we can both see it from the bed?
And then like that,
that theory,
just like what is wrong
with us that we both die.
It doesn't encourage you just for, you
know, a few bucks. You can buy a fucking,
you don't have the figure it out.
We have deal with it.
You deal with what you got.
There's a workaround for that.
God Damn it.
How does it feel though?
Like last night was your first night
being able to tell time whenever you want.
Is that crazy? It was really cool. Like
I knew what time I was going to bed,
going to bed now and then you woke
up in the morning and I go, Tom,
what time is it? We're trying to go
six 20 yup. I knew it was awesome.
Felt empowering.
Oh,
hello and welcome to how to
create a perceptual map using x.
So my name is [inaudible] is the worst,
worst hate excel as an alternative.
By the way,
there's nobody more arrogant than
someone that's mastered excel.
They talk about it like, Oh, you
don't know how to make toast.
You just fucking put the bread
and he pressed the button.
Excel is so hard and
they already showed you.
Once God,
you highlight in his control l seven
you had to highlight the column and then
it's the sum of all these things
you can make in minutes and that's
available@sexualmaps.com.
The first thing you need
to flashback made a list of brands,
at least two attributes.
The attributes schooled fuck off.
And if you want to,
this is optional.
Well it's definitely boring,
but you think they would have created
a program more intuitive than excel
because excel is so counter intuitive.
You have to take a fucking
class to learn how to do it.
So how is that a useful program?
It's so hard. It's very hard. God,
I almost fucking flunked
that class every time.
I mean of when did they start teaching us?
Um,
do you remember that when
they started teaching us, uh,
Xcel things,
I was in college and I had to learn it
from my statistics class and my friend
Bronwyn was good at it.
So I paid her in beer to do my homework
because I could not figure out excel.
By the way. Did you see this? That, uh,
Steven Seagal and band of course
people have been sending this to me,
not to stop.
The last time I asked the CIA to
provide me with people in answers,
they gave me people in
answers that my questions
the way they wanted it to be answered.
Me,
the Ukraine has banned Steven Seagal
as a national security threat,
making him the latest of several
cultural figures to be blacklisted.
The Ukrainians Security Service said
it had for bidden Seagal entry to the
country for five years.
Wow.
And a letter published by the new site
apostrophe the services press secretary
later confirmed the band to other media
letter said such as made when a person
has committed socially dangerous
actions that contradict the interest of
maintaining Ukraine's security.
The move comes after the
accuracies citizenship and Russia,
which has backed separatists in a
simmering conflict in eastern Ukraine.
President Putin handed Seagal a Russian
passport and told him that he hoped
their personal relationship will remain
and continue during a meeting in the
Kremlin last year.
So there you have it,
Mr Steven Seagal is no longer
welcome in the Ukraine.
That's a pretty big,
and I am the king of in province for free.
I do forgive you. Good for the Ukraine.
Yeah. Good thinking. Oh, why did,
why does he need Russian citizenship?
I mean, well, he's a Russian, um,
ethnic origins. Yeah. I had no idea.
Well then that makes sense. Yeah.
But it's also because I
think it's a big part,
the big part of it is that in
certain parts of the world,
he still feels like it's 1992. Yes,
baby. Yeah. I know. Eastern Europe,
they still like, fuck man, you
kick a lot people's house. Yeah.
I still get excited by him.
Um,
want to see this woman
speaking of [inaudible].
Oh my guy yet listen to this woman.
Oh Wow.
That's a woman during out karate exhibit,
feeling it,
feeling that shit.
This is awesome.
She's great. I hope she won.
She deserves it for that level.
Why are you screaming like that?
It's not necessary.
It doesn't, it's weird. They don't
tell you to scream like that.
And usually the,
you know,
the funny thing is her screams don't align
with the point of impact was to go to
the, it's like as punchy
as you, as you move.
She's like screaming right
before she moves. Very peculiar.
Timing's off.
It's crazy.
[inaudible]
okay.
All Right Sarah,
this really looks like some bullshit.
Most of these moves.
All Right Sarah, like that doesn't look
like that could kick anybody's ass,
but she, I don't know. I agree.
Cause it's like fucking dancing.
I remember when I took Kung Fu and
then they'd teach you like the dragons,
whatever movements,
you know,
it's really just to say a dance movie.
Five people like that.
They just showed,
I saw a video of like a traditionally
trained MMA guy against some Kung Fu
master. Oh, you don't
want to see it? Oh my God.
The MMA guy just pummeled him and
it was like really bad. It wasn't,
it wasn't cool for guy was like,
you know,
trying to deflect some of it
and the guy just beat him.
Like they had to pull
them off and they're like,
this guy's gonna die if you don't stop
doing this. He was a Kung Fu master,
you know, no match for MMA,
which is what I'm saying that,
well that's the guy obviously
got involved because he's like,
this makes sense. Let's see how
these two schools of fight, you know,
do against each other. It was
bananas. I mean the guy just,
he punched through the guy's ridiculous
deflections and just fucking beat him,
beat him, beat him on the ground and just
kept pummeling him and it's like, um,
okay. I think we know, which is
the better. All right, thank you.
You know, you far through your
asshole, you know what I mean? Yeah.
That's the whole point I think.
Yeah. A Dad boner fishing,
what's going to happen to that classic
gets 10 pounds. I just made up my,
I just made up my deference
at the windows 10 pounds.
I just made up the difference
Mark Zola.
Okay, okay. Yeah. That's
a deadbolt or, yeah.
But again, I feel like, you know,
it makes sense why he's excited.
He was obviously behind, like he was
like this is making, in other words,
he probably caught something earlier.
It wasn't as big.
He won whatever competition
he's in. Yeah. So you know,
I celebrate his Dad Boehner ranch with
them too. I like those sporty glasses.
Those are always a real dad
fashion move and sexy. Right.
Definitely the multicolored shiny,
the rope. Oakley only with the rope.
Yeah. You gotta have the rope. How's
the fishing? You got to have the rope.
That's what, that's why you wear them,
you know, cause you're fishing. Yeah.
Because they could fall off. That's
right. That's the road I'm saying.
I like the dads who were at just
like walking around near port.
That's what I'm saying.
It's awesome cause he doesn't want,
dad doesn't want to lose it. But on
the boat it makes the most sense. Yeah.
But it's cooler when you carry
it off the boat. Certainly.
I also like the dads who put the
glasses in front of like on their chest.
Like you were him backwards.
You let him hang on. I'm sorry.
You let them hang backwards on your back.
So the back shirt. Yeah. Yeah. Like you,
they talk them into the back. You
can see that. Yeah. That's Kinda,
I wasn't even thinking or if
you want to go to the Guy Fieri,
that's what I put them on the back
of your head. That's what I'm saying.
Glasses facing backwards guy
kind of patented that move. Yeah.
Really sexy look.
Yeah.
Yeah. The real dad reaction right there.
Seriously. Um, let's see here. Seriously,
seriously. Uh, let's see.
Guy Fieri, you know what?
A douche bags on glasses. So
that's kind of what, like,
I don't have anything against
Guy Fieri personally, of course,
but as an aesthetic, it's a really douche
bag here. It is authentic, right? Yeah.
Yeah. Isn't it? So see how it
puts them on. That's crazy.
The back of this. Yeah. It's like, he's
like the poster boy for a douchebag.
Just aesthetically. I mean, again,
I don't know him as a person,
but the whole vibe is like, I'm
a fucking, I know it's weird,
right? That he embraces the Douche
bag. Look, I think, you know,
that's just who he is. Right? And
I, and also, here's the weird thing,
when you want to talk about this, this
whole thing has really worked for him.
Yeah. No, he's, he's
really successful. I mean,
that's why I'm not shitting on the
guy, but as the look, the look is like,
and I think, I don't know if
this is true or not, but I heard,
please tell me this is true.
He has a car collection,
um,
where they're all like the same color.
Are they all fire like fire print?
I'm sure he likes flames.
All yellow bright. Yeah. It's like,
it's a real attention seeking color.
Yeah. He needs a lot of attention. Yeah.
So here you see like an old
corvette. Yeah. More recent corvette.
There's the flames, like I
said, yeah, there's the flames
on everything. Wrangler,
there's a Camaro back there,
a big pickup. What is this?
Here are some dodge maybe.
Yeah.
Fire Ozek look at his car collection.
I can't believe he makes that much money
on that show. It's amazing, isn't it?
Yeah. Oh good for him. I mean, that's
great. That's great. But man, it,
it's totally him to have them all
in yellow. Yeah, it's a douchebag.
I'm definitely really
weird men.
Really bizarre that he would have
that many fucking yellow cars.
You think that like one yellow would
kind of be part of it would be your
collection,
right?
You'd be like, I got one yellow.
Great. You want to, I mean, I,
you think you'd want to vary it
justice to be like, I've got a,
a red corvette. I've got the Yellow
Hummer. I've got whatever. Dammit.
What a fucking check. Yeah. We should
tell him how to collect his cars.
We should tell them it's up to us.
I want you to start reaching out to
guy and can you please play the flight
attendant? Oh yeah, yeah, yeah. So you
sent me this, uh, audio file. This is,
um, well, why don't you set it up?
While I was flying back home from Bart
next and I noticed that the woman doing
the rules, the FDA, whatever has
the FDA food, Drug Administration,
Faa, I'm reading the rules, safety stuff.
She was really mushy mouth and marveled
and she wasn't pronouncing the words
they all jumbled together.
So I recorded her and at first
like really weird sounds normal.
But then as you start
listening you're like, oh yeah,
like she's just kind of like right.
Oh for us is and then with their mouse
to use the mouse Cutler customer advisors
here that supplemental
oxygen is no longer needed.
A Volvo, Volvo, Volvo
sausage of gender.
The laboratories are held in a plastic
retainer clip to use the mouse,
take the of the mouse out of its plastic
retainer clip and breathe normally.
What was the burden Laurel?
Yeah,
we have meant to him a water line in
your seat on a Christian is be careful.
It is learning as a
flotation device to use it,
pull it up and take it right to the
nearest usable exit when exiting the
aircraft, your arms to
the shops. I get to yet
tell you what's going on here. This
is my theory. This vicious sick. Yeah,
reading that thing.
Yes.
And she also knows by law
she has to read it. Yeah.
So her feeling is,
let me just get through this thing as
fast as possible because she's not a slow,
she's, what she is doing is she's reading
it really fast. Yeah. She's not stopping.
We're sentences and commas over it.
She's just like [inaudible] and
so she's running through it,
but also this other role is full time.
You know what happens is like if she
doesn't even pronounce some syllables,
she still gets through it faster. Oh
yeah. First thing is like finished
fucking thing
and felt life Vassar located in a former
cabinet in the event of a water line
and your fight isn't over in the
adult. No pause. Permission Card.
New parents exercise for this aircraft
they made north or to enter in our
service are directly across from us for
additional emergency exits are located
over the wings. Mid Cabin to any side. X
designs are already identify these axes,
nihilism Rosie escape mouth finding or
if we were to those lights to the nearest
exit, keeping them on an exit.
Maybe looking at blogs by the way,
definitely has some Vogel from Megan and
I have been together for nearly three
years. I will say sense. What's a
blocker done? Instructions for about,
about your crew.
Regulations prevent you from tampering
with disabling or destroying the smoke
detectors for two laboratories. There's
no urban of boats, American loud.
Because what happens is some
of them can understand her.
I think some of them it's their
time to shine. In other words,
the performers and they say exits
are located in above the wings,
right and rear and the
front of the aircraft.
Take a moment now to look around and
locate the nearest exit. And they,
they, they read it like they're,
they're reading southwest.
We used to do the jokes like in
the event of a crash landing,
of course there won't be one
like that. That dumb shit.
I fucking hate the joke reading due to,
I don't need to be entertained,
but I do need you to
enunciate a little bit.
I mean that was just marbled
mess next to me going
to good one. Really, really
fun to really ham it up.
I guess they stopped doing that.
Uh, used to be a lot fun. You know,
they still do it.
They laugh and then a number,
they throw the peanuts down the aisle on.
The plane is on an incline on and I'm,
they go turn off your cell phones,
your blackberries or
blueberries or strawberries.
That's a sound.
You hear people like that really,
really
laughing it up. That blueberry job
that, that left with the black dice.
Whenever you're a comedian and you, you
have moments of self doubt, you're like,
am I funny? Am I, is it
worth what I'm doing? Yeah.
Go on one of those southwest flights.
Watch people laugh at those stupid fucking
instructions at the flight attendant
does and then you'll walk away like I'm
one of the funniest fucking people world.
Yeah,
right.
That'll give you all the confidence you
need to have somebody do a fucking a
seat belt joke about,
make sure if you don't know,
I can come over and I'll click it
on four and you just pull like this.
You don't click it over your head.
I can over your waist.
Can you hear people
like that on the plane? You're
like, you know what? Yeah,
I'm funnier than this compared to this
dummy. I have to interrupt real quick.
A call just came in,
don't know what it says,
but I feel like it's worth, I think
you're a liar. No, I'm serious.
I don't know what this is.
I think I know what it is.
It,
it's burned again.
It's some kind of eating me up since
I left you that message last week. I,
um, you know, I've been thinking
about it and honestly I don't,
I haven't known you as long as Christina,
so
I haven't known her you as long as her.
So like I'm just thinking
about it and I'm like, well,
I've known you for a couple of years
and you've been very charming. And
I think I love the time and you know,
I'm,
there's nobody in a world that's better
suited for each other than you and
Christina and you know,
I'm not knocking your personality,
but I was like, wait a second. It's
like the law of averages, you know,
a known her for a million years and she's
been consistently amazing and awesome
and she's been such a good friend to me.
I can't call you up on the
phone and tell you that
you guys better personality
because Christina, she's like,
she's so quick and she's so generous
and she's so bright and silly.
And then sometimes she says something
like, Hey, my brain was like that.
So I'm calling because,
well,
I don't even like being this to this
and the honestly, because I feel like,
you know,
like very difficult.
It's been very emotional and
must a message in my first
thought was like, shit,
I should have just kept my
mouth shut. And then so, okay,
so I'm calling because I want
to change changed eight. You,
Christina has the better personality.
That's that.
I don't know actually. No, I think,
I think,
I don't know.
This is so difficult.
No,
it's Christina. No, let's do, I dunno.
Um,
you better him.
She did have some doubt though.
That's got to feel good.
Does she felt a little bit of doubt about
what are you paying my friends not pay
him anything. Don't even know
Mary Lynn, especially Mary Lynn.
She heard about it and when I started the
store she goes, oh, uh, heard about the,
the personality salmon ship. She was your
hands down. She did. And she did. She did.
I'm going to have to do my research.
She's 100% said that whatever.
I'm going to have to call these
friends. Yup. That top dog laugh.
I love so much. His blonde joke labs. Yup.
Does that bum you out that your dad thinks
that stuff so funny and you're like,
you're like the best working
comic out there. And he's like,
I love those blind joke buddy
is like the best. Do you know the
world? But I of course you are.
But he, um, I of course, God, I
had this conversation with people.
Well,
I mean we've talked about it,
but I talked to other people all the time
about how I met with this great writer
last week and he was
telling me how he wrote it.
I don't want to divulge all these things,
but basically he wrote an amazing episode
of television that is really highly,
you know, celebrated and it's
really smart and really funny.
And His dad was like,
I didn't know what you're doing.
And His dad, his dad's a
successful smart guy, but field.
But then his dad told him about the bore
at scene where he brings the poop down
the stairs. He goes, now, that's right.
Right.
And he's like,
you don't think that this
like Emmy nominated thing I
wrote? No. It was like, no,
but see that's why you're
in comedy. Yeah, of course.
If your parents approved
of you, yeah, you'd have,
there'd be nothing compelling you to
tell jokes to strangers and get that.
Of course,
you got to get it somewhere.
You got to get it an eight
from your folks. I know, I
know. Man. It crazy. You know.
Could you imagine who you would be if
your mom and dad approved of you? You,
we certainly wouldn't have this
show. No. Why would you do it?
There'd be no reason.
Yeah.
To cultivate a personality to go out there
for 15 years after week in the clubs.
I know amongst my dad.
Yeah. So I can shape something and
I'm not talking about a blonde joke,
I'm saying within my wheelhouse. I know
what kind of thing would make him laugh,
but every once in a while I'll lob out a,
I genuinely think this is funny.
Let me see if you do think it's funny.
I thought never. No silence.
Total silence. Yeah.
And then like, I'll be like, do you, he
goes away. I have never mind. I'll like,
I'll read them. I'll say,
I said this about this,
right? Yeah, I will. Because
you're like, oh yeah, so,
uh, I was talking to your mother and he'll
just, I'm like, wow. I get bombs so hard.
He's still, it just doesn't, it's
not, it's never going to be the thing.
It's never going to be it.
Well,
you know what?
Thank God for it.
Otherwise we wouldn't have the life
we have today. Of course. Thank God.
Our plane. I got on a proof. I've
got a big thing this weekend.
I'm going back to Oregon. He had a
bad bike. Got a bad bite this weekend.
I'm going back to Oregon, Oregon, I
think. Oregon, Oregon, Oregon, Oregon.
That's a good one.
Um,
and I'm doing two shows in blue,
Jean,
otherwise known as Eugene.
Goat go ducks, uh, Oregon.
And then Portland. I'm
back there. Glenn. Uh,
I believe the early shows,
I know the early show in Portland
is this sold out at revolution hall.
There's still tickets
left to the late show,
which I think is at 10 30 revolution
hall Saturday night. Uh, Eugene,
Oregon.
I'm there Friday night and there are
still tickets left to the late show.
I'm there with Ryan sickle cells.
Sickler so if you want to come see us,
we're going to both be there.
Um, all four shows ooze.
Additionally, I'm coming
to Tucson, Arizona.
That's toxin. Then Reno, Nevada,
Reno is what re Chico p p.
Um,
and then the Macula to a casino.
See Macula. Um, and then I go,
I'm in the deep dirty.
I'm in, uh, Richmond,
Virginia Beach, Virginia
genes borough, North Carolina,
Asheville,
North Carolina and Charles come,
got South Carolina. It's
just a lot online. Uh,
and then I also have, oh, I'm
coming to Montreal. Canadia oh,
I'm coming to Montreal right
before I go to Wilmington,
Delaware.
And I also go to Hampton beach
and finally balls and whores,
Maryland, Baltimore, the city that reads.
Then optimum Straya and of course a
live podcast with my blue Jean on,
uh,
August 20 what gene?
I don't know. August
23rd. In addition to that,
we have added two more alive podcasts
in Irvine on separate months from vine
burned by separate months.
Here's why.
A tough to make it go all the time.
So we just added them a few months apart.
We're doing one July
9th that's on sale now.
And another one, we're doing it
a click on this here. October,
October eight which is obviously
a long way away, but we've,
we've added them already.
So July 9th and October 8th there's
7:00 PM shows at the Irvine Improv.
We're going to do a live podcast.
I'm hiring sound engineers
to come record know.
And that's another one that we're like,
why don't we have a clock next to our bed?
We should be hiring.
I know that was a w we learned our lesson.
So those will be,
they'll sound a lot
different than the last time,
but also there'll be a lot of
fun to come to the live show. Um,
Jean Blue Jean Jean.
I am May 19th and 20th and June dork.
Teddy's at Gotham.
Come on your club June
1st through third Denver.
[inaudible] Dong Dong Qvar at the calm,
calm Commonworks comedy works downtown.
She's June 16th and 17th
man friend disco at the punch.
Ryan Kennedy Crab.
Come see me tickets@thousandranch.com
spelled out.
Thank you for everybody who has already
come see me has been really, really fun.
You guys are very encouraging that it,
that's it.
And then those live dates you said,
you know what I'm saying? You feel me?
I'm talking about Oh yeah,
I know exactly what you mean.
Go to a thousand ranch dotcom and buy
some tickets to see those big mushy
purples.
I love how he says mushy
purple proposal. Hunches. The PR.
Yeah, it's a good mushy purples.
Um, money. This has been in
my, the thing here for a while.
It says a weird MMA interview.
I'm not sure what's going on.
I don't know the details,
but we can watch whatever this is.
Let's see. Does Dean, the president,
fat TV and we're here at Jagan
House and I'm here with Matt Major.
Okay. Matt looks maybe like you
should be 51 50 or something.
Right. And also your opponent. Non Binary.
Uh, I prefer not to know
anything about my opponent. Okay.
I guess that's what motivates
you in the [inaudible].
Let me tell you what motivates me.
What motivates me is staying in the dark
tunnel. Okay. I stay in a dark tunnel.
Cause when you were in the darkness,
you can't see shit anyway.
What fucking difference does it
make to know who this man is?
Right. I get it. Is
that eye shadow? It is.
That's why I was thinking it might be
a Zimmer [inaudible] situation. So, um,
that if, uh, I don't know what your
opponent's going to expect from you.
I don't know what to expect from you.
Uh, but what, what school do you find it?
Format? I find the dark tunnel. Hey,
starts on. No Man. That's kind
of scary. Yeah, that's right.
That's a good analysis.
Yeah.
So
this kinds of stuff in the dark little,
do you know what to do? You know what?
The beavers and the holes are
zoinks this guy was reportive
of committing a horrific crime.
It would not be that surprising,
right? Yup. Yeah. Yup.
If you were a snake and you were in a
tunnel on the hole and a big fat beaver
came in,
there were two books,
sharp teeth were there
with just flew through yas.
You think you're going to make it
out of here? I don't think so. Matt.
I'm the beaver in a hole.
Oh dear. Yeah. It's a chemical imbalance.
See how much funnier though Kevin Weeks
is talking about taking a nap. Yeah.
It's different. Yeah.
Cause this is not, see,
he's not aware of his world. Right. You
gotta stay grounded for it to be funny.
It's true. He need to have one
foot in the door of reality.
So how do you see this fight ending?
It's not that I see an ending.
I don't ever want it to
end. Oh, for it to begin.
Oh, you're, this guy is smiling
and you're fucking terrified.
I don't know nothing about
this guy either right now.
So it's kind of a scary thing.
So, uh, yeah, my prediction.
Other deer grass. Don't ask any more
questions. The rapture. Oh, Christ. Okay.
I predict that the vampire aliens going
to get in the middle of this whole thing
going to be like, we don't
want the priority is on, on.
Okay.
Wow.
I am the reason for it all the
reason why silver side his ass down.
He doesn't want to burn in hell.
He's either acting like humble your
ass mother fucker. Any last words?
Thank you so much for me. This
opportunity. That's hilarious.
A lot of people don't want
to give me an opportunity man
fucking free.
I don't know why
I'm a bit scared of myself,
man.
That's hilarious. Yeah. So Matt,
Major Bella, Taller fighter, uh,
reputation and one of
the strangest men see,
can't tell if it's a performance
or if he's generally the strange.
I want to see if since the
time this has happened, if, um,
anything with this guy, I mean, I
don't know anything about him. Matt.
Let's see.
Major seems real.
I don't know. I shadows
a nice touch too. Yeah,
that's what I'm saying. Like you
can be playing a role, you know,
possibly interesting choice.
Uh,
what does say this interview with
homeless MMA fighter is really weird.
Okay.
There you go.
So fucking a man say
no more and that major,
not actually reading the posts on our
next door app about the homeless guy and
is under carriage by the bank.
The white people around here who were
real freaked out by him. Yeah. And it's,
by the way, that next door
thing, someone got me onto that.
It's super fucking just racially
motivated. People are just like,
there's a black guy driving.
It's kind of depressing when
you start like, cause you,
what they do is they build up and then
you can like see them and they're always
black Saab Brownish guy and you're like,
okay,
okay.
Either that or it's really benign like
raccoons or eating trash in my yard.
Anybody having trouble with the wind?
Right.
But then there was that really funny
one that you shared. The Black Guy,
a black guy wrote, he's like, ah, I'm new
in the neighborhood. I am black. It'd be,
see me walking around, I like to get
fresh air from time to time. Yeah. Yeah.
No need to post. Yeah. It's like good
one dude. Yeah. Cause they'll be like,
there was a guy sitting in his car and uh,
not doing anything but he was black.
Just a heads up.
They'll phrase it, you
know, they'll, they'll,
they'll try to make it sound like
they're not being scared. Yeah.
But they'll be like,
uh,
African American males were just deriving
and then not even doing anything.
They're just driving. Just, I
don't know if anybody's seen them,
but they're in a white car
and they're just driving like,
what's the story though? The drove. Yes.
Silly silliness. There's nothing going
on guys in the neighborhood. Nothing.
Not a fucking thing. Nothing
to report. All right, Jean,
we should run j e a n s no,
as it's singular is right.
It is a, do you want to hear,
um,
I think we already did Chinese eyes,
British accent, that song.
That's yesterday's news.
Gotten to come and those farts, dude.
All right. I think we played that one.
You nasty but DJ. Huh? I don't know.
There's a bunch of songs, but I don't
know which one's been played. Uh,
pushes theme. Oh my gosh. Pushes theme.
That's you push.
You want to hear that?
All right. Thank you guys for listening.
Don't forget to go to your mom's house,
podcast.com a thousand
ranch.com check out the blog.
Oh yeah, yeah. A blue band posted a behind
the scenes. He did a really good job.
It's fantastic blog of the last of those
Irvine shows we did a couple of months
ago. And um, it's really cool. He did
a job. You get to see how we get ready,
what we do before and after shows.
Yoshi, a special interview with him.
It's really good. It's on the, uh,
some of the youtube page. All right,
thanks guys.
See you next week.
Wow.
Big words.
They love to,
to chatter.
You're going to get stabbed.
It's crazy.
I didn't make it up.
And that's when he's saying.