Well go to your mom's house,
Christina Vincent.
All right, here we are
here we farm. Here we go.
Here's the thing.
You left that the other way
anymore
any more and just do it like we
always do. It wasn't so much to ask.
Okay.
Anything else? Can you eat
your sandwich or something? No,
you can just do the minimum. Oh
my God, I did everything else.
I put in all of the things
I did the lighting. Okay.
Don't act like I don't do it all
good. I don't do it all. I do lots.
You want to do it all?
Hello?
Do you have anything you want to point
out to our listeners? Know why? What?
What's the big deal? Well, you
said you, what's happening?
There's nothing going on.
You said you guys and messages.
I said that I read the comments on our
youtube channel and some people are
saying that I look pregnant and
you know, that's very rude. Um,
especially cause those
mother fuckers are right.
Number two.
Number two,
thug is incubating right now
as you call him. It's a boy.
It's a boy. It's a boy.
Number two. So yeah,
we're in second trimester and I had to
hide it this whole time and now you can
just let it out like, oh my
God. And there is so big,
my milkers are so big and
everything is so big right now.
You're trying to cover them up.
Pointless. I got lucky though because our
cars are,
um,
the holidays as when I had my first
trimester. I got pregnant in October,
so I got to be kind of sick and on the
downlow outside of all the cameras,
which was nice.
But then I couldn't hide it.
The last two weeks I've been wearing
sweatshirts. You have seen the comments.
I've seen him too. That's
up. Look pregnant. I know.
And with your second child,
apparently you show way quicker and I
was showing like at five weeks I felt fat
as shit already. So. Well,
it's exciting. Very exciting.
Number over to [inaudible] number two,
two thugs in the house.
Now what are we going to name this
one? When are you thinking? Well,
we fucked up on the last one because we
were going to go with a Ruth's Chris.
Tom's Ruth's Chris.
Tom's Ruth's Chris and then called junior.
Well because I ate so much
of it. Yeah. With Ellis,
we should've named him Carl's junior.
Now this one I know was also
a fan of daily time daily.
I think that's a really good name
for it. The Sun. That's a good one.
But this baby I've really been craving.
So
I was thinking Domino's, Domino's
or domino. We're about thin crust.
Oh cause that's what I'm,
my jam right now is thing.
Crest domino. Thank crest extra
cheese and pepper. Tony's on there.
The domino sounds kinda like a cool name.
Like it was no sub domino.
Our blanket. I like blanket
blanket blanket like Mike. Yeah,
nobody's named domino. That'd
be really original. Great Name.
But yeah,
Carl's Jr we're going to go and have his
name legally changed to Carl's Jr and
then this one we're going to do
dominant. I leg it. Well, uh,
there's a lot to cover.
Um,
we'll talk about all this stuff and
the naming of our second thug and more.
Let's get the show started and
let's keep it a fun, you know,
mean people's main concern. Obviously
when, when we had a kid last time,
they're like,
oh,
he's having a kid going to make you
squares or make you know, more fun.
And Joey Diaz was very
worried that I might become a
woman. Don't become a woman,
become a woman. He said. So I hope
that never happened. That was my wife.
I hope you stay and not a woman.
Yeah.
I'm gonna cut my hair off with this
one though. Here we go. Jane started.
Let's get the party started.
Okay.
And I just wanted to share with all
of you why I felt the need to share me
placing menstrual blood all over my face
and what power it holds for us as women
earn these products that we've
been shaming for so many lifetimes,
period.
Blood on the face to add a pretty raw,
pretty nasty people,
by the way. Thank you.
A lot of people have messaged me that
they watched my new special disgraceful on
Netflix over the weekend.
I've got,
I really received a between comments and
emails and the thousands of messages.
So I thank you all for them. Uh,
much love, no hate f all the haters,
but uh, it's been, well,
I still have no, hey,
overwhelming people telling me that
I'm nasty as hell. I'm the next champ.
Yeah, no, that's, there's no way.
You're the nasty champ. Yeah.
Oh
No,
no, no, no, no. Everybody was
telling me, they're like, it's funny.
You're nasty as hell. You still
grossed you nasty. Yes. Listen,
I've been nasty supreme of this household.
No Way.
You've even attacked me for
being so nasty. You're like,
you're telling me how nasty I am
with my farts and like how I'm just,
I talk and think. Just
disturbed to crave things. Yeah.
But that's at our home life. But on
stage I would say the, I'm the Nastier
and I'm way Nastier than,
but you're a woman, you know?
But that's why it makes more of an impact.
I'm even nastier register as an impact,
but I'm definitely aware of the crowd.
You're the nasty champ. That's some
bull shit right there. True. No,
I am the nasty champ. Everybody asks you
in bed last night. Oh, you were like,
have you ever heard of this?
The scrum Gob Gobbler the chumps smuggler?
No.
What I asked you was, do you know,
do you know what a ball hog is? Yeah.
Okay. So it's a sports term. In sports,
if you play basketball or soccer and
somebody won't pass the ball there,
a ball hog, like they're hogging the
ball right there. They're not sharing,
they're not passing it around.
They're keeping it all to themselves.
So they're called a ball hog and I
found that term being exploited by a
different industry.
Hi.
And I'm Blah
[inaudible]
stupid.
How come that wasn't the opening class?
How'd you pass out or menstrual blood
lady? I wanted to save it for you.
She nasty, nasty champ, not us.
I love that they took, I love when
they take an innocent sport's term,
like your Bhag, share the ball.
They turned it into a vile,
perverted slang.
It's just such a, another silly porno
Yang, like there's no woman on the plant.
And really maybe there's like two fucking
freak shows out there and they're like,
I love balls. I got to have
them. I'm out. I'm a ball.
If this is such a fucking dumb fantasy,
it's such a not why. It's hilarious.
No,
and really does nobody know.
I love sucking on Fox
and they have a whole series.
Oh yeah.
Hi,
I'm Payton Lafferty Lafferty.
That sounds like a Peyton Manning,
so you have to like hate and last
day they have to say their name.
They have to say that they're a ball hog
and then they have to just suck balls
for like these whole things.
Dude, it is easy money.
There's a lot of funny ball talk,
you know?
Oh fuck.
Lot of vocal fry balls are funny though.
They're funny. The problem with balls,
there's a, there's a smell sometimes
if they're not clean enough,
but other than that balls
are pretty low maintenance.
Sniff, sniff. Okay. Now let me
put it right up against your eye.
Bat your eyelashes.
There's like five people on the planet
that really had this. They were like,
put your eyelashes against my balls.
Yeah, it's not a lot. Are you into that?
No, not really. I should
try it out. You know,
we got to put this one aside for
doctor drew the ball worship,
make it make a drew list. True. Um, me.
Oh, the trial. So my show,
I watch your show and I just get,
that's what drew basically told us.
This is the sad ever
piss on me. Beat me black guys.
Do you think you could ever be
girl
on the com? Yeah, he's got to rub his
balls on the, come down and give a shit.
Here's the thing,
man.
Anything that doesn't involve
come on my face or getting an STD.
Nothing can happen from
putting big deal man. I mean,
what's the going rate for something
like, I mean not, not as, not as me now.
Oh as like a comedian and mother
of almost two children. Oh,
I've millions, millions but
light. It's going to ruin my life.
It's not possible.
You're short on that and I don't care
if my life is in the toilet for the rest
of it. The rest of it. Yeah. Like I
pushed the ball scene out of that.
Let's just say, yeah, like
20 years ago. I'm just, who
cares? I'm gonna ruin my life.
Yeah, let's just have one of
those girls. Like it's just,
it's never gonna happen for me.
Yeah.
I do a ball scene for like $1,500
that's not, that's not bad.
I think you're asking you for a little
much. I think they would probably be like,
get out of here.
That's you're not,
you're not doing it ruining my life for
1500 care about that part. They're like,
this is a ball scene. Just balls.
But here's what I would do.
Being the entrepreneur that I am,
I would,
I would open up my own website
and I would be the ball girl.
Oh, you know what I mean? I would,
I would make it and I do the eyelash on
the balls and I had to put my feet on
the balls. Like I'd be the ball
queen is how I would do it. You know,
I'd make a business out of it.
That's pretty good.
And I charge guys to come over and then
I'd smashed their balls or whatever.
Making House calls. That's extra money
though cause I've already ruined my life.
I'm the ball 80 for the rest of it. So
I really gotta yeah, I gotta try it out.
What would you do? Well now that
I want to be the entrepreneur,
I think like go back 20 years and I go uh,
if I could go back
in time and be like I don't want the
life that I have now I want to go down to
the CD path. Then I would start
my own site called a Gargle,
my balls.com and like you're thinking and
then I would be like into camera like,
hey it's me.
You know which one are you dumb hookers
out there with sucking my balls. So many.
And then some girl would
walk in and be like,
I would like sniff my balls.
Get your nose in there.
Yeah,
that's a different life
path. Right. As I was saying, if you
really want to throw it in the toilet,
but you got to think in terms
of branding and long term,
I think it's a good brand to get into.
I think so. It's a niche market. Yeah.
I think there's a lot
of people would be like,
it was pretty interesting lane here and
maybe there's some awards. I don't know.
It's not that bad. But the farting,
that's not bad either. The fart videos.
Easy money. Really. If all the genres, um,
the FARC videos the easiest.
Yeah. There's got to eat food.
Fucking dude fart all day.
Every day. That's right.
You didn't imagine being pregnant.
I do. The pregnant lady stuff.
Even better money.
That's when I really jack up the prices.
Yeah. Yeah. A lot of fun. Nope.
Seems like we have a fun new
lane to explore with the balls.
It's not bad. It's not
bad at all. Try it out.
Try it out. Try it out. Go have fun.
You'll trust first fun stuff out. So
back to period, blood on your face.
Um, what about this video?
Would you ever make that video?
Which video would you make? Um, which
one is more harmful to you? You think?
Oh fuck.
I mean it's you
20 cause it menstrual blood on it cause
I think that one would tell people it's
different signals you're sending.
One of them is like,
I mean we haven't even seen this yet,
but she says I smear period of my, um,
I think that would tell people you're
mentally ill and then the ball one might
just be like, oh she's, she needed
money. She's desperate. She's sad.
Well it's the, would she rather,
it's the word you placed a shame.
It's the original.
What'd you rather,
would you rather masturbate in
front of your family or you,
am I going to assume responsibility
and be mentally ill or
I can't believe I'm thinking this,
but I think I'd rather there's a
ball video of you exist then period.
Blood because period blood on your face.
Yeah.
You can't really explain that one.
Explain it. There's no going back.
Let's hear her.
Explain it.
Three reclaiming the blood and through
reclaiming our menstrual cycle. Yeah,
fully allowed me to embody like everything
that I was fully allowed me to have
the freedom to be able to express
who I was in every way. This,
you know this thing about,
Oh hey, oh, Gilmartin's here.
This is not how this is supposed
to go. All right, let's stop.
All right,
so, uh, we re settled, um,
and you want to introduce our
guests with us? Is that fantastic?
Paul Gil Martin from the, uh, mental
illness. Happy Hour, Clara for Paul.
I mean, that's the how we do this. Well,
how do you do just awkward silence?
That's usually it is.
And then, and then, uh,
you guys have done each other's podcasts.
He's been a guest on that deep, Bro.
I've been a guest on
his show and I thought,
why not have them on your mom's house?
This is a perfect fit. It don't, you know,
I invited myself. No, no, not
true. Yes. I said, you know,
if you, if you ever need gas,
I'd love to do your podcast.
So No, I'm happy you're here.
I learned my lesson spending
last year alone on Christmas Eve,
Christmas and my birthday. You know,
want to be stubborn. BEACOPP yeah.
When you have needs speak up.
I think I've been stubborn about that
shit more times than I'd like to admit in
my life about like, nope,
I'll just stay here and,
and I'll just show everybody by staying
here. It's not saying what I want.
Right. Yeah. And I can't be
rejected. Yeah. And I get
to know my video game. Yeah,
exactly. Maybe I'll find a
new porn clip there. Hey,
I'll get an APP and we have a,
we were just playing this porn clip called
ball hogs. Um, it's a familiar with it.
Um, well there's a, a line of, uh, I mean,
you're familiar with the term
ball hog in terms of sports. Yes.
Somebody who won't pass the ball.
Right.
So there's a series adult
series called ball hogs.
It sounds like this.
All right.
Hi,
I'm Sierra and I'm Bala.
Well, they just really like balls. Um,
here's something that you will
never hear about pornography.
Somebody watching it.
I wish the sound was more graphic.
Yeah. Yeah. More detailed, more
s, more smacking and drooling,
a lot shows up, pillows, balls.
We were talking about the ball clip and
then we switched to this woman who is,
um,
she was explaining how she's trying to,
what does it like recapture her family.
There's this whole thing about shame, uh,
in a, uh, when it comes to
women's menstrual cycles.
And so some women like to reclaim their
menstrual cycle and that's what she's
doing.
Yeah,
yeah.
Do it.
Reclaiming the blood through a private
link reclaiming our menstrual cycle.
It fully allowed me to embody
like everything that I was,
it fully allowed me to have the freedom
to be able to express who I was in every
way.
I gotta say one of the things I'm
happy about what she did and what she's
talking about is fucking gross, but it's
nice that she's attractive. It helps.
If it was like somebody gross doing
it, I'd be like, this is really nice.
That's a really shallow thing to say,
but it's actually really true. Yeah.
If she weren't hot,
we would
all be more like not watch all the clips.
We would stop and be like,
she's really gross. I,
I've only seen five
seconds with this cliff.
But the first thing that comes to my
mind is she's desperate for auditions.
I think she's one to go in.
Do you think supposed to be a
ball hog or like a real active?
All the boobs don't look natural.
No, no. Extremely made up for it.
So it's like if you're going to do
the whole menstrual blood thing,
why not not wear makeup?
You know why not be completely
stripped down completely as you,
I'm not saying be naked,
but be as you are completely right like
your vagina and match naturally for the
full,
the full effect.
That is a very interesting point
that she's doing like this.
I'm connected to who I am.
I couldn't be more done up and it looks
like fake boobs. I could be wrong.
I mean, Hey, wait a minute.
Isn't that why she needs to
reclaim her natural essence?
Maybe she is so disconnected because
of the fake blueberry and all this. No,
this is like a whole other level. I didn't
think we were going to get to, come on,
come on.
By putting these up on social media,
I really found it just kind of gave an
invitation to people to be able to know
that it's okay to share
this part of yourself. No,
that's not the message at all.
There are some things you
shouldn't share with social media.
One of them would be willing to face,
you know,
I'm a little ashamed of the
noises I make when I Shit,
but I dunno if I want to try to
ease the public into accepting that.
Well maybe,
but maybe what she's talking about here
is you taking that leap and knowing that
you know what you should be.
Okay.
And how about you posting one of those
videos of you taking a Grunty Shit? Yeah.
And, and, and kind of knowing that
it's okay. Paul, you're a person.
I love the word guarantee.
Why?
Why this insistence that everybody be
comfortable with everything publicly.
Now I don't show a little
bit of shame in your game.
Just a little a is fine.
I don't think a lot of us feel invisible
in our lives. Like something's missing.
Like there's something special about us
that isn't being recognized and we just
need to find what that is. And then
the emptiness will be filled. Yeah.
So her specialness is, or period
is what you're saying. Yeah,
and probably because nobody else
has done that. So it's like, oh,
like the episode I was listening to
where you guys were talking about possum
possum guy in purple lady
and Michael's arts and crafts.
Like the people that find their
identity through, yeah, yeah, yeah.
There's a lady at the coffee shop I go
to who is hat lady and her hats like,
like if it was this, it was the set
of a James Cameron movie, her hat,
you would go by, they put a little
too much effort into it. It's,
it's the most ornate crazy,
it's a nativity scene on,
on a person's head and each one's
different and God bless her, you know,
if that makes her happy to do that.
But I think it has the opposite effect.
When people look at it, they
go, oh, she's, yeah, yeah,
yeah. That's exactly it. Am I going to,
I guess we were having the discussion if,
if she had to choose between being
one of the ball hog girls, right.
Or the menstrual blood lady,
who would you rather be?
And I think it's like,
it's do you want to own being like crazy
kind of crazy or if you're the ball you
can be like, well they kind of did
it to me. You know what I mean?
Like I've been to,
and it was a money thing.
Maybe I did this for a living when I was,
cause I actually think that like
the ball Hogwan you'd be like,
you kind of have some empathy,
like she's probably in a bad place
and she needed some money. I'm like,
but I think it's almost better to be a
ball hog than crazy hat lady, you know,
is at least someone's jerking off to it,
jerking off their hat,
laying low and not a one guy in
Germany are always. Yeah. Yeah.
You know,
it's been really hard to face off with
all of the negative comments on me.
You know they were coming. They were
not asking anyone else to do this.
I'm just saying this has
been my experience and it's
been really empowering and
it felt really good to
connect with that part of it.
Your you and your sister hood has really,
really challenges the definition
of empowering. Yep. Well,
I've always thought that the
yes, that Ha. First of all,
pornography is empowering.
Being a stripper is empowering,
rubbing menstrual blood on our face. Is
this empowering? You know what though?
What it boils down to is the
same strokes where everybody,
everybody likes the same thing.
That's all different.
Different strokes for for her it's
empowering. For me, I'm indifferent.
I don't have any negativity
towards menstrual blood. I
don't have any preference.
Do you think 20 years from now she's
going to look at this clip and roll,
roll her eyes or be like, yeah,
I'm glad I did that. I mean,
any healthy person rolls their eyes and
what they did 20 years ago. I hope so.
Anybody who's making progress 20 years is,
yeah,
that's a lifetime. That's a
long time. Let's see it. Are
we going to see her face,
right?
Oh yeah.
Hmm. Wow. There you go. You know,
Paul, now you said the actress thing.
I feel like this was kind of an actory.
I don't think there's any doubt. Yeah.
I don't think there's any doubt. Do you
think there's any frustrated actress?
Yeah, you're right. You
think there's any right?
That's like fucking James Cameron
will see this. Yes. Oh yeah.
That's like, you get like lost in the
delusion of, Oh, I, I, I experienced that.
I want it on an audition. One time
it was for a Steven Soderbergh movie.
Jerked off all over the road.
I had the decency to do
it in the parking garage, go to the
roof parking where nobody is. And uh,
I went on and I never get auditions.
And it's like,
all of a sudden it's just Steven
Soderbergh movie I'm auditioning for.
So I'm super excited and,
uh,
I do this a republican character,
uh, sometimes for, for comedy.
And I thought, oh, this guy's
perfect for this audition, this,
this part is perfect for
this, this guy. And I'm like,
there's nobody more perfect for this part.
I'm going to get this and
it's Steven Soderbergh.
It's probably going to be an award
winning movie. That part's going to be,
I'm probably going to get an award
for this and then I'm tripping.
Imagining my,
not only me giving an award speech,
but me arguing with people the next
day who I forgot to include in my speed
while I'm waiting to go in on the
fucking audition and I go in and I'm a
horrible, horrible, I didn't
even get a call back back.
I feel so good.
I know that I'm not alone because I've
had like I've had those same fantasies
and like have thought about like what
I wear a Tux or would I wear a suit
and like take myself through the
whole thing. Absolutely. And then you,
then you get the call.
Like the actually they,
they didn't even say
anything about your audition.
They didn't even acknowledge
that you auditioned.
We tried to find out and they don't
remember who you are and I'm like, oh no.
That moment you had,
for those of you I've never heard of Paul
Gil Martin or the mental illness happy
hour.
That's basically like what your show is,
is having these moments of
being painfully honest and, yes.
And I should have mentioned,
sorry earlier. Uh, you're
also stand up comedian.
You been on television a million things.
That is it dinner and a movie.
That was the thing that probably most
people know me from a new comedy central
half hour and stuff like that, but I don't
do and Chris stand up anymore. Um, yes.
When I'm not doing anything,
I'm at the Christian science
reading room and I laid off,
I read through a monocle.
Wow.
I want to clash it up.
Yeah. Yeah. The old school,
I liked what you don't do
stand up anymore. I don't,
I just do this a satirical
republican character sometimes,
but as far as going to clubs and doing
that now I bought five years ago,
I just kind of hit a wall and when I
have an agreement with the entertainment
industry,
uh,
they won't show an interest in me
and I won't show an interest in that.
We both kept our under the bark.
Uh,
do you get to perform the character,
the Republican character?
I'm like on live stages
and yeah, go on. Uh,
Carolla's podcast. Oh by,
uh, do it on Jimmy Doors. Uh,
Jimmy Dore Does live shows.
Um, so I do with there,
there's some youtube clips. I put a fake
campaign ad out about, I don't know,
10 years ago as a guy, but it's really
fun to do because it's kind of like my,
my picket sign of when I get
pissed off about shit. Oh yeah,
there are a hypocrite.
So I just pour it all into this kind
of clueless character. That's fine.
Who is a hypocrite. Yes. It must be.
You must be really like searching
for material these days.
Not really allowed to talk about, oh my
God, it's, it's, it can be overwhelming.
I guess. It's funny because when
I started doing the character,
it was almost cartoony and now
it reality has caught up to it.
Yeah. So it's really just rearranging
the reality into a punchline, right?
Cause I guess you could see the character
down and be like, yeah, I believe that.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Where's
he representative? Actually,
a lot of times when I do it, people
don't know. It's not a real character.
Do you get people to get angry at you?
Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Oh yeah. Cause his,
his views are like, you know, one
of the things he says is, is uh,
Mexicans make two things, tortillas in
trouble. No, that's fantastic. Yeah. It's,
it's, it's, yeah. Know my favorite thing
about like those guys in real life is,
and that's why that line works so well
is like a fifth grade level vocabulary,
which they did this thing during like the,
the uh,
the campaigns like leading
up to the election and they
actually found that like,
uh,
they studied all these interviews and
speeches that Trump did and found that he
had like,
he stayed in like a third to fifth
grade level vocabulary easily.
And that actually, that, that had
a huge impact. He's one of us,
he would say things like, things
are bad things or sad, awful.
This is just terrible.
And it never would leave that range
of kind of simplistic language.
I thought it was really fascinating
language study. Even though he said,
I have the best words, I have the
best words. And I'm like really smart.
Really smart. Really smart. I'm
like genius, right? Pretty much. Um,
you were asking me last week how,
um,
how people in Star Wars Yeah.
Communicate with like the monsters,
you know, like the bookies
and watch the star wars films.
You'll notice that Chewbacca and
uh, our R Two d two, it's always,
and then the actors like what's that
are too? You want dinner? He's like,
well you want a hot dog? Apparently
this guy has like a, like Kentucky,
oh Jesus.
Many people have asked me to do my
Chewbacca or am I walking impersonation?
And by that I mean my mother language
and found out it's actually three
languages. It's not, it's not
just a bunch of sounds and
whatever.
And I went back to Wikipedia,
found the language does, I'm going
to use, which is called true to work.
It's a, the called the common
language of the Wiki people.
It's actually for trade and travel.
It's the one that most non wookey's
would have used in the stories.
This is one of the most disturbing
levels of fandom is when they going like,
this
is real. You know how these people
in this world and you're like,
that's a made up world bro. But like not
like, he's like, well I'm more than the,
some of the natives prefer to address it
this way. You're like, it's all made up,
man. We talking about PDS. How Wikipedia,
without further ado,
hello, how are you? Goodbye.
I will. Thank you. Was
not just making Sam a friend.
So I don't know.
I love that somebody
gets so into something.
It's just so hard to take it
seriously when it's so niche.
Cause I think all of us,
maybe I should just include myself,
find something I like and get,
we were kind of talking about this
before we start recording and get
ridiculously into it. Like
when I discovered we get
obsessed, oh, when I, when I,
uh, discovered good wine
for the first time. I mean,
I'd been a drinker all along. I'm sober
now, but I've been a drinker all along.
But I had always thought, oh wine, you
know, that's for pussies. You know,
what's the big deal? And I was
buying a, a friend of mine,
a bottle of wine because he loved
wine. And I said to the, to the clerk,
you know what if I give you 50 bucks
for a bottle of wine that you think is
awesome, uh, I'd, I'd like to try that.
And so I took it home and it
blew my fucking mind really.
And within three months,
I had 24 cases,
a vintage wine in a rented
humidity controlled storage
locker and was searching
for wine every day on the Internet.
You've got obsessed, dude.
I thought you were about to say I was
25 grand in debt. That too. That too.
Hey, sorry to interrupt,
but can I move this?
Cause I can tell that it's blocking
my face. What was that? Oh,
now can you be, is he
cool? Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
Just for editing because
I can see you perfect it.
And it's that way with everything that,
that I get into this,
I run the wheels off it.
When I got into photography,
taking pictures of dogs,
photography,
especially if it's pictures of
dogs is photography within the,
within the first year of having that
camera, I took so many pictures,
the counter rolled over,
which means over 10,000 pictures.
So I you have a real obsessive,
totally, totally obsessive. Yeah.
I've never,
I've never done anything in moderation.
Is that alcoholism? Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
It presents itself in many
forms and junkies. Oh,
you mean alcoholics? Like it's
the similar, yeah, it's all,
it doesn't really matter
what the substance is.
It's the trying to distract yourself from
the discomfort of being in your skin.
So how long, wait, how long have
you been sober? For? 14 years.
So that's a long time.
Congratulations. Um, is there,
was there something that you
took to immediately after
like your sobriety began?
In other words, like some people, as
soon as they go sober, they're like,
I really got to get into this working.
Within six months I had a
full on cabinet shop and my,
now that paid dividends because I know
how to make furniture fucking really?
Oh yeah. I could show you pictures.
I make mid century modern. Yeah.
And I still do that,
but I'm not obsessive about it.
But it was to the point where I
would be at dinner with my wife now,
my ex wife and she would be
saying something to me and
I would be half listening
and the other half of me would be saying,
oh,
what kind of joints should
I do it dovetail joint on
that thing or what kind of
wood should I use?
And I know now looking back cause I'm
not as obsessive about things that it was
a way of me distracting myself from
shit I'd buried as a, as a kid,
but it everything do you have that weren't
day kind of upset or many upsets are
really not really, which is
nice. Yeah. It's nice. Myself,
I guess that's my current day obsession.
That's good.
Or will be till the day I die.
Yeah.
I mean I think what a lot of people
at least hear about or some of us know
people that go sober and some of them
get really into fitness and exercise or
food. Yeah. Uh, which is
the opposite first. Uh,
the first probably three
months of my sobriety,
I was doing a nine shots of espresso
a day. Oh my God, man. You know,
uh,
one guy who does he,
I think he does double
that a day over ice.
Um, no, I do, I do a lot.
But now this dude does just straight up
espresso on ice when he pitches just,
just the bean come out and like he,
he ended those,
the hardcore workouts and
he does a lots of candy.
Candy, sugar, sugar rushes. Yeah.
I'm just coming off a one
year Ben and Jerry's bender.
What was your flavor? A American
dream. What's in that? It's so perfect.
It's vanilla ice cream, but like
really, really good vanilla ice cream.
And then fudge covered,
uh,
chunks of waffle cone fuck
and caramel swirled in,
in every once in a while you'll hit a,
a caramel deposit that it seems like the
Ben and Jerry worker had nodded off at
the Carmel Lever, you know,
and it's just like, oh my God,
I can't go to bed now. I got to
see where this fucking thing ends.
So real danger for me is ice cream.
Really dangerous.
I've got some over the holidays where it,
cause we don't normally have it and
like what do you like? I'm pretty,
I'm pretty much a purist,
pretty simple with I like vanilla ice
cream with chocolate chip and not mint
chocolate chip, just regular
truck, mint flavored.
Anything like one of those where you can
taste like vanilla bean really tight.
And then like the offset with
like that crunchy chocolate.
It's all about the texture
man. And then I also, uh,
I love that there's
multiple versions of this,
but all the different cookies and cream
ones I can like I can get a pint of that
and within minutes being like,
oh,
I can see the bottom of the pipe right
now cause I get zoned out and be like, um,
I'm like,
I feel sick to my stomach and that stop.
And then the ice cream
farts two hours later.
Those are a whole lever, uh, level of,
of sulfur that like the other, it's,
they're hot, they come out almost hot.
But my stomach will start hurting
and I'll get gas under my ribs.
And I found that I'm lactose intolerant
and you know what, then that's ancient.
By the way. You don't get gas,
you don't know it's party get gas,
but it goes under my ribs hurt. That's
the fucking worst pain. I feel like the,
the bullshit though is because I tried
for a while when I was buying it more is
like s like,
you know soy ice cream garbage man.
What's the point? All, all the knock off.
Like this isn't real ice cream is dog
shit. Yeah. You gotta have realized,
how do you feel about frozen younger guys?
I mean I'll fucking eat it, you know,
but I always feel like I wish I
had ice cream right now. You know,
kind of like it cause I liked the
shittiness of it. I liked, you know what?
I like Mcdonald's Sundays,
they're fucking great.
There are hot fudge Sundaes are
fucking great. Tastes like ice cream.
Mcflurries remember we know a guy
who was so such that he would get two
different McFlurries because he doesn't
want to mix the tastes of who hurt him.
His monitor his daddy.
He was hurt by his daddy.
I think he had a really weird
relationship with his mommy finding out.
A lot of people did. Yeah,
he went to podcast. Yep.
Fucking depressed when, when? When I
weapons spoken to him in a long time.
But man, when he went down this,
this kind of depression cycle,
he went down the food and I remember
there was drinking a fucking two leader,
like was sitting with
sugar, uh, a Pepsi Max,
which is like they're, they're amped
up Pepsi, Pepsi Max. He was doing,
he would get a six pack of Cinnabons.
Yes. How was he not a diabetic?
He became a diabetic. Yeah. Through it.
Well, he reached his goal. He would eat.
So of the six he would
eat one, two, three,
four and the inside of five and then
so he would have one and a half left to
tell himself that he has control
thing.
It was fucking nuts man. Wow.
And as you still learn it? No,
he's out of it now. It was, but
he was, I've been in that vortex.
It's, yeah, it was bad.
Your brain is saying one thing and
your body is just going fuck off off.
To see someone
in that and not know what's going on is
like really alarming because I think all
of us were like, what the fuck are
you doing? Right? Yeah. You know
that's bad.
That's real deep though.
What's the longest time you've
ever spent looking for a porn clip?
Not a specific one,
but you know that when you're looking
at porn and you're not just like,
all right,
I'm just going to look at this and I'm
going to jerk off and get the anxiety out
or whatever,
but you're like the hunt for the clip.
The Jam you're getting,
you're getting high off than just the
anticipation of this is going to get real
dark real quick for me.
Not Long, long time.
Five, six hours probably for me. I've
done that five or six hours you guys.
Oh yeah. I've gone without
eating. I lost weight one time.
I want it on such a porn porn vantage.
It was shortly after I
got out of my marriage.
Just didn't want to feel.
This is so embarrassing.
But I moved when I had lived alone.
It was like a year after I moved out
here and I would go down those like long
rabbit hole foreign searches
and I remember one time I
got a phone call from one
of my aunts and I stayed on the phone
with her as I look through clothes for
shoes but not masturbating,
just like perusing,
realizing that I was so in the zone,
like zoned out that I
was like, yeah, no, yeah,
we would be good to see you.
And then I would keep clicking through
stuff and seeing and they're like, no, no.
Did you have the decency to switch
to incest porn? No. No. I wanted to,
I wanted to stay true to
what I was into at the time,
but it was fucking how half assed or
those answers when you're oh yeah,
that's the thing is what, just like
a roll out of it. That was that.
I could tell her voice like the way
she was answering me, it was like,
what are you doing? Right? Like what you
what? I mean, she was like, uh Huh. Like,
okay.
Like
she could tell that I
wasn't paying attention.
You can tell when someone is not paying
and that's when I was laying attention.
I was like, no, I know.
It was times on the road when I call
you when you were like, ah, yeah, no,
you're doing your porn sir.
No, it's usually sports.
What are your sports?
I'm just a big football fan. I like
you used to play right? No, no.
I mean I played high
school football but okay.
But I mean I like college football and
I'll watch highlights and I'd be like, oh,
that's crazy. And, but I don't know.
I get, I get sucked into that but not,
I don't get like zoned out by that.
Really.
I use map my TV I liked, I like
my TV yell, mom likes her shows.
I go down rabbit holes
of shows like benchings.
There's like two categories.
There's the one that that released
the drugs in your brain. Yeah.
And then there's the ones that are just
kind of interesting to you. Like, yeah,
that's when I tried to like um,
like vintage hockey fights.
I like those but I don't like get
high. Right, right, right, right.
But like porn, I will just feel like
dopamine they ended is just like,
yes, let's keep going. Yeah.
Your reptilian brain food.
That's true foods.
Avast
I got to slow it down cause I'm
preggers right now I'm going went down.
We'll know because I've already gained
too much weight for the pregnancy.
Like I got, I got a talking to
from the doctor already so. Wow.
Well cause I was eating,
I was doing Domino's pizza for like
the first trimester because your son,
you're nauseous so you
don't really want to eat.
So when you do want to eat it's going
to be crap just because like your body
wants carbs. The baby ones, carbs.
So I was like waffles a cheeseburger
is at midnight and then yeah,
just,
it's already packed.
It's what I feel like I've got to
reign it in kind of a shameful speech.
She was like, so we're not going to
do that again, are we? I was like,
Oh shit, I better go eat some
vegetables as her husband.
Where do you do on the sidelines if you
see her starting to go over the edge
because there's a fine line there.
It looks like you don't
want to be controlling or
insulting or feel like you're
objectifying. Not, that
is fine. I think that's,
I think most, I mean, unless I saw her
something doing like destructively eating,
I was, yeah, I'm just like, whatever you
want and just totally cool with me. Well,
I think I ran it into,
and I know you're not out of control.
That's what I'm saying. But like,
yeah, I mean when, I don't know,
anytime I've been around any pregnant
woman who's like, I got to eat.
I'm just like, all right. Yeah,
that's the, that's the go flag.
That's the green flag or whatever.
They do. No real argument against that.
But I gained a lot of weight.
I gained weight too much because I
was eating Carl's Jr twice a week.
The best was his, his um, his
sheep or like how you should eat,
how he eats because he
was like a very like thin,
you know you could tell like type it in
control guy and it was like have four
almonds have this thing
literally for Asparagus,
fuck to medium size. I read it.
I was like this is what he eats.
This dude eats this and he's just
like this is what you should eat.
And then once a week he sees a
dominatrix to let go of all this.
Yes. Those are the guys that
go to the dominate tricks.
Oh and he goes at the bottom of the sheet,
it's like once a week you can splurge
and have two ounces of ice cream.
What is two ounces?
The two licks I do,
I look at somebody like that and they
might as well be from another planet.
Like I used to look at people that would
only finish half a beer and I would
just think what is that like?
Yeah. It's like how do you do,
what is your native language?
Wow
Sake. I think Meyer has been
pulled out of the socket.
No.
Why did you pick out someone?
One fourth year size.
So this guy would be the kind of guy
that is from another planet and I think
here he actually shifts
to another language.
Rawr Rawr Rawr Rawr Rawr
Rawr Rawr Rawr Rawr.
Approximately. He says he's a Jedi Knight
now for those who didn't follow it,
I'll do it in motion now.
I can't take it man.
Can't take it either.
But that dude really thinks
he's teaching Tom Stand.
How much money for you to learn Chewbacca
language? And I mean learn it fluently.
Like I know you're doing
Rosetta stone for Italian.
You're doing Rosetta stone for wookie.
It,
it would seriously be a lot more than I
got from Netflix to do a special and a
lot more. And you have a test every
week and you have to be fluent.
It's several million dollars.
Why? Why Italian? Why?
Well, I speak Spanish and um, you know,
I had an interest in
learning French and what I,
what I discovered was Italian is so much
easier for me because it gets close to
Spanish. Like all the pronunciations
are pretty similar. Yeah. Um,
and so far like I'm flying through it,
whereas when I did the French,
when I was like, fuck, I kept like,
I just kept hitting walls and like,
so I'm doing it because I want to do
something to stimulate that part of my
brain, but I don't want to too big
of a challenge. So, and with Italian,
the one thing that sucks, I feel
like there's more utility in French.
There's definitely more places you
can use it. And definitely more pussy,
more and more posts. Number one,
Paul De. Yeah. I mean I have like,
what are we going to do
another couple of years,
so I know I'm going to have
some fun soon. Um, but yeah,
I'm still, I'm doing the Italian just
because the very least the AU pair. Yeah.
You know, if you, if you don't have enough
frequent flyer miles to go to Paris,
just get a free childcare. Do you work
on your fuck with other languages?
Do you ever like, uh, we taped when
I was doing dinner and a movie,
we tape 10 days in Italy and so I did
like a crash course and so I learned,
you know, just a spoon. The Bolt Tailgate,
they act mineraly parrot, fab order.
There you go. Pull native apps,
things like that. Like five,
like five sentences.
But people soap,
appreciate it when an American takes
the time to learn their language because
most Americans just come in there with a
sense of entitlement and are just dicks.
And so it's like, oh, okay. They
recognize that we are fucking country.
Yeah,
just learn like people learn a couple
of basics I think anywhere you go it's
like, just learn how to say like,
excuse me, thank you, please.
For even for like a basic trip.
It's like, it goes a long way.
Or like I'll never forget being in
Paris and I'm having lunch and a nice
restaurant with some other students.
We were, we were actually in Madrid,
but we went over to Paris for a couple
days and we're sitting in this restaurant
and the server comes up and one of
the girls who's American turns them,
she goes English, right.
And I was like, you.
And then everybody at the table was
like head down and the guy was like,
yes I do.
I just speak English.
But he even saw from our looks how
embarrassed we were. I was like,
why don't you just say I can't you learn
to say, excuse me. Do you speak English?
Or like I don't, I don't speak French,
but no, she had to go English. Right.
Um, he was like, yeah.
And also like I've dealt with your type.
Oh yes. Yeah. When I go to Hungary,
I'm not very good Hungarian unless I'm
there for like a month and then all kind
of maybe pick up a little
whatever. Uh, but own thing. Yes.
But, um, they're so rude
over there. That Hungarian,
Oh my God.
That's why I barely try because like I
remember last time I went there like in
[inaudible] 99 or something
or on a 2004 or whatever.
I was like trying to order and he kept
correcting my pronunciation and grammar,
but like in a cock sucker where
I, um, I should find via, I,
I should find these Ganache I guy. So he
would try to wow. And I was like, Bro,
I'm trying like, you know what I'm
fucking saying liquor. Like, you know,
you're so upset about it. I'm so upset.
Did you call Him Dracula? I wasn't.
Not Romanian maybe. Oh, okay.
Yeah, but neighbor, same thing.
Same Shit. Different
toilet. The cousins, um,
got a store email here when men poop.
Do they holder Harry Dick
and balls in their hand push.
They're soggy dig down into the
toilet and Cayston pee comes out.
What of the Dick is so
long and touches the water?
I learned this from my husband. He
goes all in. Love you mommy. Tina.
Thank you Jean for choosing
my husband and the audience.
Friday to say his body was dog shit.
Oh, this must have been at your show.
I remember him. I remember them.
Delightful couple. Very enthusiastic.
If we hold our dick and balls
in our hands when we shit, no,
we push it down obviously in this,
push it down.
Push it down in between your legs.
Here's the seat rim.
You Push it against their pee
down. Yeah. I never knew that.
Otherwise you get pee on the toilet seat.
You think it would hang out the outside
of the toilet or just maybe just dangled
wherever it wanted.
I didn't fight him,
but think it either has to be in
the bowl or outside the bowl. Okay,
but here's my thing.
If you push it in the bowl,
what if it rubs against the inner rim
and touch his Poo and pee? No. No.
There's no poo up there in
the front. It took. It's fun.
Our toilet there is in the front. Someone
takes explosive dumps in that twilight,
but it does do touch the porcelain.
It's kind of gross when you're in public.
That's what I was going to restaurants.
I'll lay a tissue down just for my own
peace of mind because you're touching the
porcelain. Yeah, but I mean, yeah,
it's just how it is. It's gross.
But then your painter gets other
people's pee and stuff on it.
Probably Mike doesn't hang low enough.
You know what I'm saying? Yeah. I've,
I liked that. She was like, what
if it touches the water? It's like,
do you know what kind of hang you're
talking about right now? That water,
it's not like, right. They asked for it.
I would gladly be able to
have that problem. You know,
male comics are always joking
about when they get older,
their ball sack and they can
touch the water. Does that happen?
I've looked some guys.
Yeah.
And you sit on enough toilets
where there's also weird,
um, mechanisms for toilet.
Sometimes you'll sit on a toilet,
you hit flush and it has like water
comes up and then goes down. So you'll,
you'll jump cause the water
will raise it up to your balls.
But like for the most part your balls are,
unless you're a ball hog,
in which case, you know, uh, then,
then you get your, your balls.
Let me put it right up against her.
I
get so aggressive,
I think about 15 years ago because
it didn't used to be that way.
And I don't want to sound like
an old person, but, uh, no.
I remember porn when somebody
wasn't getting punched.
We've had the discussion that
when we are introduced to it,
we're basically too young,
your kid.
But we were watching pretty much eighties
porn where the thrill was just that
you're having sex with some,
like that was, yeah, that was,
we were seeing a vagina and then
in the scene they were like,
this is so great that I get to have
sex with you. Like that was, yeah,
that was the interaction that I'm so
glad I missed delivered a pizza. Yeah.
And then, you know, it was big hair
and it was just naked people
doing it. Yeah. And then it,
I think it's because, I don't
know, there was maybe the,
as the exposure of it grew,
people became more desensitized.
I think so then it heightened. Yeah. Well
the, I don't know. But then again, okay,
what are the most popular
searches for porn?
It's MILF porn is one of like
top category. It's not the, um,
that's true ball licking the fist,
double fist. Anal. Fucking, it's not,
it's not the most popular for sure.
And everyone is kind of in the
middle of what their tastes are.
I think it's just marketing and like,
Whoa, I'm going to, it's like Click Bait,
right? Five Dick's and one bought
whole Wagga to see how that works out.
That's going to break bad. How's this
going to break open? Right, right.
Cause I don't know,
I'm trying to
pull up the, uh, it says that
there's the most popular. Yeah.
What are the big searches right
now? Pop most popular porn, Sir
Gay.
I read the,
I heard some podcasts where straight
guys are searching for gay stuff.
Meaning there's a lot more
gay men out there then are,
are copping to basically
they're saying they're gay.
I'm sure MILF has big
looks like a Hentai. That's the uh, yeah.
Uh, cock cock holding
was big. Lesbian. Wow.
That whole crazy term. Uh, gay, big.
These are the biggest search
is a 2017 accord. Yeah.
Oh, crazy things chain. It
sounds pretty basic though.
Dick big deck that lesbians, it's like
same shit. Different toilet ma'am.
Yeah. Um, and the most
viewed categories for women.
Uh,
like in the u s the biggest term for a
search term for women was lesbian as same
as South America. In Africa,
you'll never believe it.
The biggest search term was
ebony. Um, Russia. It's anal.
Wow. Um, yeah. And it looks
like, yeah, those are kind of it.
And then mature and teen teen is
a popular term as well. Oh yeah,
I've heard that's a big one. Yeah,
it's the bed. They seem, you're right.
It's not like airtight six
Dick's or it's not like that.
That's the curiosity
click, I think. I mean,
what about Trans Trans Sexual?
I thought that was very popular.
It wasn't the top 10 list,
but I'm sure it's a very popular term.
A lot of that chicks with dicks.
Yup. Um, what is, uh, let's see here.
Why do infinity wipers happen? Oh,
exactly what you're talking about.
Like a bath of 90% of the time,
I'm a solid one to Weber.
Occasionally get stuck wiping
for at least 10 minutes.
Really destroys a good
roll of toilet paper.
And your help is it keep it
nonbinary Zack, if I may,
because I'm kind of like
the queen of Infinity Wipes.
This is why I invented shit.
The shower for me,
the only way to stop the wiping is to
take a shower and I don't know why,
why that is, but the minute you
take soap and water to your Heinie,
you're going to stop the wipes. Oh
Wow. You have that ever infinity?
I christened the house I live in now.
It was empty. I had just taken ownership
of it and I had to take a shit.
So I go in there,
I take my first shit in the house and it's
one of those shifts where you're like,
ah, there's not enough
toilet paper in the world.
So I get in the shower and there's not
even a shower curtain and there's like no
soap like day one it was,
and I just remember thinking really
this is my first memory, this is,
this is how I Chris and this is the worst
bottle of champagne to crack against a
shed test. That first shit in the house
you wrecked your remember you really do.
I think shaving your asshole and wiping
from front to back has been the biggest
key for me. Oh. Which
minimizes the multiple wives.
My Dad has multiple series on it.
It's wiped direction,
white portion diet that sometimes he goes,
you've got to let things settle.
So what he, cause I've asked him, he goes,
we need to do buddy is you stand up kind
of thing. We'll realign inside of you.
Because sometimes it's just the way that
you're sitting in the way your insides
because he goes stand up,
kind of let things go back together.
And then sit back down.
I've tried it actually has worked before.
Like he, I mean he says it like really
like a researcher would say but he,
yeah he insists on it and I've,
I've, I've, I've thought about it.
I think it does make sense.
The next time you have an infinity wiper,
just try standing up for a second.
You know I'm going to have everything
go back to calibrate. Yeah. Yeah.
But it's too late at that point.
I mean it's like after you get in a car
accident, drive better. Yeah, I know.
I know. Because here's the thing, if
there was already brown all over you,
you're already in. It's already
messy. It's not all over
you. You're just having a,
a whole, it's like leaking basically. So
Diet I think is the biggest thing is one
of life's really most sublime pleasures
is the shit where you wipe and you go,
I didn't even need toilet.
So true. Go Shit. It's the best.
That is the best thing.
You double checked it.
There's something in the bowl
you're like, yeah it did. I miss,
is there a piece stuck to my leg?
Cause this is too good to be true.
[inaudible] shit coming. Um,
we've been talking about,
my dad says things incorrect,
like mispronounces so many words.
Um,
so we're getting a lot of emails about
it along the lines of our parents saying
things wrong. When I was a child,
we had a cat for the longest time.
I thought that his name was Charlie.
It wasn't until I was laying
in bed one night when I was 23,
but I realized the cat's name was Charlie
and that his name was being said with
an extremely thick Boston accent.
Grateful to Albert.
We're washing it. I looked some scrum.
You run like a lady Mike from Albany.
I don't know what that part means. Scrum.
Do you say that on the, on the spectral?
No, no. He says you run like a
lady. I don't know. Um, but yeah,
well my dad is proceed.
Like that's an accent that you're hearing.
My Dad had a foggy brain old guy,
but he's been doing it for like,
like we were talking about when he was
here for the holidays. Uh, like, I dunno,
Casino was on and my dad was like, that's
a Joe Pesci. Right? And we're like, yeah,
but haven't you heard his
name like 10,000 times?
Like why would you call them Pesky?
And he says like all types of words,
like a few degrees. Yes. My Dad,
my dad used to do that to a who
would like a Heineken's. Yeah,
that's a paralyzing. That's the
Goto. At one time my dad, uh,
said, um, uh,
I was listening to a Simon
and Garfunkel. No. And I went,
no, Dad, it's, it's Garfunkel.
He goes, Oh yeah, Garfinkel,
that's the cat, Garfield, Garfield,
native English speaker. What? We were
discussing all our theories on it. Like,
could it be brain damage?
I think it's for like my dad,
it is actually a lack of paying attention.
In other words,
it's kind of like being half into the
conversation we were watching. He goes,
you know, you don't hear a lot
about in the news these days,
is that Gerald Koocher? And
I go, Jared. And he's like,
and he goes, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So in other words it's like, you know
what I'm saying? I'm like, but dude,
you've heard his name and you've read
it in newspapers like a million times.
So your dad's half listening.
I think he's looking at some more clips.
He might be looking at porn,
he might be watching ball hogs
instead of actually talking to me,
but everything he says is kind of like,
you know what I'm trying to say?
So I'm like, I think you're just kind
of half checked out of everything. Yeah.
So then you have saying things wrong.
You know what?
I think that starts to happen and I
don't want to scare you guys. Children,
children, deprivation. I know.
Absolutely. My best friend, once
he had four kids, like there was a
part of his brain that never came.
Absolutely. Especially as the mom. Yeah.
There's a thing called mom
brain and it starts for me,
it started in the third trimester,
my last pregnancy and in for the
first year you remember that.
I would just forget because you're so
sleep deprived and you also so much,
your brain is mush.
Part of it is aging,
but I think that having
the kid exacerbates this
is your separation from pop
culture [inaudible] you're so into this,
you know,
taking care of this being and all your
home life that things kind of pass you by.
It happens more when you have a kid I
think where you're like somebody will
bring up, you're like,
who's that? And be like,
who's the number one artist in the
country right now? And you're like,
I don't know who that is now.
Just kind of passes you by.
Last night I was saying to Tommy,
I'm like, I'm, I'm 41 years old.
I think I'm finally the official age
where I don't know shit about pop culture.
Like I, I know about Cardi B and I'm
like fascinated by her and that's it.
Right, right. It's a singer. She's a
says. I honestly, I've never heard of.
He's a rapper, he's a rapper and she's got
like a couple of big hits. Huge. She's,
she's very successful right now. And
um, that's all I know. Maybe the voice,
I know Blake Shelton was on there,
but I'm officially that that turning point
where your, your lane? Well we made a,
I mean it wasn't on purpose but such a
shift I feel like within the last four
years or so where things on television,
if it's on TV it doesn't mean anything.
First of all,
like my wind down of like I want to
watch something involves Netflix,
iTunes, like what's the, you know,
renting things or watching a movie. Um,
maybe Amazon prime and like if
there's a show like that on NBC Fox,
I'm like there's 0% chance and less
like a friends on it and they're like,
I'm on this show. Even then it's like I
don't watch it but that's good for you.
I know the name of the
show, but I mean, yeah,
so like those things just go past me now.
That's,
that's the only thing I watch broadcast
TV. Exactly. What's your sport?
What do you like? Hockey? Yeah, but
you're in northeastern guy or in Chicago.
Chicago guy want it. Makes Sense.
Yeah. It's a great sports town.
It is also a bears fan and a
bulls. I was until, you know,
after they won in [inaudible] 85, 86, uh,
and they just took the team
apart from money. I was like,
why am I frustrating the
fuck out of myself getting
behind a team with more care
about winning than the fucking owners.
They're the only
professional sports team where it
is the sole business of the owners.
So I understand that they treat it more
of a business then as a hobby like Jerry
Jones where it's all
about his ego and winning.
But the bears could use some more of that.
Yeah. I mean I feel like your fandom,
if you have like ownership issues,
like I was born in Cincinnati
and we left when I was a kid,
but we left the year they
went to the Superbowl and 88
with boomer. Yeah. And like
I was a Yankee shuffle. Yeah.
And I was such a die hard. Yeah.
I was such a die hard fan.
Um,
but then what I discovered is like after
time kind of living in that with the
reality that they're like probably one
of the worst ownership groups or teams in
the NFL. It, it makes your
fandom like die. It's hard man.
It really tests there or they're
a perennial dog. Yeah. Yeah.
And you realize too that you're like,
that's so it's,
it's a real thing that a team can suck for
decades, decades. The saints in the 70s,
I don't think they ever had a season where
they won more than five games. It was,
they never made the playoffs. I know they
were dog shit. Awful. Awful. And it, and,
and, and uh, what's his name? Uh,
Archie manning was a fucking great
quarterback. Yeah, there's
bad. And then, then you can,
and then the flip side you see like, like
let's say like the Steelers ownership.
You're like, that's like a family
that they love the team, the city,
they want to win the, do things
the right way. And it's like,
and they have six fucking rings.
Do you think it's,
they know when to give up control and
not micromanage? I think so. I think,
I do think, I mean it sounds
kind of Cliche, sports be speak,
but it's like they develop a
system and like, oh, here's the,
it's like a culture, like in a company,
here's the way we do things here.
And when you get people to really buy
into like, this is how we work here and,
and you have integrity and you have good
values for like how they probably treat
employees all the way on
down. I think that, that,
that becomes something that
people really buy into. I mean,
for all the shit people talk
about the Patriots and all
that, it's like, you know,
I think they have a real culture going
in that organization. Absolutely.
Black Hawks are probably one of the
greatest examples of that. The, uh,
uh,
Bill Wirtz was the owner for years and
he was despised by the fans because he
pinched pennies. He, he was a dick.
He treated Bobby Hall and all those other
stand Makita treated those guys like
shit. Money was the only
thing that mattered to him.
And when he died, his son,
rocky Wirtz took over and,
and uh,
attendance was in a 30,000 or whatever,
a seat stadium.
Um,
there was maybe 12,000 people.
Rocky Wirtz took over.
He started bringing back the
hall of Famers, honoring them.
He got good gms, they started
drafting wisely. They got cane,
they got Taiz and it is one of the
most profitable sports franchises ever.
And when change their philosophy,
then change your philosophy.
And when they won a Stanley Cup,
all the employees got ring. Yeah.
That's cool. It's nice. Yeah.
One of the things that people,
I mean people will say like,
we'll say they know it,
but they don't act on it is if
you're a fan of anything, it doesn't,
I mean it could be sports,
it could be if you go,
I'm not going to support
that thing anymore.
That's really the only way you'll
see change. In other words, right.
Like in Cincinnati,
they'll still sell that fucking stadium
out no matter what they're doing.
People will still buy tickets to the game.
And so that lets the owners go like,
well you don't have to fucking
do anything like and money. Yeah.
Like roll the dice when you want to
hurt them. Like stop going to the Games,
stop buying tickets to games and
you'll see something will change.
Go in the parking lot and set
off car bombs or whatever.
I encourage the cottages.
I um,
this is a question we get questions
about all types of things,
but here's the question
about little people.
I was in the bathroom cutting my solid
brown and half with my powerful urine
stream. I had a thought. And you know
how when adults refer to their childhood,
they start off by saying,
when I was little, yeah.
Do adult little people refer to
their childhood by saying this also,
do they say when I was a little smaller,
I can't get this off my mind.
I need some answers here.
That is kind of an interesting question
because you do say when I was little and
if you're a little person, you might
be like, when I was really little,
I don't know. I mean it's kind of silly
when I was young or when he was younger.
Younger. I wonder if they
ever, I mean if the leg, yeah,
cause all day they're like refer to
themselves as little. So, so true.
Maybe when it was tiny.
Yeah.
When I was half to half of you,
uh,
my girlfriend can't tell the
difference between left and right.
She has to hold her hands in front
of her and make an l with each hand.
The correct orientation of the left.
Let her knees left. This is my life.
I have accepted her handicap
and to support her through life.
What we want to have a child,
well she passed on her retardation or is
there still hope for our little jeans?
We have a dog and he was real dumb.
Not sure yet. If that's her love. Brad,
I love this. One of the funniest emails
I've ever, ever, ever. So she literally,
he goes make a left and she has to go.
Which way is yeah.
And the dog is dumb and he's not sure if
that's her fault. I tell you this much.
She's gotta be hot.
She's a smoke show for eight Brad,
send photos next week because we're
pretty sure she's lightening men.
My God. What do you think? It could
be a, you know, brain thing. Yeah,
definitely. I probably is. It's a form
of dyslexia or some kind of directional.
People have terrible, terrible, I
mean, I've never heard left. Right,
but I know north south,
a lot of people are fucked up by that.
I don't know that all the time.
I have to do the never eat soggy Wheaties.
You know? What I find is that when
you live in a certain neighborhood,
especially in Los Angeles,
you get your orientation,
but when you leave that neighborhood
and you go to another just neighborhood.
Now that for me, I, I lose
the sense of all direction.
I don't know why, but yeah, like it's
like I'm standing in a Hollywood,
I'll know north, south, east, west, but if
I go to Burbank, I'll start. I'd be like,
yeah, it's south of this, and you're like,
that's north. I'm like, no, that's not.
Yeah, it just throws me off. I don't
know why I leave neighborhoods and I,
I can't orientate myself.
The only way that I,
I've always had kind of an obsessive
need to know what direction I'm facing.
And it was one of the reasons I don't
like flying into cities is because then I,
I
don't have a bearing to start with. Like
right now, I know I'm facing northeast.
Right. Um, it's just like this,
you know, you're facing northeast,
right. Didn't know that. I, I wouldn't
that, hold on, Huh? Yeah. You are.
You are fighting facing northeast.
It's just this weird,
I think it was a fear of being lost
maybe when I was a little person mean.
Did you know that? Just like, you
just know how you count. It's just,
uh, it's just as a sense
of, of, uh, I dunno,
I dunno how to explain it.
I don't,
I don't have to think about it cause
I'm always thinking of things as a grid
kind of when I get into
curvy shit, then I, I lose,
like when you get into subdivisions
where it's all curves. Yeah. Hmm. Um,
super orgasm, asthma. Do you
know what that is? Uh, our blue,
our producer just through this ignore
folder. I have no idea what that is.
I don't know
the most that I've had.
I think trevally be upwards
of 60 throughout an evening.
It's great. Especially the ones
that keep on going forever.
And then there comes a time after
a long time that I just say no,
we have got stopped because uh,
I mean you can't go up and a hallway.
I feel like Europeans have so much more
fun than us. I feel like that though.
No one American will be in this uh,
video clip super orgasm.
Actually last year I was really confused
and to me it felt like a contraction
but nice. Hmm. Do you want
to go to this seminar?
I was like during like a
little group circle. I don't,
I'm not a fan of group
orgasm therapies or, yeah,
no, it's a super orgasm
though, right? I know.
I don't, I don't, I think
one is fine. Like I'm not,
I'm not chasing the dragon
here, you know what I mean? See,
in an evening I think one is sufficient.
I would bet the next day they're depressed
because you're too high bleeding all
of that. That's like when
you take ecstasy, uh, you're
depressed the next day,
Paul, that you're withdrawing all that
dopamine or whatever the, yeah, I'm not,
I'm not an extreme type of person. I
think I'm happy with what, like anatomy,
you know? Yeah. Provides
52 year old mother of two.
Beverly is super orgasmic, I believe. So
practicing tantric sex is what leads to
super orgasm and a priestess of love and
sacred sexuality.
Do you think it's very natural for me if
I'm making love with a partner to have
many, many orgasms where my whole
body is flowing with sexual energy.
Do you think she's as full of shit as
the guys who got the comm? Hugs? Yeah.
Bugs and that they're there.
That is like a boat.
K of cliches that I search for you.
The word sacred. Um, the,
the uh, you know, the India,
the music, Sitar or whatever, the dancing.
It's all Robin. You know the word mother
earth is just around the corner? Yeah.
Do you know Julie and there?
I don't think we need
what come hugging is. No,
that's so come hugging. There's a,
I'm trying to pull this up for you.
There is a, um, boy,
there's these two people who say that,
uh,
you can come just by hugging and come
seminar.
It's, it feels like some bullshit though.
It really does. Yeah. Rarely done.
Have you ever spood so hard that
you hit your own face? Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I hung one on my
glasses one time in college.
I had to laugh.
I was like,
it made me laugh because it made me
laugh. Just, yeah. Drench yourself. Um,
I can't even imagine that
you guys clean up at clean.
It's got to be terrible for
men. It's pretty bad. Yeah.
And especially because you're,
if you,
that adolescent phase where
it's like nonstop and Ugh,
it's just gotta be disgusting for your
mother is cleaning up your [inaudible].
I was always, yeah. What's the,
what's the most inappropriate or gross
thing you've ever cleaned your ges with?
Oh, man, that's a good question. Yeah,
I get it. That's a really good question.
I mean, it was definitely
in that, in those terms.
I think of like this is an emergency.
Yes.
It was probably something that's not mine,
you know?
So like it's probably like
somebody like a parent's clothing.
I go,
you go like you think you're alone.
Then like you hear the door open like
Oh fuck. And I dunno where I'm at.
And then I just clean up. I think. I
can't think of like a specific though.
What about you?
Hands down.
It was sex with a girl and a car.
She was a single mom and,
and she presented it to me
to clean myself off with
a baby sock. I go, really? She goes,
that's the only thing I have.
I have not even a lot of surface area.
And I was like,
this is going to be lasered into
my brain for the rest of my life.
These are the come huggers by the way.
I was trying to show you.
Hi Melanie. I'm Scotty with
ecstatic hearts. Tantra.
I was just want to share that
there are many ways to orgasm.
You don't actually have to be having sex.
You can orgasm just from hugging.
So there,
ah,
it's,
it's amazing how many people in the
world exist that make us uncomfortable.
Yeah. Try it out. Yeah. They're, they're,
they're so uncomfortable because I,
yeah,
I've seen that clip now like 40
times and I'm still like, man,
well cause I struggle in my head
I'm like, oh, I'm uncomfortable.
But as it, because I'm like a prude,
am I being close minded here am I,
I think we both kind of like,
when people are like that I
get uncomfortable with there.
It's almost like their level of sharing.
Like I could make like come on, I'm like,
just fucking don't need to know
about it. You know? I'm not a prude,
but I'm just like, I don't have
any, no, I don't want to know.
I don't need to know
how much you can come.
Yeah. I'm all for freedom. Freedom
and no shame. But it's, it's,
it's less the concept of it then.
It is the presentation of it.
The presentation of it is always kind
of precious and new agey and just,
I don't know, there's, there's
almost kind of a smug theater crowd.
The theater crowds laugh at something
that's not funny at all. We know.
We understand that the
Butler would never do that.
Right? Yeah. It got a
little of that. Yeah. Um,
like I would never see Hamilton.
I think I'm so,
I'm the lamest in terms of that. You
wouldn't see it. I heard of so good.
I just hate theater. I don't know. I feel
like it's too, it's too corny for me.
I'd be like, I don't like
opera. I hate musicals. I hate,
I hate music eight. Yes. Even like,
what was that was such les
Miserables movie. Sit through it.
Get your ally.
I turned off la La land when they
started singing in the first scene.
I fast forwarded through the songs. I just
like Ryan Gosling and what's her shit?
Yeah. I don't want to fucking hear.
I started on a plane. I was like, Oh,
this movie is like winning everything.
And then I clicked that first scene,
the camera settles. She was
like, wait her. And I was
like, Nope, I'm not doing it.
I'm not going to watch this.
Don't want to see it.
I've been doing this since I was a kid,
like with Disney movies and shit.
I used to listen to records and
I would skip over the songs.
I like the store, so 69 at 70,
so submissions to wrap things up.
So we've been doing this thing where when
I, uh, just to give you context for it,
my dad turned 70,
uh,
back in August we had a big family get
together and my mom, who's Peruvian,
it doesn't get a lot of references.
Uh,
one of the dinners on the first night of
the, of the get together, I said, Hey,
dad is turning 70 tomorrow. Do you
think you guys are going to 69 tonight?
So afraid it like a child. And she
was like, what? And everybody laughed.
And then we kept teasing her
about it all weekend. Yeah.
So we told our listeners about it and
we asked them to ask their parents if
they're going to 69 at 70 and get it
on camera and they'd been selling all.
He goes, yeah, you get a
wide range of reactions.
Sometimes the parent is a playful,
sometimes they're stunned,
sometimes they get really
upset, which is my favorite. Um,
but so I don't know what these, these
are our new ones that came in. Oh my God.
Do I love that? Was the moms
that are up to, yeah, the moms.
Would you ask me something like that?
Sharon? Like really, really upset my fate.
I mean, those are good.
I like when they're like,
you guys are, this is so juvenile.
I like the, I like those two,
nine times out of 10.
The Dad's on board. Yeah,
Dad. That's always what sounds good to
me. But yeah, mom's like uptight. I know.
Dad's 62 wait, hold on.
Let's put bets on it.
What do you think her reaction to haul
the last night that he's 60 you guys
going to 69 one last time.
Oh my God.
Have you ever
or are you going to 69 one last
time? Like the last time. He's 69
well, he's hammer hammer. It's hilarious.
First question is, have you ever
play Joe here right now? Sorry.
I love it. That was
great. That's from Mr Sr.
I couldn't find the pause cause I was
gonna say we should take a look at the
mom's next time and then bet on how
you think she's going to read it.
I thought she was going to react angrily.
I did too.
That glare was like the fuck
are you asking me? Yeah.
But then she did kind of smile. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. She's had a few enter. Yeah,
you're right. Yeah. The
Alcohol House since uh,
no humor. I'm going to go
no humor on this lady. Yeah,
I could go with you on that. I think it
might not work out. Yeah, I think she's,
I think that he spends most
of the marriage sitting
there with that look on his
face. Yes. And her reaction
with that look on her face.
And so that reaction is
going to be probably remind
her that he doesn't fuck her
anymore. This is a, okay, this
is from crystal. So here we go.
Michelle is going to be 50 yeah,
that was kind of, that's a milestone.
I love the setups.
So Michelle's 50
turn 70. Yeah, yeah. Years ago. Yeah.
So because you turned the night
before it would have been,
if you turn 70 you would have been 69
so one gram per turn.
70 did you,
did you guys 69 before he turned
seven days as a send off your dad?
I love it. She loved it. She
loved it. Yeah. Did you tell her,
did you tell her? Did you tell her that
that was a surprise? Completely surprised.
Yeah. That's the best one. You can't when
you don't nail it because you're like,
oh, this one's not gonna like
it. And sometimes he's like,
she seems fun and then yeah, the hell
did you just ask me? Right. Yeah.
Well those two were both fun. He was
fun and she was fine, so that was a win.
Well, Ralph, I was wondering though,
when you turn 69
before you turn 70 than I have before
[inaudible] 70 or [inaudible] 69
is significant. All right. Excellent.
Very.
Oh really? You brought each
other's teeth with your ass holes?
They're, yeah. Yeah.
I've got a couple more here so
I'm going to say now square.
I love they're doing it in front of it.
James 70 when he was 69 wake on
the last day of his 69th birthday.
Do you think you guys would have 69
no.
Quiet twice. Oh, fun.
His girlfriend. That's like
disgusting. Like you're the weirdest.
You're totally judging. But this
lady was actually fun. Yeah.
Awesome.
No quiet toys.
Weirdest hoof on hot.
God.
My Ex's mom used to love when we would
swear because she was raised really
Catholic and really so your ex in
mother-in-law ex mother and look at it.
And when my ex moved into my house this
or you know we are apartments that are
25 years ago a friend was helping
us move along with the mom.
And so my friend,
my mother in law and I are carrying
this futon down the stairs and my friend
doesn't know that she likes swearing.
And so as the three of us are
carrying this down the stairs,
I turned to my mother in law and I go,
I can't wait to blow some loads on
this baby and my friend and she starts
laughing and she would laugh. She would,
and my friend just looked at me like,
what the fuck? I say to your mother in
Law who? Your mother in law? Hilarious.
Hilarious.
This is the last one.
She's going to be good. Yeah. The last,
the last side of him,
he 69 are you guys going to
say
nobody?
A little devil.
They're fun. I loved it. All
of the moms were cool. Yeah.
It's funny that the the daughters or the
daughter in laws or whoever the sisters
were the ones that had the
problem with that was Matt G.
Thank you for sending that in.
Yeah.
It's like everybody's been
a good time so far. Right?
I was trying to find the one.
There was one was this it? Oof.
His jeans are tight. I know. I wanted to
find that really disapproving mom. Oh,
I love those. I don't remember
which episode it was in though.
But there was one lady who got
so like controlled anger at,
she's like,
what are you doing right now?
What would you disrespect
me with a question like that
is so fucking fantastic.
Oh man, why would you ask me that?
Yeah. How would you say that?
It's really terrible. You would talk
to me like that. Um, okay. What else?
So uh, the mental illness,
happy hour, happy hour.
Have you been doing that for a while?
Six years. Six years is a long, long run.
So there's hundreds of episodes. I don't
know when it's going to get canceled,
but yeah.
Can I tell you that your show is
such a huge public service to people,
to humanity and I advise
everybody listening to this
show to check out Paul show
if you don't already know about it.
Um,
cause you explore every facet of human
existence and like there's no other
person doing it.
There's no,
there's nowhere else where people are
being interviewed about being bipolar or
being a Hasidic Jew and being molested
as a child or whatever the scenario and
what I really love on your website,
which has mental pod.com he has these
surveys up that people take anonymously
and so you can see what people are
really have had happened to them in their
lives.
You know,
things that you wouldn't want to admit
in public and interest and you can read
what things that turn them
on. Yeah, yeah. Oh, it's just,
it's amazing. It's such a
great show. I want to check
that you appreciate it. Yeah.
Anthropology. Go listen. One of my
faves, it's on my rotation. Right Tommy?
It certainly is. Try it out.
Try it out. Um, all right. Um,
thank you for coming over today.
Thank you for having me.
Any other plugs besides
the podcast? Okay. Yeah.
Thanks for coming. Yeah, it was super fun.
Super Fun. You have to come back here.
Thanks. Days. Come back to. All
right. Uh, we'll see you next week.
Thanks again for listening
and have a good one guys.
I come home. Come home, come home,
come home.
I at home.
I just come home, come home. I Skim all
Party together.
Netflix,
when Jina up at night,
I got do
something.