This episode of Your Mom's house is
brought to you by Saatva luxury mattress.
The only online mattress company that
provides free delivery set up and mattress
removal.
Well,
go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Oh,
you guys want to know where
you can see me do the standups.
I'm getting back into it. Uh, November
24th, that's Thanksgiving weekend.
If you're in San Diego and you want to
either get away from your family at that
point or bring them to the show.
I'm doing the house of Blues in man,
Diego,
California.
And then on December 7th
filler up Delphia uh,
tickets are on sale and moving
pretty quickly for that.
And then December 8th and June,
Dork titties, Gramercy theater,
the APM show sold out and tickets are
moving quick on the 10 30 show that I have
added. Other than that, I'm just,
you know, getting back into things,
doing the comedy store and,
and 2019 I'll be working on very shortly.
We're doing the story together this
week. This Thursday night. Yeah,
the eight o'clock show in the main room.
If you're around two mommies, one show.
She's a tickets at Christina p online.
Thank you Jean.
Jean, the joke, God's going to be
adding a, I added a show Sunday,
August 26 at breast balls,
beach at the Improv in west palm because
the other ones are sold out. Oh Geez.
Um,
where else have we added shows?
There's an added show in ball Sacramento,
California.
It's October 6th.
Uh,
there was an added show in boys seats,
Idaho.
Um,
I think Eugene's ad it shows gone.
Uh,
I know that in November the Welmont
theater in Montclair sold out.
We are adding a show.
I'm trying to get you the
info about when it's on sale.
It's going to be the day
before it's going to be.
The show is going to be on Wednesday. Uh,
whatever that is. I think it's the 14th.
Um, anyways, as we're doing
the show, I might get the
update and I'll let you know.
All those tickets are at
Thomson [inaudible] Dot Com.
Check it out. Try it out.
Try it out when you can.
All right,
gene,
this episode is going to be insane.
We have so many good things lined up.
Are you ready to get into it? Yeah,
let's par t f feel like this.
Hold on a second.
Every time I do this thing. Yeah.
This is a, you guys just have to
sound smart already.
Feel you guys is a sounds
good already. Yeah, it causes,
here's this guy. Oh boy. Hats
on. Bad Angle. Blown out.
It's already got all the qualifications
and shirtless. He's shirtless. Yes.
Shirtless. Oh, of course. Bad Tattoos.
It's all there. That's how we do it, man.
It's how we do this show.
Let's go. All right dude,
I just have to go off real
quick about racism. Okay. Okay.
Fuck.
Why people
don't bring it in one into this.
Well,
go to your mom's house.
Yeah. Um, first let me, before I forget,
mentioned thank you to everybody that
came out to the all new Braya Improv.
Oh, how was, it was beautiful. It's great.
What's the difference from
between the old one? Well,
it's about 45 yards away from the old one.
Yeah.
And it's bigger.
It's much bigger.
And the old capacity was like
three 75 and this one's five 50.
[inaudible] that's like a theater. Yeah,
it's a, it's basically a small theater,
but crowds were amazing.
Uh, it's, you know, I've,
I've said this in a pose that
I've said it before to people.
There's nothing like the,
like the physical space that you're
comfortable with as a comic or performer.
The Old Breyer is the first club I
ever Mc to weekend at first club I ever
featured a weekend at. And the first
night I ever headlined headline,
all three first night you ever
headlined got road head broadhead? Yeah.
That's cool. I met her. And that's your,
your home. I forgot that I did for,
I forgot that. Yeah, you were,
you were out and bring out a lot in
the early two thousands when and then
started even like,
so then I worked a lot of weekends there
and then I had a monthly show for a
while. Um, [inaudible] gave
me Tuesday nights and I would
comp the shit out of it.
I mean, it would be like a free show,
but the crowds are always great to me.
Embryo. I just always had
a good time. So I always,
I've always loved going to break it to
do those weekends. And it was awesome.
It was really, it was my first time doing
an hour in two months. Is that right?
Oh yeah. I, I know, I'm just writing
mine that went away. And then, um,
yeah, so I haven't understand that
since I filmed the Netflix thing.
I know this is my,
my first set back in,
back in business here on a Thursday at the
store. It's been over two months. Dude.
It's a long time. It's crazy. It is a
longer one. Anytime. So Lazy. Right?
Yeah.
You're fucking crybaby
now. Were there a lot of mommies
in breath? A lot. Yeah. He saw,
he knew their mommy's
cause of their shirts.
They out that I had a Josh powder
came with me, who's great. And uh,
in his introduction he would always say,
you don't from your mom's house pocket.
And they go nuts. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
No, there's definitely a strong,
strong motherhood.
The strong mommy's down there. That's
good. That's fun. That's fantastic. Yeah.
Um, well look, I'm glad you're,
I'm glad to have you home.
I like it when you
sleep in bed next to me,
even though now you're onto a
brand new serial killer show.
I am a killer and I've been talking
telling people about it online.
You have to,
you're also right.
Big Fan. Not at all. Not at all.
Not at all. He did something
never seen you do. If you guys don't know
this is a new Netflix series that um,
what it does is it features
people on death row, uh,
who have murdered or you know,
in this, in the one case, in,
in the second episode, it's a guy who was
present with some, you know what I mean?
You know,
a lot of states if they are like,
like if I drive and you kill
someone and then we drive away,
I get charged too. So there's a guy
like that. But in the first episode,
which you were exposed to,
you sat on the bed and stared down and
that was like, can you believe that?
And you were like,
I'm not listening and I'm not looking.
I don't want this to permeate
my mind. I don't know. And I,
and I say this like with like,
I try to be open minded because I want
us to be able to share things in common,
but it's so depressing.
Just the tone and then hearing like how,
how clearly they,
these people came from bad,
the first one backgrounds
and the Robertson depressing.
Oh my God, his life is
such a day. And by the way,
happy you are discussing.
I mean look at the smile on your face.
I mean there's the funny parts are funny.
I'll give them that,
but the parts are definitely very sad.
You were also exposed to how bad he looks.
Holy Shit.
That guy looks like uncle
fester on the poster. He
also looks like in return of the Jedi
when Darth Vader's mass comes off and you
see the ground.
Yeah.
And like the dark circles and he's
like Warren and you see like just a sad
broken look like a sick man.
What's weird is it says
in the first episode,
um, you know, they featured him in the,
in the interview and then
the state of Florida let,
let him be interviewed 65 days later.
So they do a followup interview.
He looks so much better.
Like the black circles are gone.
They let them go to club med for a week.
I don't know what happened,
but that guy's life story when you
really, really think about it. Yeah,
it is horrific. Well my
favorite is, I think he goes,
I had a normal and I was like,
I don't think you did just
before he turned 17 I don't
think he was sentenced to
10 years in prison. Okay.
So just a normal level
bringing in Florida prison
for more than 37 years.
Jesus. And he's only like fucking like
50 or something, you know, or yeah,
it's pretty bad.
And that, and what part makes you
laugh the hardest? He has a couple,
he has a couple of funny,
funny beats. Like when he goes,
he talks about he killed his
cellmate and then he's like,
I wish I had access to a soundboard now.
So I could play the psycho.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Like
as we're talking, he goes,
I killed the soundboard and the next
studio. Sure, sure. He goes, I killed my,
my cellmate. And then he looks at the
interviewer and he's like, he goes,
I don't feel bad about it. And he goes,
and he lasts like that. He goes, I know.
You're like, oh, this guy's
crazy. It's pretty funny.
And then they interviewed
a former former cellmate,
obviously the one that he killed and
the guy goes, he likes sits down.
And you could tell by the way,
by the weight it's set up by the dialog
that the guy who's featured the killer
of the death row guy told the producers,
oh, you should interview this guy.
Like it's implied. Right, right. And
he goes, I don't know why he told you,
interview me. I'm not as Frat guys.
A piece of shit. That's funny.
That was funny. And he talks about
like how big of a piece of shit he is.
He's like, okay, I don't
respect him at all. He's like,
he is a fucking pariah. He just,
yeah, he just will go after anybody.
He thinks he can get away with it on
and he's like, he's a horrible person.
It's to, it's terrible. And even just the
sounds of the show, cause like you said,
I didn't look at the screen. I just
look down the whole time. Yeah.
The sounds of the show. The
general tone, the Beige Ness,
no js definitely like depressing. And
then comedy, like it goes back and forth.
Sure. But sure. There's some
sad parts. I just can't,
I can't watch stuff where I just
know that there's suffering.
There's too much suffering for me. I
don't like white bummer shit. This is,
this is another caveat. There's
like a white bummer tangent. You,
you know what I mean? Yeah. Crime
shows kids with cancer, people falling.
I was hoping, I mean, I'm, I'm not
series yet. I haven't, I'm hoping for, uh,
a little more psycho
detached like crazy person.
Yeah. A little less. Oh my
life. You know, it was real sad.
And this is this a thing I'm
hoping more funny and less.
It's coming up. Yeah. Yeah.
And did you watch this?
While I was falling asleep last night
too. I did. I started episode two. Okay.
Which uh,
thank you for doing that so that it leaks
into my unconscious mind as I sleep.
Yeah. That one was, that one was pretty
sad too. I'm hoping it gets funnier,
but it's,
well,
I got to fall asleep to the
sweet sounds of a El Chapo that
I'm Spanish.
I got to hear a cobbler
where I recognize one of the,
so there's only El Chapo,
a Mexican series that I think there's,
I don't know how many seasons of
it or on Netflix. And I started it.
And here's the thing,
you always roll the dice with these,
especially with these Latin
American productions. Why
is that? Well, I mean the,
the shows that we get to see on like,
you know, the soaps and stuff and like,
like Mexican or mango and sat and
land. It's horrible. It's so bad.
And so I go, is this going to
be like a Hokey cheesy show?
Like I didn't know if it's going to be
good or really goofy and shitty and it's
actually really good. You know, it's a,
it's basically the narcos story,
but of Chapo and yeah,
the actors are great.
The production values is great.
They have a couple American English
speaking actors in small parts on it,
and I swear one of them,
uh, looks so familiar to me.
I think he was in my [inaudible] class.
I got gotta look it up.
I'll look it up. But uh,
sounded really peaceful and nice too.
It's another fun thing to fall asleep to.
Thank you for that. Um, yeah,
so that's, that show has done,
has done very well.
I guess they're,
they're looking at a possibly
doing a season four right now. Hmm.
It is. It's him. Yeah.
Yeah. I know this dude. Yup.
Wow. Yeah. Holy Shit. I
gotta reach out to him.
So his name is Dave.
Oh, hello. Nice. Yeah.
Good for Dave working. Dave's
doing it, man. Sullen, dude.
Is he doing like all fucking Mexican
stuff? That's cool, dude. You should, uh,
you should apply for these jobs. You
can speak Mexican fluently. Thank you.
That's all I hear. I mean, she got
wrong. Maybe he moved to align to align.
Maybe he moved. Oh, I don't want
you to move to Mexico to work.
Do a do a line from Chapo. Come on.
Pretend you're in it. I latching Galloway.
Yeah. Gene gunk. All the Mexican
slang makes me, let's Chin gone.
It's just fucking Mexican Mexican slang.
Fuck and fuck it are like, yeah. Yeah.
I like, I like how that sounds.
That's what I grew up listening to.
I as somebody who knows Dave, Holler
at me, man. Dave. Oh, hello. Okay.
Now we used to hang out all the
time. Yeah. David's cool dude. Well,
she took my first headshots. Then
when you're like, you get here,
you have no money. You need like heck
no, I don't have any headshots. Yes. Uh,
this is Dave here. Let's see.
Um, I don't know what I'm
Paul. Me. Yeah. I see. He did.
He did. Loving Pablo and
what's Blanca is, that's it.
It's like another Mexican thing.
Blanca. That's your aunt shit. Blanca.
Anyways, day was a good dude, man.
Good for him. Language, Spanish.
He's doing all Spanish language.
That's a great lane to be in, Huh?
Yup. Tom, you need to be applying
for these jobs. Dave hired
me in Mexico. In Espanol. Yeah.
Say Hablo Espanol bloat a spine.
Yo.
I like when your dad speaks Spanish.
He's really fluent. You know Tami,
when you were a little boy used to say
Cargill make daddy cargomatic courier,
you'd say Gargan May.
I think your dad speaks Spanish.
The worst of anybody.
I knew that if they hired him the
worst in the Spanish speaking,
so it'd be the best. He just walks in
the room. He's like, can I come back?
And they're like, we're not going
to carry you Sir Kerrick. Me.
That's all he knows.
And now we have the new version of that,
which is our son going, I hold
you and how old you are. So cute.
Can you please,
can we please pull up this Instagram thing
I'm talking about when a mute it because
I don't want it to get taken down.
Oh right. Yeah. Okay. It's a visual thing.
So if you guys are watching on Youtube,
you're blessed with what we're
about to show you. If you're not,
if you're just listening, I will
describe to you what it is we're seeing.
Cause it's so ridiculous.
So I follow Elizabeth Gilbert,
she's the writer who did eat, pray love.
Um, basically it's based on, you know,
the book where uh,
she splits with her husband and then
she falls in love with another man there
together for 14 years.
And recently in the last few years she
hooked up with her best female friend and
is like, oh, I'm a lesbian now.
Now the horrible part of this is that
the female friend she's been friends with
forever has just passed away of cancer.
And so she,
Kendall,
they came together just as this woman
was diagnosed with cancer and so she had
to watch her mate essentially die and
be ravaged by this horrible thing.
Now that being said,
I still find a way to make fun of her
and on her Instagram she posted this
thing, um, that grief is
a full body experience.
Can you please push play on this?
And I want everyone to watch this.
It's so embarrassing. And so she's doing
like, this is her, this is her friend. No,
this is her and this Elizabeth Gilbert.
No baby. You have to read the caption.
Oh, it looks like her
answers. My beloved friend,
Oh, was rye as ex wife Elizabeth. Yeah.
Anyways,
so there's this woman doing this
interpretive dance of grief in her,
in her kitchen and,
oh,
it's so embarrassing. Like if you're
watching it, and I keep like, I keep,
I get it that this is like, I have
empathy and this is sympathy and whatever,
and this is real for
this person. I like, oh,
so embarrassed when I see it. You should
be embarrassed. It's embarrassing.
So embarrassing. Totally embarrassing.
And she's doing like, ah, it's,
it just looks like,
you know what it looks like.
It looks like when a white person
goes to Jamaica. Yeah. Or Ghana
or something. And then they see
locals dance and then they're like,
I learned this and you're like,
please stop doing that.
It's the African anteater
dance. And she, it's so sad.
It's so earnest and sincere and it's only
because I don't have the connection to
my emotions to do something like
this. Of course, I'm so disconnected.
I could never do this. I mean,
of course this is probably,
they're probably better people. So much
better. Yeah. Well, I sent this to me,
I'd rather not be a good person.
Then
I sent this to a comedian friend
of mine and she's like, oh my gosh.
I was crying and I was like, really?
I was crying laughing at this shit.
This is ridiculous.
I'm like,
I must have no soul
because I mean I get like,
I get that you feel this way, but then
isn't there a level of like, don't why?
Why do you have to share it? She says,
we dance because it hurts too much.
Not Too.
We dance because we are
so grateful to this love.
Oh my God, I'm so embarrassed
by it. And then she says,
don't let this out of you cause grief.
It was settled in your bones and make
you sync with pain so you can grieve.
You can grief move through you.
You can help grieve,
move through you with music
and with dance. But do I
have to do this? I hope not.
If you did this over some grief,
I mean I just want you to know
that I would openly mock you. Also,
I do pilates twice a week.
Does that count as movement that just
keep it there and don't post it online?
Why do white ladies feel like they
have to share all their feelings? Well,
it's only a certain lane of white
lady who I happened to find the least
attractive of all white ladies.
Really?
Like why fucking white ladies have
to share their fucking let me guess.
They went to all women's college.
This kind of shits
encouraged multiple degrees.
I get it. [inaudible] studies
major. I know the worst.
Literally the worst cause my
least favorite person to be.
Of course I'm related to a ton of them.
Well look,
it's not that I don't,
I believe in all that stuff
and I behind it intellectually.
I just don't want to hear about it.
I don't want to like get on.
I just want to be bombarded by all the
time and I'm sorry her friend died or I
mean that's sad.
That's what I'm saying that I can't
help but make fun of people who express
their feelings.
But that's your job.
Don't you understand that you
shouldn't feel badly about it.
It's your job to mock people
who are sincere and earnest.
That's the world needs balance.
The world needs balance in the
world needs people like her.
It's who are sincere and
in touch with their suite,
and she will inspire people
to take that sincerely. Yeah.
But because there's
balance in the universe,
the world also has people
like us shitheads. Yeah.
Who will point and laugh
and mock and you know what?
People enjoy us for that. Some people
would get upset and truthfully,
maybe one day, many years down
the line will go, you know,
I used to laugh at that and now I don't,
and that'll be a different time
in our life, but for right now,
our job is to mock this person
for grieving like an asshole.
Other people's sincerity is my hilarity.
That's the fuel that I live on. You.
I'm such a Dick. Yeah. You don't
know that you're a big asphalt. No.
I mean, sometimes I, I'm
aware of it. I'm like, God,
I love being a professional asshole. It's
great. But then I'm like, how does that,
is that the line here?
Or like,
I'm not like that woman's
grieving and she's like,
I'm doing an interpretive dance on my
grief. I mean, like the truth is to like,
I don't agree with, that's
how you agree. Personally.
I've grieved that I didn't do that
thing alone. Crying hard. Yeah.
Feel kind of sick.
Yeah.
Drink a lot.
Stay in a dark room and kind of sit
in your depression. Yeah, but not,
not this Ernest shit, this dance
thing. I'd be like, fuck you,
I want to punch something.
So if I got like this,
you don't think you can handle it? No,
absolutely not. Absolutely not. No Way.
If you were doing that for real to grieve,
I would just be like, look, you know,
of course do it. Like I don't
want to be anywhere around it.
Please keep it in another
room. Do it upstairs. Yeah.
I tell you to come in here. I go stay
in the studio. I'll be somewhere else.
And I also think that this lends itself,
cause right now we're in an
era of nonstop sharing. Uh,
the earnest shares, you know,
you see them on Facebook,
the oversee the medical
over shares. Like, uh,
my mom's a festering wound on her foot's
getting better guys. And you're like,
I don't want to know any
of the stuff about you. Um,
but there's definitely now a blurred
line between public and private.
You know,
like there's,
there's very little delineation nowadays
between what's public and what's
private.
Like you and I had been seeing people
taking phone calls on speakerphone,
right. Like we were in the, in
a nice restaurant and this guy,
this dad has a speaker phone,
he is a speaker.
It's on speaker phone and
then he puts it up to his
yeah. And The lady goes
on a, a full, you know,
dynamic tires are, yeah. Yeah.
And then he's like, well,
I gotta I'm going to have a lunch now.
And then you use here as well,
Rah Rah Rah Rah at full volume full.
And he's holding it here. Yeah,
he's holding it up.
I don't think.
Maybe he didn't even know he was on
speaker phone and he's, he was old.
He was old. He was, he, he should
know better. He's gotta be dead now.
That was like five,
six days ago.
And then remember that guy in Starbucks
who did like a health insurance call or
something you said?
He was like,
he was on the phone with,
oh my God. You recorded him.
I did. I know I got to, he was on the
phone, I want to say with Bank of America.
Oh,
and what should be a private call because
you're talking about your finances
deco, obnoxious and
rude fucking shit. Bird.
What is wrong with people? Yeah.
Oh nope, that's not it. Um,
another thing I've been seeing are people
wearing how slippers in public spaces
as well.
Like I'm talking like Fuzzy Pink
House slippers to get on an airplane.
I side at Burbank airport. Like, look,
I'm not opposed to seeing people's feet.
That's not the problem.
I don't care.
But you're not supposed to wear
fuzzy slippers to like the mall,
the grocery store airplanes.
It's completely inappropriate.
It's just not footwear that's meant
to be outdoors. Dangerous actually.
Cause it's too flimsy.
A shoe.
Yeah.
It's silly.
It's not, it's not, it's inappropriate.
I don't know what the fuck is happening
that people think the world is their
living room. It's obnoxious.
Yeah. I mean you used to,
people used to have shame
about that kind of stuff.
He tried to keep your
conversations private or worse.
Some people listen to their music or
watch videos at full volume. You're like,
dude, nobody wants to hear
your bullshit. No, of course.
And I'm very cognizant of that too,
cause we have a sign in some, you know,
if we take him out in public,
like we always like Shh,
quiet, don't yell. You know,
via, if we're showing them
video as well. He has, you know,
he's eating so that he focuses in minute.
We make sure that the volumes down so
that we're not disturbing other people.
Right. Of course. Yeah. It's
just so silly. People are
so horrible. Why don't you,
why are you trying to find this audio?
Trying to press pause
so you can look for it.
Yeah. One second. Okay. I, I
was able to pull this missy,
if I can make it actually play here.
This is, I found it on my phone.
I was just thinking about that
ladies interpretive dance.
The least comfortable with thinking about
it again. Like it made me like get it,
get, it makes me feel icky inside.
Yeah, that's right. It's so weird.
Why do people share that
fucking Shit Dude? Don't shh.
Don't share your feelings like that cause
they're more emotionally balanced in
you. I know. Um, it's just so
vulnerable. It's like ugh. Yeah. Gotcha.
So uncomfortable. This is so gross.
So it's like acoustic guitar singing.
I videoed this guy or slam
poetry at Starbucks. No, this is,
he's, he's just sitting there
with his phone by the way.
On a table. Yeah. Speaking of his
coffee on speakerphone. Crazy.
Full volume. Crazy person.
And we're all, you know,
trying to enjoy our days. Sure, sure.
Press Four for this,
two for that.
Like fuck everybody. Yeah. You
guys all listen to me beyond.
Yeah.
Like you want like it's bad enough when
you have to be on hold in your personal
life and now you got to hear some
other assholes being put on hold.
I don't think there's anything worse than
someone else's being put on hold that
shit up to your ear,
asshole.
You fucking make everyone else
listened to your hold stone.
A fucking scumbag.
What a scumbag.
Such a Dick.
Yeah.
Now you've got an offering.
Listen [inaudible] like you
want to hear any of that?
Do
you want to hear that right?
Someone else's fucking hold.
We're all sitting there just trying to
unwind. Have a coffee and we got to
hear your commercials. Unbelievable.
Such a piece of shit. What
an asshole. Yeah, like what?
What goes through people's minds that
that's acceptable behavior to put it on
speaker phone so everybody
gets to hear you being on hold.
He's a fucking psycho and he doesn't care.
Do you think it's just
like an unconscious,
like I'm claiming the space.
It's like public Whistler's like
people that are whistling. It's a way,
it's like what birds do to mark their
territory. Like everybody listened to me.
I'm here,
I'm here.
He's so removed and he's so narcissistic
and so oblivious to the fact that that
would be bothersome to somebody else.
That's his personality.
This is my Starbucks. I don't,
I don't even think. Yeah,
I mean he doesn't like
if you were like to say,
do you think other people want
to hear the speakerphone? Uh,
hold stuff from Bank of America while
they're here? He would be like, what? Huh?
I don't know. I'm not like totally
unaware that he's even doing this. Yeah.
And if you pointed out that like no
one wants to hear that, he'd be like,
well yeah. Do you know what we need
right now in society? By the way,
you remember the Guardian Angels of the
80s those nerds that he used to dress up
and like fight crime for free and
like the New York subways and stuff,
we need to have the guardian
angels of proper public etiquette.
Now people who are designated,
they walk around and like uniforms.
So you can see like,
oh shit,
there's the Guardian Angel and that
person comes over and goes, excuse me,
you're being an asshole.
Nobody wants to hear Your Bank of
America on hold or a, excuse me,
Shit Bird.
You don't wear a fucking slippers.
I'm thinking a little more aggressive.
Go for it.
Let's take it out of the
Philippines. Uh, I think it's,
I don't know if it's
president or prime minister.
He has a kill onsite policy
for drug dealers. Love it.
So like if he even thinks
you're a drug dealer, like it,
permission to shoot you in the head on
the streets. I think they should do it.
Yeah. For socially. Yeah.
Rude people execute.
Somebody goes right there murders that
guy in Starbucks and it's innocent.
And then everyone's like, what the fuck
are they like speak phone, full blast.
And here's how we do it.
It's a fucking bullet right in the brain.
So you see the splatter, the
blood splatter on the window.
And then like in China,
when people are students, China, they
send your family the bill for the bull.
You get a thing in the mail.
It's like you owe us a fucking dollar
28 and you know who else gets a fucking
bullet in the head?
Whoever their car breaks down during
rush hour traffic on the four oh five if
you're responsible,
your car breaks down at 5:00 PM on a
fucking Friday and it's your fault that
everyone else has now even further
fucks right in the fucking head. Yeah,
and we do it in public. We round
people up. Maybe we'll delay that.
You know what I mean?
Like at the end of the week we'll do all
the assholes that held up traffic was
Handmaid's tale. Yeah, yeah,
yeah. They all get around.
We all grab a rock and everybody gets
a chance to throw 11 person. I love it.
Yeah, I like it too, man.
Let's get through this guy who
hates white people real quick.
Everybody hates wiping.
I know. It's kind of
okay. You guys just have to go
off real quick about racism. Kay.
Kay. Fuck white people. Yeah.
Every culture has something like,
look at the Chinese,
they have like honor and Mike. Okay. Like
light, like native native
Americans, like Hispanic people.
They have like heritage and shit in
their culture, heritage and their shit.
Fucking hamburgers like kicking in the
fucking door on other countries and being
like,
hey,
we're better than you because we made
you do everything for us and what a bunch
of needy fucking wipe fuck white people.
Okay.
Yeah.
Is this the new professor over at uh,
Harvard sociology guy? Yeah, the
new FTT RTD professor over there.
He's the,
he's the vice admiral FTD.
Our
head of sociology.
Yeah.
Where are all the good white jokes?
There's a million white jokes about every
fucking light culture and they're all
[inaudible]. Why is there no good,
funny white jokes? Black home.
He told me this and I hit
the ground laughing. Yeah.
We are all the white jokes bro.
We are all the white jokes.
This guy's a real self loathing,
self hating.
Fucking why come? No. Why
jokes? I mean cool tattoos.
Yeah.
Super Cool.
Do your friend drew these
in your car while you were
driving and put them on you?
We are all the white jokes. Gosh,
that's really thought this through.
I like his presentation. He's very,
he's really trying to be deep.
Like he's one of those dudes.
It's like super dumb.
But he's making the town not being
Super Dad. Yeah. He's a, he's an FTT.
Rtd is an FTT RTD buddy.
So what happened?
Was he something like woke him up more?
He heard, he was like, yeah, yeah.
How come there are no white people
joke book jokes that's fucked up.
Like really opened his eyes.
Yeah.
And now he thinks he's having
a profound thought. Yeah.
This is the first thought he's had
that's like, oh, that was your share.
This one is big.
I think they need to share is PR.
Is there like a weight that's another
person that gets executed by the way.
The need to share people. Yeah. If
you're oversharing on social media,
bullet in the head. Oh, that'd
be a great one to eliminate.
I would love to kill everybody
that does. Yeah. I think the, uh,
the Elizabeth Gilbert Interpretive
Dancer gets a bullet right quick.
This guy is so stupid. He's so
dumb. Yeah. He's really not right.
I figured that part out.
Why?
Why come people Chinese of honor
and the native Americans have heritage
and his face too. Yeah.
They also have good food.
Yeah, there's Chinese. The Chinese,
what did he say? They have
their honor. Honor. And then
we are all the white jokes,
bro. Oh, we are all the wide Joe's by
being alive. We're all white jokes.
Yeah. Okay. I don't get
it. You know who's back?
I'd love to get to this before our guests.
Guests who?
Native American back and
crazier never race yet.
You're going to love it. It's so great.
Here you go. Here you go. Here you go.
Got The money. Okay. I got, yeah,
I got a few Bob. Yeah. Okay.
You Support Tom. Yep.
Okay. I was one of the
first endorsers. Public
endorsers. Uh, president Trump.
When not ocean level rises.
Okay. Hold on. I'm so excited.
And if you don't know a damn pain, yeah,
he's a, I don't have the drop ready,
but he's a, this is why you're
fucking poor. Yeah. He's a,
he's fucking be out. Shit. Who
gives a fuck? Yeah. I mean,
you want to know why you're all fucked up.
This guy's a genius.
This is the smartest man alive. Yet Dan
Pena should run for president. He's,
he would start our policy
of public execution and I
were discussing some of the
level of some of the things you have here.
Hold on.
This is why you're fucking poor,
right? [inaudible] this is Dan.
You know you won't, we featured
them on our show. Yeah, of course.
What did you put it?
Where is it?
You had a,
you have a fucking template script.
You have a mother fucking script that a
fucking monkey can read that Alex wants
a fucking case study because he wants
to know this shit behind it cause he's
stupid and that's why he's fucking poor.
Hey,
you don't need any
motherfucking case studies.
How many fucking times do I have
to say you had the fucking script.
There's Dan. I said, don't change
your fucking war on a square.
Not a comma.
If it's got missed the fucking
word sending down misspelled.
The last thing you
fucking need is a fucking
case study.
It's my coach I speech.
This is why your fucking
whore. Okay. There's Dan,
just one of my favorite people
and really a friend of the show.
He and I kept in touch.
We DM on Twitter from time to time and
it just, we've had lunch with him. No,
he's really a treasure.
Got this aggressive persona,
but he's actually a very sweet man
to be around. Wonderful Gentleman.
Wonderful Guy. I didn't know about
this. This was just saying in,
but so this one was leading up to I think
like Dan Pena who gives a fuck about
the global warming I think.
Thank you for asking that question.
I have the answer for the question.
Okay.
We changing the gas now you're full of
shit. Sit down. I'm going to answer you.
Shut up and sit down.
Sit down.
Let's just take Florida for example,
which is one of the fastest growing
condominium beachfront condominiums on the
planet.
In the perspectives when you invest,
there should be in the footnotes.
If global warming this for
real and water wise is 10 feet.
This investment you made is fuck all.
Now one single investment
prospectus written since
2008 this century has alluded
to global warming.
Now one motherfucker.
So the people that have the money and
I'm jealous of the Vice President Gore,
which shall and I wrote on a plane from
South America with fears of I am jealous.
He came up with a scan before I did
because the financial institutions,
the banks of this world,
no,
it's not going to happen otherwise you
couldn't get a goddamn loan in London.
You know those 30 40 year mortgages,
the will be over by then.
Is Barclays bank going to give
you a motherfucking loan? That's
the best.
I love her.
I don't know what the hell he's
talking about but um, yeah,
he needs a TV show. Do you know
what I mean? Fuck Anderson Cooper,
pun on damn pain. Yeah. Every night.
If he had a TV show on scene, yeah,
I would watch this guy. Of course,
I don't have to agree with anything.
He's just entertaining
mother fucker,
but he can't be censored.
You have to let him roll like those
gotta be on like Hbo or showtime.
That's too like a fan. That's somebody
that was like, I have questions.
Shut up.
This guy's a trend for sure.
Bought a ticket to ask him. Yeah,
of course. Shut the fuck up. Well, she
also wants to fucking light him up.
Of course.
Like Dan Pena is going
to be an environmentally,
that's not his fucking lane.
Don't think the guy talking about,
she uses hillage guy.
He's a savage course.
I've watched the shit out of that. I would
love to have him on because he's easy.
He is a Trump supporter. I know.
He's the only, like, I feel like,
I think it's 97% of the scientists that
are experts in the field agree about
global warming,
but he is the only person I've
ever heard contested with.
How come? Financial institutions or real
estate. Yeah. Well how come they're like,
do you think they're going
to loan you something?
They're not going to
get back in a few years.
That it's actually not one that I've ever
heard before. So I would give him that.
Well, it's from his perspective, right?
That's what he deals in his money
and real estate and stuff like that.
But he is a white guy, so fuck white
people. I don't like them. Now. Um,
our guest should be here momentarily.
Should we take a quick break
and we'll be back in a moment?
All right. Here we are. Yeah,
we're back. Where we, uh,
we're back with our guests.
He's tall,
he's white and he's thin and
he's here still weak. Chin
is the great return guests. We've had
them on multiple times. Right. But the,
it's been a while. I spent a long
time. I think maybe I've done it twice.
Third time probably at a
different location every time.
Pretty much. Yeah. I think,
uh, the great map. Wronger thank you
for coming. This is a joy. Yeah. Love.
You guys know we love you man. It's
been way too long. Yeah. I feel like,
I mean talk, we started doing,
stand up. Three of us are in la.
Did stand up together like probably 15
years ago. Yeah, something like that.
I remember seeing you guys. I remember
the first time I saw each of you.
I remember the first time I saw you,
you didn't go up.
You were realizing you were visiting
from Chicago, you had a blazer on
and it was at like a maybe like a beige
colored Blazer and it was at Tangier,
I think I, we were like, you're like, oh.
And you were like Super Nice. I was like,
Oh fuck is this guy? Like,
cause he was like, Hey,
I'm at like really outgoing and nice.
Which is rare because people
are always stretched bags.
Matt was genuinely a nice
person. Nice person. Thank you.
I remember I used to wear like
blazers and tee shirts. It's a hot,
it's a hot look. But like, but
like I remember sometimes I'd
talk to comics and they'd be like,
oh, what's up man? Good thinking.
I was like an exam or something.
Oh, right, right. Just like,
cause they never seen me before and
they're just wondering, you know,
well and here too, I mean, I don't know
if it's nationwide, but la, anybody.
Oh,
under 40 in a jacket.
Specially if they're dressed in a suit
or something. Yeah. Oh that's an agent.
Junior age.
It's so weird how they're always in suits.
I feel like a j agents almost always
have to wear suits. Like why now,
now that you can, you see them more
out with like, oh, I just had a, like,
I just got a tucked in shirt with
what you're learning, you know,
but I don't know why they
have to be dressed like that.
Then they just get told like,
you have to look better than anyone
kind of thing you have to represent.
And it's cause because it's like,
fuck, I have friends that work for,
for ca and knows been uta in those
giant like ca building, you know,
we call it the death star because it's
just, it looks, and it is, you know,
that is some Darth Vader shit, like, yeah.
And so it's this culture
of win at all costs,
which I just can't imagine living in.
I mean,
like, like that. And that's
what the Blazer, yeah, I guess,
yeah. You gotta come, you gotta come in
like, uh, like, uh, uh, like agent Smith,
uh, um, I remember a tricks. Oh yeah.
That is kind of thing that is
the uniform of the soul. Succubus
the sales pitch program is always like
the most aggressive. They're like,
what are you doing with the, you know,
your mailing list and you're like,
I don't know. They're like, you know,
we have this program [inaudible]
it can permeate someone's computer.
You have to read their fucking
emails. Yeah. And we'll
make yours. And you're like,
wait, what? Yeah. I mean,
I'm exaggerating obviously,
but it's like crazy shit like that.
You know? As you guys know, my,
my wife is my ex manager,
so it's like,
I know stuff I probably shouldn't
know about all this stuff, you know?
And like no manager games,
no games, no games. I know,
I know agent games and it's like,
I will,
I will talk with her like when she's like,
and she's got a small roster
that's really awesome and stuff.
So she's not generally
looking for new clients,
but like sometimes I'll see somebody
and be like, oh, they're great.
Or there's someone that's got a lot of
heat on them and she'll be like, yeah,
I think I'd like to sign them. But
this person, this person, this person,
like these big dogs are kind of coming
in and stuff and I will pretend to be
them with her and be like,
you know,
just like how they talk to the client
or when she's around, you know,
that takes care is great. I love her.
I love her. Here's the thing, my team,
cause they never talk shit
about each other. Not really,
but it's just kind of thing. The of
just like, just like, no, no, no. Yeah,
like that um, teams, Godfrey
thing, he's like, you know,
you're screwed when they
say they love you, follow,
followed by,
but they don't want you for this.
So that's always [inaudible] I love her.
I love her that we're not
going to pick up the project.
But that's always the casting feedback
too. Like what did they say it?
They're like, well they said they loved
you. Yeah, here it comes. They love
me and they're giving me this part.
Actually they don't love you that much.
You love your friend. I got fired
from Chelsea lately as a writer.
We executive came down after a taping
was like, you're doing such a great job.
We love you. I just wanted to let you
know we love you. And I was like, ah.
And the next morning I got fired.
Yeah.
And that's exactly what I know.
When they told you you didn't know.
But I remember I felt really good
about myself. I was like, wow,
I'm nailing this Gig. No Way.
I just don't know how my,
I created a project and sold it with a
cousin of mine a couple of years ago and
he writes video games and writes books
and stuff and he's one the smartest guys
I've ever met. And us going through
the process together. He was like,
I don't know how you guys do this.
I don't know how you live like this.
And if when you tell me stories like that,
it's like I'm having like PTSD flashbacks
of times where I've been let go or,
or someone's, you know, kind
of, you know, you're like, oh,
I think everything is great.
And like that's when the bottom drops out.
How do you maintain cycle?
Horrible. It's a horrible
parent time.
Businesses.
It's like logically traumatizing
its own way, but the,
the TV film is Wally will stand
up is consistently shitty.
Right? Like you just know there's
always going to be a crazy club owner.
Sure is not going to be right. It's
fraught with dog shit. It doesn't change.
It's just like, you know like when
they, when Nash, Steve Martin,
why he quit stand up and he's
like Friday to Friday. That's why.
And it's got to, you
can feel like, you know,
like you think you could be a microcosm
metaphor would be like a Friday night,
like the first show law. Great.
Everything went awesome. Crowd was,
was it having a good time,
which they should. They're
little boost up, which great,
but they weren't over the top.
And then that second show where people
went to happy hour and stayed out and
they went and they missed the first show
and they're in and you feel like you're
strapping on like Swat
team equipment backstage.
Oh here we're going through the door.
We're going to the door of this crack
house and the best part of my hands on
your shoulders, put your hands
on him, on the host, the host,
he's going to kick in a door is
he's going to get shot in the face.
We know he's dead. Yeah, that guy's
going to get mowed. The rookie thing.
Yeah. Look, Caitlin, you're second. Like
I think you'll catch a couple of shots.
You got your, you have your week, you've
got your vest on. At least though,
if you're in a good club, you know, they
know they're like your support team,
their headquarters. But there's the clubs
that are like, what man? And you're like,
come on. Like what? I don't
kick anybody out there.
Like this is what it is. Nobody are like,
yeah, but you can make it better. I love,
I love clubs that have, that had
their security so good that the pier,
there's like loud drunk guy and then
all of a sudden there's someone standing
behind him like Batman. It just
gives them a little tap. Like,
they haven't orchestrated,
but no one notices these people,
but they just slide up and get them
out the suit. You know what I mean?
It's just like,
yeah,
the guy that just comes behind and just
splits guys throwing like a, you know,
in the movies like a Ninja,
a century with a machine gun.
He just gets pulled her portion.
He's gone. Like that's, I
have one super intimidating looking guy.
Yes.
I don't understand why they dumb like
when they go like this is security and
it's a guy like half
my size. I'm like, no,
it's a woman. Yeah, there's a,
I've seen great female bouncers because
a lot of times those guys are not going
to push back on a woman hit her or she
talks some shit. Yeah. And there was a,
there was a lady and uh,
I was just in Montreal this past week
and there's a lady at one club that was
like roped,
like her arms were very strong and I
like tattoos and she has like her hair
pulled back and he's like scary post
apocalyptic white girl dreadlocks.
And you're like, oh, like,
and she was, you know, where
I'm watching her and I said,
she's laughing. I'm like, oh, I feel
really good about myself. Right.
Because she's intimidating. And also like
these guys that want to like, you know,
who's gonna throw me out?
Like if she punches you in the face and
you're fighting back tears and getting
thrown out, like this is
not good. Look for that.
That guy who thinks he's an Alpha male. So
you can be like, hey, hey, hey, all right,
I'll get out. I'll get out.
You know, psychologically
it works. Big, strong woman.
Yeah. And just not even that big,
just wirey yeah. You know, like,
like strong, you know, built, built,
strong like a security likes you,
it almost feels as good
as black people approval.
It's almost as good black
people where you're like,
I feel really good about myself.
That Cleveland Improv. Yes.
I know that. Not to Brag, you
don't have to feel like I did it.
I had a great set there and walked
outside and there's that little standing
river back there and uh, and uh, uh, tug,
tugboat went by blaring Tupac.
Yeah,
I yelled out tug life tagline.
I got a second laugh outside with people
having cigarettes. That's awesome.
It's so funny that you nailed one of
my, one of my choices. Perfect moment.
It felt great.
I also know that room
when it doesn't go course.
I remember the heckles I remember
a woman in the back going a,
your mama should have swelled that nut.
Oh my God.
And I remember,
uh,
a guy just like third row he's
going through. It's terrible, man.
That's the worst.
I remember I ran in New York and it put
me to sleep in Italian and Italian guy
going, oh man. Well you kidding me
here? Like, c'mon, let's get outta here.
Like audibly, during my setup,
that's worse because you know,
it's authentic. It's not like, hey,
you suck and it's undeniable.
I'm not doing well right now.
I'll read the comment cards. You ever
read those when you were a feature? Nope.
That's a bad idea.
I don't read the Youtube.
Oh,
I know.
I learned that I only didn't read them
because I probably didn't think about it.
If I was when I was still featuring,
I would have read them all, I'm
sure. Right. These validation,
and even if you were at 300 good ones, he
would find the too. Yeah. Oh yeah. Hey,
did you do that now? You got to do
that now. Even on Twitter or whatever.
The one guy that hates your guts.
Yeah. It's just, it just feels good.
That's the joy of stand up.
You gotta keep yourself feeling.
I don't get as many, you know,
like out and out. I hate you ones,
but like I get backhanded
compliments, which are, to me,
those are kind of fantastic. What's your
favorite one? Yeah. Got to tell us. Uh,
I did a throwback show and Montreal
with Wanda Sykes and Jo Koy unfortunate
Feemster throwback show.
They put clips,
old clips of us and everyone has
a mic and everyone can stop it.
You don't know. Do you know what clip
was coming? No, not really. They had,
they had doesn't forward like a
backyard party drunk and it once.
And I remember doing
that show and be like,
I remember it being fun and I was like,
oh my low close
Chris Gethard was backstage and I was
telling about it cause he was the,
he was the next show, not not throw back
and he just got quiet and I was like,
are you okay? He's like, I, I'm
just having horrible flashbacks.
I'm having like charges of terror
going through my body right now.
And I'm just like, yeah. And I guess we
were just sweating on stage, which I,
it was, it was, it sounded like,
like probably how skydiving fields.
I've never skydive but it felt like that.
Wait, what were you saying? Compliment.
Oh, so someone said like, uh,
these guys are really funny.
No one could have saved that show,
but boy they tried.
Oh show I thought did really well, which
was surprising to me but I don't know.
They're like good try though.
No one.
Amen for effort man.
Your show and like you try hard
that. And Tom and I both
hate when people are like,
oh we saw your special on Netflix is
good. It's pretty good. Pretty good,
pretty good, pretty good, pretty fun.
It's just that thing that everyone's
an expert on comedy, everyone.
Because everyone, I pretty
much, everyone's made someone
laugh at some point. Yes.
But a lot of these people are uh,
office managers or bosses where the person
has to laugh at this things you say.
And so you like Michael Scott go
like, oh, I'm funny. I'm funny.
And so everyone has an no.
You know,
I was on my couch on my fifth beer.
You were in front of a thousand
people by yourself. Uh, Tom.
And you know what I think
I know I would've done
different things than you and
it's like, Nah, you probably would have
shit yourself and ran off stage. Yeah.
Well cause we haven't done 15,
20 years of staff who said it.
But I think the more that I thought about
it, I was like, they're right. Every man,
every man thinks they're
hilarious. Yeah. To it. Like,
if you get them at the right time, they're
like, I'm pretty fucking funny. Yeah.
And so, yeah. And you know,
some of them are, yeah.
To be fair with them actually are
really funny. Yeah. But I still,
some of them are not to any of us,
uh,
not flinch a little when we're forced
to say out loud that were funny.
I'll never write professional.
Right. Right. That, but even then,
right then I couldn't say it because
it's just like too, it feels gross.
It feels gross. Yeah. A friend of mine
and I were saying we can hang out.
It's always hilarious when anyone on
ironically describes themselves as smart,
funny or tough. Oh my God.
Talking about themselves.
So like three guys rushed us and I like
fought him. I'm like the tough one.
And Mike, you're the toes. I worked
on this puzzle. I it, I mean I'm,
I'm pretty smart. Yeah.
I mean, good for you.
Smart.
Really smart people you'll find usually
don't lead with how smart they are. No,
because they understand the
all encompassing vastness
of human intelligence.
Right. Every, every smart versus met
someone that made them feel like a monk.
Of course. Every one of them.
Yeah. You know, like who?
Someone I knew someone who knew someone
who was hired as a, as a Simpsons writer.
And he went,
he wins like,
and he was always the smartest person
in the room and he went in that room and
he's like,
I've never felt stupid in my whole life.
So it's like you need stuff like that.
Wait, can I, can I, sorry, I just, yeah,
we pull up the Instagram video that we
watched earlier and just see if Matt
feels the same thing we do. Okay. Because
that's kind of, it's a long list tangent,
tangent of like what's an calf feels?
Grody yeah.
And you're like, does
this feel, does this feel?
What am I feeling like I'm not sure if I'm
sorry I interrupted you. No, no, no. I,
that was that, that was my say. It
was okay. Just like, tell me how this,
how does this make you feel?
Just watch this. It's a video.
It's grief as a full body experience. So
this is a dance of grief, this person.
Okay.
I mean
this is just letting the grief out,
but yeah,
I'm sorry to be,
I mean she's obviously talented.
She's got good movement since
it feels like a very white,
it's a white lady thing. You Do, right?
Yeah, I think so. You know what it's
like. The thing is, it's like I grew up,
I grew up in Portland, Oregon where
my parents took me to so many things.
Like here's the difference.
Here's the difference.
If you're in a theater and you're like,
I'm here to watch experimental dance.
They were asking for it. Yes you are
right. And I kind of, I will be honest,
I kind of respect the fact that she
went ahead and put this up. Yeah.
Cause that's inviting all kinds of
shredding. Right. But at this, by the way,
none of the comments are mean.
We're the only people are going to meet.
All the comments are like beautiful
boy. Hey listen. I'm like Kara.
Kara is always just, just punching me
over the head over it. You're always,
you never are. You know, you'd never,
I'm never the guy who just like
gives it three beats and goes,
oh fuck this chick. You don't like, you're
not that guy. Never. No, not really.
But like, no, you're like
at the same time it's,
it did,
is she putting this up to help
with others? Grief, grief,
to show her dance scale because he is not
a good dancer. It's uh, the, the person.
It doesn't matter.
Does it matter the person who put it up,
it's not the person dancing.
As I listen,
as I'm giving you the benefit of the
doubt, I'm still laughing. It's still,
I mean I'm still because you're, it's a
little bit cringy yes it is. And like,
yeah, like let's say, let's say
I did this, it's me doing that.
That would be entertained.
Well, but here's the thing.
I respect this more than an
incredibly fit celebrity that's like,
like just showing his or her amazing
body and going and going and going.
There were times I didn't love myself
or postpartum picks that models and
actresses put up like two weeks
postpartum and the flat belly. Yeah.
I'm putting these pictures up to
inspire other women like no you're not.
You're not showing your pockmarked ass.
You know what I mean?
Hanging off the edge of a chair,
you know it's to insight jealousy and
envy. Yeah. Like there's that weird thing.
She's English but she does,
she does a imitations of celebrity like
videos and pictures where she's like was
girl a woman in a bikini jump
roping insanely like soul,
like soul cut and then she does it.
She's like their bellies jumping.
I went the same hashtags
which is just like perfect
video shut up Schnitzel.
This video makes me so uncomfortable
because it's so earnest cause like I'm not
capable,
I'm not that in touch with my feelings.
So when I see other people
doing it I'm like Oh God,
God gives me so much anxiety to
be in touch with your feelings.
That's what I was saying
is that it's great.
The balance in the universe is that the
earnest sincere person exists and they
are actually helpful. Good to have. Right.
That non cynical like earnest person
and then the balance is at the universe
feels that we're pieces of shit like us
to mock them and some people enjoy that.
But I don't know if it's the pieces of
shit. Well you know, I will say I because,
because,
because it's like when this person
does that and puts it out there,
they know what they're doing
and they had got you got it.
If you're going to be an artist,
you better have a thick ass skin.
I think you're right. You know, cause it's
like, and kind of go. Yeah, you're right.
All right, cool. I'll, I'll
take it. I'll tell you,
don't get butthurt because I'll put
it this way. Back to my childhood.
I remember going to these performances
and like look at my dad and he's so
uncomfortable, you know, it
wasn't comfortable because
it's just like, you know,
yeah. Try to take it and you know,
he wants to be like, this is dumb.
Like he wants to so bad, you
know. But he's kind of just,
just trying to keep an open this,
your mother forced you guys to watch
this horse shit. I think it's just,
I'm kind of try to map, look like my dad
would take me a little bit, but like, uh,
like he also would be like,
alright, you know, let's,
let's go to this thing
and take me to that.
Take me to every Schwartzenegger
movie every day. His bond. But because
I had none knowledge and perspective,
I wasn't like,
I feel like right now there's
a movement and you know,
like fucking white pride anti women
dumbos that while we're red hats and blah,
blah, blah. And those guys,
and I think those guys took those
movies seriously as a commando was real.
They thought Schwartzenegger was
really, and that was a real, you know,
and they like the enemy.
Ah,
I just want to stab someone so bad and
they really want a death star to blow up.
But that shit doesn't exist.
Trump's sells smart by the way.
It's set up in multiple interviews and so,
you know, it's true. No, it's true. By,
by our definition. Yeah.
You know it's true. Yeah.
He probably also says he's
funny and tough. He has said,
he said when that horrible Parkland
shooting took place at that school,
he's like, I would have gone in
there unarmed. Yes, for sure.
And like he's like fucking,
yeah, I would have run into easy,
I've heard an assault rifle.
I would have run into that phone bro.
For real though. Like you don't know man.
I know I've done some wild shit. Yeah.
For Real.
Why don't we give him a chance next
time there's some somebody hold up in a
trader Joe's or something.
Let's just fly in.
Yes. He said stand down.
Stand down. Swat team.
Yeah. No, that's smart. Tough.
And what's the other one?
And Fun and funny because
people will sometimes,
sometimes people will tell
you after shows, they'll be
like, I'm pretty funny guy.
And you're like, all right. Or I'll
get emails. They'll say, um, you know,
I watched your special or I was
at your show and I have, uh,
some material that I think nice
you would be able to, to like,
I'm not gonna use it cause I don't do it.
I'll give it to you and I'll be like,
okay, cool, thanks. And they'll
be like, so do you want it?
If you want it hit me up.
And I'm like, no, I'm, I'm good. And
then they'll follow up and they're like,
it's fucking like Primo material
and then I'll not respond and,
and they'll write, hey, uh,
I know she didn't respond,
but I'm going to share
it with you anyways.
And it'll be like a of a,
of just writing with no punctuation.
Oh God.
You're like, right, that's fine.
Well, and it's all, it's also like
willful ignorance where it's like, look,
I don't want to learn all the, I didn't
want to go through all that stuff.
You've gone through it. Yeah. I just want
to get it. I want you to think the lady,
I hated the thought,
the pornography of suffering that like
American idol and all those shows do
where they show you the
people that succeed.
You thought you could sing
it killing yourself or shame.
But there was one lady who came on and
just couldn't dance and couldn't sing and
then had a meltdown,
which she's like,
I know you can do that thing where you
put people's voices through it like a
filter and make someone a star
do it for me. And it's like,
why would we do that? I want to be a
star so you can have all this. What is,
what do I gain in breaking my neck to
do that? So it's like that thing of,
of someone just being like,
well I know you did stand up
and shitty rooms for 20 years,
but like I just want to skip ahead.
You had a friend who I'm no longer
friends with actually. She was like, yeah,
I'd like, I'd love to do what you do,
but I don't want to go through like,
you know,
learning how to do it and failing and so
I just want to be like successful at it.
I was like, I don't think I can
be friends with you. I mean,
I really don't think I can know
a person is horrible. Yeah.
I mean it's like I love being lazy.
It's the best.
It doesn't get you anything and you
need to recognize that. So gross.
You don't deserve things. You just want
the glory. Speaking is an only child.
Right. You know what I mean? I always
thought I was a golden golden boy.
I'm not right.
But it's like
the amount of people who just
want stuff handed to them.
And it's a stereotype for millennials
and I don't think it's any more or less
true than our generation or whatever,
but like the amount of people who once
they hit 30 and they're not Drake slash
Zuckerberg,
right.
I wonder how it's going to shatter
their psyches cause we're like, no, no,
I'm a blow up.
I'm going to blow up.
It's the pressure to be a Zuckerberg by
the time you're 30 because there are so
many fuck heads that are super multi
millionaires and now you feel inadequate
because you're not a multimillionaire
by the time you're 30 and that's just
silly.
And the whole thing really is like if
you actually just get into the work of it
and like you really love it.
You got, it sounds Cliche,
but the ups and downs come with
that and you will feel like, oh,
I did something meaningful. You don't
want to miss out on all that stuff.
The good and the bad. The bad stuff
helps a lot. Absolutely. It helps.
A couple of things I have to update
on before I do this. Excuse me,
this advertisement. Sure Bud. Um,
first is that I got the message that
added show in Montclair is happening
Wednesday, November 14th.
It is on sale this Friday,
this Friday Thompson grow.com tour.
We're adding a show in Montclair
at the Welmont. Additionally,
the bikes socks are on
sale now. Yup. Socks.
You know, they are, I will
say I want a pair of those.
I will send you a pair of
those and you can go and, uh,
get them there@merchantmethod.com slash
Tom Sigora got them up on my Instagram.
Just want someone to give that to
their mom. Who Does it? I love bikes,
not realizing what it is. Just like
something, a convict stream kids.
Yeah. So there's, there's that. And
have you seen, you said familiar?
Oh my gosh. Cool. It's so good.
And they're so beautiful. The tick,
right? She's gorgeous. And it works.
That's the music that indicates
it's time to talk about teeth.
So quip is bringing us this dental update.
Do you have a nice smile?
Even going to the dentist,
taking care of a year.
Twice a year I had a,
a snore guard made.
Okay. And the first one
they made didn't work. Oh,
I took it home. And um, you know, they
take a mold of your mouth. Oh, okay.
I didn't know that. Yeah.
And then I brought it into
the dentist. Yeah. Try It on.
And he basically like under his
breath was like, fuck. I was like,
why? He's like, he goes, we'll send
you a new one. And I go, well, yeah,
I mean it's got to work. Right. So,
so anyways, they sent the new one.
Do you have any complaints?
Oh, it's saved our lives.
If you have somebody in your
marriage, your spouse, wherever,
whoever sleeps next to you that snores,
go to the dentist and get a professional
snore guard word. Does it go?
So it just took your mouth to
mouth and it has bands, uh,
the, the top deck dish
and the bottom tray. Yeah.
Have a band that are adjustable.
So what happens is the principle of
the idea is see snoring is caused by
different things for different people.
Right.
Most of the time it's that someone's
lower jaw actually drops down.
Yes. And then obstructs the air passage.
So the mouth guard with those bands,
depending on how tight you make them,
just keeps your lower jaw up.
So you fall asleep and instead of your
mouth dropping, oh, it just stays up.
Stays forward.
But what if you sleep like with breathe
through your mouth when you sleep?
I mean there's, yeah, there's
open and there's, yeah,
there's air can pass through it. Okay.
It's just like, oh, of course. Keeps your,
and then if you have like
a really strong drop,
you can make the band super
tight in your mouth. Like just
looks sexy, right? You want to laugh.
A lot of guys that have their mouth garden
and it also, you feel because you're,
when you're,
you don't realize when you snore a lot.
I didn't that your sleep is super fucked
up. [inaudible] always like dragon,
like God. And ever since I
started, I started wearing
them years ago. He's got it.
This is a new one. Uh, always feel
completely differently. Really. Yeah.
You sleep deeper. Yeah.
I don't always snore,
but like my wife will wake me
up and I ordered my first one.
Like when she recorded it,
she recorded me snoring.
And this is back when we lived in the
Rampart division. This is like, Oh yeah,
near Macarthur Park.
Right. I remember that.
Every time I go to the dynasty
typewriter. I think of you guys. Is that,
that new place? How is it? It's good.
Yeah. It feels real old school. You know,
a Jamie who used to run
the Improv runs it and he,
he just bunch of different weird shows.
Uh, it's the one thing is parking is,
is just a monster over and your car is
going to get Jack Cooper down there.
Uber. Yeah. There you go. Well,
there's the heads up, just Uber, Uber.
But the shows are good, but it's a
fun, it's a fun room. Yeah. Um, before,
I don't want to just, I just
want to jump over it. Your,
you started basically a new
version of your podcast.
What's it called? It's called advice
from a dipshit with Matt Broenger.
That's perfect. Thank you. I'm
very, very proud of the name I,
everything I've ever named, it's
just like, doesn't make me laugh.
Like every album, every special. Like
is it, is it a name that makes me laugh?
You know what I mean? I always, I,
I, you know, we both have bits about,
about tattoos. Oh yeah.
We both hate meaningful
tattoos. I hate meaningful special titles.
I don't hate him. Oh, there's gotta be,
I know there's a few that we got to talk
about it at all. So, you know, I mean,
it depends, but, but uh, or, or
album titles are sincere ones.
You mean like if someone
calls, you know, like,
like I'm waiting for the guy to name his
comedy album or a special beast where
it's like, which is a nickname would give
you like a compliment, not a nickname.
We gave each other, but
anyway, that guy's a beast.
Then the picture is like,
first thing I had to change
the caution tape. Caution tape.
Caution tape to this comedies. Too
dangerous. It was a crime scene.
There's a crunchy to killed. So hard.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Oh, tape over the mouth.
Equal opportunity
offender. Uh, the victim,
but the podcast was called
Ding Dong or with Matt Bronco.
I would still like it, but people who
don't know who I am, there's like, what?
Who is this? Tara? Would you got it like
a rest of, what's the billboard? What do,
what's the show about? Okay, I get it.
You don't like what I have
to read it and understand.
I feel like advice from a dip. Shit.
You're like, I get it. Yeah. So people,
people can call in. Can I read the,
the number? Of course, yes. Of course.
People call in and just leave a message,
like whatever you want to ask about
because I feel like, you know,
I got married at at 43, I, I've had a Dui.
I made a lot of fun in the sky.
It's in my life,
but all of which kind of made me who I am.
They're like,
we're all made of mistakes,
you know? And it's just like,
it's kind of become this dear dip shit,
Abby for millennials and older
where people are just like,
and I get older people asking me how the,
how I get, how you get over heartbreak.
I get, um, people, uh,
younger people going, like,
my parents really want me to be this,
but I want to be this. Yeah. You know,
I get people, like, how do
I tell my family I'm gay?
And it's like I draw from experience,
uh,
just people that I've known
who've gone through this,
but mostly through my own experience
and I'm actually going to have, um, uh,
I started having like guests on every
couple of episodes to listen with them
with me because I don't hear him
beforehand. I don't pick the messages.
My producer partner Amanda does.
And so she'll, she'll be like, Ooh,
I got some in the barrel for you
this time. And she'll play them.
And I'll be like, whoa, like what the
shit? And like I'm doing them live now.
And so it's fun because the audience
hears him for the first time with me.
And there's nothing like a packed
room where a guy's like, hey man,
love your comedy. I got a weird
Dick. I'm like, all right. Yeah,
we'll live with that. We'd be a lot of
fun. It's a lot of fun. And it's like I,
I treat everything sincerely.
I make it into entertaining,
you know, as a comedian.
But it's like I'm not here
to make fun of people. Right.
And so people know that it's kind of like,
I came to use the term safe space,
but it's like you say anything you want,
don't prank me,
don't do a character cause it ain't gonna
make it. I'm not going to play it. Well,
you're going to be respectful
of them it sounds like. Yeah.
So the number is 323-SEVEN-SIX-3228 if
you want to call it three g three seven
six three zero two two eight and just
leave a message. Love and, and it's fun.
It's only a half hour so it doesn't
take too much time in and out.
You can throw it on and, and it's, and
it's, it's, it's a blast man. I love it.
I love doing it. I love it
man. Yeah. Thanks man. Yeah,
I'm very proud of you for doing that.
Are you guys, you guys know here,
I'm so inspired by how big this podcast
is and how awesome. It's so fun doing it.
Yeah. Cause I've always been a fan
of both of your voices as Comedians,
like your people that I hang out with.
And I always just laugh at a time.
I saw you on the road and you were like
just in a Mcdonald's and I was like, Hey,
there's water at an airport. And I
always, I was thinking about this,
I might've said this on the show,
but I remember the first time we did
stand up actually together and it was in,
it was in Venice and you
went up and crushed and then
someone up after I went up
after you and did eh, and I got off
stage and I was like, who is that guy?
Cause I'd never seen you. Yeah. And this
guy sidled up next to me and was like,
yeah, you know why he didn't do
that? Well, because that guy,
he's not supposed to kill like that.
And he didn't know you at all based on
how he thought you looked or something.
Oh. And I was like, okay, fuck this
guy. Yeah. Yeah. Tom's cool. Yeah.
I like it says name Tom. I like Tom. Yeah.
But it was that thing like Dion, Udacity.
Yeah. Of people to be like, look to
see you. I got same guy. Be like, ah,
it's a chick depravity. Okay.
Of course. You know what I mean?
It's just that these categories sure.
People put, yeah, I love watching.
I still love watching standup.
I still love watching comedy and I
love being surprised. That is true.
Any surprises?
The best elements where you're just like,
where did this person come
from? But I never go, oh,
this person is going to eat it ever.
No,
cause you don't know you. I do
that. No, you don't ever know. Yeah.
Do you do if a guy looks like he's
nervous a little bit or if he immediately
comes out with way too much
cursing right off the bat or hey,
how are you guys doing tonight?
How's everybody feeling?
Ah, or you can see, you can see
like, like kind of hallway backstage.
A bravado like fake confidence.
If it's someone who's like fucking,
you should have seen my show Thursday
or something and you're like, oh,
this is going to be bad. [inaudible]
like that. That's that's Oh yeah,
definitely are talking about another show.
How well they did.
I'm like it treating it
like a locker room. Yeah.
That's a lot of hot chicks there,
man. Have you been bro? Real hot shit.
You're like this guy's going
to eat his own dick. Yeah.
All right.
You ever see those comics before?
Like when we were starting to
come up to book book shows,
there was always a guy in the alleyway
kind of pacing back and forth.
Nervously listening like heavy metal
music to get himself palms like that guy.
Yeah. Shadow boxing. Shadow
box. Always a bad sign. Yeah.
Trying to get themselves psyched
to go out at midnight real quick.
I was about to go out and we let her
bring us out on at midnight and I'm back
there with Hassan Minhaj and I'm like,
my legs are so stiff.
I'm just stretching my thought.
I was just like, he's like,
you just stretched before you
out. And I'm like, no, I never
do. And he's just like long as you're
not shadow boxing. He says the same time
we knew the words he used to
get ripped at the early shows.
That Guy Cameron, it was at
the cat club. He would just,
he'd be like, I'm up, I'm up the class.
And he would just like whiskey whiskey.
Yeah. But then when it
was, it'd be really funny,
like you're seeing like a seven minute,
oh,
so this your ra next week you'd be like,
I can't wait to see that guy again.
And he would be like,
he'd just drink like five whiskies and
then he wrote about you fucking bitch.
You,
you'd be laughing at him being a mess.
Be like, you're not laughing at that
funny anymore. You're like, this is crazy.
Like this is a guy screaming at a bus
stop basically. You know, you're like,
this is bad. Which you Matt,
would you judge this guy?
Ah, fuck. I can't hear him.
I like to have some,
I would like to have
to do is your roadmap.
I would like to have some
sex. Oh, Mike, you come
last lady 10 15 times before I even went.
And beau marks.
So he's just putting it out there.
Yeah,
about that ladies.
I would like to pass her one to have sex.
So what does he want though?
The nuance. Well, he's saying,
are you tired of poets, poets? Jesus.
Just say what you life is short.
We found him last week.
We played this,
those clips and we talked about it for
awhile. It turns out he's got other clips.
No, wait a minute. What did mommy say
last week when he came into our lives?
When we go down this guy's rabbit
hole? Yeah, let me, let me,
let me say, uh, that's, that's awful.
Yeah. And ridiculous and just, uh,
all right buddy. Like, you know,
cut it out. But counterpoint.
If that guy was like in a bar and it
was like different people going up and
singing little little,
little folk songs,
country songs and it went up and was
like, boom, Dick do like to have some sex.
I like to have some titties. It'd
be like, Hey man, that's fun.
That's how you send that message. You
don't just go, I like some sex. Yeah,
I'd like some titties in my, in. My last
lady came 15 times where I went. Boom.
All right man.
Women like a little romance compared
to most of the people we played.
This guy is romantic. That's a sad
thing we're on. We're also in Neward.
The fact that he has and why? Why so
close to the camera. Listen, we've,
we've analyzed the visuals on this
capsulated that exactly
because what that last week,
that's what we were saying like you
can't just come out like that with women.
Women don't respond. Maybe other dudes
respond well to that, but you're right.
That's what he needed an accessory.
Now women don't like that. No,
you don't say it's
staring in someone's face.
You kind of say it off in the distance,
you know what I mean?
Like you're an old man bartender. And so
it was like, hey, how's it going Sam? Me?
And he's like, yeah,
that's funny. He's not,
he's saying it to the universe.
I mean everyone feels
that way from time to time
labeled the this folder,
the make you cum guy.
So let's see.
No, I wish though. That's a bad, bad cold.
You can just my club to someone
hurting them. Lastly though,
what is he watching Rachel Maddow last
week it was Rachel Maddow their way.
Now it's your way. It's some kind of CSI
type drama. I think so, wait a minute.
The taking the teeth out is
really a bold move. I know.
Because last week I think that helps his
mouth technique. It probably does, right?
Cause all right. Just say that in the
presence of police. He did this last week.
Look, he ended it. I remember
with a big smile. Yep.
Hey, I noticed that as Trumpers
were creepy. Yeah, we'll wait.
We'll wait to false looking.
Right when everyone,
when someone looks weathered
but their teeth straight,
like it's weird.
Nothing just straight up
sex or by no hard feelings.
Hey listen, I want to, I don't
want to have hard feelings.
Put your teeth in assholes. Yeah,
just put your fucking teeth in Bro.
Claim person will be clean.
Somebody's mail is good down there.
You know I keep my shelf,
the unmentionable this thing,
the thing that women are self conscious
about in shouldn't be. He's like,
make sure it smells like who's heat and
make demands on someone's vagina. Yeah.
Well he said it's about myself.
Cleaned up. I will. I will.
I will bet $1,000. He has real smelly
balls. Would you smell them if he asks?
You know, I would pay someone.
I'd pay a Vegas Professional.
Oh,
it doesn't matter.
They should be somebody out there
and watch to hook up. Check.
I wish I could be a rich woman also
rich. That's harder. Younger or whatever.
Whatever.
Get in with her
gate in with her. You're not only one
sex, he wants to live off a lady. Yeah.
Was He watching?
It looked like a black and white.
I feel like he checks off all the
boxes for what? The modern woman,
I would not have predicted it, but that,
that first video he is watching MSNBC.
I did not think that was his lane. I
mean, I think it's kind of immaterial what
he's watching.
The fact that if reflecting on his glasses
and he's still looking at the video
and go on, I'm gonna put it off. I
mean, you've been on camera a lot.
He's framed really nicely. He's
framed real close. Yeah. Keep,
do you remember that movie election?
Yeah,
I remember the cut to when he finds out,
Matthew Broderick finds out his kids, uh,
kids,
coworker,
his co teacher is having sex with Reese
Witherspoon's high school girl character
and the closeup on his face and he goes,
you can't believe how when, or pussy? Yes.
Pardon me. Yeah. And it's, it's
close because it's awful. Yeah.
Because when a guy is talking about
that stuff and you're that close,
there's nothing worse.
Yeah.
It's one of the funniest parts of
the movie and he's just like, ah man,
don't talk like that,
you know? Yeah, that's,
well that's the thing of phenomenon
on our show is that all the creepers,
the creeper guys, the framing is always
too close. They're generally shirtless.
Their lip poorly. The sound is bad.
Like they all check these boxes. Yeah.
Of Psycho. Well behaviors or thing.
He's not done making demands. There's a,
there's another video. There's
demand. No, it seems like, I mean I'm,
I'm just reading kind of the notes
about it, but let's see if he,
oh, hello up there.
You're doing great today.
Full volume background. Go T.
Thank you for all the vagina.
Any shots.
I appreciate that very much.
He cleaned up at least now he's in a
nice couch. TV is ground full volume.
I for his video,
I'm going to go out on a limb
here and say he's doing like a,
like a politician move. A man walked
up to me in Indiana though. Oh right.
And he said, my taxes are too high.
And I said, you know what? They are.
No one walked up to you.
No one ever has no one.
Nobody said this guy posted shots.
I'm going to go out and I'm gonna go out
on a limb and say thanks to the hundred.
I mean
maybe
I would like to encourage our audience
to send him some Pussy Dick Painting.
See now he's going to get a time.
Yeah,
I would really hope you just staged
it in a square. I really hope they do.
Yeah. Loud, beautiful warm
Herman on here. No, no.
They get shit. Got Sports.
Great. Stay with you longer.
Cheat on you with another one and
won't cheat on you with another guy.
Oh see he's kind of being
self deprecating there.
He saying it's like saying I'm
not the best looking guy and I'll,
I won't cheat on you.
Yeah. Good looking guy and
I can have anybody he won't
possibly by curious. Right.
You really want you and you weren't
you for that report I got on my arm
but hold on also.
Do you want everyone looking guy? He
won't. Just like, he'll love you today.
He does.
Think about that ladies and get rid of
these tattoos whenever you're oh going to
be all lengthy and sag you. They're
not gonna look as good as they are now.
Don't get that to
Islamic.
Came up in my throat was telling
you ladies, you can send them pics,
but not if you have.
I mean that's it. This is the, this is
the old white guy. Entitlement for sure.
Yeah. Let me, here's what I want.
Here's what I want. Here's what I want.
Here's what you should do. Here's what
you should. Here should. You should do it
and he gives nothing. Yeah, he put in his
teeth and we're supposed to high five.
Well, he grew up, he grew a stylish,
trimmed goatee. That is pretty nice.
I put in my teeth today for
this video. Wow. Thanks asshole.
But get rid of these statues.
Get rid of your table ready or should I
put my teeth and get rid of that tattoo
that costs you $200 and send me some
money. Jesus Christ. What an ass hole.
You wear a hat that says f g t r
t d on it. What does that mean?
What do you think it means? Let's start
there. What are you thinking of me?
F. G. T. R. D. D.
Uh,
it can't be fat. Great titties,
right? Cause that's tube.
That's two descriptors before the tea.
No, but I just, I know the show it.
I think the team's gotta be
that our t. D. F. G. T. R. Td.
What could that mean? Just like
it's a hat, you know? Yeah. Okay.
I mean, can I send you one?
You send me a hat? Yeah. Cheap.
I know that every Lester is just crying,
laughing. I mean, it's something terrible,
isn't it? We haven't actually
said we haven't defined it yet.
We haven't defined it.
We've dropped it a couple times,
but you know what it means. You just
haven't said to me in, that's right. Okay.
Yeah. That's horrible. Well,
should I just put it on and walk around
like a mall in Sherman oaks or something
and just see if I get
punched in the mouth. Well,
why don't we let the audience try to
come up with what they think that means.
Let's not,
let's not,
let's give it a week and see if people
can come up with what they think it is on
the message boards and
on the Facebook page.
Let them discuss and we'll see if that
in fact is a shirt or hat we can make 'em
stay on the line. Also, by the way, um,
made an an another video somebody found.
Okay, we got to go soon. Does it stand
for first? Great Tang replaces that Dick.
That's it. Did I nail it? You
nailed it that first time.
You get some time and so much
better. Yes. It's just a monster.
It doesn't move of the lip.
Millennial, lesbian. Oh, okay.
First Great Tongue replaces that day.
Anti male oppression store
a woman who hasn't been, uh,
it got enough oral from her lover.
That's true. You know what I mean?
Just put it in. Thank you. Like my wiener.
Yeah. Thank you for naming it by the way.
Sure. So now we can sell it as first.
Great Tongue replaces that Dick.
First Time. It's got to be
great. Tom's gotta be great.
You gotta be just someone who
knows how to use it that day.
They ain't alive.
Juvenile.
Oh
wait. It was two feet everywhere. This
guy does it everywhere. One, two, three,
four staying alive. And he uses his
lung infection as an instrument.
And the way they had it your way better.
That is the United States
because it will be,
we'll get together with the newer remix.
Yeah.
Wow. Let's see. What would
you rather have though?
The Mickey Come Guy's teeth
or this guy a hundred times.
Yeah. They need to put him on the
voice, right. Because it's like, oh,
all right. Yeah. You know, it's a talent.
It's hard to guess the person's, uh, sex.
You're listening to it. Definitely
hard to guess the age. Yeah.
And I could see someone being like,
man, that's that good rhythmic soul.
I'll take it. And it turns any
smile and the teeth. Oh, have to be,
that's what that show is. If
you don't see him, see him.
Okay.
On
live outside.
He really has a lung infection.
Uh, no. Yeah. Doctors.
Rusa I mean, I'm just thinking is this
tragic tale? I have a month to live.
No. Our, our, uh,
our producer labeled this file that I'm
looking at the top of it. Like, oh no, no,
no. We've just always, he, he,
he's a homeless man. I don't know.
I don't know anything about him.
I just know that we've had now
three or four times videos of him.
This particular man in different
settings singing, staying alive. Yeah.
Before he looked like he could be outside
a restaurant. Yeah. Yeah. Now he's in,
in the San Andres on the
side of the road. Yeah.
Gotcha. If he's like, pull over
to fixing my tire and this guy
and he's like, I'm, I'm not
going to help you change a tire.
Okay. Just stay United
day. The line. Yeah.
I think he's, he's really just
had too much sun. Yeah. Jamie.
Got to go to press, pause the problem.
Um, can we, can you stick around or no?
Yeah. I have to pick up my son.
Okay. Can, uh, do you have,
do you have time to hang out for like
another 30 40 minutes? Yes. Absolutely.
Why don't we do that? Let's pause.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's great.
And we're back.
I just took brawny pants to pick up our
son. How was that? Did you enjoy that?
I enjoyed it. It's cute,
right? Yeah, I liked it. Um,
it did make me laugh that Tom
made a good point. He's like,
I don't think you can get it out of the
car. And I'm like, yeah, you're right.
It's a preschool. Yeah, I get it. Yeah.
Cause he was yelling at walk in ahead
of you. Just a grown man. Noah was true.
I didn't think about it.
That's just the visions of a divorced
dads that deserve to get divorced.
Yeah. Tommy. God Damn it, it's mine. I
don't care what any court says. You know,
they've, I'm sure they had to deal
with that sort of thing. Oh yeah.
I can't be just standing in the parking
lot and parents like I've never seen him
and I'm sure there's probably not
a teacher. Oh no, not a caretaker.
There's probably friends that have
tagged along. Sure. Been like,
why can't I come in? Oh No,
no, no. And then, and like
walk in and they're like, yeah,
I, I remember like my, my parents
are both educators now retired,
but my dad used to, he was
in administration the last
like 10, 15 years. And he's,
he was a principal and a vice principal.
And at one point he was principal at
this place near our house called, uh,
called Holly Rude. That's like,
like maybe k through five.
And I remember walking up and my dad's
was, is, is like taller than me now.
He's kind of shrunk with AIDS,
but like,
he's a big guy and he's just
destroying these kids in foursquare.
And it was just so fun to watch,
but it was like I was walking
onto the playground. I'm like, I,
this is feels so weird. I'm
like, I'm like, Dad, hey.
And all the kids just turning to my dad,
hey, like they all y'all back at me.
But it was like my dad's like, oh, it's
my son. And we were like, okay, okay.
But it's just like, that was
my first exposure to, you know,
you can't just walk in here, you know,
it's just so I'm very conscious of it.
No, of course. And there's a code to get
in and they watch those kids like, Huh?
You got to, they ain't going
nowhere. You have to, yeah,
I know he's fucking psychos out.
Right.
My old voting place used to be inside
a grade school that was down the street
from my, Nah. I'd go in there and I'm
like in the hallway alone, I'm like,
this is not good. Where's the
boating? Why'd you put it here?
And I see the sign and I just run
over to it and get in line like whew.
Thank God.
No,
just a bad. Yeah, no. And I love
is Matt wanting to put our um,
lung infection guy on the voice. So
great. Which I think is such a great idea.
I was laughing at that. Um, especially
cause you're right, that I've done,
I've only said I show
once, like they, they,
the judges have their backs turned
to the, yeah. Don't, why is that?
Just that you're not biased by,
I think that's the idea. Yeah.
I've only seen it once, twice,
but we are in the age where,
you know, it's silly. No,
but I'm saying you sell people get
huge careers because they look,
yeah.
Yeah.
Where's your telling me about that white
singer who sounds black and they were
listening? Oh yeah. And the
other day. Yeah. Oh I've,
I could tell I could go when
Bobby Caldwell's a hit song,
which you won't do for love. What you
won't do for love came out. It came out,
it came out like 25, 30 years
ago. Yeah. It's like a silhouette.
They wouldn't put him on an album cover.
They would put on purpose and they knew
because it was a hit with black urban
hit and they were like,
do not show it. Scott.
I grew up thinking that guy was
black. No, if you hear the song,
I thought it was black.
Yeah.
Also. Uh, um, he did. Um,
so how does the song go? Sing
it cause I forget it. Well, do,
do pho Lou Bennett,
pepto,
it's an attorney.
James that comes on.
Everyone feels good and raided
the barbecues. Yeah, it's
a, yeah, it's a white guy.
He's a white guy. He looks like
a real cracker too. You should,
you should check out the song. Open your
eyes. Common sampled it for that song.
The light. There are time
that Tim too. Thanks guys.
White guys white. What's Bobby
also? That's why we call. Yeah,
he still tours. He's still, he does
like standards and stuff, but yeah.
Now Alan Thicke
sounds, yeah. He was kind of like a
modern day. What's that? Blurred lines.
Yeah. I don't think his, his dad Robin.
It sounds whiter than anyone. Yeah, he is.
He skipped generations. You know, if you
guys had like a red headed kid, like what?
How'd this happen? Like same thing,
right? Right. Real soulful son. He is,
he's super soulful.
Doug Stanhope had that bit about, remember
that the woman that went on like the,
uh,
Britain's got talent and saying,
you know the song and killed it and
like, and was like, oh my God, and,
and stay at home.
It was like,
have you heard about the
unattractive woman who couldn't say,
has anyone heard of this, this wondrous
creature? And it's like, oh my,
and it hit me. I was like,
oh, that's all that was.
She came out and she was
just Kinda dumpy older lady.
Turns out that she also
had some mental yes.
But it's like, why was that so
surprising? You know what I mean? Like,
I like the unattractive person that
sings the sacs soulful song, you know,
about being left or whatever. The
English woman, she had mental problems.
That's what's her name.
She's English and she won
like the American. Exactly.
What exactly we're talking to them, right?
Yeah. It's different. That's different.
FTT Rtd. Yeah. She looked like
she looked like a bill. Bellacheck
yeah. Yeah. Kara. Kara for New
England and I got her that tee shirt.
That's like the many moods of Bella
check. Oh yeah. And it's like same face,
static. Furious. I'm relaxed.
Can I have a sip of your coffee?
I've been drinking so much water that
I need something to stop the hydration.
Right, right, right. Um, just,
uh, you know, uh, to voice.
Could you imagine him? Because here's
the thing with the lung infection, dude,
this is big bill.
Bellacheck just see the one sports person.
I know her name. Everyone's
screaming it right now. Susan. Yes.
Susan Boyle. Go. Yeah.
But the thing with the lung infection man,
uh,
that we've deduced is that
there's actually some talent
he had. He's on key. He has
really good rhythm. You know,
it's a little off putting because he is a,
he is a leathery man.
He's asked about four
teeth evenly spaced apart.
Yeah. And it's like he took out
certainty. How did that work?
Perfectly spaced. I did other
ones stay, you know, like,
like Spartan warriors while the rest
of the soldiers die. Realize why
is that? He is definitely, you're
like, this guy needs more teeth. Yup.
But you also realize you can get
by with that many teeth, you know?
And I never really thought
about that until I saw his name.
There's so many things he can't eat dark.
You can start all,
you can pull that off
a rib short. Yes, yes.
You can eat spare like pork ones are soft.
Bobby Lee has no ballers
chooses steak in the front of his mouth.
Cheery the front teeth.
Bobby gets some olders he's doesn't have,
he's been without them for so long and
he's just used to not choose steak.
No good. It's weird. It's weird
that he does something weird, right?
Such a straight laced normal dude.
Such a square doesn't just take his pants
off and anyone and presence right now,
but you need the front teeth to chew up,
like to take a bite of something real
important and then you need the backs.
The rest are superfluous. But what if he
has? What if that guy has great Maulers?
That's all you need.
Sparkling Ivers but pulls up.
He pulls all the brushes back.
They're meticulously flosses.
He can get them whitened.
Who would check that shit out? I will
say that guy has no problem flossing.
Easy peasy jump school.
He might have a nice guy.
Okay,
what'd you rather pay?
You're going to spend about $25
you're going to go to, okay.
You're going to watch, you're going
to sit, you're going to watch,
even if the staying alive guy belong.
Infection guy.
Yeah,
or the grief dancer.
Oh, say United state United. Yeah. I
like to party. Yeah, that's a funny man.
I don't know. I don't need
this. If I'm a little fucked up,
I'm losing my mind with that guy.
He's going to walk on stage and I'm
going to turn to the bar and I'd go,
everyone gets a drink. It's a good
time. You smoke something a little.
Like if I get a little hit, a shot, I'd
be like say, you know, I'd be like, dude,
I do it again and I just start throwing.
But he's got to close with stay United.
That's true. Although we don't
know if he does any others.
Maybe he just does that 25
minutes of stay United. So yes,
it might be the same song over and over,
but that's the one that's doing
this for an hour
because I know this guy's making a good,
like you got hit like a door dealers
and it's going to be a lot of
people just laughing at him.
What a board.
A Basketball Jersey.
Just as you start to feel bad for him
and you're like, man, this is fucked up.
He'd be like, I hate your girl's pussy
too. And you'd be like, all right man.
Hey know what shut up.
Is that your lady like you're a pussy.
You're like, hey, hey, hey man, fuck man.
Take it easy. I got you
this, I got you a door deal.
He would say the most critical,
oh, these guys are wild cards.
He's been out in the sun.
He's been drinking his whole life.
You don't know what's
going to get a guy like,
like sometimes you see those
comics that like idolized,
you know those comics that just like,
I just say anything,
you know the political
correctness is my enemy.
And so those people that just say
something absolutely bananas that he's not
funny.
That's is between song filler.
I never laughed. He's like, no, but
I mean, you know she was asleep.
Like
we're trapped here with him.
Like she's your girlfriend and Nah,
just some girl I found anyways.
Stay United States stay in it.
No one clapping. Yeah. Ruin it so fast.
I was told that this video I haven't seen,
we're supposed to watch it and decide
who's out of line because there's two
people. Okay. And I think they're in
a whole foods. That's what I'm told.
I haven't opened it yet,
but okay.
Let's see if we can agree or disagree
that one of the two participants is
Adeline. Okay. Okay.
We go with that.
We have to do the same.
You really shouldn't be blocking the
handicap and crossing you all any of this,
any of this blue, right? No one is
supposed to be blocking you at anytime.
Thank you.
I'll take that into,
okay. So I think it's, she's one of
the participants, right? And the guy.
So she's saying don't, it seems like a
reasonable start. Yup. She's like, Hey,
you shouldn't be blocking
this. Yeah, sure.
Picks up. Can you please move
out of the handicap plate?
Please move the out of
the handicap plates.
I'm here.
You're in the handicap space?
No. The thing is they're only
briefly like they're just crossing.
I wish I had more visual and I
don't mean to see her. I don't,
I'm not like [inaudible],
but like I don't see where is the,
let's start.
Okay. Do we know it's at
right? Blue is handicapped.
Yes it is. I didn't know that.
I didn't know. I've been guilty of
this. Okay. Okay. Okay. He's stamped,
but they're not like, it doesn't seem like
they're really obstructing. No, she can.
She can work around. That middle is
worn down, but that's still handicapped.
You know what I mean? Right.
This whole area. Wait, wait,
so this whole thing is considered
handicap, right? If you,
my understanding is correct. Blue is his
handicap. I think you're correct. Yeah.
Okay, so she looked, she has a boy. She,
she made her point and she said
like, you know, he's like, yeah,
I'll take that into consideration.
Which she definitely didn't mean
he wasn't like he was he. Oh yeah.
He was already, he was pissed that there
was no, there was no, excuse me. Right,
right. Which I get it. I mean that's a
natural, if we're having a conversation,
so we're like, you're really like,
okay. Yeah, you do. You know how to,
how to interrupt. Right. Even
unnecessary interruption. So wait, let's,
I think it's about, this is crazy. I
think it's going to pick up the pace here.
Is that okay?
Okay.
People are not supposed to force
you to get out of this by law.
You're not supposed to be going to
take it up with management. Okay.
How about if I call the police?
Okay.
Oh, he says you're insane. Okay. She said,
I feel like he's getting to butt
hurt by her. And in fairness,
she does have what sounds like a very
grating voice. Yes. You know what I mean?
Some of us do. Hey, and she's also
a little too on top of it. Right?
Like she's looking for a fight. I mean
like he's not, it's not like she was like,
I'm trying to get into this space
and you're blocking it. And My,
my suspicious mind is like, who turns
on a recording device and in walks up.
Oh God, I don't know. That's
just me being super suspicious.
That's like, oh, I, I try
just maybe listening as a fight.
Yeah. Someone was like, excuse me.
They're waiting for a little bit.
Yeah, the scene. The building. Yeah.
And it's what the,
what the things I'm suspicious of is when
it recording starts before usually if
someone's like, and it just, it's starts
and a cop's yelling at this person,
this person probably did escalate. Not
the person recording, but they're like,
I got, I'm going to record
this. You're, you're, yeah.
She's what's known as a
shit mixer. Yeah. No, I saw,
I saw one too where a guy walked up to
cops that were like on a scene somewhere
and he walks up and they're
like, can you stay there? Like,
can you stand back and say, I don't
have to do shit. Ah, fuck you.
And they're like looking
at each other like, yeah.
And then of course they see the
camera doesn't like it does trying to,
and it's like I'm, I'm as angry at
certain cops as anyone is right now,
but it's just like that. Dot. What?
What the fuck does that solve?
Just one random cops. Yeah. Dude.
There's just come up and try you trying
to get them to do something crazy with
you. Now this bride is looking
for trouble. Oh really? Shit.
Oh really? You're insane.
I'm doing my job. No,
but you're doing it illegally.
It's not illegal and I'm surprised
that you shop yet. Oh, okay.
Well lets you got the New England accent.
I'm surprised you shop here. Yeah.
Oh boy. Yeah. She's,
she's upset about something else
and then she started to go away.
I wish this picked up more where
she's talking to management, I think.
I think she's going to
go walk up and close up.
Just stab each of those
melons with a knife. I wish.
Yeah, that you're insane.
You're insane. Yeah. Yeah.
She's just rising to one shop.
Yeah. Yeah. Which is by the way,
the appropriate response
to people like this.
I think you should just have licensed to
tell people they're crazy. No. Yeah. Well,
I do feel like that guy could have
handled it better and been like, you know,
but it's, it's, you know, I can't,
it's always funny. How would you,
you'd be so annoyed now.
Totally. No, no, no, I'm not.
I'm really not judging him because I
don't know how it would have been that
situation. I'm sure it would've been
so pissed, you know? But you know,
if this person is driving
thing with a straw and I,
I'm not, I'm just going to be like, ah,
okay. You, we'll get out of the way.
Sorry, ma'am. Whatever, you
know, pending, she's being
mommy to, you know what I mean?
Right. Too many people that you need to
be like, I mean, and also the approach,
it's always about, if she
could be, she said, excuse me.
I don't know if you know this, but you're
standing, I don't know if you know what?
I didn't know that I'm in my forties I
never knew blue as handicapped. Yeah.
Not that I would be like, Hey,
get outta here. Wheelchair guy.
Excuse me.
Like the fuck Outta here.
So I know nothing makes me laugh harder
than just someone being that immediately
crazy. Yeah, I know. That's what I'm
hoping for with every video I open,
just not hold back. I didn't. Same
Guy. Yeah. I remember when I was a kid,
it was at the time it was horrifying,
but I looked back and I laughed
so hard that like me and a buddy,
we couldn't have been more
than eight or nine it,
we're in the park and there's a water
fountain and there's hardly any water
coming out over like maybe four seconds
pass by. We're like, I don't know. Ah,
this guy behind it. It's like, it's
like what? Holding a baby? A grown man.
You girls going to drink or not?
Both two boys were both two little boys.
It's not coming out very well. Well, like
stuttering, like just shocked. He's like,
well then suck it. And we're like,
we just walked away. And Morris,
who's that insane to a young
boy? Ugly Bagel face? No,
no, I don't think. I think Eglise last
night, last I heard it ugly, went to MIT.
So he's a smart guy. Deep cuts for that.
That's a deep cut. Deep, deep. Yeah.
Prank. A guy named ugly
Bagel face. What we found,
we found this the silliest name in the
phone book and called him like a thousand
times,
but very childish.
I very great by the way.
We were playing,
how obnoxious it is earlier
when people have, uh,
conversations on speaker phone in
public, oh, isn't that the worst? Or,
or people that watch videos
in the airport get your life.
I've had two guys that I've said, uh, hey
man, do you have headphones? Can use them.
And they're like, I don't
have them. And I'm like, okay,
I don't need to hear that thing. You
just turn it down. And I'm like, yeah.
And they look at me like I'm
crazy. Yeah. It's bold. What?
I can't watch my television and public
and they look these, literally, this was,
I recorded this, this is my recording.
That's me. And this is the guy
on Bank of America's hold on
speakerphone is Starbucks.
Do I want to hear about Bank of
America's offers? And he's on hold.
So he's just playing it. Wow.
That's so rude. Yeah. I mean
that's so brutal. And he's just
leaving it there eating this thing.
Everyone's drinking his coffee
like hey fuck head. Yeah.
But I was telling her like,
this guy's a complete fucking oblivious.
Like it doesn't give a shit, you know?
If you were like, why you doing that?
He'd be like,
cause
I'm on hold.
[inaudible] what am I supposed to do?
Yeah. Yeah. I don't have a choice. Yeah.
I got to hold it to my head. I was going
to do that off of speaker phone. No, no.
Wait. So you've walked up to people and
you've been like, do you have had fun? No,
I just look old. Like we were
all sitting in the same, uh,
gate waiting for the flight. Yeah. And
I'm like, hey man, do you have headphones?
Can you put those on?
I was just saying,
I've had phones when you put those
on in the same sentence. Yep.
So they don't say anything. They're
like, I don't have it. It's like the,
and that's the same thing. They're
like, really? There's nothing I can do.
You're forced to listen. And I'm like,
all right, can you turn the sound off?
And they're like, well, they
can't believe it, of course,
because it's like, listen,
nobody likes confrontation.
And I'm not, no, no. I hate it.
I hate it so much. I've maybe
shushed people two times in the,
in the, in the, in the movie
theater maybe. Yeah. Maybe
I will put up with stuff.
I have found out the best
neighbors on our CULDESAC. Yeah,
the craziest on the
other side of the fence,
right beneath lay of like a pool and they
were up 10 30 [inaudible] trying to go
to bed. They're blaring eighties music and
sing along to it. And I'm just like, ah,
I just go out in the backyard and I'm
like, hey guys, past 10, can you, uh,
can you turn down? Fuck
you, like right away,
right away. Like, like by another
fucking house. Uh, and he said,
but like to each other, not to
me just being like, oh, fuck man.
Is this your new place, your
current place, place? And
they're, they're, they're,
they're rarely around, but
they already, they have a
neighborhood rep, uh, as these,
as these and it's, and
it's super young. No, no.
They have two kids. They turn it down.
They turned down and they were like,
welcome to fucking neighborhood. And I
just said thank you. And went inside.
It's like I'm not playing your game. I'm
not going to be the other. You're going,
you're, you're, you're faded. You're not
just drunk, you're on something else.
I they probably were doing
lines or something, but it's
like he hits, yeah. Jesus.
Jesus.
I mean I feel like I kind of live in the
neighborhood with parents that do coke.
You know what I mean? That's still want
that have like the party a little bit.
I think maybe Silver Lake more
than Los Felix, but like it's,
there's still that element
and like, uh, yeah. So it's,
well,
cause they are there in your neighborhood.
You have parents who still
want to be cool. Yes. Yes.
I like Tom and I have surrendered
to this game. We're like, listen,
we're fucking suburban lanes
are still cool though. Cool.
I go to the mall only confrontation
that I've had with the loud thing,
cause I didn't say shit to this psycho,
but uh,
at the airport gate I saw somebody
with a laptop on their lap open.
Yes. Facetime calling with that. So
they were like, yeah, Brazil. Yeah,
I know. And then you hear the person
and I just walked in front and I go,
how's it going? Like that
Nice. And the guy was like,
like looked at me like the fuck,
how's it going? And he just was like,
anyway, so we're going to get on the
flight. So he just, he, I just was like,
made it myself, be known to him.
She was, I was like, you know,
you should take your shirt off first.
Everybody there,
I mean everybody at the gate was
looking at this guy like you're crazy.
You're crazy guy. Yeah, no,
somebody emailed in a loud car
because we were talking about it.
I'd like to nominate someone for the talk
and openly on the phone in public hall
of fame while waiting in line at
riding a woman, answers her phone,
puts it on speakerphone,
then hands it to her five
year old daughter who is now
walking around the store,
holding the phone while the mom yells
across the store to talk to the person on
the phone. It was in fucking sane. Uh,
that's for the talking public champs.
Yeah, that's, that's, that is
totally crazy. We got a good one.
We were just in province town, uh, you
know, the way the top of the, of, of the,
uh, the Cape and in New England and
it's, it's the gas town you ever been to,
which means the funnest town and is
like this great little like beach town.
We'd never been, we just wanted to go, we
were already on the east coast for like,
Oh,
let's take a couple of days ago.
And the guy who picked us
up to get to the airport,
like the Lyft driver picks us up real
thick, west Indian Jamaican accent,
uh, any. And he's like, the phone's
ringing. And he's like, he's like, Oh,
who's is this? And it turns
it up. Then, uh, Jacob o.
G h A. R. R. Where are you?
You're supposed to be here. No,
you said a it dirty. I did not say
30. I did not say 30 and he's like,
Jihad, Jihad. Jihad listened to me.
She had, and she keeps screaming.
She's screaming at him, his
employer. And he was like,
how'd you go to the hospital?
And a g g had stopped yelling.
I have people in the car. Are you
going to the hospital or are you doing,
are you doing left right now?
Are you doing left? Right.
And we're just like, wow.
Oh my God.
It was like the most brutal over here.
And it went on way too long and you
finally like shut it down. But it's like,
that would be my nominee for
worst. That's a horrible, yeah.
Like you don't know your boss's number
and you just answer it while people are
in the car. Oh, I got by the way,
probably a thousand messages and tweets
because Russia has appointed Steven
Seagal. Yes, I saw your
Instagram post. Yeah.
Special Representative of humanitarian
relations, but sure. U S and arm breaking.
He is, I don't know if
you know this, this is,
you can talk about people talking
about themselves. Oh yeah.
This is him in the interview.
I mean I am the king and then province.
Does that make sense?
I would believe he's the king of Improv.
Steven Seagal probably. Yes,
yes, yes. Ans you so hard.
Do you know what that actually means?
Because I watched more of an interview.
I don't go off script.
The other actors do and what I do is
I'll just change it in the moment.
So like while you learned the lines
of the script for the movie. Oh yeah.
He will just throw stuff out
there and you have to figure out,
he doesn't do improv comedy Improv.
He does.
I'm just going to say the
lines I want to say. Yup.
And scrap the other act or
I'm lazy. Yeah, yeah. Like A,
here's the lines of scrub. Well, here's
what I'm going to say. Yeah. They're like,
okay.
I mean this is a guy who like God is
career career start by being like,
he was like a studio execs.
Karate trainer. That's right.
And the exact would take 'em in in a
meetings and let, let's, let's spar. Yeah.
Would you put this guy in a
movie? Is that right? Yeah,
and its story and this was the 80s when
it was all cocaine and misogyny know.
And so like you know, he came out of
that era and probably just never changed.
It was just like, no, you come
to my trailer, I want a blowjob.
Is there anything going on?
Is there any more like a that
I dropped off your lunch order.
Mr Seagal. That's all I'm doing. I know,
right? It's like, but could any be,
could it be any crazier than they serious?
Mostly appointed Steven Seagal.
Yeah.
Like a special representative that now
someone on the US side is going to have
to go. Yeah. All right.
I'm going to talk to Seagal today
about yeah, how we can better.
It's, it's in the, we're in the upside
down. Donald Trump is president.
Steven Seagal is this fucking
thing. Hootin and we're
best friends now with him.
It's, it's all this is absurdity. Yeah.
World is done. We're all going to die.
Um,
it's all
Hofer. Here's what Maury
over one more email. Uh,
first I wanted to thank you guys for
the weekly free. Funny. Secondly,
I would like to bring some awareness of
how main mommy buns and his psychopathy
hay has been buying,
but then official to me.
I used to love watching people
hurt themselves just like Tom,
but ever since I lost a leg,
God dammit.
Oh Shit in Iraq and seeing
some pretty horrific stuff.
I couldn't sit through it anymore.
Yeah.
It has been over a decade of darkness
for me and something has been missing.
But ever since I started listening
to the podcast, things have changed.
Listening to the audio of people
getting hurt desensitize me,
and I'm now joining, watching
my favorite content again. Oh,
thanks to Tommy for making life
worthwhile. Keeping them high and tight.
Piss on me and beat me.
Try it out. Sal Gonzales,
p s my wife was expecting our first baby.
Hey,
Tina. Uh, is in the delivery
room. Okay, great. Good luck
to mommy and the tuner. Oh.
So
you know,
I thought,
but definitely like audio of like serious,
horrible injuries do. Oh, we do. Yeah.
Okay.
And Todd and Tom Laughs and laughs and
laughs like a psychopath. No, he does.
It's totally, totally crazy.
That's not good at all.
And I have feelings for
people. It's, it's nuts.
But that is actually, that's really,
that's a really nice message.
Bye.
Helps this guy. So that's
good. I'm glad. Yeah.
Yeah.
Wow. Okay. Yeah.
I'm not going to ask.
Okay.
Crazily, my husband, he's so
stoic all day around the house.
Like we have this newborn,
we have these two dark for so
ever.
Life is pretty happy.
The only time I ever see him really joyful
is when he's watching a serial killer
show on Netflix. Oh, mine are laughing
at people getting hurt. It's so funny.
It's true. Joy. Yeah. Look,
that's nonsense. It's not,
I want to, uh, Plug
Matt's podcast again. Um,
the advice from a dipshit advice from a
ditch advice from a dip shit with Matt
Brown. Thanks buddy. Um, make
sure you check it out. He
gave the number out earlier.
Um, make sure you call it,
leave a message. Get advice
from a real dip. Shit. Funny.
It's at. That must be really funny. Yeah.
I'm going to have you on. I'm gonna have,
yeah, we'd love to do that. And
all you for first got tongue
first.
Good.
Tom Or RTD replaces the Dick.
Oh,
first good time of the day. Are you first.
Good tone replaces the decks out there.
Make sure you call as
well. Um, a reminder,
the bike's socks or at the store.
I added a show in Montclair,
New Jersey.
It's on sale this Friday at the Welmont.
Go to [inaudible] dot com Christina's
adding a show at the Grammercy in New York
City and your door. I did. I
shot a shovel fighter there. Hey,
amazing, amazing, amazing theater. Can't
wait to see it. I've never seen it. Uh,
here's our closing song.
It's called barely staying alive,
uh, by Billy and drew. Anything
else Matt, before we go? That was,
it's been a joy. It you guys, thanks for
coming again. You are coming back again.
Absolutely. A new location. It has to
be. If we have your back. I said, no.
Well listen, I just, I feel like I, uh,
help you move on up. Yeah. You know,
in the heartlands of the Jefferson. Sure.
Like every time I come back, you're like,
wait, what? We just got
a million more listeners,
so we got to move into this podcast.
Castle. Move into a new place. Huh. Um,
always good to see you, buddy.
Thank you for coming. Thanks Ben.
Cut.
Cut,
cut.
Cut.
That Wednesday
you went and visited.
That was good.
I know you're around buying it
then you let it
come on.
Come on.
They basically
didn't,
they basically
get what you will get is
that way
we know that when
you win,
it is,
come on
now when he's dead, I think
that is the United States.
Come on,
come on.
Yeah,
Come on.