Well, well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Shout out to my friends
on trips scares people.
Boy.
Get up a few silicide
rescued up
if
you know what I'm saying. Do you
know what I'm saying? Not yet.
Really keys and do this.
I remember
my mom and mom and mom,
God is going to kill
Mommy.
Mommy House.
Your genes are so tight. You
Fisher. I'm drinking water.
Look in my business so clear.
It was Denmark crisis unbelievably fast.
Some are fussy on a
bloody diarrhea worked.
Ocilla Samuel linkedin requests going to
hook up a PDK shrink and zoom marijuana
75 on one day.
And if you want to hear a call,
five chicks blaster from my,
how do you say asphalt?
Never thought I did the scene that
they were up in the one the shark.
God blessed as a big word. God
bless the Cincinnati far. Okay.
Okay.
Pretty impressive.
I was a little nervous in the beginning.
Yeah, cause it was a little aggressive,
real aggressive. But then we
know this guy. What's his name?
This is the,
this is Lord Columbus.
It's called triple pipe montage pizzas.
It's your mom's House boot him up. Are
you sure they sound very similar. I mean,
unless he's got a new name. Wow.
Could I have a pen name? Yeah, maybe.
I feel like it's the same guy. Yeah. Oh,
that's really good stuff. Yeah. A lot of,
a lot of old school
still worked. A lot of stuff in
there. Yeah. I was really impressed.
Really impressed gene. It's
always good. How you doing?
All right. I got my fancy a
green jacket on. I get that.
You didn't even really acknowledge.
I mean it's kind of, it's,
it's throwing me off so much
that my brain's processing it.
What about it is throwing you off?
Just the awesomeness of it. Yeah.
It's bold. It's bold fashion
choice. Well, I was at,
was this part of the new Gucci Collection?
No,
I was at the mall getting my phone fixed.
I walked through Macy's or as you
call it, the garbage dump. Yeah.
It's not really up to your standards,
but I saw this and I thought, why not?
So I got it to Macy's purchase
and then they had that
Macy's. You feel like? Do
you feel like Macy's is,
it's not as bad as like a Sears?
No, of course not. No. Neither
one of them. I mean, they're fine,
but it's fun to mock
them. Yeah. Not Nordstrom.
Is that what you call it? Not Nordstrom.
Not Neiman, no, definitely not.
And even not Barney's.
Who really shops at Neiman Marcus though?
I feel like that's so fancy.
That's fancy.
Barton used to Barf. Fuck
Barneys, dude. I went there.
It was like in a, you know, in a rush.
I was like, oh, I need, I forget what.
I needed a belt or shoes and it was one
of those things where a quick stroll
through the store,
it's almost like they look at you like,
do you really want to get to here? Yeah.
Like the guy was sympathetic. He's like,
we have this discount one
for 400 and I was like, ah.
I think isn't there another store?
He's like, he has other stories.
You should probably check them out.
Barneys is ludicrous.
You can't get out of there without
spending four or $500 on one fucking sock.
It's preposterous.
It's fucking dominant.
You gotta be an idiot if
you're doing that call that,
but it's for a certain
people that want to do that.
A certain level of mommy.
Yeah. Well it's like, I think you
want, your thrill is in spending a lot.
That's what you mean.
Even if even if I had
the millions to spend,
I'm not sure I would do it. Like
I don't, it's just not, it's a,
it's an ethical thing.
Yeah. I Dunno. I think that's some
people's rush though. It definitely,
I know it's some people's rush.
Do you like to yeah, they go.
Like I spent all in,
I spend a $500 on a belt.
You see them with the shot, you know, 10
shopping bags. You see people like that.
Yeah. They're getting, they got together.
They got a rush from it. Yup. Yup. Um,
all right. We should do
a, a proper show open.
We did our fitness today,
man. We'll get into it. Fuck.
And we'll get into fitness.
I'd been down for two weeks.
I know there's a lot to cover. Fuck.
Um, here we go. Let's open the show
proper.
Like
hello my little Munchkins and
welcome to my channel. I'm sexy.
And today's topic is
of course no leaching.
You came here because you're curious,
you clicked on the link to see what the
heck is vaginal leaching and why would a
woman put out of all things
leeches in her vagina?
No,
bring it in one loving.
Well welcome
to your mom's house,
Christina pushes.
It's interesting.
Is
this for you?
No,
I know.
And I looked at all the clips when you
were gone this morning and I thought this
one, he's really going to
get a cake out of an eye.
I was this close to asking
you, Hey, what did you,
what are you thinking for the
opening clip? But I was like,
I'm going to give him the benefit of
the doubt that he's going to choose
something different than
vaginal leaching or um,
reading national discharge
off of a panty line.
While you should checked your doubt at
the door. Cause that's what we're up to,
right? Yeah. Yeah. I
think a little bit of, um,
I don't know what the word,
what's the word,
like a infantilism or something
happening here where she's,
she's very much a little white girl.
You see Minnie mouse in the background.
That's what she is. That's her
little doll in the background. Right.
She's got Minnie mouse and then
pink, pink pig, the heart hangers.
Then I just noticed that
now her titties. Yeah. Yeah.
And she's got a necklace this pointing
stripping ges into her titties, you know?
Yeah. So she wants you to see
him, but that is a thing. Um,
psychologically when a girl,
we're like,
still wears a lot of pinks and
they're an adult. I think it's like,
that's why like those porno girls,
they talk like really girl hi blighted.
It's like that. Your feet refusing to
be a woman kind of thing. Of course,
it's terrible.
Of course you put them
the China,
the amazing women would put leaches
in the vagina is to treat some kind of
condition or to improve
their health and wellbeing,
um, to improve their sensations,
whatever the reason may be.
Mainly it's health
reasons, of course. Yeah.
Of course it is. Duh. It's like drinking
your P to, to cure a cold. And I just,
cause I haven't seen any of this.
I just noticed that those are leeches
right there in that jar. Yeah. Yeah.
You think so gypsy? She kind of looks
like Roma. Yeah, I can see it. She's like,
she's my tribe. Yeah,
totally. She's my tribe.
She's somewhere like Romania
or something. Right? Yeah.
It's fucked up. How did you discover
that that's what your vagina is not,
you don't think it would be good?
It's not just for health reasons.
It helps sensations.
Helps everything.
Sensations. I came across a very, very
interesting,
should I say article
placing leeches in her vagina in order
to conceive a child at the age of 50 so I
thought it was quite interesting and I
thought I'd bring it to your attention.
Yeah. Very nice. He didn't
bring that to our attention.
Seriously though in the, this is would be
considered an educational video. Right?
Right. Cause she's trying to really
look at the hangers for real,
but they really are
out there, right? Yeah.
I mean there's how many unbuttoned
buttons you see? One, two, three,
possibly four is on the fourth
one down. Yeah. I mean, well babe,
did you think that she was a scientist?
Well,
I think she's trying to
give off the idea that this,
that she has knowledge to share.
So if your video is about
how dare you, you're so misogynist.
Well, no, I mean I liked that.
I like him.
Why can't she be hot and smart?
Why can't she be a doctor and
slutty at the same time? Tom,
Gabby, I'm in totally in favor of her
tests. Painting her with that brush.
Just because you're, you're funny doesn't
mean you can't be sexy. That's true.
Sorry.
I know I'm going to also
do real life demonstration.
Not using myself using the site.
A little doll.
Oh,
so your pussy get leads. That's
the whole test to show, man.
That's a science pushing legion show Dan.
Well then do it on fucking live league
so we can see your snatch. Yeah, man.
That we get a lot of use.
I know that clip and this is gypsy
meaning explained that her first treatment
was like having a pap smear. Okay.
The doctor plastic device
known as a speculum,
a stock kilo.
This is what the device gets.
Slide straight triggers out of her mind.
No Shit.
God Damn it dude.
And the doctor inserted this baculum
into her vaginal canal and then proceeded
to add three leeches and then
allow them to do their job to do
to her uterus. Oh, we always nasty
is healed. That is so foul, man.
That's fucking,
it makes me cringe.
Y what can be more natural?
Look a bit more love and then
putting it leaches and your vagina.
I uh, just knowing what vaginas are like,
I just don't think that's a good idea.
I don't have one, but I can, I've seen
a few. I don't think that's a good idea.
Just what do you mean? I don't think
it's good to put leeches in your puss.
What I'm concerned with,
I think it's okay and your puss,
but then it can go into your
uterus and then it's like, well,
how'd you get the leach out? Leach wants
to. That's what I'm saying, cause she,
it sounds to me like you're really opening
up the badge and putting something in.
It means it can go through your cervix
and into your uterus and probably cause
massive damage to the elite doesn't have
a pager. Right. You can't be like, hey,
you got to get back here
now. Do what it wants. Right.
Unless you're tying strings to all of
their next and then you pull them down.
I mean this is the crazy sharing.
Really comfortable with
why he wasn't he was doing.
Nina said that in an interview.
We just basically attracted themselves
to the inside of her cervix hatched. Oh,
inside of her cervix sound very
pleasant when the therapy was over,
the leeches dropout. Sam coming out
fatter than a bottle of nail Polish.
Oh. Oh. So they were really enjoying them,
sucking the blood so they suck the blood
out of your cervix. That's, I can't be,
I can't, sounds like a nasty
sounds like those leeches Kinda.
Yeah.
Lot of Stan.
A maybe just a little bit of glass glass.
Oh man, bitch, you crazy. Now,
why doesn't she do it if she's so
stoked about this man? I don't know.
Let's see if she explains why c
side effects for the curious and Manju,
you might be surprised to know that
the vaginal leeches did their job after
eight months of using just covered
that she was pregnant at the age of 45,
much more energy than before,
but that wasn't the only side
effect of the leach therapy.
Eight months. What every day. I got
to explain more than that and I don't,
I really can't see how that would help.
Fertility has nothing to do with, uh,
does it give you better egg quality?
Does it as she's in they're nuts.
This is nuts.
I also noticed that my orgasms
were longer and more intense.
She confessed in an interview stating
that she had some of the best orgasms
after each different around of treatment.
That's awesome. You know, I know this,
I mean, we all know why she's crazy,
but again, I have this
theory about the makeup. Uh,
whenever you see a girl, first of all
that color is bananas. Lipstick. Yeah.
But when you see the liner of the lip,
Lennar going above the
line of the lip there,
you see that trick and she
think she's fooling over here.
That's how you know bitches cray
like crazy. She's on a visual,
like you just glass a bitch. And if
that make up goes up over the lip line.
No good hound. Or she got makeup
tattooed on like tattooed eyeliner. Oh,
we also saw last week the shadow
eyebrows like into the eyebrow.
Like if a bitch for eyebrows are too thin,
I mean tiny pass could tell.
He has a joke about that.
But if your eyebrows are all fucked up,
you know, you color them different colors.
I knew a girl who had purple
eyebrows and like Booboo,
that shit does not look good. Nobody likes
that. No dues aren't gonna like that.
I have my little friend here
to help us demonstrate it.
I have my jar leeches and
our little Minnie mouse.
Johnny's going to help us
demonstrate how not to damage.
Like you imagine if you're on a
date with this woman, you know,
and like you're just like, oh yeah, she's
attractive and you're having dinner.
And then she's like, come over and
then, you know, all right, uh, what,
what do you want to do? And she's
like, have you ever heard of valley?
Imagine will leach therapy. They're
like, wait, what? He's like,
I'm going to show you
on my Minnie mouse doll.
I sliced her pussy open so that I can
show you on her as opposed to help for
health and, and also orgasms. At that
point you're like, you know what,
I have a meeting in the
morning that I forgot about
when the woman
looking at her whole,
she cut the fabric out of her legs
need to be put together like this.
Knees have to be opened
to open up your knees,
put your legs when you're in labor,
check you.
And if you can play some
mirror and shine a light,
I wouldn't advocate that self belief
in yourself to do this.
She's telling you how to
do the shit at home. Bitch,
you crazy this. Um, no, no, that's true.
Once it's inserted,
you will then open it up
at, first of all, it's really simple
to open yourself up with a speculum.
Right?
The instrument keeps the
vagina entirely open.
Yeah. What's, I mean, even
just doing that to yourself,
probably not easy. No, it
doesn't seem easy. Well,
it doesn't feel good when
someone else does it to you,
let alone doing it yourself.
Like there's no way I can imagine that's
just like you're at your Thursday night,
you know,
it's horrible.
Once a year I got the
speculum and putting these uh,
leeches in my purse right now,
where do you even get the leeches?
You go to a pet store
and this will come out really,
really huge. When it's fun.
So with the knees or feet together,
like her smile,
you will then proceed to place.
The leech all the way is in your
first step all the way inside.
So
unless you're all the way deep inside,
at least the Leech.
Thank you.
Shouldn't do it.
I don't think you should do it.
I don't think you should do want
to go ahead and say that I will.
I don't trust this lady,
but what if the what if leaching your
penis could make it bigger for you? Do it.
Everyone would do it. If you told
the Dude, hey here, Dick Hole.
If you put a legion there,
it'll grow.
But you could tell them all you gotta do
is slice it up your deck off and put a
leach in there. And guys
like all right. Yup.
The ers would be full of dudes at
leeches on their dicks. 100% yeah,
that's definitely a Leech is
definitely not going to make it bigger.
I don't think so. I think it's
going to make her dick smaller.
Well what if you could be like, but it
sucks the, the nutrients, the blood.
It replaces it with whatever you can
say anything. You can make it. Yeah.
Tell him to put it in their asshole and
then they would put a leaching your ass.
Will you typically at beggar?
What? Honey? Honey. Honey,
help me out here. Here. Hold. Hold my ass
open real quick with this thing. Yeah.
Yeah. Tighten the knob. It
can you see a real big good.
Now put like 10 or 12 leaches up in there.
What if it gets stuck inside my uterus?
I won't be able to come out.
I'm here to tell you that
there's absolutely no chance
the leach getting inside
the cervix.
There's no way because the walls,
the lips of the cervix or like shut
closed and there's really not much passing
through.
Yeah. Except when you opulate
or when you make a baby like,
well how do you think sperm gets through
the cervix? You Ding Dong, it opens,
it opens and it gets her.
Yeah, she's so sneaky.
I don't know where she got
her medical degree from.
Harvard I think is what I
was reading in the little.
Um,
and then once they're finished
they will crawl out on their own.
Ah, girl, Don, you too. Um,
how long have you tried anything open
again to remove the leeches that's now
going to be happening? The leeches
are going to crawl out by themselves.
Okay.
So you just,
you're just sitting there and then a
leach cross it or coach it just slithers
out. I'm done. Oh, you're done.
Oh, there's three more in there.
Just give it a minute and they're
all fat. Oh God. It's so nasty.
So glad you shared that.
You know,
we got a bunch of emails and messages.
People were like,
do not make fun of this guy last week.
The cook the chef. Yeah. And I don't
even remember how I even know who he is.
Chef John. They're like, don't fuck
with chef John. Yeah. Because he has,
all we're doing is saying this guy
has up speak like very, oh that's,
that's the chef I, yeah. Yeah. This
guy, for some matters we probably be,
you're one of the great mysteries
of the culinary world since,
how can there be a recipe for re fried
beans when there's no such thing as a
fried bean recipe? See Fried
bean recipe. Yeah. Yeah.
I'm going to go ahead and soak one pound
of pinto beans and cold water overnight
and like everything these days,
there's a lot of controversy on whether
you should do this or not and I'll let
you do your own research. But I've
been a been soaker from way back. Yeah.
So I did that. Mine Soak in cold. What's
a bunch of Bursa really love this guy.
I don't know.
I don't know anything about him.
I mean the been soaking controversial.
My God,
I guess some people don't soak their
beans. I like the sub mine plenty.
You Soak your beans all day
in your hands like this?
Uh, yeah. I didn't know
that guy was famous. Yeah.
Oh look how the tables have turned
no wrong here. You have a Zvm. No,
I have h two o I have my bottle
and then at Fiji is mine too.
So yeah.
Well anymore for me it's probably
the first time you drank water today,
so I understand. Yeah, that's true. Yeah.
Um, anyways, so yeah, a lot of people,
chef John I gotta heat for Chef John, Huh?
Yeah, they, yeah, they were really real.
A lot of people have chef John.
But then we got this, uh, from a,
uh, an Ozzie listener of
ours said that this guy,
Frank Walker,
whatever he talks about,
he does have speak in Australia.
Hello Frank Walker from
national tiles this week.
National Tiles had a beautiful range of
polished porcelain floor tiles slashed
by up to 30% or more.
Hey, he draws out every single word. Yeah.
Or one out of every fight. He was, whoa.
It's definitely, it's
definitely a hook. Yeah.
It makes you remember that how that
guy speaks. Yeah. Well, you know, it's,
to me whenever any Australian
person speaks, I'm like,
oh, that's funny. It's not,
it's not American.
You know,
it all sounds different to me when
I hear him talking. I liked it.
It definitely sounds different, but
yeah, there you go. That's funny.
It's that in America I think they all talk
like this is what I'm saying. Like, oh,
I don't hear the distinction
so much. Whenever I hear an
Aussie speak, I was like,
yeah, uh, uh, yeah. It
just sounds wacky. My,
they all sound wacky cause it's
not American. Yeah, I hear Ya.
It's until this Sunday
only at national tiles.
Beautiful range of polished porcelain
floor tiles, but only until this Sunday.
Right. International towels now and
save go do I website for details.
National tiles.com. Dot. EU.
If I was a producer in the booth with him,
I'd be like, Hey, you keep these words
and you should stop doing that,
and he would probably be like,
that's what I always do.
I pick,
I pick a word and then I make it eight
syllables when it's to do not like it and
I'd be like, no, I don't fucking
like it. Stopped doing it. Wow.
Hello.
This week,
national tiles had a beautiful range
of polished porcelain floor tiles.
It's weird. It's definitely
weird. I kind of enjoy it though.
I like it more than a, yeah.
People really liked that guy.
He kept getting messages about him.
He sounds like he's genuinely sweet.
I think that's what it might be. Oh,
here we go. I think you said this great.
You called him a Gay Lord.
Oh yeah, that's right. Hey,
do not call chef John and up speaking
Gaylord chef John was created by God
herself.
Her share seven minute video recipes.
He taught me proper knife techniques
like what does that she full nod.
Do you even know what that shit
is? Doubt it. Well, obviously no,
I keep my knife technique high and tight.
You spit in the face of cuisine and art.
Chef John's angelic Singsong
cadence is evidence.
There is a higher power in this world.
Comparing his cherubic delivery to
vocal fry is an affront to humanity.
This is the lowest looses thing I've
ever seen from your mom's house.
My balls are dry and I'm
slightly sweaty now by Hitler.
Dustin. Ps, I'm off to make a sell.
I salt crusted beef tenderloin.
And what does that mean, la? Uh,
I dunno for dessert that you barbarians
would not know anything about this guy
seen die hard. Die Hard. They
love him. Sorry. Sorry Chef John.
You talk like a retard but
tiny like a Gaylord retired.
Okay, Lord. Stupid Retard.
But you're apparently a great chef.
Speaking to that. I was going to be sweet.
Yeah, you were in the bathroom. You came
in. I go check this out and on my own.
I just had the thought can
retarded people drive right?
And the answer is yes. It just blew
my mind. Really blew my mind too.
I did not think that. I don't know.
Remember what I remember why it happened.
Now I went to the Fedex to drop off a
package and as I was walking back to my
car, I saw the car that was
parked, you know, head to head.
And I go as high retarded
guy in the driver's seat.
And I thought that cause I retarded guy.
And then I got in the car,
I looked at him and it wasn't,
but at that moment I go,
I wonder if retarded people can drive.
He just looked retarded.
He looked retarded for a moment. So I
just kind of, I looked at him and I go,
hold on here. I just kind of
looked put together that he wasn't.
But then the question was in my mind,
the burning question,
and I looked it up and the,
here's what I found out,
there's no rules anywhere
preventing them from driving.
It's crazy.
Here's the thing,
if they can pass the test,
that's what it's all about.
So if they pass the written test and
they pass the actual driving test,
nothing says, well you pass these,
but you're, you know, retard drive,
Corky Thatcher on life goes on. Was
he able to drive, he was able to act.
We know that that guy could realize and
memorize them. Yeah. That's fascinating.
I think it probably is all all about
down to the degree of your disability.
In other words, how, how, well it was
looking for another way of saying,
but yes,
how severe your retardation is.
So if you're like super retired,
then you can't drive. But if you're
pretty put together, you know,
I'm trying to think in my Rolodex
of retarded people that I've known,
if any of them could drive again,
you know the guy in life goes on.
He was pretty highly functioning.
He could memorize lines and
do things like that. Yeah.
I'm wondering if that guy can drive,
I mean some of them have jobs,
you know that this before and so whether
or not it would be pleasurable to be
retarded, if you would know that you
are retarded. What? That's horrible.
Horrible. Is a genuine question.
Pleasurable to be retarded.
Maybe if they don't know they're retarded,
then they're just kind of living in alone.
There's no such thing as not knowing.
It's all I do is eat lots of sweets.
They all know. Stop saying
they don't know. They know.
They don't know what they're
missing though, by not being
retarded. Um, all right.
Maybe to a degree,
like they don't,
they don't know other pleasures besides
masturbating and eating. What else?
Ultimately that's all you want.
That's what I'm saying too. I agree.
But there's others, there's more refined
things like, uh, enjoying a film,
reading a book, going to be like
a watch films retarded. Yes.
But they don't understand.
They're not going to watch the same
white bummer movies that we watch or you
know, hey, yeah,
no bureau watching a real
bummer the other day.
Well, I was sick so I though,
you know, what could I do? And I,
I got roped into 13 reasons why the Hannah
Baker suicide show and they rubbed me
in because they played joy division on
the first episode and I was like, oh fuck.
I love it. I love depressing teenage shit.
That's my, that's my jam. It's to me.
I didn't watch the whole thing,
but I watched probably half of one episode
and then half of another episode with
you. It just seemed like
an afterschool special,
like the way that the writing and the
acting like it was telling a story,
but it was like, it was
really like, you know,
kind of doing it for
kids. Right? Well, yeah.
I mean the show is about teenage suicide,
so they have a moral obligation to make
it palatable, I think, to that audience.
So when I walked in I was like,
what are you watching?
Like a fucking afterschool though.
That's interesting that uh, you're like,
what are you watching? This is
depressing where your favorite stuff is
like, and she came home and
found her husband murdered.
There was blood everywhere.
Becky was terrified.
Little did she know the murderer was
still in the house. What the hell is that?
That's your show that you watch.
Watch.
That's what I hear as I'm falling asleep
at night. It's all your murder, whatever.
Murder shows you like.
It's always about like reenacting or the,
they are not,
they haven't found the killer yet.
Which is even more terrifying for
reality crime rate. Yeah. You love
that stuff. Like the real depressing.
Like I watched fakes suicide like
fake murderer, but your jam is like,
I like real killing, like real
human suffering. You know?
That's true. Real hardship. I
started uh, the new Fargo. Yeah,
you did.
I fell asleep so fast during that.
I gotta tell you I don't have as much
of a hard on for that show as you do.
Maybe it's the mid like admitted what?
You relate a lot to that place. Cause you,
you lived in the, in Minneapolis, it's,
yeah, it's your, those are your tribe.
But I'm telling you, I really feel like
when you break down the whole thing,
the writing, the storytelling,
the cinematography,
the directing and the acting,
I don't think I've seen a better
show in 10 years plus than Fargo.
The great British baking show.
I mean it has drama stakes.
Cinematography I duck is a rope off
Chris and Marie Battery Chemistry.
We did finish it. No wait,
wait. How was the FARC go?
How was the first of the stuff?
Should we have better call Saul? Dude,
we haven't even fucking seen that.
The new new, yeah. So Americans,
can I tell you something? I'm watching
the Americans, I'm not dazzled to Csun.
The Americans has maybe turned a corner.
Yeah.
It's not first of all,
last season we had so many
compelling stories on this law,
on the episode that I just, we'll finish
the one that started to fall asleep on,
they did just hit a holy shit moment,
good storyline.
But I feel like they kind of dropped a
lot of the storylines from last season,
like page putting them in jeopardy by
talking to that asshole pastor and her
fucking the neighbor boy. And
it was like, I didn't like it.
They never killed that guy. I mean they
should have killed pastor Tim. Yeah.
Fuck him.
It doesn't make sense.
It made sense that they would
give the diplomacy a shot,
but then that should have failed
and they shouldn't. I agree.
Because like he's going to keep the
secret there to have that happen now.
I was very excited to see
the outcome of season three.
Spoiler alert if you're
watching on Netflix
of the victor was Nadia.
Yeah.
And you and I were rooting for it.
Tamale and Nadia, the two outliers,
both young, both Muslim
bakers, uh, she wears her full,
he job,
her head dress made sure it makes her
look very different than everybody else.
But I her because she was an outsider and
I like that she's like a housewife and
the best part is, uh, the bummed out
husband when they did her package,
like your interview and the husband was
like, uh, we've all been missing Nadia.
She's been doing this bike and show
and I've had to do everything for the
children. You can really
see that. He's like,
I respect her a lot more now know that
she used to come home and stop baking on
your bullshit show is what I took.
But also he's like,
I didn't realize what she did. That's
what I got. She was like, guys alive. Oh,
realize how much should
she does? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
He was more upset that she wasn't, uh,
still cooking and cleaning at home course.
It was nice to see that she won
and it really meant a lot to her.
That's the thing that I took
away. US Gray. She cared
so fucking much about that.
I didn't think I could do it. And
then I did do it again. She goes, oh,
I didn't think that I could do it
under no phone could do it. And No.
I said to myself,
I can do anything.
She speaks with a 100% British
accent. Yeah, but I did British.
That was British. Pakistani. Yeah. You
had a little bone job in there. Okay.
Well she's from Bangladesh. Yeah.
You're hearing is Bang Bangladeshi.
Hmm. I was throwing it in there and she's,
she doesn't really have a Bangladeshi.
Yeah,
and she does a little bit.
Okay,
well do you do her then
do her victory speech.
Oh,
to when sweet chocolate.
There you go.
That's not how she sounds.
I think so.
That's how Mary Berry's hounds more.
You're doing Mary.
So glad to Paul.
Hollywood
does. I don't like this. I don't like it.
I don't like it, mate. No, he
got it. He goes, I don't like it.
I'm not tasting the rhubarb. I'm not
tasting the almond. If you're gone,
if you're gone and put pineapple in it.
I'd like to taste the flavors.
I like your layers. Nice
bike. It's under bike.
I'm not getting on flavor.
Coconut wiped out everything.
Too much moisture in the bike.
Yeah.
I love when they say oh no, he,
yeah, he went to Channel Four.
It like a rival show. Yeah. Yeah.
Big, big controversy and UCL. Yeah,
we'll see what happens.
But all the wood,
I really hope there are more seasons
that we get to see cause I'm just, ah,
it's a, it's a great
show. It is a great show.
We started watching the Zombie show that
everybody's fucking was in love with
this. We're good at at
um, a show becoming a hit,
like a really big smash hit.
And we go so,
and then six years later we're like,
I'll check it out. It's like, okay,
I see what you're saying.
So we just started the walking dead.
Yeah. And it's fantastic. And we're
like, man, I guess people had a point,
those 12 million or so people that
said watch it at a point. Now,
here's the problem with the show is
that we like to watch before bedtime,
and I find that it stresses
me out. I don't stressful. Can
I say my least favorite genre is like,
we have to keep running
from the evil thing, right?
Because I have nightmares about running
and all shows. I don't like that.
Those evil running and chasing things.
Hey,
chase shows usually end on a cliffhanger.
So they end with like,
wait til next week, Huh? Like you, and
then you feel like, sorry, the next one.
And that's what the whole fucking thing's
going to be is them running for the
next 10 years. Right? Yeah. This is
shows years and years in now. All right.
So what they've built like a,
a human land like on the Matrix and
the second we were total newbies.
Now we're fucking two episodes in.
What can possibly happen?
They have to kill all those.
That show is so good.
Big that they started a nother show
where they talk about that show that airs
regular, like it's called like after
or beyond. Yeah, something like that.
And then it has,
I think it doesn't Hardwick Kosta,
retired week show Jesus Christ and they're
just talking about another show and
then the networks like yeah. Err
that err, err us talking about it
that show bananas. Yeah.
Well we have to stick to it.
I guess if I watch it early in
the evening, maybe I can do it.
I wish there were more movies.
I like movies,
my heart pounds so much when I
watched that Zombie show. Yeah. I get,
I get really emotional. Like I, you
guys have to run. You just keep going.
Like I hate it, but yeah, I agree. The
movie selection or fucking crap shit.
Yeah. When his fucking, uh, John
Debt, my WIC Dick to coming. Yeah.
You know, we bought it, we bought
dip my Dick in the WIC and it,
I remember it said April.
I Dunno,
I can't wait to see that one. I'm
excited for that one. That's a good one.
Dip My Wiccan Widdick come.
Um,
we asked you and will continue to ask
you to write reviews on iTunes because
it's what's fair and we deserve it.
Here's one that somebody sent into us.
Uh,
Mommy's,
I thought you would appreciate my review.
Here's what he wrote.
Calling all come dogs and ugly suck pigs.
Your Mom's house podcast is here for you.
Have you ever wondered if
there's any common those balls?
Everyone is just fluid bomb with Jesse.
Ever wished a mentally ill
girl could talk to Hitler
as a child? Did you make your own
poop pile for the neighbors to admire?
Do you have big old mushy purples?
What about sloppers meet hangers? Tits
for days. Do you have Dick for days?
Do you find cops to be all bald and shit?
When you're Puerto Rican,
you are just Puerto Rican. Uh,
excuse me. When you're Puerto Rican,
are you just Puerto Rican?
Are you dirty and disgusting?
Do you find yourself
farting on all the haters?
How do you feel about Lincoln Din?
What's with the jeans?
Um, do you often instruct
strangers to kiss your pussy?
Have you on occasion bellowed
bikes in the presence of strangers?
Do you ever wonder which you are
if you answered no to any of these,
I don't give a shit.
Listen to your mommy's and you'll find
that you've been the water champ all
along. Stay thirsty. Come Dogs
Ryan. So Ryan wrote that. Ryan,
that review made me want to listen to
our show. Yeah, that was really good.
If I read that, I'd be like, I've got
to check this shit out. Intrigued.
I like all these subjects. Yeah. Good job.
Check this out.
I don't know if have you seen this?
This is um,
this came in with regard to our discussion
last week about taking a pilot's
license off the table. For
Fuck's sake. Here we go.
Dear Mr. Thompson grew up.
My name is Barry Brown from the law
office of Brown and Yellow family law
attorney. I am Christina possessed keys
official negotiation representative.
This letter is in regards to the
negotiation of ceasing and desisting from
acquiring a pilot license.
We would like to officially reject your
first offer of one blow job per week for
the sum of three years.
This would equate to 156 blow jobs to
be delivered over a sum of 1095 days.
This amount of fellatio
is extremely unreasonable.
We consulted a professional and
April 20th doctor Throat Zilla.
She deemed this activity to be excessive
and dangerous for an amateur and only
to be attempted by a
professional sex worker.
My client and I would like to present a
counter offered to be paid over the sum
of three years,
50 blowjobs to completion.
These blow jobs will be accompanied by
verbal stimulation with such sayings as
where's the com?
Do you have any come when those balls,
five of these said blowjobs will be wake
you up in the morning. Bj's, Oh wow.
50 hand jobs to completion,
cheese lubricant of your choice and as
a bonus on Thompson for his birthday and
the third year of the agreement,
Christina participates in pup play.
This will include fitting Tom for a tail
and they walk around the neighborhood
on a leash in parentheses,
nothing sexual.
You feel this is more than generous
and I'd like to remind you that your
relationships are about compromise and
look forward to finding a resolution.
The two parties can agree upon.
Sincerely,
Barry Brown from Brown and yellow
family law. I love, I didn't,
I didn't know. I know, I didn't
know you retain counsel retain.
Yeah, he's working on
retainer. It's, you know what,
we sat down and we came up with these,
I hope you're okay with these terms.
Well you'll be hearing from my attorney.
So I mean that's fair is fair.
This was,
I'm also very surprising to me and we
had a pretty impromptu but in detailed
conversation with each other
and then with my dad and uh,
with Charro about folding
or scrunching paper,
it's a no brainer.
And guess what?
Guess what I found out from my mother
and then they called me little Jane
went home. She's a scratcher. No, yes,
no. My mom called me. She goes, just
would not believe this. And she said she,
I guess she poked in or you know,
Jane's on the can and then she's like,
she uses a mountain of paper,
like,
like just tons of it and she's
a scrunch or I don't have a,
it's not a moral thing.
It's not a waster thing.
It's about scrunching versus folding.
I don't care about the environment.
My problem is it's not practical because
the pool can touch your fingers if it's
scrunched yellow, brown all
over your feet. Guess what?
This is apparently a worldwide discussion.
You're kidding.
Have you seen this?
You mean we started a worldwide debate.
Debbie squared
[inaudible] Scott
are a
nation divided,
some scratch or this full crazy where,
what country is that? Uh,
obviously that's fucking the UK.
You just looked in the title. Yeah.
You said what country is that?
How many could it be?
Because it could be Ozzy.
It could be Kiwi because
that was a playful UK accent.
It wasn't a strict Royal British accent.
I mean you as a low quote master of all
people should know. Of course. I know,
but it's, yeah, they're
usually, I'm tired.
I thought for sure
Australia cause you know,
they're kind of more fun
about stuff like that.
But you could tell that accident was in
Australia. I don't know. Like I said,
it was a very playful, very playful fuck.
You live there and you don't even know.
No, no clue. It's a, it's hard.
It's, and then you got your,
well she got your Yorkshire. Good,
good Yorkshire Lass. You, by the way,
I am soliciting,
uh,
for the benefit of our
show to your mom's house.
A Nice,
we want you to write reviews on iTunes.
It is a benefit to this show.
We want it,
I'm asking you to write a review and uh,
you know, we'll keep learning
the industry fucking retarded.
Can I tell you the thought that I had
while I was sick? Sure. First of all,
I just want to share this, that, okay.
So I was sick for like fucking 14 days.
I didn't, I wasn't getting
any better really. That was,
that was weird and gnarly.
And then one morning I woke up and I
blew my nose and it was like fluorescent
yellow. It was like a
highlighter marker. Dude. I,
I'm in 40 years of existence. I
have, I wanted to show you so bad.
It was one of those things
I was so proud of and I've, I panicked
and went to the doctor immediately. Um,
but in that,
in the interim of like having this cold,
I was picking my nose and awful lot and
then it was like almost to a point where
like, I knew something was wrong.
Like I was, I was definitely,
it was becoming too much of a habit.
And then I thought to myself like,
am I going to stretch out
my nostrils forever? Right.
The Google that because my texts and my
friend, uh, and she was like, oh my God,
Dude,
I've been picking my nose a lot too
because of allergies and I'm wondering if
I'm going to permanently
stretch out my nostrils.
And my dad told me when I was a kid that
he's like, don't pick your nose so much.
Are going to widen the nostrils.
Yeah.
What did you find going gonna look like
your uncle Steve because he used to pick
his nose.
That's what my dad said that because
my uncle picked his nose a lot,
his nostrils became bigger and you know,
here's something in your formative
years and you believe it.
So I googled it and it said no.
The fact that it's not possible.
You'd have to be doing it like all day,
every day to make an impact.
And I can disagree with me.
I feel like you look in my nostrils now,
aren't they enormous?
I think pregnancy made them bigger.
Get bigger. Your coach, you can
gauge your ear Lobes, right?
People stretch out ear lobes. That's
what I'm saying. That's what I'm saying.
I have enormous nostrils.
Yours are big and hairy,
but I feel like I grew in the last,
I'm serious since I got Prager's.
My nose grew and I feel like my nostrils.
Oh, look how big they are. Yeah.
You're just kind of look like, let's look.
You have a prosthetic nose. Really? Yeah.
It looks like it's so, you know like
Steve Martin in that movie? Yeah.
Movie Ponzel Roxanne.
Yeah.
No,
yours is big and uneven.
It looks like the right nostril is
twice as large as the left. Actually,
everyone's nostrils are different.
Sides of my face is perfectly symmetrical.
I'm the symmetrical champion. I don't know
about that. Yeah. My body, my everything.
Symmetry. I'm like a
model. I'm perfect. No.
Do you know that one of my legs is
significantly shorter than the other?
My right leg is about
an inch or more shorter,
and I went to the chiropractor.
You're going to get one of those a
handicap placards for the corner.
I wish. God, do you think I
can? Does this qualify me?
So it's about time.
I wonder if it's hard to be,
we'll need retarded placards. Let
everybody know. Jesus. Wait, so you,
you agree with me that, that
picking your nose a lot? Definitely.
If you do it enough,
I mean,
I guess it also depends on the
size of the finger. I mean,
you shove a big dogs in a bunch
of big old dogs and your coach,
you can stretch it out.
Why can't you shove a big a finger in
your nostril and stretch it out? Well,
here's the difference, Tom,
and I like your reasoning.
I like your train of thought.
Yeah. The Vagina, however,
is a muscle and can go back to,
it's some kind of losers.
Loser. Poundings yeah,
multiple accounting's all
day. This isn't a nostril.
This is cartilage. And so again, I just,
I feel like that again, the ear lobe is,
seems to be more, most similar to
this. Yeah. If you're a doctor,
can you write and let us know if I've
made my nostrils bigger by picking and if
pregnancy can in fact make your nostrils
bigger. I feel like it, I feel like it's,
yes. Yeah. Yeah. He just
intuitive of course. Of course.
It's one of life's biggest questions.
It's, it feels like it should be an easy
answer. And I think that answer is yes.
Um, this is kind of a dad
Boehner thing where I kind of,
I've got to tell you, this is one of
the first Dad Boehner clips where I,
I feel like I'm aligned with this person.
Really stoked about,
look at that.
Look at that in a shine in us of that.
It's an ounce. It's amazing,
isn't it stuck and what a
feat of engineering. Yeah,
I agree. E I t five p I. E.
Chief five pain.
Haley.
I did staggering
tiger.
He's,
he's holding up if you're listening
is that he's holding up nail clippers.
But I feel like I've had this,
that type of thought before about things
like that and maybe even nail clippers
themselves.
But you're like,
this is an incredible tool that is mass
produced that we would have no idea how
to do this without that. Um, and wouldn't,
none of us could build one of those.
Yeah.
Can we make it so cheap? Did a
shine in. I shed that match. Oh,
look at the engineering. I know.
I agree. The inclined plane.
It's amazing.
Oh Shit.
He's so good.
So just start in a day saying go
make one of them be there for a week.
I know for a month. I know Mike
[inaudible] is good as I know. Yeah.
Awesome Metaphor for life. This was
such a amazing, it's staggering.
It knows no bounds, but it's cheap. Cheap,
cheap, cheap, cheap, cheap, cheap,
cheap, cheap, cheap, cheap, cheap, cheap,
cheap, cheap light. Check in check.
Like fucking chicken.
Oh,
oh, oh. Why
I t five bay last.
What life is worth us.
What fucking line.
Yeah.
Yes. The first time a dad
boner. I've nodded along.
Hi. Great. I love his enthusiasm. I
share his enthusiasm for that. Yeah,
that was rad. I mean, what other
things are there where you're like,
holy fucking shit.
Pens. That was my first,
that was my first thought
when I was thinking,
what else is that like you take pens
for granted, pair, amazing paper clips.
Some motherfucker was like, let's make
this shit then and then do that like that.
And now I can hold fucking papers to
talk about a stapler. Scotch tape.
Amaz hairbrush Amaz
like everything we use,
uh,
bandaids so that you booboos
don't get infected toothbrushes.
How are low or Ular,
but that,
that is a feat of human engineering
for sure. I mean, how he's right.
If someone was like, hey,
build a Nalco, no fucking idea.
And it looks simple and
that's why it's deceptive.
Remember on the Great British baking show?
Because everything leads back there
at when they're like, make a pretzel.
And that's something you see a
hundred times in a mall. Right?
Because we were there a lot. I couldn't
recreate the shape of a pretzel.
I don't know exactly how,
but you see it somewhat that
some version of it be be like,
that doesn't look right.
Right.
It's like the thing you take for granted
all the time. It looks so simple,
but it's not coffee.
I want a coffee right now.
I know you drink a lot of coffee.
Does your piece smell all the time like
it does cause one time you peed in the
shower with me and it smelled like
someone. I'll be honest, coffee.
I was probably drinking too much coffee
and I focus on the counterbalance more.
Now you bounce it out more. Yeah. You
have to rehydrate after you dehydrate.
You Nasty.
I love this guy.
I love him. I love it. I love it.
I had the horrible misfortune of,
of all the millions of times I've
dropped my iPhone and I'd do it a lot.
I can't believe that. Go ahead.
That it finally shattered.
I broke the screen on my iPhone and
you know when you do it at first,
like there's a moment of disbelief.
Like I,
it took me about a week to come to terms
with the fact that I broke it, you know,
like to just, it was like the stages
of grief. Like I have to do something.
You know why I,
I had the stages of grief,
that Kubler Ross thing because I don't
want to go to the fucking apple store.
Like that's my nightmare is making
the fucking appointment showing up.
And then the,
the,
the search for who works here
and then just making eye contact,
hoping that that person's an employee
with a ponytail and then just go stand
over there. That's my family knows
stand over day and said, by the way,
the lack of structure, goddammit, this
is what is upsetting the apple store.
It gives me so much anxiety.
We're not a regular store.
We have our own thing going on here.
No, no, no. Give me the regular store.
Let me stand in line
and let me know where I am in line,
how much time I have kind of
go to that. Fuck you. Yeah.
And I'll tell you what else can
irritate the shit out of me.
So when I had that audio
trouble with this one,
I was also having audio
trouble by my other one. So I
go, I'm going to bring both.
When I pick up the one that's
fixed,
this one I go,
can you take a look at this other one?
[inaudible] you gotta you
gotta make another appointment.
You can go over to that table and sit
there. I'm like, well you're right here.
Can't you just can't I just leave
it with you. It's fucked up.
Just fix it the way you fix this one.
Cause that's outside of the wacky way
we do. We don't do things traditionally.
We don't do things the way that
would make sense to do them. No,
I like tradition guys. Let me know
where to go and where to stand in line.
And then the worst is when you activate
a device. I activated my mom, watch,
go,
go stand at that table and then it's one
employee and then five old people like
me, like I don't know how
to put in my password.
And then she has to divvy up her time
between the five poor girl, old people,
some poor millennial has to
help you figure it all out.
And then the guy's like,
dammit. She goes, I've been there
sitting next to guys since she goes in,
then you know your password. Now you
don't know your password. Uh, no.
Uh,
granddaughter's name is Brandy.
And then they're like,
okay, we can try that.
And then I saw this old lady who had the
tiniest iPhone there ever was like the
first one, you know, it's like,
uh, just a, an an inch of this.
And she's like,
but I wanted to work again.
Like she was some foreign lady and
the guy and the guy was like, oh yeah,
I know that your motherboard is fried.
You need to buy a whole new phone.
And she's like, but go god,
magnus, one word, please,
please make the one word that I have.
Like she couldn't come to Jesus on it.
Like, please don't make
me spend $800. Please,
please just let me have my old ass phone.
Make it work please.
And that's all you're thinking when you
go in there and just please make this,
make my life right again. Just
make my life okay. Oh, oh,
okay. Oh, by the way, I wanted
to mention this. So I was, um,
when I, a few weeks ago maybe
that this point a month or so ago,
I had these shows coming up that
were for Seattle and Portland.
So I reached out this great artist in
Philadelphia, Paul greenies. And I go,
I go, Hey, do you want to do a poster?
We've worked together before on other
posters. And he said, yeah, he goes,
any ideas? Cause he always
says like, you know,
is there anything you want incorporate?
And at the time I remember that, um,
everybody has been mentioning
that whenever I put up
photos to promote my shows,
they're all pre weight loss. So
they're all like, man, none of your,
your pictures look like you. Yeah. And
like, you know, so I just mentioned, I go,
well, you know, I haven't had
anything that reflects my weight loss.
I'm like,
just nothing.
So far everything has been like
photos that were taken before.
That's all I gave him.
And then he made this.
I love it. I love it.
And so it's me with some
glass and, and I look like
I'm 130 pounds. It's gaunt.
Anyways,
it's a beautiful poster.
I had some left over from yeah,
look like from that tour. Uh,
it's uh, it's screen printed. It,
it's super high quality paper and
I signed a whole batch of them,
so if you want them,
they're in our store right now.
Um,
it's a great poster related. Amazing. Uh,
and there's a bunch of, uh,
let me see if this is a,
there's some other things that
are in there, but check it out.
There's a bunch of things, but
that poster is, is brand new shirt.
Don't forget that one. Yeah. And Gene,
I tell you that sweatshirt, the jeans,
sweatshirt is my favorite thing ever.
It's beautiful.
It's always in the hamper I got, I wear
it so frequently. Yeah. It's my favorite.
It's a pretty fucking, a lot of
people have been getting the, the,
the established is that now.
That's how I say that.
It's 100. I've been in conversations
where it's about to come out naturally.
Like I'm not thinking about our
show and I'll be like, you know,
you kinda got a wonder if you have the,
you know,
the wherewithal to do it.
I'll stop and I'll be like, I'm
not sure I can't, I'm not sure yet.
Well now I have to go. I say the word
stand on my head and then I go, oh,
it's stamina. I have to
reverse it. And people are, uh,
have sent in like one guy sending a
video of him at the gym and he's like,
I'm going to kill this lift.
I have to stand in line.
And you know that people don't generally,
like that kind of shirt is all
fucking wrong. We'll look, uh,
we're,
we're here.
Might as well do this
right now too. Right? So
[inaudible] you got some
big stuff coming up June.
I do,
man.
I'm gearing up to shoot my first
hour and I'm so fucking stop.
Come see me and see the hour.
That's going to be immortalized forever.
Uh, I'm going to go to Sacramento
this weekend. April 28th and 29th,
Sacramento Punchline, May 4th
and fifth. Phoenix, Arizona.
[inaudible] at standup rive,
May 19th through 20th. Jew,
Dork titties at Gotham.
Come on your club June 1st through
third Denver Com. Com works.
Dong Dong the downtown
location and then man,
friend disco at the Punch Shrine
June 16th and June 17th and I'm just,
I'm okay. I know I'll,
I'll hold off on the actual
press pause on that and I'm not
going to blow my load now that,
uh,
tickets@thousandrachdotcomspelledoutthousandranch.com.
Thank you.
My sexy summer tour is just so dumb.
Here's where I'm coming.
June toxin, Arizona
three all two theater.
June 10th Breen Ho Ho Reno.
What is that? What's Reno
greenhouse greenhouse, Nevada.
June 11th,
I'm at uh,
the Pachanga casino in Temecula
to Mech come la, California.
Uh, that's it for June, July 11th,
I started a little bit of a southern run.
I do Richmond,
Virginia. Then July 12th,
Virginia Beach, Virginia.
Then July 13th,
Greensboro North Coming
Eliana and July 14th,
Asheville at Harry Asheville.
And then July 15th,
that whole weeks in the south, it
ends at a big show. And Charleston,
South Carolina. Um, that should be
a lot of fun. Later in that month,
the 27th, I'm in Hampton feet,
Tampon Beach, New Hampshire,
28th Wilmington deck,
low DICO where?
And July 29th and Baltimore
Whores Marilyn to city that reads.
Of course, you know, I'm going
to mum Straya Brisbane, Sydney,
Melbourne and Perth.
How Fun.
And then the final episode of summer is
we are doing the podcast live in brass
balls, beach at the Improv.
That's West Palm Beach, Florida.
I am calling you out.
Indian River County Port Saint Lucy.
Dewert.
Okay.
Choke.
Papi,
Garden County Dade County Day.
Again, all of you for
sure near there. Nope.
But uh, yeah, I mean they're close enough.
If you're in any of those areas,
make the drive and uh,
it's going to be a fun, fun night. We're
going to do the podcast live in Florida,
so it's not often that we get to
travel that far and do the show,
but we're doing it.
That'd be fine.
In Indian River County. I forgot
it was called that dude. Yeah.
Florida is so fucking
weird, man. You know,
I mean from the minute you get off
the plane. I love Florida by the way.
It's not la. I mean, you know. No
worries. But I do like, I enjoy it.
Yeah. It's so weird. You seem
so happy just hearing about
it. Yeah. I like Florida,
man. I, I like the weather. I
like the people. It's like a,
it's kind of swampy and spooky are
so happy. Weird that I, Oh shit.
Goddamn Bruce Thompson
scientist video series continues
our look at chemicals on the cheap.
So if you're a cash,
it is essential in a home lab both
as a reagent and it's a precursor for
synthesizing other chemicals.
Until recently I recommended battery
acid is a good source. Battery acid,
it's about 35% concentration
and relatively pure.
And it was cheap a few years ago.
Five gallon jugs sold for 15 or $20
in gallon jugs when only $6 or so
recently a lot of doors
and found the price.
It's sky rocketed to about 15 years.
It makes it extra boring
his face.
Yeah.
The fact that he hasn't moved a muscle
and he hasn't blank to the entire time.
How do you stay that still
dead eyes?
God looks like fucked up shit.
I think he molests children to Jesus.
I wasn't going there.
I think he molests retarded children.
That's creepy.
He looks creepy and we're
going to get emails like, Hey,
that's rob the chemical go. And so
it was gonna be like, that's my dad.
You asshole.
Well, your dad's creepy as fuck scissors.
Another amazing adventure. Notice
I'm wearing very heavy rubber gloves,
acid
addition to burn.
Your voice is so monotone.
It's also an extremely hydrating agents,
so it literally sucks the water out
of your skin and charge it. Whoa. Wow.
Don't mess around in fight club
with concentrated sulfuric acid.
There you go. I think that's
what happened in fight club.
The concentrated sulfuric acid poison on
the Tyler Durden is hand Tyler pours it
on Jim Norton's hand. Isn't that what
they did? Jim Norton? You mean Ed Norton
wrong with you?
I do that all the time.
And then we heard,
um,
Jimmy Dean Stanton on
the radio the other day.
Oh yeah, the sausage. Jimmy Dean
Morgan Sausage. Jeffrey Jeffrey, James,
Jimmy Morgan's, Jimmy Dean sausage.
That's who it is. Jimmy Dean sausage.
Jeffrey gains. Jeffrey Dean
Sausage. Morgan sausage. Yeah.
Um, I have some, would you
rathers come on, man. Really?
You want to do it? Would you rather what
is, you have something else you wanna do?
No, go ahead. Go ahead.
The top layer.
Your sister,
grandmother walks masturbating.
Never have another orgasm.
[inaudible]
are you ready? Yup.
Okay. Would you rather,
every time you see somebody, and this
can be like you're walking the dogs,
which never happens, but you're
out with a kid and just a neighbor
passes by you.
And every time you see another human
being and they get within your shot,
you rep all loud fart. Okay. One of your
morning farts, like you fucking blasted.
Okay,
okay.
Or every time you see Ellis
you get so you get so excited
that you vomit.
Okay.
Or every time you see Ellis,
you get so excited that you vomit all
over yourself. I don't even see that.
How you have the nerve to
pitch something like that.
Being that you have such a
ridiculous phobia for the eye,
you know, even that concept. I mean,
you get so you get man. Yeah, I know,
but that's why it's called Woodridge.
Just Game Babes game. It's not reality.
Rather. No, I'm not listening to them.
You're so happy that you're able
to take them off lies and lies.
I promise you I'm not so either.
I'm, I've fart within earshot.
Anytime I see anyone. Anyway, so you're,
you're at the airport and it
just try every new person.
Welcome to the planner. Whenever
I see my son, I vomit. Yeah,
you get so excited that you
eventually vomit on yourself. No fart.
I would eventually
learned to deal with that.
Like the embarrassment would
become second nature. You know,
it's like somebody has like a fucking
goiter on their neck and it's like,
oh my God. But after they have that
for like a year, they're like, yeah,
I got this fucking thing on my neck.
You know, and like people look at it,
it's embarrassing.
I don't care anymore.
That's how those farts on
the positive side, you know,
every time you come out on stage,
you rip a huge into the mic and it's Tom
Cigarette fighting comedian, comedian.
It becomes a hug plus chicks.
There's chicks would be like,
this guy is pretty fucking cool.
Women love burning guys like the
guys that, that Fart openers.
Now I don't have to keep farting.
Right. So I can, you know,
keep framing every time you
have a question about that,
because you said like every new person,
so I had a show do I farted
like a thousand times? If
there's a thought that yes.
Now that I think about every
time you look at somebody,
so you've got to pick like five
people to look at you like, Hey,
make the show room pitch black.
I don't want to see anybody that's,
that's your work around. Okay,
that's true. Of course I'm farting.
What are you doing? Is it even worth
the time our nanny comes? It comes in.
Yeah, you get used to it. She'd
be like, yeah, he's a nice guy.
We go to the playground, Ellis and he
see another parent. You flirt. I mean,
it's going to hurt. It's going
to ruin your life. That's great.
Did you come up with that? No Way. Would
you have answer it though? What's yours?
Well, obviously funding because
of my severe phobia of vomiting,
God damn severe metaphor.
I'll balance this.
Where yours listener ones. Okay. So people
have been submitting them as well. Okay.
So, and then we'll go back and
forth. Uh, somebody's rights.
Would you rather read the entire iTunes
update agreement from top to bottom?
Every word no skimming.
So funny.
I'm like God or a shit.
Listen to Frank Sinatra and Garth Brooks.
Oh Man.
One after another.
For the amount of time it would rate.
Take you to read the iTunes of
Green Nolan from Winnipeg, Manitoba.
You know,
I'm one of those people who might find
it interesting to try and understand the
iTunes agreement.
What I get very angry at.
Um,
auditory assaults like that.
Like it would enrage me
to listen to Garth and uh,
and then you throw on you be 40
and I would just be like, oh,
I think it takes to read the iTunes
agreement. I mean, it's possible.
It's easy to get to scroll on. It's
on your phone, but that phone snap,
do I have to understand it? Oh,
you don't have to understand it.
You've got to read every word. I'm
a quick reader. I'm not like you.
I don't have to sound everything out and
can move my lips. When I read to myself.
It might take 10 minutes. It's fine.
I went to law school for two weeks.
Don't forget,
that's like reading an iTunes agreement
every fucking day to the iTunes
agreement. It just upsets me. The whole
thing. The idea of reading it upsets me.
Yeah. Yeah. It's all like legal jargon
and yeah, and I was a paralegal,
so it doesn't bother me. Holly's like you
have any qualifications for that stuff?
No, I don't, but I, I was an
immigration parents. So what?
It's still intrigues you.
It doesn't intrigue me, but I mean,
I've read boring stuff like, yeah, no.
So 100% I would listen to Garth
and frank for that amount of time.
Yeah. I'm not much of a reader, Huh? Yeah.
Well not breeding fucking
iTunes agreements.
I can't believe you're signing up
for that. I do it for fun right now.
You'd read the iTunes agreement,
pull it up. I'll take a look.
I'll let you know when it says God.
K. Yeah. Okay. What'd you rather,
every time you leave the grocery store,
are you listening to me or are
you paying attention? Yeah.
Every time you leave the grocery store.
Okay,
and someone's pitching some nonsense,
you have to stop and fully give
them your presence and listen to,
they'll hold children,
save the bees,
save the tsunami, whatever. The other
thing, and then you have to donate the,
Oh my God, what's wrong
with you? This is so good.
You have to do this for the rest of
your life. Every time. Every time.
They're out here, everywhere. Everywhere.
I know trader Joe's, trader, sorry,
Trader Joe.
You got to go to whole foods and you got
to listen to the whole spiel and then
you have to do whatever it is they want
you to do every so there's no hurrying
out of the grocery store is when
I saw you that lately, by the way,
I've noticed that.
I must be giving off a do not
even think about photography because
I have noticed them skipping me a lot.
Like I walk out and there'll be
two of them and they'll be like,
go talk to another person.
Well,
your beard makes you look angry in
medicine and you probably just look angry.
Yeah. Yeah. You're not like, I've
told you this before. You're not fun.
You're not engaging. You're not
friendly. You're not social.
That's what a personality.
Other people see me full of shit and they
approached me. They want to talk to me.
They want a hug. No, very huggable.
Kissable enjoyable's of human. Okay.
You know that. That's not true
about you. That's so true.
I'm so many know that that's not true
about you. I'm so between the two of us,
likable. Everybody would rather spend
time with me. Not True Bait. That's not,
oh my God. I'm talking about like in the
comedy club world, they're always like,
how's that fucking? All I hear is Tom hate
me. No, you know Tom doesn't hate you.
He hates everybody. Okay. So it's
either this for the rest of your life.
Every time you go to the grocery store
you have to do that. It's a really good,
by the way,
really good one kill or once a week you
have to go to the apple store to either
have something repaired
or to buy something,
but without an appointment.
Oh my God.
Once a week or every time you go there
as both robbing you of time. Yeah.
That's the whole point.
Aggravating and they're going to,
they're going to wear on your
last nerve and it's a hassle.
I'm trying to think which one
would I rather do. It's horrible.
It's an excellent with your other,
because they're both equally undesirable.
Horrible. I think might end up
murdering of parking lot petitioner.
I mean at least in the apple store,
I'm acquiring a toy.
You know, like in the grocery
store I'm acquiring a necessity.
It's probably you have to food and
things for the house like that,
but it's a toy.
So maybe I can look at the toy reward
as like that's the payoff here.
I mean,
you get some cool gadget here pretty soon,
and every once in a while I'll
land in there when there isn't a,
I'm a crazy three hour
line to do something.
And here's your workaround to you could,
you can game the system,
find out when the low
traffic times are right.
Maybe it's right when the store opens
at 9:00 AM at the mall. So yeah.
My problem with the parking lot,
uh,
petitioners is that I feel
like they work from this.
They like to the worst shape come
from a guilt place begins with those.
Sometimes they'll say like, I'll be
walking to my car and they'll say, uh,
do you know that there's
300,000 kids in Los Angeles?
They don't have a place to sleep tonight.
And I'm like, no. Yeah, wouldn't you?
Like, wouldn't you like to be able
to do something about that? No. No.
Well, now you can. So they're just like,
they're just guilting you. They're not,
they're not like sharing
information with you at the farm. Make you
feel bad. Of course, of course. It's all,
it's all manipulation. Do you want to
donate a dollar to the save the teachers?
Now I give money to teachers. I do, but
I feel like save the children. Like do,
I'm saving my kid right now. Like
I'm, I'm wrapped up in a toddler.
It's a full time job. I'm taking care
of my children so don't worry about it.
Okay. Someone else submitted.
Wait, why did you choose apple?
100% man. Apple. I have to
say that I don't enjoy the,
here's what I hate so much
about the apple store.
I don't like the mall driving to the mall,
parking at the mall
and dealing with it. I would rather do
the parking lot. So listen work. Yeah.
Cause I'd make friends and because
I'm friendly with everybody,
cause I'm such a good personality
and I'd, you know, I'd make it fun.
You should met both of us
and fold them assigned to interviews.
Well we just see like who really,
really who they think has a
better personality. Right?
I mean it's obvious it's me because I,
I actually don't believe that
you believe that now people are,
you have a much more cold.
Yes. You have a much more cold,
much more cutoff,
much less engaging in warm personality.
And you know it, you're always like
Tommy, you go talk to them. Oh,
it's not because you're
a better personality,
but because sometimes I don't
want to deal with that person. No,
because you're just, you're more of a
curmudgeon. You're more like a wreck,
loose that you know, you can't you, oh,
I'm a loner for sure. Yeah. Well, I mean,
on and on. I enjoy a lot of people's
coats. Ted Bundy. I mean there's, there's,
there's your, you have that same kind
of am the alone champ. I definitely,
but I'm very selective of
who I spend my free time.
I had a handful of friends
that I've had since I was 14.
People don't like you in general though.
I would say that's not true, I think.
But I think I make a great impression.
Um,
like a cursory sort of surface friend.
Absolutely.
Ask anybody at the comedy store if there,
who do you like better?
Tom And Christina? Not Comedy
wise, like who's Funnier,
but who do you like as a person who's
a better personality? Hands Down,
I'm going to win that.
Keep going and okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Would you add there?
Be Skinny and eat whatever you want.
You can eat whatever you want and
stay then and not have to exercise,
but your poor kinda stay poor
for the rest of your life.
Or you're rich.
You can eat whatever the fuck you want.
You can exercise, but you'll
always stay fat. Say you're fat,
but you've got like stacks. Like you're
a multimillionaire and you don't have to,
you don't have to work.
You can work when you want,
so it's skinny and poor or rich and
fat and you can eat what you want.
In both scenarios.
I feel like for many people,
this is so easy.
And I think the only reason that it's,
I find it intriguing to me is, uh,
even though I'm
not skinny, I've recently lost
some weight, you know? Yeah.
Well this one I designed, especially
for you, right? You're, you just,
you just started to, you know, lose
some weight. You're looking better,
you're feeling better. And you know
how good that feels. Oh, it's the best.
But what would you like
to be the best version?
Like the best version of that,
but you're poor,
poor, and you can't, there's no hope like
you're and how poor qualify. Yeah. Okay.
Uh,
I mean,
you're not talking about like,
I can't pay bills and I can't do anything
right. I mean, it's gotta be like,
okay, you're not Bangladeshi poor.
You're not living in a cardboard box and,
and, uh, defecating and shouted in Los
Angeles terms. Yeah. Korea town in 2008.
Okay, so you were living in like
getting by Barrio, getting by,
getting by in the Barrio. But
that's it. I mean, you're,
you're locked in the rampart division.
You're living in that apartment.
Jose's your landlord.
That's as high as it's ever going to get,
but you look amazing and you
can eat anything you want.
You don't have to exercise.
And you stay skinny and healthy.
And that's the thing you have.
You have all your health and you can eat
whatever you want it, but you're rich,
rich, rich. Yes. Stacking it, but
fat, fat as fuck. And how fat.
That's the other thing. Okay.
Uh, what's the heaviest?
You don't have to say the
number, but whatever your
heaviest is. Yeah, that's what,
that's what it's got to stay. Yeah.
That's where it stays now. Oh, sorry.
Cause I have my answer. Oh,
you do? Yeah. Yeah. 100% rich.
Hundred percent. Why? I mean, I, I,
you know, I remember being that fat.
It's not that bad.
I mean, people actually, honestly,
until we invited fat shaming,
no one really gave me
a hard time about it.
I have like one person every once in a
while I would say something on social
media. They'd be like, you look fat
in this big. I'm like, all right. Uh,
it's not that bad.
So because I made the number
something you've already been, okay,
let's then let know. I'm saying even
if you look, I could have gotten
fatter and let's say in this
scenario I'm even fatter.
I would rather have the comforts and the,
the hurts of that lifestyle.
Right? Uh, and no,
I guess that I'm going to die at any time,
but you have enough money to kind of
do something. I can take medicine.
That's right. Right. And I can,
you ain't got the best access to
medical care and now you're fat.
You're not manwell your rebate. Oh, come
on. No, no. Listen, you're, maybe you're,
you're, you're bad. You're five
bills. No, you did not. That I know.
This is a different scenario.
So if we were driving down scenario,
this is an additional question. So
we've, we've had, that question's gone.
New Scenario. Okay. Same, same
stakes, but you're 500 no,
definitely not. I'm not doing that. That's
too much. Yeah, that's too much. Oh wait,
who's 500 people on Tlc on those people
that they're like, hey, maybe
in a week or two you'll die.
You don't do something that's too fat.
You want to know.
That's like for my height and frame.
What would be like,
what'd be punishing for you? Yeah. I mean,
well definitely the upper 200300300
would be like really heavy.
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. What? For
my frame? Yeah, you would be,
you'd be like, Jesus, man, you
really need to drop some weight.
How fat was like Mama June.
Oh, okay. You don't know how
that is a dom delouis fat.
Oh yeah, he's three over 300. What'd
you be damned Eloise fat? I mean,
I wouldn't want to. Okay. What about God,
you're still doing this because I'm
trying to, I don't want, I don't know,
men's weights. Like I don't, I don't
know what 300 pounds is on a man.
I can kind of guess on a woman. I just
don't know your weight. 300 pounds.
Ooh. Like my, okay. Picture my heaviest.
Another 30 something.
35 pounds basically.
It doesn't seem like a lot to me.
Fucking a really 35 more pounds on that.
How fat was la? The Front?
Shucks. Cylance and wells. I mean,
at that point he was probably,
he looked like he was over 300 pounds.
You're Orson Welles fat. That's the
level of fat at the end of his life.
Let's look at it.
Okay. Um, let's see what we have here. Fat
Worsen
cause you would take, so
what's, what's the lure?
It's the money that you'd rather have
money is what you're saying. Well,
I'd rather have,
um,
the,
the comfort and the security. The
money provide. Yeah. I mean, your mind,
I've been very broke and,
uh,
and I, I have no shame about
having been that broke.
And I feel like that period
taught me a lot, a lot, uh,
about myself and about life. But I never
want to go back to being broke again.
Sucks. I mean, yeah,
that was terrible. So,
but you heal what have you could
look the best and you'll never
age shitty. Like you'll,
you'll just be hot fat.
Orson Welles kind of looks like me.
Not at all.
Ah, holy. That's his leg
right there. That's kind of,
it kind of looks like a gut because that
picture is, I see that I'm going to try.
I mean, he doesn't look
good. That's him thinner.
Hmm. No, that's fat. Yeah.
Let's definitely fat.
Yeah. He's, he's definitely
fat there. Um hmm. I Dunno.
Let's, how about this though?
How fad is he?
Um,
you'd be fat and rich. So
here's the thing. I mean, yeah,
you could die anytime, but
you've seen these commercials,
I thought, is he here?
Faith?
It
doesn't do anything.
I remember he's got his Chyna
action that drunk underbite
just doing anything. Sorry.
Cut. Okay. Rolling. Two,
take two.
I mean, yeah, this guy is, but he's got,
he's got to be like three bills. Yeah.
So that's how fat you are. Just so,
just so you know. I would do that. Rich.
It'd be awesome
because the level of Richard describing
it sounds like it's so much fun. Yeah.
You're just like Richard Brown
balling out of control. All right.
Some big fat rich guy.
So what? Okay. It's fun.
Yeah.
Well you start driving it up like
you're saying. I mean that's the thing.
Everyone has their, their limits for
things. If you go up to 500 I'll be like,
no. Okay. But here's the
thing. You're skinny. Yeah.
And you can eat as much as you want.
So I get the satisfaction of all the food.
I want to gain weight, but I'm
poor. So what? But I've done it.
I've told you I've done it.
It was a thing.
It was a phase and I don't want to do
it again, but I know you love to eat.
Imagine you could just eat, eat, eat, eat,
eat, eat. You don't have to gain weight.
Okay. Just the free all. I
think we chose our sides then.
Sounds like you chose that,
right? You'd rather be poor. Ah,
I hate fucking being poor. Yeah. Actually
I would rather be hot and skinny.
Then I'll just find a guy,
some fucking rich guy,
some fridge fat guy and I'll be like,
let's hook up and then we'll
find each other. There you go.
We did it and I'll marry
you. Harrison. Yo, Mary.
Ah,
French champagne.
There's always celebrated.
The guy pick up the California champagne.
My Song,
he's really good cars by Ed and I.
That same French excellence.
The bottle don't like the
best French champagne.
It's vintage tainted show Pharma
shots one or two take three.
Action please.
The French champagne has
always been celebrating.
Excellence is a kind of fun.
Your champagne by far.
Mass Song.
Bob, Bob, Bob, Bob. I have one more.
Okay, cool. So what's the lesser, I mean
I shouldn't say that. Okay, here we go.
This one's just more base. Okay. Okay.
Would you rather, every time you fart,
it's a short or every time you burp.
It's a birth.
Every time you fart, it's a shark. Yeah.
Or every time you burp, it's a birth.
Yeah.
Whew.
Um, God. Yeah.
That's a really gross, I haven't burned
in a long time since I was pregnant.
Barfing is the word that's really gross.
I feel like you've,
I birthed a lot when I was a
kid. Here's, I think you'd have
to choose barfing though.
Okay. Because, okay.
They're both growth.
They're both uncomfortable.
Sharding ruins that part of
your day completely. Like,
you're going to have things you need
to be doing that you're like, I have,
I have shit in my ass cheeks right now.
We're as,
while the burping is disgusting.
You can at least be like
however gross this is,
I could still walk into this
place right now. You know,
I can spit on the sidewalk. Right.
But you got to change underwear
when you start it fucked up.
Time they ruin. Takes up.
Yeah. Well, I like it.
That's your concern is,
oh, wait a lot of damn
moments. Well, listen,
but listen,
here's why.
I choose sharp because you choose
sharp because you can prepare,
you bring wipes and you bring
panties with you on the road.
You pack yourself a diaper
bag like we do for the kid.
Basically our kids shirts and you
just wipe it up and y'all is nasty.
It's nasty. Or I would wear
adult diapers and that way, dude,
that's how you do this.
So you just wear adult diapers,
you shorten the diaper and you wipe your
ass with fucking moist towelette and
then you're done. Right.
It's just so nasty.
You can hold in a fart and that way you
wouldn't have to shirt, but a birth,
you can't borrow everywhere.
All right,
you just wipe and then
you're done. I hate kissing.
Fine. Hey, somebody sent
in this clip. This is
audio only of a, your
favorite thing of barfing? No,
it's a pornographic film. But this
one has a very funny line. Okay.
Uh,
tell me what you think of this.
You ready to be a single mother? Oh my
God. Are you ready to be a single mother?
Me.
Here's some multis in that pussy round.
Ready to be a single mother of six.
Say Mother say,
wow. Yes. You're not going to
call my phone after this, right.
I'm a block your number. You're not gonna
come to my crib. Right, right. Hi. Hi.
Here we go. Oh Shit. Oh,
oh,
oh.
That's pretty clever,
Huh? As far as writing,
I'm sure the writers spend
some time on that. Nope.
I'm amazed he could get out that dialogue
as well as he did. And the jacket. Yeah.
That was really a lot of work on his part.
A strong performer. Oh Shit. Oh.
But I mean, you're ready to be
a single mother. That's a funny,
very hard ready to be a
single mother. Yeah. I mean,
anybody that's known as single
mother been a single mother. Yeah.
Not Easy. I wouldn't, I wouldn't take
that ejaculations oof. I know. No thanks.
Because he's basically
telling you never, ever. I get
it. Yeah. Don't contact me.
I heard it's pretty funny.
Um,
you got an email email here.
Uh,
I feel compelled to weigh in on your
wiping style conversation from episode
three 92.
Yeah.
I believe that both bunching and
folding have benefits and drawbacks.
The bunch picks up more,
but as you said,
leaves you open to poopy knuckles.
If you aren't careful,
the fold is more civilized
and protects your knuckles,
but it has been known to require more
wipes and is prone to punch through with a
finger. If you are thorough and a
committed wipers such as myself,
this is why I employ a hybrid strategy.
I will take a length of paper,
perhaps eight squares are so fold at once.
Then bunch half allowing the flap to
form a tail like the train of a wedding
dress.
That way I enjoy the superior wiping
power of the bunch while protecting my
knuckles from collateral
damage with the fold.
I hope this helps and if you choose
to read my email on the show that can,
that I can change a life. Keep it
classy. Jeans, Zach from Texas.
There's some, I hear some
flaws in your logic. A,
how do we know that the folded wipe
leads to more wipes than a bunched wipe?
I don't. I mean we need to
see some scientific evidence,
empirical data to back up this claim.
I don't know. Yeah, I don't know.
I don't know that that's
founded in anything. Check
out this lunatic. I used to,
uh,
have a joke about this in my act.
I never made it onto like
a special or anything,
but I used to make fun
of people that did this.
What's up guys? So people have
been asking me, Oh, how come?
And the recent training videos, even
posting, I see you wearing jeans. I mean,
I just, I've never seen a fucking
guy where it is in the gym before.
So why are you the exception?
Is there a benefit to wearing jeans?
So I want to answer that question today.
Why this house smells destiny?
Where jeans, well, I'll tell you why.
It's because a long time ago your
man used to be professional climber.
And I'm not talking about one of those
climbers that you're going to a facility
and you climb goes fucking rocks
though I was a ghetto climber.
I used to climb fuck a buildings, legit
buildings with my fucking fingertips,
you know?
And what happens is that if you're wearing
shorts or track pads to going to Rick.
Hmm.
So for many, many, many years,
all I did is I trained with jeans.
I used to do a wall runs with jeans.
I used to,
everything with James flips would genes,
the whole fucking nine yards.
And I know that sounds a bit unusual,
but I don't think this is that uncommon
in the park who slash climate world.
Yeah.
But if you gave me the choice whether
or not I could train with jeans or with
track class, I would choose. I would
choose. Jeans are 100% of the time.
It's fucking great. I love it. I can
go ATG on a squat with jeans. Oh,
I can get much tighter on a
deadlift for jeans. It's like,
it's almost similar to multiply. You
know, you're having that extra thickness
here.
I think you look so crazy with gyms or
at the gym with jeans like I used to
make, I used to have a joke about how,
you know, like what are you a fuck?
I forget the joke,
but I was like,
are you a communist or is
it like a Romanian fucking
infiltrator wearing because
you look like a lunatic. You look like it
looks like an episode of the Americans.
Like the, the person just arrived
and they're doing the fitness.
My trends. It's a Hungarian dude. Um,
I this think you're kind of low and loose
when you say things like that. Yeah.
Given that were in your mom's house,
do you think you could have some
fucking respect? Yeah. Just so you know,
I'm having [inaudible] pants made out
of denim right now as we speak. Yes.
I used to everything with jeans. I don't
like spandex. I want them to be denim.
We both been doing pilots. I know we
both did. We made fitness today. No,
I wish I never had to workout by.
This is the second time I've never had
this happen as I'm making fitness my
right tricep, it goes into a
full cramp. It was so bizarre.
It's just,
it's one of the things I've never had
it happen twice cause you're not wearing
denim denim shirts and then then we're
just looking at it. It's going to, yeah,
like clamping up and releasing.
You're not used to making
fitness as hard as I do. Yeah,
I think that's part of it. I'm also the
fitness champ. That's right. That's right.
Um, all right. Well anything
else you want to fill her up?
Holy Shit. That is big time. That is.
Hey fever
shot shot.
Okay,
look at bids
by the way.
I want it to announce that
this Friday
we are releasing the a
Yoshi live podcast episode.
So the late show and Irvine will come
out this Friday for all you genes out
there and sperm vine,
the sperm vine show
with Yoshi will be out.
Oh boy. Is she all right. Fill
her up. Jane, what do you got?
We know it's been so long since we've
done this show and I thought, you know,
we've never really done a
super mega celebrity edition.
I thought why not do the
most famous people in the
world? Okay. The Kardashians.
Wow. Why not? We know and
there's a whole new school now,
so let's get into it. Fill her up.
Seal her shot. Let's start with the,
with the ladies. Okay.
Is it Kimar Kylie. Wow.
Cause those are kind of like the two.
They're all famous.
But those are the two probably
most famous. Those are
the two, the two hotties,
right?
Well Courtney and uh,
they're less or lesser card and
they're not as hot as Kim and Kylie.
Those are the secondary third dairy.
Technically she's a gender.
Well Kylie Jenner. That's what I'm saying.
It's all the same clan. You're right.
But,
so Kim is like the two point,
the 2.0 model and then
Kylie's the 2.4 whatever.
You know what I'm saying? Is it
2009 or 2017 I mean, I'll tell you,
I got a problem right away with like,
she looks like I liked snakes,
but she looks like a,
like a little doll or something,
you know?
What do you mean she looks too
juvenile? Oh, she's too young.
She's too young. It's
not that like, you know,
I mean this looks like a little kid.
Yeah,
she's still pubescent is
what you're saying? Is She,
I don't know how old she is,
so I, I'm assuming she's over 18
for the purposes of this report.
I hope so. She's 18 so
she's a teenager. Yeah.
All right. I don't know. Never
mind. I'll go back on that then.
So I feel better now.
Yeah. So it's basically,
do you feel like teaching someone
a few lessons or do you want,
I guess,
you know,
the most famous post posted in the world
that has just been beaten up left and
right by monstrous black dogs.
But she'll be like,
so are we going to, are you going to
come in me? And I'm like, I'm in there.
And she's like, no, seriously.
I'm like, Oh really?
And we've seen what she's capable of.
If you've seen the rage a video,
yeah. She's used to like
some massive black dogs mind.
And let's throw this into the ring
before even, so is this one, by the way,
she's going to the black guys,
but let's keep in mind that
Kim's very insecure, right?
She's the type that
you could really abuse.
She's kind of a Karen in this situation
and I don't know what Kylie's emotional
status, but I know, I'm know for a fact.
Not as confident as we think she is. Yeah.
She's been a victim of a violent crime
pretty recently, a year ago or so,
or however. She's
traumatized, she's fragile.
There's a lot of things you can
get away with in a girl like that.
That's really good coaching.
Yeah.
And I think ultimately she knows like,
oh don't neglect the balls.
You know? Like do you think
Kim knows that because she's,
she's not gonna be like, Ooh, balls,
there's a gross. I'm like, no, no,
you got to pay attention here.
On the other hand,
Kylie's young and dating rappers
and those guys are like, bitch,
put it all in your mouth.
Right, right, right. Those
guys are just kind of savages.
I'm assuming she doesn't even know that
not swallowing is an option, you know,
cause she's,
is she dating Tyga was that was,
I think there's a big scandal right now.
Oh, I think he got photographed without,
with another girl. Oh, we'll see. I, I
don't know Taiga, but I've seen him. Yeah.
And I think he's, he looks
like a savage sexually. Really?
I had assumed it was covered in tattoos.
That's what does it for you.
And you think that means
savage? He's a rapper. Yeah.
Tattooed rappers, you know? Yeah. I know.
I don't think he's rapping about
rainbows and fucking lollipops,
but I don't think Kanye is like put my
balls in your mouth all the time. Yeah.
He seemed, he seemed a little more
oddly enough, more normal when it comes,
you know what I mean? Like I
would believe that. I mean,
I don't think he's a stable normal guy,
but I don't see him being like,
look bitch underneath I'm a
foreigner in your mouth. Right. Well,
cause he's done that before camp.
Right. That's your baby Mama.
You got to give her some respect. Right,
right. Put some respect on my name,
put some respect on it.
So there's a lot of variables
here dealing with, yeah.
I still think you've got to go with Kim.
I do old school. Yeah. I mean, you know,
it's a better story. Um, you know, I like,
I like a good story and uh,
I feel like it's legendary in there.
Who knows what could happen.
Maybe I could find one of those rings
she lost in Paris or something, you know?
So I would go for that.
I think that would be more fun.
She's got two babies that came
out of there. That's cool.
I like bitches with babies. Talent
that, yeah, I'm going to go Kylie. Yeah,
I think that's better for you. For me
personally, I think it's better for you.
She's kind of a dope.
She's 19.
I could really traumatize
her and you know,
she always wants to talk about it as
like selfies and her new cosmetics line.
What I feel like we screwed up
though. Why? I feel like the other,
the next most famous female genders
actually Kaitlin, well let's go there.
That's the next one. Well that's a lady.
Yeah, but they're not the way I frame it.
Okay, let's go for the guys.
Yeah. Old School. Bruce Jenner.
I'm talking in his prime cause I
didn't think you'd want to woman.
Like did you really want
to fuck her downstairs?
Thing is she still has a doll. I
think she still has a dog. So yeah,
that kind of rules it out for you.
I know it's old school,
Bruce Jenner and his prime.
I'm talking like eighties
athletic or Kanye.
Oof, man. It was really tough. A
lot of variables to deal with here.
Uh, versus some guy who's like, I
think I'm a woman inside, you know?
Yeah. That's the thing. It's just
weird shit happening with him. I mean,
look at this guy. That's it.
Those muscles. Look at that.
Use The fucking man. Dm. Brucey yeah.
Well that's a really tough
one. He's got a good,
here's the,
because
physically I don't really care.
I feel like it's the mental instability
and I think they're both have a good bit
of that instability. But maybe
it's just that, like with Bruce,
the only thing is like,
you know,
he wants to do this thing and he's kind
of trying to come to terms with it.
But you would know that
at the time, right? Yeah.
You wouldn't know that.
He might not know it,
but it's going to manifest in other
ways. You might be like, can I just,
do you mind if I wear a wig
and a panty hose and you're
like, okay, yeah, whatever.
Yeah,
but like with, with Kanye, you're
just dealing with this in bill,
unbelievably out of control.
Ego,
the porn out. He likes porno law and he's
acting out a lot though. And he's like,
he's so annoying. You know he's having
like near mental breakdowns and stuff.
See, because Katelyn's annoying as
fuck now. Right? She's annoying. Right.
But as Bruce, she probably stayed
in line, you know what I mean?
Like her ego is under, I don't
know what his ego was like when he,
this is a good question for you.
You should answer this first. Yeah.
So sexually,
you know that like he can do it.
I mean he fathered a bunch
of kids and you know,
and I'm looking for that fertility game,
but then Connie is not going to treat you,
treat you like baby Mama.
He's going to treat you like, like a
little piece of trash on the ground. Yeah.
I don't like that. I don't like Connie's,
I'm, I'm just putting this on him.
He might be brutal. He might
be disrespectful. Yeah,
that'd be fun for you, Bruce.
I feel like he'd have the unconscious,
the lady as he is coming right now.
Uh, and he's smiling like that.
Hmm.
You know,
come face. Oh, there we are in
Amy. Yeah. Look how cute he was.
See, there he goes. Uh, yeah.
That's more of a calm face.
Look at them. Short shorts. No,
I like him. You know, athletes,
you can't go wrong physically. He probably
looks great. Naked. A, he's got this,
the anima. Yeah. Stand
them up now. Lazy Lover.
He's going to have a lot of weird stuff
going on and it's more interesting.
I think ultimately Kanye would
be very toxic to be around.
It's so annoying. Such a fan
of him as a producer. Right.
But I think that would be the thing.
I'd be like,
I'll just deal with it and then
it would give me, you know,
first listens to these things would not,
you're just a Pete,
you're just a slam piece baby.
You're talking relationship.
I'm talking about filling up
grilled cheese. He's like,
yeah, come check this out.
And then I'd play a song from maybe that
I'll ask such a good song is a baby.
He's filling you up and sealing Yusha.
He's not letting you listen
to his music's like his raps
coming over. Oh, uh, uh, Ross is here
and 21 stab at what's the other fellows?
And he'd be like, go make them a sandwich
to donate a little bitch. I'll be like,
all right,
I'll make you sandwiches.
Well I guess we agree to
disagree. Yeah, I think we chose,
we chose who was right for each of us
on that one. Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
Um, look, we got to wrap this up, gene.
Okay, hold on. Can I do another one?
Another one.
Kaitlin or the mom.
What's her name? Chris.
Right. Chris Jenner.
Christ Christian or Caitlin or about
the same age. Let's walk through it.
Wow. CAITLIN's in new lady. She's probably
going to want to definitely Chris.
Chris, man. Well, okay, let's
say Katelyn has a vision and new,
freshly made vision.
Yeah, I dunno. I don't have any
problem with it, but I just feel like,
yeah, you do. You'd have to
have a problem. You wouldn't
have a problem with it.
No sound don't a problem with doctor
made machine probably feels funny,
you know? It feels weird,
right? I guess. I don't know.
I mean I've only had real Virgenes
but what if, I don't know.
I don't know if this is Dick turned
inside out though. That's what I'm saying.
And so as a straight guy, wouldn't
you still, you'd be like, oh,
this is like a dick. Like it's still a
deck, right? It's still a dick. Yeah.
I'd be like, you have your dead
Dick, but where are your dad's balls?
You'd still have that in your head that
you were still having sex with another
dude's Dell. Yeah, of course he would.
It'd be tough to get through it out.
It's still a dick. Yeah, I think
Chris would be, um, I don't know.
Something about her that would be fun.
She seems like a fun,
Fun Lady. She's a fun time.
Savvy, smart business oriented.
I mean, look, she built this family,
she did career. It's pretty miraculous.
High maintenance as shit,
but I mean, I don't know.
Now let's go through this because she's
just been dumped by a husband of how
many years converting to being a woman.
She's damaged goods too.
Yeah, she's had her spirit broken. You're
like just putting your mouth. Yeah. Yeah.
I think I would definitely rather
fill that up though. Yeah, the, yeah,
the mom Kaitlin's going to be
annoying. Oh my God. Hi. Maintenance.
She's more high main is to me,
I think then the other lady,
and we don't even know actually
that Caitlin likes men.
I don't know is a big thing about that.
Oh, is that right? Yeah. It was like, no,
I like,
I mean at the time it was like that
he that she likes women that just
transitioning. Oh, feels like a
whim. A woman but likes women. Oh,
I didn't know that. So she's, well,
I mean this was what I first heard
long ago,
so lots of process call me Caitlyn.
It's so complicated. I can only imagine
how horrible it must be to go through.
It's a lot. God, poor woman. All
right. All right. Well, there you go.
There you go.
Uh,
please go to a lot of hard hitting quite,
I mean, this one really broke me down.
It's picking your nose. Make your
nostrils big on retarded people drive.
Would you rather fuck
Caitlyn or Kris Jenner?
These are the questions
that we answer on your
mom's house.
On the podcast.
They'll try 99 a please shop through
the Amazon banner. He'll Trump 90.
Sorry. No, Trump gave him a bad
shout out. Yeah, you did. And uh,
Trump stupid. Oh, this is huge.
I can't believe I forgot this all the way
until the end. Oh, today. Uh, this week,
the 28th, the 28th of this
month, mostly stories.
My album based on the last
Netflix special comes out,
the audio release comes out.
Here's the thing,
it has two bonus tracks,
two pieces of audio,
two tracks that I just recorded,
um,
last month that I told them.
Uh,
instead of keeping these for
myself for the next special,
put them on this album.
So if you get the new album,
it'll be on iTunes. Of course, Amazon,
wherever you can buy and stream music,
it'll be there. Two bonus tracks.
I would love for you to get it.
If you're interested in hard copies.
I ordered a limited edition, um,
about a hard copies.
There'll be autographed and signed next
week and if you're a vinyl collector,
the vinyl comes out in June.
So there will also be a limited
amount of limited run of vinyl,
which I'm going to do a signed,
uh, version of those with a poster,
but that's in June.
But the album you can download,
you can buy a hard copy in the
next week or two. All right?
That's it gene or anything?
It, I love you. I love you.
Bye guys.
A lot of people,
a lot of people.
I don't know what genes.
Please explain
at our,
at our store
we are
at our,
at our
denim
is Jesus.
Denim jeans is a term of affection.
Jeans is like bay genes,
our genes,
but they're also,
the genes are a way of life.
That's what we're doing with this
show is about at our, at our,
at our,
at our
denim
denim,
you want jeans,
tight,
loose budget.
That's what we do with this show is about.