Do you need to wipe down
what's with the jeans?
I like this jam.
We got it from a listener.
Listener may know that
they all are. Most of
them. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
I like when the listener sent you too.
It's a cool show.
Is 100% mommy power is from Jacob.
Thanks Jacob.
Oh, listen to need. I like it.
Thank you everybody that came
out to a large, big cities.
Oh, that's a good one. That
one sent that in. I was like,
how do we never cover that large,
big titties? Utah, Salt Lake City,
Charlotte. Pities good. Charlotte
titties. Yeah. Shortly again.
Five sold out shows. Wow. Credible.
That's so awesome. Are they all Mormons?
All it was, everything was
like a, there's like a service.
It was like I was conducting mass.
She read from the Bible. Yeah. Uh, no.
They were so good. Thank
you guys so much. I really,
really had an excellent time with you
and thanks for Doug Mellard for coming
with me. Andy Gold opening
the shows. Really fun time.
Next I'll be in Phoenix Park.
Nick's Arizona downtown far next Arizona
at stand up live February 26th and 27th
then a March 10th through 12.
And Tacoma,
Washington. What would you call that to
come on you to come on Ya comedy club.
That was so good. That was so good. And
I didn't even get mad. Yeah. To come on.
You're watching him on.
Uh, that should be a blast.
All over your mom's face.
And then, uh, March 17 through 19, uh,
uh, ball Sacramento, California, the
punchline and the inner sack, you know,
they call it the right sack and then sure.
Uh,
Hilarides uh,
in Cleveland's land,
Ohio March 31st through April 2nd.
Okay.
Cleavage and Leanne, so
that's a, that's the full,
it's the full run for a while there.
Uh, and I am coming to Spokane tram.
Can sperm cans,
spine,
Washington also in action in late
April. What do you got? Jeans,
April one and two, I met flappers
comedy club and and Sperm Bank. Wait,
are you really going or not?
Cause this is April.
What?
Enrolling into for rails guys,
flip pairs.
Comedy Club in Sperm Bank one night
only. April 20th. Hey Man, for 20.
Hey, that's Hitler's
birthday. Did you know that?
You know what?
I'm going to make this Hitler's birthday
show at the venter comedy club. A PM.
I mean, only for people
who know what's up. It's,
it's going to be your mom's house.
Hitler's birthday. How about that?
And then this is where in the future,
May 27th and 28th I'm at the
comedy store in La Jolla,
California, la Jolla and also
listener. That's deep bro. Um,
this week, all I fucking
interview, I can't remember
my, my head is space of, Oh,
I talk about bitches be lying about
motherhood and parenthood. Yeah.
Shit we don't talk about because
we're afraid of being bad people.
Nice guys.
Also shop using our Amazon banner.
If you're shopping on Amazon, I beg
you, use your mom's house, podcast.com.
Go there,
click on the home page as a banner and
just do your shopping as you normally
would. That's all you have
to do to support our show.
Thank you. Goodbye. Thank you,
James.
You got it. Thank you to your genes
and thank your mother's genes.
Um, all right. Uh, guess what?
I just remembered. What's that?
I haven't taken his shit today. Oh,
it's really exciting. Let's, uh,
let's open the show. We can talk all about
it. You Ready? Ready to start the show?
Yeah, it was every show I'm at has
taken, I dunno man. Yeah. All right,
here we go. Yeah. Showtime.
Which ones did you
the long way she'll costs and Murray
first and she calls him a apart.
I mean he calls her a client.
I just have to be careful
with our language or above it.
That's all right sweetheart.
Okay.
Don't bring in one loving to this.
Well,
go to your mom's house.
Christina.
Dula Dude,
Jay,
come on.
I didn't even tell you, but when I went
to the bank the other day, this guy goes,
is that Keynes story real at the
bank? At the bank. You're Super Fan.
You have a fan there who works at the, at
the branch we go to. Yeah. And he's like,
is that cane story real? And I
was like, it sure is. I mean,
have a tee shirt for it.
Somebody.
Oh shit baskets. How can we get that
to stop happening? Someone wrote in,
did they tell us how, because apparently
it happens on Joe show too. Oh really?
They're like, yeah, it's a, so
I'm just gonna turn this off.
Turn your telephone off to Tal Afar.
It's time for this.
Uh,
yeah, the cane, the cane get the
cane shirts is what I'm saying.
Cause it's very popular wearing
my sub came shirt today.
It is definitely too big.
The one that I have,
it's like it's hanging
down past my elbows. Um,
so you know,
order the right size.
I actually ordered the right size
and they sent me the wrong size.
Me The guy that
and um,
yeah,
so I have the wrong sized shirt but um,
and then some people have been
messaging me that the orders are shirt.
Where is it?
Well if you'll look,
the sub came shirt is a presale meaning
that it's going to ship later and it
says that on the order page,
but they are going to ship next week.
So we brought it back because we,
first time we did it we sold
out of everything super fast.
We brought it back and it's on sale
now and they will ship next week. Um,
it's a great Valentine's
gift for Valentine's Day.
That's this weekend.
I mean,
what better way to tell
someone you love them by then?
By going like that, you know, I love it.
You did that and it's like payback for
our stupid neighbor who yells, oh my God.
All the time. So loud. She's the
worse I should tell him that.
That the cane story is true.
When I see that guy. Yes.
Cause he asked me and I was like, I
was delirious. I'm like, wait, what?
Sunset Boulevard at the comedy
store is where it happened to.
Yeah. And I did limousine
and then he turned away.
Let's amazed. But then you've
also perfected your black yelling.
I'm working on it a lot, but
the very first time we did
it was like near Fairfax,
wasn't it? Oh, I did it with you and,
and you're like, what's that mean?
And the guy yelled back. Yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. That was fucking amazing.
I remember I was just the beginning of
all of this. That was the beginning. Yeah.
Like go check this out years ago and
I yelled at the guy and he was like,
y'all back and then you almost had
an aneurysm laughing. So great. Yeah,
we started doing that and that was the
same year we started like when we pull
into a stoplight and there was somebody,
a pedestrian standing there and you fart
in the car member and I was and I would
yell at my husband farmed it and then
they'd be like, what? That's a fun game.
One time I was called up to a guy with
you in the car. I pulled up to a couple,
which is kind of scary.
It was at night and I hit the brakes when
they were walking down the street and
I go, I farted and then I hit the gas and
they were totally, that was fun to do.
My favorite moment with you ever in my
life and the last 1547 years we've been
together.
Remember that time we were eating brunch
and you ask the bus boy in Spanish you
go, he just said, I have to shit,
where's the bathroom? Yes. It say it.
Say it in Mexican. I said,
a mic, go look at it.
Can just point it.
He didn't even blink.
Of course not because I was normal to him.
Says I got to shit.
Where's the battery? Mikaila.
I didn't even blank dude.
Like that guy was awesome.
I actually,
the time that we first yelled
my black Ya'll on Fairfax,
I actually was recording
the guy that responded back.
So I yelled and then he
went, yeah, that's from,
that's from Fairfax. I didn't remember
him. The phrase. Yeah, that was good.
Yeah. That was the funny, yeah, that
was seriously, that was so funny.
We were just in the car, right. And we
were rolling up on it and you're like,
it was,
why is years old
by the way? Um, why are you
wearing my shirt right now? Ah,
what you're wearing my sweatshirt.
I don't know.
It fits me perfectly like a glove. I think
it looks better on me. Let me tell you,
I wore that on the flight to Salt Lake
City and the flight back from Salt Lake
City. Let's get a look at what I'm
wearing. It is a real talking point. Um,
so I just want you to see what you
look like when you were that good.
Look at what you've been wearing.
That's why I put it on today so you
can feel the experience that I've been
having.
You know,
I just feel there's so many different
things that happened with that sweatshirt
on. First of all worse. Uh,
so Doug Mellard and I went to Salt
Lake City and he was like, wow.
And then I told him how you said your,
your take was that I looked like a,
the retarded guy that goes to the
library every day and everyone's like,
Hey Kevin, are you teach special ed?
So when I was on the plane, um, first
of all, people would board and I could,
I would see them go like,
yeah, of course. Crazy.
You know,
one of the flight attendants came over
and talked to me like I was super special
and I realized that I almost
sounded special back because
I was actually putting
together, I, I've almost confused
why I got it. You know what I mean?
So I was trying to tell her, she
goes, uh, she was, she was working,
walking through the cart, the aisle
with the cart, and she goes, so, um,
I, those jelly fish on your
sweatshirt. And I go, yeah.
She goes,
I've never seen that before.
Where'd you get that? And I go,
I had it made. And she goes, Oh,
well why'd you do that? Yeah.
And then I was confused.
I didn't realize, I didn't
remember that. It's actually,
it was made first and then I go,
oh, I want to get it in my mind.
I was thinking of like my,
my first special where I have
a joke where I said I can't,
he came through with jellyfish last week.
It was the first 48 bit.
So I didn't want to explain that
I do comedy. So I just said,
I talk about it. So then I
got one and I was like, oh no,
I actually sound retarded
because I'm going,
I talk about it and then I wanted it
and she goes, that's a really nice,
and she talked to me like I was really,
really special. Yeah. And then she goes,
I go, I have another one with a
raven on it. And then I pulled it up.
I'm like, cause I like my phone was
out and she goes, I'm listening.
She was observing other people drinks
and then I was like paging through my
camera roll.
I was like,
this one is me raven on my sweatshirt.
You show. Did you show
her the other one too? No,
I didn't show her the Hannibal
one. Yeah, I showed her the raven.
Can't tell you why I like you wearing the
jellyfish and the rape. Yeah, go ahead.
Because I know you're not cheating on
me cause there's no woman in the world.
It's going to lay you wearing the
jellyfish. Why? Why do you say that?
That's so embarrassing.
So you see that you don't see it.
You don't have any sexual
feelings when you see negative.
Yeah. So bad. Really bad.
This is craziness. It's not
crazy. It looks really crazy.
Wait, you don't think any woman would
be like, Whoa, what's up with him?
I think a normal woman would be like
retarded stewardess had that reaction.
Here's how she talked to me.
I actually thought this later,
like as the flight was progressing,
it felt like somebody went,
I dare you to ask the guy that
retarded guy about his course.
And then of course,
and then she won like 20 bucks for
talking to me. She was like, oh my God.
He just said he talks about them.
She felt good about herself that day.
Like you know when like
confident, right. She was like, I,
I did a good deed by talking to that.
Real Nice for target boy
that's the economy. Yeah.
See she's like,
I'm a good person.
I talked to Ricardo people
like they're one of us.
It would have been so she was doing,
man,
I wish I was in first because then they
would have been like, I just the target.
Wow.
He has make a wish,
but they would have just thought that
you were like an eccentric millionaire.
If you're in first class, now you're just
the eccentric guy with the jellyfish.
Somebody posted when I, cause I posted
a picture of me in that sweatshirt.
They said, this is how I
imagine like the, the seat,
the guy that the startup CEO who runs
some tech company dresses like some guy
with money. He was like, fuck it. When
a jellyfish, I'm worried. Joy for sure.
And I laughed so hard because I could,
I could see that the guy,
the guy who was like, I have $1
billion, I'm going to wear a jellyfish.
They're retarded or fucking money,
right. Of which I'm neither,
I'm not retarded and I don't have
fuck you and fuck getting pussy.
Yeah. So I'm super stoked
about that. Is this a of yours?
What? Are you worried about that?
No, not really. No, not really. No.
Oh my God. I said, fuck you man. Fuck you.
By the way,
can I just point out that you were hacking
coughing last week and you cough like
a old black guy?
No,
I don't use awfully good
old homeless black man.
So gross. Yeah. That's
who you cough. Like,
okay. No, no. You Go, you go, Huh?
What is black about that?
So gross. Nothing is black.
That's all black dudes cough.
And you were going to a
black guy in the bus cough.
Oh Man. So I closed it. And that's a
black guy. Yeah. Well I'm not a man.
So my what do it do your
coffee now do it for real.
That let the audience hear how
regular I cough. No cough. Like you go
do it now.
That's not how you kept at home.
I don't know how to mimic how
I caught for real cough. No,
that's not what you were doing.
You're so gross.
Cause you do it in a two step process.
Like you bring up the phlegm
and then you work it out. Okay.
I don't know how you go and you're right.
You hear that you're like,
oh this black guy right there. Yeah, I'm
living, it's like living with Redd Fox.
We're living in the junk yard and Lamont,
c'mon, c'mon at Margate. Yeah.
There you go. Cough like that. That's
exactly what you sound like when you call.
You're ridiculous. You're
ridiculous. Yeah. Red Fox.
Yeah though is do you like the Ma?
It's sad circumstances,
but that,
that 11 year old girl sang country twice
on like the today show or good black
America, it's the bad. Then don't
ask her to say what, don't ask,
don't ask her to repeat it. I
love the power. She goes, Oh yeah,
we just got to be careful.
It's okay, Sweetie.
Which ones did you say?
Well, it's actually a horrible
story, right? It's about,
obviously it's another funny, funny
premise for a cloud. It's like, thanks.
Some bullying went on and
something horrible happened.
I don't know if someone kill themselves
or kill somebody else and they're asking
her like, what? Well, you know what
she saw? So she started saying, well,
I saw these tech.
Which text messages did you see?
She'll costs Mra best
and she calls him a pipe.
I mean, he calls her client. Okay. Okay.
Careful with our language or above it.
That's all right sweetheart.
Okay,
well that's okay then. Don't ask her
to, I can't say so. I can't say cut.
I was talking to said, oh, I
can't say, can't you dumb bitch.
Uh, um, um, um,
oh God never said that word. Oh
my God. Oh my God. What was it?
Literally like it. Good morning show.
Yeah, it was a morning show. Yeah.
One of them aware. Um, give him morning.
Who can watch those fucking dumb shows
anyways, but what the fuck is watching?
Good morning. Anything. Have you tried
watching those piece of shit morning show.
We do them for a living. Well,
they're just so here's a,
every everyone's emotions are side
phony on it. Yes. The phoniness.
Yeah.
You know that they're this painful.
I show up usually in a bad mood at those
things of course. And when they're like,
I thought went really funny.
It's going to be in town.
The same stupid energy.
Now let's switch gears. A very funny man
is in town is going to be at the mall,
at the club in the mall.
Uh,
it's always a football club that has the
relationship there. And then they go,
Tom, how's it going? And
then they wouldn't get it.
Or you can do your thing when
once we go to, uh, my thing,
what do you think I'm going to do? And
they're like, just turn it on. Yeah.
Watch any morning show
clip I'm on. Hi. Well,
my favorite is they're always
surprised that you're tired.
Yeah. You're like, Whoa,
what's up? Sleepy head. And you're like,
well first of all it's six, seven, eight,
but it's three in the morning, my time.
Right. You asshole. Yeah, you're not.
You're the one that's weird right now.
Why do they do that?
Why do they make the
morning shows extra upbeat?
Like don't you prefer to listen to
someone that's at your speed? Like what?
They should have more like us. Like,
hey guys, it's sucks. I'm awake.
Fucking hate it. I bet you hate it.
Being awake right now to uh, anyways,
here's the news like,
yeah, and they should be like, you know
what's better? Uh, today's already. Yes.
Bad Day. Yeah. I'm sure life
sucks. You're watching the show.
You're probably depressed.
I just want to tell you is a validating
your depression sucks out there. Exactly.
Let's go to the weather.
Don't bother getting out of bed today.
And then the guys like snowing.
Why this sucks too.
And they cut back what happened in sports.
Our teams loss.
All right.
That's a good morning show.
I could get into,
oh my goodness.
It's crazy.
Um, yesterday was the pooper bowl. Um,
crazy.
I gotta tell you, I know you don't
listen or care about football.
I'll just say this, uh, with
regard to football stuff. Yeah.
Oh, um, yeah. I was surprised
at what happened. Uh,
I tried to pick it just as a,
a fan of the game and uh,
try to be objective. Totally thought
it was going to go the other way.
Um, so I know you don't understand
what I'm saying and I'll,
I'll jump out of this,
but I just wanted to say congratulations
to the people of Denver. Um, and uh,
and really what an unbelievable
showing because there was incredible.
I think I just caught the very beginning
of it and I didn't realize that,
um,
it's so patriotic.
I had no idea that America goes the fuck
off. They go off. I mean, we had the,
we had lady Gaga singing the anthem.
She was crying, there was a tear going.
I swear to God. Really? The camera got
closer. There was a tear down her eyes.
And then the blue angels go
overhead and then they can't,
they cut to Afghanistan or there soldiers
standing in Afghanistan and the minute
Afghanistan soldiers are on screen and
everybody's cheer. I missed all that.
I was out.
Did they have the flag on the field?
Sometimes the horse a hundred foot flat.
I didn't, I've never watched the opening.
Yeah, it sounds like it's team America.
Oh Wow. Yeah. I was like, is this a joke?
Yeah. Or the puppet's going to come out
from fucking team. Yeah. Really crazy man.
Trey Parker. Gonna and that's done.
It's pretty crazy. It was a law.
I had no clue. America hinged
on the Super Bowl as much. Yeah.
It's our biggest commercial
product I think is wow. Yeah.
Oh Jeez.
Isn't that
John and I were up polo jeans.
Oh,
this time.
Isn't that crazy.
Um,
so we're all following the people that
organize the Superbowl thought what
better way to get things
started then bringing in seal.
You want me bringing up seal the other
day you did. It was kind of weird.
It's like he had a premonition. I mean,
we were in the, in the kitchen and I go,
yeah, we think seals up to, I know I
just started saying like, do you mean,
can you imagine?
Like I go,
I think you'd probably just still it
still towards Europe and like Eastern
Europe. Let's be clear. Not
Western central. First of all.
I mean he had like a few
really huge songs. Well, okay,
so he has the crazy song. Yeah.
Well what's his other from a rose.
Alright.
My,
my roses kissing new jeans.
That's the one right there. Kissing
jeans though with the road song. Um,
so it's so weird.
We're sitting and talking about them and
I was remembering that he was married
to Heidi Clunes hide the, um, high tech.
What do you think her asshole tastes like?
Oh Man.
There's without a doubt you
get in that ass and it's 100%.
It's a German asshole. So, uh,
so we're talking about, and actually
I was telling you that like, you know,
it's one of those things, hey, it's,
this is a tough entertainment
is a tough business, you know,
and the man can fucking sing like those
songs are, or were hits for a reason,
right? Like, yeah. So you'll have some,
he can build out some notes. Yeah.
So we were just talking about,
I go, I wonder what, you
know what, even if he does,
he just stole a tour Eastern Europe.
I'm sure actually any,
I'm sure western Europe too, that he,
if he goes, I am coming to Barcelona.
That shit sold out immediately.
Yeah. Barcelona. Yeah, for
sure. Paris. Sure. Yeah.
Rome. Yeah. Yeah. I think
it's still, I think he's still
is a draw. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Okay. So um, Iceland huge, big,
big in Iceland. Right. But anyways,
we're sitting there and then the
pregames on it, you know, you put the,
when it was on CBS, I forget what was done
and you go, I'm just going to, you know,
let it run up to the game and I turn
to the TV during the pregame show and
there's seal and I'm like,
and then there's the huge
audience outside. I'm like,
what a bizarre, just selection. Yeah.
Cause he kind of has it been in the
public at least I haven't heard from him
since the crazy song came out. What
was that in 1992? It's been awhile.
It's been a minute. Yeah. Um, and
it's just also weird. I Dunno,
you think of football,
it's such a huge commercial product.
I always think that the more appropriate
acts are basically whatever's the most
popular, you know, like
it makes sense and tits.
It makes sense that Beyonce
and her big tits are out. Yeah.
It makes sense that lady Gaga, good,
good guy. Is there, um, I don't know.
Whoever is they booked, like Kendrick
Lamar, if they book, you know, they,
if they had Drake, anybody who's
like really relevant in them.
Absolutely. In the moment.
Um, I mean even band wise,
like they had cold play this year.
It's great because I thought that was odd.
Aren't they like a Downer band like
Radiohead, but more ma, you know,
like they're more mainstream for sure.
So it's like a white bummers they're kind
of wipe bummers but I mean it's still,
I guess it makes sense, but I dunno,
it just, it's always interesting,
like you're always like, what, why did
they select these people to do so anyways,
but seal was just more than bizarre,
but was more bizarre than the choice was
the first half of him singing because I
dunno what the fuck was going on. I
don't know if he was just like, oh, what,
I'm doing one today? And
they go, no, you're singing
at the super bowl. Yeah. Um,
well, cause we were sitting on the couch
and looking at each other like, wait,
is this really fucking happening?
Is He,
does this sound bad to you too?
Yep.
The brothers were like in my
arm for my cause. I Dunno,
it's just audio cause this fantastic.
But I think it does in the beginning.
So it was like the first 30
seconds minute, he was just like,
isn't that crazy? And then all of a sudden
I was like, this is really horrific.
And then he decided to sing. It was
like at one moment he goes, all right,
I'll sing now. But even the singing
was off. It was a little, it was off,
but the first part.
But see I didn't get it
the very first. Sorry, this
is it. This is all the gowns.
No,
the first part at all. No, but it's
a little bit of it. You can hear it.
Okay.
Exactly. Singing now he's seen. Yeah,
now he's singing. Yeah. Yeah. You don't
get, you didn't get the other thing.
I couldn't find the,
sorry.
Well he was finally warming up.
You ramped up to that
shit. Sorry. Genes positive. We
pause it. Try to find it. Hold on.
All right, well we added,
okay. Um, anyway, I
interviewed him afterwards.
[inaudible]
it's so different to only in as much as
like you have the people that come are
necessarily there to see you. They're
not necessarily your fans, you know,
because they had to see a group of
entertain a little steam and CNN.
So, um, yeah, I guess that's
different. But you know, I,
I've always lived by that
philosophy, um, for not always,
but at least for the last 20 years
I've lived by the philosophy of like,
there are no bad oars audiences,
only mediocre performances.
Well that was a pretty
mediocre one yesterday, man.
Not true that the audience
was very mediocre for him too.
They pan to the crowd on there.
They were horrible living around,
but he was at dog shows.
Terrible. Yeah. For the first,
I wish I had the audio. Yeah.
Basically if you a, if you saw it,
you know, but if you didn't, we'll,
we'll try to find that over the next week
maybe. But he basically, for the first,
for the first minute of her son
goes, isn't that crazy? It's crazy.
And then I really felt like somebody goes,
you need to sing. And then he's saying,
yeah, but it was a minute
of, I'm not singing the song.
I feel like they've always said
crazy too much in that song.
But that really bothered me in a world
full of only some know how to fly.
Isn't that crazy? It's crazy.
Never going to on this.
We are a little crazy. Like all
right. Pick a different word is yeah,
there's a lot of other words. Yeah. Yeah.
There's a lot that's is a lot that,
that uh, that song was huge man. I know.
Super annoying after a while.
They do that everywhere. Yeah.
That was one of those songs.
That's a song where this guy couldn't
can tour what I'm saying for the rest of
his life, you know? Yeah. It's like,
it's never going to give by boy les.
Cause your dad would like the song.
My Dad loves this car.
My Dad was to the dad.
Is this a dad's on total debt?
Why is it a dad that's feel cool for
liking it? Right. Cause it's not a cool,
but it's kind of cool. This
part, this part, yeah. This
is like at Dad. Dj made. Yeah.
Alright. I've got my
white sneakers on. Right.
And uh, feels like approachable. Cool.
Yeah. You know, not, not like so cool.
Yeah. You feel like you could
be like, hey seal. Yeah.
I didn't realize he used to have hair.
He did. Yeah. I didn't know that.
It's a good song. Now. It
doesn't look approachable.
Cool. And this never mind. No,
no, it's way too. But I
mean, he's got like leather,
best time the chain.
Yeah. This is such a dad, you know,
my dad used to do is get songs he
likes like this,
but get the single and let it just play.
Repeat in was car man. That's annoying.
Over and over and over and over.
And he like, I like it. And then it's
all you would hear in the car with him.
And this is on of his jams. Oh yeah. Yeah.
I wish we can make an album of top dog
jams. Oh, I could, I could cry now.
I'm trying to think right now of the, of
one that I'm thinking of. It's another,
it's a dad song like this that was,
you know,
rhythmic like this.
I can't remember the name of it.
That was in his car for maybe like
a year and a half or two years.
And he had Beyonce as
great as I remember that.
That took me by surprise that he liked
Beyonce that much. I didn't know clue.
Well, the only thing
for the first, you know,
15 years of my life only had mo town.
So that's really good taste.
It's really good taste. Yes.
I think what happened is he tried to,
he tried to find what's modern
Motown and modern Motown is like,
you know, well yeah, it's R and B, you
know, so he just, but he has to find,
he had to find songs that probably
were at kind of simple chorus,
simple beats that, you know, like
the melody was catchy to him.
The more complicated songs, I think he
goes like, Oh, dad's don't like that.
You know, my dad got into in
the 90s she was really shocking.
Do you remember the band prodigy?
I'm not Firestar top.
My Dad loved that song and he would just
crank it in the house and my step mom
will be like,
like just hated it.
And he would just get ripped and
jam out to prodigy. He's like,
this is a good song. You know this
bum prodigy. Yeah, that's dad.
Everybody knows them. Your Dad jams out
to classic rock to he loves the stones.
The Beatles.
My Dad would not be grilling.
Not even a little bit.
That's like everybody likes to
stone is going to be not top dog.
And I mean not only doesn't like would
be adamant about how much she doesn't
like one of those things regionally.
Fuck what you like. Wow. Yeah.
Well those are counterculture.
And he was,
it was not counterculture and yeah,
he went to Vietnam voluntarily.
Yes.
Get that all the time. No, no.
My Dad hates the Beatles hates
Elvis. That's, that's crazy.
Probably hates every band that
performed at Woodstock. Um,
without places like fun or free love.
No,
it does not do drugs and sex.
Like everybody. Like you like sex.
I think he like sex drugs. No,
no, no, no. The sex and drugs.
And rock and roll for top dog. And
I know it's just sex and Mcdonald's.
Yeah, yeah, yes. Sex and
Mcdonald's. Coffee, coffee,
the best coffee in the world.
The best coffee in the world.
Got
Mcdonald's. I'm, I'm, it's,
it's pretty nuts. Never ordered
their coffee meeting once in my life.
Like in an airport.
It's pretty crazy.
So we may just know last week,
you know the movement is
growing and
don't say that phrase like that.
So alarming.
How much does this, this
is like when you know you,
you get what you asked for.
We were just like playing this drop,
but then people were like, all right,
we'll send you our thousand emails.
Yeah, I know. And then people
were, oh, this is good.
Best I did Conan last week.
We haven't been talking about that.
So
the team, Coco Youtube page puts
your appearance. It all says,
Hey Hitler. Like a thousand times it says,
Hey Hitler. And then people are going,
why do they reference Hitler with, what
is it about him and Hitler and his jeans?
Like it makes so little sense to
and outside or that they're like,
what's wrong with his jeans
and why is he liking to Hitler?
That's my favorite part of our show
is how exclusionary it is. Oh yeah,
no, it is the best why we're saying, Hey
Hitler or the jeans. Like I love that.
It makes no sense to people outside
of the moms circle, but that's,
that's why I shows off. You have
to be, you have to fucking know.
You gotta know man. You got
to know software. Everybody,
I should say this. Um, I want to thank uh,
team Coco.
They were really cool to me.
And also our son was on the
show or was on the show.
Our son made his TV debut was seven
weeks old. Isn't that crazy? Um,
so here's what happened.
I,
uh, have a video of log up.
If you go to my youtube page,
which is Tom [inaudible] and I
hope you subscribe to it. Um, we,
uh, we, we videoed the
whole backstage, um,
experience of going on,
of going on Conan and um,
you can check that out on my youtube page.
We also have your mom's house has
a youtube page that is now active.
So if you go on youtube and I'll pull
it up just to make sure I give you the
right URL.
Can't believe it's finally happening.
I know after how many
years of doing this show.
Well, you know, sometimes it just
takes a while to get things together.
So capsule of your coffee
mommy. Yeah, of course. Um,
I want to do this, your mom's
house. Let me give you this.
So once you go to youtube.com/your
mom's house podcast,
we have added in the last week alone.
Um,
it looks like one, two,
three, four, five, six, seven,
eight videos and this episode right now,
which is episode three 30 should,
if everything works out right be
up in its entirety on the page.
So you'll get to see
full episode,
uh, with video. Um, so please,
please subscribe to the
cage. Prescribe to it. Yeah.
And that way you can see the
prescriptions that we've put up, um,
first versus Gerber Gerber.
Yeah.
So we're making video of focus and we're
hoping that you'll enjoy that with your
dirty little jeans. Um, so wait,
Conan was a, was a lot of fun.
I was on with Josh
Brolin before I went on.
We were talking and you said
you think you'll talk to him?
I didn't get to talk to him.
We had dressing rooms next to each other,
but he had a team with him. He had like,
he had, you know, publicist and, and,
you know, assistance. And it was a lot of
people. It was, a lot of people are fancy.
And, um, he also didn't hang out from
my peer. He got up off the couch.
He's like, I got to go. He's like,
who? And then he got above, above.
I follow him on Instagram. I didn't
realize that before you daily hone in.
I forget. I, I must've been watching it.
It's normal. He's super normal. Really?
Yeah. It's like, here's me and my
kid. Here's me, Josh Brolin. Wow.
He seems pretty normal, dude. Wow.
I did not. I did not expect that.
You should say to him, Hey
Hitler, let's be friends.
Hey Hitler.
Um,
so here's what's something I want
to bring up about the Hay Hitler,
and that is that some people in a FedEx
sort of way are saying that they're
hearing something else. They're
like, they're saying, oh,
I don't think she's saying, Hey Hitler. I
think she's saying, hey ha hiller or hey,
no, and you know, it's
clearly Hitler to me.
Blogging Cure.
What I'm saying is that if that's
what you're hearing there and you're,
you're not hearing it. I asked, you
know what? What do you here, here,
this is another video of hers that
she put out. What are you here? Here.
Okay.
What?
I don't know. I, I could be
happy birthday to you. Nicholas.
Does it sound like Nicholas
to me? No, I hear Nicholas.
Huh?
Okay.
Nicholas? No, it sounds like
she saying and then lips.
Big words.
Yeah. Nick Nicholas. Nicholas.
Oh, it just sounds, it sounds
egg. A really like a
big word. What is going
on with this girl? A lot. There's
demons. Bells, there's demons.
There's a wizard, dork. Sighted people.
Okay. All right. I'm like,
when people sing like that,
I don't know, man. It sounds very
bizarre. Um, but she has a weird way of,
of communicating. Let's
say that. Let's say that.
Um,
yeah.
Why don't you let us know what you
hear because I hear Nicholas. Okay.
Well you hear that. I hear something else.
What do you hear? I hear big words like
lips,
big word.
I hear a big word.
Okay.
When is it big words.
No,
I want someone to make a remix of you
saying it now. Songs and the, Oh, really?
It's about, it's your turn. No,
no.
Colin is
Nick Nicholas.
Okay.
Yeah, it's, it's really,
it's really bizarre.
I mean,
so now we have two controversies for
what she was saying because there are
people who swear she was saying
Hiller Hillary. It's Hitler.
Yeah. She's, she's talking at all
pillar. She got blesses a Nigga. Casey,
this is what I'm talking. Why can't
you finally get some heat on that?
Okay, thank you. Yeah. Yeah.
I think she is, but she is asking
adults, Hitler for help. She is,
that guy in Nathaniel's jerk
helped me. Hitler blessing. Yeah.
God is real and God blesses a Nigga.
That was when you could not believe
what I'm half ounce was saying.
That's his name. It was really dumb. That
is crazy talk. It was crazy Todd. Yeah,
no god.
God is real.
God bless him.
God would never call you a nigger.
I'm repeating. It's you like
the news caster. You're like,
what did the text message say?
I'm telling you what the text
message and then you're like,
don't say God blesses a Nigga.
You asked me what the text
message and I'm sure you are.
No,
that's
wrong with this girl.
That's a really loaded question cause
it would take a long time. The answer.
You know what for once I'm
not interested in the story,
like I don't want to kind of don't want
to know what's up Shane Lee's story.
I feel like that's just let it go.
Her eyes.
There's a lot going on. Is it the 30
yard stare? Is that like, yeah, yeah,
yeah. Something, something's wrong. So
Nick, you're never going
to say it all right. Yeah.
Oh Man.
Christina put genes,
but genes keep a James King,
the Queen,
the queen of all
stupid.
So stupid. Yup. Hey, um, can
we give a jeep key update?
Who's got the keys to the jeep?
Uh,
man, I was, I was actually
in a full panic about this
lease is coming up and I go,
man,
we got to turn this key
and I don't want to no man,
you go, if you'll have one set of keys
date, they hit you up for like 600 bucks
for a set of keys. They can
hit you over that. Yes, God,
it's not going to cost them that much,
but they're going to hit you up for that.
And that was a way to get a little more
out of you. You know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying? I don't fucking
want to do that Shit, you know? No.
So I'm really kind of like, I
don't know where else to look.
I'm looking in all the pockets
and cause then we decided,
because that's where we found
them last time was pockets.
So now we are convinced that it's
in the park, be in the pocket shit.
And then I pulled a bunch of clothes,
decided to donate and now when I have to
go through the bag of donation pockets,
yeah. Not In there. Oh yeah. And then by
the way, when I dropped off that donation,
I opened the bag, the, and I went
and I had them take out each article,
check all the pockets a second time
like that, that nervous way of doing it,
you know,
and you go,
I look in there again and then couldn't
find them in the way that says,
Hey Hitler. Yeah. Then I'm, uh, I dunno,
I'm looking under the car seat, you know
what I'm saying? I'm looking under a,
you know, a floor mat.
No, what I'm saying, I'm,
I'm looking under the Christmas
where the Christmas tree everywhere.
I can't find it.
So finally I call you.
I go, you go, I'm going to find it. I have
the dogs never in this house because I,
I will say one of my great gifts is
my ability to find anything. I agree.
I can sniff it out. Yeah. Um, so,
so you left the house and he
put the heat on me. You're like,
you have to find these, you have to find
these. Yeah. So I look, I tore apart.
I went through your backpack. You
did. Oh, I want to throw everything.
I went through everything and I
just put my hand in there. Nope.
I put my hand through everything.
And then finally I look in the kitchen
by the oven on the floor and it's there
just on the fucking floor.
It's on the floor underneath.
What were the keys usually
hang when we hang them.
And we never even looked at it and look
like a couple of fucking rape ties.
He didn't look where the keys actually.
Hey cause we have a little hook.
We're supposed to put them on with a dog
leashes and we, and we didn't even look.
So you know, someone tried to put them
up, they fell down. Probably me. Yeah.
And then I just ignore it like I
always do. Yeah. So there you go.
We got the jeep keys. So the saga
is over guys. We have the keys.
Thank the Lord that we have the keys.
I'm really am thankful about that. Um,
I have a dentist appointment next
week. Wow. Wait, no dude, this week,
tomorrow I go to the dentist.
Uh,
do you know what I think what?
I think my mom mouth is beginning and I'm,
I'm really nervous about it. I haven't
been brushing or flossing as much.
Yeah,
yeah,
yeah.
So tomorrow I go in for my cleaning.
Hey Hitler and we'll see.
I'm nervous.
I have not been flossing
as much or brushing nearly
as much because of the baby
does change. True. Matt
was right. I know. Fuck.
I know I'm going to, I'm preparing
myself, but I'm going to wear, well,
I'll get you the, it's during the
cleaning. I'm going to listen to podcasts,
do it. It's a definitely a change where
it, you should always do that at uh,
at the dentist's office. Listen to,
uh, you know, today was, it wasn't,
here's an example.
I got up.
You are already in the nursery and I
have morning mouth. I just woke up. Yeah.
And you go, oh, well you hold the baby.
Sure. Because you go to do something.
I hold the baby and I realized
I was sitting there with
morning mouth. Yeah. No,
I ended up afterwards going
to brush my teeth. Right.
But I can see how you know,
you get distracted enough.
Maybe you just send thrown up brushing
or till like the afternoon. Yeah.
You wait awhile. Oh, and that's
how dad mouth and my mouth. Really?
Oh yeah. Cause hours fly
by with that kid. Yeah.
Just keeping it alive before you know it.
You haven't showered.
You haven't shipped yet. Yeah.
You haven't brushed your teeth.
Uh, we have a dental, dental, a
update from a listener from Joe. Um,
he titles is subject line is dental truth.
Hmm.
He says hello mommies.
I normally agree with most of your
opinions on the genes of life,
but I got to say you ain't keeping it
high and tight when it comes to your
obsession with dental cleanings,
flossing,
etc. What brushing am
and pm is key of course.
But I fear that my mommy's
had been brainwashed by the
dental industrial complex.
Perhaps I myself have been just been
blessed with extraordinary teeth.
I have not been to the dentist
in 15 years. Oh my God.
Am I chompers are doing great white,
straight and no pain.
Waste of money. Ps, Christina,
wipe your filthy ass before getting
in the south and the shower.
What's wrong with you? Now?
I have to agree with his ps,
but disagree with the subject as a whole.
I mean,
you're actually recommending to people
to go a decade or more without visiting a
dentist. He doesn't know. He
hasn't been to the dentist.
He could have all kinds of problems.
Well, he could have, you know,
there's sometimes there's certain things
with people that they're genetically
just gifted with, you know? Yeah. I mean
it could have blesses God bless people.
Absolutely. So I blesses a
Nicholas, you never know.
That's true. That's true. And it could
be that. That's his blessing. His,
he's got perfect teeth.
Maybe,
but he doesn't know. He
doesn't know how to go, Bro.
There is the anomaly. He's right.
But it's few and far between.
Don't go see your tennis, Bro. C'Mon.
Yeah. I don't think that's good advice
to just go, oh, you never need
to do that. I mean, no, most,
most people's teeth will
disintegrate, fall apart. Things will,
things will stop working the way they
should because you're not entertaining.
Need to get that cleaning.
This guy might be one of those
people that just doesn't need it,
but for the most part, I dunno
man. But it gets your life.
Get your entire fucking life,
get your live, get your ticket,
your life.
Uh, speaking of pastor meeting, that's
who that is. This is pastor man, right
frying a job.
He said
in church and that was about
people that were going to,
they said they were voting for Obama.
He's telling him, Hey John, so weird.
So He's been in the news
lately because the will,
the APP,
what does it at church in Harlem
that he is the lead pastor of.
It's um,
it's apparently going to be auctioned off.
Okay. Um, there's something
going on with his,
uh, you know, bills he's not paying up.
So here's a little bit of him
discussing this here. Okay,
let's see.
To our enemies. I'd like
to say enemies that, um,
right now there are several groups,
uh,
and we've got an office at a controversial
church in Harlem may go up for public
auction. All right. Uh, the infamous, uh,
the anti gay anti Obama passed the,
uh,
hadn't paid his bills.
Uh, pastor man Niggas, oh,
says his flock is being
fleets where we are. Uh,
all these Audis painting those,
I'll beat all these news organizations
are running up and down and talking about
it. They're going to raise money
to purchase our church at auction,
and they're just having a field day out
there and all kinds of stuff and being
spread around and they're going to
turn this church into a bath houses.
They're going to turn into a, a homeless
building for, uh, before the sodomites.
It's mainly the sodomites. So sober
minded people aren't doing it if they,
so the sodomites are,
the sodomites are out to get him.
Um, you know, they're, they're everywhere.
It's mainly the sodomites, the salt.
More minded people aren't doing anything.
Yeah, that makes sense. Yeah.
The site, the sodomites,
I was sick as hell.
So he's got a little, um,
guest. They, he's got a hype
hype woman next. Right, right.
Uh Huh. So this part
though is, is particularly,
I'm entertaining. I think you really
got to understand what he's saying here.
So if you don't know the
controversy behind this guy,
now this is the guy that said that,
um,
that Starbucks has a semen in it,
right?
Remember that pregnant if you drink
Starbucks lattes, really anti Obama, um,
really anti Starbucks, which really
bothered me because I'm a, you know,
I'm a big Starbucks fan.
I mean I'm,
I'm drinking semen right
now and it's delicious. And
they fooled me. They got me.
Um, cause I go and I pay
for it regularly. Uh,
he's really anti gay. I mean like to
the, I dunno, whatever degree possible.
Suspicious how anti gay he is.
You know what I mean? A little,
I really hate sucking cock.
Yeah.
And if you're drinking Starbucks,
watch out. If you're a woman,
you might just get pregnant by drinking
Starbucks because they've got some
pretty potent.
How Sleeman in that drink?
The fuck is he talking about? You can't
get pregnant from drinking seamen.
That's the only,
that's the only flaw in your assessment
of Starbucks semen is that it's hard to
get pregnant from drinking
it. Right. I had a,
that's not what I heard
you heard differently.
I don't know if the earth is round and
I don't know if that's the truth about
all Starbucks. Well, um,
so obviously, you know,
some pretty controversial guy. And so
since the House that the, the church,
the building is up for auction, at least
that's what the news is saying. Um,
and he's so anti, you know,
gay. Yeah. Time. Yeah. Uh,
they're saying that some,
that maybe some gay organizations are
trying to raise the money to turn it into
either like an l g B t you, uh, center
community, Cerner. Somebody even said
like a bath house. So that would be,
yeah, yeah, that'd be great. Um,
but anyways, he, um, you know,
you, he's always good for a sound
byte and this is from his latest, uh,
I guess video posts here.
Um,
let me tell you something
before we can ever own the Lord's House.
Cause that's what this is,
that this is the Lord's House. This ain't
no damn bath house. They know fag house.
Oh Man,
this is the Lord.
And before you can ever own this property
to own this property,
you will be men who are fags.
Testicles will be carrying babies,
testicles,
and given birth to them.
Throw their anus.
That's how impossible it is
for you to get this house.
When you start carrying a baby and
your bags and brought to that baby,
throw yo ass.
You can own this out.
I see you pull a baby out yo ass.
You ain't gonna pull this church out.
Mother needs to us and boom,
Shaka Laka go right there.
James, David madding,
everybody. He's calm the server.
Okay, there you go. I think
he wants to suck a big one.
Yeah. I think when people hate on a
group, there's something going on.
He's fighting delicious testicles and
succulent penis. You know what I mean?
It's a lot. It's a lot. And his hatred for
the gaze, a little suspect. It's alive.
It's another pastor that a pastor is
when anyone to think I was offending a
midget.
Hi Mommy. We've started saying that in
our house now. We have three times now.
Hi Mommy. Mommy. That's really nice.
I wish you hadn't told me
the story behind that clip,
but I still like so depressing.
Oh, the homeless thing.
Kind of a bummer.
You said you got some emails
people telling you you
were crazy for laughing at.
Some people were such bitches about it.
You know,
there's nothing funny about that.
No, it is funny how he says that.
That's how I do like that. It's
funny. Hey, can you play the,
I'm the old lady toasting
Jesus. Speaking of, Hey Hitler, now
that we're on the whole theme. I mean,
okay, so good. We want that in our show.
Huh? Here we go. Okay. Do, it's funny. Um,
let's see. Can you find her? Yeah.
Well the problem is, yeah, that every
video we get now starts with, hey,
Hillary didn't, sorry. Um,
it's the old lady at, Oh, I mean,
she looks old as feels 110. Yeah,
she was around when Hitler was, yeah,
she was his girlfriend and she's
toasting, she's in the Netherlands. No,
it sounds German. She's
goes, she goes post. Oh, and
then, and then she says what?
She says, oh man. Um, and then she says,
uh, how Hitler and they all laugh,
but then they're all like, um,
and it looks like somebody whispers
to were like, don't do that. You know?
It's like, I dunno, she's a Hyundai
grandma. Yeah. Grandma stopped doing that.
Uh, but yeah, she does it for real
too. I don't know. Oh, you can see,
but she doesn't, she looks like she's,
she's a little out of it. She's seen.
I'll do it again. All right. Now you
can tell that the way that she looks,
she looks around the room like, what
did I do wrong? What did I do wrong?
They don't, she doesn't, she doesn't know
why is there, is there popping? Yeah.
What's going on? What's out? It's good.
No, no, no. This is what's, what's up.
Why it's doing it man. Cause my arm. No,
you no sorry dude.
Come on man.
That's what's doing it.
How's an accident?
No,
ma'am.
No reaction. She's, she doesn't know
what's going on and she's like, what?
And they're all like, um, you know,
they know that it's not appropriate.
I've known my, no, I don't know what
they're telling her. And then she's,
she said that again. She's, she
raises her drink again. Like, oh,
maybe they didn't hear me.
Hi
it again. And this time they're like,
there's less of a laugh. I kind of like,
okay.
She doesn't know then that looks like
a grand side. Something is next to her.
He's leaning into her ear.
He's telling her you say it again?
Yeah.
You like you're saying it again.
Okay.
Oh my God.
The funny thing is I probably have a
relative just like this. Absolutely.
Just out of it. Hi. Lately she was
alive when Hillary was around. Oh,
she might've been 50 when he was around.
Yeah.
She looks literally 150 years old.
He doesn't know what's up.
It's hilarious.
No,
we got you saying that you
can't wait for that song.
Don't encourage that.
Uh,
give anybody that is your
chances in Hollywood are higher.
There you go. There's another, another,
another soundbite from Christine's a,
don't forget she's,
she's solutes her,
her king
shit, not my fear. Um,
uh, so this, you really
got a kick out of this.
This is, um, from a talk show. Oh my God,
I love this. Um, this made me laugh.
These or this is the, in the
UK, obviously Lancashire,
Johnny Davidson, Johnny Davidson
jeopardize his pubes ginger.
So apparently this is a guy
calls in. Well, I can just play,
you look at morning challenge and you're
looking for someone to cheer him up.
Yeah.
Rob from South Park didn't get to
terrible boarding shell like we're talking
about. Yeah. He's just like a POW pow.
Pow. Thank you. Do. Oh,
oh well I don't watch because I know that,
I know you're very good with
people who were a bit down.
I don't like spend too long on if,
cause I know it goes on.
That's right where people are going. A
bit up though. I'm sure you are. Well,
I'm from south. All nine last
probably was during the depression.
I know. What is the cost of going
on the beach? There's Donnie,
I see.
I'm depressed.
I was going to the beach for
a all the two to quit office.
I don't understand the joke,
but
he's saying I go to the beach.
The joke is how expensive
it is to go on the bus.
On the boat to the beach. To the beach
to quit. Yeah. Okay. Gotcha. Okay.
Uh, their English. This is English. Yeah.
Yes. But it's like, it's not the
queen. The Queen Talks Lancashire.
Okay, so here we go. So He's, so he
dropped out. He really, he did though.
He might've hung out in comedy clubs
here because he's big on laughing at his
own jokes. Certain comics
like really like to do that.
Fucking really can't make it.
Oh my God.
Your pet peeve with comics.
I think really because they laugh at
their own shit during their set. I mean,
only when it's like repetitive,
when it's continuous or
sometimes it happens genuinely.
Oh my God. You're remembering why you
thought it was funny in the first place.
But you mean like the person who
says it in the moment that you go,
I said this and then you find what
you said really funny. Yeah, that's,
that happens that happens in real life,
but you're talking
about the dude who like,
it's a set up and he does it every
time. It was like, oh my God.
And he does it that way.
Every single or, yeah.
Everything he says makes himself laugh.
Right.
That's really everything that
you say makes you laugh. Yeah.
It's kind of, it's just like
Sinbad, you know, like, like,
because he that doesn't he like
I, I, I dunno does he, it's just,
I feel like he's one of those,
uh, you know what I'm saying?
You got to like that kind of thing.
He got to the gym.
I'm laughing at you right now.
I don't know if we should blame Sinbad,
but I'm definitely last
time went to the gym.
I don't know that that happens.
Or is the Steve Harvey laugh at his
own stuff? I don't, I don't know.
I'm trying to think of who does it.
The one I'm thinking less famous people.
I'm thinking of comics we now,
yeah.
And the people that I see just on stage
all the time, I'm saying, you know, like,
you know what I'm saying?
Them onstage,
locally and see them cracking
up so hard at their own thought.
I'm like, okay. I mean it just seems,
it just seems it reads false to me.
Yeah. We would laugh that hard at
what you're saying all the time. Yeah.
It's a lot.
I thought and I'm depressed.
You say,
why is he calls up
bloody prices and large.
Those are the prices at Lord Street,
right?
Huh?
I'm depressed.
You say why was
let's say the bloody
one way he says to him,
Huh?
Can never get where you're going on the
same side of the road. So I took off.
I had to go to Burp.
Deal to get pot.
Okay.
Absolutely fucking with him.
And that guy has no clue. Yeah.
He has no clue.
The guy went from laughing hard to go on
at
the other dude's a lame as fuck joke.
How do they go to South Park?
I did the two quid anyway.
What are the prices
are longer shot. He, I,
you're not a master of accents. No. Cute
bluff. Okay. Playing this. I love this.
Yeah.
They will say,
Hey,
I'll are these houses here to quit
and move in another brand you and say,
well as view is you'll get round here.
1890.
Hello.
The premise is that the guy
called in depressed. Yeah.
These jokes are taking him
out of fashion that he can't,
he can't laugh any fucking harder
than how bad the areas that he's from.
Yeah.
Oh,
okay.
Okay.
Says,
well stop at the next door way says,
got to many babies are okay.
Oh, lovely. I'll tell Ya.
Standup comedy. No, one of,
I was asked to sit down.
Yeah.
This little fake lab is my favorite.
Oh Man. I wish I could understand
these jokes though. I don't,
I don't understand what he's saying.
Okay.
It's like
multiple,
sorry.
It's like top dot. Called it. Yeah. It's a
dad. These are all dad jokes. I could, ah,
I love that. And I'm saying
I'm offering this as a favor.
I wouldn't normally do this to most
people. It's just cause you're my wife.
I can break down any of these
jokes for you. Really? Oh yeah.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Tom Segura,
master of vaccines.
Okay. Uh, what would you like to hear the
joke again? Which region are we in again?
Lancaster. Lancaster. Okay. And could
you, I mean, could you explain the jokes?
I just don't,
should I go back to the last joke?
I understand the standup comedy one.
Okay. I understand what you said. Yeah.
Like it sounds like they're
kind of regional references.
Totally get them. Okay.
So go ahead. Sure. Yeah. Let
me just set it up for you.
Yeah.
They will say, Hey, I are these hives.
He's here to quit and move in another,
but on you and say, well, as news,
you'll get around here. 1890.
So the guys from south port. Okay. And
he's telling you that he's telling them,
hey, um, it, it'd be 80 quid to get
into a house around here. 80 quid.
Right. And, uh, how is it new? We'll
as do as you'll get around here.
They're from 1890. Gotcha.
He's just saying everything
here. His oldest shit. Sure.
And super cheap. It's a
shitty part of town. Oh, okay.
Gotcha. Well that was good.
Can you, can you mimic this accent? Oh
yeah. Oh yeah. Yeah. Let's hear it. Yeah.
Let me just tell the joke like the
guy if he could. Okay. Oh, okay. Okay.
Hey,
they will say, Hey, I learned these hives.
He's here to quit and
move in another brand.
Can I did moving all they do.
I lose. You get 18 idea around? Yeah.
Oh,
oh
this dude. I love it. Yeah. Wow.
Comedy.
No, no. I was asked to sit down.
Yeah, I'll be that guy. Okay. Ready?
The lab is amazing. Do you
do stand up comedy? No.
Love. I was asked to sit down. Yeah.
Okay.
Oh,
okay.
Like multiple.
Pretty good. Huh? This his
laugh is so funny. Yeah. Yeah.
What a shitty thing to do to somebody.
I was asked to sit down.
Huh?
Do you do me twice? I said yes. Said could
you finish your lock type side please.
We'll have to throw the McCleary off.
Cause the comedian wanted to get on
Scotty mcclue off with, that's him.
Oh comedian wanting to get on. Okay.
As a master of accidents.
Yeah. Well, I can just, it
doesn't matter what someone's,
you know, any accident I can,
not only can I mimic it, I also,
I never have trouble understanding.
How's it? Amazing. Yeah. It's just,
it's like the guy that
wrote in about his teeth,
he doesn't go to the dentist for 15
years. Right. His gift is genetically,
he's gifted with his mouth.
Yours is all through the
ear and then over. Yep.
Right around here and then, yeah, and
then it comes out however I want it too.
That was really good.
Oh God. I side with that long. Oh,
that was one frog.
I'm not trying again.
Well, a cigarette. Oh, there's
one fag on that. Try it again.
He's British right back, right?
He's a cigarette. Oh, right.
Oh yeah. You looked like you
sound like Michael Caine. Yeah.
I can just dip in and out of a region.
That was really,
can you do Michael Caine for us a
little bit when I love, I like a fag.
Wow.
Rupert
isn't not his name and the in
the movie. Yeah, jury runs.
Jonah was root root Brecht rubric rubric.
Not Rubric. Yeah. Yeah.
Excuse me.
She put her out
this a
bit.
Are they doing a bit now?
I think what it is is this guy's just a
shitty hacky morning guy. Is he aware?
Is that his bit? He's, does he know
what he's doing now? It's like,
okay. Yeah, it's so good. I'm saying is
he playing a part of a shitty radio? Oh,
I see what you're saying too. Perfect.
I don't know. I think he doesn't know.
I think this guy really thinks he's Rad
and funny and then the collar being a
shit. Yeah. It's really, really
fun. It's really good. Good Lord.
Yeah. Oh man, that's so funny.
I wish that people would do
that to American radio people.
I think he might be trolling.
I think it might be a troll.
Both of them.
You mean the guy?
Because the guy has posted the guy that
who's name is in the video. I mean,
unless you didn't put this up,
he keeps saying he's a worldclass
broadcasts or communicator. Um,
you know what I mean? So it's almost like
he's, he's selling, he's in. How good.
He is so hard that I
believe that he might be
out over us.
Tie Camp Pace.
I they Tykene and I say get a base.
That was really good.
Oh my gosh.
He's bad jokes.
He knows this opportunity.
Yes.
I'm going to have to go and
then he goes, don't, don't,
I'm a, I'm a frame of toasts
opportunities. Doubt. No. You have to,
to this opportunity.
Yes. Hey, go. Sexy beast.
Gow You're going to fucking do it. And
it's like, no, no, not, don't. Yes, yes,
yes. They say yes. I commend. Yes.
Hitler. What does he say again
with Hitler in you. Jesus.
Yes. Yes, yes. Yeah. No, I
can't do it. And then be like,
kick some punch in the stomach. Yes.
You're going to do it. Yes. Yes.
And he gets you fat. Shit. You fat fucking
leathery. Fuck Crocodile. Fucking fat
crocodile fat and shit.
Fuck crooked ass shit. Fuck. Oh my God.
We got it. We got to start wrapping.
Actually have, um, a meeting. I
have to go. I got a mean to go to.
Okay.
You know,
she ready for her meeting.
She Ready? She ready so much.
I got some mean to go to get to
other things I want to get too.
I said good things and the next
week, why not? I know, I know.
I got some mean the go to.
Oh No,
there's,
there's a,
is there a group these girls speaking
could have hailing Hitler made a song?
No,
this is, their version
is terrible. I know.
This is all from
there. Like teenage girls,
right? Preteen routines.
They're German.
I don't know.
How did you get
so now all their friends the show.
So
yeah, they're, they're really young
girls. I don't think they knew.
They don't know what they're doing.
Not really. They're Germans. Um,
where's the uh, the uh, the
song that, oh, it's here. Okay.
I think this is it. Um, yeah.
Yeah, we gotta run a right.
Hitler's thank you guys for listening.
Little Hitlers.
Hopefully you'll check out the
video of this where you can, um,
actually watched the show.
It'll be on our youtube page and it will
be posted on our site, your mom's house,
podcast.com.
We'll also post it on the Facebook page,
which is facebook.com/your
mom's house podcast.
Um,
we're on Twitter.
Obviously you run Instagram at Thompson
or on Twitter at Christina Paz Paz.
Wait on Instagram, but on Twitter.
Christina, just pay. Yeah.
Christine and page on Instagram.
I'm cigarette Tom because an 18 year
old British boy named Tom Segura Tuck.
It sucks. I will talk to you later.
Oh, that's really good. I know.
All right. We love you guys. Thanks for
listening to this show. That'd be mommies.
Hi Mama.
Gina
basically harassing my dad,
actually.
Hill,
you know,
he put a
cue.
He's been suspended my account,
the time overlay jail
weekly,
and
then he doesn't know if any,
could you
harassing me?
Oh,
I finally get it. What's brilliant
about this? Is it what she's asking?
She's asking it live for a health and
then he's going to get a response that's
really fucking
so he's
really dark, very dark, and
he made a dance our way out.
Pretty soon people were like, Hey,
when's the hail or short term math?
We're not doing
stuff.
Hitler.