Wow.
Well,
well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Okay,
perfect.
Yeah.
Bye Mike.
Um, I'm in west big balls, beach,
West Palm West Palm Beach,
Florida at the Improv next weekend.
If you're listening to this
and you're in that area,
I'm not going to be in that area
of Florida for a long time. So, uh,
make the trek treasure coast.
Go to the Palm Beach Improv at city place.
Big Room, big room. Um, and then I have a,
uh,
December 13th.
I'm going to do one night only at
the ice house. Pasadena. That's fine.
And then new years, Jeez, here's,
he viewed New Year's Eve. I'm an
mom. Lando at the Improv there.
I love that club. So I'll be doing,
I'll be doing new years there,
two years there. And then,
um, the new year starts.
Did you your starts and I
got a bunch of stuff, man.
Go to Tom [inaudible] dot com slash tour.
Click on that page and a
bunch of stuff in January,
Kansas City. Since January.
Oxnard isn't January, uh,
New Orleans, newer genes,
ju do horror lanes.
You whore jeans, Black Lana, uh,
theat clear. Farter
Florida. Tallahassee. Yeah.
They're all happening in a Husky
January you just said Tallahassee.
Yeah. That was really
good. Thank you. Wow.
You just earned your keep.
Tonight I'm hitting over 30 cities
on this tour coming up in 2017.
Jesus Christ, a lot of them are one
night only, so you got to get on them.
We added, we added shows. I forgot.
We added a second show in Chicago and a
third show in Miami. Annapolis. Right.
So if you're a in either city,
shows have been added and by the way I'm
whatever, just go check out the site.
Okay. Genes is going to Washington. Um,
December 19th, 2010 I like to
take December down for standup.
It's good too. I like to take,
I'll do local being a store,
but I think come on that, you know what
I'm saying? Yeah. Thousand ranch.com. No,
I'm saying click on that store.
You know what I'm saying
is that it also,
listen,
the holidays are upon us.
You got to do your shopping and using
our Amazon Danner do not fly with gifts.
Those dumb dumbs and Tsa,
if you,
if you wrap a gift and fly with it
on your carry on, what do they do?
Tommy Wilson Goode, what's to
here. And then they emerge,
they unwrap it and they go, oh, you can
go back and check it in if you want.
Like anybody fucking does that. You don't
have time for that. So go to Amazon,
send them to the destination you're going
to. Why would you travel with gifts?
It's silly. Have it shipped and
use our banner, your mom's house,
podcast.com. Click on the banner at the
bottom of the homepage. Do your shopping.
Thank you. Thank you. For those
of you that already do it loyally,
we so appreciate it very much.
Appreciate it. Bookmark the damn page.
You know what I'm saying? Thank you
Mike. Calico beats for that. Oh,
you know what I'm saying? No, no, no
privacy. Um, you ready to
start the show jeans? Yeah.
God Start Tom,
your mom and you're my son and I if
falling in love with him. He said,
are you really? I said, yes, I
am. He thinking, you know what?
I was scared to let you know too. I
am too both consenting adults. If,
if it comes down to it, you know, it's
just like the gays there, there, you know,
as long as they're over 18,
everything's fine.
No, bring it in for this. Well,
we'll go to your mom's house,
Christina visits.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah. Amazing. Right.
That clip I saw on Facebook yesterday
and I almost had a fucking coronary.
I thought it was so funny.
Yeah.
The Blue Band right away. Right
away. You got to add this.
That's the new opener for tomorrow because
that was the craziest Shit I've ever
heard. Yeah. What's, can we hear it again?
Yes, of course. Of course. You're like,
I really need to get into it. There's,
there's so much amazing about that clip.
Uh, it's so, it's so unbelievable.
Yeah.
Hmm.
By the way. Oh, this is
what I wanted to say. Don't,
don't fucking break my
balls spooky because I know
someone right now is breaking
my balls because there's no video today.
Oh,
well you listen to a mother fucker.
Yo. You know, first of all guys,
we barely had our lives together
enough to do today's episode.
This has been a massive
move. And Tom, oh my God,
left town the day we had one day here and
then you left town and I've been alone
with the baby and workers
workers coming in and out.
We have everything's chaos,
have electricians and handymen and
there's a guy right now doing shit in the
house, like all kinds of stuff. And
I know some people are like, dude,
I fucking well I like to watch it and
you're fucking up my well low cheese.
It's chaos right now. So you guys are
probably like, well good luck to you then.
Well you know, we're like, you
have a good fucking night then.
Okay guys, listen. It's a miracle
that we pulled together audio tonight.
So sorry. We're going to have to
look. It's chaos in here right now.
There's were, we did this like a,
this is a makeshift studio right now.
There's cords laying on top of
stuff like this isn't set up. So No,
I'm looking at just everything
splattered everywhere. Yes.
Bad and not, not healthy. This
is a level eight hoarders,
right? What's the highest on
the hoarding? Uh, I think five.
This is a five. Yeah, there's
pathways, which is a good sign.
You saw pathways. I mean there's,
there's fecal matter everywhere,
which is bad in buckets. My friend
Matt told me, he's like, you know,
and you want you to have the fecal matter.
Is that when you're at a five? Oh yeah.
Is that what pushes you to the last
and no, no. Pathways. Like you said,
you can't have no, wait, sorry. So if
you still have pathways, you're like, uh,
three uh, yeah. I mean you're somewhere
on that. You know, you're below,
you're like that.
So we're at a three.
I think it's so hilarious that there's
like call, cause I know that Guy Matt,
what is he, what's his, his website?
It's like five steps or something.
I forget men. Um, but
that's what, that's what he,
he classifies people as the hoarder
levels. Like if you've got dead animals,
you're definitely like a five plus
feces and buckets. You're five.
You want to hear the,
the, of course, of course.
I live for this kind of shit.
I love psychological things like this.
This is so peculiar that says
this is for for fire service.
They they watch.
It's a fire service hoarding scale.
So level one is the start. Most of
the homes we see are at this level.
You countered large amounts of materials.
It's us, but find normal clutter,
apparent signs of insects,
some apparent size of insects and rodents,
clutter and we're the level
one. All doors, windows and
hallways are accessible.
We're not even, we're well
our, our doorways are not that
accessible right now. Windows we
might be able to is a hoarder home.
That the amount of overall clutter has
begun to appear is the point where you
would consider the amount of belongings
to be over and above the normal level.
Trash cans are overflowing,
one or more exits are blocked.
Housekeeping is at a minimal level.
At level two,
the piles of belongings may be at
or above waist level. Oh my God,
God. Windows are starting to be unusable
as piles to continue to get larger.
Level three quote,
big problems begin.
The amount of belongings have
taken control of the house,
making the rooms unusable
for the occupants. Serious
hazard for firefighters.
Yeah.
The goat paths become the only
access usable space like the animal.
Yeah, I guess because
there was so narrow, right.
Climbing on mountains
on neuro level three,
the clutter may be visible
from the exterior. Yeah.
You're fucked. Stairwells are mostly
blocked from below with belongings.
It's just a narrow path. Level four
is also the beginning of the end.
Uh, the beginning of the
end of the unusable areas of
the home starts from level
four. Most of the rooms are
unusable, hoarded space levels. Uh,
the piles of belongings will be
at the ceiling where they're,
all windows are covered.
God, attic spaces are full.
Oh boy. All cabinets are full.
Even under the floor spaces.
And level five is uninhabitable.
Unable to enter.
There's obvious structural
damage. Broken walls, men.
Does it talk about the feces and the dead
animals or no? No, because this is like,
that was what I read you
was for firefighters. This,
this day. They do that.
They don't get into the fun
stuff. Yeah. Roaches and oh,
he would clutter cleaner was,
yeah. Oh, this is a different,
this is a different one. So
this one, level five is, um,
according to this,
animals at risk and danger,
uh, pervasive spiders,
roaches, mice, rats, squirrels,
key living spaces are not usable.
Um, toilets, sinks and
tubs are not functioning.
Human, urine, urine, an
excrement is present,
rotting food cans or
cans or jars are expired.
Member Tommy harder's where
she was, she was like, well,
it's not puffy. I can still eat it. Yeah,
the bacteria. So there'll be like a,
like a box of like soup or broth.
And this woman would be like,
the ordering cleaning lady would be like,
this is a year ago state. And she goes,
well, the box isn't puffy. I can still
eat. It's not puffy. I can eat it.
Is it puffy yet? And she would ask that
and they're like, no, not yet. Well,
don't throw that away. Shit. My
favorite two was when, um, the one,
the women had a problem collecting things
like beanie babies and then an entire
bedroom would just be a floor to ceiling,
like beanie babies.
The tag still on like, well,
I gotta collect all 700.
This one's a limited edition.
They're so crazy.
The Hordern shows really do.
It sounds like a bit,
but they do make you
feel good about yourself.
That's why I think that's the allure that
was the, I think why they had viewers.
Yeah. I got my shit together.
Of course. Yeah, of course.
You watch it and you go, oh,
my house is, there's a lot of
alarming shit on that show.
One of the most alarming though was
when they had, uh, a psychologist.
Do you remember that one? The
psychologist was the hoarder. Yeah.
How could you do that? And she was
like, oh, I know I treat people.
But you know,
the cobbler's children have shoes,
credible levels of denial. That's really
what it is. It's some kind of trauma.
I think that happens. And
then it's unresolved. And
then they turn in. They, yeah.
And they hard to deal with the trauma.
Usually that's what happens. I don't know,
unless some people are just nasty. Some
people just so mad. He got to be so nasty.
It's my favorite episode of hoarders.
Remember the the woman that
had 75 dead animal carcasses,
75 that was my, yeah, it sounds really,
I wish there was more
shows about mental illness.
I just love mental illness shows.
I could watch that. Oh my God,
you guys are so disgusting.
Yeah.
So far I can watch an entire series
of people who just shit into jars and
collect them. I love that. I can
watch that shit all day, man.
Why works really,
really gross when he's talking about,
wait, so what's our house at right now?
Like a three. No, we're not there, man.
You gotta be kidding me. It's
not that bad. We're not that
bad. But it's just, it's,
it's still, it's chaos for not
mentally ill people, you know?
It makes me,
it gives me so much anxiety to have boxes.
I fucking hate it so much. They
get it. Just the appearance,
just boxes everywhere. It gives
me, I just hate it. Boxes Smell.
They smell. Yeah. You just, you know that
and then there's just stuff
like you're missing. Like,
I've got the,
uh,
I've got the Cup but not the
lid to the fucking, you know,
like a boy,
one of these right here for that one.
It was just, and I'm never
going to find that quarter odor,
a whole other piece for it. I'm
missing all kinds of shit. It's just,
we will be back with, um, you know,
with an actual camera show next week,
but let's Thanksgiving week two,
we're going to be home.
We'll be around so we can straighten
things up a bit more. Definitely. But, uh,
so oil boy, you know, it
was neat about moving Tom.
My favorite thing and having
workers around is, um,
all every,
every mover that was in her
home took a shit they did bad.
Yeah.
And what's cool is there's a point in
the day where the door would be shut,
but the fan would still be on. So you
knew that people were just to show you.
Yeah. That's cool. Through them.
Through the door. You can hear it. Yeah.
Yup, Yup. Cool.
That's what you hear. Like a stranger.
A strange dude. Yeah. And like,
you know that lunchtime, I remember
lunchtime came, they broke for lunch,
never moving day, our
packing day. Right, right.
There's a break for lunch and then five
dudes came and shit in our move a whole
house like that they had, they
sent like the crew, you know,
so these six guys show up.
Yeah.
Moving couches and beds and just heavy
shit. And then all six of them are like,
I'm gonna take a shit. Right.
Shit. All Shit in your house, man.
All so gnarly. Yeah, it's been,
my favorite was we had a carpenter come
a couple days ago to the new house and
the guy shook my hand. Sweet guy.
Yeah. Shook my hand. Hey, I doing I,
my name is. So Steve, we're going to
do the thing. Great. Great, great.
Not Five minutes later. Can I use
your bathroom? And I'm thinking, well,
he's going to go number one. It's
a morning. It's early morning. No,
the guy takes a full,
yeah, yeah, yeah. You can hear it.
Hear
it. Yeah. I could smell it. And he
used the bathroom by the kitchen.
I'm cooking for my son.
I'm eating breakfast and this,
this carpenter is taking a shit in my
bag. Yeah, that's correct. Right here.
But why, why save it for my house? That
was a first call in the morning, you know,
it was a cool guy.
You think he wanted to pull over to
Starbucks and maybe shit somewhere else,
but he brought it to my house and I think
I, I just saw what he did to this too.
I think he gave me a modification hold
there for this. Oh, I was looking for,
I'm excited. I'm so excited to show this
to people when we have it set up. Dude.
You guys are going to shit
when you see the studio. Yeah.
It's a professional studio. It
is. But we'll give you a tour.
I want to do this as like a Patriot
on bonus or just a bonus. No, they,
we'll just put it up man.
Yeah.
You guys to see the quality of the
studio is bananas. It's soundproofed.
It's got like velvet on the walls.
Sound paneling,
just beyond anything drastically.
A number of major motion pictures
were scored in. It's right.
And we have a couch here that the
original owner left behind that leg,
Dr Dre sat on screen,
all these crazy directors and this
guy was a composer for films. Yeah.
So it's a cool, it's a great studio. I
can't wait for y'all to see her next week.
Hopefully I'm your mom and you're
my son and I fall in love with him.
Are you really? I said yes.
He said, you know what,
I was scared to let you know too. I
am too. Both consenting adults. If,
if it comes down to it, you know, it's
just like the gays. There's dairy.
As long as they're over 18 everything's
fine. It's just like the gays,
the gays.
Do you they just like the gates.
The gates.
Yeah.
So homosexuality, let's set
this up. These two dumb dumbs,
they have that real
dumb way of speaking to,
you know,
he's,
I'm your mom and you're my son
and I if falling in love with him.
And so I guess the story is this,
my fucking lunatic woman gave
this guy this kid up for adoption.
Oh cool mom.
And then they were
reunited 20 years later.
And then they fell in love.
That's sweet. Wonderful Story.
I mean,
and he talks real dumb like mom does.
You can tell that they're
related in that photo.
Apple doesn't fall far from the
stupid tree man. These two idiots.
I mean, is there anything more
repulsive? It's just like the gay
man. So good. That's a,
that's about 19 1991 logic.
I mean, there you going to marry your
dog. I think people still say crazy stuff.
Yeah. I got to tell you, as
a mom, as a mom, as a mom,
I'm a mother and a wife that,
and I'm also in show business.
The thought of falling in love with
my son. It's just not on the table.
Why you have a father?
What's wrong?
The other day when we found
this clip, you're like, well,
what did it take for you to date your dad?
I think you said,
I'd rather you said something horrible.
I'd rather like be drown or execute.
I would literally rather die a slow,
horrible death.
The only way I would do it is
if is if they were like Ellis.
His life depends on this happening. I'd
be like, absolutely. Like it's my son.
But yeah, no, I do anything for that boy.
Look at this kiss and they both have
teardrop tattoos, which is Kinda Nice.
I'm pretty sure would you French or knows?
Like I love my mom and she's like,
I love you too.
And like, and then we keep, here we go.
Now I think I'm falling in love with,
will you ever date your mom? And he said,
well you did your son. And I said the
honest truth. Yes I would. Oh cause uh,
19 years you're the best thing that ever
happened to me and I really want to be
with the rest of my life. I'm going
to throw up. So can we talk so dumb.
Come you talk to him. Ah, wait for 19
years, it's the best thing that happened.
Or why did you give him up for adoption
there? I don't know. I mean, God,
she's all kinds of fucked up.
She asked him that,
that ever important question asked them,
will you ever date your mom?
No. No. I asked to awesome.
Awesome. When you everyday your
mom. He was like, he's like, yeah,
I was like a me too. US All. I all like,
yeah. And then he's all like, yeah.
And then we were all like, yeah,
and then we kiss. Ask them, will
you ever date your mom and say,
well you did your son and I sit
and honest truth. Yes. I would.
Honest to goodness 19 years,
you're the best thing that ever happened
to me and I really want to be with the
rest of my life. Yeah. Dummy. It's called
having a child. You dumb. Fuck, I'll,
could you imagine banging
your head just no grow,
not that little boy grows inside of you.
You push him out of your,
your meow and then you know, sex with one
of your parents. It just like the gays.
The first approach was actually
me. Oh. What happened was we were,
we were hanging out and you know,
just talking and all and just laughing.
And I looked at her and she looked
at me and I kissed her. Oh my God,
here's a real quick,
it was a real case. Uq is was a real good
cause or okay, here's the real cause.
It's just like the gays.
Yeah.
Yeah. Damn it. These two. Oh Man.
I don't know. You gotta
stay in school, you know,
that's what you took away from this guys.
He's gotta go to fucking school.
You know,
you gotta study,
you gotta you gotta not marry your mom
and you got to not be like the gays.
Yeah. All that fancy book, all that
fancy book learning. Seriously though.
Real talk word.
What would it take for you to date?
Charro I want to fucking hit you for
even asking me such a disgusting thing.
Oh, like, oh, so, and she likes
like, Woo, I'm your mom.
Would you ever date consider dating your
mom? That's the question she asked him.
I would like, uh, uh,
what a beautiful courtship story too.
One day I was like,
would you ever date your mom?
And then he was like, yeah,
I want to do my mom who was
a real kid cause or okay.
Sometimes I call him,
he know Hito at that means son
wants to know why he calls me mom.
You know what I mean?
Thank our cases about whether I have
the right to love somebody and I sure as
hell have the right to let Monica know
it's not about whether you're the right
to love somebody. You could definitely,
you have the right to love your mother,
right? I guess the courts are taking
them to task and so they're like,
why can't they just stay in their house
and not telling anybody the weird by
yourself,
you have to marry somebody locally.
Like why don't you just do your
weird shit and keep it quiet?
You're not going to fight for
the right to marry your mom.
I don't think society is going to
get on board with that one guys.
I don't think so either. Jesus just
be goddamn weird at home. Right.
It's like it's like you always said,
you know, you've always said no.
No. You've always said, why? Why
do you have to tell everyone?
I'm proud to have come out as polyamorous
and now I'm excited to share that I'm
bisexual. I'm like, why you want to tell
everybody? No, nobody needs to know.
This guy was like, I told my parents over
Thanksgiving dinner, and you're like,
why?
Why let them eat stuff and they don't
need to know your 70 year old parents
don't want to know who
I'm poly and I'm bi.
I'm Paula and I'm by dad, buddy.
Hey, got to tell you something.
I'm Paula and I'm by
Pauley and I'm buying like they're old.
They're old.
They don't want it. They don't care. Or
in this case like nobody cares. Well,
it's disgusting.
People care if you inform them,
but no one cares if they don't know.
Fuck your mom.
Go ahead and go fuck your mom with the
doors closed. Shut the blinds. Retard.
No one cares or weird
shit on your own time. No,
don't make it illegal now. Yeah. Well the
thing is I have to marry her. Why? Well,
they're dummies.
They don't know how to shut the fuck
up and just do what they gotta do.
Not necessarily talk about it.
Just like people to fucking animals
and do all this weird stuff. You know,
they stay in the shadows. It's, there's
some things you got to keep in the shadow.
Oh my God, you guys are so disgusting.
It's so gross. It is so, so,
so wait a minute. You don't want
to go down on your mom. Oh my God.
Shut up from that same suite vision
that you came out of a really, you're,
you're fucking, what about
sucking on those? Ted does.
It's really gross. Moving on. So
maybe you could drink milk
again. So I should, uh,
from those low hangers because
swinging hangers, by the way,
I want to thank everybody. I
can't even really describe. I,
you know,
I've had a lot of fun on the road recently
with like just being away from your
family. The best part,
that's the best part.
But the second best
part has been the shows.
And I'm saying raw ball.
Raul meet Charlotte friend
men disco Jude or activities.
Yeah, they've all been so fun. But my God,
this weekend and fill up Delphia
gave every show of the last
year a run for its money.
That's how much fun it was.
The, the crowds were amazing.
And so I just wanted to say thank you
everybody for coming out to the truck.
It was awesome. Man, why don't
you marry him? I wish I could.
I wish I could marry each and every of
you like you were my own mother. Um,
Josh Potter opened for you and what's
new with him? How's he doing? He's great,
man. I mean, same old shit
sell in Buffalo, buffalo
and Barthalow. Uh,
he's still doing his thing. He was Hila
he killed, he killed, I guess Twitter.
Is he on Twitter? Can we give him a shout
out to help? Oh yeah. Um, let's see.
What does Josh Potter, Josh,
I love Josh Potter. He's,
he is very funny and he's a,
he's super,
he's one of those dudes that's funny
offstage to where you're just talking to
him and you're like,
this guy's crazy funny.
His self deprecation is so super good.
He's at j underscore
potter, p. O. T. T. E r underscore
pop. Yeah, she's on, um,
shred and Reagan in buffalo
in the mornings. Um,
he's really a great guy,
but like,
I probably got hit up after that show.
I can't tell you how many times that
people asking you about who he is too,
so that's wonderful. Yeah,
it's really good. And he's,
it's sweet.
Due to which he had great sets and
he and throat Zillow were dating.
Is that true? Well, I mean
they met, but I'm right.
I think it reminds me I am going
to her city later in the year.
Maybe I should bring him again.
Yeah, that's a great idea.
Maybe those two can spark up kind of a
connection. Be a little love connection.
Cause they start a connection last time.
Well they certainly got, you know, they,
there was a hello and a goodbye.
I don't know if anything happened.
I mean I don't, I don't hold his hand
when we walk around and kiss. Uh,
Josh is the one that turned us on
to her snapchat. Josh turned me on
the whole story. Josh was the
one who let it be known, uh,
who she is and, and what
exactly what was going on. The,
the story of course was
about, um, you know,
her and a famous athlete. So, sure.
He told me about that story
and I was like, wait, what?
And then he actually is the one who he,
uh,
he's the one that,
that got me thinking about which position
in football has the best captain worst
cap assholes. Really? Yeah.
And that's an ongoing conversation
that we've had and we had it. Oh yeah,
we had it. Even this, uh, this weekend
in the car with the Uber driver was like,
who do you think has the worst?
Kept a whole,
you really got to understand football
to have a, an opinion. I'm just
asking, can you just give me the top?
Well we basically excluded
everybody but Lineman, you know,
so we have our top tier grade a assholes
are like the quarterback diva receivers
we decided are probably like just nice
assholes like and very well kept clean
and, oh no, sorry, I misunderstood.
I thought you were talking about the
best of the best are probably wide
receivers, diva corners and quarterbacks,
you know, like the best. Why do you think,
uh, it's just, you know, that we,
they just appeared to be guys that
take a lot of pride in appearance.
They take care of themselves physically.
They're in great,
phenomenal athletic shape.
And, um, you know, they,
they probably take care of everything
including those rosy red assholes.
So that was a conversation he and I had.
And then it w it further got into,
well then what would be the worst asshole.
And that's where we,
we have a difference of opinion cause I
say offensive line and he says defensive
line. But it's, it's an interesting
theory that he presents.
May I throw out something?
Okay. Yeah sure, sure.
Have you considered, I just think that
sometimes there they have white uniforms,
those tight pants.
And I think that those teams would
have to keep the cleanest be holes.
Oh just cause they have white.
Yes.
Because I can see everything
when they bend over and I'm,
we got the that widescreen
TV. I see. I can see cheeks.
They don't wear panties.
They're not wearing panties.
I can see I outlines of balls.
So I think you can,
you gotta be careful. Cause if the
chocolate smears, if your wipe wipe,
wipe wipe and you know,
we to be careful by the way,
I've had horrible dumps since we moved
in here cause we don't have our wash.
Let's installed and I've ha,
I had disastrous bowel movements
and I've had to shit to shower here.
Well, it's like really have you really?
Yeah, because I don't have a wash.
Let the bad days not here yet.
It's terrible.
Yeah. The wash that we got
to get that hooked up. That's
a, yeah, that's a priority.
But I mean how disgusting was it
to shit on the road without, uh,
it's horrible every time. Like, do
you think this guy's assholes growth?
And let me just see what's what,
what's this person's name?
Bj and he's got a 90.
I'm going to say I wish I could see his
hair situation because I feel like it.
Does he have dreadlocks? No. No.
Sometimes I feel like people
with dreadlocks or extra
dirty downstairs too. Yeah.
That's just my bias. Then you
feel that way. They're like,
if your head smells then
your asshole on your Coochie,
you're going to stink like that too.
Could be maybe, I mean, I've heard people
say that those are pretty bad smelling.
Sometimes some drives where
you think this guy smells like,
I think his bee holes clean.
Do you think this guy, wow,
Christina was talking about
Vince Wilfork right now,
if you don't know who that is,
you can look them up.
But I think a lot of people
would look at that and go, oh,
that guy's ass holes a disaster.
I, here's why I'm, he's his head
is clean shaven and he groomed
his facial hair nicely.
I think he takes pride in his appearance.
And here's somebody who
doesn't know anything about
football and you're throwing
a whole wrench in the game
right now. Interesting. Yeah.
Well sometimes it takes a fresh
perspective on an old timeless problem.
I'm wondering,
um,
let's see who we could probably look
at that might change your opinion.
Um, right now, let's see.
See is this guy,
ah,
let's say Barnes is he,
he's uh, for the, okay.
You played for the chiefs right
now and see what this guy's ass,
what do you think of his asshole thing?
This guy's an asshole. Smells okay.
First of all,
I think all of their assholes smell.
I don't think there's a football player
alive who's butthole doesn't. Yeah,
he's dirty. Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Cause he,
you can tell he doesn't care about
his face. Okay. Barnes while he's,
he's got shared, like you said,
it's groomed, you know? Yeah.
But a man that maintains
facial hair shape,
that's a guy that cares that
his appearance in general.
But if you're just clean shaven it's like,
well there's effort but not
as much effort. Okay. Okay.
Um, let me, let me pull up. You put a lot
of effort into maintaining your beard,
right?
That's true.
And over the years I've civilized you
to care about your be whole cleanliness
and your body cleanliness, you know? Yeah.
Although every now and then you do slip
up and you'll fly home after a long
weekend of shows not showered and then
demand that I orally pleasure you and
I'll be like to have you showered in
the last 24 hours or is this your swamp
nuts from your flight and then
everyone makes mistakes. Yeah. Okay.
Who is this guy? He's disgusting.
He's disgusting. This is Cody Wickman.
Now he's a pig. The uh, now
what makes you say that?
It looks like a real nice smile.
Know that facial hair is bad.
Facial hair for 30 guy facial hair. He's
got just the chin cover. The shaggy. Yeah.
The uh, the one, one
quarter of a goatee. It's,
it's gross. I'm not, I'm not,
he's six, five, 320 pounds.
He's a little boy. Six Five, three
20 says tiny little sweep muffin.
I see what you're doing now. He's a very,
he's a dirt bag. Yeah. You think so?
How about um, well my pain Manning,
Eli Manning. Peyton manning. Eli. Well,
you know what they look like.
What do you think Eli is?
Retired or Peyton Peyton's. I
love pay it. Can I tell you that?
I love his commercials. I think
he's so funny. Like he's, yeah,
he's actually really funny. He is
funny. His timing's great. Yeah.
He's a funny dude. Those guys
are clean. I think Greg's clean.
Do you think Greg Robinson? Yeah. Clean
left tackle for our Los Angeles Rams.
Six five three 32.
It's sweaty,
but he works hard at maintaining his eye.
He
looked why? What you just read.
Do they live in this city?
We probably could get some of these
guys in here and get their take on this
whole perspective. What a neat
idea. I'll be your asshole.
How and who's got the dirtiest asshole
on the La Rams? Well that's, I mean,
come on. It's going to take
us a while to figure out,
but I don't know if someone's listening
and you're in the La Rams. We'll look.
I just showed you a couple offensive guys.
You said one was was really gross.
Um,
so let me give you a big,
a big defensive linemen.
This maybe you're not
even following a silly,
but do you think this his ass smells
bad? Hideous, so maybe terrible.
Maybe you're on Joshua's. Maybe. See,
cause you don't really know
what the position was. No idea.
But she was looking at, uh, Michael
Brocker is right now. He's a mass.
Why the facial hair is all a mess.
But see,
he look how groomed though because
it's too bushy. But see, he's not,
there's a lot of attention to that though.
That doesn't just happen.
It's not a good, but somebody
faded that down. Yeah.
But I think it needs to be made. The
maintenance is not there. He see Josh,
his theory is that the aggression
with which this position has played.
In other words, these guys are chasing
after the guy with the ball. Yeah.
Leads to a funky or dirty
or asshole. Interesting. You
know, it's an interesting,
you have to really understand
football too. I don't get the nuances,
but that's what, that's part
of why he thinks he's, neither.
One of us talked about facial hair.
Interesting.
Going on aesthetics alone
and Michael Bloggers.
We want to smell your asshole.
Micheal Brecker's. I liked that name.
Michael Brocker dirty and disgusting. That
guy's going gonna fuck you Michael. Oh,
I think so too. And if you don't
want to too bad, cause he has six,
five, three 26 God. Yeah.
Michael is a little fucking hold.
You realize these,
these last five guys that showed you,
it would make me look like a child.
That's crazy. Their meat and
cheese. Oof. All meat and cheese.
Big Ole fucks. I think our
son's going to be big like that.
I Dunno about like that. He's a big boy.
Our son's almost a year old. He wears, um,
18 month and up clothing.
She's a pick guy. He's, yeah,
he's a big man. All right. Um,
oh, I wanted to show you this.
This came in. It's pretty great.
[inaudible] he's
a pitcher. Barks. Pricer
isn't that fantastic? Japanese
class of children. This is adorable.
Not only do we have that, we also
have from India. Oh my goodness.
[inaudible]
Chrysler's
Chrysler.
Chrysler
doesn't go to the gym.
Bon Chrysler
drinks too much.
I took it to another level. This might
be the most impressive one. Yeah.
This is an entire class of 40.
You said 40 Indian children.
Adorable little kids. They're
so cute. And the, the teacher,
the woman with this is our first female.
She's like improvising to adding all
kinds of shit. So good. Oh my God.
That was amazing.
Around
all right. [inaudible] is the real water
champ. I don't like it anymore and cute.
I don't like it.
And yeah,
I can't feel,
Geez.
Oh my gosh, I can't, I
can't believe this. I know.
This is truly an international
and this isn't like, um,
like an American teaching abroad.
This is an Indian woman who I'm assuming
listens to the show and then this is
amazing. Wow. I'm blown away. I'm
blown away. Thank you for this. So, uh,
Sean, the uh, the Indian edition. Wow.
Look at the children of Kolkata. Oh. Um,
he did it so that they don't
suffer the same fate as burnt. Uh,
and then Chris wrote to us,
I moved to Japan to teach English.
I remember specifically that Mommy,
Tina Aka water champion. Thank you.
Asked for a video from Japan. So I
made one for her. I Hope Mommy Bonds,
Aka Ivs champion will enjoy this
too. That is from Chris. Let's, uh,
let's see what else is in the,
uh,
Burt is being shamed in Calcutta
now. Oh my God. And we've had this,
how many foreign language ones have we
had already? It's count countless. It's,
yeah, it's just, yeah,
you may love Commedia itchy. Both.
How? Comedian number one fat community.
Oh my God.
Is He,
why
does he meet that?
He yes,
he goes,
okay. Yeah. So he goes
eating and you're right.
He goes eating with another
fast friends is friend is bad,
but he is number one back.
He's explaining it. Adorable little
Japanese child. This is so fun.
Think my favorite thing.
God. This is hilarious.
Teachers with kids talking about fat bird.
It's my baby,
right?
Is he fat?
Yes.
Very good.
Oh my God.
He's amazing.
Chris had the kids draw pictures of her.
Yeah,
these are fantastic. These
are wonderful pictures. Yeah,
it looks like big titties on Burt Burt's
wearing a diaper and this one. Yep.
It looks like Santa Claus.
And this was so good.
Yeah. Here's a bird in a speedo.
Okay, let's right, right.
Wow. I'm so impressed. I cannot
believe a, so here's the thing, Burton,
I have a weight loss competition going
now, right? Really real now, right?
Just as the holidays come to.
Oh my God, it'd be tricky. Um,
so we have a new side bet going.
Okay.
So the big bet is that whoever's
lower has to take the other comedian,
the other friend.
And for some reason Ari Ari get injected
himself when these old is William do it
cause he was the driving force,
he said behind it. Okay. Um,
so the other, the other, the loser,
the guy who weighs more has to take the
two other people to like some desirable
event. A concert at the
staples center. Yeah. Event.
And it can be in another city.
So it could be like I want to go
to the Superbowl and it's like,
do you got to take everybody?
Okay, we have a new side bet.
And it made it really real because
the thing is that's a costly endeavor.
So I'd like Burke to spend
that money of course.
So we need to slim me down.
Yeah, I got a win. Yeah.
The new side bet is that the
loser has to shave his beard.
Oh my gosh.
Yeah.
And then you can see exactly how fast
it goes or is there's a fat cover up.
It's been a long time.
I know both of you and Bert have
had beards for years. For a while.
And I was looking at this photo we
have above the US back to back here.
We took this at Sears a few years ago.
Yeah. Look how thin your beard was. Yeah.
It doesn't look good when it's thin.
I know. It looks good. Bushey yeah.
So I haven't seen your face and I don't,
I can't remember what about
a full shave. Yeah. Yeah.
I don't remember the last time
that you'd done that. So I, when I,
I texted him that I go, how much anxiety
just that give you, and he's like so, so,
so much,
so much.
And then he sent me a picture of him at
some press event like years ago without
a beard. And I was like, Ooh, terrible. Oh
well it's just what he goes. And he goes,
when I waste so much less than this photo,
I can't even picture Burt without a beard.
I've,
I know ever known him with a beard.
I've seen him without it a while.
But you know, I'm kind of banking on a
couple things. First of all, you know,
I've been working out a lot. Yeah. Been
eating well. Your stomach is almost gone.
But the other thing I'm banking on is
his gluttonous lifestyle and it's the
holidays. And guess what? December I'm
home and he's on the road every week.
Forget it, forget it here, here's the
variable that's going to mass with Bert,
the party life cause he's the life
of the party when he's on the road,
it's booze, booze, booze,
every night eating it,
two in the morning and then sleeping and
waking up and doing it all over again.
I mean,
I want to win for a lot of reasons,
but I also think I have that
in my favor because yeah,
I don't have to get to like
a crazy number to win this.
I think if I just get ahead
and, and then, you know,
just stay, stay working out the
way less than bird, right when yes,
it could be. Yes. Okay. Um, but you know,
I think that, I don't think
he'll be able to dial it back.
Not during the holidays. We know that
because everyone parties in the holidays,
he's renovating the house.
They all live in the same room right now.
He's stressed out all the time. So
when he is home, he wants to drink.
When he's on the road, he's
going to party. He wants to
party. He's going to party.
Yeah. So where were you guys the last
time we weighed in? Who was ahead?
Who was behind? Well, it's funny.
So when we weighed w when I weighed
in with him on Ari's podcasts,
I was two 42 and he said it was
two 40 bullshit. And I go, okay.
And then he, uh, he texted me like a week
later, he goes, oh, slowing. Of course.
So actually I haven't had started
off, of course, you way less than him,
but you know, a lot of people came up to
me and fill her up and they were like,
you know, you're, you're smaller
than I saw it last time. Yeah.
I think you're going to beat Bart.
I got a lot of people pulling for me
on this and he's got his, he, you know,
he has loser, like the people that into
him. So there'll be on his side. But like,
you know, I think, uh, I think,
I really think if I stay,
I think December is going to
be a big month for me with, um,
home virtually the entire
month. Get on the routine. Yup.
Properly. You're, you're, you've
got my support and that we're on,
I'm on primal Kido. We're there.
We're, we're maintaining. Yeah.
Now you're, you're going to
kick his ass jeans. I think so.
Of course you're going to kick his
ass. And I think that those, those,
those road days he has coming up.
Yeah.
The thing about it is what
actually happens is the booze.
What happens when you drink a lot of
booze? It leads to more food eating. Yeah.
Yeah. So I think his days are
fine. It's just that when the,
when he starts boozing it up,
yeah.
He's then going to need to fill up
the stomach with the alcohol. Yeah.
And don't forget alcohol itself
is, yeah, it's sugar. Oh, sure.
That's a lot of calories.
Yeah. You're, you're talking,
that's your daily caloric intake.
How much he drinks. Oh yeah. It's,
I'm not Burt's and alcoholic,
so we're doing, you know,
we've got a real thing going on.
Say saying that real talk in order
for Bert to defeat you. Yeah.
He would have to stop drinking.
Right. In which case, yeah, he could.
And that was his big, if that was his
big goal, he could do it, you know,
cause he's just like the gays,
you gotta you know,
it's just like the gays. Yeah. Jesus.
What a couple of knuckleheads. Huh?
So anyways, that's our
new side bet. The Shave,
the shave to me is way worser then
the sporting event. Oh my God.
Cause that's just money. But yeah,
this is like, that's embarrassing.
It's embarrassing.
And if I were to do it,
that means I would go to I think
Kansas City with a fully shaved face.
Well, the good thing for you is
that your beard grows back so fast.
It grows back so fast,
but it would be shaved for longer
than you think it would. Uh,
it would take to the end of the month
to start looking like myself again.
I wish you guys would shave your
heads too. That would make me laugh.
I'm going to get a haircut on
Wednesday. Oh, go on Allen. Oh,
hi. Oh, hi again. A common, that was boy.
Oh, okay. I can't wait for TG
jeans. Did you use a lot of fun?
We're gonna to make a feast.
I've decided to cook full
American thanksgiving because
we haven't done it and
ears. Just as we wrap up, weight
loss talk, you're like, yeah,
I'm going to make a fucking feast.
Ummah.
I got us a smoked Turkey from honeybaked
ham and I got us a honey baked ham and
then I'm going to do green bean casserole.
Sweet potatoes. Yup. I'm going to do,
I'll do Mac and cheese. A
omics, omics, Pumpkin Pie.
One day you can fall off the
wagon for one day. Yeah. You know,
but you know what the funny thing is the
leftovers. I'll just give them to Sarah.
She's coming over.
The funny thing about when you start
eating healthy or like sticking to
something you like,
don't even really want no to that stuff.
It's a total bummer. Yeah. What
do you look at for motivation?
I'm mixed flow. I live in North
Carolina and I'm aware of model
meet Nikki,
otherwise known as ms flow.
I think the name is flo cause I
thought it was killed and I flat fee.
How would you what? What do
you, her asshole smells like
it is never clean. Yeah,
she weighs 700 pounds.
She's a big girl.
I Dunno if it's seven, but I
mean it's, it's definitely,
it's definitely gotta
be like close to five.
I'm thinking it's Manwell your rebate.
It's really bad.
She looks like she's the couch.
She's kind of, Oh my God.
How much to go down on ms fluff.
Oh, okay. Here's what'd you read it?
You got to either,
would you rather French or
mom or go down on ms fluff.
I mean go down on ms fluff,
but it's not going to be nice.
Now way her legs are glued.
There's like she's got that fat person
thing where she gets lesions from where
the fat lives together.
It's really bad.
I mean this is no way to live. This is
not, no, no, that's not, that's not,
she's not like overweight or fat.
You know, this is life threatening.
This is this belt. Wait, I
mean this is like, of course,
you know a doctor would be like, we
need to hospitalize you. Of course.
Know something is mentally wrong with
this person. She's like, I'm a web model.
I'll carry it there.
You've got a lesion and salt.
I don't believe, by the way,
I don't believe that she believes she's
doing. I believe that she does the cell.
You know she can sell it, but
no, she knows she's a disaster.
She's turning the negative into a
positive, but I don't buy it either.
I just love myself like,
no you don't.
There's no way you can be into
being that fat. No way dude.
Do with people like jerk off to
this like do. She has a pay site.
People are paying.
It's so great.
Is there a site where I could
sell my soggy mom tits and my,
my destroyed mom body.
Is there a,
is there a ha a soggy mom body site,
post partum bodies. Come on. No, I
am. My tits are fucking destroyed.
Yes they are. Why are you lying? You're
making it sound like you're miss fluff.
I am. This fluff. You're
not. Okay. Let's go on.
Jesus.
Fuck my ass and I want my age.
My body is my arm up.
You see how my fingers can
actually get loud and, oh
wow.
It looks like dough.
She was like the Michelin man
but fatter her arms or the sand.
Like it just kinda goes through it.
Yeah, totally. Totally not good.
She likes her ass. She wants
it to go bigger. Yeah. Far,
far
less fluff uses has super
sized soft body to make cold
hard cash is 1599 for 30 days
subscription and you know,
you could see the pictures, videos
and all, all that good stuff.
But I have had was to do a fart in BDO.
This is the one fan told me,
he was like,
I'll pay you $5 a fart and
I need response on them.
So he said, I will give you $100 if
you could just make a couple farts.
Ought to be. I was like, you know
what, that's not really my thing.
This is good. This bitch has
it all figured out. Here we
are working for a living.
He's got a Fart in a Web Clark
far.
I can't believe how dare she.
She did it.
She can't turn down $100 for a couple
of farts. Come on man. I would do that.
Ooh.
$400 for a couple of
farts. Would I do it? Yeah,
you. Of course I would do it. We do
them for free on this shit. Yeah.
I tried to Fart on Mike all the time.
I had a big fart before we were rolling.
We got to get those fart mix. Yeah.
Get the card, making them out of it.
Making sure the nanny's not
texting us. Maybe we'll do, um,
I think we should do a show
where we have some meal before.
It'll create a lot of parts. I
just made some Chili, I feel like,
but you got to time it right. There was
that Peruvian joint on the east side,
Don Felix, where we had
Lomo site though. Yeah.
And it would give me so many farts.
Interesting.
I've never heard you say that before.
Why?
Why is something about it was like there
was some type of oiliness to the way
that they made it there where whenever
I ate it for dinner the next morning I'd
be in bed like mom prom.
So maybe we need to have that one day
and Brussel sprouts make me Fart a lot.
Oh yeah,
that'll do it.
Collywobbles but it's a timing issue
because for me it takes a few hours.
Well that's the thing is we're going to
have to really work on this, you know?
But that's what scientists do. I
mean, you know, trial and error,
it keep trying to get it right.
Did I get it wrong? Right.
It's important for the listeners,
for sure.
For a
damn. She is so fucking, she's
an enormous person. Jesus Christ.
Normous good.
Laura.
She's a made good money
because you can show,
right or you can charge on one thing
is they will put it on your website.
So it would be like double that they,
but when I do special quizzes videos,
I don't really put it on my website.
I kind of let it be like you're a private
gifts to you. You know what I mean?
Do you think she's going to marry
her mom soon? She talks about,
was it just like the gays? She's
about as bright as the, uh,
the mom and son team that open mouth
like you good judge and she was out of
breath right there. I know. She's
just sitting there putting on a show.
This poor woman. I actually, I mean
she needs to go to the hospital.
She needs a surgery.
Yes.
Why do you think people like to see you
trying on clothes that are too small?
What does it do?
Mix the losing of me.
Maybe even more enormous that I am.
I like it too though.
I like to hear the sound,
ah,
putting
shirt.
Now the question is how am I going to,
uh,
but the point is
what kind of Gig?
The incredible hall.
What kind of Gig could she have?
Like, you know what I'm saying? No.
Just making the best of her
horrific situation. Like if she,
she can't really work in an
office because, you know,
yeah. But she should, I mean,
I get it, but she needs to work
on staying alive. You know,
she's past the point of like, ah, uh,
if if she were a couple hundred
pounds less, yeah. Doing
this site, I'd be like, oh,
okay. I get, but right now, like she
looks like she's going to die. Yeah.
She's killing herself with food.
Yeah. He's just not a good thing.
I'm a food whore. I like
expensive, nice phone.
See Food and it's this band cause I don't,
oh my God,
she's eating,
she's eating a watermelon and
she's topless in bed. Yeah.
She's eating a water man.
You don't see that all the time,
but everybody likes food. You just
have to be like, hey, I can't eat.
Part of the illusion though, when you're
fat, but the denial is you go like, oh,
I like food. I like it
so much. It's my thing.
The reason other people aren't like this,
right.
They don't like it as much as I
do. Right, right. You just, yeah.
You know what I noticed with being
on this diet thing is that I would,
I would make food a prize for
something, like a reward. Like, oh,
I had such a bad day, but I'm going
to reward myself with cookies.
Or like the reward can't be food.
Right.
It can't be the emotional
outlet. Like I'm, I'm lonely.
I'm just going to eat something.
And that's totally what I did. Yeah.
The other thing is like the
mindfulness, you know, of going,
of reaching for food.
But if you stop and you go,
am I eating this cause I'm hungry,
right.
Or am I eating this because I'm just
trying to like, uh, Phil, you know,
fill this a moment of feeling
nervousness or anxiety,
you know, instead of smoking a cigarette,
I'm going to, yeah, yeah. This thing,
wherever he is, smoker, quits,
gains weight always. Some
of them gained incredible.
Yeah. But I've seen people put on
50, 60 pounds. 80 pounds. Yeah.
And you can see it how,
I'm sorry,
I was just drinking water because
I'm the champion. Yeah, you can.
Where's your water? I'm interested
in the cameras aren't rolling. Yeah,
but where's your water?
I'm just curious.
What are you talking about and let them
right here. Let me hear you take us up.
Oh, you're such a faker. You're drinking
your imaginary water. No drinking water.
I have water right here. Okay. Um,
I forgot, even when I was saying,
I don't fucking know. The point is it's,
it can't be an emotional thing. No,
that's a problem. Yeah. As with anything,
it's hard not to have addictions,
alcohol, cigarettes, food. It's
just an easy thing, you know? Yeah.
It's, it's tough. It is tough.
It's hard to be a vice free sober,
essentially. I mean, and you know, and
I, yeah, cause food is, is uh, isn't it?
Addiction thing. Everything.
Yeah. Sex, gambling,
alive fruit. Shake it
for me. I think I eat,
she can't lie.
You don't know how much I eat.
Do you eat fried chicken
from a seeking something?
Just fried one pool. She, if she
just had like chicken breasts,
she would not be this fat.
Yeah. No, of course not. No.
She's eating like the buckets, you
know what I'm saying? Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
Oh
yeah. Oh No. And I was like,
would you ever day your mom? Hmm?
He's like, yeah, I will do my mom. Oh,
Tom, let's do the scene.
Okay. I'll be your mom. Okay.
So like would you ever
consider dating or mom?
And I was like, uh, yeah.
I mean I liked her and I was like,
do you like me to, yeah. Uh,
sometimes I call you like
my son or one of Quito,
but not all the time
because you're my son.
I wanted to make sexes with you
and like I made the first move.
Uh, I was like, what's up? And she
was like, hey. And I gave her a kiss.
It was like a real case, but it was
like a real kiss. Huh. But it's like,
what's the big deal? I mean,
just like the gays, you know,
over 18 is like oil.
It's a big deal.
You know, it's a big deal. I love
my mom cause they were okay. It was,
it was it just like the gays for um,
a lot of good drops on today's. Yeah.
Some good stuff in here. Far and far,
eh, so we got an email here, dad accents.
Hi,
Mommy's in episode three 69,
master of accents and water. Mommy. Tommy
talked about how top dog would speak to
Peruvian family members in English the
same way they would speak English.
I thought you might find
it interesting that my dad,
a white CIS gender man does exactly
the same thing with Asian people.
My Dad makes toys for a living,
so growing up he was in China a lot and
he's traveled to many Asian countries as
well as many other parts of the world.
You would think a well traveled mommy
such as himself would be respectful of the
cultures and dialects. He
as it was exposed to, well
within the last few years,
he started doing this really neat
thing or he speaks to Asian people at
restaurants with broken English,
things like this. Good right?
Or food comes soon.
He's also gone as far as to ask
people in a Korean restaurant,
what part China you from?
It warms my jeans to hear that the
legendary top dog does the same thing and
that our dads have something
really neat and common.
Hope you want me to have a stress remove?
I'll see Tom on December 30th mom,
Lando,
Bo through that is so fucking
funny. I like that. It's so amazing.
The Broken, oh my God. It's
such a fucking dad move.
And he does. My Dad does it
like, it's so embarrassing.
And he's like, what? Why neato neato
because he doesn't do, he can't,
he can't do any like correct
Spanish like Juanito today.
And you enjoy the very nice no,
the museum. No. And they're
like, see, I had a good time.
Yes.
Tomorrow maybe you'd like,
we go a very good place to
eat. And they're like, okay.
Do like,
why are you talking to him retarded?
Because that doesn't help him learn
English better. Oh, this good. Right.
Food comes soon.
That is fucking such a dad.
Um, mazing God damn boy,
I got to fucking figure out a way
to incorporate this in a more,
it's so fucking funny.
I love that he does that.
I really love it.
I wish we could get a recording
of your dad doing this to someone.
Does he do it in restaurants to
your dad? Oh yeah. No. But if,
if anyone, if there's another
culture, especially Latin,
I think it's like he's saying his dad
spends a lot of times and a lot of time in
Asian countries,
it's the,
it's the foreign culture you're most
associate comfortable with that you do it
to the most. So my dad would do it
probably two more Spanish speaking people.
Right? So if someone
was Spanish, he would,
he would start speaking retarded English
stuff that a Spanish version would
speak and this guy does it to Asian
people, which is just outstanding.
These good, right. These
are good. Will come soon.
Oh, I can imagine too that
those people are always like,
why is that guys speaking?
Talking day that I imagine my cousins
too would probably like of everyone I
spoke to today, only he talked
to me about that person. Yeah,
because I never ever was like,
you like school fun today? No.
Oh my God. Now you slow it
down for a foreigner. Right.
You know, you speak
slowly. I'm a listener.
Wrote this and hey Tom,
wake up.
Dan Pena is trying to bang your wife.
No, please. This is textbook billionaire.
Evil Villain behavior.
Penny is trying to get Christina all up
and Guthrie Castle and added those genes.
Keep your enemies close and your
genes closer and best of luck,
a concerned fan of the show.
Joshua.
Thank you very much. Um, I wouldn't worry.
I think Dan's got a wife
that he's really into.
I don't think he needs to squeeze on
my tits. You know what I mean? Um,
well thanks to the unexpected.
A hundred or so episodes that
you guys put out all at once.
I decided to go back and listen to
some classics and a recent Mama.
So Tina claimed to have a story where
she went to the dentist and they told her
she had 15 cavities.
So she went to another dentist where
they told her that she had none bonds.
Looking baffled was like,
hmm. Yeah, that's my story.
Well thanks to some free time.
I listened to episode 78
with Bill Burr and tamp.
Tom told the exact same story and not a
peep from Tina should have spoken up at
that time. I don't know. Liar. Hedo eight.
See something. Say something, Derek.
Because I remember when bill was in our
home that was back in silver lake and
that's before that happened to me. Okay.
All right. Yeah. Well, you know, just,
just know that the listeners are
paying attention. Okay. Okay.
I know that they are paying attention.
They are, they are dotting their I's.
They are crossing their t's.
It's just like the gays. Okay.
So you can't get away
with anything. They, they,
they keep us both in check and I know,
and I know they, they're very vigilant.
They are. I like that. Yeah. But
just say, just for the record,
it hadn't happened yet.
Does a long time ago at the bill bill
burr was in our house. That's true.
That was a long time
ago. Yeah. Um, barber,
that was one of the early
Wilford. There's an early, early,
um, um, let's see here, Tom. Uh,
here's a weight loss email, dear Tom,
number one, champ forever. And Christina,
number two water champ forever
for your back. Your birth,
your bet with Bernd is an easy
win for you money, the bank,
you know what I'm saying?
You were,
Christina had stated
getting an unbiased scale,
but I urge you to get your pal Joe Rogan
to help you with the way and it will be
the only way. Hello. Officially way in
by a true professional. Keep chugging.
Mommy's just watched a few minutes
of Burt on Rogan's election podcasts.
They had to put Burt at the kids
table and made him sit by himself. He,
he is not to 40.
He has over twice the weight of belieber
and Grapefruit Simmons combined,
I think bird his at least to 70 with an
added 20 pounds a box wine and holiday
weight. Well, there you go. Of course. Oh,
everybody knows he's way
fatter than you Tom. Yeah.
This is going to be easy
peasy. Yup. Um, genes.
There's a, a new accent, master
of accidents to break down. Okay.
Are you interested? Yeah. I
feel like you're not really
the master though lately.
Wow. Just saying, I don't
feel like you're really there.
I don't know. Let's see.
That's really hurtful.
It's really hurtful.
Why would you say something like this?
So I'd lately it's like you've
been slipping. Really? Yeah. Okay.
Let's see here. If I have
this [inaudible] du, Du,
Du, Du, Du, Du, Du, Du,
Du master of these genes.
Are you,
do you still have these?
I remember these jeans that you're
wearing in that photo. I might, I might.
I Dunno.
I don't like him anymore.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Tom Segura,
master of accidents.
Here you go.
Hi y'all. I'm old man.
Hey ran five you out that I got hope.
The vocal fold eight wellness checkup
bro. Wow. Well graphic though.
Yup, I got most of that. Did you? Yeah.
Well cause you lived in raw mead. I
did. I don't know anything about it.
So, hi y'all. I'm old.
Alright man. Hey, I ran five
[inaudible]. I got hope,
the vocal fold eight willys pickup truck.
So he said,
hey y'all,
I'm whatever his name is down here and
some part of Louise Farview Louisiana.
Before I leave I got ahold of uh,
what's his name is 48 pickup truck.
I'm sorry,
I take it all back.
Yeah.
Where are the
most that had five you out blew that hope.
The vocal fold. Eight
wellness pickup fro. Yes.
Real drive pickup truck.
He believed this guy speaks our language
and he's American. Look at him. Jesus.
How would you describe him to hot?
What do you think his buttholes smells
like? Hideous. He's filthy too. Yeah.
Golf. I'm, I ain't go
with state prison. How?
Paring it back pull out in the fire.
So, uh, it came from
Angola state prison. Oh,
you've got a transcript there.
I know you do look.
Well, I log after looking
in tanker and then male
Khafre motor home.
So he got it from Angola state
prison. Um, he's got a bed on it.
They used to haul like printers and
shit around on it and now he's going to
modify it to make it into a camper for
himself. How did you understand that?
Does this from spending time
in the south in college?
Maybe there were some guys
there that I didn't understand,
but I also live with my now how?
My first roommate? Yeah, hold on.
Anyway, that's, so I've never lived
with someone that spoke like this.
I ain't go with Bruce.
Had a facial or bed bath.
How apparent her back and forth
hauled printers back in the field?
No hold something else, pat,
because he talking about, I love his
beer. Cozy. That's a real trash thing too.
You've got the Cammo tee shirt. Yeah. You
gotta keep your can of beer in a cozy,
God dammit. God dammit. And he's mine.
While I got BJ porter told
me the funniest thing, uh,
the writer Bj Porter's on me, that
his wife has it. She's also a writer.
Uh, when like when people were
like fashionable cammo she'll go,
thank you for your service.
That's really funny.
He said he was at some like elite
Hollywood party. There was like,
had a cammo jacket on boy.
And she just looked real serious and
want to thank you for your service.
And then you'd walk by and they were like,
Eh,
located in tag her name. Thank
[inaudible] Mike Mail. Oh,
motor home.
Correct. Jesus Christ. You know,
I don't know. I feel like I should be
able to choose who gets to live you. Yeah.
Like number one od. There should
be, okay, here's the thing. Yeah.
I think there should be a basic
Iq test for living for life. Yeah.
And if you fail,
you're just not on the planet or you just,
we send you somewhere else. Yeah. I
don't know where. Maybe you cut Alaska.
It doesn't make the cut. This guy, he does
not make the cut. We ship them to some,
like the Arctic. Arctic Tundra. Yeah,
in Alaska somewhere really hard to live
and if he can survive, he gets to live,
but I don't do, you don't just
get to live and being this dumb.
Same with the incest. Yeah. Couple.
I think we give them an Iq test
shift from ship them off town.
They would fail without question.
This guy might pass.
You don't know if he built a truck and
made it into can't. I mean you never know.
Yeah,
but I don't know.
Pto blanked on the phone. Bam, Bam,
Bam stuff.
Yeah. Yeah, that's true. That's
true. I take, I take a mile.
Oh Man. He didn't look good
and great. That's why I call
it my tractor motor home.
I go,
he called this an ingredient though.
Here's what I think what you just said.
Here's a good ingredient as this
is my tractor motor home. He said,
but here's a good ingredient.
Oh boy.
Oh boy. Oh Man. He has a good
and great athletic called, right,
right, right, right. I mean
is that an ingredient, bro?
There's a good ingredient.
Nah, man. He has a good and great, I
call him my track or motor home track.
I got hunger. That's factory willing to
quick. You got a gear box on the back.
You bulla would flutter.
What was that was splitter pretty much
anything ADN forward truck you gotta give
back.
What was,
how were pretty much anything?
Hey, Dan Ford tractor.
Okay. Wow. Do you think of
Ford tractor can do an 80
something, right? First of all,
if you're listening to this and you don't
live in the United States, you got to,
you have your mind blown
right now. Yeah. I'm sorry.
Can I just apologize cause we pay it.
We play that fucking whatever,
Irish,
Gypsies and Shit and we're like,
what the fuck is that? Right, right.
This is just our version of this is our,
these are our Gypsies are soccer hooligan.
Gypsies are fucking enrollment of people.
Oh God.
Jesus Christ.
This factory where these
equipment you Bulla,
would you build a wood splitter out?
Pretty much anything.
Hey, Dan Ford tractor.
Anything a Ford tractor can
80 m four tracking. Ut Ut
yeah, he's got dogs, right?
Cows running around and go,
go low.
You Soda Water or soda water,
right. Neck, right.
Jesus. Fucking Christ. Not
a smart way of sounding.
Yeah,
I mean there's not sound smart
washing my cat. He does. Hey
Mudcat, your hands and brush
your teeth. Now. You know God.
Had you been good at? And the
gray. So lean. Yeah. If it moves.
How if this week,
wow, so he's got like a makeshift.
It's as true. It says RV.
Yes. This is, this is
traveling. Showery yeah. Wow.
That dude is special man.
Can I tell you? I have,
I'm not convinced that making
stuff is necessarily the,
the money saver, you know what I
mean? And then it's time and energy.
It took that guy to piece together.
The RFE so happy with it though.
Just by knowing happier
than him. Yes, sir.
Is just glass and that glass,
glass, glass and glass and guys,
the happiest man on the planet.
Um,
that guy's so stoked.
He's so happy to be alive.
I'm just just groups coming
through. Glass, glass, glass,
glass.
It was salt the Moose
that got it. See that's the sound of
joy. That's, that is glee. But this guy,
he gets class and sometimes he gets glass.
It's glass.
Just this guy's pretty happy too.
I forgot about that.
Yeah, I was pretty happy.
Go really bad by bad bite.
Um, so you're making us sound
bad and you're like, oh,
these Brits got it all figured out.
What about this shit right here? Okay.
Okay.
Pops.
We've had a bit of a rest
time now for some training.
What's involved in pop place?
At first seems really simple because
most people think you're just getting on
all fours, waddling around and
going more for, for the buck buck.
But it's really so much more complicated.
So there are people that are
wearing puppy or dog zip,
like leather zip ups,
like s and m dog masks and they're
on their hands and knees. Yeah.
This guy had them in a cage.
You had him in a crate now and he's
describing that it's not just about, yeah,
that you know, I gotta tell Ya. He
didn't sound like he was from Louisiana.
Did Christina? He's
definitely a UK. I just,
I don't you feel like this shit,
like how much fucking free time?
How do these people have time to
dress up in latex dog costumes?
I barely have time to fucking
take a shower every day.
You know what I'm saying?
These assholes have time to for fucking
puppy play. Getting their dicks hard and,
and latex dog costume.
Really don't have time to do anything.
Like fuck has time for this shit.
Yeah.
That's an addiction I guess in the
way I feel it was in Baltimore.
I feel I have to look to what,
Oh my God.
It's kind of like being
part of a secret club.
Take the past time involved the whole,
Oh boy.
He knows something else going on here.
You know. So many ladies are in the room
zero. Whenever it gets real
weird. It's only, it's only,
only browse
and they, they're dressed up in the
dog. They in there smelling each other.
And why howling?
It's just like the gays
and there's a fuck swing hanging.
Yeah. And they're in there.
Yeah. They're leather dog outfit.
I liked that they had to do the math.
The interview with the mask on. Right.
It's not just about a Isabelle.
You think you could take
the mask off for that dude
in my guys, I work as a doc.
Doctor. GP is a really, really busy,
it's tiring. It's exhausting. So
he doesn't have time for this.
Having the outlet off
pup play gives me,
oh recreation,
you gotta be fucking Shit that we all
have animalistic passions as humans.
We are sexual adults and my animal
just happens to be a bit more German
shepherd.
This is insane.
This is a general physician.
I know it's usually professional people
that have high stress jobs that like s
and m in this stuff, but how so?
How are they fucking each other?
Cause they're in full body latex costumes
and they did they unzip their dicks
and then fuck each other's butts? I
don't know how this works. I don't know.
I really don't know.
Uh, what draws me to human pup play
is I like the gear. I like the,
the lifestyle of it all just makes
me feel like I am 10 foot tall and
bulletproof. No, he's mechanic.
Just physical. There is emotion.
Having a,
hold on,
I get to go to my secret persona where
I have no human inhibitions that suits
reframe.
Yeah.
It's so alarming to me.
This is like more bothersome
than the woman marrying her
son. No, that's not true.
Well, it's just like the way they talk
about it, it was like, it makes my,
it makes my ass, I'll put
her to, yeah. The thing is,
is like I envy that these people are so
in touch with their feelings that they
can find something like,
I am so shut off from how I feel
that I could never be like, you know,
what secret are you? Are you
that shut off? And I just
want to be a dog and latex.
No, but I'm saying that I'm so shut
off. Like I might love this. Oh, right.
Because of who I am. I'm so quick to
be like, fuck you, you fucking asshole.
Oh right. But I wouldn't even be
open emotionally cause he's right.
Like think about it.
The argument is during the day,
I'm this helpless car mechanic,
but when I put on my puppy play costume,
I get to be a dog with
no human inhibition.
So it's his channel of freedom.
Yeah.
But I'm so fucking uptight and
judgmental. I could never get there. Sure.
I could never get there.
Mahjong wouldn't say it's a specific breed
as such terms of the personality that
it has.
It's a very loyal to see these people.
This is something I'm a little
bit of social anxiety. I see.
Wearing the popcorn's
allows a bit of anonymity,
so it means that I can interact with
people and not be so concerned as to what
they're thinking of me.
Uh Huh.
Okay.
I didn't go into human pup
play for the six part of it.
The cell phone and things. Oh, I've
had sex with anyone in puffier.
It doesn't just involve men. I've met
female pups. Yeah. Not many hands on.
You didn't entirely. I'm still
not in this video. Are there,
let me see any lady outside of
the human pup play community.
There's not too many people that
know that I'm here. I'm pub. Yeah,
I want to keep it that way. Exactly.
Yeah. Okay. Puffs come present.
God Rice. This guy come present
dripping out of his nose.
We've gathered the pups here
today for training today. Skills.
So Park Hills show me a kneel position.
Oh Wow. That's like obedience school.
Yeah. I couldn't get into this.
I mean they'll just give them a
treat. Some cute. I'm doing it.
Hey pulls his dick out right there you go.
Hey you go pups.
Well that's what we do
with our dog. Yeah. God.
Yeah. When he sent that he's sicker. No,
that belongs to somebody in the room.
We'll don't pop. See you
knew it was mine. Well Doug,
thank you book
cause you don't even get to pet them like
at night because they're wearing that
latex shit. Yeah. I don't understand
why they're not wearing fur. Yeah,
that would make sense to me and less
creepy law school. What makes it really,
any other trainers, there wasn't. What
makes it creepy is the fetish, the latex.
And he's like,
we don't fuck each other.
Well then what's the point of wearing
fetish stuff? If you're not getting laid,
it's fetishy but not shit's weird guys.
Shit is weird.
It's just like the gaze. This
guy does this body type. Yeah.
This, it's, it is a very English
thing. Sorry. English listeners. Yeah.
It's the male physique of I've
never exercised once in my life.
I've never lifted away a day in my life.
I mean,
there's obviously some Brits that do.
Yeah,
but I'm saying this particular mush
brand of male, it can be American too.
I shouldn't just single English.
Sure. The guy who's like never ever,
ever lifted a weight. Yeah. That's, yeah.
Yeah. We got to go, man. This computer's
about to die and I don't have, yes, it is.
The things that I don't have
is, uh, a charger in here.
Oh God.
Charge your mom
guys. It's thanksgiving. So
thank you for, thank you.
But say it in the master of fixe
give Thanksgiving and Marika.
Oh, that's right. If
they don't anywhere else.
Canadian thanksgiving is.
That's right. His last week.
Thank you guys for listening.
This is our first episode in the
New House and the new studio.
We really hope to have a Mardi gras.
We hope to have a lot more up and ready
to go and have our cameras back next
week. And, um, I don't know. We love you.
Thanks for listening to the show. Uh,
go to your mom's house podcast. Oh my
God, I forgot this. Tell them this.
There's a huge sale on the
merge page. Uh, it's, it's,
it's going to be black
Friday and cyber Monday.
Big Sale on all your
mom's house and merge.
So if you're,
uh,
looking to shop like a lot of people
are during this time this week,
go to your mom's house,
podcast that podcast.com or go to
Thomson grow.com thousand ranch.com.
Click on the store takes you all the
same place, big sale this Friday,
and of course,
cyber Monday.
Thanks again for listening.
We will see you in a week by genes.
Mommy. Oh, it's my favorite jam.
Oh,
oh,
oh
yeah.
Yeah.
[inaudible]
that's
not bad. Not Bad at all. Not Bad at all.