Well. Well, well go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Hi Thomas.
Sigora we'll be
at the Richmond funny bone one night
only July 11th there's two shows.
First show is sold out.
A few tickets left for the second show.
That's in short pump. That's
right. Good memory. Yeah.
There's a gas station there.
Virginia Beach next night is sold out.
Greens blow whores, North
Carolina. Hi, good one.
There's a few tickets left at the
cone Denim Entertainment Center. Good.
That's July 13th Asheville is
sold out North Carolina Asheville.
Right,
and then Charles has come South Carolina
at the Charleston Guy Yard Center.
July 15th I say it or is it
Gaylord? I think. Ah, yeah.
Gaylord Guy Yard. Yeah, he's
supposedly got yard guard.
Gay Cards.
Let me tell you something.
There's enough tickets for you and
a whole bunch of people. Oh dear.
What's going on in Charleston? Like can't
you come out? What? What? What's going on?
Is there another game or
something? I no, that's the only,
that's my only like tour date that I'm
like, whoa. But that's how it goes.
That's how it goes. Jean Charles
[inaudible]. Charles [inaudible].
Can I have my water back please? Sure.
A Montreal after that. Hampton beach,
Wilmington, Delaware and balls and
horrors, Maryland. Soon thereafter,
I go to mum's Australia. I love
Australia. It's been years.
I've never been to Brisbane. I
love Brisbane. I'm going to Sydney.
I've been to Melbourne,
Melbourne,
but I've never been to Perth and going
there too. I've never been to Perth.
So it's on the whole other side of that
country, man. You're going all the way.
Crawling all over. We're going to
Sydney first and then Perth. Yeah. Okay.
And I'm bringing the full charge with
me. Oh my gosh. You guys have to see him.
All the moms. Trillions is going to
be really fun. That's giving you,
you're gonna have so much
fun with a full charge. Yeah.
I think he is such a great companion
to have around. He makes me laugh.
I had him at the punchline.
Yeah, I laughed the whole
time. He's fun guy. He's a,
he's a super fun guy. Super Fun. And
then I have an entire fall schedule.
It's all at [inaudible] dot
com please go check it out.
I'm hitting a bunch of cities.
Many of the ones I've been hit
up about Denver, Toronto, um,
you know, I'm going back to Michigan
and we're going to be in Ohio.
All those places are on sale.
Please go to [inaudible] dot com check on,
uh,
check those dates and that's it.
That's all you got to.
You got to tell you got to do gene.
Okay.
I only have one club date coming up
on kind of taking a minute to catch my
breath because you shot a special
need a minute before I start
planning my life again. Uh,
but I'm doing September 22nd and
23rd and St Jewess Saint Judas,
is that what it's called? True tits.
St Jude tits, Missouri, Missouri,
Missouri.
Mom's very at hearing helium
comedy club. The here, here,
I'm comedy can't prop. Wow.
What? I just didn't expect it.
You didn't expect that from me.
It's offensive.
It's just offensive.
You haven't even asked me
what my pronoun is today.
How can you say that I'm being offensive
when you don't even ask me what my
pronoun,
it's changed already today.
What is your Pronoun Zay say?
Hmm?
Actually, I prefer to be called Juror
Majesty to Your Majesty's. Great.
What's Your Pronoun?
It's silly.
So immature. Wait, what's Your
Pronoun Rob? Rob. Rob. My,
my pronoun is fear.
Fear,
fear.
I feel like the Pronoun is taking the
place of which bracks and you feel like,
oh yeah, it is. What is your
Pronoun is? What is your,
what's in the racks then rob,
rob, man, he is really
entered our hearts and minds.
I love that guy. You love him.
I don't, I absolutely love him.
What do you love most about him?
It's just so authentic.
It's the dedication to it. He's
100% dedicated. Yeah. Yeah.
He's not making that up. He's just that
disgusting. Yeah. It's just, it's perfect.
Rob. Rob, I go retarded.
Um,
I'd go retarded is also my favorite
new drop. That's what you got.
Oh, well I'm doing the comedy
store most Saturdays, most likely.
And this is not 100%.
I usually do the early show in the,
or I liked doing that seven 30.
Oh our show. I just love it.
It's where all the civilized people go
out. Like, you know what I'm saying?
Like you got shit to do and you don't
get no lunatics and midnight hour
respectable people.
I just occurred to me.
And please remember when you're in
mom's Trillia to pick me up some ketchup
flavored Doritos. When I was asked
me this last time, my favorite,
but I remember I couldn't
find that they were,
they weren't there anymore last time.
Serious when I went in 2011 yeah.
It's like a,
it must've just been a one time only.
I think it's just outdated though.
I mean I've been thinking about that shit
for 20 years. I know. Please catch up.
[inaudible] all right.
And what about Cadbury?
Will you bring me back some Cadbury stuff?
I do love what that seven seeds coffee.
That's what I want to get.
That was really good stuff. Yeah, that's
really, yeah. Yeah. Will you bring home?
Well they let you, I mean with um,
customs and all that shit. I don't know.
I wonder, you know how strict they are
with bringing any kind of food items.
We'll have to find out. Fuckers.
Let's get this show started
and when I woke up
she had both of my legs over his shoulders
and I'm sure it was numb sucking my
asshole like there no tomorrow.
Don't bring it in one loving.
Well No,
no.
Go to your mom's house,
Christina.
Yeah,
turn the air on because it's
hot in here. One, two, three,
four. Heat generating light showbiz.
It's w so they put the air on.
I'm already, I'm so cold.
I'm wearing a jacket already.
And then now your turn it down.
[inaudible] the best part about sleeping
downstairs on the pullout couch bed.
Yeah.
And Not Saatva mattress.
The only highlight is that
there's no ac vent in that room.
I know, and I, it's so warm and
delightful and I don't have to,
do you know that I sleep with a down
comforter every night fully up around my
neck because it's cool that you can
call my nose is cold. All that claim,
you have problems, you have
body problems. Serious.
Well, how cold is it when I,
when I'm saying this, what
do you think in the room?
72 that's freezing and what's not?
I hate it.
And you wake up and you tell me
I saw you on top of the sheets.
Yeah, because it's not
cold. I want it freezes.
I do that as a courtesy. You know
what? The only time I enjoyed,
we enjoyed the same temperature was
when I was pregnant with Ellis. Yeah.
That was like you were hot too.
Cause it was hot all the time.
It's the only time in my life. Well
misery, if you haven't yet figured it out.
We've, we have found, uh,
the male equivalent to,
to Danny.
I hadn't figured that out yet,
actually.
I don't know what's going on with
this guy, but he's got a lot,
not to say it doesn't blink my name.
You do copious amounts
of cocaine with her.
So the point I thought my
heart was going to stop,
she told me to calm down,
gave me a drink.
Okay.
And I don't know it was in the drink,
but I blacked out. And when I woke up,
she had both of my legs over
her shoulders. She was numb,
sucking my asshole.
There was no tomorrow.
What's numb? Psyching, making
it now. Really going at it.
I tried to find it. I tried to
get away, but I was restrained.
She told me that I liked it.
She told me not to worry because she
used the good jelly. The schmuck goes,
okay.
I like schmuck.
Nobody's paid me to confess this now.
And I've kept it under wraps for all
these years because I knew that no one
would believe me. No, no one really
believe that Hillary Clinton eight.
My asshole.
Wow. Shocking him. Shocking revelation.
I mean, I'm surprised Hillary hasn't. Uh,
Hillary responded eight
Ryan sticklers asshole.
It does.
Except Ryan hasn't go to believe
that Hillary Clinton name my asshole.
A crab feast suite at Ryan sickler.
Did Hillary Clinton
really eat your asshole?
Fuck the crab feast.
Now here's how you know someone's crazy.
We put his image back up.
Well,
nobody's paid me to confess test.
Oh my God.
You can always tell crazy by the darkness
of the beard proportionate to one's
age. Oh yeah. He definitely nice and
easy. That one. I think so. Yeah.
It's not really in focus though.
It might be a little grayer than we think.
Remember they got in our old neighborhood
that used to take a permanent,
like a sharpie and Showbie
his we are not real crazy.
That's in the Rampart division.
I drove through there years later
and I saw him look good for him.
What's he up to? Just keep holding
the block down and doing what he does.
He used to be on the corner where the
Carl's Jr was any of that bench and he was
just sitting there all the time.
It'd be south of six right
often be south of six.
Yeah. Wherever that Carlos is.
Mm. That was a really good,
Carl's junior by the way.
Yeah, I'm really good. Um,
wow. I don't worry Clinton, my asshole.
I'm surprised she hasn't
responded. Really. That's a
huge alligator for a minute.
I mean, she's still getting
over this election, you know,
she's still figuring it out.
Yeah. Both of my legs
over her shoulders. Huh?
I wish I could.
I hope I can testify to the same
thing one day with hills with you.
Oh,
well we all know that's going to happen.
She had both of my legs over
her shoulders. Yana, yeah.
What would you, would you have Hillary
do this to you? Let's say I can't, okay.
I give you permission. Can Hillary
do this to you? Yeah, of course.
You wouldn't mind. Why would I mind?
She's a little bossy. That's fine. Yeah.
Yeah. I'm sure it wouldn't be that fun,
but I mean I would still do it. Yeah.
I think I would just do it for the story.
I think hills would be fine with it.
For you and are any idea
what kind of story that is?
I can't believe it happened.
I know.
I mean this guy's telling him through
his youtube channel, but yeah,
it must have happened before
she was married to bill.
I don't think that's what he's saying.
Oh, you think this is like recent?
Of course. Wow. Recent as in
at least during their marriage.
I don't think it was a 40 year old story.
Wow.
How many youtube videos will
be coming out about what you,
you've been doing on the road,
your road beef stories, road vive.
As the name of my new book
I'm pitching right now.
Road B road beef of life on the road.
You never got road beef.
Now he gives you and I got
together kind of, Hey, what,
what? No, I didn't, we didn't get rid
of beef. I've never gotten road baby.
The closest I came to Rhode beef I guess
is technically road vive was before we
were together.
I did a spot in uh,
orange county. Yeah. Like a bar show.
So it wasn't even a club show
and some girl at the show,
I was like, I dunno, I, I was
not how I normally come on.
I did a fake confidence thing. I was like,
come in here and watch this, you know?
Yeah, yeah. And then we kind
of made out afterwards. Yeah.
This is the first I've heard of it.
Yeah.
And then she got a hotel room and
here's the thing, I was like, oh,
like I'm gonna, you know, I'm going
to shove it in. And then she was like,
oh no,
my friends come and now and then
her friend showed up and uh,
her friend was like looking at me like,
what is going on?
Like it was the nerd friend who
was like, oh, she wasn't like a,
like they weren't going to double team.
You know who's the nerd
friend who was like, Samantha,
who is this guy? Cause he's a comedian.
It was so funny the way she said it too.
Like she said it like he's a fireman.
That's just, you know, it was saving me.
That's why he's here. He's a community.
It was like, uh Huh. Nice to meet you.
And I was like, well nothing happened.
That's it. Yeah. That's good.
I came to root cause we started
dating when I was super young.
You could have like bang,
both of those checks.
No one of them possible if,
if nerd alert hadn't showed up this
shitty friend too bad one time I got
preposition to get in a hot tub.
There is a small club in a small town in
Florida and the owner and his wife had
huge fakers. Yeah. And,
uh, they, they were like,
after the show, they were like,
to me the headliner there.
We know we have a hot tub back at
our place. And uh, and I was like,
oh, really? That sounds terrible. I'm not,
I don't do that. Like I don't want to rob,
Rob, rob. That's when you and
I were engaged. You didn't,
you didn't go to the hot tub?
I'd rather kill myself.
No. Why? I'm just not that
perse. I'm not fun like that.
I have a good personality,
but I'm not the sexuality champ.
That's like the slut champ. Yeah,
that'd be a good story. You'd be like,
so where to find a double team? This
owner and his wife, they're not cute.
Not Cute. I don't know. I'm not
that free. I'm really not that open.
Some nervous. I'd be so weirded out. Like
I guess some people can do that stuff,
obviously. I'm just not that
free. I'm, I'm real closed off.
I'd be so nervous when it you to what?
To do that?
Like I get a hot tub with like a married
couple and then it depends on the
setting. I don't know. Strangers
go. It depends on like the,
in other words I guess if they're
like come over to my house. Yeah,
I'd be nervous if you're staying at a
hotel and there was people around and it's
like, oh yeah, the hot
tub. Okay. Oh right.
Cause then you could just go to your room
and you have a way out. Yeah. It's like,
but like if someone's like, come over,
it was good in the hot tub. Yeah.
I would be nervous. But I think
roofie you and put stuff in your,
but only they want to do that.
But if they did,
do you think your bark will
be less tonight? That I can
sleep in our marital bed.
I think we may have a chance tonight.
Maybe
truth be told, I kind of like
my little ventless. Yeah,
cause you like he, it's hot
here right now. Now it's not.
I want to make it cooler again.
I like the freedom.
I don't have to hear dogs scratching
and you snoring or working.
And it's kind of like my own
little private Idaho. Well,
I'll give a shout out to old wheeler
who, uh, came through last week.
That was great.
Except that my camera wasn't
working and that's a problem.
But that was my fault I think. Yeah.
It wasn't in any of the videos,
so that's probably why you liked it
so much. That episode. That's true.
That's true. It really is warm in here.
Stop Yourself. It's true. It's not.
It's 74. It's freezing. It's
warm. There's lights on. It's hot.
Maybe it's cause you're wearing a long
sleeve tee. It's fine. It's light.
It's just an undershirt.
No. How can men do that?
I was watching that movie last night.
They were like a white tank under a white.
See through. That doesn't look good,
right? Oh my God, I was a a war machine.
Well that doesn't look, but then
all you see is the tank through the,
the white shirt. That doesn't
look good. It looks weird.
But I guess what are your options,
I guess as a man?
Are you done now ruining my life?
I hate when you do this.
It's so cold. When will you
be happy? It feels normal.
You know, we had our closet remodeled,
we didn't even talk about this.
We didn't have a closet for
like three weeks. So hard.
It was hard actually not having
anywhere to put your stuff.
And what we realized is that Tom and
I have nothing. We have no clothes,
we can't even fill it.
And I realized that I only
own lounge pants. Like I have,
like I'm becoming loungy pants and a 40
year old woman mom and all I own is like
comfortable shit.
And then the most comfortable stuff,
we only wear like two or three
things. Yeah, it's fine with me.
I don't mind that either. I dedicated
an entire drawer to just black tops.
I love it.
Just black.
Yeah. I have a lot of the same
tee shirts over and over for,
it's what I like that there's no need
or thought I had more. I have nothing.
I like it that way. No, I don't
want to get overwhelmed with,
cause I'm always trying to
get rid of stuff anyways.
Yeah. We're always decluttering
in this house, sell there. Uh,
so we invited, we've been sick this
week. Of course. The minute. Yeah, we,
I got home from Seattle and the kid
is sick and then we got the cold.
Everybody's sick.
Um,
but you invited cousin Bri Bri over on
Sunday and they have a little one as
well.
And you kind of,
I mean we're on the line of not
contagious anymore, honestly.
But as a, as a parent
courtesy, you kind of take,
you err on the side of
caution and you go like, ah,
maybe we shouldn't let that baby around
our baby who's still got a snotty nose.
But you are like,
screw it and invite him over.
Well, here's the thing. This is our
second time making plans with them.
Yeah. And the, the last time
that we made plans with them,
I canceled like two hours before when
I had that stomach thing going on.
Diarrhea. But that's because
I was taking, I was sick.
I was taking an antibiotic
that gave me diarrhea. Yeah.
And my parents were in town. It
was terrible. So now it's like,
it's the end of a cold.
The boy is much better.
I'm feeling better now.
I was a little Shitty,
but I knew I was on the way out so it
was like I could call him and give him a
warning,
but I know how cautious he is and the
warning he would take too seriously.
So I was like,
I just won't give them a warning and then
maybe when he gets here he'll be like,
oh I get nervous and you like that.
And I thought that'd be funny. Yeah,
to watch them sweat a little bit.
But he didn't at all. He did great.
Yeah, he really was a little excited about
it. I was like, oh maybe he'll be, yeah,
maybe he'll be like extra cautious,
but I think is funny. Yeah, I like,
I like that too when people get
freaked out cause I get freaked out.
I'm like this,
it's like this kind of thing.
Do you think this is
horrible or hilarious?
It's a guy's driving a golf cart
and they went up like over a small,
like a dirt hill. I guess it was
probably a, maybe an eight foot,
10 foot hill and then their
cart flip them off of the front.
I like golf carts and,
and silliness and golf carts.
So I'm going to go for funny.
Yeah. Because they knew
what they were getting into.
They could have gotten really hurt
right there. They could have what?
They've made a choice and they did it
and yeah. They don't look, I don't know.
Yeah. Golf carts. Shit's hilarious to me.
It's so much fun. Golkar really held up.
I thought it would flip or
something. It's just, yeah,
I kind of held up really well this is
like, um, that true TV show I used to do.
Yeah. Where it was, it was
like wild is TV, right? Yeah.
This is all the videos we cover and then
I have to be like the next time the guy
says that you gotta do that.
Like you'd have your dark jokes
from race to write like tons,
tons of jokes for these kinds of
clips. Yeah. Very. The, the, um,
when you watch those
shows in mind numbing,
you could tell which jokes were written
by the producers and which jokes written
by the world's dumbest.
That was the name of the show because
the producers jokes were like pretty sure
the worse, yeah, yeah, yeah. It would feed
to feed us, try to feed us jokes on, um,
the, the other true TV show.
How do we have to be a grown
up? And we'd be like, no,
we never did. I don't want to
say that. You want to say that?
Can you say a version of
that? No, I know I sell that.
They used to give me a sheet of jokes and
there was a couple of writers I really
like their shit and I could tell who
wrote and I'd be like, oh, I like that.
I'll say that, but literally just 20
that I'd be like, pass, pass, pass.
We had a really funny producer once and
we had a really unfunded producer on
that. But yeah, they
would, they would be like,
can you say it without cursing? And I'd be
like, okay, I guess I fucking can. Yeah,
sure. Fuck face and be like, all right.
I remember the guy that
was a bad director for us.
Like he would come in just stone faced,
which you can't do to colleagues.
You can't just be like totally anatomy
did I know? So it doesn't play.
No. So weird. Um,
another observation did I have,
oh, well I'm very observant.
I am the, um, observation
champ. So, uh, as you know,
4th of July. Is that tomorrow? Yeah.
And you and I were just talking about
how we could give zero fucks about 4th of
July and seeing fireworks. No
care. No, I don't care. I can't,
I can't remember the last time
I do photos of them. Right.
I think the photos of the
fireworks are the dumbest July 5th,
when every asshole post pictures of
fireworks. I mean, there's nothing worse.
Like a frame uninspiring of the
before the flare out please.
You like, you just see like five dots.
Right. You know, you're like, oh, in a,
in a moment. This a, a big thing.
His, here's the moment before that.
But it just doesn't translate.
And the glory of live fireworks versus
your tiny little shitty camera picked.
It's like taking a picture of
the moon. Yeah. Look at the moon.
I like it doesn't translate right.
Here's these clouds,
but that doesn't translate.
Clouds are clouds or even
down in the fireworks. Yeah,
I'm seeing fireworks,
but I can't think of a of a thing worse.
Like you have to park,
you go to the,
the local community college or
wherever they're showing the fireworks.
You just sit around with a bunch
of assholes. It's, it's terrible.
I hate when it's a big crowd. I don't
like big crowds. There's nowhere to pee.
Yeah, we're, can I say? Yeah. And then the
other thing is like on a day like that,
you find a place to pee and then it's a,
it's a beverage consumption day. Yeah.
So right away you go back to where
your group is, you're drinking again.
You're like, shit, I gotta go back.
Yeah. That always happens to me.
Oh yeah. Yeah. It's like, that's why
I hate being at places like that.
So do I just cause I want a comfortable
place to pee or Porta potties.
Disgusting.
So then,
and then you need a bracelet to get back
into the thing or wherever. Like ah boy,
get your life. I'm not even doing it.
Concerts. That's way concerts piss me.
Hey concerts too. Even a
sporting event, you know, you
go, it's like drinking beers.
I gotta pee. Where is it? Well you got
to walk up these six flights of stairs,
right? And then you're
what? Oh, you're on. Okay.
So on Terminal One you go left down
and go to l l O it's only a women's.
Oh, sorry. So you go back through,
go to the k gate and there's a restroom
there and you're like Jesus Christ and
do all that. You get your other beverage
and you're like, I gotta pee again.
A nightmare. That sucks. And then
your food options are limited.
It's like a hot dog and a hot dog, which
I love hot dogs, but I can't, you know,
I can't do that. It make me
feel sick now to eat them. Yeah.
Can't do it at 40 it's like
over fuck a firework. Showman.
And whether the neat part is in La,
I'm sure everywhere.
But you get to hear people shooting
guns and shooting Stata guns go off.
Yeah. Yeah. You get to hear it.
Two days before 4th of July or a week
before and then a week after Jesus.
What are you doing?
Why are you shooting guns in the sky?
Morons do want to hear this song.
That DJ boy butter set in. Yeah.
It's called be retarded. He
took the, would you rather
be with my parents? I mean,
he's done some amazing songs already,
but this is his latest one.
That's really great.
Would you rather be retarded or
you have to drive on the freeway.
Okay. Okay. To retired
then pass. That's fine.
Would you rather have four
penises on your forehead?
I dog
penis in my foods type or pills.
I can probably handle them
up with Nancy balls. Okay.
She's got a nice set of lungs. Okay.
She's had some work done. All right. Okay.
You'll get upset with it.
Okay.
Okay. Oh Shit. Yeah.
Would you rather only eat
Asian food? No, I go retarded.
Okay.
I'm not going to eat dog. Okay. Oh Shit.
Amazing. That's so funny. I like that.
Your Dad, you're going to be retired.
That's fine. Okay. Okay.
I'd rather go retarded. Does he say
Gallery Darden? I'd go retired. Yeah.
Uh, I love your dad's hatred
of Asian food, which you know,
I think that's one of my favorites.
Is Asian girl retarded? Yeah,
they created the noodle. Oh my God. I
mean Asian suppressed. I think if they,
they gave this scenario
to everyone on earth,
there'd be one retarded
guy walking around.
It'd be my dad and everybody else
would be like, this food is delicious.
Asian foods the best for so many
different kinds. Too many options. Yeah.
You could do something that I'm going
to use dog. Alright. He's serious.
That shows you how underexposed
to this cuisine he is.
He just telling him the stereotypical
worst thing that exists now.
You can dog. I love my
dogs. They no need. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. I mean, look,
when I was in Korea,
they did warn us not to eat the
street meat cause there was,
there were reports of dog meat being
sold. Yeah. That's those in Seoul.
I don't know, but that's my outcome on,
yeah. He don't eat dog all the time.
You just said that like, like him though.
He said yeah, come on. Come on, come on.
Okay. Alright. Okay. Alright. Alright.
Today he goes, we were, we were
face timing cause LJ was playing.
It'd being adorable. Yeah, it does
put Christina get over here. Yeah.
Didn't you see that today? I was like,
Oh shit. He got his power suit on today.
You were in a suit. He got a suit
on. I know you were saying that,
that he always dressed that
way when you were a kid.
You saw it everyday at work every day.
And then the khaki this,
that's how that came.
That's dressed down.
That's why that stuff down because for
him and technically is dressed down,
it sure is. Yeah. He looks
handsome in his suit. Sure.
So it looks great on most guys. Yeah.
If you look like shit a suit, yeah.
It really cleans up your whole act.
And the one thing that we talk about
it a lot, he and I do. Um, I can,
I all right is
if you wear this one thing that's
fun is to watch how people treat you
differently because they do it. Yeah.
You're gonna like the way you look,
they treat you weigh guarantee to just
make assumptions about you in a good way
usually. Yeah. Dressing
up is a, is a huge factor.
People assume that you're richer,
smarter, everything. Yeah.
They assume that you, that you have
your shit together more. I mean,
cause you and I are, you've gone car
shopping and you said that people will be,
oh my God mean to you.
Belittling to you.
They have basically walked
me out of dealerships cause
you look like a homeless.
Uh, it's weird derelicts. It's La La is a,
a well known dressed down place.
Yeah. People dress down here.
Oh you'd be a billionaire
and you look like a scumbag.
And I've walked in and they're like,
are you like taking pictures of cars?
Was going to shopping for one and
they're like, uh Huh. Um, yeah.
And then there'll be like, this is,
you know, this is not a free car.
Was that a contest? I'll be like,
I know man. Yeah. And they like,
just keep looking at you.
And they're like,
are you sure you don't
want to see the other?
Like they'll talk me like you want
to see the cheaper one? I'm like,
what is it going on? And I feel
like I have to be like, no, I, I,
I really am here to actually buy a car.
Do you think it's the beard?
I guess that's a whole look.
I guess Camilo says, um,
I'm going to steal something I guess.
Yeah. Interesting.
Speaking of Asian cuisines,
I had a thought I like to ask
you about this. What is that?
Which cuisine gives you
the worst farts personally?
What do you think gives
you the smelliest farts?
It's a tie between high vegetable content.
Oh,
and a high seafood content
for you. What about like spice and
heat cook curry or a, but I mean,
I don't think it's,
it's the worst
of all. No. So I think
can we give a nationality of
the food or hard to say, I mean,
I feel like it's an ingredient.
I don't know if you're,
if you're going by cuisine.
See the thing is,
I went to a Sushi place last week that
was amazing, but it was really authentic.
I mean, the guy is, you
know, fresh off the boat,
there's no roles. He was like
ordering us not to use soy sauce.
And I had no digestive issues whatsoever.
Really freshest fish,
the best stuff I've ever had. But
do you go to like a boar, you know,
neighborhoody joint and you're getting
roles and all that stuff and I blow it up
my ass.
I think it's the fried
component to those roles.
Maybe we get that hot night role
and it's got shrimp Tempura in it.
And I swear that makes you shit.
Or the spicy.
Manet's but I'm talking about farts.
I'm not talking about browns. Yeah.
Hmm.
I think Vietnamese might give me the
worst farts I could co sign on that idea
for you.
Uh,
I used to get far from this
place in silver lake that we,
we lived when we lived there and I swear
those farts, we're just rancid. Yeah.
Rotten, rotten, rotten, rotten.
I feel like you have a few
places that do bad things to you.
Ty is like, oh, that's an instant fart
maker. They may as well just call it far.
Makings Fart. Make
Curry Fart car rate. Oh,
when I was in San man friend disco,
that's what did me in Penang Curry
before my show and that they,
they texted me like, are you telling,
Jeez, I had to finish my shit.
Wow. That's amazing. Jean,
do you know we got an
email that said hygiene?
We all know Bert is fat. Yeah. Right.
That's something that
we all know. Yeah. Um,
well we all,
everyone in the world knows that now.
So
I love the internationally bird is
known to be fat as where are you fat?
But did you know that burnt Chrysler
Sr is on team Tommy. Wow. Wow.
Glass in through an old 1997 rolling
stone article about Bart's partying.
Stan Ama.
I came across this amazing blurb.
Burt's father hated Burt's goatee.
He wants offered Burt
$500 to get rid of it.
The only reason Burt had grown it
out was to cover his double chin,
but for the bucks he shaved it off,
seeing it gone.
The first thing his father
had said was fat boy. Wow.
Oh boy. Listen to those big tits. Fart.
Love Umami Ryan from
Schlong Guyland Jude Dork.
Wow. Wow. We have to bring that up to
Barton person. I had no idea about that.
Um,
you've been taking a lot of shifts
every day. I feel like too many.
I think we can ask our audience,
how many shifts a day do you take?
I don't take a ridiculous amount at all.
Downloaded a counter app just like it.
Keep track for it to go from one to two.
Well or three.
You say you had three in a day and that's
normal. That was not, it was normal.
I'll look on our next door APP. Somebody
writes wanting to set up a compost pile.
Oh,
I love,
I think of nothing worse
here. Gene, read this. You know, I'm
thinking this is your wheel house. Gosh,
out loud.
Hey,
hey guys.
I was listening to the podcast the other
day and you were talking about people
talking loudly on the phone or watching
videos that are ridiculous volume.
This is my ultimate pet peeve.
I'm a fireman and I work in a
lower income neighborhood. Well,
the other day the crew was walking into
the grocery store and there was a guy
standing out front listening to music
on a Fucking Dre Beats
Bluetooth speakers on fucking 11
at that instant,
I completely forgot that I was in my
uniform and went into a rage in my head.
The only thing I could do,
mind you,
this isn't a predominantly
black neighborhood. I'm
about as white as they come.
The funniest part is to do,
just looked at me,
turned down his speaker
and went feel you and word.
So I guess your theory is right.
If you're a black voice is on point,
it will elicit a response. Fireman, Mike,
I guess if you're black voices,
I'm going, why did you, uh,
I'm not going to say the n word anymore.
I am not going to say we're reading
an email. It's a guy, not a girl.
But why don't you always feel like I'm
reading something and I'm repeating.
Something will change.
I just,
I can't take the abuse because I don't
want the songs to come in and the remixes,
all. Anyone wants it. All right,
I'll give it to you. He turned down
a speaker. I went feel you Nigga.
Why would you say that? So I guess
your theory is right for black boys.
Don't point it will elicit a
response. I yelled, headphones.
I can't believe you actually
said it. I know. I just, yeah,
I don't think I read that part. The only
thing, I didn't read that part, I'm sorry.
The only thing I could do, what was
take a page from Tom's book. Sorry,
I skipped a line.
So basically this guy yelled headphones
and the best black guy voice I can do.
So he yelled it's headphones.
Headphones, like you do bikes.
I skipped a line. Yeah.
Oh, that's so funny.
And then he was like, all
right, man. That's so funny.
That's so funny.
Can I read an email?
Very important to and of course high
Hitler's a couple of times in the last two
weeks I've noticed something interesting
when I go to the bathroom at work.
We all know about the age
old brown cleanup preferences
like standing or sitting
folding or scrunching and front
to back versus back to front.
But this observation
at work had me baffled.
How many times do you swipe across your
brown maker with a single serving of
toilet paper? Personally, for the
last 27 years I've been wiping myself.
I've only ever done one pass and it's
onto a new clean bunch of toilet paper.
This guy I heard was going back and
forth upwards of 25 times with the same
handful of TP.
I don't care how clean I think I am.
I am not risking the chance of smearing
brown all over my, I'm curious,
curious, so foul, a common cleanup
strategy and what your thoughts on my God,
you guys are so disgusting
person had one thing I told him,
ah, like sandpaper. Well it's all
about how many passes you take. Now,
he doesn't say I,
I'm assuming he means once and then
like a fold over and then you go back.
But he says the same paper,
so it's literally one pass
and then again on the same.
No, you can't do that. I don't do that.
I fold over and then I go and then
of course, yeah, no, you have a,
you have a thing. Okay. Not do
the pass again. So if you have,
if you have, if you have
this, you would wipe. Yeah,
you would fold it. Maybe if it was
like Super Chunky, you'd be like,
I'm dropping that. Yeah. But if
you were trying to conserve you,
we folded a second time and then you
drop it, drop it. Yeah. Like van go,
I'm gonna fold that. And then when I
followed that, no, no, but is he saying,
come here, give me that piece of
paper. I thought what he was saying,
is it somebody he's asking
something different.
He's saying that somebody
went like sh yeah,
like same piece of paper all in the same
way. I think he's asking if it's pass,
pass, pass. That's nasty. That's
not even worth discussing.
Disgusting beyond belief, but I didn't
know people were capable of that.
I didn't even know that was a,
anything you can't do that.
You can't go back on the same paper.
That is nasty,
real nasty.
Uh,
let's bring it chest and balance is
critical to ensuring that your store is
built with the h vac system
you've specified so that
it operates as efficiently
and comfortably as possible.
The chest and balance from should be
independent and what direction to ensure
your best interests are represented.
The firm should also be certified by a
National Organization such as in ebb a, B,
c or t a,
B B,
to ensure basic quality standards are
met and industry exempted procedures are
used. Cool. Didn't get enough though.
Upon arrival to the job site,
the technician meets the general
contractor's superintendent
you meeting. That's my
favorite one. The uh,
the guy meets the other guy and then they
showed them like, hi, nice to meet you.
Well, he didn't understand that someone
when it looks like when people meet. Fuck.
Amen. HBB You want to see
a mom boner HPP? Yeah,
it's Kinda weird. It's a mom boner, but
she's like friendly. She's like excited.
Yeah. Sounds almost
angry. But it's actually
also like inviting. It's,
it's really bizarre. Okay.
She's watching like a
speedboat raced in the,
I think in West Virginia or something. Uh,
where? West Virginia. Virginia. Virginia.
Yes.
I think this is Charlie honey.
Yeah,
that's Charlie. Oh my
God. Get your passenger
son of a bitch.
Dammit.
Dirty Bitch.
Think she smokes.
That's one thing I've learned from
these clips more than anything is how
horrible you sound when you've been
a smoker your whole life. This lady,
I feel like we never get to see her and
I feel like I could draw a picture of
her. Yeah. Me See what I had pictured
or what's your picture? Well, it's um,
it's dirty blonde. Like she used to
bleach, bleach it and now kind of messier.
She's tail stringed out.
She's got big hoop earrings.
She's got a low cut,
a sleeveless shirt with like too much
like jewelry that doesn't really match up.
But there's a lot of it.
It's kind of tacky,
like maybe three or four necklaces
and maybe there's a ring on,
you know, eight out of 10 fingers.
Right. And some bracelets,
a big sloppy hangers.
Kimber wine, big old slop.
No Bra for sure. Um, she
goes through, I dunno,
maybe two packs a day and um,
she drinks,
she has a road cools or no, Virginia
slims or something, you know,
something long Capris or something.
Yeah, she has a lot of roadies. You know,
when she goes on, when she gets in the
car, it's got a big like tub thing.
Some people drink ice tea out of it,
but it's like a 32 ounce and she,
she has her, her road drink. You
know. Interesting. I went dark hair.
I'm going to go, uh, big and
pretty bad. I don't think so.
I think smell can keep,
it's supposed to keep you a little trick.
I don't think she's five bills, but I
think she's like, she's abroad to 20.
I'm going to go. Ah, I'm
curly. Shoulder length,
brown hair and kind of a
melody caught not a mullet,
but melody where it's shorter
on the sides. Sexual passes.
Terrifying to go over.
She's a real, she's a swamp
person. Like she's a pig. Um,
I'm going to go for a t shirt
with a silly slogan on it.
Like what the kind of her
neck large or like an,
I'm an aggressive fluent in sarcasm.
Yeah. Stuff like that. Fuck. Are
you looking at whatever? Yeah.
They don't call me bitch for
nothing. Whatever. Damn slogan. Uh,
faded blue jeans
and flip flops.
She bought sh the cheap
one from like Safeway,
Kroger and we don't have that on the
west coast, but she goes to Kroger.
She gets the flip flops from Kroger.
Go ahead.
Well,
you guys are doing well.
Why?
Yeah. After I got booths,
soup and everything,
you guys are doing good.
Hey,
I got you on video.
He's going to get hit.
That bolt's going to come back, smack
them right on that. Can I tell you that?
Of all the scenarios of human existence,
hers would be like,
I would rather,
I would probably rather be
a sex worker in Bangladesh.
Have that life than be her.
I don't think so.
Repeat what you said to yourself
out loud a couple times.
Visualize sex worker life in
Bangladesh. Right? And Making Mousse.
It sounds better than this and this
woman's life. I don't think so.
I mean the fact that you are born in
America, I'm assuming she's American,
she has all these opportunities
afforded, Eh, you know,
and you've pissed your life into being
a river person who screams at people you
know, you failed, you
failed. I think it's good.
I don't think you want to be
a sex worker in Bangladesh.
Potato Patato you know what I mean?
She's made a lot of bad choices.
Grs that. I got that on video. She says,
can I,
can I say what really annoys me too?
I hate that personality where somebody
messes up. Like Raymond made a mistake.
Clearly.
I don't know if he did this intentionally
to his friend in a race and then the
person has to chastise I j Ray man.
Yeah. You went in, you did that wrong.
Fucked up.
Like they love to pre no
harp on the person that did
made an innocent mistake or
something like that.
That makes me crazy.
It's like they thrive on making
you feel like shit for something.
You did hate it.
Who Soup?
Oh,
this is what I feel like a real highlight
for her. I think she really enjoys it.
Yelling at people. No, I mean like
the watching the little boat race.
That's why she lives on the river there.
O m g
and then the laugh
dirty. Yeah. What if I would
turning into that gross?
Would you divorce me? Oh, a hundred
percent seriously. Later. Yeah.
It would take you a while to turn
into that. You can't be that tomorrow.
20 years of smoking. Right,
but then I would, yeah,
I would take off God damn sleeve.
You're making your move soup everyday.
That's how you'd get your next guy. He'd
be like, Yo, I was single for a while,
but then I learned this moose soup
recipe and the guys just started coming
around.
I heard you getting married.
Yeah. And we're serving
moves soup at the assumption
is that the crop stuck
in my craw. Hey, okay.
Would you rather be married to that lady
moose soup lady or the girl that does
all those fart videos and the shed the
shed videos. Cause remember you were like,
I want it to be the fart mistress you did.
And you go, I don't want to be married.
The fart mistress and we've,
we have the URL reserved.
So yeah, I'm, I'm not going
to let you hold me back. Yeah.
Hmm.
Yeah,
yeah.
Oh good.
Yes. It's like a monster. So
not her though. This shed lady.
I'm the shed lady and I do Fort Mister
Star Com and that's my job. Right.
And anybody that does a
Google search can find that.
And I'm your wife or your the moose
and the Moose Soup Lady. Yeah,
I dad get it here. I got more bad
5% foreign ministers was attractive.
If I didn't know she was making farts
in that shed, I would be like, yeah,
she's a good enough looking lady.
But you dropped our son off at school
and everybody knows you're married to
Fargo stories. Yeah, I mean I
would get over the shame quickly.
I think I'd be much more ashamed
to be married to moose soup lady.
I find I find her voice
repulsive. Yeah. Damn.
Let me suck your cat cam on.
Please let me lick your ass.
Would you let her know she's so gross.
She sounds disgusting.
I don't want any part of it.
How would you go down on me? Ah,
no guys. Oh my dad's actually,
you know that God might did stop.
It's, I think it's just the approach to
sex that we need to work on it with her.
She'd say it out right?
There's a way to get in.
Hi,
I'm Roxanne de Palma and I want to know
who out there is curious about eco sex.
And you're like, what the
fuck is eco sex, right?
Yeah.
Well, um, I hate everybody.
I hate the world.
Oh, the wind in your hair can
be stimulating into the lading,
the texture of tree bark.
I mean,
that's exciting in itself to really let
your fingertips run across the tree.
Bark and feel it erotic.
Goodness.
You want to fuck a tree?
Yeah,
I hate these people. Do you want, um,
would you have lesbian eco
sex with the Moose Hoop Lady?
Uh,
what or,
or you have to live in the fart shed
and I'd smell her all that lady's farm.
Well, here's the thing. Most
soup lady never goes outside,
has no idea what outside in that video.
Yeah,
but she's not going to tie
yourself to a tree. This is,
this is the proposal and live in the
Fart Shetty and I'd be left alone.
This is terrible.
I want you to know that I will be tying
up a real live human for your viewing
pleasure.
We're going to a tutorial
and a scene,
so you'll get to see me and my
girlfriends summer on an upcoming video.
Summer, summer. Got Bands, have ECOSOC
close up on that.
It looks like a big hooded clit upside
down and the entrance to the vagina is
right in here. It's pretty sexy,
I think. Yeah. Yep. Oh my God.
Over people.
Jen found gentle.
If you ever go straight for
the clit and be so gentle,
like barely touch it,
I'm going to don't spit after
me. You stupid bitch. Wow.
You got really upset with, well,
I just think it's another racket.
It's another one of these Weirdos is
trying to make a buck off of innocent
people and like,
I don't feel like it's genuine.
That's the only thing I wish this
lady really love fucking trees.
That's what I'm saying.
If you really are in a tree fucking,
you're not making videos,
you're just doing it and
you're, you know, nobody knows.
Yeah. Keep it a secret. Hillary
Clinton, my asshole. Okay.
Seckler sick.
So we're that.
Ryan would come out with that and never,
I would write,
I would say that he never told us.
G
O N J O g Jab Kubo via
dad paid you by their paws
like Uyg page by Deb both.
She's so grody that
this is pretty good. Somebody said, uh,
I once worked for at best
buy for a total of two hours.
First hour was doing orientation and I
should have know things were not going
well.
What everyone always had the fakest of
smiles boy and I'm being polite to the
point of being nauseous.
She votes work,
opening shift and nightmare of non robot
humans cheer squad and volleyball game.
Before the opening of the store,
I did not participate in the game and
when the time came to open should be a
roll call.
I did not say my name,
nor did I clap along to the chance
of best buy is the best by Gosh,
quickly singled out as non complying.
The manager's stared at me and
gestured for me to play along.
Immediately shaking my head and
defiance. Yeah, feeling he had no power.
Pulled me aside and told
me this is what they do.
I need to be a team player or
else I won't succeed there.
I think he understood what my position
was right when I told him to fuck off and
walk out of the store.
The manager followed me outside and kept
asking why I didn't want to participate
in the warmup.
You felt like a winner when I said nothing
and drove off with my middle finger
up. Keep it glassy. Chris P s
please fuck my triple. Yeah.
Slow way. Good for you. Good for you.
I feel such a connection to Chris
said a lie. I could not do that.
Could not be a part of that at all.
It's not worth it.
Can I read an email I got okay.
Hey,
are we are Walmart?
We are,
we are Walmart.
Oh my God. Go ahead. Alright, so we've
had many questions about blind people.
Uh, how do they wipe? Yeah,
I love that you're like,
this is real serious. We've
got another one. Uh, hi.
Hey Hitler's. I was just making it
brown and wiping the correct way,
but I'm wondering if blind people
can be racist. I think they can,
but I want to know my main
non-binary mommy's thoughts. Also,
could retarded people be racist as well?
Well, of course. Yes or no question.
I'm on. That's a stupid
question. Nate. Ps bikes.
Well, I mean, obviously retarded
people, yes, they can be racist,
but Ken Blind people be
racist. I'm, I mean, I mean,
I look, racism is what based on the color
of your skin, that's what people say.
Yeah. But I think it's
also based on cultural, um,
stereotypes. Correct. Yeah.
I mean other things too.
I mean, a blind person is going
to pick up on, uh, somebody,
I dunno,
some common behavior or a perceived,
you know, attitude of, of somebody
that they're around and they're also,
there's other stimuli,
right?
So it's like they met somebody and then
somebody around them is going to say
something like, I use medic. That was
Jewish guy. You know what I mean? Like,
and then they're going to maybe
repeat things to them like, oh, Yep,
that's what it,
that's what the Jews always do.
And then that block is that the blind
person just is going to, oh, I can't see,
therefore I can't have a perceived,
I'm sure it cuts down on
racism because, yeah, I mean,
they're definitely not because you're
not making that snap judgment as quickly.
You might go,
oh,
that guy's real greedy and he's
acting Jewy and therefore he's Jesus.
But you'll be,
you'll be more,
you'll be more tentative about
your racism is what I'm saying.
It won't be as quick.
You'll have a real,
I think actually being blind makes you
more of a pure racist. I loved that.
This was the episode. You're
like, I'm not gonna say anything.
They're not going to get me anymore.
And then you just walk into it. Fuck,
it's fine. Yeah, it's fine. Look,
I don't have hate in my heart,
but I was saying that I think we,
you could really breed a more pure
racist culture with blind people.
I think the best racists actually
just more clear in their racism.
Pure hate because they don't see it.
Yeah. Like they're feeling like, oh,
that's a, Oh, that's this
group. I hate them the most.
Saying that that was a
Cambodian guy. Yeah, I know why.
I thought he was an asshole. All right.
I got you. All right. Yeah. Interesting.
That's so funny that there's
somebody right now that's
like those fucking Cambodians of course.
Definitely hate,
hate them the most. The most, the
most, the most, you know, when you,
they're more like obscure,
totally obscured,
but the more obscure the um, the race
of people, that's what it highlights.
How absurd it is.
Mainly more the smaller the group and
someone being like they're the worst,
the more you go, then that sounds
pretty crazy. Damn Lithuanians. Yeah.
What did they do again? Oh,
he's cooking fish outside
as a group. Yeah, they're
all bad. Yeah, sure.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Tom said,
go master back saints.
That's a bad accent by the way.
Whoever did that.
Who did that?
Josh,
I knew it.
It's been a while.
Thank you Josh.
I am the master of accents and there's
a new submission that I've been asked to
break down. Um, oh,
also I should mention
quite quickly if you,
I feel most that my vinyl
vinyl of mostly stories is in,
it's signed.
I autographed the first batch of them
and they will come with a bikes poster.
The first batch comes
with a bike's poster.
So if you go to merchant method.com/tom
Cigarette or you just go to Tom
cigarette.com and you click on my store,
it'll take you and you'll
see the a merchant,
the vinyl sales. What?
What's wrong? Nothing.
My name is Doctor Dove at
hospital language inflammation
officer at the Center
for the Scotts lead and
payoffs. So far. No problem.
I would like to speak about the
Scots leader and it's sadness,
toll historical speeding's
Jesus and got it right. It actually,
he's in Perth so it's a double double.
Yeah,
so he is Dr. David Horse broke that.
Just the way he says his last name.
Like look how it's spelled. Yeah.
My name is Dr. David Hospital,
a dove at hospital and get an inflammation
or facade at the center for the
language information officer at the
Center for fleet and pay off grass lead in
Perth. I would like to speak about the
scope. Cute. I'd like to speak in beauty,
sleet and it's sadness. Toll
historical speeding's. Oh Wow.
Fuck the septic tall.
Yeah, and it's personal.
Spearings and spearing with septic septic
tanks that you could basically, Huh?
Wow.
Yeah.
Firstly,
personally escorts.
What is Scott's
and modern Scotland?
Sports is a name for the bay leads.
Gather up together other names
a doric and scorch for the bay.
Derek Scott and by,
and they're probably in by,
so there's other names where the Scots
there, Derek and they're poly and thereby,
okay.
So far it's easy
scopes is couldn't to brain to the
Germanic family leads and as like Tang Soo
Thrun sprung fee.
The old angles lead.
Can you imagine based old dangles and
it's doctor escorts has been spoken and
Suitland an Easter Scotland the
loans because the seventh century.
Do you know what this video ties for?
Is the most boring video? Too Boring.
What was difficult accent?
Look at this guys. No, you
better brush up their skills.
I go to Australia.
Gene.
This guy looks just like
this with this same stair.
When he tells you to suck it,
right?
Is it good in your mo?
Oh miss beer rub rub
his mouth looks so dry.
Do you understand what this one
was talking about? The different,
the language of where Scott and Scott
Scott's are from these old time goals and
it's Dr stuff.
Forethought before the bangles and the
doctor and the bangles and the doctors
has been spoken and sooth.
Lynn and Easter Scotland and Southland
Easter Scotland on Easter and Scott.
Oh,
for the seventh century Ed.
That's easy.
Seventh century a d
don't mention to this lead
to be fun for instance.
And the runic carbons on the rebel
cross free Shire get and the Accenture
century Ed Baguette
like a Scott was that bag,
those delicious breads? No,
the Lord of the ring is Bilbo Baggins,
Bilbo Baggins.
So he's talking about him though.
This thing belongs to Bilbo Baggins
Scott's case done and often the and
Shetland.
The Shetland ponies.
Yeah. I'm going to be the miss spoken
tongue and the outs and the [inaudible]
an active saint. There it is. The
buy leads who sculpts till old stuff.
I'm so boring
today.
This is too boring.
Was first clearly set on a cat.
All right. Yeah, I know.
He really did Trump,
his accident was was trumped
by his boredom when I
studied in England and we had
to learn about like this kind of thing,
like fourth century stone carving,
like I don't think there's anything more
boring than looking at fourth century
stone carvings. I know you're
like, God, why are you,
and you know what the other thing is
about those things is some parts of you
sometimes like when you're a kid you go,
well later on in life
this will be valuable.
And then sometimes you look at things
you were taught and you go 20 years later
you're like,
that was,
that was as boring as I thought
it was and that was as useless
as I thought it was.
Like when you had the lesson here,
that shit dates historical dates
and more things happen. I'm like,
man, I mean I'm glad I know these
things, but I don't know. Yeah,
I don't care. Not like humans don't
care. No, the average person isn't there.
That's what people care about. So
we can lose soup. Yeah. Boat Rides.
Getting your Dick sucked fucking trees.
There you go.
Fuck this tree with me so hot. Oh my
God, I'm gonna fuck this tree later.
It's truly looks like, uh, I hate that
kind of stuff. It's, it is so fake.
She's so fake. Come on. I love that. That
guy quit mid, like first day of work.
Uh, well you can't fake it. Oh
Wow. Okay. I'm another email. Okay.
Okay. Read it. Hi Hitler. I sincerely
love both of you in the podcast.
Uh, okay. That being said,
I seriously cannot stand hearing Christina
say that coffee dehydrates you even
one more time.
It angers me.
I know people have thought that
since like the 18 hundreds,
but if you do a tiny bit of research,
you will learn that the
dehydration qualities versus
the amount of water are far
more hydrating than dehydration.
Coffee actually do you hide? Sorry.
Coffee actually hydrates while
making you brown and more alert.
Wow. And he writes, Tom, you are
forever my water champ. Love Hitler.
Privacy's Rup now I don't agree with you.
I think that,
show me the research. Uh, rob simple
Google search. Well, I look, I'll,
all I've learned when I've ever been on
a diet is they consider like caffeinated
tea and coffee to be quote negative
waters. Meaning that they are dehydrating.
Yeah. And you must replenish them.
Then. How come after I drink coffee,
I'm fucking thirsty.
Thirsty Shit. Interesting.
You don't fucking saying I know what
you're fucking so it's a diuretic.
It makes you piss alcohol. Same thing.
I will. Do you agree with this guy?
Well I dunno.
I mean I think what he's saying is the
amount that you're being dehydrated from,
maybe the caffeine is outweighed by
the amount of water that is in a coffee
because coffee is mostly
water, right? That's right.
But maybe it's negated because it makes
you pee so much and you lose more water.
The body loses water. I assumed I
would like to see more uh, data.
So,
so what I rob God,
you want to see the light champ?
You know we have the what,
you know what I'm saying? Ship. Yeah. They
said this is the leg champ. I might be me
mean like it's like there's like,
like we do like communication,
like more like everyone but like certain
guys like are like good at some kind of
certain thing. I for example, like
someone is good at calling Nash,
someone is good at like DP engaged,
someone is good at like everyone like
give their opinion and then if everyone's
just talk each other and they
would just choose what like every,
everyone thinks that is
the best, you know? Oof.
I guys nonbinary for sure. Right? Well
yeah I'm also like champ. Oh my God. And
I say like, so I'm like so do I. But,
but he really did an astounding amount.
Right?
There was a lot like a like
for like, like, like, like,
like, like, like, like, like
a lot of likes in his defense.
I think English is a second language.
So maybe searching for same for you.
Well I guess that's your defense dad.
Get your mail.
So O m g DAB.
This
makes me really happy because
he looks like an ash tray. Yes.
Gray in color lists and I
don't think it gets real ready.
I think you can put a
lot of stuff on there.
You can keep on licking and she's
still like your shit. You're like,
it's pretty dry. Like, yeah, stays
like that, you know, like, um,
stays like that.
When I smoked cigarettes,
my pallor was always gray.
Like it does, it like sucks.
The very nutrition, the oxygen
out of you. You look gray,
everything is gray. It's
gross. Really bad for you.
That's what she says
right before she comes.
She's like, keep going, keep
them. And then her, her eyes
rolled back and she goes,
so Naz, she, Nancy, Nancy's. How well
this is exciting.
I'm excited.
[inaudible] amaze. Amaze,
amaze. Where'd it go?
See fireworks the greatest
of all time. The greatest actor
of all time has a new movie.
And we have the trailer. Oh my
God. Yes. Oh my gosh. I'm so,
is it on Netflix or I don't know if it's
going to be on Netflix, so maybe it is.
Maybe just straight to youtube.
Here it is.
Can we read the rotten tomatoes
reviews on his films? Yeah. I mean,
here's the movie synopsis. Action
legends, Steven Seagal headlines.
This explosive thriller that pits US
forces against Eastern European drug
cartel. Oh, great.
When crime boss Salazar turns informant
US Marshal Jensen and his team must
guard their luxury hotel safe house.
But as cartel underboss Sinclair
who's played by UFC superstar,
George Saint Pierre and his hit
squads to send a murderer Salazar,
this situation explodes in raging
agent Harrison played bicycle,
who will stop at nothing to root
out the mole that compromise
the operation.
That sounds like a one long set.
This sounds like the other, every
other movie. It's always the drug guy.
And then he's got to train
the girl to do martial arts,
to go get the guy in the suitcase.
So we always lied about who they said
they were. I knew that this was my party.
This is going to be like do it anymore.
And then there's a girl,
there's always a young girl that he
asked the rescue from the boss teacher,
I'd have sex and
how to have sex.
They have a sex for 50 years
and I am the king of in province for,
for you.
It's so gross. Yeah. So here it is.
I'll scout cartels. Alright, here's the
trailer. This time in eastern Europe,
he never does
my gym.
Confirm Beard.
Very dark, very dark. It's nice and easy.
He's like 60 years.
It's just jet black.
Tim Confirm location themselves.
Salazar as the boss,
a little most quiet and
cartels and eastern Europe.
Salazar is not an eastern European name.
Ps, that's Latin, isn't it? Yeah. Salazar.
That's like every drug lord name and
every movie. Right? Does it sound angel?
It's a Latin, yeah, and they're giving
it to an eastern European guy. No Way.
No Way. There's no wise or disease or
cs or Jay's and he's nine eastern block.
We do not kill.
Again, it's mixed. Weird, but the,
the mute, the sound is mixed. Weird.
Again,
this is the guy to the guy.
This guy I'm sure learned his lines
and then every day on set he's tall.
He's like, why is he saying that? He's
like, he just improvise. ECM prompting,
but do you hear that the voiceover is
mixed lower? Yeah. Then the background,
you could even do that,
right?
Can't even hear the voiceover
because I don't know why.
That doesn't matter to somebody on this,
you know what I mean?
Someone invested their money in making
this term. You would think they'd be like,
can you fucking audio mixes right.
It's so enormous.
Yup.
I was going to say he looks good
cause they put them in a Kevlar vest.
I had this shirt. Yeah, that's,
that's a bad guy's friend. Believe me.
Oh you start putting on layers of things
and you kind of look like everybody
else.
Yeah.
I good. Blended body in a
bag is a one Joseph Salizar.
He'll bring it on [inaudible] side.
What are you waiting for? Soldiers go,
here's a girl I used to see me alive.
So there's Salazar with the east.
He's Salazar. Please talking.
Everyone needs to Bryce to see me alive.
Why are you talking like that?
Salazar?
No weirdo.
Like government be like [inaudible]
or something. Yeah. Yeah.
The government has him. Dea faked
his death. So as people would know,
we flipped it. Salazar is going to be
a star witness for the next 10 years.
The cartel once here,
we have to sit in for 24 hours for
cartels going to be out to exterminate his
entire bloodline.
How on him bad.
That's George Saint Pierre.
The fighter. The fire.
But can you tell already that
that has a bad acting? No,
you can't look,
I want him dead in the eyes. Don't
know expression. Yeah. You would say,
here's how I do it. I want him
dead. But at least that, right.
They're barely trying to do it.
Looked like a guy would want him dead.
That's how you do it. There's some
expression. Right. But this like, look at,
look this blank stare. I
looked him dead. They're like,
they're like, do it more
angry. I want him dead.
W NBC. Oh wait, where's that? No,
that was the shahs of sunset where she
was like, oh, singing. She's like, yeah,
yeah,
yeah. Uh, me and my friends are
on the, uh, I forget it was,
she was like in La, can you say it
with more enthusiasm? And she was like,
I'm singing. No. He's like, no, the
sing it. She was like, I'm going to,
he's like, you don't think much. She's
like, it's all I do. And he's like, oh,
it's terrible. So I'll be, can
I tell you though, honestly,
I'm kind of liking the storyline.
So they fake the drug lords death so
that he can be flipped for America.
Right.
And now the cartels after his
whole family whole bloodline.
So I kind of like, the premise is a
solid premise. I liked those masks.
It could be interesting or terrifying,
but why do we want to save the drug lords,
family and everything? Why? Why do we
care is now he's on the good people,
so we have to maintain his good faith.
Okay. Okay. All right. I'm on board.
I got minute.
I want him dead Alaina and day
Germany's tar bloodline.
Sitting ducks.
It's funny how all of these
movies always have a female,
either a DEA, FBI, US marshals,
some agent who's like unusually
attractive. That line of work.
I've seen some federal officers that
are females. They don't look like that.
Or doctors too. You'll like Katherine
Heigl is the doctor. You're like, no,
that's not what my doctors have ever,
ever looked like a doctorate. No,
never to that woman. She didn't need to
go to medical school, so she didn't go.
We're the only one,
man.
Wait a minute.
You call me,
you're
going to live or you're Gunna die,
I guess on why call him because you want
the answer to, but you're going to live.
Right.
But that's also kind of a philosophically
you can make that statement about
everyone. Whoever you ever call, right.
Or whoever talks to is going to protect
you. You're, you're talking to him either.
Whatever. You got to die. Yeah, that makes
sense. Right? But they're calling him.
He's like,
I'm the guy you should have called first.
Clean this mess up when you call me,
you're going to live or you're gonna die.
Whoa, Whoa, Whoa, whoa.
Shit. I want to live.
Can you rephrase it by the way they're
doing them favors with these shots. Yes.
Is you're leaving out the hoochie.
Oh boy. See? Oh, and also layer.
See Leather, a thick leather
jacket. A fat guy friend. Yeah.
Collared Shirt like I know.
And the yellow glasses.
We're back on the yellow sunglasses.
There's them onscreen and off.
It's not flattering. It's not.
It's not a good luck here.
Chet Chet black, dark,
dark, dark hair. He looks,
he looks like the crazy guy at
the top of the show. Yeah. The uh,
the Hillary Clinton had sex
with. Yeah. Yeah. I know.
Twin eight his ass out, right?
Yeah. Right. That's wild
that she did that story.
I can't believe sickler hasn't
told that story yet. Hey Ryan,
why don't you tell that story? God,
please bombard him with tweets.
Seriously.
Hillary Clinton aid your ass out
can protect him when they call me.
When they call me.
You're going to live
or you're going to die.
Which is it? Let's go. Good.
And this doesn't sound mixed
either. No, it's terrible.
I can you turn it up actually
so I can hear the voiceover
more? Yeah, and he does.
Did you see his mark? Wait, this is
his martial arts. He was doing Tai Chi.
He was like, there's maybe this
fingerless gloves. Anyway. Yeah.
That was how he got ready to fight. He
did like, it's not even there. It is.
Yeah.
He's got his thumbs out of
it's thumbless glove.
They call me.
Yeah.
Can protect him when they call me,
when they call me,
you're going to live
or you're going to die.
That's an improvised line. Yeah.
That sequence. Yeah. It was.
It said something and he was like,
I got, Steven said he got it,
and then the producers that got, damn it.
It's just he doesn't want to memorize.
Yeah, of course. He's like, I get to
just easy. So you do like at an audition,
you're like, I got, I got the idea. These
title cards are made on a Mac. Definitely.
Like, isn't this a standard? Yeah.
Yeah. This is on your APP. All right,
let's go.
Good.
Oh, there it is. A Blue Band
and pointed this out to me.
You know the trailer is that obviously
it's supposed to highlight the best
moments of your film,
and they clearly leave in a dummy,
like a falling.
This is clearly a dot.
Yeah. You have to watch it obviously, but
if you, if you're watching the trailer,
Oh one 21
they're dropping a clear
damn. Oh my God. You're right, it looked
light and it's like its hands or uh,
yeah. You wouldn't put that
in the trailer, which Ya know,
or you just cut it faster so that people
can't tell, but you get to see it.
Wow.
That's exhausting.
Steven Seagal.
George Saint,
let's say they may have spent
like 20,000 days step up.
I'm going to give him some credit here.
I think this one might not be such a such
a piece of shit that is still a piece
of shit, but it's not the worst.
Yeah. This is not the worst
cartels.
Well that's the name of the movie cartels.
Cartels.
Cartels. Yeah. I mean, I don't know. Yeah.
I wish there would have been
eight. My asshole. So weird. Ryan,
when tell us about that.
I know my mans my legs over her shoulders.
Yeah. It's really crazy. She made me
new copious amounts of cocaine with her.
There was so much kicky punching in
this though that I feel I have a hint.
I feel like the story will get lost.
Oh,
you think might suffer a little
cookie bunch kick, kick, kick. Yeah.
So much kicky and shooty punching.
Yeah,
it's a lot. God has a lot. Yeah.
No,
she was numb sucking my asshole.
Cool. To rise, numb,
sucking to the point of it.
It gets numb.
You keep sucking on this.
I got it.
So now a picture of Hillary Clinton just
suck in the over and over on that guy's
bubble.
So great.
I didn't know if she was even into like
cocaine and I know she doesn't seem like
that kind of a lady.
You don't think so? Hmm.
Let's take of all the bullshit to deal
with the bill all these years while she's
probably menopausal at this point.
Not Interested in sex the whole lot.
Do you think at this point she's like, do
your thing. I don't care anymore. Yeah.
Other separate lives have been since the
Wenski scandal for sure. You think so?
If not before then she knew
he was a fucking a real pos
before she's put up with
it for decades, decades. She knew. She
knew about it. She knew everything.
She was like,
wow.
Whenever it's the price I pay for being
married to power to power their total
house of Farts, you know? Yeah. Yeah.
But do you think that he's like, oh,
it's going to go to the store and she's
like, I know where you're from. Yeah.
Why lie? Yeah. I don't fucking
this chick. And he's like,
Hey, you know, actually, uh,
I was out. I was walking around and
I was leading by over vermouth soup.
I'm going to go, he's got you mind.
She's like, go do what you gotta do.
Ah Hah.
You insatiable peg.
I couldn't imagine being in a
relationship with somebody like that.
I would have a very hard time. I would
hate that. The People Power dynamic.
That's power. Yeah. At his
house. At farts. How's the
first half of her gone down?
Um, all right. I gotta get
going, gene. Oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh God. No, I love you.
I love you too. I got, um, let's see.
Ben Solo submitted this song. It's
called sharpening the knife. Um,
so, oh, I know who that's going
to be about. Yeah, please.
Uh, come see your show, Tom.
cigarette.com thousand range.com
your mom's house podcast.
Thank you guys as always for listening.
See you next week. Bye Jean. Hi, Mary.
Shop shop, shop, shop,
shop, shop, shop. Shop
in the hallway
and you'll make it.
You get the peanuts,
peanuts,
peanuts out,
and you get the boy in the
hand. And your ruff, ruff,
ruff, ruff, ruff, ruff, ruff,
ruff, ruff, ruff, ruff,
ruff.
Rawr,
Rawr, Rawr, Rawr, Rawr,
Rawr.
They're
nice.
One left side,
left side
down.
50 50 50 you
have to do every day, every, every day.
Every day.
What? I let this Guy Jack My Dick
and the answer is a resoundingly yes.