Do you need to wipe down
what's with the jeans?
All right.
Thank you David for sending a
dope beats.
Man.
I love when you guys send know your songs,
your instrumentals.
It's all great for the show.
Thank you very much. Um,
welcome to your mom's house.
We are
video recording this again.
Louder.
You discovered the video for
the first time last week.
We're very excited to have video
now of Michelle incriminating now.
I can't roll in like total shit. Yeah. Um,
can you tell me how bad I
look? Fat. Tired. Thank you.
You guys look like you just rolled out
of bed. It is good. We did by the way,
note for, for big guys especially. Yeah.
You wear a shirt that's too big for you.
You look even fatter. Yeah, that's true.
It was way too big.
It was.
This is a shirt that fits
still fat but not quite as fat.
So still hashtag still fast.
Hashtag still fat. Not Quite.
Um,
let's see.
Next week I'll be in Barton
[inaudible] Harry Zona.
Hey at stand up live downtown Phoenix
26 and 27 parts and only four shows.
Uh, so please get your
tickets now to come on me.
Washington, Tacoma,
comedy club. Good work.
March 10th through March 12th, there's
already a sold out show and that's in,
that's a month from now.
Um,
the punchline comedy club and
back in your mouth. Sacramento.
17th through the 19th of March.
And then Cleveland,
Cleveland Steamer hilarity his club
and Cleveland Steamer, Ohio. Uh,
March 31st through April 2nd,
and then finally in April, Spokane.
But he got for that spring.
Can we can,
yeah.
Comedy Club in Spokane and
sperm can Washington. Uh,
there are more cities and dates coming
through through the rest of the year.
Really. So as those come, I'll announced
them. Jeans, anything. Yeah. So I'm,
I'm doing a fundraiser with
Mary Lynn Rice Cub. Joe Rogan.
Rach Cooley Bay. Yes. Joe. And uh,
I think Greg Fitzsimmons March 9th
at the comedy store. Eight o'clock.
It's a fundraiser for a
Firebase. Oh, for school.
What does that sound more noble than like,
like my bullshit school fundraiser sucks.
I don't know.
So come out and help a cause is from
Maryland. Maryland's kids school,
I think is what that was for.
Uh,
April 1st and second flip Harris
Comedy Club in Sperm Bank. No.
Fornia for 20. I met the Ventura
Comedy Club. Hitler's birthday.
Thank you very much of Ventura
comedy club. Eight o'clock show.
March 27th through 28th
La Jolla comedy store.
It's all on thousand ranch.com.
Check out. That's deep, Bro.
podcast.com this week I have a
psychotherapist on and we're discussing
serendipity. It's not a Sandra
Bullock movie. It's no synchronicity.
Synchronicity,
the random things coming together
and they means not moving, sir.
Deputy not with her. Wasn't that what?
It's synchronized. I fucking bored. Yeah.
Yeah.
I don't know some other Andrew,
what a saying to Kate Beckinsale back in
sale to sale. There's no Z in it. Okay.
What happened to her? She's
anorexic. She's dead. She died.
I didn't know she was dead.
She doesn't eat. I don't know.
I really liked her though. She's
British. Yeah. Do her accent quickly for
you. Left a note in my glove.
That's it. You love it. Eh?
I can't wait to see you neither
can my con. Hmm. That's,
that's what John Cusak, that movie love
and my pussy movie glove and my pussy.
And then she's like, have you wanted
to see my car this whole time?
I can fit all five fingers of this
glove in my asshole. Yeah. Guys,
also, if you do your shopping on
Amazon, I implore you to use our banner.
Go to your mom's house,
podcast.com.
Click on the banner at the bottom of
the homepage and deer shopping as you
normally would. It just helps the
show, gives us a little money,
helps us do things like keep the video.
Camera's rolling and there you go.
Anything else? Am I forgetting?
Twitter, accuracy and p Twitter
at, what's your name again? Tom.
Tom Segura you have verified.
Oh yeah, it's, it's huge.
I should also say all my tickets
if you haven't figured it out.
My live shows Tom. Dot.
So don't forget, wait,
when did you get verified?
I got verified a couple of weeks ago.
And did she say anything to me? I
feel like I did. I did. Damn sorry.
I'm totally should have thrown a
party and I had a party. Oh yeah,
you weren't there. I had a
great party. It was awesome.
Everybody was having a good time.
Well that's funny cause
I know what that's like.
I've been verified since the
beginning of verified yet. No. Oh,
that's sucks. Or Facebook or
verified for like a year. Maybe more.
Why didn't you have to pause?
I mean like a bear and when you just want
you to realize what's it must suck to
not have a Facebook account.
Well I don't care. I'm not,
you know we both lacking not even on a
fight. Instagram Shit. What's up with dad?
I feel like that's a while away. It
still Graham Hall. I see the Instagram,
Checkmarx and they have like
400 followers thing. Boom.
By the time they get around to doing that
you like some other medium is going to
be sucks.
Life is terrible.
Verifying is all about
it. Huh? Ooh stupid.
All right. Thank you to all our sponsors.
Keeping our show alive and going.
Keeping Blue Band seated right here.
Camera's rolling.
Are you ready to start the show
genes already? There's so much.
There's a lot to do.
Hitler. Oh boy. Here we go.
I shit without them.
Don't get me fucked up bitch. I'm still
hurting shit and we'll fuck. Okay.
Christina,
Eric, when you make the sound and
you like when I make this sound,
was that Angela Johnson and
then it sounds like her, her,
her nail bed Kinda,
she doesn't use that kind of
do it like do it. You're the master
of all acts. I can do any accent. Um,
do this girl. Okay, here we go.
Cause people are stuck. Motto. No.
Oh No.
Yeah,
she has a lot of videos that she makes
and just puts up and they always do.
Who's that crazy people that sounded like
you think I'm referring to big words.
I just smashed these lunatics.
They always do.
They always go, I met the mentally
ill not, I didn't know what color.
I haven't seen this.
I think you understand what
color we're talking about here.
Bad.
I don't know which color she okay. I know
she's probably crazy. Like they all are.
They certainly are.
Yeah.
Ya now we are
now, um, Columbus,
Columbus lady who you can't imagine
what she looks like. I don't know.
She could be Asian. She of course
he's Asian. Oh, okay. Yes, of course.
That's why maybe,
well maybe you didn't hear the
portion of the clip once she goes,
that's what she's saying about her.
Okay.
That's my favorite job
where I'm still cute.
I might live a little bit more taking
time to talk, but don't get me fucked up,
bitch. I'm still heard shit and
we'll fuck your, is that okay?
You want to fuck with my mind?
You want to fuck with my mind.
That's but mommy's accent. Yeah. Yeah.
That's an Angela Johnson has
perfected that. You do it.
It's pretty good. Uh, that
fan used to do that too. Oh,
not really a stretch for him. He used to
do it because he heard it a lot at home.
Is he one of those,
one of those?
Damn Angela actually perfected
an accident that's not native.
Thank you. Yeah. Well she
doesn't have the gift,
but she's good at that one wrote asking
you to do a Cajun accent one long day.
I owe you lunch. I'll nail you wine long
nail. Don't want to fuck with me, man.
You want to fuck with me?
Ching Chong, Ching Chong. Yeah.
That's a nice way to do it.
Yeah. So she's saying, look,
well I'm sorry. Camera's
facing her. And she's like,
don't get me fucked up.
You know?
And she goes,
so I might look a little more,
and she pulls Asian eyes already more.
And she was,
she goes, she goes like this
with her own eyes and she goes,
I might look a little Jane, but I
will fuck. Don't get it twisted out.
Fuck Yo at, I'm a hooded
shit. That's what she says.
I always forget the point of these videos.
You get lost in them. Yeah. So wait,
which her eyes are already what?
And then she pulls this,
she pulls her already Asian eyes.
So she's Asian and she,
she does this with her eyes and she says,
I might look a little like that.
I smell a new bit for you. Yeah.
You got a new hour to build. Yeah,
I do.
What do you think I should say with that?
She doesn't say Ping Pong. You
added. You're tagging for me. It,
yeah. This girl has a lot of
really good Asian clips. Actually.
They're not even Asian.
She's aging and she, uh,
she makes a lot of videos
where she actually, she seems
like she is hood is shit.
I don't know where she's from,
but she acts like she's down.
Usually the people making these videos
are, what do you mean all videos?
Not that bright. Now the ones that
are like, I'm fucking this and that.
You all know me, I'm going to do
that. And you're like, all right.
I actually think she, this girl is
pretty self aware. Like, Hey Hitler.
Like, yeah, she's like a hey Hitler
vibe to her. She, she actually,
you know, we gotta talk about that
in a moment. Oh, most definitely.
It's, yeah, it's way different than
it grown. It's grown, it's grown.
It's grown quite a bit. Um,
where did this go? Oh No,
no. Hood is, fuck, I'm fucking kill
you. Like what's the point of these?
What is the point?
I'll kill a bitch.
I cannot believe we didn't
investigate that more Hitler. Yeah,
but let me finish with this girl first.
So my new favorite drop is this.
Did I do it again?
Oh,
someone's been boning up on her
accidents this week. Practicing a lot.
Sounds like you're mocking or no,
I'm doing it exactly like she's doing
it does it sounds like you're kind of,
no. No. Okay. So here's what I hear.
Another clip of hers.
Yeah.
What does this genius have to offer and
why are you insulting her like that?
Sorry.
You're right.
Oh, Anna bad. My Day because I make
crazy as videos, but Chad bitch style,
he is talking for free and go home and
kiss your kids before you even brush your
teeth.
I say shit.
She does have a good point. That's a good
point. I know. Fuck no, I stand corrected.
Yeah. Now you feel stupid. So stupid.
Foolish. So a bitches suck. She's saying
you're, you're a horse sideboards.
I'm making fun of her for making crazy
videos. Like you're a bad mother.
You're saying I was wild.
But you hose are out there sucking dicks
for free and you're fucking going home
and kissing your kids. Brush you
teeth. Wow. Snaps, snap, snap,
uhmm pal.
Feel that burn
I think was interesting about these videos
is like, who's who's antagonizing you?
Like who's threatening you?
I think people make these videos where
they talk a lot of shit when they feel
powerless in their lives.
So it's, um, it's a form,
it's an expression of rage in a way.
It's like,
it's like somebody hitting a heavy
bag and beating the shit out of it.
That's a way of physically do it. So if
you don't, if not doing it physically,
you were doing it verbally.
You're doing it to a camera to express
maybe your rage and your lack of power.
I'm sure no one gives a fuck about her.
That's what my thinking is.
What is your problem with it? I'm
just saying, I think most people,
people who are not thinking about
you, you know what I'm saying? Right.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm talking about people
who make videos that go,
if anyone wants to fuck with me,
I'll fuck right. That's right. Yes.
I don't mean to not like her.
I like her. Yes. It just,
I'm trying to understand where
she's coming from. Yeah. Yeah.
That's an awesome sound to make for the
podcast. It's also a video now. I know,
but I mean it's really cool for the
audio quality to SIF to beverages,
like the guy from TMZ.
Are you going to slurp like that?
Yeah.
Why do what I want when I want.
I'll do the fuck I want and
nobody can tell me what my mind.
Okay, great. So
is that good? Yeah, it
was good. You do it now.
Ching Chong Ching Cha Ching
Chong do it like she does it.
She does it. She does it. All right. Um,
you want to feel me? You know
me? No, I'm talking about, yeah.
So you know what I'm saying?
I'm talking about feeling what I'm saying.
Long Time Mountain
filling. I me who's that?
That's half ounce. Oh, okay. But
that's in a proper interview.
Yeah. I'm saying, yeah,
I'm, yeah, I'm, yeah, I'm,
yeah, that's what he sounds
like me. I'm yum. Yum, yum, yum.
Yum. Yum. Yum. Yum. Yum. [inaudible]
there's a lot to get into.
Yeah. The video by the way,
if put up the video of it and,
uh, we had a profile shot going.
We're trying this now just to,
um,
really to get a feedback from the viewers.
So this is going to be a different angle.
You can tell us in the comments what
you think. Tell us if you like this.
Do you like the other video angle more?
Yeah. How do you want to watch that? Yeah.
How do you want to watch
the show? Let's screen. Uh,
so leave that up to the microphone.
It's different. It's different.
I see your book and I imagine it,
I finally took a shit today, babe.
I didn't shit yesterday, but I showed
this morning and shit all night yesterday.
That's not good. Yeah, it was okay
though. I just, I came out normal.
Hmm.
That's not normal at all.
What happened yesterday? Yeah.
I just forgot to take a dumb,
I don't know how that,
how do you forget it's taking
care of the kid, you know, we,
you and I were taking care of him all
day and my dad came over and then I just,
the day rolled and I forgot. I just didn't
have the urge to shit. I don't know.
Yeah. But it's okay. I made up for it. You
can stop worrying. I'm totally worried.
Is Everything all right now? Everything's
fine. Is Everything going to,
it's okay. You can stop worrying. Are
you going to make it? Yeah. How was it?
It was normal. It was just normal.
Like, I dunno, it was a clean break.
There was nothing on
the paper. Um, you know,
when I feel like when our son shits,
like he's had some fucking
disasters in his diapers lately.
Like I feel like guilty just wiping
it up and moving on with the diaper.
I feel like we should, we should shut the
shower, our son, you know what I mean?
Shit. And then bay them. Yeah.
Like he might get a bag the time,
I know seven times a day.
No,
but there should be like a baby blue
day that I can wash his asshole with.
Can we pay them? We do enough. Yeah. Yeah.
I'd like more like my instincts are
to bathe him immediately after. Yeah.
I mean if I shit the way he should and
all over my balls and my butt cheeks,
I might be like, you know, I'm gonna jump
in the shower after this. Right? Yeah,
that's what I'm saying. But we
just use wipes and we know. Yeah.
Let me wipe that shit
up. He's got no hair. No.
So you really are getting it off
of his skin. Pretty Clean Shaven.
What are you shaving her baby's hair
off. I shave his legs and stuff. Yeah.
I should have his legs in his chest.
That's awesome. Peach fuzz on his arm.
So I trim that. You cut it
off. Good. I use clippers.
Oh, you don't ever want to ask
you when you breastfeed him,
do you feel like going?
Yeah.
Are you
all on the graphic tee?
You
watch talk me dry.
Thirsty.
Well, it's always though that
gets me, oh, it's so gross.
Yeah. That's why I say it Ellis, every
time it's so weird that you did you,
every time you get them you go like fast,
come a little bit loud,
sign to suck me dry.
What is happening? You're
really fired up. I like it.
I get it. You think I'm saucy
today? You're a spicy. Yeah, I see.
Ooh, get sauce. Bearnaise yeah.
Yeah. You're really fired at
a German. It's so, it's, it minds
me. My Dad's accent a little.
I think that's why it's alarming to me.
Yeah.
What one your dad came over
yesterday just chillin, Bro.
Did you like that? Yeah, he came over
wearing like five neon colors. Yeah.
Did you notice it came
out of Real player player?
Like he had a bright neon orange jacket.
Here's what's up. And then like some, uh,
like yellow flare and his shoes,
another color shirt and other colors,
shorts and other colors, socks.
Another color, glasses. Shades were
yellow and he's like, yeah, I'm good.
I'm getting at, I'm doing my thing. You
feel me? Don't tell talking about I'm
his feathers.
Right. He's at the helm. What?
Mitch you, I'm saying? Yeah.
You know what I'm saying?
Mutual home. Good motherfucker right
there. You know what I'm saying?
That's how you, that's how
I hear what your dad, yeah.
It's just how I know it's arts. Yeah.
How many other brothers and sisters,
what do you feel like? What do
you feel like when, uh, when you,
when your dad was spitting game yesterday?
It's so funny now that I'm a mom.
Like now that I'm a parent,
it kind of doesn't affect me as much.
It's like this weird thing happens
where you forgive your parents for their
personalities are like, now you're
just crazy. Yeah, that's fine. Yeah.
You think you've tried but he's got a
great personality. No, he's awesome.
But you know what I mean?
My Dad's not like, um,
like the all American Dad, you know, he's,
he's got his own stuff happening.
Very unconventional, I'd say. Yeah.
But Fun. Right? It's totally fun.
He's like Party Dad. He is party dad.
He's probably dead. I mean,
that's what I feel like.
Your dad sounds so weird.
Did he talk like that? Yeah.
Well he was spitting game
yesterday. Yeah. Like plans,
rolled takeovers kind of shit.
I know he lives in a really good mood
though. He loves being a Grandad.
I think this is really changed
him. Uh, he's really happy.
He keeps talking about
how good looking the is.
You said it like 10 times when you
left. Yeah. Doula. He was like,
this is a good looking kid. That's why
he's always like, some baby is so ugly.
This baby is not ugly. He's a really good
looking kid. Was, he's a big boy. Big.
Then I go, yeah, thank God. You
know, it's like he's, you know,
it makes you feel more comfortable that
he's getting sturdier and he's like,
but also as a man, you want your book
to be big. And I go, yeah. He goes,
yeah. I go, you know, I think we're
going to put Alison to sporks when he's,
when he's a boy and he goes as good idea.
Maybe tennis.
Tennis is good money. And
Dennis, I go, what about soccer?
Soccer's for poor people.
I go down,
we're not going to send them to Brazil
in a favela to play. He's going to play,
you know, in La. Yeah. Other kids?
No, no, no suckers for poor people
that is as good. There's money
in 10. Yes. How about Marshall?
And he's getting sponsored right
away. Yeah. Like what? He's hungry.
He's not going to make a living. Yeah, I
go. What about martial arts now? No money.
A martial arts. What is the money part?
I guess just like people with money.
Oh, I got it. Yeah. Yeah. Well
then golf too, I guess. Right?
Which should sign him up for
golf. So boring. Oh my God.
What if that's his favorite
sport? I thought about that.
I mean, you never know.
I remember when we were, um,
probably like over 10 years ago,
my buddy read was about to have his
first kid and they knew it was a boy.
He was Luby's excited, you know, go
to baseball games and play baseball.
And I think one of, one of the other
guys, Casey or somebody goes, uh,
what if he doesn't like baseball?
And you'd like,
you can see it hit him in the head. Like,
I'm thinking about that. I was like,
well what if he lives or what have
you liked soccer? He goes, well,
I'm not going to go to the games,
but I still love him.
Please not going to support
his kid. Hey, I got a soccer
game today. I'll see you later.
It's terrible. Yeah, he was. He was
sold on that. Like I'm not going,
I'm as too boring. What if our son is into
something retarded that we don't like?
Like what's the most boring thing to
watch swimming, but that's fucking boring.
No swimming I could watch cause it was a
race. So race, race is always exciting.
Uh, if he sucks at swimming,
that would say, yeah,
like if he was like always laughs,
like swim.
Yeah. But no, I don't, I think is when
it's your kid, you don't really care.
I mean I would, I would go watch
them do anything. Don't care.
I'd watch him take a shit. Yeah,
we do watch and take shits.
That's true all the time. All the
time. We hold a mess. He's shitting.
That's my shit's in our hand.
I like, I kinda like it though.
It's like he's doing something,
you can't do anything wrong, kid,
whatever you want to do.
We support that.
Did Not say that I actually
meant to hit this. I'm like,
oh, but that button's right
next to the others. Yeah, it is.
I'm putting a little marker on it and
then her priorities. There you go.
There you go. There you go. Okay.
All right. Um, okay. Thompson Cora.
Oh, I got to tell people this
real quick. Um, God blesses you,
but also to anybody that bought the,
what blesses you?
Anybody that got the cane shirt. Um,
I've gotten a number of messages.
We would try and respond to everybody.
It was a presale and the Presale,
you know,
you sell it up to a point and then
they ship. So there's been a delay.
And for people that didn't know,
I apologize.
And here's what we're doing to
anybody that ordered a cane shirt,
you're all getting an extra
free item from our store.
Um, and that's how you, what it is.
It's just going to come in there. Uh,
but everybody,
everybody that ordered ones would get a
free extra item to make up for the fact
that a lot of people didn't
know it was a Presale,
even though it says it on the
order form. Um, additionally,
next week we should have a new
shirt and it will not be a presale.
It'll be an, uh, shipping, uh,
ship immediately order. Um,
so hopefully we'll be ready
to announce it next week.
I'm not even announcing it until those
are in stock. It won't be a Presale,
but I'm just letting you
know now if you got it,
you're getting an extra free
item to make up for any delay.
We just wanted to point
that out, okay. Okay. Okay.
What's the free item? Is
it, did you shave something,
your pubic hair off his pubic hair?
I was doing,
I didn't want to tell anybody
but his pubic hair. Yes.
Do you think someone would pay a
premium for Tom Cigarettes? Pubic hair?
I would guess no.
You been getting a lot of fan mail
from gay dudes who are really into you
pubic hair. Yeah, we read, I read that.
I sent you that one. Did you go love it?
I love Fan mail from your
gay fans that are like
your gorgeous, my stoma. Okay.
They're not saying I agree with that.
I agree with you guys.
My husband is gorgeous and yeah, there
was one guy was like, please, if you,
if you also, if you sell a show, please
play a bear in the show. Yeah. Yeah.
He's like, I'm angry. We would love for
you to come do this private event for us.
Oh, okay. Attitudes that
are the dudes at the,
or the dude's there, dude. Yeah.
There's a lot of, there's a lot of
fanfare from that. I don't mind it. No,
you know what I'm saying?
That I'm talking about that check
or cash [inaudible] you feel me?
I'm telling about that's what's
up. What I'm saying. Hitler.
You want to talk about Hillary first? I
like to address it. I just feel like, uh,
we,
we did stumble it,
you know what's interesting is that you
and I fall in love with like the first
part of clips.
Yeah.
And then we just completely forget
to listen or pay attention. Yeah.
Kind of like came in when we
discovered, sorry, canine. Okay.
We were just like enthralled with her.
We didn't even realize she was
giving an anal tutorial and,
and how crazy she was.
Huh? What is also amazing.
Why is two gentlemen I may yeah,
yeah,
yeah. With lone penis. Oh,
we just didn't know. We don't know
it. Hey, Hitler's about. Yeah,
we like a phrase and then we run with
it like idiots and then it can be
something horrible.
Yeah. Um, so one of the,
Oh, so amazing what is also amaze
and I truly, that's what she says.
Like she's convincing. I
truly was satisfied. I says,
I didn't think I could be.
Sounds like Kay may one
way ticket from Thailand.
Sounds like you're kind
of one Donald to talk.
I was 15 years old.
I love when you do her.
I come from Thailand to the
gentleman part. Good man.
I was with two gentlemen. Wait,
can you play or do you, can you,
you have it or I don't want to, um, yeah,
that's a bit too is awesome.
I May,
I'm a
gentleman with la Ha Babysat.
Painted cause he did the, uh, that's
the youtube safe version. Yeah.
I liked that one better than on 60 plasma.
It's a much more hardcore,
but you ain't no mill Tommy. My,
Oh, is that her? Is that key man?
Oh No,
it's just another cool chick
tongue. My stick your
tongue in my os. How?
Hi, I'm Kim Man. I am a model. Yeah.
For more 60 plus melts
now 63 years of age.
Yeah. This is my second time
around here. And surprisingly,
I have an experience with two
young gentlemen who have a really,
really huge penis.
Oh God.
I liked her.
They to these tenets mutually
satisfying that she said that like,
I couldn't believe it. They
truly satisfied. I'm sorry
with two gentlemen especially.
What is amazing is,
is that I was able to take really,
really hard long penis
into my vagina as well as,
and there is solid.
Yeah. Her cadence is amazing. Yes.
I love when people who don't speak
English natively talk cause they do it so
differently.
So I'll sort of like the little stuff,
like making something plural
when it's not so funny.
Jan Demands, they're not gentlemen sweety.
Those are gentlemen you need to make.
You need a mason gentleman's. Yeah, yeah.
Real skew notion of gentleman's. Um,
well back to Hitler when,
Hey Hitler first came on the scene.
Yeah.
It's like we just get,
sometimes it's just like a drop.
We don't really look into it. We're
just like, this is pretty funny. God.
So we played that and
then people were saying,
I think you guys are not hearing this
correctly. She's saying, hey Heather,
hey hiller her Hemler or Hitler,
Hitler,
Hillary's right hand man.
Let's not forget handler.
He doesn't get as much attention.
So then,
um, we go, okay, that's, it's, it's,
it's debatable. Right? So then last week,
um,
another audio clip came to our attention,
right? A blue band pulls it, sends it.
So people are saying,
that's Nicholas.
Other people like myself think it's lit.
Right. Um, and people were
like, no, no, no. It's,
it's know there's a debate.
Well,
what didn't occur to us until
a few days ago was, well,
let's look into these
videos a little more.
The videos on her page.
This is a girl named Danny.
Um,
she has countless videos.
I really don't know how many,
I don't know if there's a way to tell
when you get to there. Maybe there is. Um,
let's see. How many videos did she have?
Can you tell when you just hit this?
I Dunno. Danny Blue Band. Blue Band.
I can't really, I can't tell
grid. Does the grid tell you?
But it doesn't tell you how
many though. Right? People,
that's how many subscribers she
has there anyways, it is a lot.
It's a lot of videos
were paging through it.
I go out and just put up a ton of stuff.
What's one of the first videos
I see asking for Hitler's help?
H I. T. L. E. R.
Crazy Hitler asking for his help.
Hitler. It's me being me. I just,
yeah,
Danielle. Okay, so we know that the hills
a problem we talked about before it.
Yeah.
A few videos later.
The video is titled Asking for
Hitler's help. Number two. Sure.
So it's a second time.
It's so weird.
Hey, Hiller is Nini? Yup.
I have a really big problem right now
and it has to deal with Malen Allen,
new person. Oh Geez, lily.
Hey is stuck and smelling Allen
belly button and I'm a get him out,
but I can't,
so could you help me get him out?
So
that was a fear of going to help
with this. Hey, I don't have,
okay,
I'm having a really hard time getting
him out and I got my belly button.
Here's the thing too,
is that there's only one Hitler,
like after roller to most people
stop naming their children,
adults or Hillary as a surname.
So this is the fewer she is, she,
there's no other Hitler that, who else
could help like that? I mean, obviously,
I mean obviously I'm saying what else
could help? Like even in the afterlife,
he must have some power. They're probably
evil powers and maybe that's why she's,
she's uh, you know, back in
the dark in the lower, yeah,
yeah, yeah. I think she's,
she's saying a Baltimore, you know,
right. Yeah. Wow. Maybe. Yeah.
She's interesting by the way.
So her name is Danny. Yeah.
And she refers to people that watch
these videos and likewise. Dany JAKKS no,
that's great branding. It
is great branding. You know,
she's on top of a branding game.
This is called cause a video here
called warning about a lesbian video.
I don't know what this is about.
Um,
all right.
I only put ads.
Ruins isn't Louis Tomlinson.
That's the guy from one direction.
Is that right?
I don't know.
I'm not a fan because
she has a lot of um hmm.
Let's see.
Isn't English pop? So yeah, I remember
of the, of the group one direction. Um,
she has a lot of videos to him.
Um,
let me see.
So to Hitler and then this
guy from one direction,
those are her two of blogging.
She has some to Harry styles who I
believe's another one direction guy.
That's a really crazy Hitler. Um, yeah.
Then she says, this is a
video called telling Louis
Tomlinson, I'm pregnant again.
MMM. MMM. MMM. Okay. Okay.
So you go through these and then it
says singing happy birthday to an end.
The title of the video. Big words. Yeah.
Lips and it's on youtube titles on Youtube
titled that way the word is totally
spelled out, not like astericks
or so. Yeah. Wow. So now there's,
there's no debate. Um,
it's not a very nice title,
I think even for your dany acts. But
here's the thing, much like, you know,
she's just reading off with the person's
name is, is that her fault that she's,
she's just repeating what's given her big
words. Yeah, I dunno man. I don't know.
There's, there's so many
videos, there's so many videos.
Um,
there's even one where she says
something to Sophia Smith and she's like,
Sophia Smith is bad.
And then,
and then the next week is called eating
Sophia Smith Pussy. Really? Yeah.
And she just looks the air.
What the fuck this chick is whacked.
Um, while she's off her meds. Big Time.
Yeah. I don't know what's going on.
Hey Dany yaks
talk about a personal moments on
'em because it's really personal.
But yeah,
I just have to say to those
like wanting to do, um, okay.
I basically don't why being on?
Because it's really
uncomfortable for me on top.
How to do annual SEC's annual. Yeah. Um,
uh,
why being on top?
It's really uncomfortable for me.
Plus I don't know how it is.
Do Annual Sec's annual site?
Maybe Hilary.
I love being on the bottom just because
oral sex there's a lot more comfortable
cause oral sex.
Sex is good for other people
that I just like oral sex better.
What up? No, you're leaving
that out all together.
I really don't usually talk about this
stuff on you to just be cause there are
like kids on youtube. Um, then
tell him all about annual section.
Then the Hitler stuff is normal for you.
Annual sex is um hmm.
Interesting choices we're making.
Yeah. I wonder if Heather can help you
with the annual sex and the click. Yeah.
Finding the click. Touch my click just
lik that motherfucker right there.
That's wrong with people.
There's a video here called asking
Simon Cowell to do me a favor. See,
I don't know if this is reaching the
people you're meeting this school.
I don't think it is. I think, no, I
think nobody that you're targeting.
Is that right?
Hey Simon,
I know you're actually a
one directions manager,
but could you like do me
favor like really quick?
Um, yeah, you got it.
I'm going to mail a gift to,
to lily for Valentine's Day
and if I do send a gift,
I dunno. I mean for her to think
that Simon cow was going to get that,
it's almost,
it's almost less likely that Simon cow.
We'll help you then Hitler will.
Yeah, I kind of agree. I don't understand
why you think Simon's a harder target.
No one's looking for Hiller. Yeah,
everyone's out for Simon, so yeah,
he really got an aim
a little lower. Yeah. I don't mean,
I think you should start with maybe
like a, like a mayor. The local dude.
Yeah. Maybe somebody on the city
council and then be like, Hey,
will you help me get this guy out of
a belly button that he's stuck in?
Because Hitler and Simon
callow are very busy guys.
Hello? First of all, he's
dead. Yeah. Um, he has a lot
of evil things to do. We can't,
but you can't bother and burden
him with one direction questions.
But I, but oddly enough, I, I could see
Hitler being like, I enjoy one direct,
like I could see him liking the
band on accent is very entertaining.
It's five white guys. I don't even
know if I realize this is nice,
but I don't really see what's there.
What do you know their songs? No,
I don't know their songs, but
they're, I know they're immensely, oh,
we can't play that on this
show anyways. Uh, yeah,
I'd say we should listen to them.
Oh yeah. And there's one here.
It's a nine second video. It says turning
Justin Bieber back into a male. Hmm.
I Dunno.
Back in to a male.
Is this for Hitler?
Hitler. Hitler request. It says it's a
spell. Oh, she's doing what she does.
She does spouse. Yeah. Yeah.
Wow. It's a lot happening.
You think if you had a
kid that was like this,
you may want to pay attention
to the youtube videos.
I'm interested about this right
here because she has a video here.
I'll talks about the ying Yang
twins. Oh, I like those guys.
Yeah. Like, uh,
trying to get you off and they're
actually doing the dirty work.
So Amalia,
who's dirty work doing the dirty work?
Mama Mia, like, yeah.
Yeah. Like suggests she is,
her world is Yang Yang twins,
one direction.
Hitler, you know, housing, right.
Houses.
So this is, this is feeling very Shane
leash. That was going to say that.
And you know what's interesting,
the common thread with
all of these cooky shoes,
you tubers. Yeah. Poor audio quality.
You may never know how to produce
a decent video. Shane Lea,
same problem with the beeps and the yeah.
And the um, and then the
rappers, the fake rappers,
the music beds always too high on
their stuff. Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
That's a sure sign of mental illness.
Kind of do this for you real quick.
Sorry.
Mid Show break now
because I need to be in there.
The Ah,
the little overkill.
Little over done. Okay.
So we solved the Hitler Nicholas Debate.
Um, you know, a lot of times
advertisers have asked, they go,
how do you feel about, um, a pre produced,
uh, advertisement? In other words, we
just give you a file and you play it.
And my feeling has always been no,
I think,
I think speaking directly to the
audience with products that we actually,
you know, use and endorse always works
better. There's more of a connection.
But there's this one ad that came in
where it was pitched to us and I said,
you know what?
I think it'll still work for our audience
even though it's not us reading the
copy it's made and then we play it.
Okay.
And so this is the first time
I'm playing it here on show.
Um, and you know, obviously if
you guys don't like it, you know,
I'll tell them and we'll read the copy,
but I just thought, let's give it a whirl.
So here's a, our mid show, um, ad
love,
delicious homemade desserts,
but recipes can be complicated
and takes so long to make
measuring
for delicious desserts
guarantee
delicious
scrumptious kids will devour this.
Similar A,
here's the cake mix, chips, marshmallows,
chocolate cookies.
Now here's one of my favorites,
just syrup, sugar, cinnamon,
and then just layer in some biscuits
for fresh and warm. Sticky buns.
There you go. I love this.
Do you know that I there,
the books are everywhere now.
Kicked there like at the pharmacy
and stuff. Yeah, I love it.
Well I think we got the verdict.
This is an ad we can play on the show.
I think you'll like it. I like it.
I mean hopefully the audience likes it.
I feel good about it.
What a great product. Clever marketing.
Yeah. Clever branding. Clever,
clever, clever. Pan On and
where you're going next.
But do you want to play the
thing that I brought in? Okay.
So do you want to set this up?
Cause I don't really know.
Like tell them what you did.
Well,
so on that steep bro,
I had a licensed psychotherapist on mark.
Uh,
mark Barone was on and he's from Seattle
and we talked about Carl Young and
synchronicity and I thought since
I have a therapist on the line,
why not have him assess your artwork and
given an analysis on what he thinks is
going on there.
Legitimately.
I've never heard you just said play this.
And I said, what am I playing? Go. Oh,
just just play it. Just play
it. So you had him look at it.
So this is a Skype session
with a psychotherapist and
we finished that steep bro
and I go, Hey, one more thing.
Can you look at my husband's artwork and
just tell me what you see in the art if
it's normal.
And did he pull up my Instagram?
I emailed him a screen grab
of the painting that you did
call her home at last home. At last. I
didn't know the name of the painting.
So when you say the painting, I
have to figure out which one. Okay.
So this is what you did in Denver.
This is, this is on Instagram.
So the listeners can go to
your Instagram cigarette Tom,
and look at this quote,
painting art work. And
let's just see what a
licensed psychotherapist
says about what you through.
What does it signify here?
So with me is Mark Brown and he
is a licensed a psycho therapist,
Highmark by Christina. Thank you for
joining me. I really appreciate this.
Thanks for having me on. Yeah. So, um,
I've just emailed you my husband's,
um, art work that he did. He stayed
in a condo in Denver and the,
all the comedians leave behind
a piece of art for the home,
the house that they stay in. And first
of all, what are your credentials,
um, in, in psychotherapy? If you could
just let us know your background,
what's called a and m a,
which means I have a masters,
master of arts in sciences.
So,
but basically you are a,
you're a professional mental health
person. Yeah. Seven years for awhile.
Okay. So I've sent you the artwork
that we've been discussing.
If you could take a look at it and just
tell me, uh, what do you see here? What,
what would the mental health of a
person making this type of art or what,
what does it look like?
And please be honest.
Well, uh, so there's, there's a what, uh,
what I've never seen right away is
there's a lot of phallic energy here.
Interesting. There's a, first
of all, there's, this gun
is pointed and I don't know if that is,
this is a self portrait or not.
I think he might be.
Yeah.
Um, so there's this gun
with it with, uh, with, uh,
and it's purple, purple
gun with a red kind of,
some fire are kind of shooting
out of the front of it.
And then it's got this,
it looks like a male figure space.
So the gun is pointed towards his face.
And the other Phallic element is that
he's got a really long tongue that's
hanging out of his mouth.
So it indicates that there's some,
you know, maybe fear of this, of this
entered maybe this new students, this,
sorry. There's the way that he
is looking at it, the eye is,
his eyes are really like bulging out.
So it's like there's this like fear,
like obsession, you know,
uh, uh, Dick Obsession. Yeah.
This energy sounds about right.
And then what's,
what's interesting is that above
his head and above the gun,
there's this,
there's this kind of half,
half circle above him, which, which uh,
which looks a feminine,
I would say
it's a dark son. I told
him, but just listen
and it's, and it's black.
It's, it's pitch black. Yeah.
And so that's kind of like hovering above.
And so there's like this, um,
this female energy, which is like,
uh, you know, dark and
mysterious and powerful.
Wow.
Is it both is above him and
then, and then he's, uh,
yeah,
he's kind of, you know, like,
okay,
bound by this, you know, this,
this, uh, his own energy,
you know,
and then there are these,
okay.
His little fingers down at the bottom.
Okay.
It's, they kind of look
like, like claims as well.
They're bushes. The
bushes, you know, the, the,
the birthday, I'm sorry, when
did your husband's birthday?
April 16th. Four days from
the fears seen Aries? Yes.
Ah,
yeah. So fire, he's a fiery guy.
Very, so the, actually that,
can I tell you what I
actually painted was my second
okay.
Option. Oh, really? What was
the first one? The, first of
all, I should tell you this,
the way that I drew that painting,
it's the way that I draw it. You too,
with the bulging eyes and the nose.
It's my go to profile,
how I know the, um, the first
option that I was going to do.
And I only had second
thoughts. I was like, ah,
I don't know if they'll hang it up here.
I was just going to draw a big cock with
balls and have it just shooting ges out
onto the,
and isn't that interesting that Mark's
assessment is that it's valid because the
tongue is kind of a cock kind of sort
of how I would've drawn it. Yeah. Yeah.
There's a dick shooting his load
at your and your mouth. Yeah.
Is it a self portrait? No, it's
just, that's always how I draw
the me part. Is this,
um, the ominous? Yeah.
I don't, by the way, I don't hear mental
illness. Like you like to bring up black,
that black thing. He said it's supposed
to represent the s it's the sun.
Yeah.
Yes,
we got that to you. But it
looks, it's a black side
and it's, and it's shaped like a,
it's kind of shaped like a breast,
right.
And oppressive female breasts at energy.
So it's like this aggressive energy,
kind of like damp and his fire.
I wonder who that is.
Weird.
Huh?
So areas is a very
vascular and fiery science.
So I'm not surprised at all to get
a little bit, we were about it.
Energy. I feel it. I really feel,
I'm really not surprised that,
um, that there's this fiery,
fiery energy there.
Oh Man. Oh, I'm sorry. So that's
what you see in those, those bushels,
those things with fire.
I think there are,
there are a little kind of, which is
a fire. Yeah. Plain sexual energy.
Would you say
sexual or creative energy? They can be,
they can be kind of one in the same.
So you're dampening my creative. Yes.
I'm breaking your spirit essentially.
Like you have all this
phallic energy tonight.
I mean, that's what I've been
trying to get out with an it. Well,
it's actually a little more than that
if you want to keep Martin current
assessment. Yeah, a little deeper.
I would say maybe those are often the
I and the energy I would say is usually
identified as sexual in our culture. You
know, there's this focus on, you know,
male energy and you know,
we'll just everybody, right.
Everything revolves around,
you know,
the Friday and I think libidinal energy,
you're redirecting your creative. And
I'm, I'm obviously squashing your,
the dark cloud above. Yes. Uh Huh. Okay.
How's sex? Right. So that's the narrative.
I'm not saying that that's true,
but still what he's really
looking at is the gun,
which really I think over the represents
sexuality and then the little bunches
of planes underneath it or maybe more
just the creative energy is coursing
through his veins all the time.
Hmm. Interesting. And then
the oppressive, sorry,
does any of this makes
sense? No, I love it.
And then the oppressive female figure
that's dampening his sexual energy,
is that what you're saying?
I Dunno. You know, there's some fear.
I think there's just maybe
a little bit of fear.
I love that. I've always
been scared of you. I know.
That's why I love it that someone
else sees it. Yeah. I love it. I love,
love having an expert.
Isn't it great.
You should have mark do
more of your artwork. Yeah.
And also I'd like to have a gallery
person assess it as per value c and I,
I wanted to get a real artist to
critique it and I actually, I,
I tried and I couldn't do it in time by
the way that Shauna recognize like real
recognize real art talent.
Yeah. And then another artist,
you used my piece for inspiration. Oh
right. That was great. Yeah. Yeah. Wow.
Okay. So he did really, did you see what
he did? I did. It was really spectacular.
I reposted it on my Instagram.
It is not so much better.
It's like a real artist
did it, you know, I love it
around the power because hey,
come on women or power for it.
Uh, uh, difficult because the drawing
is fraught with horrible things.
Terrifying things.
I think it's, I think it's, I think
it's great. I think he has a healthy,
uh, potentially healthy, a youthful energy
about him. That's interesting.
Cause he is 57 years old it,
yeah. No, well energy about him though.
Sometimes the incorrect on the,
you know, yeah. You old man.
He's very spry. Yeah.
He's very, very well.
So, yeah. Yeah. You know,
the ominous kind of breast of could be,
oh,
you let him continue to thing. I'm
57. Yeah. You're a horrible person.
That's good fun. It
also just be, you know,
that having to be having to be this,
this adult,
you know?
Interesting. Yeah. That
makes the, uh, the,
the power that tells him
no to his penile desires.
No.
If having to conform to
this, uh, to this, uh,
idea, uh, the, you know, what an
adult male is supposed to be. It
interesting. So yeah, that
would make sense. He just,
this is my husband's our work and he
just had a child with me and yeah,
that makes a lot of sense.
And you know, he's uh, yeah.
You know what's hilarious?
The tongue that the tongue was hanging
out, you know, it was just so, um,
whimsical, you know, it's just kind of
whimsical 10 code for, to, so it's like,
yeah, there's this ominous like
have to be a parent, but also,
you know,
being a useful kind of plants.
This guy reminds me of my cousin Bri.
Bri. Yeah. The way he sounds, he's sweet.
He's very sensitive. Should I
keep going? There's no other,
I mean that's the assessment
of your art work. I, there's,
there's more detailed if you
want to listen to it later.
I also asked him if you were normal
because you watch so much murder.
All the murder shows. Yeah. Do
you want to know the answer? Sure.
He said that actually,
yes,
because you're in touch with your dark
side and that it's a really healthy
expression of being in touch with one's
dark side. So there you go. You're,
I asked him to rate you on a scale of one
to 10 your mental health. And he said,
I, you know, and in all
fairness, he's like, I can't
really do that cause I kind of,
I'm familiar with both of you from the
show, the podcast, and I can't do that,
but I'd give him like an eight,
eight meaning on a scale of one
to 10 your mental health. Oh,
he listens to this show? Yes. Oh, and he's
familiar, you know, it's kind of biased.
Sounds like he's really
cool guy. He's sweet. Yeah.
You told him I'm 57 I
did. Yeah. Well I was,
I thought he asked me how old does he
look? In all fairness, I forgot. Okay.
So just so he knows now since
he listens to this show,
I am 36 and someone is having
a big birthday this year.
Let's talk about,
let's talk about that birthday
that's coming up for you this year.
I won't be able to see
this birthday for a long.
Really interesting.
What birthday do you have
this year? 30. And then plus,
how many are you excited for it?
No Big One. Can I tell you it was,
what's
devastating
is that Allie really have 10 decent
years left and then it's like the decline
towards death, you know, absolute 50 is,
and then you're just on a downward.
Uh, yeah. Yeah, that's true.
But you can have a really
good run for 10 years. No,
I think for about 20 plus your second
if you're in decent health. Right.
50 to 70 is a really good
run, I think. Okay. Yeah.
But then when are you going to rehab?
When are you gonna get your second wife?
I don't think that's going to happen
until after 50 you think I have 10 years
left on this marriage and then, yeah. And
you're gonna get your 20 year old? No,
I would say 15 years.
Oh, you and I have left.
I think so. And then you're going to
trade me out. Yeah. Okay. That's not bad.
That's not bad. Good run. Real good.
Run 40 can you believe it?
I never thought I'd see 40 I
thought I'd be dead by now.
You know when you're 15 years old
and you're like already man. Wow.
What do you think you're going to be with?
I'll probably be like,
oh my second marriage. Yeah. Well I
don't think you'll get married again.
I think you're just going to
have, yeah, countless lovers.
Parallelize the few air lava
pool boys and stuff. Yeah,
I'll bang like hot young things. I won't,
I wouldn't, I can't marry after you.
I love you too much.
I would really be devastated
if we divorced for like a
whole day or two and then
I'd have to find someone else to grow.
How sad would you be if we split?
It didn't really think about it.
What would you do? Seriously?
What'd you even marry again? I don't
see myself marrying again. Too much.
It's too horrible, right? Yeah.
What would I want to marry again?
I don't want to marry. No,
seriously. No, it's too much.
It's like it's your whole life with this
person. What I would do is project life.
You know, I'd probably go
through like my intense, um,
you know, intense like slut
phase, right? It's normal, right?
So you go like, you know, you bag
like a hundred slots and then you go,
I got to fucking keep it together.
And then you find one that you're going
to date for a while. Then she's like, oh,
I can't wait for my wedding day.
And you go, oh, see you later.
How'd he goes on to the
next one? For sure. Yeah.
And then you're like,
it wasn't a towel.
And this is like,
this goes for almost all of
the moments in the scene.
It wasn't until somebody was actually
there telling me you have to in you or you
have three in you that like it actually,
it kind of clicked. And I'm like,
oh my God, this is actually
happening and I'm proud of my song.
That'll be, that'll be you after
the divorce. Yeah, for sure.
To Send me three and me. No. You know
what? I would jog. Just be alone a lot.
Drink a lot and read.
Yeah, I do. Just quiet.
I don't think I'd want to deal with
dude's anymore. You know, you're all,
you're all over it and imagine
aren't you just fucking over?
Probably 55 I get mad. Yeah.
Just blow my brains out.
No, I moved to Tahiti. That's what I
would do. And just live on an island.
I wouldn't even fuck with society anymore.
If we divorced a 55 I would go
to Ellis will be grown. Right.
Almost down when he's in college.
I'll go live in Tahiti. Yup.
And just live on the
island fish. Yeah. Dude.
Wild out and just get weird. Oh
yeah. Homesteading, whatever.
A bunch of plastic surgery.
Big chompers.
Big Old Steve Harvey's in my mouth.
Hey,
you're 22 I'm 55 Aria.
I want your veneers to be extra
bag and hang out at clubs in Vegas.
You guys want to have some drinks on me
and I'd be like that all guys
bought and I was all drag Scott.
We'll have like a silk shirt with
a big like fire pattern on it.
That's the sad you just described.
The saddest doors. The status guy.
It's the guy in the neighborhood that
drives the yellow for are you got a
houseboat
sometime?
Houseboat is the saddest
divorce guy thing. Aw.
That's when you know you blown it.
Living on a houseboat.
Kids every other weekend.
The pretty cool water
because I think the fantasy is they're
going to live like Miami vice course.
Didn't he live on a house but with a
crocodile or some bullshit dude. Yeah.
I mean I feel like if for some reason
talking about it makes me feel like it's
real. I feel so sad. Right?
Jeans. No, the houseboat.
I'm saying fuel is really written
like not the divorce part. Yeah.
No and that's the divorce part.
Well,
they'll cause a houseboat feels like
a divorce it, eh? Yeah. It's terrible.
So I got all this stuff here now.
It's so just not,
it's amazing how little you need to live.
And Wifi is overrated.
Oh yeah. Rock sometimes.
Cause it was about, no,
I don't like a kitchen either. Got
this microwave. It works awesome.
Everything's microwave and I just need
an Arby's. Yeah. And it's so depressing.
It's depressing man. Anyway, so
did you like your art assessment?
That was really great. Thank
you. What's his name? Mark.
Mark slipped or private to mark.
Thank you very much mark.
I actually really did enjoy that.
And you can hear mark on this week's
episode of that steep bro discussing
synchronicity. Phenomenal therapy to
what's therapy and what's the point?
Damn cake.
Pineapple upside down.
Well you get hair plugs to oh yeah,
yeah. But I want it to really thin it.
Like really,
really go bald first and do like Doo Doo,
Doo Doo Doo like stabs in there.
It looks like little stocks
of salary all over my head.
Hey girls, the saddest is
when you show old guy. I mean,
I haven't been to a club in a long time.
I've been in clubs where you see,
you know, or at the bar.
Yeah. That guy. Of course.
What do you ladies drinking?
I got it.
Let me go around for all of them.
Hair dyed, jet black. Nice and easy.
Here's a good lesson for people.
I'm also single,
married,
divorced.
It's all about sending
the quality dick pic.
Yeah, my top pick.
Okay,
well number one
irks my nerves.
She did my Nigga baby oil was $2.
Get yourself together.
That's a pretty good list.
I didn't know Dex could get
ashy. Well, you don't see
enough black cocks. Oh, true.
If you did, you see something rational?
I wish I saw more even brown ones. Yeah,
sure. I didn't know. Rule number two,
make sure your shit is hard
and that was a good point.
That's good for every race
like this because we're all calm.
You say Amy and everybody,
grandma,
I don't know what he was thinking.
Girls are mean and petty and
that's the Shit we do now.
Anytime we look at your limp dick
ass picture, she's going to cry more,
right? Yeah, I agree with
that. Make sure, you know,
I've never been sent a dick pic other
than yours because we started dating
around the time cell phones started.
No,
I can sell phones back in 84 people.
Four people sending Dick Pics
in 2005 yeah, but I probably,
it was probably not like today.
Today. Yeah. No, it's a thing.
It's really much bigger now, but
I agree. It's like watch porn.
Nothing makes me angry. Or they
know a limp. Dick, especially you,
you get this hard before the scene.
You've expressed this before.
So I saw one of those like showtime behind
the scenes pornos and that's what the
director got basically mad at
the guy for. He's like, dude,
I want you to pull it out,
ready to go. And they gave
him time alone. They're like,
go get it ready. And the guy couldn't
do it, so they killed the scene. Oh Wow.
Said no shooting today.
It's a lot of pressure though.
I think he's a lot of pressure. I'm
ready to get in there though. It's again,
an important is that you're divorced
career. Yeah. That's a good,
I think it's a good second career.
I think that's just not a good
one in the early like in your 20s,
but good for your 50s and stuff. Well it's
a niche market. They got that old man,
young girl. But is it is it's also, um,
you know what the hook could be that
it's a self funded thing. Other words,
not someone's not going to hire me,
but maybe I produced them.
Myselves get a site, put
it out there. Hey, I'm 55.
I'm recently divorced. I'm doing these
pornos now. What do you think to do that?
Great idea. Maybe you could, uh, the
good news is your parents will be dead,
so no one's,
they'll be dead.
Our son will be in his sexual prime would
be a good example for him. And then,
um, it also could also, yeah, what fund?
Send more people to my standup shows.
It's always about selling more tickets.
So you go, hey, you like my
porno. Come see me to stand up.
That's a really neat angle.
Business Savvy.
Rule number three,
brainiac made sure she wants you a dick
pic ain't nothing worse than getting the
eye known as dick pig. Like who are you
and who sent you with his lip as she did?
Save yourself the trouble and get to
know it's also how you lying bitch,
bitch. Yeah. You should. I think an
unsolicited Dick Pics. Not Good. Right?
I, like I said, I've never, I'm
received and that's not a call.
Don't send us your Dick Pics. Yeah,
no. Uh, I don't know, I guess.
Yeah, right. Do you include
the balls in a dick pic to,
I don't think it's as important,
but they're there.
I'd like to know that they're
there. You want, well, how would it,
how would the person is saying you just
like, you mean like from above? Yeah,
like I want to see the Dick and the
balls because I think balls are neglected
and they're often just as
important. So send those. Yeah.
Let me see if those look high and tight.
If they're not, I'm not interested.
I don't like droopy goat nuts. I
don't like, I'm hanging in sad.
I'll ask my dad to send a picture of it.
Is His boss really hang?
I saw them one time and know is
everything all right with what?
And I go your ball bag. Yeah. It looks
like it's hanging down on your knees.
They look like to pig nuts.
Seriously looked like cinder blocks that
are just in like a skin in a paper bag.
That's about to tear open. Yeah. Do
they hurt when they get that hanging?
I don't think so.
They look like they weigh a lot though.
A number four,
make sure your Dick pic is memorable.
Girls Gets Hen Dick pics a day.
Make Yours stand out like gift wrapping.
Stick it in the ball to her favorite
ice cream. Kelly. Oh Shit. Pig.
Do something with it. Other
than that, hold it like we
don't want to see you hope.
I'm still
surprised that you don't think the
unsolicited Dick pic is a great thing to
point. Like nobody wants that.
Oh, I don't want to see anybody's,
which is the point she made and
you're like, I don't like unsolicited.
It's gotta be the worst. I imagine
if you're a guy, don't send a girl,
just a dick pic thinking that it's
going to be exciting. I think the whole,
the whole proposition of sending a dick
pic is ludicrous. Most women I do too,
but what I'm saying,
I want to see a deck.
What I'm saying is when you
send an unsolicited one's crazy,
you're really not just rolling the
dice. You're, you know, you're,
you're at the risk of truly upsetting
someone. Yeah. So legal action, legal,
also embarrassment. Why
don't you make sure that your
dick pic would be one. Okay.
Or maybe she sends you a pick first.
You know like,
oh here's a pair of scissors and my coach,
now you send me your Dick
pic scissors in my, yeah,
the Dick pic is a very male thing I think.
Cause they have dicks other guys. No,
no, no. I'm saying like you don't, you
know, who wants to receive a dick pic?
Other dudes like it's not necessary.
I don't,
at least from the women I know we don't
get that aroused by a picture of a cock.
Like it's not the same thing.
The same as guys also looking at
naked women badge is, I assume. Yeah.
Like for us it's not, we, I think we
like to see a dick attached to a body.
At least that's what, as a woman,
yeah. Show me the whole thing.
Don't just send me your car. Who
Cares? Plus the scale. You don't,
there's no scale in a,
in a picture.
So I'll hold something next to
your deck would be your, yeah,
that's a better poet.
Hold a can of soda next to your day.
Some reference scale. Yeah.
Yeah. Cause I don't know.
You can make it look enormous and it's
not wire. Yeah. Pick a fucking liar.
Make fucking liar. Get
a hairspray can, yeah.
There you go. Wow. I've sent a few
experience. Yeah, I'm on the road a lot.
So
let's see here. Um, oh,
this came in. You know,
you know about this guy, right? Martin?
Is it strictly shell? Shell clue?
What's his name? Martin Shkreli. Uh,
this is the guy who,
he's the most hated man in America.
Um,
he became really well
known, I don't know, six,
nine months ago when he says,
uh,
when he has the company
that he was a CEO of,
bought this patent on a pharmaceutical
drug that helps like AIDS patients.
And it was selling for something like 12,
$13 a pill,
something like maybe $7 a pill
and he raised it to $700 a pill.
Oh my God. And then there was just
huge backlash. What a pos is kind of a,
yeah. Oh, the biggest pos.
Then, not too long ago,
he was arrested for a company that he
used to work for a hedge fund for like a
Ponzi scheme there. Oh, wow.
So everybody was celebrating.
Apparently there's a new
thing here where he, um,
it looks like he says a friend of
Kanye robbed him of $15 million.
I don't know how that
happened because see,
it says I'm keeping his name in the
headlines. Oh, there's a new, you know,
a cognac out called the life of Pablo.
He made a $15 million offer for
exclusive ownership of the album.
Um, but it'd be put forth
50 million on the album,
only to be duped by a bit coin
thief by the name of De Quan or,
um, and he's writing who
the fuck has my $15 million,
uh, someone named. So anyways,
so he's saying that, you know, all this
shit. Now he also, in addition to this,
had a beef going with, uh,
Ghostface because he's the guy.
Do you remember that? A
few, like a year or so ago,
Wu Tang decided to release an album with,
they would only make one copy of and the,
and it had like some crazy, you know,
uh,
cabinet chest made and it was one copy
and then the person who bid on it would
own that copy and they could do as they
please with it. I didn't know that.
That's okay. It's kind of a crazy
idea. Well he won. He, he owns it.
There's Pos. Pos bought it for
$2 million. And then the idea,
a lot of people thought that whoever would
do it would buy it and then share the
album,
you know,
cause that would be the joy in it
had thing to do is share the album.
Well he said he's never even listened
to it and it doesn't plan on sharing it.
Wow. Just has to have it basically
like, you know, like a villain,
like a sociopathic piece of shit
that he is. So yeah, he's a,
he's a fucking wow.
What a cool guy.
So this piece of shit, he's also
tweeted some bullshit to Ghostface,
um, cause go said something
about him. So he called him, uh,
you know, I dunno, it
caused some type of asshole.
He said ghost is mad that the
Shaolin outsold his last five albums.
Do the nonprofit rap rapper basically
saying he doesn't sell records anymore
talking shit.
Well there's somebody you don't want
to talk shit to this ghost face killer.
Right. I don't know if you remember, not
too long. Over the summer actually, um,
uh,
action Bronson talk made a kind of a
slight dig at Ghostface and goes put out a
video where he just eviscerated
this guy for a full fucking,
I don't know, 10 minutes. Um, he
just talked mad shit and he's like,
you got a big ass bitch one day I
might sit that shit on fire. Yeah,
it was my favorite line ever.
I might sit that shit on fire and then he,
he has a his mean face.
It was like a fat kid.
So Ghostface made a new video.
This one is over 11 minutes long where
he's talking shit to this super bill and
Pos Martins strictly whatever.
Um, so here's some stuff,
some stuff right?
Why is that not as far as mine.
Yeah.
Hello?
Yeah. So I don't know why his bleak,
but Martin says, where are your
goons? Not as hard as mine.
He was lifted up your skirt motherfucker.
So
already Ghostface winds,
the entire thing
goes to stop pretending. Stop
acting. Stop lying. Yo Man.
Yo Man, you hilarious man. You
must be on real in a certain man.
You know what I mean? It took
us out, man. It's like, Yo,
you will forget supervillain man,
the man with the 12 year old bag,
this will he be, his name was Corelli
right there when y'all see him.
You know what I mean?
He does. He is built like a,
like a young man. Uh, Martin,
the Pos. Oh, it's 12 year
old buttons. Yeah. So He's,
he's talking shit about his build,
which, you know, I don't even know how
we change to this. Like this is goals,
verse three to pay it like 2016 you know
what I mean? All you can do right now,
just try to fly away in front of my face
with this is, this is, this is error.
Check this place out, man called dot
knows anything. You know what I'm saying?
Walking around with fake goes like,
he's tough and he ain't got to a real
bone in his body. You know what I mean?
I do know what you mean.
Yeah.
I did all tough today.
You won't come at me and you don't
go to check out with the 2 million.
I was acting like we washed the rappers,
like I'm a washed up wrap up,
but you don't put a washed
up rap album for 2 million.
Yeah, that's a great point. Yeah.
Probably the best point is if
you're talking to shit to the guy,
the you bought $2 million.
Yeah.
You get your life getting your entire,
yeah.
So tell her wonder about your seriously,
because I'm wanting to be like, Yo man,
was he jumping rope as a child?
Was he planning on how Scotch or
eat ice cream with his fellows?
You know what I mean?
We'll have the sleep overs with the boys.
Do you understand that?
It's talking about it's ghost,
semi coded way of saying are you gay?
Oh it was as a jumping rope.
As a child you eating,
oh all those activities are
gay. Yeah. For a little boy.
Do sometime I wonder about you seriously
cause I'm going to give him like Yo man,
was he jumping rope as a child?
Was he playing hopscotch or eat ice cream
with his fellow isn't you don't mean
it will have a sleep overs with the boys.
You know what? I'm saying it's like,
where did you go wrong?
Wow. That is fucking hilarious. Wow.
Oh, you don't believe you?
The people don't believe you.
I won't even believe you.
You don't even believe when your own
goons of course. You know what I mean?
He been a video of him like with his,
you know,
Aka his goons, like his body guards
with him talking about like he has,
he has the same kind of street
credit that you might have.
Or like if you fuck with me, you're going
to get from there. Come on. Fox was the,
with this face,
you know what Martin said to the people
out there all over America and all over
the world that my rooms in
his heart is yours. Yeah.
I'm about to show you something.
Hold on.
Can me go,
oh, by the way. Yeah. You know what?
These mobile homes, where are you at?
Where you at?
A party.
He brought in like his mother and um,
a couple other women masks.
Um,
oh, ghost face, by the way,
has a new product out there
that would like to give a,
an unsolicited unpaid endorsement is woo.
It's for your a vape pen,
smoke weed.
Um,
it is a vape dad would be interested
yes. In something like that. Yeah. Yeah.
It's uh, I think he, he put out
a commercial. Oh, that's cool.
Yeah. Well support Ghostface.
Absolutely. Yeah. I'm a big,
I'm a big fan of his fuck that
Martin Guy. And where is it? Is this,
it hit a commercial for it
that I saw somewhere. Woo.
Where? Yeah, yeah. Oh yeah.
He said like if you, I'll just
play if it plays here, this is, um,
his new product.
Welcome back to living made easy.
I am your host fake and
if you're just joining us,
we have a very special guest here
in the studio today, Mr Tony Starks
post brought to share
with to studio audience.
This is a sweat.
He is called the Google.
All you got to do with just put this
goal inside, just dynamite stick.
It's like a pen.
You know what I mean?
Take that hit and off you go and walk
and you've got to start skipping. Done.
The
best thing I've ever heard in my life.
Walking. You're going to start skipping.
He's the best. And he's absolutely
in the conversation for greatest MCS.
Anybody who doesn't know, just doesn't
fucking know. Yeah, it's crazy.
This kid's going to
talk shit to him on his,
on his skill level is
fucking bananas. Um, okay.
Wait, is it liquid swords? No,
that's the jets on the resin. Yeah,
they're pretty Tony Album. Uh,
what does he got? Fish scales? Um,
well he's got, uh, the album
Hemin and Ray Quan did together.
I think they did that together, right?
Uh, Cuban linx. Isn't that them together?
I mean, it's, it's considered
a, uh, uh, Ray Quan.
I'm one of them. He did with them. Yeah,
that's that one. He did it with him.
Um, he, dude, he's unbelievable on,
on all of the, uh, Wu albums too.
He's got incredible. He's
incredible skills. I mean,
even Rizza who produced everybody's Shit,
he said multiple times,
that ghost is, is the best.
Best Rapper. He's a, he's, he thinks he's
one of the best of all time. Look it.
Here's his APP. Oh yeah.
Iron Man, supreme clientele.
Pretty Tony Fish scale more fish.
Um,
collaboration that albums.
Put It on the line.
We massacre and of course all of the uh,
oops,
hang out ones. Anyways
guys. Ridiculously talented.
That's crazy man. Yeah. Total asshole. Uh,
by the way,
we're always looking for champions in the,
you know what I'm saying? You feel
me? I'm talking about um, oh yeah.
And I got to play this real quick
before I go to dental update.
I was live tweeting
[inaudible]
so as I said, I went in for a
dental cleaning last week. I live,
tweeted the event and
basically everything,
I mean I got to talking to
my gums were number three.
Like she was rattling off my number
three, three, three, four is in the back.
And she chastised me, I need to floss
every day. She said, and I was like, look,
I'm a new mom. I don't have time to
fucking do this shit anymore. She said,
y'all have to floss every day.
And then they took a full set of x rays.
How many cavities do you think?
I have?
Four zero.
Zero.
So my teeth are in good shape, but I
did get reprimanded for not flossing.
And truth be told, I haven't
been flossing. Is Madge.
I had the beginnings of mom now,
so I'm not proud of it and
it shouldn't be proud of it.
But she did get through
the cleaning and you know,
I just got a little reprimanded.
Subsetting we're building up
our floss game. I'll admit it.
Have you been flossing
floss last night? Last night you saw the,
you know, I just did, we had meat. Yeah.
You should definitely it after like,
yeah.
Okay.
Um, real quick for the,
you know what I'm saying?
So here's the names are ghosts
now means from just from this,
you know what I mean? You know what I
mean? But you know, you know what I mean?
You know what I'm saying? You know
what I mean? You know what I mean?
You don't mean you don't mean it, you know
what I'm saying? You know what I mean?
You want me, you know what
I mean? You know what I'm
saying? You know what I mean?
You know what I'm saying? It's like,
Yo, man, did you switch it? I mean,
you know what I mean?
You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? It's a
lot of them. It's a lot. Yeah.
I'm like,
I don't have a job that in my
life and so I got to get going.
Meeting to go to.
We've got to roll.
Thank you guys for watching the
show. Thank you for listening. Please
go to your mom's house,
podcast.com Tom Seger.
I dot coms were to compromise and
ranch.com the links to tickets and um,
[inaudible] dot com.com
www dot.
We'll leave you with these jeans, uh,
ghost crew. You know what I'm saying?
All right.
Bye Bye.
Mommy.