Yeah.
Hey, what's going on? It's Bill Burr and
It's time for the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Friday.
Monday morning podcast.
Yeah.
[inaudible]
just checking in on you. Just
checking in on you. How are you?
How's your week going? Oh, don't worry.
It's almost over it stars day, right?
Don't you get paid on Thursday?
Back in the day it did. You
get that fucking check, right?
That'll piece of paper with the numbers
on it. Then you go down to the bank,
you fucking,
you're right on the back of you stick it
in the machine and then the numbers say
you got this number
right. Just a bunch of numbers.
That's all it is. It's
all, it comes down to, um,
I'm actually, I'm in a great mood. I got
a great night's sleep last night. Uh,
went out and visited some friends of mine
and drove home about 80 miles an hour,
85, sometimes 90. Oh, I was
cruising. And even when, you know,
they fixed the highways at night,
you know, which totally makes sense.
You can't do it during the day,
but she always get mad at night.
You like j just fucking cry. He
would have to Reggie traffic.
They got it unfair to traffic jam.
Right? And you get all fucking bad.
Cause if fixing a highway and fuck at
one 30 in the morning when you should be
in bed, right? When the fuck
else are they going to do it?
That's why I just kept telling
myself as I was getting mad,
you know I'd be cruising along. This
is fucking great. This is great.
Look at this. Flying down the fucking
highway. 90 fucking miles an hour.
You should be able to
do this all the time.
24 seven get the population down
with whatever I fucking want.
I can jump on the highway. Happy
then five minutes. Oh Wow. Right over
right.
And then all of a sudden you come over
the hill and you see that Arrow and then
you see the brake lights
and he does go, ah yeah,
fucking assholes.
You know I had AC DC cranking
cause I'm a middle aged,
not even middle aged. I'm 47 times
two is fucking 94 who's kidding?
Who you guys think all red
faces going to make 95 um,
I'm an old fuck.
I'm an all white guy who likes Facebook
and I'm listening to ACDC and I'm
rocking out.
Okay.
My hybrid. Oh yeah. That's what I'm doing.
I'm doing everything to
wearing those Mervin shoes.
Wear those fucking awful shoes that
people a little bit older than me wear and
they wear them with no
socks and dead jeans.
Those slip on fucking shoes that I think
were cool for like two weeks in like
1993 they Mervin's right? Melvin's
okay.
What's a melon? I'm Melvin. Somebody
fucking gives you a Wedgie. MMM.
Okay.
Who the fuck ever thought to do
that? You realize how funny that is.
Okay.
I got to say, well,
nobody thought to do it until it was
pants and then once it was pants,
somebody just like I had God, Damn,
these things are riding up on me and then
it just rode up on the wrong sadistic
guy's ass. And he was like, you know what?
What if I did that a lot
quicker to somebody else?
A lot harder on purpose. Premeditated,
riding up with the jeans and when he
heard the scream of, of uncomfortableness,
it warmed his heart.
And then some other sadistic fuck
sod or maybe just some fucking, uh,
you know, like joke thief, except
like a fucking bully. Like thief.
One of bullies do that.
Like they see a bully bullying
somebody else and be like, you know,
I'm going to, you know, I'm
going to do something like that.
I'm do my version of that. Then
the bully calls him out on Twitter,
then there's a big dust up, right.
Then they got to go on a bully
podcast and clear their name.
Okay.
Anyways, um, who knows,
who knows in this day and age of non
controversies becoming controversies,
who knows what could happen.
Um, yeah, I'm in a great mood.
Like I got home one 30 in the
morning, I put on the Celtics.
I still have even watched the
Bruins beaten the Canadians.
I know they beat the Canadians.
I'm fucking trying to do the
basketball and hockey thing and I'm,
so I'm behind like two games.
The Bruins and I know they got
Vancouver tonight and I just checked the
standings. What the fuck
happened? Or the Canadians?
My Boston Bruin heart was in my fucking
throat when they started off at nine and
Oh my God, oh no, they're going
to end the drought this year.
They're going to end the drought and then
what am I going to say? I got nothing.
I already have.
The only thing I can say is how long
it's been since they won their last one.
Cause other than that they can go like,
yeah, well we got like 52 of them.
It's like, yeah, but you know, the
first 12, you were beaten like,
you know the fucking Montreal Marauders,
the Quebec conquistadores, you
know, you one best fucking, uh,
best five out of nine,
whatever the fucking series
was when you played on a pond,
do you realize how fucked up it is?
And the Stanley Cup was the
size of a shot glass, you know,
hurry up and finish this game so we can
have world war one. Um, that's really,
I mean, I don't give a fuck
that they count those things.
I just like teasing them about it. Um,
even if just count the ones from the
modern era were never going to catch him.
I realized that as a fan. Um, but
wasn't going to say it. The uh,
I still for the life of
me do not understand as we
are now it's super bowl 50.
Why NFL Championships do not count.
Nobody has ever been able to give
me a logical explanation to that.
All right.
Is it because the two leaks combined
rather than the NFL absorbed the AFL?
You know, the way the NBA absorbed,
you know, like four or five ABA teams.
Is that what it is?
But for the life of me,
it's like those championships were one,
they will wonder in those years like
take like the Eagles Eagles like, oh,
they never want to fucking
know a Superbowl gives a
fuck. I mean, that sucks.
I mean, it's been a long fucking time,
but they did win a championship in 1960.
Okay. And the way, the way the NFL
acts like that was caveman days.
Like Mickey Mantle was in
the prime of his career.
Baseball still drops to
their knees, you know,
in honor of that guy. Okay.
Forget about fucking Babe Ruth. You know
who fucking,
he's who's fucking Rehab was eating hot
dogs and drinking beer and catching up
to the fucking the team on the train by,
by jumping in a biplane.
If he wasn't too fucking fat
with weight and balance, right.
They could find a scarf long enough to
wrap around his giant fucking elephant
neck. Right. Why don't they count us
that mood? Jim Brown's title
doesn't count. What was it,
64 65 the last time the
browns wanted slash. Ravens.
Um, I dunno. I didn't know what
the fuck I'm talking about.
I thought it was in a good mood.
Marty going conti. Anyways. Yeah.
I don't know what happened. The
Canadians, like as of today,
they at one point they are know the
season ended today they wouldn't make the
playoffs. So I'm going to go out on
a limb and say that Canadians team,
I'll tell you those, those Montreal
Canadians, they're very streaky.
Yeah.
I'll tell you right now, if
they're not looking unbeatable,
they are looking a unwinnable
I, whatever the fuck you'd say.
Anyways, let me plow ahead here. So, um,
I got to watch that game
at some point, but I'm, uh,
I'm getting ready to do the,
uh, the Patrice O'Neal benefit,
the wonderful Patrice O'Neil, the
best comic I ever fucking saw.
Um, you know, from my generation,
it's just, it, it's just a fact.
He's the best and a wonderful
positive night of, uh,
of hilarity supporting,
uh, the people that, uh,
Patrice was taking care of all his is
his loved ones. Uh, that is Tuesday.
And uh, from what I
hear, it's all sold out,
but we will be releasing it the
last second, uh, a few tickets,
um, here or there, which I guess is
what they do at all conscious people.
We say that going like, you know,
oh I wanted to see fucking whatever,
whatever band, you know,
and a dude you just like an hour before
you just walk up and they release
tickets.
That's like a some sick fucking level
of being able to get tickets, you know,
cause I'd be the asshole.
I just got a fucking stubhub speaking
of which I wanted to go see Bob Newhart.
Bob Newhart is doing a show out in
the desert at some casino. Right.
When I say on the desert, I mean
the 10 east to like lucky, right.
He's out there cause a, you
know that's a, that's a,
I think that's his generation.
That's where they fucking,
that's where they retired.
You know that place was like,
that place was like a
what Brooklyn is now. Oh,
like silver lake out here. Like
where all the hipsters are.
That's what that was to his generation,
I think way back in the day.
And those stayed out there and they
were retired. So I fucking go on.
I go on the inner web, there is
Richard Rolling says on gas monkey.
I go on the inner web and he
and I, I try to get tickets,
sold the fuck out.
I was so upset that I couldn't get a
fucking ticket. But on the other level,
I'm like,
this guy is 83 years old and he's still
selling out the big room in a casino,
you know, fucking
awesome that is credible.
You now ridiculous is that he's worked
clean his whole career and I'm sitting
here cursing up a storm,
giving them compliments. I'm
going to figure out a way,
I'm going to get to that show.
It's all not January 29th.
I'm going to figure out a way to get
in there. I don't know what I gotta do.
You know,
maybe I'll fucking drive all the way
out to the desert and I'll stand around,
you know, hoping that maybe a
couple audience members died.
The tickets got freed up.
Um, I'll come on bill,
let's, let's, let's,
let's not take it to a negative place.
Disclose to the AFC and NFC championship
games. How could you do that?
You know, speaking it dying. By
the way, speaking of death, um,
you know, I went on the Internet
today and I was looking up, uh,
a with a fuck. Is it? Oh, here it
is. Here it is installed later.
Get out a beat. It trying
an hour try tonight.
Jesus hugging me more fucking
needy. All right. Where is it?
New York City.
Yeah.
Discuss is world's largest tax funded
mass grave might be turned into a park and
I lived in New York. What bad debt?
Start spreading the news.
I'm wearing sweat pants.
I'm gonna go down to Tad stakes Eddie
some shit and I'll feel like I'm making it
the air, you know, successful New Yorkers
thing just cause they're in Manhattan.
You know what I mean? Everybody looks
at themselves like they're the star,
you know? No one sees themselves as
background, you know what I mean?
You're the ones waving up at the
Beatles. You're not in the Beatles.
You understand? You're the one
in the crowd screaming, you know,
fainting and security takes you out as
you're looking at somebody successful.
Right. That's who you are. Yeah.
Those people already on the subway as
they try to jam another person in there
and the world needs you.
The world needs you. Okay.
If I can go to white castle and
a boat Odo 18 or those burgers,
I'll be a fat tated
fuck in the upper deck.
I'm sorry. All right. World's
largest tax funded mass graves.
So there's an island out there,
which I had no idea. Uh, I mean,
I knew of Ellis Island and then as the
island at the Statue of Liberty is on,
then I knew there was one that
the navy owned or some shit,
but there's this other
island out there that, um,
they just bury people that don't have
any money or nobody knows who the fuck
they, it's called Hart Island. Or
is it towards some Boston would say,
fucking had island.
Let's go out to Highland Joe, and
maybe we can find a fucking goal.
Got In trouble with the bookie.
Um, Hart Island, New York,
Rosalie Grable looks down
over rows of white pipes,
some broken or covered in
mud, sticking out of the dirt.
Each tube marks the
grave of 150 adults, uh,
dash homeless poor veterans and
unclaimed individuals who couldn't afford
anything but a spot in what's widely to
believe to be the world's largest tax
funded mass grave, you know,
tax funded mass grave, not
mass grave. Cause believe me,
I think the isn't there
one underneath the,
okay,
isn't there one underneath like
Wall Street, these mass security,
a bunch of native Americans as some shit
and then they just bury them all isn't
what they used to do back then.
All right, that takes care of that.
Who wants to build a log
cabin? Right? Lunatics. Um,
so whatever Grable, a 64 year
old resident of the upper,
upper west side wants grass and wild
flowers to hide the dirty white plastic.
She's come here to honor her mother who
died in a hospital bed with no savings
to leave to her daughter. She said,
I'm still getting used to the idea that
my mommy wound still calls her mommy.
That's creepy. A wound up
in a potter's grave. I know.
That's my mother. I know that my mother
was expecting something more true,
much more traditional. I don't
understand people who like when they die,
they want to have one of those
above ground fucking like tombs.
You know like the above.
It's like the above ground swimming
pool of grave sites. You know?
It's like how fucking special do you
think you are? Cause it you're dead.
They should just have mass graves.
They should have a giant pit.
You just fucking,
you know the family doesn't need to see
it but yet his fucking throat in there
though. It in there and
then you, your dissolve,
you become the next fossil fuel. Right?
Think about all the fucking people
that have lived in the world.
If we had in one giant fucking massive
grave and each country and you use
whatever fucking whenever you,
I don't know how the fuck he end up
turning into motor oil whenever Deli.
That's what happens.
I know if you jump off a building you
explode like a water balloon because
you're mostly water and a, I don't
know if you eat a lot of Italian food,
you know like I do. You got a lot
of olive oil in you. Who knows,
maybe you even help out somebody
who's fucking lawnmower in the future.
That's what they should do. Holy Shit.
That I just solve global warming.
Or maybe I solved the Middle East crisis
and if elected,
I will begin burying all dead
Americans in the same hall.
All
in a hundred years from now, we
will use the fossil fuel that,
that is created to free ourselves
from the Saudi Arabians.
Okay.
I am so sick of seeing world leaders go
to the UN and act like we have a friend
of some sort of a friendship.
Um, I dunno if there's,
that's something you
could do. But anyways,
I became fascinated with that
expression. I was saying, right.
Potter's grave. So I looked
it up and of course, you know,
my research on the Internet in the
Internet never goes past Wikipedia.
Never goes past it, you know?
Okay.
Uh, all right.
A Potter's Field Comma poppers field or
a common grave is a term for a place for
the burial of unknown or indigent
people or is that indigent?
All right. So I clicked on
indigent or ended. I don't,
isn't it astounding how fucking dumb.
I only mostly astounding about how stupid
I am is the fact that you guys fucking
listen to this.
I actually thought it was halfway smart
until I started reading out loud here.
I, N D I, g e n, t indigent.
Indigent. You say tomato. I say indigent.
What? And digit indigent. I'm
just going to stop saying,
I just, I'm just, I feel like every
time I say it, I'm like, fucking,
I'm like that guy. I played blackjack.
Want to hit me, hit me, hit me over.
Over. Your fucking IQ is just going
down. All right, so I looked up a,
that word that I'm not
gonna say anymore. Oh God.
Is it possible to get embarrassed on
a podcast that only you are doing,
you know? Yep. It's possible. I'm
doing it. All right. Park and I,
and when the ends up coming up is poverty.
Poverty is a general scarcity dearth
or the slate of one's money. Well,
what the F, how did this come
to a FTE industrial revolution?
Mass production in factories made product
production goods increasingly less
expensive and more accessible of.
More important is the
modernization of the agriculture.
Said fertilize it dented at debit, but
the poverty reduction is a major goal.
Oh, give me a fee. Is it really,
is it really a major goal when the
fucking CEO takes 80% of the profits?
Huh?
One of the guys who's
fucking working the line,
his daughter's already hooking his
up in the CEO's office, blowing them,
you know, cause she can't go to fucking
call her. Then the circle is complete.
Oh, that was a little poetry there.
All right. The u s expression,
let me get back to the Potter's
field. The u s expression,
Potter's field derives from
the Bible. Oh, GJ page.
Referring to a field used for
the extraction of Potter's clay.
Such land used for agriculture
could be used as a burial site.
So after they dug out all the clay,
they just threw people in there. Well,
there you go. That's a good use of space.
Okay.
All right. The term comes to all,
let's, let's read some Bible. Oh my God.
I know. I've done this. Read some
Bible Brits read from the Bible.
The term comes from Matthew
27 Semi-colon oh colon,
three dash two seven colon,
eight in the new testament of the Bible
in which Jewish priests take it's 30
pieces of silver returned
by remorseful Judas Colon.
Oh Jesus. It'd be some antisemitic shit.
Okay. And then so it says then Judas,
who portrayed him? I
think that's Jay Star.
He betrayed Jay star. They're seeing
that he was condemned, repenting himself,
brought back the 30 pieces of silvers
to the chief priests and ancient saying,
I have sent in betraying
innocent blood. But they said,
what does that to us? Look
out to it. Yeah, there you go.
There's the antisemitism right
there. Hey, what do we give a shit?
Just give us the silver
pieces there. Rod Judy.
Okay.
And casting down the pieces
of silver in the temple,
he departed and went and
hanged himself with a halter.
Definitely a halter top.
They had those backs there,
but he hung himself with a
little fucking sports bra. Uh,
but the chief priests having taking the
pieces of silver said it's not lawful to
put them into the core. Bona
didn't Chrysler used to make those,
the Chrysler core Bono with orientee
and later the term Mike box.
What the f I'm Mike Box.
Isn't that a bug also arms box or poor
box refers to a box that is used to save
coin or a piggy bank is what you
should say to save coins for charitable
purposes or for charitable purposes.
Oh, so then, okay, I get it.
So then they say, wait a minute,
this guy killed the king of the Jews and
was sitting here with the fucking loot
from the caper.
We'll go stick it in the fucking
donation box and nobody says a word.
You got me. All right. And then they,
after that they had consulted to get,
you know what? This might be a
new section. You want me to guys,
I'll start reading the fucking Bible and
I'll give you my interpretation of it.
Gradually I'll start my own church, right.
And I'll say that I have a direct
link to he that is the one if,
and then gradually I'll slide my
direct link over into just saying,
hey am maybe I'm that guy. I am that guy.
I am him a blow me. I'm
fucking all the women here.
A you guys get out in the field
and grow some more apples.
It's basically fast forwarding through
running a cult. Oh does the FBI here,
everybody drank this
over the lips and over the gums. Suck
it down. Here they come. All right,
throw the site. Refer to these
verses known as the bookbub up above.
Okay.
That's really interesting and fucking
said there is something sad about that.
Right?
Is anybody ever had like a fucking
marquis on their head site? You know,
like a big gravestone
and then just have like,
you know like the Chicago theater
but like to scale to a headstone
performing for Aternity
or some hacky fucking former
show business a Christ.
Now I gotta look this shit up. Now
I've gotta look this shit up. Yeah,
those people who have wacky
headstone saying, here we go.
Funny headstones.
Okay.
All right, here we go. What do
we got here? What do we got here?
Images for funny headstones.
No. What are the odds?
Any of these are going
to be funny. All right,
Charlie. All these are just
funny. Named Charlie loser.
Born in 1887 and John Loser.
Jesus Christ is such losers. They're
buried in the same fucking place.
Joke's over. Let me out now.
[inaudible]
oh, Leslie Nielsen. He's got a joke
on his, what does it say? Let her rip.
I don't know what the fuck that means.
Well, these are just funny names.
Stiff Tipman boogers spanks.
Who put this up here? Fucking Beavis
and buffet. Butthead ones by, I mean,
funny sangs. Jesus Christ, the Internet.
Funny sayings. Headstones. There we go.
Oh my God. This is a riot. Oh. Epitaphs.
Here we go. 15 are the funniest.
[inaudible]. All right. Somebody
has.dot, dot. Well, this sucks.
That's not bad. Billy
Wilder. I'm a writer,
but then nobody's perfect. Jesus.
Oh Jesus. It's such an NPR joke.
Uh, Jack Lemmon in, oh,
it's like a movie headstone.
Jack Lemmon was one hell of an
actor. And a funny one to boot.
Here's his Harry stars in his
final row. Well in the ground. Uh,
that's a good one. Uh, this one
gets to the point. Well this sucks.
Okay.
It was another one. All right.
This one. This ain't bad.
Once you get used to it, that's not bad.
I was supposed to live to be 102
and be shot by a jealous husband.
Okay.
Near this spot. You know something to
actually, if they are all interesting,
I think people would go to fucking
graveyards more rather than,
than getting creeped out by it. Um,
near this spot. Samuel Whitmore,
then 80 years old killed three
British soldiers. He was shot.
He was shot. Bayonetted
beaten and left for dead,
but recovered and live
to be 90 years of age.
This guy's talking shit here. I lie,
but don't you cry for one day to
you will die. Ah, what? I can't
Lindsey Nielsen let her rip Merv Griffin.
I will not be right
back after this message.
That's a winner right there.
I like that somebody wrote
high, get it. Such a comedian.
You can't make anybody happy. On
the Internet. All right, Bill Kugel.
He voted for Republicans and
had little to do with them.
If that was bad.
Here's one. Said I told you I
was sick. That's, that's funny.
Okay.
The other one, I knew this would
happen. Some of these are pretty good.
Rodney Dangerfield. There goes the
neighborhood here lies something,
something hanging by mistake in
1882 he was right. We was wrong,
but we stand him up and
now he's gone. Oh Dude,
you can't go with poetry.
I guess that's it. Well there you go guys.
That's about as good as it gets and
either, you know you can do better.
Okay,
well she just said, what the fuck are
you looking at? I don't know. Let's,
let's read the advertising. Shall We?
Lot of death. A lot of debt this week.
A lot of death on the
podcast. Um, all right. Ah,
here we go. The reeds for this
week club. Debbie, you club Daddy.
My daddy went to Yale. Uh, we've
been, we've all been there.
You come home after a long
exhausting, exhausting day, right?
You want to get shit faced and all
you want is to sip. You want to sit,
you want to sip a glass of wine and relax.
So you can lie to yourself that you're
not an alcoholic because you're drinking
wine. But unless you planned ahead,
you probably don't have
a bottle in your house.
You've already spent enough time wandering
around the grocery store. You know,
don't get lost in the wine aisle.
You just end up picking out
a bottle based on the label.
You don't really understand
it. You get home, you open it,
you realize you don't like Chardonnay
as much as you thought you didn't.
You're holy, big stinks, right?
Please include all of the
following points I'm going to,
you wrote it well with club, with
club Debbie. Daddy, can you get me to,
you have to swear to God. I'll study
a, you never have to go about worrying.
You never have to worry about, um,
being wind free again with club.
Debbie Daddy I puked on the dean is a
revolutionary new wine club that sends you
wine directly to your door, saving you
all those trips to the grocery store.
Not only does club Debby club,
Debbie, I'm not really depression.
I just hang out in the
oval office, send you wine,
they send you wine that you'll love.
Drinking Club Debbie and club Debbie,
my mom seems Barbara Easy. Six questions.
Quiz figures out your pallets so every
bottle you receive is quickly tailored to
your tastes club. Debbie club.
Debbie is leading the great to
glow to glass wine revolution.
I can not even remotely read this week.
They worked directly with vineyards to
cut out the middleman which saves you
money. Club down the head club.
Debbie, I'm going to run again.
Even offers a no risk guarantee
that you'll love what they send you.
Call the action and right
now@clubdebbieactsspeaksspanishisofferingmylistenersfiftypercentoffyourfirstorderwhenyougotoclubdebbieat.com
slash bird don't ever come home to a
wine free house again. Just go to club
debby.com/burr to get 50% off your first
order club. Debbie, my friend Shannon,
other frame of the face
with a shotgun.com/burr.
All right, zip recruiter,
ZipRecruiter. As a business owner,
your company is only as good as the people
you hire. Posting jobs in one place.
Well, that isn't enough to
find quality candidates.
Short staffing leads little time
to post to dozens of job sites.
Well, I have the solution with zip.
Okay.
You can post to a 100 plus job
sites with one single click.
Be instantly matched to candidates
from over 6 million resumes.
Plus you can watch brand new
candidates roll into zip.
Okay.
Easy to use interface within 24 hours. Zip
has been used by over 400,000 businesses.
Insert and improve user
testimony. Colon parenthesis,
please refer. Please reference
testimony. You attend them.
Document and parentheses
offer and call to action.
I'm reading all this shit from now on
today. You can try ZipRecruiter for free.
Go to ziprecruiter.com/byrd and
ziprecruiter.com/berg hi, one more time.
ziprecruiter.com/bark and last.
Lastly, but not leastly trunk club.
You ain't going in the malls,
but you want to look cool.
One of a whole trunk full
of fucking clothes came to
your door. Well, it's easy.
Just go to trunk club.
Don't waste a second and of the new
year in a crowded mall with Trump club,
you can make 2016 your
most stylish year yet. Hey,
and the best part is you won't have
to do any of the work yourself.
2016 is going to be your game changer.
You're going to be getting pussy
like you never got your fresh start.
Start the year off on the right foot
and the right pants were in the right.
Jackets over the right shirt.
Trunk Club is here to handle your
wardrobe so you can focus on what matters.
Watching ESPN.
Please include all of the following
points in your read while you're rolling
them. I'm gonna read them.
Trunk Club takes the hassle man out of
shopping by finding the best clothes for
you and your style. You'll look like
1 million bucks or at least a grand.
And we'll always have the perfect clothes
for the season@trunkclub.com slash
burr you aren't you answer a
simple questions about your style,
your preferences and sizes and
it's all these signed. Uh, they're,
all of those things are assigned
to you by an expert stylist.
Your stylists will handbook, and I'm an
expert. I know what a shirt looks like.
Your stylist will hand pick clothes from
the best premium brands just to prove
what you like and send back
what you don't like it.
Just like that a trunk arrives on your
doorstep filled with handpick clothes
that are perfect for you. Hand pen,
pick clothes from migrant workers out
in the orange grows on the shirt groves.
Try them on. Keep what you're like
and easily return what you don't.
The prepaid trunk trunk club
is not a subscription service.
You only pay for the clothes you keep
from your trunk. No hidden charges,
just great clothes. Call
to action. Slash. Offer.
It's a brand new year full of
possibilities with trunk club.
You'll start the year off
looking great in clothes.
Pick just for you get started today.
How would they not know what the
fuck to do at this point? Good Lord.
This is long. Get started today.
And Trunk Club will style you for
free for free shipping both ways.
You only pay for the clothes you keep.
You've already made these points
to take advantage to go to trunk
club.com/burgers trunk club.com/burford
trunk filled the clothes you'll love
wearing in clay. She case you didn't
notice that the first 50 times I said it.
Additional points, dimension
parentheses, not required.
Trunk Club also offers locations
in La, Chicago, Dallas,
DC in New York City where you can meet
one on one with your own personal stylist
.
We things to do during
a quarter life crisis,
a quarter life crisis. Don't
you love our advertising?
Could just come up with a
fucking phobia you never had.
Who is a quarter life crisis? Oh my
God, I'm 25. What am I going to do?
Was the volume this far down? Did I
accidentally kicked the volume of shit?
Yeah, Christ. Um, don't
worry. Don't worry. I'm,
I'm still working on the garage and uh,
I'll, I'm going to, I'm going to figure
out how to make this fucking work. Okay.
It's becoming, once again, everything
in this house is, is a mother fucker.
And when I finally learned to do
is I'm not fighting the house,
I'm not fighting the house anymore.
I will adapt to it. All right.
Everything has to be some sort of a
geometric shape that doesn't exist yet.
That has no definition than God. Dammit.
That will be the shape of
the fucking room. All right.
Is there anything else I wanted
to talk about? Um, oh man,
this lady fucking cut me off when I was
driving and just the fucking thoughts I
had and everyone that you have be
like, I can't do that and go to jail.
I can't do that. I put
her eye up. You know,
I was thinking about pulling up next to
if I had a paint gun and her sticking
the, when her face out the window
to give me the finger like,
like they all do and just fucking
blast and are right in the face.
And I immediately, I was
thinking about her eyes.
So that's where the paint ball went
and put her eye out. And I got,
I don't Dunno, back the fantasy
up. Okay. Take it down a notch.
Right in the middle of her forehead.
Hit her right in the forehead and watched
the botox shoot out on either side.
Nah, but then you know,
people behind me would take down my
plate and I just was sitting at the red
light behind her. All of these
fantasies of the shit I wanted to do.
Follow her,
find out where she fucking works slash
all of her tires and then take the knife,
stick it right into the head, rest
of her driver's side seat, you know,
with something fucking
written in newspaper writing.
So you know when you take the
fucking letters from the newspapers,
so it looks totally even
more creepy. And I was like,
well why would you do that? There's
going to be cameras in the parking lot.
You can't do that. And then the light
turned green and she made a right.
And I kept going straight and I just
never thought about her again until right
now. And with that,
that is the, uh, you guys
have any yummy hears some, uh,
once you write in the murderer
is fantasies that you have
when somebody cuts you
off and fucking traffic,
all this shit that you think about doing
but you don't do because that's the
difference between you and a
psycho. All you do is think it,
but you don't fuck it. You don't
carry it out, you know all,
at least I hope you do or else I probably
just got put on some sort of watch
list, you know? No, it gives a fuck.
I'd love to be put on a watch list
and I would love to be watching them.
Watch me and see how long they could
watch me before they fucking nodded off.
See watching another hockey game. Oh my
God, this is the worst assignment ever.
Jesus Christ. Um, all right,
that's the Thursday afternoon.
Just before Monday for, uh, just for
Friday, Monday morning podcast. Uh,
have a great weekend. You
can, uh, let's go patriots.
I think this is going to be as always,
it's going to be a very tough game.
Going to be a very tough
game. Oh, by the way,
I finally watched the a
Carolina Seattle game and um,
this is what I have to say. You know, I,
I find it amazing that
the Carolina Panthers,
when they had two weeks before that game
even came, right, they had a week off,
so they had two weeks and millions of
dollars at their disposal to get that
field into a better,
like into much better shape
for that great Seattle defense.
It's amazing how they just for some
reason couldn't get that together.
Now it's not illegal.
All you really have to do is just have
a feel and paint some lines and put some
numbers on it. You're not required
to have it in the greatest shape,
but that was just one of those
things as a patriots fan,
you just look at and go, isn't that funny?
I wonder what would happen if we
were to do something like that,
even though it's not illegal.
That'd be a nice fucking five days.
Other patriots up to
it. Again. Um, anyway,
so we're going into a Denver, we're
going into Denver. It should be a,
a tough game. And, um,
I have a melancholy feeling about
this. Like this might be the last, uh,
Brady Peyton manning matchup, you know,
and if Peyton Manning's retires after
this year, and then there's just one,
right, Tom, terrific. And
then some day he'll be gone.
It'll be retired. And it's just,
it's going to be like
Jesus fucking Christ.
I remember when they came in the front
and when those guys came in the league,
I was already in my thirties,
wasn't I? When Peyton come in 97,
I turned 30 and 98. So 30. Yeah, 29,
30 years old on fucking believable.
And they're considered old.
I'll be in my fifties. When Tom Brady
retires. God willing, God fucking well,
God willing. He plays
that long and God willing,
I fucking make it that I am making into
my fifties and don't end up in a fucking
potter's grave. You know,
I wouldn't give a shit.
I think that's the most arrogant fucking
thing you could possibly do is, um,
give a fuck. I get dead bodies
presented for the rest of fucking time.
That's just the fucking needs.
Just like dude, just Frisbee,
Frisbee my body off the back
of a pickup truck down a cliff.
I don't give a shit. Um, oh by the way,
with that just reminds me of something.
The fuck was I going to say? Christ.
It left me. It left me like
all thoughts do. Um, all right,
so that's the podcast. Have a
great weekend. Your con, uh,
should be a great game out in Denver.
I love their defense. Um, of course.
I don't think it's going
to be an easy game and uh,
I am surprised that we have favorites
because we have historically not done well
out in Denver and it always
fucking snows. All right,
I'll talk to you a 20 cons on Monday.
Oh No. Why
Shit about the fucking guy who's
got that? You know, he went
over to, he went over to Uganda,
that Guy Kony Kony 2012. You see that?
You see how quickly they
brought that guy down.
This guy shines the light on the
a, on himself first and foremost.
And how he and his child are dealing
with it, which is really bizarre.
I mean, I don't know about you guys,
but it was enough for me to see the
boy soldier crying because he saw his
brother have his neck sliced
right in front of them,
you know? And he goes from that to be a,
now I'm going to sit my son down and
tell them about the, it's like, Whoa,
I didn't even get it. All right.
So anyways,
this guy shines a light on this bullshit
that's going on over there and all of a
sudden everybody's in an uproar. Obvious.
And everybody gives a fuck about Uganda
and these boys soldiers, you know?
Then all of a sudden the United
States government is going, dude,
we're fighting to boards. We can't
even afford to fight one now.
This guy's bringing this shit up. Gee,
wouldn't it be nice if something fucking
happened that would discredit him?
Next thing you know, a
couple of days later, a,
this guy connected with the film for debt.
Kony 2012 gets caught
jerking off in public.
Was that the only guy who found that
unbelievably fucking convenient.
I didn't buy it for a second. In fact,
I tweeted, you know, back in the day,
they used to assassinate you. Now they
just do this. You know what I mean?
If they can make it look like
we landed on the moon in 1969,
you don't think that they can make you
anybody they want make it look like
you're rubbing one out in the
fucking parking lot. I don't buy it.
What that fucking Douche bag was doing,
not douchebag that fucking self-serving.
Cont there we go. That's
what I was trying to say.
What he was doing with that film was
he was putting pressure on the United
States to go over there and fucking
somehow insert themselves into that
situation, which would have
cost a ton of fucking money,
you know?
But there's no way to be like,
hey, fuck those boys soldiers,
you know, because of,
of, uh, the way the cu,
because of what it says in our pamphlet,
you know, give a shit or you're weak.
Give us your pour and we'll exploit
the shit out of them. And, uh,
let them die of tuberculosis in a
damp apartment. And then years later,
whoever made the most amount of
money gets a statue made out of them.
That's all in our thing.
So we can't look the other way
with these fucking boy soldiers.
So what's easiest thing to do? Just just
make that guy look like a freak show.
First of all, who hasn't jerked
off in a parking lot? Honestly?
You know who hasn't done
that? You know, your,
you fucking girl goes in to exchange
something. You sit in there, you bored,
you can't get any radio reception
because you know, it's back in the day.
You just say, ah, I'm bored. Right?
You've got a girl in
your life. So you know,
there's gonna be some sort of Napkins
in the car. What are you gonna Dope,
right? You got the captain's
chairs. No one could see you.
Yeah.
Oh, this is taking forever. Eh, what am
I rub one out right yet that Dah, Dah,
Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah, Dah
Webinar. Everybody's got a
fucking camera. You know?
You know,
what's amazing is that everybody hasn't
got caught jerking off in public at this
point. Everybody's got a camera
in their raw, their cell phone.
When I'm trying to say people is I
don't buy it and it doesn't matter.
I don't give a fuck whether the guy from
Coney was jerking off in a parking lot
or not. That doesn't change whether
or not this boy soldiers in Uganda.
But what's great is,
is then the conversation switches from
what's going on over there to low let's
this guy doing easy rubbing
his dick like we all do.
And then everybody would be like, yeah,
but we don't do it in public as to what
that makes you better doesn't make you
better. It just makes you
more considerate, doesn't it?
I mean,
if he had two people and they were both
shooting heroin and one person had the
decency to do it in their house and
the other person does it out in public,
at the end of the day,
you're both drug addicts.
So if you really gonna sit there and
shit on this guy for jerking off,
then you would have to
basically be not jerking off
at all. Right?
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, I'm
asking you to look into your hearts.
If you have not rubbed one out,
let he who is not rubbed worn
out in some sort of pop. No,
you'd never jerked off at work.
God, I'm fucking bored. Excuse me,
let me go to the bathroom. Maybe they
think I'm taking a shit standing up,
right? Come on.
If you're a guy in your arms along enough,
at some point you've jerked off in
someplace where you shouldn't have.
You jerked off to somebody you
shouldn't have. You've done it.
We've all been there. Who gives a fuck?
There's still boys fighting and
wars over this. So you know,
if you want to help out, help
out. If you don't, don't,
but don't let some guy rub
one out in a parking lot.
Change your mind either way.
You know what they're doing right now
that doing what women do when they argue
when they start to lose is they bring
up other shit and they spin it into a
different room and next thing you know,
you're arguing a whole different argument
and argument that they wanted you to
fucking argue so they knew that they
could win rather than keeping the argument
on fucking track of
saying, listen sweetheart,
I don't like the way you fucking
been dressing lately. Okay?
I got in this relationship to treat
you like a piece of fucking meat.
All right, and lately
you've been slacking off.
People are still boy soldiers and Uganda.
Whether or not that guys rubbing one
out are open in his ass for the world to
see. Don't ever forget that.
Don't lose sight of
what the real story is.
Okay?
That is all good night and
God bless the United States.
[inaudible]
all right. All right.
Chicken Vice. Hey Bill,
I'm 25 and I've been listening to your
podcast for a year now and I really enjoy
it. I want to get your advice
on my current situation. Yup.
I could have assumed all of
that. Um, because I'm arrogant.
And why else would you write in? Okay.
After a lot of failed relationships,
I wanted to try a new
approach of meeting women.
I met a 21 year old girl through my
sister in law and figured she was
interesting and pretty enough to
consider for a serious girlfriend.
We started hanging out as friends so I
could be sure that I was in fact able to
be friends with her before I made
a move to something more seriously.
More serious, sorry.
Things have been going well for the last
two months and we get together a couple
times a week to hang
out and do stuff. Wow.
[inaudible] last week I finally decided
that I wanted to make my move on her.
I was saying goodbye to
her up to hanging out,
and I finally moved in for
a kiss and she backed away.
Yeah.
It got really awkward after
that and she kind of said, oh,
I have to go.
About 10 minutes later I got a text
from her saying, sorry for backing away,
but I don't want to
ruin our friendship. Ah,
AH, dude, you fucking waited
too long car. I would go,
go watch that Chris Rock special where
he still does the friend zone. Um,
anyways, he says, what
the hell do I do now?
She has always been very flirty with me
the entire time we've been hanging out.
Oh wait, she's been flirting
with you now. Fuck her.
She works at an all girls camp during
the summer and she always hangs out with
me on her days off. So I know there isn't
anyone else she is seeing. All right.
First of all, scratch that. All
right. You have no idea what, what,
how does that expression go?
Okay.
You know, only the devil knows
the secrets in a woman's heart.
Isn't that how it goes? Something
like that. Don't ever fucking,
you have no foul. I
don't give a fuck. Okay.
You could have a woman in a Goddamn cell.
You still have no idea what
the fuck they're doing.
Okay.
Um, the sorceress um,
anyways,
am I to believe she is so naive to think
that we were just hanging out as total
platonic friends.
The only reason I could think why she
would do that is because I am agnostics
and she is a semi-religious girl.
What do you think I should do?
You know what you should do fucking walk
Robert Deniro in heat.
Just walk away. All right.
Just walk away. This is
what you do. All right.
This girl's being all flirted with
you and all that type of shit.
She gets your Dick hard. You're
trying to be a gentleman.
You don't try to fucking finger blast her
on the first day cause you think she's
special. All right, so three days after
flying kites and going on picnics,
you go in for a kiss. She pulls up, Eh,
Eh, didn't want to ruin the friendship.
Give me a fucking break. She knows
what the fuck she's doing. All right?
She's toying with you.
So this is what you do.
This is the best thing that you can do.
When a woman does something like that
that makes you want to go out and eat
fucking sheet metal is you don't,
you don't give them the emotion
that they want, which is she,
they want you to be upset. And, uh, I
don't know. I don't know why I have no,
I don't know fucking why, but she wants
you to be upset. So this is what you do.
Okay? He just say, Oh yeah, hey, I didn't
know what I was doing. That's cool.
That's cool. Whatever. All right.
And then she had very few any fans
and be like, yeah, absolutely,
we can totally be friends. Alright,
so don't try to fucking bang
her anymore. Don't blow her off.
So she has no idea what you're doing.
Just keep hanging out with or whatever,
doing this and that. And then we
do just start fucking working out.
You get jacked, right?
And then on the side you start talking
to other broads and then one day you show
up with a fucking Goddamn Hickey
on the side of your neck. You know?
And then you fucking just don't even
address it. What said I, you know,
I was hanging out with some girl last
night. So what are you doing today?
And you just, you just, you mind fucker.
Right back. You fight fire with fire.
That's what you do. Get on with your
life, sir. Fuck her. That's it. All right.
That's it. That's, that's what I feel
my solution is always the same. Okay.
Is when whenever a girl does
some shit like that. All right?
Or if a girl breaks up with you
or anything like that and, and uh,
if a girl still wants to be friends with
you after she broke up with you, don't,
all right? You get the fuck
away from her hurt locker. Okay.
Put on your bomb suit and fucking walk
away. Don't be the, don't be the hero.
You fucking walk away because they just
want to keep you in their life as they
slowly get over you and just constantly
be taking a state knife and shoving it
into your heart. Fuck that. All
right? You get away from him.
This, there's no point
being around this girl.
So right now this girl just
tried to mind. Fuck you.
So if you do the automatically
just cut off being around her,
she's going to win on some level and
she'll actually get some sort of level of
satisfaction that you reacted that way.
Because because even though you
think you're saying fuck you,
what you're really saying is I actually
cared about you and that's gonna feed
her Goddamn Ego. So don't do
that. So just be like, yeah,
I don't know what I was thinking.
You know? Uh, yeah. You can't. Yeah,
you can't. You can't blame a guy for try.
And that'll annoy her like she's just
some piece of meat you took a swing at.
This is such terrible fucking advice,
but you know what? I believe in it.
This is how I've lived my life. If you
want to end up like me, 43 not married,
no kids, that's how you do it.
I Dunno. Yeah. Just whatever
she wants to hang out. Yay.
Let's hang out and don't be weird
around her. Don't be weird. Hey,
sorry about that. I don't know
I was an idiot or whatever.
Now that's what you do.
That's what you do. All right.
And then what you do is start
talking about some other girl,
wait a couple of weeks and just say,
hey, you know, I Kinda met this girl.
I kind of like her and Blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah. You know, this is,
this is a fucking, this is
the old hook and lateral play.
I don't know if this'll work.
This is definitely a hail Mary.
But maybe if you fucking start
saying, hey, and I met this girl,
hey know I kinda fucking like, or you
show up at the Hickey on your neck.
I don't know what happens. The spinal
cord muscles, the spinal cord muscles,
the muscles around this spinal cord get
fucking eye. They get weak, you know,
and all of a sudden they just
fall face first and the elap,
sometimes that happens, you know,
but you're not going to know when
they should try it. All right?
Don't be Chris Webber and be looking
to pass the fucking ball here.
You want to take the shot? You
understand me? So what you do,
sometimes I say this shit and I,
and I step outside of myself and I just
realized what a fucking moron I sound
like. But I don't know. For some
reason you guys listen to this shit,
so whatever. Good luck to you. I just
home green
[inaudible] spray and the boat
safe. What's different?
They hard to get all those time.
[inaudible] do some little
differences this week
rather than me just sitting
here in my pajamas ranting,
ranting and raving.
I decided that I would get closed this
week and have a friend of mine come by.
Um, the one and only dom. I rera
everybody. Thank you everybody.
Do you mind if I get undressed? Huh?
I would feel more comfortable doing the
show I like in the nude and the nude in
the nude, not just in the nude.
I realized now, you know, look, look
how much weight I've gained right now.
You know, I've gained since I've
known you, but 30 pounds. Right.
And I know that. I can tell.
Well, you don't really look,
you don't really check me out. It is.
Oh, duck my head. My head is bigger.
What are you wearing? That slimming black
tee shirt. I've got Barry bonds head,
but it's interesting because now I don't
even know if this is a bit yet built,
but I think there's something
minute. I have to look.
I don't like women my own age. Right.
I mean, I can't, I can't fake that.
I get aroused by them. I always wondered
that. No, I always wanted to lean it.
I wish I had that kind of
love or something that I
need like a hot young chick,
but the only hot young chick I'm
going to get has to be flawed. Right.
She gotta be as daddy issue
inside or outside. Yeah.
You just gotta be messed up in some
way. But that's what I'm looking for.
How many, uh, how many strippers
have you, have you dated, dated?
Uh, only a couple. I was
in love with one. How old?
How old were you when you did, when
you made that move? Uh, two years ago.
You fell in love with the
stress lower yet. First of all,
it's just a country song.
She was filling low. Um,
she was not stripping at the time.
She was bartending and just give him
the occasional lap dance and really
beautiful girl. Been to that
bar. Fun. But I'll tell you,
oxycontin and alcohol really mess you
up. Yeah. I don't know if you knew that.
Yeah, I got some, but I still
love the girl, but she's a don't,
I don't think we're getting
back together cause that oxy,
her husband and her two kids
keep blocking us. Oh Jesus. Dom,
you're making me feel
good. Making me feel good.
Some of the choices I made back
in the day, dude, oxy is a,
that's a terrible one,
right? Yeah. That's one
of those things like even
when you get off at your,
I don't know that you're ever a,
depending on how long you do it, the same.
I lost a buddy of mine to that.
Oh really? I got another one. Uh,
he's not doing so well.
Did you grow up in a neighborhood that
was a lot of drugs? Um, not like that.
Not like that. It was a, I grew up, you
know it was called the sec bullshit.
It was weed. There was the weed guy,
there was the bookie and then w and then
there was, you know blues obviously,
but you know when some coke
when you got older, but uh,
like nobody was doing like heroin and
crack was like you're out of your fucking
mind. Cause everybody thought if
you smoked crack, that was it.
You had done well the, they say
you get addicted the first time.
That's what they said. But I got friends
of mine who dead and they're like,
yeah, maybe they're addicted to other
things they didn't have time to be.
Maybe they're just better people and
better, stronger. You have good friends.
Let me ask you this. If you had one
drug that you think you would like,
what would it be? I know
what mine is. If you,
if I could do a drug that I've never
tried and I tried and you think that they
like, it's not gonna have any
repercussions. Just want to the feeling.
What feeling would it
be? Tai, I have a tie.
Well is I want to know, I want
to know what it feels like.
Like that train spotting where you
sink into the rug the first time you do
heroin. That's exactly, that's
exactly what I want that.
But I got to admit the
hallucinating thing tripping,
but I'll put that says that
somebody told me, like you said,
awake when you're tripping.
It's not like you don't know.
The trepanned you see the door
fucking melting. You're like, oh,
it's because I'm on acid.
It's not like those high school
films where you'd be like,
you thought you could fly and shit
like that jumped out the window. No, I
uh, what was that movie with that old
guy? Was it something funny to me?
Larry Alan Arkin did a part where he
played an old guy and he fucking, uh,
he just, he got addicted to heroin
like his seventies and he's just like,
what the fuck? I'm 70. That's a good,
actually a good idea just to try it.
It's 70. I mean, I'd rather go out
shooting drugs and go out taking,
you know, Dick in the
ass. That must hurt, man.
That's the thing. You ever think about
that seriously? Bill taken one? Yeah,
excepting one. I think taking one for
the tee and taking one for the team.
All tell him your number came up. Sorry.
You're not going to like this like this.
I don't think so. We worked this out.
No, I've actually thought
you, you only a priest. How I,
how I want to go out and buy
wolves eating shredded by animals.
Yeah.
I either want to live to be like 105
like you live so long that there's like
nobody at your funeral because you
outlived everyone who gives a shit or the,
you know, because cause that is what funny
image cause that's one of the things,
if you live long enough, this,
I'm pretty sure he had people that cared
about like people doing the eulogy.
Like, I mean, you know, he says I met
him when he was 87 and uh, you know,
he was all like, he like playing
cards, which those slippers,
I always wore those slippers.
But if you die, like,
you know, like all my friends, you know,
who have died tragically fucking young,
it seems, I mean you pack the house
and everybody's up there flying.
That's the only good thing about
Diane Young is everybody gives a fuck.
If there's articles written about you,
there's nothing worse with, I mean,
there's nothing worse than dying
yet, but Diane old also is, you know,
you sit in there, you got that
fucking old terrified picture. Know
my uncle Tony when he died, he really
was very prejudiced and very angry,
but he also loved his children.
He loved God. He loved mountains.
And then when he died, it was so funny
that make up for the racist. Yeah,
but I'm saying he was that
balanced crosses on people
in the nature love birds.
It's true though. He was
like all that. And he's,
and what were standing around the coffin?
You see that mountain? It's for us.
It's for us. Not these other
people. This is God's country.
But when we're around the
courtroom, we're standing, you know,
people lie about people after they
died, and this guy leave for Deli,
who was the first Italian character
ever did? Like I got down a little, uh,
he said, we're staying there.
Me and a friend of mine is a priest and
like a couple of my cousins and we're
standing there over the body and he goes,
he never had a bad word
to say about anybody.
And we went from crying to fucking
laugh. And I'm thinking, like I said,
all he did was have bad words said,
but everybody, and then he goes,
listen to this, this is a
really old reference. He goes,
he never hated anybody except
Larry Bowa, right? Larry Bo,
the old for the Phillies. And he
goes and he looks up, he goes,
he hated that mother fucker would
of vengeance. Was he a gambler? No,
he didn't gamble. He just hated him.
He hated the Larry Book cause he hit
one 75 but he was a great fielder.
But I mean hell, what a, what an
obscure reference to make at a funeral.
Right. So in general, back in the day,
he probably just didn't
like second basements right.
Straight in front of the board.
But I love that everybody laughed.
I've had a couple of
those that like funerals.
Oh, we're crying, losing from
crying, crying, crying, laughing.
I did that one time, a buddy of mine,
his dad died and it was just one of those
fucking, you know, tragic. You know,
we were young and he died on to
nowhere and the kid had already lost,
his mom was fucking horrible.
And uh, so it was pouring,
raining to make it even worse. Fucking
like the, remember the movie seven?
It was raining like that. Okay.
Yeah. So we, we, you know,
go, you know, we'll go through the
surface and now they're gonna, you know,
put the guy on the ground and
the guy was so popular. I mean,
it was just a zillion people there. So
they had like one of these, you know,
one of those pop tents with no sides to
it. So there's so many fucking people,
everybody's jamming in there. Me
and my buddy can't get in, you know,
we're on the outer ring, we're
just getting rained on and shit.
And my other asshole friend is just
inside the tent and he's sitting there and
we're all crying and stuff and bringing
the body down. And all of a sudden,
just from the weight of the rain,
like this little like canal
started pouring down and
just missing my friend and
my buddy in the middle of crimes,
we're standing rain just reached up and
adjusted it. So it went all his coat.
But he had like this wool kind of coat
on so he couldn't feel it at first.
And Dude, I'm talking, crying, laughing,
just crying because it was so sad.
And that's the thing too that I never
thought people ever understand about
comics when they have a distasteful joke,
like of a boat sinks as a plane
crash and you have a joke.
They always think it's cause you're
insensitive and they'd sometimes don't
understand that it's, it's a defense
mechanism where it's sitting the pain.
Yeah, I'm feeling something bad. I don't
want to feel it. And then you, you,
you make a fucking joke
and then you're laughing.
Cause you don't want to feel that. So
you're actually doing it because you get,
it's kind of, I think, I
think it's like a dysfunction.
It's kind of a form of dysfunction.
Well, I couldn't file jokes.
We all know how terrible that is. And
yet when you give a 20 incidences,
but you could, you can twist
them around. I usually bring up
back on myself, you know, like, uh, one
joke that says, you know what about me,
father, I wasn't hot enough
for you. You know what I mean?
Like that kind of thing to make it
me. I wouldn't want to hurt a kid,
but there's a good example of
something that's cause so many people,
so much pain. And I'm not just talking
about the physical pain. Yeah. But, um,
you know, we do.
Oh No, you, you end somebody's
life when you, that's why that,
that said Dusky guy, you know, like
they shouldn't put those good. They,
they should automatically get the
death penalty just immediately.
They take them out. Dude, if you've
got a rabid dog in your neighborhood,
you fucking put it down. Those
sex offender guys, that's it.
Because all those people
that that dude fucked with,
it's like that's gonna now affect. You
want to talk about dating strippers?
Like how that's going to affect who
they pick. You know who they pick as a,
uh, a wife, how they treat
their kids. They make, they,
there's a chance that they
could, you know, sometimes,
I don't know if it happened.
I'm going to go beyond my intelligence
on this shit, which isn't too hard to do,
but I,
all I know is that that's generations
of therapy because of the abuse of the,
they repeat the whoever. Then
those guys don't get the,
you can't put that guy in jail
and like, I mean, how long,
like you're attracted to what you're
attracted to no amount on a cell. Well,
especially that time. If
they suck you in a cell,
how long before you wouldn't
like big ticket strippers,
you'd come out eight years
later, I'm dumb. I wait, get,
bring me to some pick tickets for
those guys. Like eight year olds,
you stick him in a cell
and you talk to them.
You try to undo it and show them an
adult that they're wired that way.
That's it. I'm just fucking sick
putting, put them down. It's your ethic.
It's why I don't believe in a
higher power that gives a fuck.
Well, that's a whole different
subject, but I understand that.
But did you hear that pedophile joke
about a, you might have to tell joke joke.
No, not at all.
It's a two guys sitting on a bench and
see an 11 year old boy walked by one guy,
pedophiles. It says to the
other one, he goes, boy,
he must've been hot
back in the [inaudible].
It must have been something
back in the day. Oh,
that's fucking twisted.
[inaudible]
[inaudible].